<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1174615" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-08-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3059</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Graham David Staley, Chief Financial Officer and Investor Relations Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Luiz Fernando Ziegler de Saint Edmond, Chief Executive Officer, Latin America</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Jo&#xE3;o Castro Neves, Chief Executive Officer, Quinsa</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Bernardo Pinto Paiva, Chief Executive Officer, North America</participant>
      <participant id="5">Luiz Fernando Edmond</participant>
      <participant id="6">Graham Staley</participant>
      <participant id="7">Lore Serra</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep">&lt;Q &gt;</participant>
      <participant id="9">Bernardo Pinto Paiva</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep">Graham David Staley,  Chief Financial Officer and Investor Relations Officer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thank you for waiting. We would like to welcome everyone to AmBev's Second Quarter 2008 Earnings Conference Call. Today with us we have Mr. Luiz Fernando Edmond, CEO for Latin America; Mr. Graham Staley, CFO and Investor Relations Officer; Mr. Jo&#xE3;o Castro Neves, CEO for Quinsa; Mr. Bernardo Paiva, CEO for North America.</p>
          <p>We would like to inform you that this event is being recorded and all participants will be in listen-only mode during the company's presentation. After AmBev's remarks are completed, there will be a question-and-answer session. At that time further instructions will be given. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Forward-looking statements are based on the beliefs and assumptions of AmBev's management and on information currently available to the company. They involve risks, uncertainties, and assumptions because they relate to future events and therefore depend on circumstances that may or may not occur in the future. Investors should understand that general economic conditions, industry conditions, and other operating factors could also affect the future results of AmBev and could cause results to differ materially from those expressed in such forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Now, I will turn the conference call over to Mr. Graham Staley, CFO and Investor Relations Officer. Mr. Staley, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Julia  and good morning, good afternoon, everyone. I am pleased to be with you again today to discuss our 2008 second quarter results. As usual, I would like to start the call by sharing a brief overview of the quarter and then Luiz Fernando, Jo&#xE3;o, and Bernardo will provide you with an overview of our results from Brazil, HILA-ex, Quinsa, and North America. I will close by providing more specifics regarding the second quarter financials.</p>
          <p>Before I start, I would just like to remind everyone that all numbers are in Brazilian GAAP and that percentage changes used in this call are on an organic basis unless otherwise stated. Turning to the results now. During the first quarter, our consolidated EBITDA reached almost 2 billion reais, which represents a 10.1% growth when compared to the second quarter of 2007, driven by a recovery in the Brazilian Beer and CSD market, a solid performance in North America and another quarter of strong results from Quinsa. The Brazilian business bounced back from a challenging first-quarter and is now back in growth. Unit volumes, which we previously reported has grown about 3.1% in April, closed the quarter up 3.8%, while CSD and NANC volumes grew by 2.5%.</p>
          <p>Luiz Fernando will be providing you with more details of the key drivers in a few moment. Our EBITDA margin in Brazil increased by 90 basis points behind good top line growth and as expected a much better performance in cost of goods sold and SG&amp;A. Despite higher commercial investments in our CSD and NANC business. Our Quinsa operations continued to deliver strong results with EBITDA growing 37.9% on the back of beer volume growth of 14.5% and CSD and NANC volume growth of 11.5%.</p>
          <p>In North America also, EBITDA grew by 5.3% despite declining Canadian industry volumes due to poor weather in the month of June. Market share grew again this quarter. Net income declined in the quarter, but is ahead 4.7% after six-months. Excluding goodwill amortization, net income declined by only 2.7% in the quarter. Earnings per share, excluding goodwill amortization, grew by 5.9% and is up 13.8% year-to-date.</p>
          <p>And I will comment further on net income at the end of this presentation. I will now hand over to Luiz Fernando as we start to look a little deeper into the results of each of our operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Graham. Good morning, everyone. Let me start with Beer Brazil. As Graham mentioned, our second quarter results rebounded from our weak first quarter with support for our view that despite full inflation putting pressure on net disposable income, the main reason for the beverage industry slowdown in the first three months was the expected and unusually cold and wet weather together with an early Carnival. Good revenue management together with strong and proper execution allowed us to maintain a flat market share of 67.3% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>You may have seen early this week that our market share according to the latest news report fell by 70 basis points compared to the previous month although year-to-date our share is still flat versus 2007. June volume growth was relatively low to the quarterly average and July was good, in line with the overall growth seen in Q2. We are obviously giving guidance into the market share results and once we fully understand them, we will respond in a rational and disciplined way implementing initiatives and recovering our share position. As you know, we do not react across the board but selectively and with precision using our proprietary tools. Looking forward, I'm optimistic about two innovations in our Skol portfolio, never the new 630 ml proprietary returnable bottle in Rio and the rollout in selected regions just a few days ago of our new world leader proprietary returnable bottle. Both innovations are helping to drive the Skol brand forward and of course the share.</p>
          <p>And turning to the second quarter, our Beer net revenues per hectoliter in Brazil reached 150.8 reais, a growth of 4.9% when compared to the 144.3 reais reported in the second quarter of 2007. This increase partly reflects our price increases in December and February, as well as an increasing the scope of our direct distribution network and the continued excellent performance of our premium brands, which grew around 11.8% in the quarter. Our beer COGS per hectoliter grew 8.3%, due to the anticipated increase in the cost of malt and corn, salary inflation and the benefits of currency.</p>
          <p>As expected, this was a big improvement from the first quarter's 13.1% and is consistent with our expectations of delivering a considerable improvement in beer costs throughout the year, as the year progresses, as our <mark type="inaudible" /> and our planned productivity and efficiency initiatives start to come true. Beer SG&amp;A excluding depreciation and amortization grew by 7.5% due principally to inflation, volume growth, and increase in our distribution, partly offset by the timing of certain marketing programs and investments which we launched in the first quarter. Beer EBITDA finished the quarter at 8% above Q2 2007, the EBITDA margin is essentially flat compared to 2007. Turning to Brazil CSD &amp; NANC, the volumes increased by 2.5% in the quarter and we delivered market share growth to take it up to 17.4% for the quarter, 60 basis points higher than last year. The latest Nielsen shows a further increase to 17.8%.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we continued to invest in soft drinks innovation for the launch of new products like Guara, which brings the Guarana flavor into the flavored water category. The consolidation of the citrus H20H, pear, apple, and Sukita grape and the 3.3 liter PET package which we will launch in the first Q. Despite continuous pressure from food inflation consumer spend, we continue to see good opportunities in the CSD business in terms of market share and profitability and we'll continue to invest in this segment. We believe we are well positioned for the future.</p>
          <p>The SG&amp;A, net levels per hectoliter grew 3.3% in the period impacted by a tough comparison from 2007. We continue to track and monitor pricing opportunity today and as a result, we have put through a number of increases in selected markets in the last two weeks. Soft drinks COGS per hectoliter fell 6.8% -- 6.1%, sorry,  in the quarter as a result of our anticipated hedge gain in sugar and currency.</p>
          <p>As discussed in our first quarter call, the benefits from our hedges and our plan to increase efficiency initiatives should help to improve the soft drinks current results even further during the second half of the year. Soft drinks SG&amp;A expenses in Q2 grew by 12.1% when compared to last year as a result of investments postponed from Q1 and moved into Q2. Year-to-date growth is 7.7%; despite this, CSD delivered another strong EBITDA result which was 18.4% higher than last year, with improved EBITDA margin of 37.5%.</p>
          <p>Before turning to HILA-ex, I'd like to comment on a couple of topics concerning Brazil which have been receiving significant attention from both the media and the investment community in recent weeks. Firstly, the proposed federal taxes changes in the Beer and CSD industry in Brazil which will take effect on the &#x2013; on or after January 1, 2009. At this stage, there is no new information to report. The tax authorities still need to determine how the tax will be regulated and we are in discussions with the relevant departments. Consequently, we cannot estimate how any increase will impact the industry or AmBev.</p>
          <p>Last week, the government announced a 30% tax rate change for non-beer alcoholic beverages, we do not think this has automatic implications for beer for a couple of reasons. Firstly, tax revenue from beer have grown substantially as a result of the recent introduction of 2 liters and secondly, beer prices have not grown as quickly as other alcoholic beverages in recent years. Therefore, an increase as high as 30% is not appropriate. I would also like to comment on the new law  introduced in June, which has established new limits for drinking and driving, the so-called Lei Seca.</p>
          <p>First and foremost, I would like emphasize our full support for any law, which addresses the subject of drinking and driving. We've always actively supported the government through our responsible consumption program and the donation of more than 5,000 breathalyzers to authorities and we will continue to do so. We are still in the early stages and it will be a few months before we are able to estimate the impact on volumes, if any. So far, we have not seen any dramatic changes in the trends from the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Brazilians are used to adapting to changes in their environment, and I am sure they will do the same quite frequentlyin this case. In fact, we have a number of initiatives already underway or in the planning stage to help consumers and the trade handle the transition. In the long-term, we do not believe the new law poses a material threat to our business.</p>
          <p>Well, let me now briefly turn to HILA-ex, the business generated an EBITDA loss of 28 million reais for the quarter. The Beer business grew by 3.3% with Peru, Ecuador and Dominican Republic delivering another quarter of market share gains and double-digit volume growth. However, we continue to face several problems in Venezuela which have significantly impacted overall beer performance for the region.</p>
          <p>Our strategy in the region remains unchanged. In most of the countries in which we operate, beer volumes and share are growing quickly while we continue to reduce the fixed cost in the business. And although the challenge we face in Venezuela will prevent us from being EBITDA and cash neutral in 2008, we will remain committed to pursuing our long-term goals in the region. As stated in our last conference call, 2008 will remain a challenging year even though the Beer industry has returned to growth during the quarter and we expect market growth in the second half to be similar  to the second quarter trend.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, we have confidence in the long-term health of the Brazilian economy and the beverage industry, in the strength of our brand, and the quality of our people. We rely upon the strength of our portfolio and our tried strength of precise execution in the market, pricing discipline, and cost management to continue to improve our performance in the second half of the year. Our people respond well after results of the first quarter and I have confidence in their  ability to continue to deliver.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn the call to Jo&#xE3;o, who will talk about our Quinsa Beer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Luiz, and good morning everyone. Okay. Our Beer and Soft Drinks operation delivered, I think an attractive result in terms of solid growth and increasing profitability with double-digit growth in almost every market where we operate. This has happened in spite of let's say difficult political scenario in some of the countries within the region.</p>
          <p>Consolidated volumes increased 13.3 organically in the quarter based on excellent performance on both the Beer and the soft drink business. Our volume growth was 14.5 in the case of beer and 11.5 in soft drinks. Solid market growth throughout the region and higher market shares in Argentina, Chile and Uruguay were the main factors for the significant growth in volumes.</p>
          <p>The market growth achieved in the beer business is a result of actions implemented throughout the region to develop the beer category. Our innovation group allowed premium beers first in Argentina and then Chile and now also in Uruguay, another successful action which permitted us from gaining share from the wine category in Argentina.</p>
          <p>Net revenue per hectoliter grew organically both in beer and soft drinks, as a result of higher prices throughout the regions and strong performance from our premium brands. The company performed particularly well throughout  second half in Chile, with Stella Artois delivering outstanding growth. In the case of Bolivia, the premium segment consolidated its position through the wide brand, a traditional Bolivian beer.</p>
          <p>In Paraguay, the Brahma brand that is over-performing the rest accounting for the important volume growth of our business. And unlike in individual beer markets, Argentina holds its all time record in the quarter in terms of volume even exceeding the volume before the divestiture of the two brands due to antitrust requirements.</p>
          <p>The Company performed very well in the premium segment through stock block and the recent models, Red Lagers, gaining market share in a growing and competitive market. The Bolivian business continues to post strong growth rate despite an certain operating environment, performance has been particularly good in the cities of <mark type="inaudible" /> , we took advantage of the industry volume records with our market share remaining stable. We also focused on some product innovation like [indiscern] our core brands. Our Chilean operations showed an important recovery in the quarter, based not only on a growing industry, but from a method  and important market share gain. We performed particularly well in the supermarket and traditional distribution channels, led by promotions and innovation. The Beer market in Paraguay continues to recover, which allows us to show another quarter with important volume growth.</p>
          <p>The company allows promotion activities and loyalty programs to compete against imported beers, achieving good results in the quarter. The Brahma brand had an excellent result gaining market share and becoming the most significant penetration of our global revenues in the region. Our Beer business Uruguay has also performed very well, reflecting a significant volume growth with increasing market share. Our premium brand, Patricia, showed an impressive performance gaining market share and contributing with higher profitability to the portfolio. We are also developing the category in Uruguay for the introduction of dark premium beers and a focused campaign to increase beer consumption in the wintertime.</p>
          <p>In Soft Drinks, we had an excellent quarter in terms of volume and net revenues with market share gains in growing market, both in Argentina and Uruguay. In Argentina, Pepsi  .. and Quinsa brands grew within their segments, while the A segment as a whole gained a market share versus the B brand, explaining a great part of our outstanding performance.</p>
          <p>At the same time, the company also performed very well in the flavored water segment, where the H2OH products continued growing and gaining market share in this growing market. Our net revenuesderived a little benefit from price increases and better sale mix.</p>
          <p>Regarding our costs and SG&amp;A expenses, we are introducing the initiatives or have introduced  initiatives within our control to mitigate the negative effect of higher cost of raw materials although metal and soft drink or mostly, in the biggest case soft drinks, transportation and labor. With strong focus on achieving debt transfer and efficiencies as well as the deconsolidation.</p>
          <p>Current growth rates in all the markets were <mark type="inaudible" />. Together with focused revenue management, cost initiatives have resulted in decent organic growth of 37.9% in the quarter, and 40.8 EBITDA margin which is 300 basis points above last year.</p>
          <p>I'd like to end my comments by congratulating my team for going the extra mile towards our aggressive targets. We have been able to overperform in the regions that had been particularly unstable during the recent months. And I feel very confident that with the status quo we will continue to unstrap, overcoming the obstacles that appear and fighting hard to keep our operations growing if the economy slows down.</p>
          <p>I'll now invite Bernardo to take over. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Jo&#xE3;o, and hello everyone. Looking at second quarter, I'm happy to say that Labatt delivered results consistent with our dream of growing EBITDA with no loss of our market share for the second quarter in a row, it's the first time in many years. Our EBITDA grew by 5.3% in the quarter on organic basis. The growth came from top line driven by share growth and by pricing in line with the industry. The industry volume as a whole in the quarter was below last year by 1% mainly due to the bad weather in May and June. Even with this poor industry Labatt's volume was almost flat against '07 due to market share gain. Our market share of Labatt grew by 30 basis points on organic basis in the quarter, resulting in a gain of distinct 30 basis points for the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>I'm happy to see that consistent to -- with our strategic focus on the Biela brand. All of our key brands, Budweiser and Bud Light is to sell <mark type="inaudible" /> grew their share in the quarter and in year-to-date as well. Talking about the import segment, we launched  Stella Legere, all light in mid-June. The light import segments are the fastest growing ones in Canada and Stella Legere will meet this trend. Stella Legere will bring distinct quantity and heritage of Stella to the light segment. Here we also address greater dealer inculcation. We had a good start but it's too early to draw conclusions.</p>
          <p>On the cost side, our Q2 cost productivity inflation profits were in line with what we saw in Q1,as we going to see to partial offset because of input pressure, through planned efficiencies and EBITDA initiatives.</p>
          <p>Our SG&amp;A is also under control showing a reflection of minus 4.9% in organic basis, driven mainly by EBITDA initiatives, and gains on  non-working dollars. Looking ahead '08 continues to be a tough  year where we continue to focus on few and big things. I'm confident that our top line strategy of  focus is at key brands, disciplined revenue management, create programs that deliver market share and effective execution is paying off. To support this strategy, we have been doing great focus to build a world-class sales organization in Canada. And marketing discipline and tools to ensure consistent and sustainable brand communication will get market share. Canada is a very tough and competitive market. And you can be sure that there are competitors, we will try to recover share during the rest of the year. What I can say is again we are ready to fight the fight.</p>
          <p>On the cost side, raw material price continued to be a concern. In the second half of the year the inflation on input price will be more challenge for our cost per hectoliter than the first half. In addition to driving into the <mark type="inaudible" />on non-working dollars, we will continue to work on revenue management opportunities, which include pricing <mark type="inaudible" />. Just to wrap up, I remain very confident in our ability to deliver full-year EBITDA growth with no loss of our market share, in line with the dream that I shared with you at the start of the year.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to go back to Graham.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bernardo, in this final portion I would like to guide you through the main lines between the requisite EBIT of almost 1.6 billion reais and the net income of 402 million reais as disclosed on Page 16 of our release. Total operational income and expense with a net expense of 437 million reais in the quarter in line with the expense of 444 million in the same period last year. The main item on this line continues to be goodwill amortization and transaction gains and losses from foreign investments. Our net financial results with an expense of 334 million reais, almost flat when compared to 337 million reais in Q2 last year. The increase in interest charges of reais denominated debt was fully offset by higher interest on cash and cash equivalents, higher interest on tax within judicial deposits and lower interest on contingencies.</p>
          <p>The provisions income tax and associated contribution was an expense of 354 million reais versus 295 million reais last year. This increase is mainly the result of increased earnings before taxes, lower interest on owned capital and higher non-deductible items such as goodwill amortization and translation losses from investors. Our net debt remained relatively stable at 8.1 billion reais at the end of June, compared to 8.2 billion at the end of March, as we distributed our excess cash flow from operations by way dividend and interest on capital on April 28.</p>
          <p>Our currentstrategy remains unchanged. We will continue to distribute all excess cash generated if we cannot identify value enhancing alternative uses within the business. Pay out will continue to include a combination of dividends, interest on capital and share buyback. The timing of execution of the buyback program will always depend on a number of factors, including the company's perspective on valuation and the goal of <mark type="inaudible" /> (24:40 price of the stock. During the second quarter, we adopted a conservative approach to our share buyback program given the market rumors and uncertainty surrounding <mark type="inaudible" /> transaction.</p>
          <p>At the end of June, 2008 we had distributing to shareholders 610million reais by way of share buyback and 1.07 billion reais in dividends and interest from capital. Also paid a further 987 million reais of dividends and interest on capital starting on July 31.</p>
          <p>We will continue to review the balance between dividends, IOC and share buybacks on an ongoing basis. In closing, AmBev once again reported EBITDA growth in the second quarter with good performances in Brazil and North America and yet another strong performance by Quinsa. We have robust business plans in place for the rest of the year adjusting both top line growth and costs and will be leaning heavily on our strong execution capabilities as the year progresses. I will now hand back to Judith and open up for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Operator Instruction]. Your first question is coming from Robert Ford of Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good day, everybody. Luiz Fernando, you touched base on competitive dynamics within the context of the Nielsen <mark type="inaudible" />. Can you elaborate on that a little bit more with respect to which geographies, which brands are being most impacted and historically which responses have been most effective in this sort of the situation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Bob, first it's -- I think it's important to say that year-to-date including July, share is flat versus last year, and the trend month after month during the year, or the trend and the share itself, became in line with last year. So, we were very confident that we will repeat the same numbers we had in 2007, maybe even higher with the strategy we had in place. July differs mostly the -- the use in July differs mostly to June volumes and as I said, June volumes were weak and that was mostly aligned with the bad weather we had during the month. July volumes were much better than June and in line with the average of the second quarter. So the share that was reported by Nielsen was unexpected.</p>
          <p>We knew we have some pressure in the off rate channel where the competitive environment became more aggressive after <mark type="inaudible" /> launch of the eighteen pack and the half-liter can. They decided to implement these different strategies that will be that was basically to maintain share and profitability in balance, so they can win the packages at a more aggressive price than the price they had before, but if you don't take the opportunity to increase their 12-pack or the single can price, that means that on an average, net price came down, and as we already anticipated in the first Q, in cans our competitors didn't have the same behavior and the consumers didn't have the same behavior as they have in returnables.</p>
          <p>So, not only they did not follow our price increases in the same pace with returnables, but on top of that, with the allowances they have, they put more pressure in can prices. So we knew that, but we believed that we could compensate that with our returnables improving, and the fact is that we lost share on an average like 70 basis points, more in the off trade, but also in the on-trading traditional channel, we lost across the board, and we lost mostly to Cinca I think 80% of the loss were for Cinca. The other players were pretty much flat, and we lost in most of the regions, but the main contribution, of course because of the weight we have was Sao Paulo, the great Sao Paulo. I saw some people relating that with the traffic restrictions, we don't see that kind of relations because it was not in the regions where the police did all the controlling things. So it was in different regions, different performers.</p>
          <p>So Sao Paulo was the main contributor to the loss, but we had similar situations, not as relevant, but we had other -- the same situations in other regions of the country. So far, we don't have all the details yet, because Nielsen, only reports, they report the numbers in a very summarized way the first day, then they follow it, hold back a day t to the competitors by one or two days later, so our team is working very hard to understand it was -- if it was something that happened in one month or if it's really reversing the trend that we had. Again, we -- first we have to understand the Nielsen numbers compared with our internal researches, we're very precise in the planning in terms of where we should act, how we should act, but we believe it is still a little early to predict if the trend reverted and of course we will just watch what's happening and will have to react accordingly. So, of course we will be stronger if we need, if we realize it is a trend, and of course I know investor are concerned we'll have to react with price. But we always react with price very precisely, very surgically, we have to react we do have right plan and not the closest one. So, I don't think why it should be a big concern going forward, but of course we have to understand and react if needed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. And then Bernardo mentioned some rising raw materials pressure in the second half in Canada. Our perception was that you cycle into better fx hedges in the second half of the year, can you more comprehensively address some of your expectations of rising hedges, maybe some raw material commitments that exist in another regions, and what you've done going into 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Paul, I'll take that one, Bernardo. You recall, Paul, as we've previously said that our reference for AmBev consolidated weighted cost of goods was 5%. We are still driving very aggressively towards reaching that 5% number on a per hectoliter basis and all the action plans are in place to do that. Despite the fact that obviously we are seeing higher inflation in Brazil, and the fact that InBev performing very well, I mean, the weighted average is obviously increasing because the inflation in that business is obviously higher than it is in the rest of the company. But nevertheless, we're still striving to beat the 5% target that we have given in the past. In terms of the hedges, the most effective hedges are, as always, in Brazil, and the big benefits come in the second half of the year with both sugar and currency. I think we started to see some of that in Q2 with the 6.1% decline on a per hectoliter basis for CSD in Brazil. We continue to expect good performances from CSD in the balance of the year, which we realize will bring Brazil down and allow us to get to that 5% target. Canada doesn't have quite as many hedges in place, some of the commodities we just don't hedge those items. And so we're facing as everyone else is, increasing day to day prices, which Bernardo and his team will work very hard to mitigate with DVP and efficiency savings but it's fair to say that you have to also see some increasing cost assists in Canada moving-forward the balance of year. As we look at 2009, we continue to follow our hedging strategy, we've always said plus or minus on smaller margin, which gives us some discretion to take a  position on cyclical commodities. So we're well hedged well into the first half of 2009 and that brings us obviously a lot of visibility over let's say about 40% of our cost of goods. And it's fair to say that the pressures that we saw in 2008 versus 2007 are not quite as great in 2009 versus 2008. Of course that is full dependence on the current situation continuance, if we see prices, specific commodities increasing dramatically in the six months, obviously it's going to affect the hedges we can place for the second half of 2009. So, just a note of cautious optimism that 2009 cost of goods doesn't look quite serious as 2008 versus 2007. Hopefully, that answers the various questions you raised.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very reassuring. Thank you very much, Graham.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is coming from Lore Serra of Morgan Stanley, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Good morning. I wanted to go back to Brazil for a second and just ask a little bit about pricing. We saw your pricing fall a little bit sequentially, and if I look at your revenue per hectoliter levels in the second quarter they are up about 3.5% or so from the fourth quarter level. So, can you talk a little bit about why we're seeing revenue per hecto &#x2013; a little bit  softer than I would have expected? Is that focused in the supermarket channel, or in cans as you sort of imply some of the recent pricing action has been, or what's driving that trend please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So, the first thing is the seasonality, of course first Q involved an anticipation of Carnival, even Easter at the very beginning of April, that moved the can mixed higher so in the balance of cans and returnables were more favorable to can. That makes our prices on average be higher than in second Q when the mix comes back to the average, put it this way. But also even in cans we expected the competitors to follow us on our price increases as they did on returnables and of course as they didn't, we had to close a little bit the gap, so we had to give more discounts in the big supermarkets than we expected and &#x2013; but we had also the returnables, the last representative because when you rebalance the price strategies the mix shifts towards the off-brand. So on average when you compare to last year, the mix of course came down, the cans came down from the first quarter but not in the same way it did last year. So you have both consequences. One the can price is lower than our expectations and because we have to close the gap and of course that mix there -- the shift towards -- the supermarkets introduce specific packs. That's what happened, but I think when you compare to what happened in July or June shares effective in July, there was a price change because of introduction of the eighteen pack from Cinca  they brought prices down at the end even more than they have in the past. So I wouldn't say that the reaction to this share loss is a consequence of the -- the share loss we had in July is a consequence of the Cinca new packs in the floor, the average price reduction. But not in the second quarter, second quarter was more a known price increase from our competitors overall in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So if you look to the full-year 2008, I know you don't like to give guidance on margins but it seems like you got less pricing going into the second half than you would like and maybe depending on how quickly this Cinca pricing reverts maybe even tougher than what we are seeing into the second quarter? Your SG&amp;A spending is trending up a lot in the first half of the year, it's up, I don't know, 12 -- 12.5% ex the depreciation and your comps are obviously up so is there a way you can somehow shoot for flat margins in Brazil this year or how can you offset some of those trends because they seem near term somewhat negative notwithstanding your comments on -- your optimism on volume at the beginning of the call?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think there are several reasons to believe that margins could expand next quarter. First, of cause we already mentioned the hedge effect. They will be more relevant quarter-on-quarter, so you saw that second Q was better than the first and we believe it will be even better in Q3 and Q4. Of course more in CSD but also in Beer, so this is one of the reasons -- second reason of course volumes help a lot so you dilute more fixed cost. And, as the solution is not linear so the more volume that you have the more volume on top of the previous years. Of course the absolute volumes increase more in the fourth-quarter than they increase in the rest of the quarters because of  the seasonality being more or being higher in October, November and December. So, for you dilute more the fixed cost that we have. But it's not -- the fixed cost doesn't progress in line with the volume quarter-by-quarter. Of course price is a concern, we don't want to react with price and if we have to react as I said, we will react very precisely, not across the board, but we don't believe in that.</p>
          <p>So, when you look at the progress you may have the impression that we didn't pass as much price as we wanted, but the fact is that we didn't, but we don't control our competitors, because they have to decide their initiative. What I see today is basically the low price brands; if you want to call them in this way, they're being more aggressive among themselves. So, as some of the competitors decide to be more aggressive in discount and the pricing it's not necessarily against AmBev,  it could affect the other players. So, today we really have specifically in the off trade being more competitive to near and low dollar low price between competitors that somehow is affecting us. So, of course we cannot fix prices as much as we would like because we have to maintain a balance and profitability and share in the short-term, but also making sure that the long-term health of our market is okay. So, of course make sure it is again -- early to anticipate the initiative we will watch closely, we will do that greatly we are trying to understand first it is if something that happens in one month of this work, we take the initiative then and of course understanding the causes, the drivers and then deciding what to do. It's really early to anticipate possible consequence of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and if I could just ask one more question -- the volume comparisons get pumped into the second half of the year and your market share levels were pretty strong. So, can you just give us a sense of why you are optimistic about the volume growth in the second half of the year? Does this relate to some of the new launches, you mentioned the returnable, the 600 ml? Or are there other factors you're seeing in the market that make you optimistic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said, June was a weak month and again because of the weather, if you compare the seven months of the year, we only had weather flat or better than last year in two months right, and June was really poor, that's why I would say that we are not expecting the share loss because somehow it can be mixed with the weather effect. July was again good and in line with the average, or even slightly better than the average of the second Q and the inflation starts to reduce the acceleration I mean if you compare month after month inflation came down and then as we said last quarter, the Government, the Central Bank was taking initiatives, so they basically increased interest rates and in Brazil it's not only about the past inflation, the twelve months rolling out to last month, but also the expectation of the inflation goes forward that impact the business. So, in our view the market is more, I mean, we don't expect the market to be as strong, but we do expect it to be at least in line with what we saw in the second Q. On top of it we are implementing several initiatives, some of them are very important like the world leader returnable glass bottle that we are launching now, <mark type="inaudible" />. But, again early to anticipate end results, but it's a relevant one, it's probably the biggest returnable innovation we did since I remember. So, we are confident that this kind of initiatives can transform  the market and give us more flexibility to add both in prices and share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your next question is coming from [ph}Trevor Sterling of Stanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, all my questions have been answered, thank you very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is coming from Alex Robarts of Santander. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi everybody, thank you. I guess, I'd like to go back the Lei Seca comment that you made earlier, I mean clearly this is important for just general visibility in terms of 3Q volumes and the Brazilian operation and I can appreciate that you, I guess, as you say, I mean need a few more months to kind of fully under or kind of grasp the impact, but if we could kind of just get a better understanding, what you've seen since late June when the law came in force -- and I mean just some thoughts maybe you could share with us vis-a-vis the geographical impact &#x2013; cities, suburban. Do you think that this is creating a behavioral shift in consumption patterns generally, for beer vis-a-vis you know the on premise -- the off premise, are you seeing kind of some trend there? And I guess kind of the last bit of this question, is the political aspect, I mean to what extent does the beer industry in Brazil have a chance to kind of fight this or suggest that this 0.2 level can be higher or changed in any way, I mean -- I guess it's kind of a long question, but it would be great if you can give us some sense of finally when you talk about no dramatic change expected in 3Q versus 2Q. Can we get potentially negative volumes in beer year-on-year in 3Q or again perhaps you don't want to give any numbers now, but any comments will be great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very straightforward <mark type="inaudible" /> When you put together market growth, the inflation, consumer inflation or growth trends, weather. If you put all these regular impacts and you compare that with the Lei Seca I will say it is impossible to explain any of the shift in line with the Lei Seca introduction in Brazil. I mean there it's not as relevant as any of the other drivers that we know in the industry that affect the industry today. This is the first comment I can make. And second of course, we're tracking and monitoring the consequences and we &#x2013; in our PPI week after week we track reduced because people learned this kind of a behavior they have to have and they start going to the restaurants with a determined friend that will drive -- that will not drink and drive so they drink soft drinks or they drink a no-alcohol beer which by the way we lead the segment, we have all the 0.0 alcohol beer in the country. That trade we have, so we have several restaurants in Brazil, for example, that have a kind of a driver that will bring your car back home, and then they have a kind of a motorcycle or a motor boy, that will drive the driver back to the restaurant to take the next consumer.</p>
          <p>So I think, to be honest, for a long time I'm avidly supporting global initiatives to restrict the drink and drive thing. Because we believe it's the right thing to do, and of course because we believe the impact is very small compared to the benefit of having the consumers in good shape, and all the negative image, that's all these accidents related to alcohol bring to us. So I think net-net, of course we always based the volume impact is of course neutral to negative, we cannot be 100% neutral, but we believe, in long term we will get the benefit of that. Again, there was an improvement week after week, at the very beginning we felt more effect on the premium segment on the &#x2013; super  premium segment, because of course, Brazilian consumers on average don't have a car, they don't go out to have food and beer, it's not like that. People drink their beer in the neighborhood, in the places they're used to go, and not necessarily like in other very developed countries compared to Brazil. So we are confident that with the time coming, things will be more to neutral than to negative. And so far, we haven't seen any, let's say, strong consequence of the introduction. But all the media that you probably saw, because of course it's part of the education -- educational content. I mean not necessarily proportional to what really happens, but the press, the government, the media, they all try to educate people and to make them change behavior. So that's what you saw from the outside world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is coming from Jos&#xE9; Yord&#xE1;n of Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. My first question was answered, but I had a question about Venezuela. Other consumer companies seem to be making at least some money in Venezuela, in a high inflation environment it's pretty easy to pass on your added cost to consumers and I just want to understand, what's different about your position in Venezuela that does not allow you to enjoy, frankly, what other companies are seeing as perhaps rising margins in that environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To be -- I think we have several factors in our business, even in Venezuela. First starting last year, we increased prices ahead of our competitors and we followed them very close and we thought that our brands would not suffer closing slightly the gap we have versus our competitors, both <mark type="inaudible" />  and not only that we followed much faster than we usually do. So we did not have time to read the market accordingly and to make precise moves, as we should. And after that, <mark type="inaudible" /> attack us in our stronghold market that we follow that have never to be able to perform into these regions, but given the price of procuring &#x2013; and several initiatives they implemented, they were able to capture a lot of market share in some of these regions where we were much stronger than the average. Then we had several problems in our industrial facility, during which <mark type="inaudible" /> we had some turnovers in our people,  we really did bad in Venezuela we were not able to manage all the problems we had. Of course, that is the factor and what you see today is the consequence of several problems we had throughout the last quarter of last year, and first quarter of this year. Things are more under control today and then of course we believe we can recover. We've already made the changes we have to make and now have to work hard to recover our share position, which is low. So it shouldn't be so difficult, I think moving one or two point share up in Venezuela is much easier than in Brazil. Of course, we have to solve &#x2013; to fix our problems and we are working on it and actually a better second half compared to the first half we had there. It's true, Venezuela is the biggest market, the biggest volume and today the most profitable market in July. It had the beg effect on the July results. We don't disclose it country like country again, but don't mix things, we consider to have a great performance in Dominican Republic, Peru and Ecuador, all of them growing double-digit volume and in line with our growth strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is coming from Alan Alanis of JPMorgan.Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Good morning. I have two questions. One for Graham regarding EBITDA and operating cash flow, and one for Bernardo regarding <mark type="inaudible" />. The one regarding EBITDA and operating cash flow, EBITDA is up 10% in the quarter and 7% year-to-date organically. However net cash provided by operating activity is down to 28% for the quarter and 34% year-to-date. Could you give us some details on what is happening with AmBev's working capital and other operating line items in order to reconcile the differences and what should we expect going forward? That's the first question. And the second question is for -- is regarding Anheuser-Busch Labatt regarding, what is expected level of collaboration in potential synergies between Labatt and Anheuser-Busch? And how will this benefits be shared between InBev and AmBev? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Alan.I didn't quite catch all those numbers on the operating cash flows, but let me talk in general terms and maybe we can have another conversation off line. We have a very high intense focus on working capital. We did see some, as Luiz mentioned earlier in Brazil, we did face some channel mix changes during the course of the year as the business moves slightly towards off-premise where terms of collection of receivables are longer than they are on the on-premise. So, that  has led to some deterioration. But at the same time we have very aggressive approaches on inventory levels and accounts payable which will stay in place for the long-term. There are probably some -- some non-cash items which I will I'll try to fill in the picture for you here a little bit, but we assure you that there was no lack of focus on working capital. No lack of focus whatsoever, perhaps we can talk a little bit more separately and go through some of those percentage that you gave. I'll let Bernardo make some comments, if he wishes but on the AmBev &#x2013; on the Anheuser-Busch, InBev transaction it would be totally inappropriate for AmBev to comment on that, a transaction that -- a transaction between two of the parties, it's far too early to comment on any implications for AmBev, obviously as part --with InBev having control stake in  AmBev, we hope there will be some opportunities in the future, but it's far too early to comment on those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Graham, just to add, I think -- 100% focus on <mark type="inaudible" /> shareholders with our focus and the way that we're operating here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right, Bernardo. Absolutely right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Alan, I think you should call us separately on the detailed cash flow question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is coming from Celso Sanchez of Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi good afternoon. Wondered if you can give us a bit more color, I know there's been a intense focus on this market share, in short-term market share, the bigger picture stuff going not just the second half of this year, early next year, with the ICI looking to the -- some sort of increase whatever the quantifiable number is, can you give us a sense of how you look at your priorities? Obviously volume helps fixed cost but at the end of day pricing is always much more beneficial to margin, can you give us a sense if the FDI goes through &#x2013; I'm sure it will vary somewhat based on the amount, the absolute amount of any increase. But I would assume that pricing and past results of that tax increase along the supply chain would be more of a priority than necessarily keeping volumes at a high level, which is ultimately just volume contraction, but rather a more modest volume growth rate but that would more basic assumption. Could you comment on how you look at that and specifically with respect to any kind of  price increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Celso, this is Luiz. I'll try to answer your questions, but I lost some of your words here, so correct me if I don't understand. So with regards to FDI, again the -- the government, they are -- different thing to the FDI, right? The first one is tax changes that the government submitted to the Congress and was approved. And then the government submitted another bill, changing some of the rules and moving the effectiveness of the new law  to next year, the next January 1, probably January 1. And -- but they still have a lot to regulate. So it's really difficult for us to anticipate the kind of impact that it could imply because we don't have the details, the roundup on details,  the kind of differentiation it could implement how they are going to affect the market to start with the depreciation, the size of  the gaps. So it's really difficult to say today what kind of consequences we may have. So we have to wait, we continue to work close to the government and to all the authorities that are involved with that. There are two sides, of course, there's the side of the ones that really want to defend a fair playing field issue in the market. And there are the ones that are trying to take benefit in and  to make things more flexible for them. This is the first piece.</p>
          <p>The second one is that the announcement of 30% increase on IPIfor the non-beer alcohol industry, most of the alcohol that do not include beer on that. I think as I said the 30% of course is now a reference that some people can use, but in our case we don't believe that's the right reference. Because as I said during the same period we have the full immediate implementation in the country, that tax collection, federal tax collection up by more than 16% compared to any other industry, the whole alcohol industry. So the government was able to through reducing tax evasion, I'm not saying they reduced 100%,  but through reducing tax evasion using the full meters increased tax collection and making a lot more share.</p>
          <p>So this is one thing. One other thing is consumer prices, and saying consumer prices that includes retail margin <mark type="inaudible" /> it didn't move up as much as other alcohol beverages. And for several different reasons that tax isn't aligned with our price to consumer. So we believe that the 30% will be too much for us, and of course we're willing to act  with the government, when it's appropriate because so far we don't have any discussion with them in that regard; we do have in terms of the regulation, but we haven't have any discussion in terms of any tax increase.</p>
          <p>So again early to anticipate. We are working hard in both directions, that they will have to live with this uncertainty for some time and of course at the moment it comes, the size it comes, we'll try to pass as much as we can into consumers, balancing our profitability with our share. Of course we believe it that impacts us  it will impact our competitors too, so share wise I think we should be in good shape, and of course the industry, depending on the size of the impact, will suffer as much as inflation will suffer in the country because of the relevance of this industry in the inflation index. I mean we will try to pass if not 100% as much as we can to prices when it come, and if it come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, that's a helpful answer. Thank you. And just a second question. Can you give us a sense, you talked earlier, I think Graham, you mentioned this about share buybacks and when there's value and obviously you are restricted while the deal was sort of in progress. Now that it has been announced, is there any restriction that's come off? Are you still kind of restricted and if not I would imagine that this low price used to be a fair amount of value, is that just more a function of what the controlling shareholder's priorities in terms of value are, what its cash flow through dividends or is there an opportunity to see some buybacks now that things have been resolved?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, Celso, the transaction has been announced, but the transaction still hasn't closed. And there has been a lot of uncertainty out there. We place corporate governance very high on our list of priorities and because officers -- some officers and board members of InBev which are also members of the Board of AmBev, we think it is the right approach to be conservative and just stay out of the buyback market for the time being. We will review that as things develop and as things progress towards &#x2013; what InBev say, I think will be a closing towards the end of this year. But at this point, we're just being very conservative and staying out, and obviously we will review our buyout strategy accordingly and that will have some impact on our dividend policy as well ....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, just to be clear, based on the corporate governance policies, there couldn't be a buyback realistically until the deal closes <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think never say never, I think at this point in time, there is still far more work to be done from what I can see between Anheuser-Busch and InBev and others, the shareholders of those companies have got to vote on the transaction and the regulators have got to review it. So for the time being, I don't think I can say anything more than the time being but as we get closer towards the end of 2008, perhaps things will become more crystal clear and at that point, any issues or concerns we may have over corporate governance will dissipate and at the point we could go back into the market, but we haven't got a timeframe, we haven't got an event in mind -- we are just taking it week by week.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
          <p>Operator : You have a follow-up question coming from Alex Robarts of Santander. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually that was really it, again, Graham, your comment to paraphrase, but basically what you are saying is that the buyback will basically be on hold for the coming months until you guys feel that there could be no potential conflict of interest vis-a-vis this transaction with Anheuser- Busch and InBev, is that fair to say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not sure it's as strong as on hold, we are just not buying at the moment, but, yes, you've basically got it in a nutshell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, your final question -- there appears to be no further questions. At this time, I'll turn the floor back over to Mr. Graham Staley for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much, Judithfor your help today and thank you everyone for joining us, and as usual we look forward to discussing the Q3 results in early November. Take care, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This concludes today's AmBev second quarter 2008 Earnings Conference Call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>