<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1247829" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-08-13</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3059</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Nelson Jos&#xE9; Jamel, Chief Financial Officer and Investor Relations Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jo&#xE3;o Mauricio Giffoni de Castro Neves, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Robert Ford</participant>
      <participant id="4">Lauren Torres</participant>
      <participant id="5">Alan Alanis</participant>
      <participant id="6">Lore Serra</participant>
      <participant id="7">Celso Sanchez</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jose Yordan</participant>
      <participant id="9">Alexander Robarts</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and thank you for waiting. We would like to welcome everyone to AmBev's 2Q '09 Results Conference Call. Today with us we have Mr. Jo&#xE3;o Castro Neves, CEO for AmBev, and Mr. Nelson Jamel, CFO and Investor Relations Officer.</p>
          <p>We would like to inform you that this event is being recorded and all participants will be in a listen-only mode during the company's presentation. After AmBev's remarks are completed, there will be a question-and-answer session. At that time, further instructions will be given. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Forward-looking statements are based on the beliefs and assumptions of AmBev's management, and on information currently available to the company. They involve risks, uncertainties and assumptions, because they relate to future events and therefore depend on circumstances that may or may not occur in the future.</p>
          <p>Investors should understand that general economic conditions, industry conditions and other operating factors could also affect the future results of AmBev and could cause results to differ materially from those expressed in such forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll turn the conference over to Mr. Nelson Jamel, CFO and Investor Relations Officer. Mr. Jamel, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Vijay and good morning everyone. I'm pleased to be with you today to discuss our 2009 second quarter results.</p>
          <p>Before I start, I would just like to remind you that, as usual, the percentage change discussed during this call are both organic and normalized in nature. Normalized figures exclude relevant items that are not recurring in nature. As normalized figures are non-GAAP measures, we disclose our consolidated net income, EPS, EBIT and EBITDA on a fully reported basis in our earnings release.</p>
          <p>As usual, I will start the call by showing a brief overview of the quarter and then Jo&#xE3;o will provide you with an overview of our results in Brazil, Hila-Ex, Quinsa and Canada. I will close by providing more specifics regarding the second quarter financials.</p>
          <p>Turning to the results, during the second quarter, our consolidated EBITDA which is close to R$2.4 billion, which represents a 13.8% increase when compared to the second quarter of 2008. Year-to-date our EBITDA has reached close to R$5 billion, an organic increase of 51% versus last year, while our margins expanded to 140 basis points to 45.1%.</p>
          <p>Our Brazil EBITDA increased by 8.1% supported by 7% volume growth, with our EBITDA margin in Brazil increasing 90 basis points to 47.8% driven by good revenue and cost management, partially offset by sales tax increases, freezing of certain market investments, and a higher accrual for variable compensation in the period.</p>
          <p>Year-to-date our Brazil EBITDA has increased to 12.9% in organic terms. Jo&#xE3;o will provide you with more detail of the key drivers in a few minutes.</p>
          <p>In Hila-Ex, we lost R$10 million compared to R$29.7 million in the second quarter of 2008 driven by volume growth, good pricing and its strict cost management. Our Quinsa operations delivered strong results, with EBITDA growing 37.3% despite negative volume growth for the region in the period. In Canada, volumes recovered for the poor first quarter and grew 2.3% in the period due to both industry growth and market share gains. Our EBITDA included 14.1% in the period driven by good pricing and timing of certain marketing investments.</p>
          <p>Normalized net income totaled R$1.375 billion in the quarter, which was 34.1% higher than last year. Normalized earnings per share increased by 34.6% in the quarter. I'll comment further on net income at the end of this call.</p>
          <p>I will now hand it over it to Jo&#xE3;o to start to look a little deeper into the results of each of our operations. Jo&#xE3;o?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Nelson, and good morning everyone.</p>
          <p>Let me start by discussing briefly our consolidated performance. We closed the first half of '09 with another strong quarter, delivering year-to-date EBITDA of R$5 billion, an organic growth of 15%. This growth exceeded our expectations given the continuing challenges in the industry volumes across the countries we operate other than Brazil, where disposable income and overall macroeconomic environment remain positive. These results were only possible because of the quality of our brands, our people and our focus on productivity and innovation as a way to prepare for what is proving to be a challenging year in several markets.</p>
          <p>Now let me start by detailing Beer Brazil. While real disposable income growth continues to contribute to industry volumes, we also delivered good market share gains in the period according to Nielsen. Our market share increased by one full point to 68.3% in the second quarter of '09 against last year. Year-to-date, our market share is already 10 basis points higher than last year at 67.7. These market share gains have been driven by our focus on innovation and are evidence of the strength of our brands that together continue to grow the preference in Brazil. At the same time, a more rational competitive environment in Brazil during the period has also contributed to our share gains.</p>
          <p>We remain committed to try to optimize profitability while improving our market share. And we are pleased with the performance of our 2008 and 2009 innovations today. We continue to look for new ways to connect with our consumers and enhance our brands preference to position ourselves to grow profitability in the future. During June for example, we announced the launch of a new 300ml returnable glass bottle and the launch of a new liquid under the heritage of Antarctica brand in Antarctica Sub Zero, both of which join our one liter returnable glass bottle, our 269ml slim can and Brahma Fresh, as relevant innovations, which have been well received by the Brazilian consumer.</p>
          <p>Our Beer net revenues per hectoliter in Brazil declined slightly when compared to last quarter. Excluding the impact of our sales of barley, our net sales per hectoliter increased 1% in the period when compared to last year. As I mentioned in our first quarter earnings call, we made our price increase to consumer during the summer, which was mostly followed by competitors. While price to consumer were raised in line with inflation, we have seen our net revenues per hectoliter growing 1% in the period.</p>
          <p>This is primarily a result of taxes growing ahead of inflation for us. As a reminder, Brazilian federal tax increased by 15% this year, which in the past occurred, every four to five years. It normally pressures net revenues per hectoliter in the first year it becomes effective.</p>
          <p>Moving to our cost of goods sold. We're very happy with our performance. Our beer COGS per hectoliter declined 11.8% in the second quarter, when compared to last year, as we continued to benefit from our currency and commodity hedges, lower price of corn, and improved efficiency at our plants, partially offset by general inflation. However, we do expect a more challenging COGS outlook for the balance of the year as our currency hedges rolled into less favorable levels for the second half of 2009, particularly in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Beer SG&amp;A, excluding depreciation and amortization, grew by 30.4% in the period. This increase is a result of higher volumes, general inflation, timing of certain investments, and higher accrual for variable compensation in the period. Year-to-date, our cash SG&amp;A increased 17.5%, mainly as a result of volumes, general inflation, and higher accrual for variable compensation.</p>
          <p>Normalized beer EBITDA finished the quarter only 0.8 higher than second quarter '08, with gross margin expanding by almost 400 basis points, driven mainly by good cost management, while EBITDA margin contract 200 basis points when compared to last year, mainly due to the tough comps on our accrual for variable compensation. More importantly, year-to-date margins expanding by 100 basis points, with EBITDA growing 9.7% versus last year, which is a more representative figure of the business's underlying performance so far, as some marketing investment and accruals for variable compensation phase-in have impacted disproportionally our second quarter results.</p>
          <p>Beer Brazil carbonated soft drinks and non-alcoholic beverages, our volume performance was once again strong. This was driven not only by the industry growth, but also by market share gains in the period. Our market share reached 17.8 for the quarter, which is 40 basis points higher than last year.</p>
          <p>CSD Brazil continues to be an important contributor to our overall profitability. CSD and Nanc net revenue per hectoliter grew 4.7 in the period as we continue to price selectively in certain markets, partially offset by higher taxes on sales. We will continue to track and monitor pricing opportunities very closely.</p>
          <p>Soft drinks cost of goods sold per hectoliter fell sharply by 15.6% in the quarter, despite the low comparison from second quarter 2008, driven by our currency hedge gains and lower PET price and packaging mix, partially offset by higher sugar prices. Also in soft drinks, we're expecting much more challenging outlook in our cost per hectoliter than we saw in first half 2009.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A expenses excluding depreciation and amortization decreased 4.5% in the quarter, as we anticipated important investments to support our brands into the first quarter. Year-to-date, our cash SG&amp;A increased 13.2%, mainly as a result of volume, general inflation, and also higher accrual for variable compensation, partially offset by the timing of certain investments.</p>
          <p>CSD delivered impressive EBITDA result, growing 63.3% versus last year, with EBITDA margin expanding by 1,400 basis points to 52.6%. Year-to-date, our CSD EBITDA grew 30.9 versus last year, with margins expanding by 660 basis points. And once again, the year-to-date results are more representative of the business's underlying performance so far.</p>
          <p>Before moving to Hila-Ex, I want to just spend just a couple of minutes to go over the impact of our accrual for variable compensation in our year-over-year comparison for our SG&amp;A. Because our team in Brazil had a zero variable compensation year in 2008, and our year-to-date results in '09 has been positive, our SG&amp;A excluding depreciation and amortization in Brazil has grown just under 17%, or 260 million, in the first half of the year. Of this increase, about half of it is explained by our accrual for variable compensation for Brazil.</p>
          <p>So should Brazil continue to perform well in the second half of the year, the accrual for variable compensation should continue to drive part of the SG&amp;A growth to the similar levels. Excluding our incremental accrual for variable compensation, our Beer SG&amp;A would have increased by 8.3 year-to-date June, while our Brazil EBITDA for the same period would have increased by 17.4%.</p>
          <p>Turning to Hila-Ex, we continue to face challenges in the region with an EBITDA loss of R$10 million for the quarter, driven by significant decline in the beer industry volumes in some of our key markets. However, we have started to see some encouraging results, which give us the confidence we are on the right track to turn around our performance in that region. Beer volumes declined 8.8 in the period as a result of significant industry decline across the markets, while CSD and non-alcoholic beverage volumes were up 10% due to strong industry performance in Peru.</p>
          <p>Moving now to Quinsa and our operations in the South of Latin America, we are very pleased with our overall performance in spite of the industry contraction observed throughout the region. We have been able to overcome this industry slowdown by gaining market share, both in beer and soft drinks, and introducing specific actions to boost revenue and optimize our cost structure. We achieve an EBITDA growth of 37.3% and a margin expansion of 590, almost 600 basis points. Both our quarter and year-to-date figures represent all time records in terms of EBITDA and EBITDA margin, with each single unit delivering strong growth rates.</p>
          <p>Our volumes were down 3.5% as a result of market contractions, mainly in our soft drinks unit in Argentina. We gained market share in beer and soft drinks, mitigating the overall industry slowdown.</p>
          <p>Net revenues per hectoliter grew organically, both in beer and soft drinks, as a result of price increase introduced in line with inflation and focused initiatives in terms of trade spend and revenue management. We aimed our efforts at capitalizing opportunities in the value chain, while fostering our premium brands' performance. At the same time, we are supporting and reinforcing our mainstream brands to maintain customers' loyalty and avoid migration to value brands in times of economic downturns.</p>
          <p>Our COGS and SG&amp;A expenses were negatively impacted by increasing labor, transportation, and some raw materials, mainly due to inflation. Nevertheless, we're benefiting from lower price in some commodities, effective currency hedges, and the continuous search for savings through ZBB and other best practice implemented. We recently made some strategic moves to strengthen our position within the region. We took control over the Pepsi franchise in Bolivia, and we added up the Budweiser brand to our portfolio in Paraguay. We are confident that these steps will add value to our business by consolidating our top line while bringing cost synergies.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to our results in Canada, well a bad delivery &#x2013; a 14.1% growth in EBITDA versus last year. This brings year-to-date EBITDA growth to 10.6% versus last year and showcase our ability to drive top line growth while continuing to remove cost from our business. Top line grew 5.9 in the period and has now cued profit growth at Labatt for the sixth straight quarter.</p>
          <p>Volumes in the quarter were up 2.3% versus last year, with increased shipments in all five Canadian regions. We continue to focus on maximizing revenues as evidenced by posting a 3.5% growth in net revenue per hectoliter in the quarter versus last year, while gaining 0.1 share points versus last year.</p>
          <p>Our COGS per hectoliter growth was 8.3% in the quarter as we have begun to cycle the commodity price to run up from last year. Secondly, significant production efficiency gains in our domestic brands are reducing the cost impact of our growing import portfolio.</p>
          <p>Cash SG&amp;A declined by 10.4% in the quarter driven by timing of our sales and marketing expenses, which will be reinvested in the market in the third quarter, and our relentless focus at uncovering efficiencies and removing non-working dollars from the business as evidenced by our ability to reduce our total distribution expense in the quarter, despite in bringing more volume to the market.</p>
          <p>We are very pleased with our performance in the second quarter and excited at the brands and brand building activities that we have in place in the Canadian markets. In a time when our competitors are focusing on the value segment, we are focusing on value creation and innovation.</p>
          <p>Our focus brands Bud, Bud Light, Stella, Keith's and the Lakeport family have gained 1.4 share points versus second quarter 2008, and both Bud Light Lime and Keith's White, which we launched in May and March respectively have both already surpassed our annual volume expectations.</p>
          <p>More than ever, we are committed to our strategy of focusing investment in our key brands, disciplined revenue management including price increase, smart trade programs and obsessive sales execution.</p>
          <p>We truly believe that our great people, strong brands, and tight management process, will support our dream of building both EBITDA and market share. Before I wrap up, and hand it over to Nelson, I would like to comment on the recent ruling by CADE, the Brazilian Antitrust Authority, with respect to a loyalty program called T&#xF4; Contigo, which resulted in a 352 million fine as well as the base that suffers in the press regarding some other market &#x2013; AmBev marketing strategies.</p>
          <p>Though we are fully recognize the importance and need for antitrust regulation to ensure a level playing field, we disagree with the merits of CADE's decision regarding our T&#xF4; Contigo program and we'll challenge it in the Brazilian Courts. We believe the program, under its current configuration, it's not anti-competitive. Based on the advice of our counsel, we understand that the likelihood of loss in this case to be possible, but not probable. Therefore we have not accrued for this amount in our financial statements.</p>
          <p>Therefore, other antitrust issues that has been reported in press reports, we believe that our marketing strategies are pro-competitive since they are designed to either attract more consumers and improve the service level at the point-of-sale, once you respond to consumer demand in terms of packing, and liquid differentiation, and have consumption occasions at more competitive prices.</p>
          <p>Thus, as market leaders, we take antitrust compliance very seriously, are committed to comply with antitrust law, and we will continue to defend our rights to innovate in order to better connect with our consumers or to improve our relationship with points-of-sale.</p>
          <p>Going back to the overall business, I wanted to finish by saying that I'm very pleased with our performance in the first half of '09. Our year-to-date normalized EBITDA growth of 15.1% was possible, despite volumes slowdown across most Latin American markets other than Brazil.</p>
          <p>I must say, we expect a tough year. We've prepared for it by putting all of our energies and methods to face the challenges. The results are proving our management teams around organization were well prepared and took the right actions with focus and discipline to meet the targets. I want therefore to take this opportunity also to congratulate our people in Brazil, Hila-Ex and Latin American South and Canada for their results achieved in the first half of '09.</p>
          <p>We expect the second half of '09 shall be more challenging year-over-year growth than what we saw in the first half of the year across our regions, both through industry reasons such as in Latin American South as well as tough volume in the marketing investment comparisons, particularly in carbonated soft drinks, NANC Brazil and Canada. But we believe we have the right plans in place and I'm confident that our people will continue to execute the plans we agreed earlier in the year.</p>
          <p>These plans are important not only to guarantee our short-term results, but more important it will position our company for future growth. Now I'd like to go back to Nelson.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jo&#xE3;o. In this final section, I would like to guide you through the main lines between the normalized EBITs of R$2 billion and the net income of R$1.3 billion as disclosed on page four of our release. Our net financial expense accounted R$249 million, a decrease of 22% when compared to R$321 million in Q2 last year.</p>
          <p>This increase is mainly driven by lower interest rates, as a result of the reduction in our gross debt and of the interest rates in the period. Our effective tax rate in the period was 21.6%, compared to 24% last year. This improvement is mainly a result of higher tax incentives versus last year.</p>
          <p>Our operating cash flow generation in the second quarter added up to R$2 billion, which is around 31% higher than last year. Year-to-date, we have generated R$3.6 billion in cash excluding our H1 2008 operating cash flow by just over 50%. All of this, while growing our profitability and investing in our brand and innovations has showed by our market share gains in Brazil, Canada, and Argentina. Nevertheless, operating cash flow generation remains one of our areas of focus for the second half of 2009.</p>
          <p>Our gross debt decreased to R$8.8 billion at the end of June, compared to R$10.7 billion at the end of December, as in the first semester, we focused on the retirement of R$2.5 billion maturing debt, while distributed to shareholders approximately R$500 million in interest own capital. At the end of June, we raised around R$400 million from BNDES to support our investments in Brazil. Since then, we have paid R$800 million in debt, which matured in July.</p>
          <p>We remain committed to proactively manage our capital structure and to return the excess cash to shareholders. And we had paid out in July extra R$745 million as IOC and dividends. Besides, we just announced the new dividend and IOC payments of around R$1 billion to be paid in October. That said, and assuming no significant change to the trend we see across the different markets, where we operate, I believe we are in good shape towards maintaining our dividend payouts similar to our 2008 levels.</p>
          <p>I will now hand back to the operator and open up for questions. Please Vijay .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Robert Ford from Merrill Lynch</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning everybody and congratulations Jo&#xE3;o and Nelson on the quarter. My question has to do a little bit with respect to the pricing, quarter-on-quarter, and I know addressed this in your comments, Jo&#xE3;o, and I think it was addressed in the earlier call as well. But I was curious, with respect to the segmentation efforts, the roll of the one liter and how you see the dynamics? Quarter-on-quarter, there was a relatively significant move in terms of pricing as you mentioned. And I'm curious just as to how you see the roll of the one liter in that dynamic? And what you anticipate over the balance of the year, with respect to any additional pricing you might be able to take?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bob. Well, thank you. And let me start by addressing the part I think on the dynamics and outlook of price and then I go into the details of your question. I think the outlook as we stated in the first quarter and still stated today, is that, I think the whole industry given the pressure the worry about the crisis and so forth and so on, the industry has &#x2013; it was and it still is concerned about profitability. Given that what we saw in the marketplace is that we moved prices, as we always do at the very end of the year. Competitors follow faster than in other situations and then prices have pretty much stayed where they were.</p>
          <p>Of course there are price activities, but nothing different than the usual. I think some people could think, maybe we gained share and we are, of course, happy with the share gains that we had this year and that because of that a more aggressive pricing situation could come in the marketplace. This is really not happening. Okay, I mean it's happening to the normal extent that there are promotions and so far can show one.</p>
          <p>So actually, the dynamics are good. And I think &#x2013; when I think about the outlook, we will as we see opportunities to rise prices, we will take those opportunities. It looks like it will be as usual towards the end of the year. This is I guess just on the broader &#x2013; on the broader page.</p>
          <p>When we think about the decline, I would tell you that the decline is two-thirds to three-fourths due to the tax situation. The fact that the federal tax or tax in general went up, it took most, whether 67 or 70 something percent of the price increase and a minor portion, whether it's one-third or one-fourth was due to the mix. Mix, whether we're talking about one liter, whether we are talking about Brahma Fresh, whether we are talking about the 269ml. We have had innovations, I mean, we now have the two new ones that I mentioned. Some of them with higher mark-up. Some of them with higher contribution margin some of them with lower contribution margin. So the liter does have an impact, but it's a minor one.</p>
          <p>So when I look about the future, I think the packaging mix will have an impact. But I think most of the impact will be, first from taxes, and second, I would say equally, price activity that we will not lead, because we're still on the &#x2013; working on the basis of putting inflation to prices, sharing profitability, very happy with share but it's not enough. We will always want both. So I'm actually looking in a positive manner for pricing.</p>
          <p>Positive in this case, is not positive in a sense that prices into price to retailer will fully translate into the net sales per hectoliter. Again, mainly from tax and second from packaging mix. The utilizations if we were to talk a little bit about them, as we have said it is the focus of the end of last year, this year and some of the years to come. Some of them will bring higher mark-up or lower mark-up, but I think what consumers in a way are looking for, I think it's interesting to see, that a lot of the market share growth came from innovation and people did see positive aspects of the proposition that we brought whether out-of-pockets, whether semi-gathering or if we're talking about the liquid such as the Antarctica Sub Zero.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Jo&#xE3;o, this year is going to be a little bit different going into the end of the year because you have the deadline for the SECOVI system implementation. Can you comment a little bit about your own experience with SECOVI and how you see the industry implementation as we get closer to the December 31 deadline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I actually think, Bob, when I talk about this rationality of the industry. I think the SECOVI once again in the same way the flow meters, back four or five years ago have helped to bring more people into tax paying situation that on the SECOVI is enhanced better version than a flow meter. Okay, we are in full compliance giving the calendar -- giving the schedule -- and we think most of our competitors are coming into this situation also. So this is happening in our industry as well as similar systems are going into other industries.</p>
          <p>So I actually think this is one of the reasons, why we have this rational situation or somewhat rational situation in the marketplace. I think as we roll this out, towards the end of the year and beginning of next year that actually should continue to help us in that mater. I think we as have always done in the past have to do as much as we can with the government to fight tax evasion, and we will continue to do so, and the SECOVI is one of the way to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then just lastly, I know you had an adverse sugar compare, but you're still hedged. Can you talk a little bit about your sugar costs going forward to the extent you have visibility?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think I will not, you know I would not go into the details for each component and Nelson can jump if you want to as I ended this. But basically, very favorable currency and commodities hedges on the &#x2013; especially currency hedged in the first quarter, not as favorable in the second half. And that's why we mentioned the comps on cost of goods will be a little tougher.</p>
          <p>As we roll into 2010, I would say that 2009 will be somewhat of a tough comparison. When you look at 2008 not that much, so we will probably be between the two. I think what could be good news for us to compensate some of the commodities that are going up is that, reis has decreased a lot and as reis decrease a lot, if it continues to decrease in the second half, this of course will help the cycling of the currency hedges for next year compensating the levels that we see in sugar that now are in all time high and as we roll this into the next year, that would be not favorable. But the currency will more than compensate for that as we roll into the second half of 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much again. Great, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bob. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Lauren Torres from HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. On your first quarter conference call, I think if you seem rather hesitant to endorse similar volume growth in Brazil for the second quarter, but you delivered similarly &#x2013; but &#x2013; similarly strong results this quarter. So should &#x2013; probably you could talk about the drivers of that growth. And if you think these types of growth rate is sustainable as we think about the second half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well. Lauren, very good question. You are right, I mean, I was hesitant and as I continue to be, I rather be as more of a mood type set I rather would be cautiously optimistic. Maybe I was more cautiously as we entered the second quarter and now, I'm cautiously optimistic. The reason to have that mood is, I think the fact that we were in a sort of tough mood &#x2013; tough mood mindset, help us to make a lot of hard decisions on the productivity side, and really helped us a lot in the cost of goods sold and somewhat in the expenses.</p>
          <p>We &#x2013; as we go into the second half, we definitely have a different mindset than we started the year. And as we see the industry better than expected and see this year better than expected, we have to prepare for a better summer because I think the worse that could come is not having the volume to serve our clients. So, we are squeezing every bolt to have a capacity everywhere, so I am more optimistic, but it's hard to predict. But let me then tell you about the fundamental factors that should affect us in the second half.</p>
          <p>And I think first, when we talk about the industry, we said that in the beginning of the year, the fact that the minimum wage has increased by 12% and that actually food inflation, it's still come down every month. This actually is a positive factor, very important positive factor that rolls into the second half. So that will help us to maintain at a positive industry.</p>
          <p>I think second, which definitely is very hard to predict. Although, some people continuously try and we also buy that is the weather. And we think, we have had positive weather, we also have had a lot of holidays in Brazil. And we are executing very well holidays also in the marketplace. That also helps, and that will continue to also be proved in the second half. So I think those three things, per capita income, weather and the holidays, and so forth -- those are things that will probably help the industry in the second half.</p>
          <p>In terms of market share, that of course has helped us a lot. I think there is one thing going on for us in the first half, that will also go for us in the second half, hard to say it will be of the same magnitude, which is the innovation. A lot of our share gains as I said in the previous question come from those new things that we put in the marketplace, so I think we are reading well consumers' mind and putting good things out there.</p>
          <p>We know our competitors are already and we will be clocking that so, right now we are playing a game where they are not there, they will come out to the leader as they have already come out with the smaller can. So &#x2013; but we also have the new news, we have Sub Zero that was not there in the first half we have the 300ml returnable bottle that was not there. So it's hard to say whether we will continue to run, whether continue to increase or even maintain a much higher level of share than what we started the year. We are almost two full points ahead of the beginning of the year -- share. So that should also continue to help us in terms of volume -- not as much in the first half, because we see competition coming, but somewhat it should help.</p>
          <p>So I am starting the second half on a much better mood than we started the first quarter or the second quarter, with all the cautions that a crisis moment should entail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Trevor Sterling from Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Sterling is your phone line on mute? We are unable to hear you, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Apologies for that. Two questions the &#x2013; concerning the currency hedges and looking at your policy of 12 months old, give or take 12-month hedges and when the weakness in the reis came, would it be fair to say that the big weakness on currency hedges comes in quarter four rather than quarter three?</p>
          <p>And the second question looking at Hila-Ex, this is quite a big contrast in the performance in beer and soft drinks. Is that purely a matter of country mix as you said strong performance in CSDs in Venezuela &#x2013; in Peru and presumably weak beer in Venezuela?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, well, on your first part of the question Trevor, is the currency hedged? Yes. The fourth quarter is the worst comparison as I stated in the beginning of the call. So that's actually -- given that we know the plus or minus 12 months, potentially 14, whatever. That's &#x2013; that is the case.</p>
          <p>And in terms of Hila-Ex what we saw, is that we saw actually a stronger industry in Peru in soft drinks, so that has helped the volumes of CSD and have seen bad &#x2013; some bad market, some bad volume industry wise even as reis also in Dominican Republic that has made the comparison negative for beer. Which I think it's interesting for Hila-Ex is that I think we have been betting in the right innovation also in those markets. So although the industry has declined, as it did in some of the markets in Latin American South, I think we are betting on the right products.</p>
          <p>So for example Brahma Light in Dominican Republic. We also launched the liter, the liter bottle also in Dominican Republic. And actually when we think share wise the performance has been very good. And that's true also for some other markets, but we did two things. So we knew early on that those markets would be tougher in a tougher situation. We think we have the right innovations in place there, but we did a much tighter control both in terms of cost of goods sold and &#x2013; as well as expenses. And I think that's the reason we actually quite happy with the much better although negative and this is somewhat normal given that we are trying to grow those markets, but we don't want to be burning as much cash as we burned whether last year or last quarter. So actually happy that the cost control both in variable cost and expenses have helped compensate part of the industry decrease mainly in beer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Alan Alanis from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good morning Jo&#xE3;o, good morning Jamel. I have a few questions, the first one is to do with, could you remind us how much of your beer volumes in Brazil are being sold through the 600ml? And how much of your beer volumes are roughly are being sold right now in your one liter presentation please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We're going to go with all the questions first, Alan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, that's the first one. The other two are regarding Canada and the ABI ramps.</p>
          <p>And I would like to hear your comments regarding what the strategy there? And how much the increase in the cost of goods sold is related to this, this significant shift towards Anheuser-Busch brands in Canada as you mentioned this Bud Light, and Bud Light Lime and Stella Artois being very strong performance in Canada but those might be less profitable brands for you. I would like to hear your thoughts regarding the strategy.</p>
          <p>And the final question has to do with the just a clarification of a comment that Jamel said, you mentioned that dividends might be similar to the levels of 2008, does that include dividends and share buybacks or only dividends? If there are only dividends that means that the money given back to shareholders will be around 20% less this year in 2009 than in 2008 and significantly lower than 2007, and I want to see if I'm listening correctly to that statement. These are the questions Jo&#xE3;o?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay great. Okay, Alan. Well, I will take the 600 and the one liter and I can give my comments on the Bud Light Lime situation in Canada and then I'll leave the cards of Canada and the dividend clarification for Jamel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think first we don't &#x2013; we for competitive reasons will not fully open the details of the 600 and one liter, how much is one and how much is the other one? I think what &#x2013; I would say two things.</p>
          <p>First, the one liter is a very focused strategy, okay. And then you know the market, you know soft drinks also. The one liter has been mainly focused on the route supermarkets. Okay, so the small supermarkets from one to four checkouts. And in areas where competition potentially has a value proposition that could be very aggressive, mainly also in those channels.</p>
          <p>So it's not a across-the-board type of situation. But once we found the right price point and the right channel, which was somewhat in the mid of the first quarter, the liter has started to develop much better than it was. I mean, I have to remember that the liter has already like 10 or 11 or 12 months, but as we fine-tune and find the right execution for the one liter bottle, that obviously cannot be everywhere, given that -- its lower contribution margin. We're very focused, and we see a lot of consumers liking that <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>When you &#x2013; when I said in the beginning, just to also share a little bit of a view, that out of our share growth or volume growth, a lot of it's coming from innovation. But then it's not really only the one liter. It's really the combination of much more availability in different cans. You have to remember now that cans in Brazil, we used to have just one offering and now we have at least six, okay. We <mark type="inaudible" /> 250, have much more 473 than we had before, much more 269, the 12 pack, the 18 pack, the 24 pack. Those are things that when you look two, three years ago or sometimes even next year were not available.</p>
          <p>So that has a big impact, together with the liter, but also together with Brahma Fresh. So you can think one-third, one-third, one-third just to think about how innovation as a whole and not just the liter. There is a lot of noise about the liter but the contribution it's really evenly distributed by those at least three different things that I just mentioned to you and we're coming also with Antarctica Sub Zero in parts of the country for the second half.</p>
          <p>So we're excited about the second half when you look about innovation, liquid and package as you know those are two areas that we are, we are working on and we know that a point in time competitors will come trying to copy some of that. When I talk about the Bud Light Lime and if I go back I think we explained, couple of years ago when we entered Canada, that we actually have a very, very good contract. We used to have a very good contract and we still do because the contract is the same with ABI, nothing has changed after the acquisition of Anheuser-Busch. So we had a very good contract, such a good contract that the Bud family -- gave very similar mark-ups than the Labatt Blue.</p>
          <p>So our tough decision back then was actually to find the right portfolio. And when we saw that we had the number one selling brand with Bud and that we are trying somewhat to hold it because robust of this and that we realized that was the wrong decision and then we start to focus in the right portfolio, that is much before this ABI integration or closer ABI relationship. In that &#x2013; given that, that is a fact and Bud is the number one selling brand. Bud Light was one of the most, the brands with the higher growth rates.</p>
          <p>And given that, we by consumer research thought that consumers were looking for that lime flavor. The brand proposition of Bud Light Lime was a clear potential winner in that marketplace. And we entered just at the end at this &#x2013; during the month of June. So, it's very early to give you any specific feedback, but they are very early, let's say two months, results are very encouraging so we're very happy with the introduction of the brand. And we are also very happy with the profitability that brand brings to AmBev given the very good contract that the previous management even before we bought this company were able to negotiate with Anheuser-Busch. Okay I give it to Jamel now for the other two pieces of the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jo&#xE3;o. Okay, hi Alan. Well regarding &#x2013; let me start with the COGS in Canada. We are &#x2013; I think we talked a little bit about that before, that Q1 and Q2 we should have a different comp in Canada. And as we would enter the second semester we'd start to see &#x2013; especially because of the commodities' price we start &#x2013; added commodity price, we start to see a better COGS performance versus last year.</p>
          <p>So what we saw in Q2 if you look at the increase of just above 8%, primarily driven by first quarter in terms of the hedge of the commodities we had as well as the depreciation of the Canadian dollar, so on average we had an implied exchange rate depreciation of 10% in Canada versus the dollar, which is an important component of the COGS also there. And that was pretty much driving the difference or the increase we had so far. And that should, as I said, get better for the balance of the years.</p>
          <p>And of course since we are selling more Buds and Bud Light like Jo&#xE3;o said, this has a better mix impact in the COGS, which is benefiting both net revenue and &#x2013; but also impacting cost and then we see, the net impact in the margin level, but at this stage, it's clear to see that the pressure or the decrease in our gross margin in Canada is much liked to the dollar depreciation or dollar appreciation and the commodities such as the first quarter had in terms of commodities rather than anything else. So that was about the COGS in Canada.</p>
          <p>Now going back to your question on the dividends, so what we said and then continue to say right to that we have no reasons to sit on excess cash, right, so, all our policy is also to distribute and payout the excess cash. You know that in the first semester and we had an important amount of debt maturing &#x2013; had R$2.5 billion maturing &#x2013; that we ended by retiring. At the same time we managed you to raise R$400 million and also have additional R$300 million in the pipeline for the second semester, second tranche of BNDES money that is used to support our CapEx needs or investments.</p>
          <p>So that's all we had to handling debts, and therefore, we just resumed our share buyback and our dividend payout strategy, which, as you look towards the end of the year, when I said that we should get to the 2008 levels, that's a range. We can be slightly up, slightly less. I'd say, today, more towards &#x2013; we already commented we can at least match the amount of dividend excluding the share buyback we had last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But that said there was this size as we see the evolution of the results for the balance of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now, you are &#x2013; right now you are roughly at 0.4 times net debt-to-EBITDA. How do you see the corporate structure in terms of debt &#x2013; net debt-to-EBITDA ratio for the remaining of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we had &#x2013; the 0.4, you're right. I mean as we take a bit of June that's a number you should see because we had a accumulation of cash primarily, which we used part of it already in July, when we tied something like R$800 million of debt, which we had of course <mark type="inaudible" /> net debt. But then we had the IOC and the dividend. So everything we announced so far in terms of IOC and dividends of what you &#x2013; according to the rates of cash also in the next month &#x2013; sorry in this month, but if you take our net debt-to-EBITDA ratio, we're up and go past the 0.4.</p>
          <p>Our historical range is something between 0.8 and one. We tend to be in the low end especially because of the IOC benefit that I can get once I can pay out IOC, a maximized IOC, a lower leverage help us in maximizing IOC and that has a extremely attractive fiscal benefit. So we should always find ourselves to watch the low end of that range. But it's something that we are handling on a constant basis and we don't expect the one to be towards a deleveraging below like the 0.4 or below this level like towards the 0.4, like we saw, this should catch up already in this first month of the second semester. But this is also in the end dependent of how much cash we can generate so it's a dynamic situation and that's what we assess constantly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Thank you, Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Lore Serra from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi thanks for the question &#x2013; taking the questions. I just want to go back for a second in terms of the Brazilian beer pricing in the quarter and I understand the comments made about mix et cetera and the taxation but, the fact is that your revenue per hectoliter went down 3% sequentially and if I'm not mistaken the excise tax increase was effective January 1, so could you just go back and help me understand what drove the 3% sequential decline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Hi, Lore this is Jo&#xE3;o. We &#x2013; when you look on a quarter-by-quarter basis you have the impact of taxes overall. So, tax overall is a combination of federal and state taxes. So taxes have taken. If we look at pure prices, okay, so price to retailer, prices pretty much remained flat, okay, quarter against quarter price to retailer. So when you see the &#x2013; two-thirds to three-fourths of the decline that you see, on a quarter-by-quarter basis, is taxes overall. So, it is the 15% IPI tax increase but also, you also have the state that's, on a quarter-by-quarter, semester-by-semester basis, they also increase their taxes.</p>
          <p>So, they also, they always do one, two or three times per year surveys, this year price increase there is a catch up process, okay. So, you should not only think about federal tax, but you have to account for state tax which is actually has not changed at all from past years, but maybe because the IPI was flat people are not taking to account the state taxes. So that combination of state tax and federal tax is where it takes this 60 to 75% of net sale &#x2013; of the impact on net sales. And the rest is the mix combination of the cans, the liter, the brands, that whole combination that's basically what it is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay that's helpful. So just speaking about the second half of the year, you are expecting more COGS pressure as you've talked about in the &#x2013; I mean, overall but I assume in the Brazilian beer business as well, the factor of variable comp and bonus accruals affecting SG&amp;A will hopefully recur because you want that to happen. So if you don't get more pricing isn't there some risk that your margins are going to be under pressure in the second half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would start by saying that one first, in terms of the variable bonus, it will only occur if we have good results. So given that we always worry about share and profitability and giving that we're having gain &#x2013; probably more share than we expected in the timeframe of course we wanted to recover and they have fully recover on a year-to-date basis, but only by 10 basis points but when you compare on a monthly, month basis it's more like a 200 basis points. We entered the second half in a way in a much better situation than we entered the first half. So I actually have the possibility here if we find situations where we can move prices and we &#x2013; if we were thinking that our margins will be affected. And I think we now have very good visibility on this. We have &#x2013; we may have opportunities to do some revenue management there. So I think we have a lot going on for us to try to not just to work on the gross margins. So if we find savings whether that's in cost of goods sold or whether that is in SG&amp;A, sure, put it back in the marketplace. As I said in the beginning of the year if I find good ideas I'm not going to work for the next budget cycle to really speed it up good ideas but again always given that we want to maintain an important level of profitability.</p>
          <p>If that doesn't happen, if &#x2013; I mean if we don't have the results we expect, there will no &#x2013; there will be no variable bonus payment. I think when we take out the variable bonus payment, and given that we grew the way we grew, I think if we look on the first half and not just on the quarter, because then you have the timing situation, I think we have pretty much SG&amp;A in control given that formula that from what we have mentioned that we look at in the best &#x2013; in the very many best years. So, I think we have SG&amp;A under control, actually we have a lot of good things in terms productivity helping us to eventually, if we need to, put some money back in the marketplace. Although we have tougher COGS, which is true, we also have savings that could also help us. And if we find a good situation for price increase on that mix of share and pricing we will do so. So, I look at second half more cautious but I'm optimistic giving the sort of things we have recovered this year in pricing analysis and in the control of expenses as well as cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great and just one quick question year-to-date, I think your CapEx has been something like R$500 million versus about 1.8 billion last year, can you just give us an update on what the CapEx budget is for this year please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure I'll ask Nelson to take over that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Our total &#x2013; hi, Lore, our total CapEx for &#x2013; the budget is around R$1.6 billion, out of it one billion in Brazil, and that's the type of investment level we expect to see, by year end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the good &#x2013; just to complement a little bit on this, I think the good thing that we've been able, expecting a tougher year but with the same CapEx we still expect that with the same CapEx we will be able to deliver a much bigger growth than we had I would say initially anticipated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our next question comes from Celso Sanchez from Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. I &#x2013; sorry to beat a dead horse on the revenue per hectoliter but just looking back I understand Jo&#xE3;o what you talked about was the state taxes. And I know the timing hence these are the second quarter versus first, there's an impact but when we look into years past the progression of first to second quarter, there really has been almost no change at all. So that's &#x2013; is that a big chunk of that 3% that what you referenced before the state taxing or is that really a pretty major change in mix away from cans in the summer time to perhaps less expensive presentations in the second quarter. You could just clarify that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Okay, Celso, I think it's the right question to question.</p>
          <p>It's &#x2013; again I think the last time we had an IPI increase is five years ago, so that doesn't happen every year. So we have to pass on inflation into prices, okay? And on a sequential basis it's much more, let's say, that combination although on a sequential basis the federal taxes are much lagging back so state taxes have a much greater impact. I would say that this is at least two-thirds of the impact and the rest is the mix. I mean it's not that I don't want to give my information on this, but it is what it is. I mean, we haven't lost any retailer margin, we have not lost any distribution margins. So those things are totally is still under control and we still have all the targets related to this, we are very comfortable on the margins whether retailer or distributors. But again, it's been a year and we knew it was going to be at this year on &#x2013; regarding taxes. And we still worry about taxes. We work day in, day out regarding that discussing with the state governments, with the federal government to avoid the &#x2013; it to get worse. And then the mix has an impact. But &#x2013; it's &#x2013; the smaller &#x2013; smallest piece in this whole equation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yeah. Just maybe talking a bit more about since the end of the second quarter, if you could give us some color there, that the comments that FEMSA has made, have talked about maybe rolling back a little bit of their pretty large price increases on a year-over-year basis. And having done some of that towards the end of the second quarter. So presumably that plus in fact that they did it late in the second quarter and that you mentioned in your press release, pretty rational environment.</p>
          <p>Has that changed at all? Would you consider what's going on since June 30 in the marketplace any less rational, or are you still comfortable -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, surprising or not and I think it's a very important question. We haven't seen that much price activity from them. I think ourselves, FEMSA and <mark type="inaudible" /> have all been rational to this point. If we were to relate some price activity, I would say this comes more from Itaipava perspective than from the other two players, but again this is nothing different than what we use to. So I think the industry is looking for ways to fight the innovation rather than price. I think we have seen already Itaipava launching a 310 ml can we have heard the rumors about FEMSA and Schin launching their one liter, about Itaipava launching their one liter.</p>
          <p>So my perception today, Celso, after a month and a half into the third quarter, is a more that sort of situation. I'm not saying there is no price activity. There is price activity, but nothing different than the normal. Nothing different than &#x2013; or maybe people expect it because of share loss or share gain. Their share gain is important, but let's also remember that what we did is to recover what we lost, okay. And then, okay, in the second quarter maybe we went a little bit further. But this is actually the situation today.</p>
          <p>So I'm not saying &#x2013; I'm not positive on the &#x2013; that we are going to see a major change in the third quarter. Up or down, okay. I mean maybe slightly down, slightly up, but nothing big. And then I think on the fourth quarter, as always, if we find, as we have found in the previous years too, to answer with the price, we'll do so. I mean that's how much outlook I can give pricing wise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Just finishing up the pricing question in Canada, can you talk just a little about what the role of Blue in the portfolio there? At least in Ontario, we've seen Blue below 30 for most of the past twelve months. I would have thought it would be more color of the Canadian, and it's at a substantial discount there. So can you talk a little bit about how you see that part of portfolio evolving and what the role of Blue is now versus maybe a year ago and years past?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think compared to the years past, it was &#x2013; a little bit in the way of I was answering the other question, is Blue is -- it's not a &#x2013; let's say, a top focused brand as it was in the past. So that has been a change we've made a few years ago. We &#x2013; of course it still has a role in the whole portfolio, but it's not the sort of focus than it was.</p>
          <p>And I think Canada, in a way, is also in the same mood, I think Brazil, in terms of innovation. I mean we have launch Bud Light Lime, we have launched the Keith's White launch, we have been strengthening the Lakeport portfolio, we've been strengthening the Bud and Bud Light portfolio.</p>
          <p>So I think those four or five family brands are right now of a greater focus than Blue. Blue will play a role as we have other brands in Canada, but not to the same extent that it had in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Jose Yordan from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, everyone. Well, my questions were answered, but I have one more on Hila-Ex. You mentioned in the press release that you were well on your way to break even or you had some concrete plans to break even. And I'm just interested on when exactly can we expect a break-even run-rate, let's say, for Hila-Ex. Is it the middle of 2010? Or what &#x2013; any color on that would be helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Hi, Jose. It's Jo&#xE3;o. You know we don't have &#x2013; we don't give very specific guidance here. What I can say is that, without getting to the details, I think every country operating Hila-Ex have now clear strategic roles than they had in the past.</p>
          <p>I think the work we did in the first half was to sort of stop the bleed, okay, especially in Venezuela. I think the team is doing a great work to stop that. As you stop Venezuela bleeding, you almost stop the bleeding of the whole Hila-Ex. So that's what we did.</p>
          <p>So I think we go into the second half on a much stronger position than we did in the first half. So I think the true situation is here. Even if we were to reach let's say break-even in the fourth quarter, that doesn't mean necessarily that I have reached already found a solution going for every year.</p>
          <p>You know our mindset when we entered there -- at least you have a zero cost option. I think that's have been the situation when we entered most of those markets. It makes still sense in some markets it doesn't make in other markets.</p>
          <p>But the zero cost option that causes R$80 million is not a zero cost option. So I think the first thing we have to do is try to go forward that zero cost option, which is break-even. But also remember that if we have a earnings strategy of still acquiring A or B by being there, we may have to be more aggressive in some markets and less aggressive in some markets, and we will see what will be the outlook as we get there.</p>
          <p>I think we have a clearer strategy today than we had in the past. And I think we have a plan to stop the bleeding in Venezuela that would definitely help the total of Hila-Ex to get to, let's say, to break-even level faster than we could expect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. I mean &#x2013; and maybe if you can give us a little color about why was Venezuela bleeding? Because I mean I guess the other visibility we have into Venezuela is through the Coca-Cola operations there, and they are not particularly bleeding, certainly not in the next &#x2013; in the last six months, with the artificially strong currency, et cetera. I mean what is different about the beer business in Venezuela versus the soft drink business that was making you bleed? Not to mention obviously that they're market leader and you're not. But I mean aside from that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah that is a big portion, of course, but I think there is no just one point. I think the combination of points. I think given the focus that we have in different markets, Venezuela was not that focused, and I think we made a few mistakes with the brand, the brand building efforts that we had, wasn't the exactly right pricing that we had, actually also in the CapEx that we had, so it's really a combination. I think we had the good run, back in 2006, 2007 we had the opportunity back then to maybe to make some CapEx investment to actually grow because we were on a roll. We were growing share. Back then, we were like more on the eighth, ninth, 10th sort of level.</p>
          <p>For different reasons we probably didn't do that. As you don't do that, then you ended up just moving the price, and maybe was not the right moment to move the price. And then you ended up, not exactly protecting your cost as you should.</p>
          <p>So it was really a combination of things, that at the end, given that we lost some share, you lost critical mass, when you are the number two or the number three -- as it is the case, number three in Venezuela -- any critical mass that you lose by losing share, it's a huge difference in the marketplace or in the P&amp;L, actually.</p>
          <p>So I think our P&amp;L in 2008 suffered from losing scale and by losing scale without predictability. If you lose the scale without predictability, you didn't respond fast enough for that new situation, which in a way was not just the 2008, but to us, some decision that we made even before that.</p>
          <p>So I think we quickly learned that in the beginning of the year and tried to reestablish the new situation, and made the right operational changes to be burning rate or burning cash on a level that is right for that operation. If you don't find ways to find the right scale for an operation where you have 4, 5, 6% market share, then your P&amp;L will never work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Alexander Robarts from Santander.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks everybody. Okay, I guess my main question really is on Beer Brazil SG&amp;A. I mean, that the cash SG&amp;A was -- obviously there were some issues -- and surged pretty impressively there. And I'm trying to just understand if we're seeing kind of just a general step up here in your business in Beer Brazil. And I guess the question relates specifically to this item that you discussed vis-&#xE0;-vis the higher expenses from channel mix. If you can give us kind of some color behind that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that &#x2013; is that a one-up. And I just kind of connected to this. I mean, when you talk about Brazil SG&amp;A, right, kind of the more &#x2013; the larger number increasing in the quarter 14% -- that adjusted number -- and then for the first six months, 8%. Do you think for the year are we going to be more toward the 14 or towards the 8? So that would be the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Alex this is Jo&#xE3;o. Do you want to give me all the questions, to just have an idea, because that is the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, okay. And the next two are really clarifications. I just wanted to understand, as you kind of mentioned in the press release, you're more optimistic on the second half than you were earlier in the year. And is that really -- or is the change there really just this notion of food inflation coming down quicker in a better innovation pipeline? Or is it something else?</p>
          <p>And then the second clarification is, in the appeal process with this fine &#x2013; the antitrust fine &#x2013; maybe you've talked about this before, but can you keep to T&#xF4; Contigo program alive, or do you have to suspend it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay Alex, thank you.</p>
          <p>Well, on the &#x2013; maybe starting on the clarification piece, I think what I was trying to convey on the more optimistic is twofold. I cannot be, let's say, as cautious as I was as I started the year. Because when I started the year, the way the world crisis would unfold in Brazil was not clear. So, therefore the world is not clear, not so clear -- not that is very clear now -- it was not so clear -- in Brazil, less, even less. I mean because we didn't know what was going to be the impact in Brazil.</p>
          <p>In second and third I didn't know exactly how our innovations would perform, so the reason I go into the second half more optimistic because now we have a better view on Brazil, so Brazil was better than what we expected, as the world given what we read hear and analyze, also is slightly better. So that the two external components, world and Brazil, are better, as well as our innovation market programs, market share gains, our specific industry. So I go into the second half much more optimistic than I was entering the first half.</p>
          <p>And having said that, we maintain, let's say, the cautious peace, given that I mean we're still in an unstable world. So much more optimistic about the second half, given all the disclaimers and worries about the COGS comparison the year-on-year comparison for consumer, So that's the first clarification.</p>
          <p>On the appeal process and specifically on your point of the T&#xF4; Contigo, the T&#xF4; Contigo, as is currently configured, it can stay as it is, okay? So I think that's the clarification. Going on Beer Brazil SG&amp;A, if I understand your question correctly, I would make two comments. We mentioned, as I said, the 8.3 rate for the first half. I think it's a number to keep in mind. That goes to the 16.9, with the accrual of the variable bonus. So the 8.3, if we think that inflation was 4.5 to 5, that the volume went up by the numbers that you know. That the fact that we're still growing our direct distribution center, so forth and so on. This has &#x2013; this fully explains the SG&amp;A.</p>
          <p>So if we go into the second half and we had no variable bonus accrual, given that last year we didn't have, we would be around eight or below. Okay, that's the sort of number. Again, if we were to repeat the volume growth that we had in the first half, okay?</p>
          <p>In terms of the step up, I think the best way to look into this, although that's not very easy to necessarily forecast or predict here. We are maintaining healthy levels of share of voice, okay? And we found innovations that work. Given that we have that -- as long as I find good ideas, I will only step up if they work. So it will be sort of a cooking in its own sauce. If I find the money from an innovation, if I find money from some product launch, and then I can put it back into the marketplace. So -- but if not, then I will not step up. I will step up if I see that it works and that I can as a leader grow the industry, as a leader grow my share, with innovation, which we learned a lot in the best year, years or so, contributing for us not &#x2013; to be not just a good company in sales execution, but also in terms of brand building, brand preference, understanding better our consumers, given that we know that the price premium tomorrow also depend on the brand preference that we do today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the higher expenses from the channel mix, Jo&#xE3;o, what is that referring to exactly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I know the channel mix exactly. I think you may remember that every time supermarkets have an important growth in the mix, they usually bring some additional expenses. This is on the key accounts mainly, which is around 10% of the Beer volumes. So if key accounts were to grow, it could have a growth also in that. That's what we're referring when we say channel mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you're not expecting something like this kind of in the third quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think supermarkets overall in Brazil are having a good run overall and in our business, so they have been growing. It's &#x2013; again it's not any breakthrough or anything but this has been growing slightly in the past few years. It continues to be slow that always add a little bit to the SG&amp;A growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the question-and-answer session for today's call. I'll now turn the floor back over to Mr. Nelson Jamel for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Vijay , and thanks everybody for your questions and attention this morning and that's all for today. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. We appreciate you joining us today. You can disconnect your lines at this time and have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>