<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1507767" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3059</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO &amp; Investor Relations Officer">Nelson Jos&#xE9; Jamel</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer">Jo&#xE3;o Mauricio Giffoni de Castro Neves</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Alan Alanis</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Lore Serra</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Robert E. Ford</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Gustavo Piras Oliveira</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Inc. (Broker)">Alexander Robarts</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Ita&#xFA; Corretora de Valores SA">Felipe Cruz</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities USA, Inc.">Lauren E. Torres</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thank you for waiting. We would like to welcome everyone to Ambev's Third Quarter 2012 Results Conference Call. Today with us we have Mr. Jo&#xE3;o Castro Neves, CEO for Ambev and Mr. Nelson Jamel, CFO and Investor Relations Officer.</p>
          <p>We would like to inform you that this event is being recorded and all participants will be in listen-only mode during the company's presentation. After Ambev's remarks are completed, there will be a question-and-answer section. At that time, further instructions will be given. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the safe harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Forward-looking statements are based on the beliefs and assumptions of Ambev's management and on information currently available to the company. They involve risks, uncertainties, and assumptions because they relate to future events, and therefore, depend on circumstances that may or may not occur in the future.</p>
          <p>Investors should understand that general economic conditions, industry conditions, and other operating factors could also affect the future results of Ambev and could cause results to differ materially from those expressed in such forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>I would also like to remind everyone that as usual the percentage changes that will be discussed during today's call are both organic and normalized in nature. And unless otherwise stated, percentage changes refer to comparisons with Q3 2011 results. Normalized figures refer to performance measures before special items, which are either income or expenses that do not occur regularly as part of Ambev's normal activities. As normalized figures are non-GAAP measures, the company discloses the consolidated profit, EPS, EBIT and EBITDA on a fully reported basis in the earnings release.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll turn the conference over to Mr. Nelson Jamel, CFO and Investor Relations Officer. Mr. Jamel, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Maurine, and good afternoon to all. Thank you for attending our 2012 third quarter earnings results call. As usual, I'll kick things off by giving an overview of our results for the third quarter. And then Jo&#xE3;o will discuss in more details the performance of each of our business units. And to close I'll be back with a summary of our financial figures, before we go to Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Well let's get going. Our consolidated EBITDA performance improved considerably in the third quarter, jumping 19.2% organically to a little over R$2.8 billion. Consolidated EBITDA margin expanded 170 basis points arriving at 47.3%. Looking at each of our divisions, we delivered 23.1% EBITDA growth in Brazil, with 220 basis points of EBITDA margin expansion, which is 51.2% in the quarter and net revenues were up 17.8% with volumes &#x2013; volume growth of 0.2%.</p>
          <p>In LAS we were back to double-digit EBITDA growth, despite volume decline of 2.3%, with our team delivered 20.9% of organic EBITDA improvement and EBITDA margin expansion of 70 basis points. Net revenue grew 18.7% in the region.</p>
          <p>And also an industry driven decline in volumes, 0.9% organic to be precise, but still managed to deliver positive EBITDA for the quarter growing 0.2%, with an EBITDA margin of 45.7%. And finally, HILA-ex continued on its steady path of growing EBITDA and contributed R$66.8 million to our overall EBITDA performance. Normalized profits for the quarter reached over R$2.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Jo&#xE3;o, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Nelson, and good morning and good afternoon everyone. Third quarter was a challenging and exciting quarter at the same time. Challenges because some of the headwinds we've seen throughout this year, such as tax and sluggish economy in some of the countries we operate, in a way they remain to continue in the same manner.</p>
          <p>But it was also an exciting quarter, because our team showed resilience, perseverance and disciplined execution in their profound ways to deliver, what I would characterize as an outstanding result by leveraging an optimal price mix strategy capable of translating into positive EBITDA results.</p>
          <p>Let's dive right into each of our business units beginning with Beer Brazil, which have an EBITDA growth of 22%, which since 2009 is second only to the fourth quarter last year, when they benefited from the easy comparison related to reported cans.</p>
          <p>Beer Brazil volumes were up 0.2% and market share was down sequentially around 30 basis points averaging 68.5 for the quarter. We estimate the industry grew by about 1.8. We believe these results are mostly to do with our decision to time our price increases differently than past practices.</p>
          <p>As we mentioned in our press release, a substantial portion of our increase in price to retail actually ended up happening in the third quarter, which was much sooner than last year and obviously had a favorable impact on our net revenues performance, which grew 18.5%.</p>
          <p>Since the Brazilian Federal Government announced on the eve of the excise tax increase to postpone part of such increase to April 2013, we have already announced certain price reductions to capture a lower tax growth as the intent all along was to past through to consumers whatever incremental taxes there maybe. But the quarter was not just about further pricing. This result would not have been possible without the strength of our liquid and packaging mix and the success implementation of our main commercial strategies.</p>
          <p>First, innovation volume continues to expand considerably and it still represent more than 10% of our volumes led by Skol 360 and Antarctica Sub Zero, which keep delivering a larger array of consumers, different functional and emotional benefits while adding more flexibility to our price strategy around the country.</p>
          <p>Second, since early 2011, the accelerated growth of our premium volume has proven to be an important source for improving our price mix and in the third quarter it was no different. Our premium brands grew volumes more than 19% led by Budweiser, which celebrated its one year anniversary since the launching in Sao Paulo last year. And we believe that since we are building a solid foundation for Budweiser to become the leading international premium brand in the country.</p>
          <p>In terms of distribution for instance, Budweiser has been sold since the beginning of the year in major cities throughout the country where its numeric distribution had doubled since then. From a consumer standpoint, the brand had steadily increased its level of awareness and preference among Brazilian consumers, creating results so fast, but we think even greater times are coming.</p>
          <p>Third, in north and northeast, we focus on executing our commercial strategy behind increasing Brahma ties with consumers in the region by leveraging our soccer platform with initiatives such as launching decorated cans of nine local soccer teams in the region. Growing Brahma is key for us to continue closing our market share gaps in the region, which is what we have managed to accomplish year-to-date and in the past two years.</p>
          <p>The other highlights from the region was definitely the arrival of the 300-milliliter returnable glass bottle, and the startup of two packaging lines for such presentation in two of our northeastern breweries, which bring us to our fourth top commercial strategy, returnables. The main driver behind our returnable bottle performance in the quarter was our push behind reintroducing returnable glass bottles into the off-premise channels with the one liter and 300-milliliter returnable glass bottles being placed either outside supermarkets in the greater number of pit stops we've been operating or making them or making their way inside key account or small formats supermarkets.</p>
          <p>Through September over 60% of key account stores in the region where the 300-ml bottle has been launched were already working with such presentation which is a remarkably improvement when we consider that in the beginning of this year, this figure was below 5%. And as this strategy gains ground, the more we improve our pricing flexibility and most important of all the more we deliver to consumers, new and more affordable pack sizes for different needs and occasions.</p>
          <p>Turning now to COGS, our COGS per hectoliter was up 12.8%, hit by higher volley in aluminum, higher depreciation of our industrial assets and negative packaging mix given the greater rates of one-way cans in the quarter. Year-to-date though COGS per hectoliter is up only 5.2%.</p>
          <p>As for expenses SG&amp;A rose 20.5% mainly as a consequence of higher accruals for variable compensation as compared to last year. Part of which is explained by a tough comparison giving low bonus accruals in the third quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>Commercial spend and distribution costs also grew but at a lower rate. Growth in our sales and marketing spend is consistent with our plan for the year, whereas our incremental production capacity for certain presentations had a favorable impact on distribution cost. All-in-all, for Brazil Beer, we delivered normalized EBITDA growth of 22%, and an EBITDA margin expansion by 150 basis points giving us 50 basis points of expansion for the year.</p>
          <p>Moving on now to Brazil, carbonated soft drinks and non-alcoholic non-carbonated drink, which had a second outstanding quarter this year and delivered the strongest performance in at least the last four years. Volume grew 0.4%, and market share was down 40 basis points, because in addition to the impact from pricing as already mentioned in my comments on Brazil Beer; we're also up against a very tough comparison of volume and market share wise due to the Pepsi two for the price of one promotion carried out in September of last year.</p>
          <p>In any event, year-to-date our market share remains flat at the record levels set in 2011. Our three-pronged commercial strategy built around; first, reinforcing our presence in the single-serve; second, pack price for multi-serve; and third, expanding ways of returnable packaging continued to show consistent improvements in the quarter.</p>
          <p>On the brand side, Guaran&#xE1; Antarctica volume in share growth is explained among other things by the arrival of one liter returnable glass bottles to the northeast with the packaging line that went live in our new Pernambuco facility.</p>
          <p>Distribution covered for this presentation more than doubled since January. Similarly, Fusion energy drink also benefited from a significant increase in penetration since the beginning of the year. Finally, CSD &amp; NANC also received a helping hand from Soda Antarctica, Sukita Laranja and Sukita Uva, our lemon, orange and grape flavor soft drinks which deliver great results, thanks to the success execution of a promotion for these three brands during the quarter in many parts of the country.</p>
          <p>In terms of pricing, net revenues per hectoliter improved 13.9%, thanks to the timing of our price increase, which followed a similar trend of what we saw in beer and also increase weight of their execution. As for costs of goods sold, we saw a raise in our numbers as anticipated in our second quarter call. COGS per hectoliter grew 9.3% because we faced a tough comparison against Q3, 2011, which enjoyed a 2.4% decline versus the third quarter 2010 because of currency gains and favorable sugar hedges at that time. Net-net COGS per hectoliter has grown 4.9% for the year so far.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A grew much less than the second quarter, but was still up by 18.8% with general inflation, higher direct distribution and higher variable compensation accrual being the main factors as was the case in beer.</p>
          <p>As a result, EBITDA for Brazil carbonated soft drinks and non-alcoholic non-carbonated drinks increased 28.8%, while EBITDA margin expended 570 basis points, which translated to an EBITDA margin expansion of 200 basis points for the year. Though there is too much to be done this year and beyond I would really like to stress that so far it has been a truly great year for this division, combining the maintenance of our record market share levels of 2011 with a much better price and EBITDA performance.</p>
          <p>Let's now move on to our international operations starting with HILA-ex division. Normalized EBITDA totaled $66.8 million with an EBITDA margin of 16.7%, which has an enormous improvement, thanks mostly to the consolidation of Cerveceria Nacional Dominicana's results, but it's still below the levels of our other business units. Therefore, we believe there's still plenty of room for growing that business in a profitable manner.</p>
          <p>By the way, a quick update on the integration. In the quarter, we already began capturing synergies through initiatives, such as the integration of direct distribution centers and the sales team, implementation of CBB and leveraging on vast scale and tools for C&amp;B procurement efforts.</p>
          <p>On the revenue side, we have been very disciplined so as to achieve better profitability overall, while maintaining or enhancing the brand health indicators of our local juice like Presidente, which is among the best beer brands we have ever had in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Latin America South, total volumes were 2.3% with beer volumes remaining flat in CSD &amp; NANC volumes declining by 5.9%. This volume performance results mainly from the Argentinian environment, which has to yet to improve and from a tough comparison on the CSD &amp; NANC sides given different time of promotional activity year-over-year. Nevertheless, thanks to our strong market share performance in most markets and our pricing initiatives across the region we're able to deliver net revenues per hectoliter growth of 21.5% overall, 19.9% in beer and 22.9% in CSD &amp; NANC.</p>
          <p>On the brand side, Stella Artois and our recent innovation launch, Quilmes 1890 and Quilmes Lieber are the most noteworthy, but in CSD &amp; NANC we're pleased to see H2OH! Limonetto perform extremely well.</p>
          <p>COGS and SG&amp;A for the region grew R$13.8 million and R$23.2 million respectively, mainly impacted by the inflationary pressures in Argentina. Despite this sustaining cost pressure Latin America South EBITDA grew 20.9% with gross margin expansion of 220 basis points and EBITDA margin expansion of 70 basis points.</p>
          <p>Wrapping up with Canada, Labatt's volume declined by 0.9%, largely driven by a weaker industry. According to our estimates, the Canadian beer industry declined by 1.2% versus third quarter 2011, mainly driven by poorer weather across the country. Meanwhile, net revenue per hectoliter increased by 1%. Our innovation have continued to deliver strong results and help us offset historical seasonality in the market share during the summer, which has been stable in the quarter and has been gravitating around 40.7% for quite sometime now.</p>
          <p>Also Bud Light continued to show market share growth and Brazil is evolving very positively. COGS per hectoliter increased by 1.2% due to higher commodity costs as well as shifting mix towards one way cans. SG&amp;A on the other hand decreased by 5.2%, largely due to the timing of marketing investments in previous quarter as we mentioned earlier this year. The net result was an increase of EBITDA of 0.2%, while a flat EBITDA margin of 45.7%.</p>
          <p>Before handing back the call to Nelson, I would like to briefly provide an update on our expectations for the full year results following our third quarter performance as we approach the critical month of November and December.</p>
          <p>Our expectations for volumes and cost of goods sold per hectoliter growth for the year in Brazil have not changed. Accordingly, beer volumes in Brazil should resume growth with a better balance between volume and price as compared to last year, while COGS per hectoliter should grow below inflation.</p>
          <p>Net revenue per hectoliter however improved significantly in the third quarter, which has caused us to update our guidance for the year to high single-digit growth, which is in line with what we have delivered in the first nine months of 2012.</p>
          <p>As far as CapEx is concerned, we have reiterated our commitment of investing up to R$2.5 billion in Brazil for the year. We believe that the changes promoted by the Brazilian Federal Government in connection with excise tax increase, creates a better environment for investment close to this level.</p>
          <p>So to finish off, some of you may remember that on the second quarter call, I said we had done our homework since June and that it was time to execute. Well our third quarter results show off that we are off to a good start but there is still a lot of hard work to be done if we want to deliver a strong finish for the year. That's the goal we have before us and that our team, myself included, will pursue as we're determined as ever. Nelson, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jo&#xE3;o. I will now cover the main items between the normalized EBIT of more than R$3.3 billion and profits of little over R$2.5 billion, I set forth on page three of our release.</p>
          <p>Net financial results were a negative R$144 million, which is R$38 million worse than the third quarter of last year. The main cause behind this change was the non-cash accretion expense of approximately R$63 million in connection with the good options &#x2013; option associated with our investment in the Dominican Republic.</p>
          <p>The effective tax rate for the quarter reduced to 15.2% as a consequence of higher tax benefits, such as interest on capital and other tax adjustments that helped to offset a higher taxable basis generated by higher EBITDA performance. Through September 30, the effective tax rate was 17.3% versus the 21.8% of last year and for the full year we expect it to be between 20% and 22% before a lower effective tax rate than what we had last year.</p>
          <p>Finally, we ended the quarter with a net cash position of approximately R$2.1 billion, which does not yet account for additional dividends and IOC payments of roughly R$1.7 billion, which took place on October 15. Approximately, R$5.5 billion have been distributed to shareholders to-date as dividends in IOC.</p>
          <p>So, that's it. And Maurine, could you now remind us about the procedures for Q&amp;A, so that we can take some questions, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. We will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question is Alan Alanis from JPMorgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much. Congratulations Nelson and Jo&#xE3;o. The question I have is regarding the SG&amp;A growth, this 20% that we have during the quarter. How much &#x2013; I mean, I know you've clarified that a lot of it is accrual for variable compensation, but could you give us a bit more color regarding how much of this increase in SG&amp;A is A, regarding higher direct distribution on the one side, and B, more regarding your initiatives such as <mark type="inaudible" />, the pit stops and the micro events? And if you could also give us some color in terms of how much of this initiatives, these three last initiatives can be expenses that are more discretionary in the sense that you can come in and out any given quarter depending on numerous factors or how much we should use in our model a more this new kind of level of SG&amp;A going forward? That will be the question. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Alan. Well, thank you. This is Nelson, and I'll start mentioning of course about SG&amp;A. You already touched on the key elements of the 20% growth we had this quarter, which was the variable compensation accrual, we had a kind of a tough comp, so if we look at this growth, more than half of this was driven by variable compensation, right. So that was the main element, but every time we talk about SG&amp;A and think it on a longer-term, like you said if that was on your question, I think it's important to go back and kind of refer to that equation that algorithm that you talk about, which is we normally should see SG&amp;A growing pretty much in line with inflation plus one or two points depending on how fast we're move from direct distribution and for also the impact of the volume growth, roughly between 30% or 40% of our volume growth in a way or another affect our commercial tract and then affect our SG&amp;A.</p>
          <p>So even if this new initiative that we have in place, such as <mark type="inaudible" /> pit stop and micro events, I think the question, it's not going to change fundamentally even because the part of the investment associated with this as a new initiative is CapEx related more SG&amp;A. So like the micro events, in advance we buy the art. We have CapEx along that and not SG&amp;A, but again back to the equation, we also always said that we'll never be bounced by the algorithm given, I mean if we have good ideas or we want to invest behind the new initiatives we are going to do it, right. So, definitely what's happened this year, so we're not going to really stay to the algorithm because of I'd say different elements that are affecting our SG&amp;A.</p>
          <p>So in a nutshell, we might talked about the different sectors in Q1, Q2 and now in Q3, but I think it's fair to say that this year if one would apply, the algorithm should get glued to something like a high single-digit for 2012. And remember that last year, our SG&amp;A grew only 3% to 4%, so we have a third comp this year, but again if we proceed through the algorithm, instead of the high single-digit let's say between 8% and 9%, if you combine inflation, plus volume driven impact and also direct distribution, we're going to be beyond that and that's going to be pretty much as a consequence of first of all increased sales and marketing investments, especially to support the sort of price increase we're taking.</p>
          <p>So, we're putting in the marketplace a real price growth and a lot of this has to do with the excise pass through, but again have to ensure to give proper support to our brands given this extra price we put. Also distribution costs, they are going to be higher than what the, say the algorithm would prescribe and that's not only because of direct distribution, but mainly because we decided to accelerate some of the innovation rollouts and primarily the 100-milliliter glass bottle as I already mentioned in previous quarters. And we had also some incremental variable compensation accruals if you compare versus last year.</p>
          <p>So I think maybe the number to think of is, we're going to grow for the year definitely less than what we have grown year-to-date, which was in Brazil around 16%, but more than the high single that the algorithm would imply, so we're going to be somewhere between this two numbers as a consequence of the things I just described.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very useful and makes sense given the record high gross margins in the last 12 months that you have. It seems that the timing is right. If I may ask a quick follow-up just regarding &#x2013; could you give some comments regarding market share both in beer and in soft drinks in Brazil going forward, what are your expectations in terms of market share? That would be all. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Alan. This is Jo&#xE3;o. As you have seen in the past few years, I mean if we take 2009, 2010, we grew more than five points from low to high and on average around 2.6 getting above 71%. We have said in the past that we always would like to be between 67%, 69%, but of course, if we can grow above that on a profitable manner, well of course, why not. We are around 68.5% so we are &#x2013; let say well above still the 67%, 69%. I think in the commercial, let's say, the economic pressure be in the currency or be taxes, they are on everyone.</p>
          <p>Therefore, I think we can continue to fluctuate within this band of 67%, 69% looking for the optimal price mix strategy. So that's sort of an outlook if we think about share. I mean of course we always like to reaching our what we call our scenario three, which is grow our EBITDA within what we want, growing share or otherwise looking for the best balance possible.</p>
          <p>I think for soft drinks, it's not different in the sense that in the past we were fluctuating between 17% and 18%. We have finally broken getting to a point in time last year above 19% in a specific quarter. Therefore, I mean, we actually have been gaining share for more than 18 months which is sort of a plethora in this quarter. But I see &#x2013; I see potential for going somewhat further.</p>
          <p>So if we were to have some sort of range, which we never talked about but thinking that we could be between 17% and 19%, which is above our historical trends, I would consider to be possible as to where we are year-to-date and much better share or in line with last year, but much better than historical, which is the best result in the last three years. So that sort of where I would be looking at or targeting for the foreseeable future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much. Congratulations again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Lore Serra, Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Jo&#xE3;o, I wonder if I could ask a little bit about pricing in the quarter and you explained in the press release that some of it was because of the timing of the price increases, but I wonder if you could just give us a sense of kind of as you're into the fourth quarter, two things, as you're into the fourth quarter and you're up against a year ago when you had a price increase and maybe you've rolled back a few things. How much are the consumer level prices do you think up year-on-year in the fourth quarter?</p>
          <p>And then the second question is traditionally you've raised prices and there has been a catch up in terms of VAT and margins in the system, how quickly do you expect that to catch up? And then I guess maybe there's three questions here, big price increase how do you feel about, can the consumer take it? Antarctica is growing which traditionally has been lower price, I don't know if that's saying the consumer is a little bit resisting, your volumes aren't just strong but it's a big price increase. So maybe I should have led with this question but consumer competition, how's it taking the pricing? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, so I think I got like three or four questions within the same one. Let's see, if I can tackle them all. I think first from a mathematical standpoint I think what we said is what you're calling the <mark type="inaudible" /> money the HSD, right, the high single-digit, we are around nine for the year, and said HSD or high single-digit for the year. So, I think from there you'll pretty much can get to where we're going to be in the fourth quarter. I mean that there is so much mathematic information in there to be able to forecast what fourth quarter we expect. But I think as we said, the more important part to it is how consumers are reacting to it.</p>
          <p>I think twofold, I think with few good goals in terms of short-term as well as the medium or long-term, I mean our short-term is what we're facing as we are talking to you and I think a little bit more towards 2013, we have good impression about everything that is happening in the Brazilian macroeconomic environment, in terms of the pickup, that we're starting to see in the fourth quarter and we also think that most of the things that the Brazilian Federal Government is doing or the measures to stimulate the economy, they should help the economy of 2013. Minimal wage will not be as a strong as this year, but it will be a real growth of 2.7%, which is still quite a bit, so bringing more money into the economy.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" /> with a lot of infrastructure project as well as the reduction at interest rate, I think the combination all those things with the Confederation Cup in 2013, in the World Cup in 2014 give us room to be sort of exercising the options towards this optimal price mixed growth. Of course, if we need, we have gone up a little bit. We can always roll prices back down, which we haven't felt the need yet. I mean, if we feel so, we'll do that.</p>
          <p>I think there are other things that we don't talk a lot about, but probably are also helping our outlook going forward on top of the consumer environment, which is positive right now, positive going forward. But also when we look at substitutes, it's important to mention that the <mark type="inaudible" /> or the control system for beverages done for the Brazilian government for beer, soft drinks, now is also fully implemented in what the government believes is where it should be for the <mark type="inaudible" /> or a spirits.</p>
          <p>So they are already catching like 80%. And when you look at some other alcoholic substitutes, price have gone up way above inflation and above what beer has done, because they feel the pressure of having the tax controls in place, which is also for us, and the additional controls that we believe the states will also put in place. So in case, there are any other tax opportunities, whether potentially some inflation that is going on, we think the controls will get tighter and tighter as we move on in the next two, three years. And this will also make a big difference for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what about the issue of kind of how much of the rest of the chain will adjust to the price increase you've had? Will it be on a shorter timetable than it's been in the past?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think because the increasing taxes are impacting all the players at the same time on a "heavy manner". And everyone is also facing due to the same cost pressures or even greater than what we feel. Our impression from the public available information suggests that some of them have already taken pricing as well maybe on a faster speed than the average. But I prefer not to further speculate on what other competitor are doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm sorry. I was taking about VAT and sort of retailer margins, things like that, adjusting to the price increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, every time you move the price &#x2013; actually the first thing that happens even in the very short-term, you gain some margin, okay, so that's not being very different. But I think the difference this time around from all stakeholders or other competitors, retailers, anyone, this has been sort of announced four months ago. So because it was announced four months ago, I think everyone was ready to the October 1 date. Therefore, pretty much, you saw a lot of stakeholders acting upon it right away.</p>
          <p>And talking everyone, but when you ask about VAT, VAT hasn't really changed a lot. I mean they have their sort of whether yearly, quarterly, semester, depend on the state by state calendar that has &#x2013; doesn't change a lot on a year-on-year basis. So it continues to move in the same manner that it has moved in the past. So this actual movement has not made any significant change on VAT. The only difference that it will read with the expected calendar, the price increases as we move forward. There is always a delay, which is sort of a positive if you think about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Bob Ford, Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thank you and good day, everybody. And first of all, guys, congratulations on a very impressive quarter. I was hoping that you might be able to discuss the initial pricing, the market response and the availability of the 300ml presentation, not just in the Northeast, but in the trade as a whole, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bob, thanks. I think, first, regarding the initial reactions a little bit along the lines of Lore's question. So I think from a &#x2013; I think actually &#x2013; I think what I was trying to convey is that the response was positive given that we saw, what we just said, most stakeholders moving along and the consumers' sentiment, it's a positive one, given that, as I guess, it was announced from different analysts. I mean, everybody was expecting the economy to pick up in the fourth quarter. We see that happening. So I actually think that we are sort of lucky that our price increases coming at the best moment from a GDP pickup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, Jo&#xE3;o. I wasn't talking about the price increases. My understanding is that you're putting in a 300 ml presentation at a substantially lower price, right. So I'm talking about the initial pricing of your 300 ml, which I think is a very...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I understood that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I understood the question. I was going to get here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because when you understand the overall pricing strategy, the 300ml has a very important part to it, which is you are &#x2013; we are able, as we've been able, actually, more and more in the best four years to have sort of a price increase, but continue to have affordable presentations to consumer. So, that shoots a little bit our pricing strategy. I think the 300ml has already grown a lot this year, but we expected a lot of growth in 2013, in 2014 and in 2015. I think we will not reach a plateau for the 300ml before the end of 2014. I mean we'll probably be doubling it, more than doubling it for next year. And probably another significant growth in 2014 and that should start to stabilize after that. It continues to be a very important strategy for us, because it allows us to have a better pricing umbrella, but again have an affordable presentation for consumers.</p>
          <p>We have new lines, of course. I mean we continue to have a lot of new lines, many of them as planned coming in the fourth quarter. And we already have roll outs for other regions, depending on where it is in 2013, and some more in 2014. So still a lot to be done, already helping us a lot. As I mentioned in the beginning of the speech, being very low accepted, we are totally focusing it on the off trade, on the pit stop, on the small formats. And we're still far away from the sort of coverage that we deem appropriate for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Jo&#xE3;o, where are you putting it in, in terms of price relative to competitors' can for kind of the mainstream brand like you said, Brahva, Kaiser or Nova Schin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I mean it will depend on a &#x2013; it's slightly different from a market-to-market. I mean we try to price to perfection in different regions. Okay? But I think the view that you get is in some places we continue to have, when we promote over special occasions, be holidays, or be together with the key account change, we can have the liquid for R$0.99 and with the bottle at R$1.49. So if you think tough at &#x2013; even when you taking at the R$1.49 , it's competitive against cans of the competitors, and when we take the bottles, totally competitive.</p>
          <p>So introducing it to market &#x2013; I would say that in many places we're still introducing it, because the consumers are buying. We're selling many times baskets, so that people can take home. There are other areas where you can see it at R$1.19 and then with a R$0.50 for the bottle at R$1.69, but net-net, continued to be very competitive. And as every other project that I think Alan mentioned at the beginning not so bad, pit stop, the micro events, they all have very strong &#x2013; very, very strong NPV positive project and it's not margin dilutive, because of the returnabilty. Even at those price points, depending on the can you're competing against has even better margin per hectoliter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's brilliant. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is Gustavo Oliveira, UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Nelson, Jo&#xE3;o, good afternoon. Good afternoon, everyone. I have a question. I would like to understand a little bit your strategy or your understanding of why you need the price reductions now in the fourth quarter, if it's something tactical just to recover a little bit of a share losses, as of your competitors are not falling? And understanding from your response in some of your previous questions is that perhaps you don't need to do that across the board. It's going to be more or like on some tactical resource or perhaps in some channels. I'd like a little bit more color on what's the strategy in the short-term and how you would implement it? Whether it's going to be like some real price reductions or you're going to go by more with like some sort of promotions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Gustavo. So I guess, first to put in perspective, the &#x2013; let's say, the commercial pricing strategy continues to be the same, which is price to consumer in line with the inflation, plus any new tax increase. So that continues to be in place. So when we understand that and we have prepared all of our prices for <mark type="inaudible" /> and given that part of it was rolled back, we wanted to give a part of it back. But, of course, as we implement it, we implement on a very theoretical manner, so there are places, areas, cities, brands.</p>
          <p>So the rollout is a smart rollout, where we need pushing the brand or the package, or the combination of brand pack in region, where we deem appropriate. So you'll find some places actions with the liter leader. So what we call the 400ml for free. In some areas you have seen some actions on the one way. So there is not to one single super bullet. I think the smart way to rollback some that we didn't expect that will come so often at the last minute. So that combination is a smart way to give back parts of what we &#x2013; what was given back, and in line with our strategy of putting prices in line with the inflation plus the tax increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When &#x2013; I still want to follow-up on that same question. When you think then about the first quarter, because then you're going to have the tax increases in April, would you have to reverse it in the short-term to a point that would be a little bit confusing to your channels, or it's something that is manageable, or you won't have to raise prices again in the first quarter? Just to understand this short-term dynamics a little bit better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's too early to get into details of 2013. I think if I was to refer back to some of the things I said, I think we continue to have more pricing flexibility than we had in the past, either given the pack price strategy and the different brand strategy that we have. Now, combine also with the <mark type="inaudible" /> different beverages. So net-net I feel that we are entering 2013 in a better pricing environment than we saw in the beginning of the last two years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I have then two more like &#x2013; more &#x2013; a little bit of just some data driven questions. If you could give an idea of your effective tax rate for 2013. And the last question would be also in terms of your tax increases in soft drinks. Is there is any room for negotiations with the government for a process similar to what you're achieving in the beer industry. And if you achieve that, if there is room even for that to be retroactively to &#x2013; for the beginning of the first four quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Gustavo. This is Nelson. Well, just first tackling the effective tax rate. We had a good quarter in that and but you know that it's tricky to look at the effective tax rate on a quarterly basis. First off on an yearly basis, I think it's easy to understand the drivers there. So perhaps, what we just said and then we should expect to be this year between 20% and 22%. So that's going to be below last year level. We are not giving any guidance for 2013 yet, but it's reasonable to assume, we always refer to this, is that as our earnings before taxes grow and all the tax initiatives we have are pretty much flattish. It's reasonable to assume that over time, this growth is marginally taxed at the nominal corporate tax rate, is around 32%, 33% for Ambev as a whole.</p>
          <p>So the trend is always of a slight increase over time. The good news is that this year is going to be below last year, but, again, we're not giving any specific guidance for 2013. We prefer to stick to the short-term at this stage, okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then Jo&#xE3;o is going to take your second part of your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gustavo, regarding soft drinks. And of course, we are positive towards the constructive dialog that we have had with the federal government. And it seems both since Board in Brazil has been created, and since Brazil has been working closely with ABIA, the both associations to which we are part of, in beer and in soft drinks.</p>
          <p>I think we've been able to try to get closer to a optimal balance between tax collection, volume growth, and the floor to help job creation and CapEx investment. The decree that was first published on May 30, has been already renewed two times. You have to remember that was first time around that it was republished positively, the soft drinks industry. The second was the beer, and we continue to be at the table with the government trying to find you know given a better balance. We are in a better balance than we were, given both reviews of the decree.</p>
          <p>We think there is room to continue this dialog and try to just prove the government that other things can be done. I don't think we're not going to see anything that's going to be retroactive, but I do see the possibility of a better environment than the one that we have right now for soft drink.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Jo&#xE3;o.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is Alex Robarts from Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, hi, everybody. Just want to go back to the price environment in Brazil Beer, I mean, clearly, the rate hike, the magnitude of the increased prices and the stickiness kind of the critical issues here going forward. And I'm still not getting a sense &#x2013; and I appreciate this is a little bit strategic for you guys. But I'm still not getting the sense to the extent that we've seen your competition kind of lag or fall immediately. And if you could kind of give us a sense of did these guys &#x2013; did your main competitors in Brazil Beer move as you expected that they would kind of faster or slower any type of color would be very helpful to understand that?</p>
          <p>And I guess just the second thing is really on Argentina. I appreciate the industry is still not where you like it to be. You talked about kind of hitting all time record beer market share last quarter with the industry declining kind of mid to single-digits. Can you tell us sequentially how is that Argentine beer industry fared versus 2Q?</p>
          <p>And the final thing is just a quick one on the Dominican Republic. You talked about $190 million, right, in EBITDA from the May 2012 to May 2013, is that kind of a number that you're still comfortable with. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Alex, thanks for the question. I think starting from the end, we are committed to, at least, beat the $190 million. I mean we're working hard towards that goal. So a lot has been going on, have many projects and most of them have been <mark type="inaudible" /> have started. Some of them have already finalized. We have a very close follow-up. The team that is running it, it's a very, very senior one. And we're actually very happy with the way things are progressing in the Dominican Republic and Centro America overall. So point number one.</p>
          <p>Point number two. I think in Argentina we have one of our strongest franchise, very good team, with a lot of experience in the beer business, but also in the macro Argentinian environment. And I feel that we are ready for whatever situation that may come, whether it's a pick-up, whether it's a slow deceleration, or even a faster deceleration, I think we're ready for it.</p>
          <p>One of the ways to show that along your question is what's happening to the market share. So even in this tough environment and with some strong pricing increase, we continue to beat our &#x2013; not just our share targets, but results of the previous year, whether in the quarter or whether in the year-to-date. So that's also very positive despite a slow growth to declining industry. So, of course, the outlook's not great, but combination of strong team, strong brands and a lot of experience facing that type of macroeconomic environment. I feel that we are ready for any of the three scenarios, but any stable picking up or decelerating.</p>
          <p>Regarding Brazil, as we said, I mean tough to speculate on what other companies are doing. But important to remember this has been announced four months ago, the increase in tax is that all the players, actually in some case, will impact our competitors given the slightly more when it does for us on average. Everyone is facing the new dollar level, which impacts of course the variable costs. But I mean the public information suggests that some of them have been taking pricing. So that's positive news. And the ones that have disclosed information to the market have been talking about the same thing. So I mean that's as far as I can go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is Felipe Cruz at BBA. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone. I have two questions. First one would be, if you could give us a breakdown. Out of the price growth here in Brazil, how much comes from higher list price distribution, packaging mix, and premium and these other improvements in average prices? And the second one, if you could give more detail on how much premium brands accounts for your current sales mix? Is that it is growing by 19% year-to-date? And how that's been evolving in the last years and how do you expect it to evolve in the next couple of years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Felipe. I mean, I think that given the first one, of course, is we don't broke them down in a lot of details, but in terms of direction, it's a bigger in part from pricing, of course. And second, but a distant second, is premium, which we've been saying that we were at around 4% about a year ago, and saying that we thought we could double in three or four years. This has been moving up very fast. We're already at around 5.9%. So that's very positive. So that's also helping. So that's I think in the second level. And the third level, but also distant to the premium is the direct distribution. So that's sort of the direction. Pricing, big time. Second distant is the premium, but growing fast in terms of our mix and then third direct distribution. What was exactly the second part of your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, you already answered the second part is this 4% a year ago of premium brands accounting for your sales mix and a 5.9% right now. And do you still expect it to go to 8% in the next two to three years, or do you expect, given that is it's growing in a faster pace than you expected to be a little bit above this 8% that you expected previously?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's too early to tell. I think rather keep the good news, I mean growing close to 20%, a lot should be done. I think as we improve also our aftermarket the more we get closer to what we think is a optimal aftermarket. I think better news regarding that will come. And if we feel we should be talking about the greater number, then doubling from 4% to 8% in three, four years. We'll update you on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Lauren Torres, HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone. I understand you're not or not ready or timely to talk about 2013 yet, but you've always talked about this goal or target for more balanced volume and pricing growth in Brazil. And I was just curious, also of any visibility that you have now with respect to how the consumer is trending, GDP growth, you mentioned the minimum wage, if you could get back to this mid single digit volume growth. And then, with that said knowing any visibility that you have now on commodities or the excise tax increase next year, pricing have to be above that, meaning that you won't achieve that more balanced volume price in 2013. And like I said, very general comments is what I'm asking about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Hi, Lauren. It's Nelson here. Let me start touching on the outlook for COGS. As you know we're going to come back to give this precise guidance for next year. We think it'll be a little bit too early to provide specific numbers around it. But, of course, as our hedging policies probably can know by all of you, having a hedge put on a rolling 12-month basis, we don't assume until next year we're going to have of course a negative impact from currency, given the real devaluation during the course of 2012. But on the other hand, I think a good part is that it was an amount. So it's going to be mitigated by lower commodity costs. So we're not ready to commit to or to give any specific guidance, but the rationally, we have &#x2013; we're going to see this sort of impact.</p>
          <p>I think regarding top-line, I think it's very useful to know that we have a rate outlined by the government. This is on the last version of the decree, increases is over time over six years, right, in which we're not going to have any big impact in any single year. It's going to be an escalation of the so-called multiplier in a way that will not going to face any major real increase in any given year. It's going to be more smooth movements rather than what we saw for us in the first version of the decree. So also, these give us also some confidence that we'll be able to manage price without having to take any bigger price increase or any big real growth price decree as part of our strategy, already mentioned by Jo&#xE3;o.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean I think Nelson covered most of it and I think customer environment getting better. Our mix from a supply standpoint is getting better. We're also working on a better route to market to deliver all this sort of new and added complexity. I mean we're already in the third or fourth year, so I think we've been getting better year-on-year, when you look at this I mean yes, GLC coming down <mark type="inaudible" /> continues to be the same. So we're learning from our own, whether lessons or mistakes or just overall positive. And if I were to summarize, I mean we have a lot of new commercial initiatives that we quickly mention here <mark type="inaudible" />, pit stop, micro events. I think all those things are also turned off, not just for the returnable presentation growth, but also to bring people more and more to the on-premise market, which is a type of situation that Brazilian consumers like.</p>
          <p>We work very hard to make their experience at the point of sale either a better one through <mark type="inaudible" /> or a much more fun with the micro events. I think this as we look towards 2013 and 2014 and all these events that is going to happen in Brazil, I think it's going to be a very good add-on. It will get very well along and hope to get that even better consumer environment than the one we're already seeing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. That's helpful. Thank you. And if I could also just ask on your CapEx spend, obviously, you didn't have to pull back on that as a result of any tax changes. So I was curious, year-to-date, how you're trending? Where the spend is going? Is it sufficiently covering your plans? And I don't know, if looking forward there's more room to increase that number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure. I mean, look, we maintain our CapEx, there's nothing to do with any concession or anything. I mean it is just we continue to need the added capacity, given the whether 300ml, No, that's helpful, thank you and If I could just ask on your CapEx spends even though 1 liter returnable <mark type="inaudible" /> is a super big hit. And we have only in three plants. So there's a lot to be done. So we still a lot of very good ideas and the level of CapEx investment that we mentioned for the year. Since we do the right one for the year and in due time we'll talk about whatever the next level for next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lauren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes our question-and-answer session. I would like to turn the conference back over to Mr. Nelson Jamel for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Maurine, and thank you everybody for attending the call. I think it was a good opportunity to discuss with you guys not only our year-to-date results and the great results we had in this quarter, but also to talk about our strong expectations for the year-end closing and also for the future. So, I'm very glad and looking forward to speaking with you guys again next year. Thank you. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The conference is now concluded. Thank you for attending today's presentation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>