<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1135238" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-02-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3059</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Graham David Staley, Chief Financial Officer and Investor Relations Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Luiz Fernando Edmond, Chief Executive Officer for Latin America</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Jo&#xE3;o Castro Neves, Chief Executive Officer for Quinsa</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Bernardo Paiva, Chief Executive Officer for North America</participant>
      <participant id="5">Robert Ford</participant>
      <participant id="6">Luiz Fernando</participant>
      <participant id="7">Andrea Teixeira</participant>
      <participant id="8">Graham David Staley</participant>
      <participant id="9">Bernardo Paiva</participant>
      <participant id="10">Lore Serra</participant>
      <participant id="11">Alexander Robarts</participant>
      <participant id="12">Alex Robarts</participant>
      <participant id="13">Celso S&#xE1;nchez</participant>
      <participant id="14">Lauren Torres</participant>
      <participant id="15">Jose Yordan</participant>
      <participant id="16">Ricardo Fernandez</participant>
      <participant id="17">Tufic Salem</participant>
      <participant id="18">Trevor Stirling</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and thank you for waiting.  We would like to welcome everyone to AmBev's Fourth Quarter 2007 Earnings Conference Call.  Today with us we have Mr. Luiz Fernando Edmond, CEO for Latin America; Mr. Bernardo Paiva, CEO for North America; Mr. Graham Staley, CFO and Investor Relations Officer; and Mr. Jo&#xE3;o Castro Neves, CEO for Quinsa.  We would like to inform you that this event is being recorded and all participants will be in a listen-only mode during the company's presentation.  After AmBev's remarks are completed, there will be a question-and-answer section.  At that time, further instructions will be given.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996.  Forward-looking statements are based on the beliefs and assumptions of AmBev's management and on information currently available to the company.  They involve risks, uncertainties and assumptions because they relate to future events and therefore depend on circumstances that may or may not occur in the future.  Investors should understand that general economic conditions, industry conditions and other operating factors could also affect the future result of AmBev and could cause results to differ materially from those expressed in such forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn the conference over to Mr. Graham Staley.  Mr. Staley, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Nelson, and good morning everyone or good afternoon to those of you in Europe.  I am pleased to be with you today to discuss our fourth quarter results.  I'll start the call by sharing a brief overview of the quarter as usual and then hand over to Luiz Fernando, Jo&#xE3;o and Bernardo who'll provide you with an overview of our results in Brazil, HILA-ex, Quinsa and Canada.  I will close by providing more specifics regarding the fourth quarter financials.</p>
          <p>Before I start I would just like to remind you that all numbers are in Brazilian GAAP and that the percentage changes used in this presentation are on an organic basis consistent with the new reporting format initiated in Q3.</p>
          <p>So let's get to the results.  During the fourth quarter, our consolidated EBITDA reached R$2.8 billion which represents a 24.3% growth compared to the fourth quarter of 2006.  On a full-year basis, we delivered almost R$8.7 billion in EBITDA, a growth of 16% over 2006 driven by beer volume growth of 4.6% and CSD and Nanc volume growth of 9%.  Our earnings per share growth excluding goodwill amortization was 11.3% for the quarter and 15.5% for the full year.</p>
          <p>The Brazilian business delivered a very strong result in Q4 with beer volume growing 7.9% and CSD and Nanc volume growing by 17.1%.  This led to an EBITDA growth of 28.1% for the quarter and 16.8% for the full year.  We're also pleased with our Quinsa operations, which saw EBITDA growth of 25.5% on the back of beer volume growth of 7.6% and CSD and Nanc volume growth of 14.6%.</p>
          <p>In Canada, despite the tough competitive environment, domestic volumes grew by 1.1% resulting in a 5.3% EBITDA growth.  HILA-ex had a loss of R$3.5 million in the fourth quarter, but the region improved profitability in the year by R$42 million.  Our combined operations delivered net income of R$1.1 billion marginally down on fourth quarter 2006 and I'll comment further on net income at the end of this presentation.  Obviously, a very strong end to the year and I'll now hand over to Luiz Fernando as we start to look a little deeper into results of each of the operation.  Over to you, Luiz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, Graham. Good morning everyone.  I will now provide you with details regarding the Brazilian and the HILA-ex operations.  Starting with beer Brazil, we are happy to announce volume growth for the quarter of 7.9%, which yielded 5.5% volume growth for the year.  We ended the year with 68.6% market share in December, which represents 9 months of consecutive share growth recovering most of the loss suffered at the beginning of the year.  Overall 2007, market share finished at 67.8%, which is 100 basis points lower than 2006.  In January 2008, share fell 0.4 percentage points following price increases which began to be implemented in December.  As in previous years, share was also impacted in January by supermarkets' general seasonality.  We are tracking the market and responding appropriately to ensure we do not suffer the same sort of share losses we experienced last year.</p>
          <p>Our beer net revenues particularly in Brazil reached R$145.8, a growth of 6.9% when compared to R$137.8 in the fourth quarter of 2006.  This increase reflects our initiatives of revenue management as well as the continued excellent performance of our premium brand, which grew more than 2.5 times as quickly as our mainstream brands.</p>
          <p>The gross margin is lower than in prior years, we continue our strategy of expanding our direct distribution network and consolidating our third-party distributors into our multi-brand network.  Positive impacts from our hedge arrangements as previously reported helped to offset pressure from labor cost inflation, higher raw materials prices and packaging mix.  COGS per hectoliter grew only 1.8% for the quarter and 2.4% for the year.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A was in line with our expectations showing a decline of 0.9% for the quarter.  Though there were some quarterly variations in the timing of marketing spend during 2007, SG&amp;A for the full year excluding depreciation and amortization grew by 7.5% reflecting volume growth, the increase in direct distribution and inflation.  This strong volume performance and the timing of SG&amp;A spend helped beer EBITDA grow by 25.5% in the quarter with EBITDA margin growing by 450 basis points which is a record 54.1%.  Full-year EBITDA margins also surpassed the 50% mark for the first time reaching 50.9%.</p>
          <p>Turning to Brazil CSD and Nanc, net revenues per hectoliter grew 4% on volumes 17% higher than last year leading to a net revenue growth of almost 22%.  It's important to mention that we experienced supply problems in one of our biggest CSD plants at the end of 2006 lowering the comparison for this year.  We also benefited from the seasonality of H2OH! which is stronger in the first and fourth quarters or the summer season and from the launch of Guarana Antarctica, our new and already successful line extension.</p>
          <p>Market share stood at 17.2% for the quarter, 40 basis points higher than last year and 20 basis points higher than Q3.  January 2008 brought further good news with market share reaching a record high of 18%.  The strong volumes combined with anticipated hedging gains and the shift of some SG&amp;A expenses from Q4 to Q3, as we discussed in Q3, yielded a very strong Q4.  EBITDA finished 55.1% higher than last year with an EBITDA margin of 40.7%.  The full-year result was an EBITDA increase of 28.8% and an EBITDA margin growth of 250 basis points to 37.1%.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, we continue to see opportunities in CSD business in terms of market share and profitability and we will continue to invest in this segment.  We now have the largest pack size in the market.  We just launched a 3.3 liters and the flexibility in terms of pricing to react quickly when needed.  We are well-positioned for the future.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to HILA-ex.  The region generated an EBITDA loss of R$3.5 million for the quarter and a 20.1 million loss for the year.  The beer business showed good volume growth of 8.9% positively impacted by the successful launch of Innovations in Dominican Republic and Central America, good growth in Peru but negatively impacted by the challenges we have in Venezuela.  Beer EBITDA grew by R$1.7 million in Q4 benefiting from gains on the cost side and savings through ZBB initiatives.  The HILA-ex CSD business delivered a small EBITDA improvement as we reposition our brands to better address some local market conditions.  We continue to build our business in the HILA-ex markets.  Beer volumes are growing.  We are facing the fixed costs in the business &#x2013; we are reducing the fixed costs in the business and are nearing EBITDA and cash flow neutrality, giving us the confidence and flexibility to pursue our long-term goals.</p>
          <p>It is always important to mention that behind the numbers we have a fantastic team.  They work hard to make that impossible dream happen.  Our people are determined, focused and know what and how to execute. They thrive on tough targets and never give up.  Even when the trends are not favorable or the market is moving against us, our people have the ability to close the gaps.  This is the AmBev way and continues to be our greatest strength.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call to Jo&#xE3;o who will talk about our Quinsa business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Luiz and good morning everyone.  Well, our region here continues to grow in the quarter confirming the positive trends observed during the year in reaching outstanding full-year results.  Consolidated volumes increased 10.2 organically in the quarter based on the impressive performance of the soft drinks business, which grew 14.6% on organic basis, and 7.6% organic growth in beers motivated by higher volumes all over the region except in Chile.  Argentina, Bolivia and Uruguay kept strong growth rates while our business in Paraguay showed an important recovery based on growing industry volumes.</p>
          <p>Net revenues per hectoliter grew organically both in beer and soft drinks.  In the beer business, growth in revenues per hectoliter was motivated by strong performance of premium brands and some price increase implemented throughout the region.  In the case of CSD, we benefited from price increase introduced in Argentina and the carry-over of increases introduced by the end of 2006.  Our premium brands performed particularly well in Argentina with outstanding performance in Stella Artois, dark beers and local premium brands.  In Bolivia with our premium brand, Uadi and Chile with increasing proportion of sales by Stella Artois and our two recently launched dark Brahma beers.</p>
          <p>Analyzing the individual beer markets, Argentina posted its all-time record in the quarter in terms of volumes even despite the divestiture of three brands due to anti-trust requirements.  The company performed particularly well in the northern and central region of the country gaining market share in the growing and competitive market.  The Bolivian business continued to post stronger rates despite an uncertain operating environment and some price increase introduced in the quarter.  We took advantage of industry volume records with our market share remaining stable.  We ended in the quarter the investment in capacity required at our Santa Cruz plant to meet the increasing demand of the past two years.</p>
          <p>Chile has been our biggest challenge where our volumes had a slight decline in the quarter despite good performance in our premium brands.  Nevertheless, we have been able to increase our EBITDA and EBITDA margin in the country through a specific revenue management actions.  Our recently launched Stella Artois brands in can and one-third liter format continues to increase share within our portfolio strengthening our premium brands.</p>
          <p>The beer market in Paraguay had a strong recovery in the quarter after experiencing a decline in the first three quarters of the year.  The company benefited from higher market volumes and launched the Labatt brand to compete with other imported beers based on focused distribution and advertising.  Our beer business in Uruguay has also performed very well reflecting volume growth with stable market share and a strong performance by our premium brand Patricia.</p>
          <p>In soft drinks, we had an excellent quarter in terms of volume with market share gains in growing markets both in Argentina and in Uruguay.  In Argentina, the Pepsi brand grew within the A segment of the business while the H2OH!! brand also strengthened its position within the flavored waters.  In Uruguay, despite the outstanding performance of the Pepsi brand, the company benefited from the comparison with 2006 when it experienced a month-long distribution strike which severely affected our volumes in 2006.</p>
          <p>Solid growth rates in the main markets where we operate together with focused revenue management and market execution represented an EBITDA organic growth of 25.5% in the quarter.  Our full-year results confirmed this growth trend having organically increased our volumes by 9.7% and our business by 22.3, making us one of the fastest-growing units of the group.</p>
          <p>I would like to end my comments by saying that I am very excited with the outstanding performance we had in 2007 and about our profits for continued growth.  We faced the challenges in 2008 as we did in 2007 due to unstable environments and some cost pressures, but I am very confident our margin will continue to grow by taking advantage of the opportunity that appear in the consolidation of best practice implemented during 2007.  I'd like to thank and congratulate the Quinsa team for the impressive results.  We are in the process of developing a strong ownership culture and the level of talent in our zone I'll always continue to aim high.</p>
          <p>I'll now invite Bernardo to take over.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jo&#xE3;o, and hello everyone.  First of all, I would like to say how pleased that I am to have the opportunity to manage the North American business.  I began my history at AmBev 17 years ago as a management trainee.  Throughout this time, I have worked in supply, finance, trade and market, and sales including as a sales VP for Brazil in the last three years.  In my first three months in North America, I have traveled across this big country here and in all the province and I have met a few people from each of our business and I am very confident that I have a great team here.  Miguel has built a very strong basis on which we can grow and I would like to thank for all of the things that he did here.  It's my firm belief that North America has a favorable prospects for the future.</p>
          <p>Talking about the fourth quarter, Labatt had a very, very good EBITDA result aligned with the track that we had in the last few years despite the tough environment that we have.  In terms of market share, we have posted a slight decline in our organic market share.  However, the growth of the Lakeport brand allows us to keep market share stable on a pro forma basis.  The major driver that we had was the solid savings achieved in the industrial costs.  Despite the high efficiency in our breweries, Labatt's team continues to drive further improvement day in and day out.</p>
          <p>Talking about the '07 numbers, the total numbers, we delivered 6.4% of EBITDA growth with our market share slightly behind last year on a pro forma basis.  For '08, I do not think I need to tell you that we have a tough challenge ahead of us.  Increased cost of inputs will put pressure on our gross margin.  Although cost management is a strength of our business, and for sure will continue to be, that will not be enough to compensate for the heat in COGS.  However, we have decided to maintain our strength and grow EBTIDA every year and we challenge ourselves to do that with no cost to our market share.  So performance in the top line is a priority and I'll address this as follows.</p>
          <p>First, talking about our brands, we have the leading brands in the core premium, domestic premium and discount segments.  We will certainly take full advantage of these trends.  Look to the Light and Import segments, you have a huge room to grow and we are very confident that our brands Bud Light and Stella Artois can even more develop to grow in those segments.  On these branding matters, I will count on the help of our new marketing VP who comes from North America with a successful record of 20 years of marketing experience, a level of reach from the in-depth side of our business.</p>
          <p>Second, talking about trade initiatives, we have room to improve the content of our trade problems and the effectiveness of these to drive volume, share and brand efforts at the point-of-sale level.  Third, sales, we have an opportunity to review our process and the organizational structure in order to improve the execution of our problems and the relationships with our customers.</p>
          <p>Finally, revenue management initiatives.  We really think that this is a market that we can make money here in a good way and we really think that we have to maintain like this across all markets.  So we will certainly look closely about any pricing issues that we can find.  However, those things that you would think about pricing will never be allowed to come at the expense of market share.</p>
          <p>Overall in tough years like '08 the message I want to convey is that we need to pick a few choices and focus our results and energy behind these choices to make them happen and deliver the results.  I am confident on the strength of our team here. We will win and in Canada growing Bebidas with no cost to our market share.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to hand things back to Graham.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot, Bernardo.  In this final section, I would like to guide you through the main line between the reported EBIT of R$2.4 billion and the net income of R$1.1 billion as showed on page 16 of our release.  Other operational income and expense showed a net expense of R$335 million in the quarter compared to an expense of R$197 million in the same period last year.  This difference is primarily explained by the higher goodwill amortization as a result of the acquisitions of Lakeport and Cintra in 2007, the change in the amortization curves for Labatt, and translation losses on foreign investment due to the appreciation of the Real against the Canadian dollar and other Latin American currencies.</p>
          <p>Our net debts for the R$7.4 for the end of the year, flat compared to situation at the end of the third quarter and 5.5% lower than 2006.  Our net financial result was an expense of R$307 million, almost flat compared to Q4 last year. The full-year expense was R$1.25 billion, mainly impacted by higher interest expenses associated with the Quinsa bonds issued in the second half of 2006.</p>
          <p>The provision for income tax and social contribution was an expense of R$500 million versus R$466 million last year.  This increase is mainly the result of lower interest on capital, which is a tax-deductible expense.</p>
          <p>Net profit per 1,000 shares in the quarter amounted to R$1.84 compared to R$1.85 in Q4 2006.  However, when we exclude goodwill amortization, earnings per share rose 11.3% in the quarter and 15.5% in the full year.  Regarding our pay-out strategy, we retain the policy of distributing all excess cash generated if we cannot identify value-enhancing alternative uses within the business.  This calendar year we returned to shareholders approximately R$2 billion in dividends including interest on owned capital and R$3.1 billion in share buybacks, a total return to shareholders of approximately R$5.1 billion.  We will continue to review the balance between dividends and share buybacks on an ongoing basis taking into account markets and industry norms, and the impact on shareholder value.</p>
          <p>In summary, AmBev is reporting strong Q4 and full-year 2007 results.  Once again our disciplined and consistent execution against our initiatives has resulted in a continuation of our track record of delivering EBITDA growth quarter-after-quarter. Looking forward commodity costs certainly pose challenges for us especially in Canada.  However, for 2008, AmBev remains confident in its ability to maintain consolidated cost of sales per hectare liter below the level of inflation.  As a result of the productivity initiatives in place throughout the company plus the favorable results from our sugar and US dollar hedges in Brazil.  In summary, we have a positive outlook for 2008 based on our robust business plans and our strong and consistent execution capabilities.</p>
          <p>I will now hand back to Nelson and open up for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  <mark type="Operator instructions" />.  Our first question is coming from Robert Ford of Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good day everybody.  Congratulations on the quarter's phenomenal performance.  Particularly in the Brazilian businesses, I was very impressed by the volume growth that you had in the quarter despite the rainy weather and I had read that Schincariol had been intending to spend as much as R$460 million.  I haven't seen any evidence of that order of magnitude of spending and I was wondering if you could comment on the competitive environment as well as what you're doing to drive volumes and then my colleague Nicolette Albrecht in London asked me if you could expand on the price increases that you're pushing through in this January please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bob, this is Luiz.  Well, first the competitive scenario and the market environment in Brazil, I think something that you have to consider that the interest is growing.  Of course, you have the weather impact, positives and negatives, but the industry, the overall industry is growing both for beer and soft drinks, even faster for soft drinks.  So we are of course taking advantage of a better Brazilian scenario, economic scenario for the country.  Second, when you compare fourth quarter with the first quarter, we were able to close the gap in terms of the market share loss.  So we started the year more than 1.5 points lower than in 2006 and we finished the year less than 1 point behind 2006. So part of that market growth that was not seen in our results during the first half of the year, now you see because you have the industry plus the share growth.</p>
          <p>Regarding market investments, I would say, I wouldn't like to comment on our competitors' investment and announcements because part of it is, I think the announcement itself is as they don't disclosure their numbers is a marketing strategy itself.  So you never know exactly if you are talking about the same things we are and you can hear that from different competitors, different numbers and you never know exactly what they are talking about.  So I would say the investments in the country they reflect the good momentum that we live in Brazil now.  Everybody is investing.  I think both ourselves and our competitors are increasing investments in the market.  In our case, we have been able to capture these additional investments or compensate these additional investments with better management of our ZBB or the known working monies we still have.  We always said that we continue to see opportunities to aggregate more our business and to reduce layers to be more effective before we are able to invest more in the market and more important than that is our market programs are working very well.  I think year-on-year we are learning how efficient they can be and our people are executing better.  So what you see is the result of several things and of course we are very pleased with this kind of results.</p>
          <p>Regarding price, just to anticipate the question, we did implement prices during December for returnable bottles.  We did that different from 2006 where we wait until January 2007 to increase prices.  This year we decide that according to our strategy it would be better to anticipate and we did that during December.  Of course part of the net revenues for the year that you see quarter-on-quarter is a result of that, not only because we anticipated prices but because premium did very well, direct distributions and the same initiatives in place for many years.  But we did implement prices in December and we are now implementing for cans for the off-trade after Carnival. So we anticipate returnables and we postpone cans compared to last year.</p>
          <p>If you look at the market, we have some good signs, some bad signs but I would say better than last year.  We see our competitors maybe a little more pressure because of the commodities and then it seems that in their strong markets, so their stronghold markets, they are following prices faster than they did last year, not in the whole country but in the good part of it, both Petr&#xF3;polis  and Schincariol all followed prices. Femsa does not increase prices since I think end of 2006.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then Luiz, what was the blended price increase on those two adjustments please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, around 5% for both channels but not across the board.  I mean we did very precisely brand by brand, region by region.  So on average I would say 5%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much and again congratulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is coming from Andrea Teixeira of JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning everyone and thanks for taking my question, and also well, congratulations obviously very strong results.  Just on to the benefit of talking about, I know you mentioned in the press release on how strong you feel about costs in 2008 also if that the hedges, but can you elaborate more if you have additional gains given that we have even weaker Real, I am sorry stronger Real now. And also the second question would be on Canada, if you feel pricing, I mean have we seen the worst in terms of pricing?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Andrea, this is Graham Staley.  Yes, cost of goods sold certainly are a challenge for us in 2008.  They are for all brewers, as you know pressure on barley, on corn, on aluminum prices, and now recently in recent weeks sugar, but we remained committed to our hedging strategy.  The hedging strategy is certainly helping us at the moment and precisely for the fact that it buys us time to reengineer our business and think about where we want to move in the future, that hedging strategy will stay in place.  As you look across the region, we have some different experiences.  Here in Brazil, we have strong benefits on sugar in 2008 and the dollar hedge and if you rightly say there will be a little bit of extra benefit from those dollar hedges as well.  As you move further north into Canada, we're going to be under pressure on the grain, there is no doubt about that and that's posing real challenges for Bernardo and his team.  In Quinsa, some...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Graham, just would like to add here in Canada and basically the last three months, basically we react with some price activities here mainly in French Canada and our net revenue went down when you compare '07 the last quarter to '06, but basically we're trying to do now is to really in the most important regions to put price up again, that's in line with inflation that we face in '08 and I think that the other brands they will follow us, the other companies, it does.  Again they have the same impact in the COGS that what we have.  It's hard to say that they will follow us up or yes or no but again we try really to keep price in line with inflation and to do that in the first quarter of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, in general and just because we have the, you're talking about a pro forma basis or you're talking about just effects, because you haven't affected also their position so if you look at 2008 full versus 2008 '07 talking pro forma you see like a better, an improvement in pricing, is that what I read from your comments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Andrea, through <mark type="inaudible" /> or us, from you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, it is <mark type="inaudible" />, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrea, this is Graham again.  I think we've got some communication issues here.  Andrea, could you repeat your question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes sure, Graham.  Just basically I was boarding on these comments regarding the pricing; I got confused because of the, obviously the effect of the merger with the new brands in Canada.  If you were saying that it is taking prices 3% throughout Canada, if we should read that prices will be, at least in Canadian dollar terms, slightly better like 3% better than 2007 but that is pro forma or just as, that's probably pro forma I would say, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, Andrea, this quarter that the price would be along the lines of inflation and then try to move in the first quarter.  The most important reason we try to go there, but basically it would be a line roughly we did in the last years, the inflation that could be closer to 2% but not exactly in the first quarter, as the  average of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  And just on Graham's comments, I'm sorry to jumping.  But on your comment, Graham, you were saying on the cost environment if we can net-net the effects that you were mentioning you'd feel even more optimistic about the cost side than you were before in December or how you feel about this, what you had guided that you would see additional margin gains in 2008.  Should we expect additional margin gains in 2008, given 2007 wasn't so strong?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we're looking at sort of weighted inflation for the whole of AmBev of around 5%.  Since three months ago, we feel the same level of confidence but obviously with three months of further experience and work we've got more granularity around that confidence.  So in other words we've proven the numbers even more than we did, we've proven them to ourselves three months ago.  So we're not going to go any further than to say we expect to beat that 5% inflation rate.  Knowing AmBev you know we're going to keep pushing and pushing even when we get below it, obviously to maximize our margins.  But we feel no more confident, no less confident, we just have more howls so to speak in terms of the plans of action.  So overall no real change in that overall guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perfect.  Thank you very much, Graham. And again congratulations to all of you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is coming from Lore Serra of Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and congratulations as well on the results.  I wanted to ask a question about the hedging, but actually looking further into 2009 because as you talked about, you've locked in the hedges for '08.  Given the spike that we've seen in grain cost, that's obviously more likely to hit in 2009 than 2008, given the way that you hedged.  When you say you're still committed fully to the hedge policy, should we assume you're saying that you continue to hedge into '09, even though those hedges on the commodity side, both in terms of sugar and in terms of grains, will obviously be at much more adverse rates or is that not what we should be reading into that comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Lore.  As I said our hedging policy stays in place.  Normally it's around the norm of a 12-month hedge, so we have flexibility in our own policy to go short on that or long on it, only by couple of months, we don't have that much flexibility.  What that allows us to do is it allows us to take more information on board about what's happening with commodities, especially grain and currently with sugar. Sugar is a good example, where we've had some hypes recently where we don't think they're going to be long-term.  So we allow ourselves the opportunity to take a view on those commodities, but with always with the intention that when we get to the end of the year we'd like to be 12 months covered.  So no change there and yes we are as you would expect starting to hedge 2009.  At this point in time, we see no reason to change it for the very simple reason, it provides us certainty in our business and it tells us what we have to do.  Being the company and the size of the company we are, we have the ability to put these hedges in place and by doing so we're then able to plan ourselves accordingly and if we have to take other initiatives then we take those initiatives.  We're not speculative, I think it's really important to point out that we're not speculative, which is why we have the 12-month policy in place, but we do give the luxury of having a view on the marketplace for a particular product and currently through a very small window around that 12-month policy.  And at the same...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's helpful, and could I just ask on Brazil Beer, it was obviously a great finish to the year with almost 8% volume growth organically and 5.5 for the year.  As you think about putting those numbers, I know you guys are very good at planning and modeling your volume growth. How do you think about 2008 and I guess implicitly I'm asking for some of your views and guidance on what you think '08 will be, but is there any way we should think about put to that, should 2008 be a year like 2007 in terms of volumes, can you see the continuation of the strong volume trends you saw in the fourth quarter into '08?  I'd be happy to hear any of your sort of thoughts on volume growth into '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you said very well Lore.  We're not giving any guidance.  What we can say is of course if the conditions, the market conditions remained the same and if we're able to implement all the initiatives we have to implement defending on our share, we've been growing the share, continue to grow premium brands' prices and I think we had a discipline for the last several years.  I think we should expect, if of course economy, Brazilian economy and global economy, remains similar as it was in 2007, I think we should expect similar figures.  There's no guarantee out there but of course I don't see many changes in the total environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is coming from Alex Robarts of Santander.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi everybody, thanks.  I wanted to go to Brazil Beer and specifically at the cash SG&amp;A and what I thought was remarkable was the extent that you really were able to pull back on that cash SG&amp;A, getting that slight decrease for the quarter and having put most of that expense into the third quarter.  I guess the question becomes I mean is this something that we could perhaps expect for the first quarter, in other words as we look at what you plan to spend in terms of Brazil Beer in the first quarter, are we going to have kind of a fair comp year-on-year I forget exactly first quarter '07 but are we going to see this decline again in that cash SG&amp;A and kind of like the annual, for the year the question becomes I look back in '06 and it looked like the beer cash SG&amp;A was slightly below your volume growth full year '06, this year as you state cash SG&amp;A was in line with your Brazilian Beer volume growth.  In '08, do you think that cash SG&amp;A might be in also again in line with your volume growth, above or below?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello Alex.  It's Graham Staley.  I think that as we pointed out on at least two of the calls last year, we did have opposing history last year in terms of when we decided to spend the dollars.  When you look at the year as whole there has been no real change to the pattern that SG&amp;A cash, cash SG&amp;A is moving really in line with our percentage of volume. We've always said about 30% of the volume increase would translate into increased SG&amp;A plus obviously an increase in direct distribution, then of course inflation on top of that.  And when we do the math you'll see that works pretty well for both the beer business and CSD when you take the full year into consideration. I know you'd love to know what the quarterly breakdown was going to be but obviously so would our competitors as well.</p>
          <p>So we've got our funds in place. I think you should look forward in 2008 to the same sort of algorithm applying.  In another words, 30% of volume growth plus inflation plus direct distribution increases as we take more third parties into our network and then from time to time there may be the occasional extra item but as the year as a whole you shouldn't expect any change in that pattern. But I think it would be unwise at this stage to talk too much about the quarterly phasing because the year has only just started.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But for the year I guess, Graham, can we think about that cash SG&amp;A like in '07 growing in line with volume or is that not a fair assumption?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think the algorithm I was suggesting you use is take about 30 to 40% of the volume growth and apply that to SG&amp;A growth, add the inflation to it, add 1 to 2 percentage points of growth depending on the extent of direct distribution which is always a little bit of an unknown because obviously we're not always sure how we're going to extend the network until it obviously happens.  So that mechanism, that algorithm still applies to 2008 as it did in 2007.  So you shouldn't be looking for any dramatic reductions in SG&amp;A at the end of the day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough, good.  That's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Quarter-to-quarter, yes, you'll get some variations depending on when we decide to hit the market.  We'll obviously talk about those as those quarters come around, as we did in 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hopefully, that helps.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah and I guess I just wanted to go secondly to the market share performance in the soft drinks in Brazil. I mean clearly kind of record market share in 4Q in Brazil you noted in January, 18%, another all-time high. And I guess you also talk about seeing further opportunities of getting share.  I mean where are you sourcing this share from?  I mean would it be fair to say that this is coming from the expense of the other A brand of soft drink brand, could it be also some of the B brands and kind of if you could comment a little bit on the government efforts and this idea of trying to reduce the informality and, that would be helpful?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, I would say that there are two factors that are driving volume, the soft drinks volume.  One is of course the market.  You know that soft drinks business is more correlated to real income, even more correlated to real income than beer in Brazil.  That means the market is growing fast and together with the real income you have several innovations impacting the market.  So more than beer the innovations that are being implemented in the market, they're bringing lots of volume.  In our case, H2OH! is the winner. So of course we launched it at the end of 2006 and as we said we faced some supply restrictions at of the end of 2006 there. When the summer came in 2007, we still had those some restrictions.  And then came the winter and we realized that the seasonality for H2OH! is higher than for the soft drinks.  So of course what you saw at the end of the year was H2OH! increasing share in our portfolio and bringing some additional market share.  In terms of the source, it's of course H2OH! is taking share from other soft drinks but also from other beverages.</p>
          <p>As we already said is flavored water is like light CSD, it's very difficult to define exactly what it stands for in terms of the consumer perspective and of course we are taking share from everyone including outside the CSD industry.  Specifically, for January, the additional share came from Coke because they increased prices during the end of the year.  We always follow later according to our specific strategy.  They are the leaders.  So we track, we monitor and then we decide what to do.  We are now making the decisions and implementing some of these opportunities to close some of the gaps that opened during the beginning of the year.  But on that which for 2007, I would say the share came from B brands, not because of lasting formality.  I wouldn't say that because the flow meters are not implemented yet. They've been delayed for almost a year, but because of our execution and because of real income means that people are going into let's say more less value brands than more brands.  They are going after the better brands.  So both for us and Coke got some share from the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is coming from Celso S&#xE1;nchez of Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning and good afternoon.  I guess all that real income growth topic, the mix, the beer business in Brazil certainly has been something you've talked about for a while and as you said maybe the premium or super premium side has slowed a little bit relative to where it was before, but it certainly seems quite robust.  Can you update us, number one on where that mix is as a percentage of your volumes?  And number two, do you think there's room for that to accelerate?  Obviously the base is bigger now than it used to be but with the economic outlook that we see and your abilities to execute even better now than they were.  Is that something you see as a major focus for you given the real income share coming over the next several quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you repeat the final of your question because we lost your voice.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, basically just asking about the shift, potential further shift in mix towards the premium brands, towards the Bohemia and Original and other line extensions for those and how that might be affected and helped by the real income growth that you're talking about as a further driver of revenue per hectoliter that would help you the weighted average above inflation over the next several quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we've been implementing so many initiatives to drive premium volume, it's always difficult to say exactly and of course the base is much lower than the mainstream.  That it is difficult to be precise in what is the real income growth impacting the premium, and what is the initiatives that we are putting in place.  The fact is most of our premium brands are growing very fast, specifically the ones that we're putting more focus are really doing very well for Bohemia, Original, the draft beer and we see that the market is very positive to increase the share of the premium in our portfolio.  So we'll continue to pursue this opportunity.  Today we are at 5% of the total volume is premium, on average for 2007.</p>
          <p>We believe we should continue to expand of course because the opportunity is out there.  When you compare with other industries in Brazil several industries have 15 to 20% of its volume in the premium segment.  So why would beer not have the same kind of size, so other initiatives that we've put in place, we are now importing brands from several countries.  We started with Uruguay, now we have Uruguay in Argentina.  We have some European brands that are being rolled out into some specific markets starting from Sao Paolo and the premium brands are doing &#x2013; the super-premium brands and specialties if you compare to other more developed markets are also a big opportunity.  So not only the premium and the premium plus but also the specialties and the super-premium segment.  So I think going forward if our initiatives continue to work, you should see the same kind of the results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess that 5% number still sounds to me like a very familiar one for the last few years, so given the growth rates that we've heard you reportedly speak to as multiples of the mainstream, I guess I wonder is there a reason it hasn't accelerated already and have you been kind of formulating your strategy more carefully now you're ready to really launch it or you really are pretty comfortable with it growing at the rate that it's growing, which is obviously above mainstream but still not accelerating the way we thought it would be? I would have thought it would be approaching sort of 8 to 9% by now given what you've talked about over the last few years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, if you go back I think two or three years, the premium would represent 5 something %, less than 5.5%.  We finished the year with an average of 7% right, so it's increasing.  But the difference may be compared to other market is the mainstream segment is very big in Brazil because we are the segment itself.  I mean if you take our three main brands they represent more than 90% of the mainstream segment because our competitors all of them sell at a discount 20 to 30% discount of our brand.  So the way we define the premium is not necessarily fair, right? Because you take scope is 20%, keeping 20 to 22% higher than any other competitive brand.  So the premium that we define here are the brands that are selling at 15 to 20% above Skol, which is already a very high price.  So you never consider the Skol brand is kind of a core plus, right core plus to premium which is difficult because you really compare it to 68% share that comes from the mainstream segment.  Right, so when you take this 2.7 times I think we grew the premium compared to the mainstream that means more than 15%, almost 16% growth year-on-year, so it's pretty fast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to be clear, I think I just heard you said 7% of the mix, rather than the 5 I thought I heard you say originally...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>7% of the mix on average for 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, very helpful.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is coming from Lauren Torres of HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  My question is a follow-up on your North American business. Last year we saw some good cost savings and you benefited from I guess it was a favorable brand mix and also brewery efficiencies.  Just as we think about this year and higher grain costs, I was wondering if you could talk about where you are in the process as far as further upsides from brand mix and also brewer efficiencies, what should we expect in that regard as far as a offset to some of your higher costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I think that for basically this year one of our strengths is the cost side of the business.  We continue to work on that.  When you get to the top line as I said in my speech, I think that we have the three leading brands for imported segments, I'm talking about Bud, Alexander Keith's and Lakeport and for sure have Bud Light and Stella to help us to grow this top line in '08.  And the other important thing is the mix of the regions that we'll try to manage better in '08 than we did '07; that's what I can say to you for now.  But I really think that managing, investing our money and energy behind those few choices that I mentioned and manage the mix of the regions, we can achieve our EBITDA growth at the same time the market share growth for this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But are there further efficiencies, it seems as far as improving efficiencies in your breweries and what-not, there was some good upside there last year. How much more of that is to come?  It seems like it did benefit you last year and will it continue to benefit you this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we increased.  It will not be enough to compensate all of the hits of the imports that we have in malts and so on but we increased a lot because again it's one of our strengths and all the initiatives that we have in terms to increase the efficiency in breweries and our freight and all of our ZBB challenge, we'll continue to do that.  So just what I've said, one it will not be enough to compensate the heat that we will have in the cost.  That's why the top line will be more than ever a big focus for us in '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just lastly, I don't know if you could comment about what you've seen so far this year but also in Canada with respect to pricing. Any change there or is it just as much discounting this year as we've seen towards the end of last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said before the last quarter was tough in terms of price because we lost market share in French Canada a lot during last year and then we react the last quarter and especially in the last two months of the year. And we gained share, not everything that we lost but we gained share.  In the first quarter, I think that we increased price in some regions and I think that the other companies they probably follow us but again we've tried to manage our net revenue and check if it's possible to increase price here and there with no cost for our market share. We follow up this very, very closely every day in order to okay that track if you have any room to improve a little bit more price because we need that and know the COGS that I said before but with no cost of our market share. But we did some price increase yes in last month and the beginning of this month in some regions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is coming from Jose Yordan of UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning everyone.  My question is a follow up to I guess to Laurie's question before about '08 volumes and I guess your answer was that there was no real reason why you couldn't show similar numbers but I would mention one at least which is the fact that GDP growth forecast by economists are all calling for some sort of reduction in GDP perhaps with interest rate hikes &#x2013; a much bigger chance this year of that.  And so it seems to me like there is going to be certainly a tougher headwind in terms of achieving the kind of volume growth, and of course you raised prices in December, which leads me to believe that there was some sort of inventory loading ahead of that that might have helped your December volumes anyway.  So that is your tougher comp as well for next year.  I mean with all this in mind I guess one would have to either forecast a lower volume growth for '08 or a much higher marketing spend, then how should we &#x2013; how will the company approach that tradeoff in '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Luiz. Are you specially Brazil or are you talking overall?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm talking about Brazil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So I'll start to answer then I'll ask Graham to jump in if he thinks it's necessary.  But basically you're right in terms of the GDP, which is likely, the projections are it's likely below last year but in the other hand net income continues to grow.  So you have several effects because you have the number of companies making IPOs in Brazil are making the employment to grow and there's far more employment to grow.  Government just announced another real minimal wage increase around 10% compared to an inflation of 4 to 5%.  So real income continues to grow ahead of GDP, right?  So when you look at that and when you compare in our models the net effect is very stimulant.</p>
          <p>Of course you never know because you still have some regulations in Brazil, government still influencing in some prices, for example in oil prices and gasoline and things like that.  You never know exactly what will happen in one or two months, but if you look at the government behavior, if you look at what happened with the CPMF, which was checking bank taxes where the government lost it; it's a R$40 billion reduction in taxes for the government and then they come in and announce for January R$40 billion above last year without the CPMF.  So the economy itself seems to be performing very well and somehow the currency appreciation is offsetting part of the grains and oil threats or increases. And when you add that to our commodities and hedging strategy is allowing us to increase prices still in line with inflation.  That means that the real price for beer is not growing ahead of inflation.  That means the purchasing power in the case of beer is maintained.  So I think I would say it's neutral.  The forecast would be very similar to what we saw in 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome, Jose.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is coming from Ricardo Fernandez of Banco Itau.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah hi, good afternoon and good day.  Couple of questions, first is getting back to the direct distribution; obviously this has been a trend that you've implemented for quite some time.  I was just curious to know is how much is left to actually acquire that is not already yours and then how long can that be a benefit in terms of margins for you going forward?  And then the second thing was focusing back on this demand equation; maybe if you can just correct me if I'm wrong but I think that the minimum wage going up 8.5, 9%, again real wage growth increasing that you have a considerable amount of people who weren't normally beer drinkers moving towards beer, especially in the Northeast.  Have you seen a, I don't know if it's a shift but at least have you seen regional differences in beer consumption in the last year, in the last quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Ricardo.  Let me get the end of your question first.  You're right but it's very difficult to analyze that in the short term but you are right in the opposite way, because we were expecting volumes to grow faster in the North and Northeast region in the second half of the year ahead of the South and Southeast but exactly the opposite happened.  So to be honest I think net-net you have some Northeast regions inside the Southeast region so in terms of consumer power, consumer behavior.  But of course you have the weather impact on that.  So you have to analyze that in the longer term to be sure what's really happening, so net-net you're right but in the opposite way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So if I can just jump in, so maybe the Northeast consumption story as I call it is still in the works, I mean it hasn't really materialized yet but one would think that it should?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, if you take the long-term, if you take three or four years what usually happens in our models is that you start with a consumption increase in the Middle East, Middle West and Northeast region and then all of a sudden the industry that is basically based in Sao Paolo, in Rio, in Minas, they start to react.  So first thing is the purchasing power increases in the North and then the industry forward sells the inventory they have, enough that they have to reinvest to expand capacity and to hire people.</p>
          <p>So the technical, the specialized people are still in these regions and of course industry takes more time to react than necessarily the demand in these regions.  And it's easily compensated because of course the total volume in the South and Southeast is much higher than North and Northeast.  So it's a cycle.  You never know exactly where you are in terms of the cycle. It of course depends on the country, the long-term country performance.  So what we experienced in the second half of 2007 was basically the South and Southeast region reacting to this demand and increasing the number of employees, formal employees, so it's a cycle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the start of the question distribution, direct distribution?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sorry, in direct distribution &#x2013; when we started that I think seven or eight years ago we said that we'll probably reach the 50% of our volume in direct distribution.  We already did that.  I think this year we finished at 52% of our volumes in direct distributions.  But we also said I think one year ago that we believe that could reach around 60% of our volumes.  That's because the way we go is that we learn, we develop the systems, the infrastructure and of course depending on the volume performance, the dilution of our fixed cost is very good and that allows us to expand in those specific regions where it makes sense.  So the equation continues to be positive as the volume is growing and as we are learning and we continue to learn and be more efficient.  So I think at this time I wouldn't change that but I really believe that we still have for the coming years opportunities to increase direct distribution and on average in a slower pace that we did at the beginning but in line with 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And obviously as your volumes grow it's sort of a moving target and then new volume concentrations pop up where it didn't make sense before and it makes sense going forward, is that also the case?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Once we establish one direct distribution center then of course we do that in one specific area and then if other opportunities around that specific place, they come up, we make a decision. But of course the more volume we have, the more we dilute the fixed cost and not necessarily the equation works in exactly the same way for us as for our distributors.  So the tradeoff is not something stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is coming from Tufic Salem of Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, just wanted to check with you about organic CapEx over the next couple of years, if you can give us an update on that. If there is any for 2008-2009?  And also if you can specify a bit more about your capacity utilizations, specifically in Brazil and how much capacity you expect over the next two years to come onboard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take the CapEx question and I'll hand over to Luiz to talk about capacity expansion, etc.  If you look at the cash flow, you'll see that our CapEx as you describe it, organic CapEx, was something like R$1.6 billion in the full year 2007.  I think you can expect that trend to continue.  We need to continue to invest in our business as the business grows.  At the same time obviously we want to try to run at full physical capacity as best as we can, so don't look for any dramatic step-ups or decreases in CapEx, look for a continuation of the sort of trends you've seen in the past.  And on expansion specifically in Brazil, I'll hand over to Luiz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The capacity varies a lot.  You can never take Brazil on average.  The regions are not 100% connected.  They are somehow connected, but of course the logistic cost will increase a lot if you try to ship products more than 500 or 600 kilometers.  We do when we need for specific periods of time or for short periods of time, but of course as the volume is growing we are reviewing our footprint.</p>
          <p>As I've said in my answer to Ricardo we have more volume growth in the Southeast than we expected and we have less in the North. That means we will have to reevaluate our priorities and we'll probably have to announce a new plant or some line expansion, so some new packaging line in the Southeast region.  But that is I mean in terms of our total CapEx, I wouldn't say that would impact dramatically the level of CapEx we have today.  I would consider maybe in terms of the number of equipments we have to put in place are a little higher, but you have to consider the currencies is much better today.  So in reais, I would say the CapEx would be in line with inflation.</p>
          <p>We do have capacity for the year; even if we don't put any line in place we do have capacity for 2008.  Though we would love to have these new expansions in place to avoid some logistic costs or to save some logistic costs.  So moving forward you should see some announcements with regards to capacity expansion, but without any kind of detract in terms of supply in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is coming from Trevor Stirling of Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, I've got three questions for you.  The first one coming back to the timing of the price increases.  Can you give us just a bit more detail on when exactly in December those price increases on the returnable bottles took place?  I'm just trying to get a sense for the extent to which that influenced both revenue per hectoliter and the volume growth towards the tail end of last year?  Second question refers to cost of goods sold, and I appreciate that you can't give guidance on the detail of the impact of the hedges, but in the InBev conference call I think Felipe [Dutra, InBev CFO] mentioned that 60% of COGS was dollar related in Beer Brazil and I wonder if you were able to confirm that and if so what would be the equivalent number on CSDs?  And the final question is concerning Canada, I noted that in the exports in Canada the organic revenue per hectoliter dropped 13%.  Is that a currency-related thing with exports being billed in U.S. dollars?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Trevor, this is Luiz.  Let me get to your first question.  First, we will not give you a precise moment for the price increase because for different reasons they happen in different times and I would like to discover that but to help you I would say they were implemented in the second half of December.  So each brand in a different moment to give time for the price to consumer management with the trade for each of the brands and to manage the inventories and the logistics restrictions. They are always difficult to manage all the volumes at the second half of December.  So I would consider taking 10 days of December on average for the return on this if you want but this is only an average.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Trevor, the question on COGS, I'm not quite sure the context in which Felipe mentioned the 60% number. But in terms of total Brazil I don't have the split here in front of me for soft drinks and beer but in terms of total Brazil the dollar exposure of total cost of goods sold that we show in our P&amp;L is somewhere between 35 and 40%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>35 to 40%.  Thanks very much, Graham.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the last one on the US exports net revenues yes, the answer is yes, it's due to the dollar, the weaker dollar, American dollar when compared to the Canadian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's great. Thank you very much indeed, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our final question is coming from Celso S&#xE1;nchez of Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi sorry, something I've actually been a little curious about, it sounds like it's less of an issue now in the press but should we hear about potential concerns about electricity shortage or crisis again.  Can you just remind us kind of where you are?  I know few years ago you invested in some self-generation capacity and so forth.  Can you remind us where you stand now if there were to be a crisis, how much does the self-generating capacity you have or just what's your situation if that were to happen, what position are you particularly relative to competitors if you have a sense of that?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Celso two things, first, given the strong rain that we experienced specifically in the South and the Southeast region in January and the beginning of the Feb the government said the risk of any shortage is at least postponed for 2009-2010, for the summer of 2010.  The risk has been postponed for the country itself.  In our case we still have all the infrastructure that we put in place for the last shortage we faced.  I think it was 2001, so we have all the co-generation implemented in our plants. And we are not using it and we can use at similar prices, even lower prices that we are facing in the spot market, of course not on average, but if we had to substitute the spot market for our self-generation, we would be able to do that. You never know exactly region by region but on average I would say it's not a risk in terms of production.  There's always a risk in terms of coolers, the economy itself, but in terms of capacity it's not a risk and it's at least postponed two years from now, and as far as we see several initiatives from the government to close the gap, we have to wait and see if the investments will really be ready.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just to be clear, all the plants, all the breweries have the capacity to run independently with co-gen and also even your glass bottle plant?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not necessarily because you have to consider the total energy that we buy, not a one plant specifically.  So we have a surplus in terms of energy capacity and we have to transfer this capacity and make some agreements with the companies that manage the energy in the country.  So this is not a plant by plant it is more region by region but even though you can transfer energy from one site to the other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  There appear to be no further questions.  At this time I'd like to turn the floor back to management for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>No closing remarks from myself other than to wish you well and thank you for taking part in the conference call this morning.  We look forward to talking to you again in a couple of months when we have the Q1 2008 results.  Take care, everyone, bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  This does conclude today's AmBev's Fourth Quarter 2007 Earnings Conference Call.  You may disconnect your lines at this time and have a wonderful day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>