<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1369244" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-03-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3059</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Nelson Jos&#xE9; Jamel, Chief Financial Officer and Investor Relations Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jo&#xE3;o Mauricio Giffoni de Castro Neves, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Robert Ford</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Lore Serra</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Jose Yordan</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Lauren Torres</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Alan Alanis</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Gustavo Oliveira</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Luis Miranda</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, and thank you for waiting. We would like to welcome everyone to AmBev's Fourth Quarter 2010 Results Conference Call. Today with us we have Mr. Jo&#xE3;o Neves, CEO for AmBev and Mr. Nelson Jamel, CFO and Investor Relations Officer. We would like to inform you that this event is being recorded and all participants will be in listen-only mode during the company's presentation. After AmBev's remarks are completed, there will be a question-and-answer section. At that time, further instructions will be given. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Forward-looking statements are based on the beliefs and assumptions of AmBev's management and on information currently available to the company. They involve risks, uncertainties and assumptions because they relate to future events and therefore depend on circumstances that may or may not occur in the future. Investors should understand that general economic conditions, industry conditions and other operating factors could also affect the future results of AmBev and could cause results to differ materially from those expressed in such forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn the conference over to Mr. Nelson Jamel, CFO and Investor Relations Officer. Mr. Jamel, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Maureen, and good afternoon, everyone. I'm pleased to be with you today to discuss our 2010 fourth-quarter results. Before I start, I would just like to remind you that as usual the percentage of change discussed during this call are both organic and normalized in nature. Normalized figures refer to performance measures before special items and special items are either income or expenses, which do not occur regularly as part of the normal activities of the company.</p>
          <p>As the normalized figures are non-GAAP measures, we disclose our consolidated profit, EPS, EBIT and EBITDA on a fully reported basis in our earnings release.</p>
          <p>I'll start the call by sharing a brief overview of the quarter and then Jo&#xE3;o will provide you an overview of our results in Brazil, HILA-Ex, Latin America South and Canada. I'll close by providing more specifics regarding the fourth quarter and full-year financials.</p>
          <p>Moving to the results, during the fourth quarter, our consolidated EBITDA was close to R$3.82 billion, which represents a 19.5% organic increase when compared to the fourth quarter of 2009 while our margins expanded 310 basis points to 51.3%.</p>
          <p>Our Brazil EBITDA increased by 18.5% in the quarter, supported by a 3.6% volume growth and by a 9.3% revenue per hectoliter growth, with EBITDA margin increasing by 220 basis points to 53.6%, driven mainly by price increases in the period, partially offset by higher packaging and sugar costs, and SG&amp;A growth, primarily due to higher logistic costs.</p>
          <p>In HILA-Ex, we delivered a positive EBITDA of R$12 billion in the quarter, already excluding Venezuela results as a consequence of a transaction completion with Cervecer&#xED;a Regional, and registered an organic growth of R$20.2 million versus the same period, thanks to a better performance across the region.</p>
          <p>Our Latin America South operation delivered 21.7% EBITDA growth during the quarter, with a 25.7% EBITDA growth in the beer business with volumes up 5%, while soft drinks volumes were down 1.3% despite market share gains, and EBITDA was down 0.5% due to higher input costs, mainly sugar, and a higher SG&amp;A.</p>
          <p>In Canada, volumes decreased by 5.3% in the quarter due to both industry decline and market share loss year-over-year, which is pretty much stable for three consecutive quarters at this stage, but is still below Q4 2009, while our EBITDA increased by 15.8% with margins increasing by 830 basis points due to an effective cost management.</p>
          <p>Normalized profit reached R$2.6 billion in the quarter, which was 47.8% higher than last year and normalized earnings per share increased by 46.8% in the quarter. I'll comment further on profit at the end of this call.</p>
          <p>I will now hand it over to Jo&#xE3;o as he starts to look a little deeper into the results of each of our operations. Jo&#xE3;o?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Nelson, and good afternoon, everyone. Starting with industry trends in our main operations, we saw in Canada the same softness of previous quarter, while in Argentina the industry recovery, started in Q3, has grown a bit further.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, the strong beer industry growth from previous quarter has decelerated mainly due to a tougher comparison against the fourth quarter of 2009, and the price increases implemented in the markets. As a consequence, our beer volume growth was 3.4% in the quarter, also impacted by a 20 bps share loss year-on-year as a result of our price increase for the summer, which widened the price gap to competitors.</p>
          <p>Our market share in Q4 2010 for Beer Brazil was 69.8%, which took the full-year average market share to 70.1%, which is the all-time high market share for one full year since AmBev was created and 140 basis points above 2009 average. As a result, our volume for the year grew 10.7%. Our beer net revenues per hectoliter in Brazil increased by 10.5% this quarter as a result of price increases in line with inflation and implemented earlier in the quarter versus 2009. On top of that, we also increased our direct distribution participation and were able to deliver a strong top line growth supported by our innovations and brand building initiatives.</p>
          <p>For example, both our liquid and package innovations continue to deliver a solid performance. Skol 360&#xB0;, a new liquid, and the 250 ml one-way bottle are examples of recent launches that added to our innovation portfolio, which also includes our one-liter bottle as well as Antarctica Sub Zero among others and made it even more relevant for our top line growth. The brand health indicators increased as much as our market share. All mainstream brands gained preference, and we also achieved our all-time high score for the total portfolio.</p>
          <p>Now, talking about our COGS, Brazil Beer COGS per hectoliter was up by 6.8% in the quarter as we were negatively affected by higher packaging costs including tax on imported cans as was previously stated, which shall impact our first quarter 2011 results, but not the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>Beer SG&amp;A, excluding depreciation and amortization, grew by 7.7% in the period as a result of volume growth, general inflation and higher logistics costs which, however, affected us at the lower extent than during the first nine months of 2010, as we have successfully executed our challenging capacity increase plans which should help us in our results in 2011 regarding logistics. In addition, although not ideal yet, we now have a better industrial footprint in the North and Northeast regions of the country.</p>
          <p>Overall, normalized Beer EBITDA for Brazil finished the quarter with a 18% growth versus the same period last year and EBITDA margin expanded by 150 basis points. For 2011, innovation will continue to be top of the list to deliver sustainable and profitable top line growth. We also plan to increase our focus in the premium segment while maintaining or enhancing our execution for the mainstream.</p>
          <p>Moving to soft drinks and non-alcoholic, non-carbonated segments, our volumes in Brazil delivered a 4% growth in the quarter as a result of industry conditions while we kept our share almost flat, standing at 17.5% as an average for the quarter. Coming from very tough previous quarters, we were able to deliver double-digit EBITDA growth as we had gross margin expansion despite the negative cost environment for raw materials and also improved our SG&amp;A expense.</p>
          <p>Our EBITDA posted in the quarter a 20.7% growth with an EBITDA margin expansion of 570 basis points.</p>
          <p>Net revenues per hectoliter in the segment grew 3.8% in the quarter as we continued to be impacted by price increases below inflation. COGS per hectoliter increased organically by 2% as a result of our sugar hedges, PET resin, packaging mix, partially offset by a better currency hedges and product mix.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A, excluding depreciation and amortization, decreased by 20.8% in the period, mainly as a result of lower bonus accrued and marketing investments phasing. For 2011, we continue to see opportunities in our CSD business despite the commodity pricing environment and the challenging competitive landscape. We will focus even more on innovation, such as our recently-launched energetic drink fusion, which was a result of a comprehensive study to deliver a winning proposition for this new segment we are now entering into.</p>
          <p>Turning to HILA-Ex, volumes increased by 0.5% in the period as a result of a flat industry for the region while in Dominican Republic we reached our all-time high market share. HILA-Ex EBITDA was positive R$12 million, mainly as a result of exclusion of our Venezuela operations after the deal with Regional and also better performance across the region in particular and easier comparison with fourth quarter 2009 on marketing investments.</p>
          <p>Moving on to our operations in Latin American South, we achieved a 21.7% EBITDA growth. We are enjoying industry growth in most of our beer operations, including Argentina, where the market has started to recover. We are also gaining market share as a result of strong support to our mainstream brands and innovation. In Argentina, Quilmes continue to improve its brand health indicators and launched a new branded campaign.</p>
          <p>In Paraguay we launched <mark type="inaudible" />, a new one-liter bottle for Brahma in the Brahma wide mouth.</p>
          <p>In Bolivia we continue complimenting our Pacena brand's well-known attributes related to tradition and heritage with a younger and more modern image.</p>
          <p>Premium continues to be a source of volume growth and profitability for LAS as Stella Artois and the local premium kept growing in the region over performing the direct competitors and further developing the category.</p>
          <p>We complement the support to our brand through effective revenue management initiatives. We focus on market execution with actions aimed at maximizing our sales prices in line with inflation and optimizing our trade spend.</p>
          <p>In terms of costs and expenses, we are experiencing higher costs of labor and inflation. We are also suffering important increasing soft drinks raw material, mainly juices, sugar, and PET performance. We are introducing initiatives to achieve savings and introduce industrial efficiencies that will partially offset these higher costs. This quarter our soft drink operations still show an EBITDA contraction, but we are already seeing important improvements compared to the preceding quarters.</p>
          <p>Now moving to Canada. Labatt continued its third quarter 2010 momentum delivering an EBITDA increase of 15.8% over fourth quarter 2009 as lower volumes were again compensated for by a significantly lower cost base. Volumes were down 5.3% versus the fourth quarter of 2009, which was a similar decline that we reported in the previous two quarters. However, export volumes represented a large proportion of the decline offsetting an improvement in the domestic share trend.</p>
          <p>Although we still lost 80 basis points of share versus fourth quarter 2009, there are two key points to make. The first is that Labatt has delivered a stable share level over the last three quarters established a foundation for the share price profitability equation onwards. The second, that our big brands of Budweiser, Bud Light and Stella remained on a growth trajectory in 2010 notching overall gains in both brand health and share.</p>
          <p>Talking about revenue per hectoliter, Labatt delivered a flat performance versus a year ago in a somewhat more stable pricing environment while COGS per hectoliter declined by 12.5% in the fourth quarter as we continue to cycle significantly lower commodity hedges and efficiency improvements across our supply network. We also continue to see the posted benefit of closing the Hamilton brewery in April of this year.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A, excluding depreciation, declined by 20.7% in the quarter due to lower volumes, marketing expense phasing, and a lower variable compensation accrual versus last year. Overall we experienced several top line headwinds in 2010. This included the climbing Canadian beer industry volumes and a heightened pricing environment, which impacted our ability to grow net sales per hectoliter while putting significant pressure on our market share position.</p>
          <p>In the back half of the year, however, we were able to set a foundation for 2011 by stabilizing our market share position while maintaining our cost discipline to ensure we deliver full year EBITDA growth versus 2009. We continue to be very confident in the strength of our Canadian team and have built a 2011 plan focused on delivering top line growth.</p>
          <p>Going back to the overall AmBev business, I wanted to wrap up by saying we are pleased with our full-year consolidated results as we deliver a 6.7% total volume growth, a 7.8% beer volume increase, a double-digit top line growth, and even a slight margin expansion of 10 basis points despite significant all-time hits in our P&amp;L such as the impact of imported can and the higher risk cost we faced in Brazil, which should not occur in the same extent as we look into 2011.</p>
          <p>Additionally, I want to highlight that in Brazil we kept the strong top line growth with an all-time high market share. And last, we also delivered solid EBITDA growth and strengthened even further our brands as well to continue to lead the way in the premium segment. In Canada, despite the difficult top line environment, we're able to react through an effective cross management to finish the year with positive EBITDA growth. And finally, in HILA-Ex, we posted a positive EBITDA in the fourth quarter, following the deal we announced in Venezuela and remain on track to deliver a long-term strategy in the region. This does not mean we do not have our challenges. It's much the other way, competition is tough in all of our markets, and 2011 started with the soft industry, particularly in Brazil impacted by the heavy rains, which will translate in volume growth deceleration in Q1.</p>
          <p>From our end, we will continue to invest behind our brands and exploring the opportunities through innovation and execution in the marketplace while pursuing further productivity gains to invest behind our cross-connect-win strategy and deliver sustainable long-term growth.</p>
          <p>Finally, I'd like to thank the great people of our company, who are our major assets -who is our major asset for our 2010 results, and say that I am confident with all of them, we will be able to continue delivering strong results in 2011.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to go back to Nelson.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jo&#xE3;o. In this final section, I would like to guide you to the many items between the normalized EBIT of R$3.3 billion and the profit of R$2.65 billion as disclosed on page 3 of our release. Our net finance results were R$75.4 billion negative, which is R$89.4 million better than last year. This is explained by lowering net interest expense as a result of a lower debt and higher cash and equivalents as well as better results on derivatives relating to our ongoing hedging policy. In the full year, our next finance results improved by R$663 million.</p>
          <p>Our effective tax rate in the period was 17.9% compared to the 29.1% last year. The main reason for this result was an increase in the income tax incentives and a one-time reversal in Canada, which helped our full-year effective tax rate to reach 21.5%.</p>
          <p>Our net debt decreased to negative R$207 million at the end of the year compared to R$3.1 billion in the end of December 2009, while we paid R$4 billion in dividends and interest on capital during Q4 2010. Our total payout for 2010 reached a total of R$5 billion which is about 40% higher than 2009 levels.</p>
          <p>Cash generated from operations in the year totaled R$11.6 billion, which is 9.9% higher than 2009 as a result of better operational results and our focus on improving working capital while we remain committed to our CapEx plan, particularly in Brazil, and as we see further investment opportunities in the country we are ready to invest up to R$2.5 billion CapEx in Brazil during 2011.</p>
          <p>I will now hand back to the operator and open up for questions. Maureen, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from Bob Ford, Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Thank you. Good day, everybody, and guys, congratulations on the quarter. I think it was extraordinary and very surprising. But given the stock price reaction today, I suspect that there's some concern with what you said is wrong in terms of kind of a soft start to early 2011. And I know there's bad weather, but can you comment a little bit in terms of how you see consumers accepting the price increase right now and whether or not there's any sign that competitors are following at this point? One would think that they would, given all the input inflation that they are seeing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bob. Well, thanks for the comments. I think the outlook for 2011, to the extent that I can comment, I think there are some pros and some cons, right? I mean, to begin with, I mean, a clear pro for 2011 is the low unemployment figure that you have right now, the lowest we ever had in Brazil.</p>
          <p>If we're to look at a con, and I'm talking macro first before talking about rains or anything like that, we're seeing this year minimum wage at R$545, which is a flat &#x2013; I mean, it just is in line with the inflation, there's no real income increase, which is &#x2013; you can see as a con, right, or a neutral point. True at the same time that that means a 7.5% real increase for 2012. So I think there are some measures being taken by the government to try to cool down the economy.</p>
          <p>I mean, some people are saying that 7.5% was too big of a GDP to be sustainable and the government is trying to cool down to maybe the 4% or the 4.5% off the road and you have to take some measures to do that.</p>
          <p>So I think there is a combination of some positives and some negatives in the short term with a positive medium-term outlook, which is the 7.5% going forward. So that's more the macro piece. When we look at our situation, I think the most important point where to start, and I think we start talking about that in the last quarter, is we are at one of our very best positions talking about the commercial situation in Beer Brazil. We reached our all-time-high market share for the year. We also reached many months during the year our all-time market share. But not just that, also our preference also reached many months the all-time-high preference also for the year.</p>
          <p>We had an important price increase, as we mentioned in the speech, and the fact that we build those options, the options mean that we can sit and wait for a bit longer when we compare to our competitors. They have to follow somewhat. There is a pattern in the past few years that it will take a few months before they completely follow. Carnival may be a point where, maybe after Carnival, we'll have a better idea or an exact idea, to be honest.</p>
          <p>The pattern that existed in the past, that continue to exist, is a follow, a higher follow sooner, for returnables and a softer or a slower follow for one-ways. I think going forward, after Carnival, people are going to start feeling the pressure that you just mentioned about commodities, about inflation. So we could see people coming up closer rather than later, but again, yet to be seen.</p>
          <p>I think the good thing is that we are sitting at a healthy and a good market share position after a price increase. We will continue, as you know, to balance share and price. So the good thing about that is that when you face a price increase and you started at 70x, you can wait for a longer period of time, and therefore defend profitability for a longer period of time. So that's where we see the situation today.</p>
          <p>Competitors have followed somewhat; not to the full extent. I think another month will be clear how far they will go and how far we want to go, waiting or reacting if we feel appropriate at a certain point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Jo&#xE3;o. I've got to believe that you didn't have that in place in the entire trade for the entire quarter. So I was curious if you could give us a number when you add up mix, vertical integration, maybe some of the packaging strategies that you have in place. And then if you could also address some of the price -- or the tax adjustments that are about to take place with respect to the top line taxes, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If we're to &#x2013; let me start by the second and then we will clarify the first part, but I'll answer also. But I mean to the second part, as you know, the company pays about R$10 billion, R$11 billion in overall taxes, which is two-third state taxes and one-third federal taxes. Okay?</p>
          <p>This state tax continues to move in line with price movements. I mean, that's the trend for the past X years, forever has been like that. And the federal tax, well, it's a discussion between the industry and the government, has usually been like that in the past. This discussion with the government has actually just started, so we don't really have a view. I mean, we are sitting with the government &#x2013; the industry is sitting with the government as we speak to find out where this will end. So there's not a lot more we can say.</p>
          <p>I think one thing we can say is it's a different moment, right? I mean, when we sat down with the government last year, it was a moment where growth and jobs and everything were more important. They're always important, but they were more important. So the government sought the proposal that was, sort of, put together with the whole industry and the government about not moving taxes &#x2013; federal tax at all. So that's what happened last year, so we had no movement at all.</p>
          <p>So it's normal to expect something, right, in the sense that there is no room for a zero tax increase. But again, no decision on any tax update as of today, so there's nothing we can say. As soon as this conversation or this situation ends, we will update this.</p>
          <p>And having the first part of your question, our prices have pretty much moved in line with inflation. What you see above that is a combination of some price movements that we're taking earlier in the quarter so that makes the comparison easier <mark type="inaudible" /> in line with the inflation for the last quarter of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Jo&#xE3;o, just to clarify the one tax issue. Right now the debate is only the reference price for the IPI, right? They're not discussing any change in methodology or an actual increase in the effective rate. It's just the reference price on which that rate is applied. Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's over &#x2013; I mean, legislation was changed two years ago, right, in the beginning of 2009. So I don't think legislation will change. But the discussion is the overall tax increase, right? That's as much as I can say. The overall tax increase, we don't see changes in the law if that was your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I guess so. It's just the new law gives the federal government a lot of leeway in terms of timing and magnitude, right? And I think that --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think at the end &#x2013; I mean, this is a &#x2013; this conversation or this negotiation has to taken into account, the overall view or desire of both sides. We are very confident, let's say, in the medium term, where we see most of the actions taken so far by the government as trying to find the right way to, let's say, cool down the economy. But watching a medium-term growth, I mean, I think as anyone sees the 7.5% income growth, real income growth for next year, I think they're trying to build a bridge, a sustainable bridge, for this to happen.</p>
          <p>From our end, as you saw also in Nelson's closing remarks, he mentioned about our appetite to invest R$2.5 billion. This will be, if that happens, will be the biggest CapEx investment, bigger than last year, this year we're talking about close to R$2 billion, so this would go up to R$2.5 billion, which would partially help 2011, especially in the north, northeast, but also prepare 2012. So this &#x2013; if we get up to this, will depend also on many things, right? But the appetite is there to invest in the medium term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Lore Serra, Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just one quick thing, and then I wanted to ask on the operations, and I don't want to turn this into an accounting discussion, but I guess you changed the rate of amortization of your PP&amp;E, that changed your depreciation in the quarter pretty dramatically. Can you just quickly outline what other accounting changes were made in the quarter, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Hi, Lore. This is Nelson. In fact, we &#x2013; I mean, when we issued our release, we tried to be more precise and tried to isolate some things that we, in the end, treated as a scope change. So therefore, the organic growth translates more of the underlying real performance, right?</p>
          <p>So there were major or mainly three elements that we treated as a scope change, again, to provide a better, let's say, understanding of the underlying performance of the company. The first one has to do with the impact of a review of the useful life of certain items of our PP&amp;E in Brazil, and there was a change in the expected uses of some of these assets. So, of course, the effect of this change generated an extra depreciation expense, which we treated as a scope change in both our COGS and our SG&amp;A.</p>
          <p>This will, of course, increase depreciation, but at the same time we'll have a tax benefit in terms of our bottom line with a net impact as a result of this update on the useful life of some PP&amp;E items in Brazil, as I said.</p>
          <p>The second one impacted our line or other operating income is about the net present value adjustment of our long-term fiscal incentives, which have implied interest rates that are way below the market interest rates. So they're subsidized by the government as part of the fiscal incentives granted.</p>
          <p>And the third one which affect the SG&amp;A line, the cash SG&amp;A, is the impact of actuarial net gains on special funds expense due to assumption changes and that was about R$71 million. So these three lines are the main changes we try to highlight in order to provide a better understanding of the organic performance, and I agree there are many for a signal core, but we thought it was important to give this type of visibility and exposure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And then just back to the operations, when you talked about the first core outlook looking weak, you said particularly in Brazil. And I'm wondering if that's a generalized comment and whether you can give us a sense of why this being weak implied a negative number in the first quarter?</p>
          <p>And then just in terms of a little bit more color on the pricing, I think it was said in the ABI call that you moved one-ways more. So I guess that means you took more pricing I guess in the supermarket channel which would imply you have a lot of flexibility to move that around if competitors don't follow. Is that the right way to think about the pricing environment for the next, I don't know, month or two until you understand what the medium term dynamic is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was the first part of the question regarding the other markets on the first quarter? What was the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I understood what you said, Jo&#xE3;o, I think you said the first quarter outlook is not so strong particularly in Brazil, and I'm wondering whether or not that implies that the volume softness is outside of Brazil as well as within Brazil?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. No, no. I mean, we mentioned just Brazil. We saw the heavy rain, let's put it this way, issues much more concentrating in Brazil. The impact of the price increase probably bigger in Brazil than in the rest and also the comps for Brazil are tougher than the rest. So we saw softness in other markets in the last couple of years. So I actually think that there are easier comps for all of our other operations. So the comment was much more specific about Brazil. I would say the rest has actually more going for them than the other way around, okay?</p>
          <p>Regarding the comments on the ABI call, which was a correct comment, of course, is that &#x2013; let me try to clarify, because your question is a very important one is, it's not that we increase one ways more. It's just that on average, lately in the past like three or four years, the increase in one ways, it started always in the same level, okay? But then it didn't stick as much as the price in returnables, okay?</p>
          <p>So this time, given our share situation and all the mix that we have now more favorable than we had in the past, allow us to put a price that maybe was in line or maybe a bit higher, but the point is the price is there, right? And you are absolutely right when you said we do have more flexibility. So it means price in returnables were in line or better than in the past, okay? Better in line with the past, and it is sticking, and the price follows, it's coming let's say on a faster pace. In one ways, the price was in line or a bit above, but or mostly in line. But we are maintaining that, okay? We are maintaining that. We will maintain for a while. We have been maintaining already for a while because we have that option.</p>
          <p>So in the past we were at maybe a little bit more pressure on the share than we are now. So we had to give part of that back sooner. We are not giving that back, not as off now. And then if we needed to do that later it's the easier part to recover. It's a much more elastic segment and the brands are really healthy, so we can easily get back the share if you want.</p>
          <p>I think two points also to clarify, we're seeing really volume growth deceleration. We're not talking about a decline, okay? It's a growth deceleration, just to clarify. And that's it. I mean, I think that's a very important question. That's what's happening. Again, it's a good thing in the sense of having the options to wait and see where this will end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And if I could get just one last one, typically at the end of the year you've given some outlook on costs for the coming year, and I know that you talked about having favorable hedges, et cetera, but is there any general commentary you can give us on the outlook for costs? I mean, we saw an almost 7% increase in the beer COGS per hectoliter in the fourth quarter when you're also getting the benefit of some hedges. I know that you still have the impact of the imported cans in the quarter, but anything on an outlook view you could give us on cost, particularly in the Brazilian Beer business, would be helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Lore. This is Nelson here. Well, the type of outlook we are giving, sort of the direction we are giving is that, as you know, we have this long-term goal of growing COGS per hectoliter at or below inflation, right? And I think in 2011, we would be able to stick to that. I mean, we are saying we have on the currency side an upside for next year, so because in 2010, let's say the implied effective rate in our COGS was R$1.92 per dollar, and given our hedging policy, we already have a view on 2011 to expect an implied rate, FX hedge rate of 1.7 per Q. So that's going to be an important upside.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, there isn't any increase on the commodity side, which is as you see; the major commodities backed our COGS. They have grown in the last 12 months, an important amount, and <mark type="inaudible" /> there are 40%. On average, of course, this is going to be further than 2011. Less of an impact because we have this hedging stretch ,so we decided to hedge way before, and will have a lower impact. But in the end, all the, the net effect of everything, we believe our COGS per hectoliter could be at inflation in 2011 or slightly below.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Jose Yordan from Deutsche Bank Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jo&#xE3;o and Nelson. My question relates to &#x2013; there's a lot of comments on bonus accruals in the press release, and given that this was a record year, I was surprised to see that. I thought that basically only happened on Wall Street when you have record years and down bonuses. So any color you can give us on that? And then I just wanted to follow up on Lore's question about the other operating income and your reassessment on the present value of fiscal incentives. I just wanted to double check that that is a cash increase that you have going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Jose. It's Nelson here. Well, starting with your first question about bonus accrual, the fact is in 2010 the same area; we are pleased with the result. I mean, we think they were very good results. Our bonus accruals also consisted that. So we had also an important bonus accrual. The only reason we highlighted this point is that although they are high &#x2013; one of the highest bonus accruals we ever had, they are lowered then in 2009. And the reason for that is that the bonus accrual has a direct correlation with the expectation and the target achievements we had in any given year and just to put in context, while at the beginning of 2009, just, I mean, after the crisis that affected the whole world by the end of 2008, there were a lot of uncertainties, and you have, let's say, maybe lower expectations about 2009. Before we set targets that were somehow aligned with the expectations. And in the end we managed to grow our business much more than expected.</p>
          <p>So there was really an over achievement, especially during the second half of the year. When you started the year we didn't expect for interest to grow, just to given an example, Beer volumes, 12% year-over-year, Q3 and Q4 2009. So there was really an outstanding, I would say, result in 2009. I especially when you compare <mark type="inaudible" />. So for 2010, in the then &#x2013; right, and even though everything that happened in 2009, and much high expectations for the year, we had somehow a more stretched target which was again aligned with the expectation for that new moment. And therefore we had less of an over achievement. So that's the reason why bonus accrual is lower than in 2009, but again, it's still an important amount and one of the highest bonus accruals we ever had in the company. So that's the reason. I hope it clarifies your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Very clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first &#x2013; the second point about the scoop we took with regard to the other operating line, there we are talking about just the net present value of this long-term fiscal incentive. So in practice what we do have, there are different source of government grants. And some of them, they are based on the following methodology or model, let's say. We have the tax to be paid, there are taxes to be paid, VAT primarily. Instead of paying it on a recurring basis, you get incentive to pay it, let's say, 10 years later and this amount will be corrected if you will, sometimes <mark type="inaudible" /> inflation, or it's just &#x2013; I mean, very attractive interest rates. So they are really below market rates. So this more a mark-to-market adjustment of this very, in a way, cheap financing, if you will, gives vis-&#xE0;-vis the market rates and <mark type="inaudible" /> a non-cash impact. And in terms of cash what effect was going to happen, we are going to pay these fiscal or this tax <mark type="inaudible" /> pay according to the agreement you had in each different state over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Lauren Torres, HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. My question is regarding investment spend. I guess thinking about it by territory and by brand in Brazil. It's interesting this morning InBev did talk about obviously the potential in the North and Northeast. Just curious about how you're thinking about directing the spend this year to that market and to that area and if you could keep up with the potential growth that I think we're going to see.</p>
          <p>And then also, too, they talked about investing behind mainstream but also focusing more on the high end. Just curious to get your thoughts about how you're breaking up your spend there and developing maybe more of those high-end brands this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Lauren, this is Jo&#xE3;o. Yes, very good point. We actually have in Brazil now, Brazil was a country that in the last couple of years as you know and not in many countries that happen, has actually all the different social classes grew, okay? So we've been talking here a lot about class C and D. And how much it has grown and how much we had, 30 million people coming from D to C in the past four or five years, how we're going to have another 30 million coming from D to C again in the next four or five years, but to be honest, also A and B are also becoming wealthier. Okay?</p>
          <p>So we actually have a positive double-whammmer from &#x2013; for us going forward which is, we can grow, take advantage and having strategies to take advantage of the growth of class C and that's one sort of strategy, and also to benefit from this growth also of A and B. So how do I connect this with your question? I think first in the last couple of years we worked much more on Beer mainstream, so it's called Brahma and Antarctica. We gave a lot of focus on that by launching different liquids and different packages.</p>
          <p>We saw the results of a lot of growth in that marketplace and a lot of this was much more geared to C and D. I think the challenge going forward, the positive challenge going forward is that how do we maintain, that part of the franchise is strong and taking advantage of C and D in the Northeast and North is a great example. It's an area where we have a lower average market share. We see the preference of our brands growing.</p>
          <p>We are building &#x2013; we built new capacity and are building newer capacity. Already &#x2013; we already announced a brand new plant, our newest plant and biggest new plant in Pernambuco, a state in the Northeast of Brazil. So we are putting our money where our mouth is. We're saying we want to grow there. We need a capacity already built. We have a better footprint but not ideal. We'll get better as the time comes by so that the investment will not just be a marketing investment.</p>
          <p>We also need the capacity and the flexibility to launch in the North and Northeast the same thing we launched in the South and Southeast so that we can continue to see the growth we already saw but maybe even further. I'm not talking about 2011. This time I'm talking about the outlook.</p>
          <p>But I think now the challenge is, okay, maintaining that but also winning stronger in other categories such as the premium. We have already a good premium portfolio with Bohemia and Original, which are the bulk of our premium volume, but we have Stella that we already launched five years ago on its best momentum growing as it never did, and we will launch Bud at some point this year. So this portfolio of two local jewels and then two international brands with two different positions, we're going to have a very strong premium portfolio, and I think we can take full advantage of this as time comes by.</p>
          <p>So the challenge will be the execution of this, how can we maintain the good execution on beer mainstream and take advantage of the premium portfolio combining, of course combining is the added complexity. So we are fine tuning the, I think, the good execution we have at the point of sale by different channels to be able to really implement this strategy at its full extent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And may I ask, Heineken has made a point to say that coming into Brazil they're going to focus on the Heineken brand and trading up the Brazilian consumer. Are you seeing more evidence of that or does that threaten your position at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we're definitely seeing more of that. I think they've been doing a good consistent job. I think Heineken is also at one of its best positions in the past. Heineken has been in Brazil maybe for 30 years. Okay? It was a good brand, maybe 20, 25 years from now, back then, and then it declined, maybe lost 70% of its volume, and now that they brought the company here, they're already doing a better job and now they're more focused on that.</p>
          <p>I think there are two things that's going to happen. One is it's tough to buy a company that maybe 95% of the company is in one brand and maybe 5% is with the other brand that they're saying they're going to invest behind. So I think they will do a good job in Heineken. I think that will actually more be a good for everyone. The premium segment should &#x2013; usually grows when so many people do different things at the same time, and we have Stella as a great brand to compete against Heineken in that particular part of the premium segment.</p>
          <p>So I think this will potentially be one of those situations that is a win-win for both. But potentially, if they do that, there may be an opportunity for us. What is going to happen with the other 95% of the volume currently, which is the Kaiser brand? Would that open another opportunity for us? Maybe. So we'll be watching both segments, how to take advantage potentially of lack of focus on Kaiser and at the same time, fight in the marketplace in the premium segment, which I think will be a good fight but I actually think it's going to be a good one for both of us just because the A and B segment is growing quite a bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Alan Alanis from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for taking my question. I have a couple of questions, one regarding CapEx. This level of up to R$2.5 billion, clearly it's a higher percentage of sales than you have had historically significantly. We thought that last year was &#x2013; 2010 was going to be an exception. Could you clarify Jo&#xE3;o or Nelson, how much of this CapEx is going to manufacturing and how much is going to other and what would that other be, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Well, I would say that R$2.5 billion against the R$2 billion is an important increase. Of course, the biggest increase was going from R$1 billion to R$2 billion, but also we had two years in a row of 10%. Of course, that was also, I'd say, unexpected if we were to sit down two years ago. And we see the outlook for the &#x2013; when you do a CapEx like that, you do in part for the year but you also do in part for the next four years or no, for the x years, if you want.</p>
          <p>So, and we see a lot of good things happening in Brazil next three to four years. So we feel comfortable about the increasing once more the deadline. And we have been saying that we have the appetite to go up to, right, if we think we need to fine tune this, we will, but we see the potential to go. We don't fully open how much goes to A or to B.</p>
          <p>What I can tell you is that from &#x2013; if we compare the percentage of 2011 against the percentage of 2010, we are increasing even further the part that relates to industrial capacity, okay? So out of the R$2.5 billion, the percentage that goes through manufacturing directly is an even bigger one than the one piece that was in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. That's certainly useful. But after 2011, what would be the right way of thinking regarding CapEx? I mean, if you could express it as a percentage of sales or in another metric, what kind of reference would you give, Jo&#xE3;o?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. It's hard to give a reference. I think what we said, maybe a couple of years ago, a couple of quarters if you want, we said, look. I mean, we continue to be paranoid and fanatic about maintaining the cost base as lean as possible. But we also said that if we found good ideas, good innovation, good pipeline, we would invest behind them. If it takes, if it took money for us to attack in the North and Northeast by increasing the logistic costs, if it took us R$X millions to import 4 million hectoliters of cans, we would do all of that.</p>
          <p>So to make a long story short, I think the CapEx is a little bit the same way. If we continue to see Brazil, let's say booming, if we think that the 7.5% GDP will have a big impact in 2012, and then that maybe GDP will grow again significantly in 2011 and '12, and that will need us to put more money behind CapEx, we will do so. We want to play on the attack and having the means to play aggressively.</p>
          <p>I mean, without having capacity and especially without having the flexibility to play this different game with innovation, we will not be really putting our money where our mouth is. So I would say that in the short term, the R$2.5 billion makes sense after two years of important growth. And Brazil looking good for the next three or four. So tough to give you one, it could depend a lot on the continuation of this outlook. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. No, I understand. Now in that same line of thinking, I mean, you gave out R$5 billion of dividends in 2010. You're going to generate &#x2013; I mean, you're going to have operating leverage because you're growing now more strongly with your prices and with your volumes, it would be expected that your free cash flow will again increase in 2011. How do you envision your capital structure to evolve in the short and medium term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let me finish maybe the first question, because it goes together with the second, and then I'll let Nelson take on the capital structure. But this, let's say, positive problem on continue to generate more cash also gives us much more flexibility to invest behind good projects. So we're just running the number as we were speaking. Let's say we went from a percentage of between 7% and 8% to 10%, which may be of sales, right, for CapEx. But it's okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe a lot or not. But &#x2013; so generating so much free cash flow and having so many good projects internally gave us the confidence to move from 8% to 10%. If we feel, because the macro is not there, or because the pipeline is diminishing for whatever reason, we can always bring that back easily. Okay? But again, the very good free cash flow generation gave us also a lot of room to operate the caps on a more aggressive manner. So just to finish the first part of the question, I'll give it on to Nelson.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Hi, Alan. I think in terms of 2011 outlook, right, I mean we're not giving any specific guidance or, certainly not talking about the number for 2011 in terms of total payout. But the fact is we have been inconsistently increasing our payouts. Right? I mean, we did it in 2010, 40% above 2009. We just announced another R$1.1 billion. And as we're talking about the capital structure, like you mentioned, and we still finished the year in a slightly net cash position which as we said before is not our goal at all.</p>
          <p>So talking about the future, I think it's fair to assume that the sort of behavior we had in the last couple of years, is &#x2013; will be the natural, let's say, scenario, the base case scenario for 2011. So I think then we want to be consistent also with that for 2011 in terms of payout <mark type="inaudible" /> use of cash.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So in other words, you basically would feel comfortable remaining in a zero net debt position for the foreseeable future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We don't see any major upside today in increasing our leverage at this stage. I mean &#x2013; and we do see more of an opportunity of holding a little bit more of a cash for a while like we have been doing for <mark type="inaudible" />. And again, the payout, of the total payout, the trend would be to grow, like you said, given the outlook for 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Okay. Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Gustavo Oliveira, UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, everyone. I have two questions. The first one is we're beginning to see some logistics improvements and &#x2013; that's flowing to your EBITDA margin. Can you also <mark type="inaudible" /> whether you have your logistics optimized or if we're going to continue to see improvements in logistics going forward throughout 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I mean, well, as we said in the opening statement, in the speech, I mean, we invested in additional capacity during 2010. So the added capacity will already help us in 2010 &#x2013; in 2011. Again not ideal, there's more things to do to give &#x2013; to get logistics to a even better place. So we'll see &#x2013; well, there is some benefits already in 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But &#x2013; I mean, on what we saw on the third-quarter results, it's not even close to be maximized you would say so. It's kind of a <mark type="inaudible" /> early stages of logistics benefits or --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, very early. I would say that we saw very little in the &#x2013; from a logistics standpoint, we saw very little in the fourth quarter. I think what we can expect is a better one from 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the second question is related to your innovations and your premiumization strategy. First on your innovation pipeline, do you think you have a very strong innovation pipeline without considering your premiumization strategy for 2011? And therefore your CapEx is as high as R$2.5 billion or how do you see that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I see that the $2.5 billion, if you go up to $2.5 billion, the $2.5 billion will help us a lot in giving us the flexibility to play aggressively on the innovation pipeline that we have for the next couple of years, excluding, as you said, the premium, but the CapEx also do help us also for the premium, the CapEx, not just for the beer mainstream. The CapEx is for the combination of the beer mainstream, and we need that because we have a lot of good ideas in-house. We also need for the premium because we want to go to other areas, but we also have the investments for CSD.</p>
          <p>I mean, we have talked a little bit about CSD. We have just launched a few new things. Also for CSD, we want to bet a bit more on the innovation also for CSD and go into new segments as we just said also on the speech.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the CSD business, are you considering to increase your returnable presentation volumes? Is that the guidelines we're going to follow or --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we're definitely analyzing it. I mean, it's a possibility. I would not rule that out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But that's not necessarily why your CSD CapEx is growing, right? There are other things --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean &#x2013; yeah, we don't open up by segment, right, but the increase will help us in &#x2013; let's say if we say that we have in Brazil, let's say, three segments, just broking beer mainstream, premium and CSD, if I were to break like this, the CapEx that we are talking about will help us in all the three segments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. My last question is your premiumization strategy. Our understanding is that Grupo Modelo is also negotiating, I imagine, with you and with other possible partners in Brazil the imports of their beers into Brazil, and I mentioned that the negotiation, the outcome of the negotiation should be known by the market relatively soon. Do you think that that would delay or would that have any indications to the launch of the Budweiser? Would you postpone until you see a decision on the negotiations with Modelo? How are you thinking about it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I cannot comment on any negotiations. What I can say is that we feel that, the right timing, we postponed the launch from last year to this year basically because we were out of capacity, and so it didn't make sense to launch that during 2010. So we took advantage to just better fine tune the proposition we have at hand, and we'll launch that during the second semester when we feel that everything in terms of CapEx will be where we want it to be. We don't see anything, let's say, delaying that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Luis Miranda, Santander. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, guys. Good morning and congratulations. Just on Canada, you were mentioning &#x2013; last quarter you were mentioning about the rebalancing of the promotional grid and now you comment on the stable market shares you have been able to sustain. I don't know if you could give us some color on the outlook for 2011 in terms of the term for margins.</p>
          <p>And a follow-up on the expansion programs, you mentioned that the R$2.5 billion would go a little bit higher on the industrial capacity. Could we expect, similar to last year, maybe a 10% to 15% increase in capacity and also targeted &#x2013; highly skewed to the North and Northeast? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, starting just to stay in the same theme, already in 2010 the average of the industrial piece that went &#x2013; the average of the CapEx that went into industrial, the average that went to the North and Northeast was higher than the participation on the volume that those two regions have. And definitely that will continue even more in 2011 just because the most important investment is the new plant in Pernambuco, so just by that it will take an important piece. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well regarding Canada, it's Nelson here, indeed we saw, definitely in Q4, say the most positive point was the cost management side or the cost side where we saw modern expansion, but even in the top line we had for the third quarter in a row more of a stable market share, as we said, still below previous year, below Q4 2009, <mark type="inaudible" /> market share, and net revenue per hectoliter was flat, which is not great, one could say, but at least it's better than what we had before, so I think we finally got to a balance which was since the beginning our objective between share and profitability, but the major challenge remains on developing top line.</p>
          <p>I mean, we are confident we have the right plans in place to grow the top line, based on field execution and brand building, but the market is very competitive, right. I mean, and this top line growth also depends on the overall pricing environment, so it's always difficult to predict, but we are confident, as I said, to have the right plans to do it this time, starting from a more stable, let's say, foundation in terms of share and price, and with our financials I'd say protected by the good cost management , let's say, evaluation we got there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome, Luis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This does conclude our question-and-answer session. I would like to turn the conference back over to Mr. Nelson Jamel for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you very much, Maureen. Thank you everybody for your attendance today, and we are very happy with 2010 results, and also excited for 2011, so hope to talk to you guys soon. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The conference has now concluded. Thank you for attending today's presentation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>