<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1240506" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>36</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Arvind Sood, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Kevin Sharer, Chairman, Chief Executive Officer and President</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Robert Bradway, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">George Morrow, Executive Vice President, Global Commercial Operations</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Roger M. Perlmutter, Executive Vice President, Research and Development</participant>
      <participant id="6">Geoffrey Meacham</participant>
      <participant id="7">Geoffrey Porges</participant>
      <participant id="8">Bret Holley</participant>
      <participant id="9">Christopher Raymond</participant>
      <participant id="10">Steven Harr</participant>
      <participant id="11">Yaron Werber</participant>
      <participant id="12">May-Kin Ho</participant>
      <participant id="13">Eric Schmidt</participant>
      <participant id="14">Jim Birchenough</participant>
      <participant id="15">Michael Aberman</participant>
      <participant id="16">Mark Schoenebaum</participant>
      <participant id="17">Joel Sendek</participant>
      <participant id="18">Eun Yang</participant>
      <participant id="19">Aaron Reames</participant>
      <participant id="20">Maged Shenouda</participant>
      <participant id="21">Michael King</participant>
      <participant id="22">Joshua Schimmer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>My name is Dennis, and I will be your conference facilitator today for Amgen's Second Quarter 2009 Financial Results Conference Call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. There will be a question-and-answer session at the conclusion of the last speaker's prepared remarks.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to introduce Arvind Sood, Vice President of Investor Relations. Mr. Sood, you may now begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dennis. Good afternoon, everybody. I would like to welcome you to our second quarter conference call. When we communicated our Q1 results, you may recall that several themes had affected our Q1 performance adversely and yes, we felt that we would see a sequential recovery going into the second quarter based on segment and share growth, planned price increases, and normalization of inventory levels. Most of these expectations materialized in the second quarter and we'll discuss these trends in detail.</p>
          <p>Today, we've also announced an important partnership with GlaxoSmithKline related to the commercialization of denosumab outside the United States. So let's get started as we have a lot of ground to cover.</p>
          <p>Our Chairman and CEO will begin the call today with a strategic review of our business and offer additional insights on our partnership with GSK. Our Chief Financial Officer, Bob Bradway, will then review our quarterly results together with outlining reasons for raising our full-year guidance. George Morrow, who's our head of Global Commercial Operations, will discuss our performance in the U.S. and international markets and provide a commercial context for our partnership with GSK as well as how this partnership will allow us to achieve greater value for denosumab compared to what we would have achieved on our own in markets outside the U.S. Our head of R&amp;D, Roger Perlmutter, will then provide a regulatory and pipeline update. He will provide some additional color on a Phase III study comparing denosumab to Zometa in delaying the time to skeletal-related events in breast cancer patients. You might recall that we had recently reported top line data from this study.</p>
          <p>We'll use slides for our presentation today. These slides have been posted on our website and a link was sent to you separately by e-mail.</p>
          <p>So before I turn the call over to Kevin, I would like to remind you that our comments today will be governed by our Safe Harbor statement. In a nutshell, it means that through the course of our presentation today, we'll make certain forward-looking statements and of course actual results can vary materially.</p>
          <p>As in the past, we'll use non-GAAP financial measures to help you understand our underlying business performance. These non-GAAP figures have been reconciled with GAAP figures in the press release that we sent earlier.</p>
          <p>So with that, I would like to turn the call over to Kevin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Arvind. Good afternoon everyone and thank you for joining us today.</p>
          <p>At the beginning of the year we shared two broad objectives: focus on execution in the core business and deliver on the pipeline and in particular the promise of denosumab. I'm pleased to report that we've made solid progress on these objectives in the second quarter and will continue to focus on them for the remainder of the year and beyond.</p>
          <p>In terms of the core business, as we discussed last quarter, the first quarter is typically soft and this year was further impacted by the downturn in the economy, and its impact on unemployment and health insurance coverage in the United States. However, we also shared our thoughts on why we would expect to see a recovery in the second quarter and the remainder of year.</p>
          <p>This quarter's results have bolstered our outlook for the full year and give us confidence to raise our full-year earnings guidance and point expected sales towards the upper end of the 14.4 to $14.8 billion guidance range. In terms of the pipeline, we reviewed data from a key denosumab study investigating its use in advanced breast cancer patients with bone metastases and are extremely pleased with the outcome as Roger will discuss.</p>
          <p>We are also expecting additional pivotal Phase III data on denosumab in oncology as well as Vectibix in colorectal cancer during the third quarter. Roger will provide more details in a moment.</p>
          <p>Today, we announced our collaboration with GlaxoSmithKline for commercializing denosumab internationally. George will outline the details of this important collaboration, which we believe will maximize the value of denosumab for all stakeholders, most importantly patients and also create value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>This collaboration, which will include commercializing denosumab in European and emerging markets, is a thoughtful approach to leveraging our strengths with those of Glaxo. It came together after months of intense conversation, data sharing, and joint planning. Glaxo has multinational presence and their expertise in primary-care markets in particular will be central to maximizing the value of denosumab. The agreement will also provide a sustained P&amp;L benefit for Amgen, allowing us to retain our significant financial flexibility to invest in other programs.</p>
          <p>We are preparing intensively for denosumab's review by an FDA advisory panel on August 13 and look forward to working with the regulatory authorities both in the United States and Europe to bring this important new therapy to market. We will increase our investment in denosumab during the second half, particularly in the U.S. as we prepare for denosumab's launch.</p>
          <p>Before turning it over to Bob, I'll share a few thoughts on the ongoing discussions around healthcare reform. Amgen supports healthcare reform aimed at providing all Americans access to affordable health insurance. We are taking an active role in addressing the challenges facing our healthcare system by working towards solutions through effective healthcare policy including appropriate legislation on biosimilars. We're pleased to have a seat at the table. While there is still much uncertainty regarding the economic environment and healthcare reform, we remain focused on delivering financially, advancing the pipeline, making denosumab a success and in so doing serving patients.</p>
          <p>I know I'm talking to Amgen's staff today as well and while both these events happened outside the quarter, I want to spend &#x2013; send a special thanks to teams who worked so hard over our July holiday shutdown to get the denosumab 136 trial results out and those who worked so hard to put together an agreement with Glaxo. And to everyone else, thank you for making the second quarter a solid success on all fronts, commercial, research and development and operations. We appreciate all you do for patients.</p>
          <p>Now, I'd like to turn it over to Bob for more details on the quarter and 2009 guidance. Bob?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Kevin. If I can direct you to page 5, I'll walk you through the adjusted P&amp;L for the quarter. Let me start with revenues, which as you can see year-over-year were down about 1% in the second quarter to $3.7 billion. As we're looking at these results, recall that the Aranesp label didn't change last year until the third quarter, so our results for that product look weak by comparison this quarter. And in addition, our results were negatively affected by a stronger dollar this year.</p>
          <p>Looking at our results sequentially, it's worth noting that revenues were up 12%. Recall, as Arvind said moments ago, that in the first quarter we told you that we expected segment growth, share growth, planned price increases and a normalization of inventory levels to drive sequential quarterly growth in 2009. While we benefited from the first three of these in the second quarter, we have not yet seen inventory levels normalize as we had expected and so we think we'll see some of that in the balance of the year.</p>
          <p>We ended the second quarter with wholesaler inventories at the low end of our normal ranges for all products with the exception of Vectibix and Sensipar, which ended within the normal ranges. And George will give you full details at the product level on that in a moment.</p>
          <p>Shifting to a review of our business by geography, U.S. sales were relatively unchanged at $2.8 billion for the quarter. Internationally, we posted second quarter sales of $801 million, which is a decrease of 6% versus the prior year after taking into account the negative impact of changes in foreign exchange, which aggregated about $103 million for the quarter. Excluding the impact of foreign exchange, total product sales increased 1% and the international product sales increased by 6% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning now to operating expenses, on an adjusted basis, our total operating expenses were down 5% this quarter versus last year and as you can see, our operating margin increased reflecting our success &#x2013; or reflecting the success of our ongoing cost-cutting efforts.</p>
          <p>I'll now walk you through the components of our operating expenses starting with cost of sales, which for the quarter, increased by 3% primarily due to higher fill and finish costs at our manufacturing facility in Puerto Rico resulting from lower utilization in 2008 when this layer of inventory was made.</p>
          <p>While our cost of sales margin is up on the quarter versus last year, some sequential context might be helpful. Recall in 2007, our full year cost of sales margin was 15.8% and in 2008, it fell to 14.9%. For the first half of the year, our cost of sales margin is approximately 14.5% and we continue to be pleased with our ongoing efficiencies and operations.</p>
          <p>Turning now to R&amp;D expenses, as you can see, expenses for the quarter were down 16% year-over-year, but note that a big piece of this decrease stems from the fact that in the second quarter of 2008, we expensed $100 million in connection with the in-licensing of a molecule from Kyowa Hakko. The remainder of the expense decrease was primarily driven by lower clinical trial costs for denosumab and Vectibix, which in turn were partially offset by a $50 million expense in the second quarter of this year associated with the exercise of our option on the Cytokinetics' cardiac myosin activator program.</p>
          <p>Turning to SG&amp;A expenses, which were relatively flat to last year, our lower staff-related costs, lower litigation expenses, and lower enterprise resource planning system related expenses were offset in the quarter by higher promotional expenses for marketed products, increased spend for activities in anticipation of approval and launch of denosumab and higher expenses associated with the Wyeth profit-share due to higher Enbrel sales in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Excluding expenses associated with the Wyeth profit-share of $301 million and $283 million in the second quarter of 2009, 2008 respectively, SG&amp;A sales were actually down 3% compared to last year.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the tax rate, let me spend a few moments discussing our adjusted tax rate, which as you can see is down to 18.1% for the quarter compared to 22.2% in the prior year. There were three main drivers for the lower rates in the second quarter. The first one is that in the second quarter of 2009, the tax rate benefited from the federal R&amp;D tax credit which had not been extended by Congress in the second quarter of 2008. The second is you will notice in our GAAP reconciliation that we've reached an IRS settlement on certain transfer pricing matters for prior periods that informed our estimate on Puerto Rico profits for this year. And finally, third, we had increased bulk manufacturing activities in Puerto Rico in 2009.</p>
          <p>So when taking into account our first quarter adjusted tax rate of 21.5%, our year-to-date adjusted tax rate is approximately 19.7%. We expect our full-year rate to be closer to this year-to-date adjusted tax rate than to the rate we just posted in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to earnings per share, first quarter 2009 adjusted earnings per share were $1.29, up 13%. And as you can see, earnings benefited both from the decreased tax rate and the decreased share count following our buyback in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Our GAAP earnings for the quarter were $1.25, up 49% on the prior year. The year-over-year increase is largely driven by a $115 million income tax benefit as a result of resolving certain non-routine transfer pricing issues with the IRS that I referred to a moment ago and the fact that GAAP net income for the second quarter of 2008 was negatively impacted by $263 million for loss accruals for settlements of certain commercial legal proceedings.</p>
          <p>So turning to page 6, as you can see, we once again ended the quarter with a strong balance sheet and healthy cash flows. First, let me spend a moment on some key balance sheet items. Our second quarter global cash balance was $12 billion. And excluding the impact, as you can see on the footnote, of APB 14-1, our debt increased by $1 billion year-over-year, driven by our $2 billion debt issuance in January of this year. We expect this to drop back to $11.2 billion after we retire $1 billion of floating-rate notes that mature in November of 2009.</p>
          <p>Stockholders' equity increased by $2.5 billion, as you can see, year-over-year to $21 billion. With respect to our cash flows, we generated $1.7 billion of cash flows from operations in the second quarter of 2009, which is an improvement over what we generated in the second quarter of 2008, primarily due to higher earnings in the period.</p>
          <p>We didn't repurchase any shares during the second quarter of this year. Taking into account our first quarter share repurchases, our full-year weighted average shares outstanding would be approximately 1.025 billion shares, if there were no additional share buybacks this year. We currently have $2.2 billion remaining on our Board-authorized repurchase programs and we'll continue to use that authorization opportunistically.</p>
          <p>Now turning to page seven, I'd like to give you updated revenue and adjusted earnings guidance for 2009. Based on trends through the end of the second quarter our 2009 revenues are trending towards the upper end of our guidance range of 14.4 to $14.8 billion.</p>
          <p>On earnings per share, we now expect 2009 to be in the range of $4.80 to $4.95 compared to the previous range of $4.55 to $4.75. Our revised EPS guidance reflects the lower tax rate, as I discussed earlier, revenues trending towards the upper end of the guidance range and continued operating expense discipline. Finally we think that capital expenditures for the year are likely to be less than $600 million compared to the previous guidance of $650 million.</p>
          <p>Finally turning to page eight, I'd like to make some comments on the important partnership that we announced today with GlaxoSmithKline. As Kevin noted, we're delighted to have Glaxo as a partner. The deal we struck with Glaxo is designed to see that our incentives are aligned with them from start to finish across a range of potential revenues for denosumab. That's important, because this is a long-term partnership which runs beyond the next decade in the emerging markets and in Europe. We had as an objective from the outsets to create a partnership with them that was a win-win deal for both parties and that's what we think we have here.</p>
          <p>Now let me briefly try to give you the financial highlights of the deal. The economics for us include a simple upfront payment and subsequent commercial milestones aggregating to $120 million and then tiered royalties. After taking into account these pieces, in Europe we and GlaxoSmithKline will share equally in the commercialization and development expenses and profits related to the partnered portion of denosumab. For accounting purposes, we will book the sales and then pay a profit-share to GlaxoSmithKline as an SG&amp;A expense.</p>
          <p>For territories in which Amgen has limited to no commercial presence today, for example, many of the emerging markets, GlaxoSmithKline will handle both the PMO and oncology indications. For these territories, Amgen will sell product to GlaxoSmithKline at an agreed transfer price and record product sales based on such amounts. GlaxoSmithKline will then sell to end customers.</p>
          <p>We ran a broad comprehensive process to consider all of our options for commercializing denosumab. In GlaxoSmithKline, we believe we have a partner that will enable us to achieve greater value for denosumab than we could have achieved on our own and we believe we have a deal structure which gives us the flexibility to expand our participation if we choose to over time.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn it to George, who'll walk us through the product performance for the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Bob, and let's go right to the commercial highlights on slide 10. Product sales declined 2% year-over-year driven by two key unfavorable comparisons. First, core 2009 U.S. Aranesp sales declined $89 million due to label changes which occurred in August of 2008. Second, a strong dollar diminished international sales by $103 million.</p>
          <p>International continued its solid performance growing 6% year-over-year versus the second quarter of 2008 before foreign exchange effects. Aranesp share in the nephrology setting remained steady, Neulasta continued to hold share in the face of new G-CSF biosimilars and newly marketed products including Vectibix and Nplate performed well, contributing $28 million in growth.</p>
          <p>On a sequential basis, global quarterly sales grew 12%. Enbrel contributed 141 million in higher sales as both segment growth and inventory levels recovered during the current quarter. The U.S. ESA business contributed $119 million of sequential growth with both EPOGEN and Aranesp showing increases in sales. International contributed $65 million of sequential growth including a foreign exchange benefit of $10 million. Wholesalers' inventories remained close to their March 31 levels, which were at the low end of the range.</p>
          <p>Next slide. Worldwide Aranesp sales decreased 16% in the second quarter versus last year. In the U.S., Aranesp sales were down 21% year-over-year primarily due to label changes made in 2008 with oncology sales down 27% and nephrology sales down 11%. Overall, U.S. segment share decreased by four points versus the second quarter of 2008 and was flat versus the first quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Internationally, Aranesp sales remained flat excluding foreign exchange and I'll discuss specifics of share and segment changes when I review the international results.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, I'll update you on the trend of utilization of Aranesp in the U.S. market. This slide displays actual weekly U.S. Aranesp sales going back to quarter two, 2007. As a reminder, the sharp peaks and troughs were largely a result of inventory buildups and depletions, not fluctuations in actual patient utilization. The red trend lines indicate average weekly sales over the past three quarters. These lines exclude returns and discount accrual true-ups as well as the effects of wholesaler inventory fluctuations, which serve to distort the quarter-on-quarter comparisons shown on the previous slide.</p>
          <p>The weekly trend lines continue to show relative stability in our U.S. Aranesp business in 2009 with slight underlying growth in the second quarter versus the first quarter driven by demand.</p>
          <p>Lastly, we're continuing our ESA REMS discussions with the FDA and expect resolution later this year.</p>
          <p>EPOGEN is next. EPOGEN grew 3% in the second quarter of 2009 versus the second quarter of 2008 driven mostly by patient growth and an increase in net price. We continue to expect minor dose fluctuations as healthcare practitioners refine their treatment practices to achieve and maintain patient hemoglobin levels in the 10 to 12 gram per deciliter range. Bundling is being discussed at legislative levels and proposed rules are being considered within the CMS and as we learn more, we'll be in a position to comment.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 14, Neulasta and NEUPOGEN combined declined 4% second quarter '09 versus second quarter '08. In the U.S., sales declined 2% driven by a decline in unit demand offset by higher net prices. Quarter-end shipping patterns and inventory fluctuations contributed to the demand decline. If we normalize wholesaler and end-user inventory fluctuations, we estimate that unit demand was flat versus quarter two 2008.</p>
          <p>We continue to believe the growth rate of the NEUPOGEN/Neulasta franchise in the U.S. will be driven primarily by price with modest incremental penetration in untreated patients at moderate severe risk of febrile neutropenia and offset by medical practice changes that reduce the utilization of myelosuppressive chemo regimens.</p>
          <p>During our first quarter call, we mentioned we would be introducing a medical benefit co-pay card to lessen the financial burden on patients who need our medicines. And in June, we launched the Neulasta First Step program to assist low income commercial insured patients with their co-pay and coinsurance requirements. In the first four weeks, early 500 clinics and hospitals have enrolled.</p>
          <p>Internationally, Neulasta and NEUPOGEN declined 9% year-on-year with 5% growth, excluding foreign exchange effects. The NEUPOGEN/Neulasta franchise growth continues to be driven largely by the conversion of NEUPOGEN to Neulasta and I'll provide more detail on biosimilars later in the presentation.</p>
          <p>Enbrel is next on slide 15. At a reporting level, we experienced growth of 7% versus the second quarter of 2008. 4% of this increase was driven by a modest inventory build in quarter two of 2009 versus a modest drawdown in quarter two 2008. The remainder was driven by demand. Within demand, we experienced price growth partially offset by unit decline. The unit decline was primarily in dermatology where we lost some share year-over-year to new competition.</p>
          <p>On a sequential quarterly basis, Enbrel sales were up 19%. 14% of this increase was demand-driven with solid growth in both rheumatology and dermatology segments and stable share versus our competition.</p>
          <p>During the second quarter, U.S. Enbrel maintained its leadership position in both rheumatology and dermatology. We saw two new competitors launch in rheumatology recently, yet Enbrel has held its share at around 34%. And in dermatology, Enbrel continues to get the majority of its first-line biologic use for psoriasis capturing more than 60% of the dollar share in the segment during the quarter.</p>
          <p>On our first quarter call, we mentioned the launch of a new co-pay program for commercial insured patients known as Enbrel Support and during the second quarter adoption of this program was significant. This program, together with our other patient assistance programs, ensures that appropriate patients that need a treatment are able to start and stay on therapy during these tough economic times.</p>
          <p>Slide 16. Next, I'd like to quickly address the recent volatility in segment growth. In the first quarter of 2009, Enbrel experienced sharp growth rate declines in both rheumatology and dermatology segments. Historically, both the rheumatology and dermatology segments have been impacted by seasonality with softness typically seen in the first quarter, followed by strength in the second quarter as patients work through their annual deductibles and other insurance changes. We are hopeful that the segment growth bounce back in quarter two indicates that segments may be back on a trajectory that is consistent with historical patterns.</p>
          <p>On to Sensipar on slide 17. For the second quarter, worldwide Sensipar sales grew at 11% versus the second quarter of 2008, essentially due to demand. This performance reflects 11% growth in the U.S. and 13% growth internationally, which would be 27% excluding the negative impact of foreign exchange.</p>
          <p>Next is Vectibix on slide 18. Our promotional efforts continue to focus on identifying specific and appropriate EGFR eligible patients based on our existing label and highlighting the key benefits of Vectibix versus the competition. Future growth is highly dependent upon label expansion into second and first-line metastatic colorectal cancer. Efficacy data in combination with chemotherapy from both Vectibix first and second line metastatic colorectal cancer Phase III studies will be available this year with label changes to follow.</p>
          <p>The next slide summarizes our international sales performance. Internationally, sales grew 8% excluding divested products and excluding the effects of foreign exchange versus the prior year. In fact, quarter two was a record quarter for our international business before the effects of foreign exchange. Similar to the first quarter, we saw a growth across all products, in nearly all existing territories and from expanding into new territories. This strong performance reflects a slight increase in segment share year-over-year for both Aranesp and Neulasta.</p>
          <p>The next slide looks specifically at new competition in Europe in these segments. As we can see on slide 20, most ESA competitors and biosimilars have launched in Europe in some major countries and other countries are expected to launch this year. For G-CSF biosimilars, we saw the first launches in the fourth quarter of 2008 and expect additional launches in 2009 and 2010.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, we look at international segment share for Aranesp in nephrology. As we gain more experience with the G-CSF biosimilars, we will also provide similar information on share for that segment.  As in recent quarters Aranesp nephrology share remains steady as biosimilars take share from EPO Alpha and EPO Beta but not Aranesp.  In some situations we respond to competition by lowering the price of Aranesp but we always strive to maintain a premium to the first-generation EPOs.</p>
          <p>Okay, switching gears, I'll finish up with a few slides on our partnership agreement with GSK.  As discussed at our November analyst day in New York, slide 22 reviews the issues that prompted us last year to explore this notion of a partnership.  I should start by saying that we believe based on the emerging clinical profile that d-mab [denosumab] is expected to have a very competitive profile in both osteoporosis in cancer settings.  Nevertheless, our preliminary view was that building our own primary care sales force and local health authority access teams outside the U.S. given the likely lower reimbursement expected should be contrasted financially and operationally with a partnership arrangement where Amgen covers specialty audiences while capitalizing on the efficiencies, scale and experiences of our partners existing primary care position and local access field teams. We also wanted to explore if partnering d-mab across indications in so called emerging markets were Amgen lacked a commercial footprint could be a more prudent pathway to both launched d-mab and eventually establish our own affiliates.</p>
          <p>The next slide outlines our aspiration for a partnership when we began the process of meeting with companies last year.  Our team ran an extremely thorough process initially screening 11 very interested companies and taking a few to the wire building granular go-to-market plans and P&amp;Ls for several European countries.  This enabled our key operating team comprised of commercial, medical and business development personnel to make a well informed recommendation on which company would be best positioned to create greater value for d-mab through partnering.  Greater value we believed could be created if partnering could lead to faster and deeper patient access at a lower overall cost.</p>
          <p>We believe this was possible because adding d-mab to an existing sales organization would result in greater reach and frequency of detail in high potential primary care doctors at a much lower incremental cost than building our own primary care sales forces detailing only d-mab. Sharing the incremental profit over time would lead to a win-win situation for both sides.</p>
          <p>So slide 24 outlines how we will proceed. First, go it alone in the U.S. Again, the business logic is a combination of compelling economics. Despite d-mab being our only primary care product coupled with the critical nature of combining a clinical reimbursement and fulfillment discussion into a total office call and this is in contrast to a pure share of voice situation. Tucking the cancer indications into our existing oncology franchise is relatively straightforward.</p>
          <p>Next, partner PMO in Europe, and when I say Europe, it's really the expanded commercial footprint we have right now. GSK was the clear top choice in terms of value creation and our deal structure incents both parties to drive the growth aggressively. Taking advantage of their primary care capacity, and expertise as well as strength in other capabilities, we believe will expand the PMO market opportunity. As is the case in the U.S., Amgen is extremely well positioned to launch the oncology indications for d-mab in established markets.</p>
          <p>And finally, partner all d-mab indications in select emerging markets such as China, Taiwan, South Korea, India and Brazil. However, as we continue to expand our commercial footprint globally and we are now 51 countries through affiliates or distributors, we have structured the deal in a way that facilitates operationally and financially the establishment of standalone Amgen affiliates. Now that the deal is done, both teams will be working hard to put the finishing touches on our launch plan for d-mab.</p>
          <p>And finally, my last slide. We are just including this slide for your reference, to clarify the territorial responsibilities. Roger?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, George. This afternoon, I will summarize the results of our activities in research and development during the second quarter and say something about what we expect for the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>Certainly the most important results that we obtained bridging the end of the quarter were those from our Phase III steady comparing subcutaneous denosumab with intravenous zoledronic acid for the reduction of skeletal-related events in patients with advanced breast cancer metastatic to bone. I will remind you that boney metastases are associated with a variety of complications called skeletal-related events, which include fractures, the need for surgery, the need for radiotherapy and development of spinal cord compression as a result of expanding tumor mass, an event which can represent a medical emergency in these patients.</p>
          <p>Slide 26 outlines the protocol for the 136 breast cancer trial. It's the same sort of protocol that we've employed in all three of our skeletal-related events trials. These studies are large each one involving on the order of 2000 patients and are event driven. In the 136 study 2049 patients with breast cancer and documented boney metastases were randomized to receive either zoledronic acid given according to the approved label instructions or denosumab.</p>
          <p>The study met its primary endpoints and all secondary endpoints demonstrating that denosumab treatment was superior to treatment with zoledronic acid with respect to the time to first skeletal-related event and the time to first and subsequent skeletal-related events with hazard ratios of 0.82 and 0.77 respectively. Both results were statistically significant.</p>
          <p>I would emphasize the importance of the latter endpoint since for any patient it's important to delay not only the first skeletal-related event but also any subsequent events. Our prior Phase II studies certainly suggested that denosumab treatment might prove to be superior to bisphosphonate treatment in patients with boney metastases, nevertheless, we were extremely impressed with both the magnitude and consistency of the denosumab effects in this first Phase III study.</p>
          <p>The safety profiles that we observed in this study were in general consistent with what has previously been observed for these two agents. For example, although the dose of zoledronic acid was reduced in patients with evidence of renal insufficiency, as recommended in the FDA approved label for this product, zoledronic acid associated renal toxicity was observed in our study at about the frequency that has previously been reported. This effect, however, was not seen following denosumab administration, either in prior studies or in the 136 study.</p>
          <p>One new adverse event for denosumab was noted in the 136 study, namely the occurrence of osteonecrosis of the jaw. I should note that we took pains in designing our study to focus carefully on all dental events that might represent osteonecrosis and we empanelled an independent adjudication committee comprised of experts in this area to examine each case report. Based on their analysis there were 20 cases of osteonecrosis of the jaw in patients treated with denosumab and 14 cases in patients treated with zoledronic acid. This numerical difference is of course not statistically significant given the very low incidence of this complication.</p>
          <p>However our results strongly suggest that at least one feature of the pathogenesis of osteonecrosis of the jaw is suppression of bone resorption, irrespective of the mechanism whereby this is achieved. I must also point out that the cases of osteonecrosis that were identified by our adjudication panel are quite heterogeneous with respect to the severity of the lesion, the presence of other risk factors and the resolution of the process which any number of cases occurred while the patients were on still therapy. A complete analysis of these cases will be presented in an appropriate scientific forum.</p>
          <p>Let me emphasize that there have been no cases of osteonecrosis of the jaw when denosumab was administered at the dose we have used for postmenopausal osteoporosis, which is 1/12 of the dose that was employed in our studies in patients with advanced cancer.</p>
          <p>Now, the breast cancer study that I have just reviewed is just the first of a set of three studies that explore the use of denosumab to treat patients with advanced malignancy.  Later in the third quarter we will see the results from the second study, in this case in patients with multiple myeloma or boney metastases from a variety of solid tumors, for example lung cancer.  We also have a third study in patients with prostate cancer metastatic to bone, results from which are expected next year.  Needless to say, we're hopeful that these studies will demonstrate the same kind of efficacy that we observed in the breast cancer study.</p>
          <p>Turning now to other areas of research and development on slide 27, we're continuing to work with the FDA to design an effective Risk Evaluation and Mitigation Strategy, or REMS, program for Erythropoietin Stimulating Agents [ESAs], as George mentioned.  Those discussions are moving forward well.</p>
          <p>We also recently-announced revisions in the label for Vectibix, especially language noting the lack of treatment benefit in patients with metastatic colorectal cancer when those tumors bear activating mutations in the KRAS gene. As we discussed with the Oncologic Drugs Advisory Committee late last year, we sought these changes because we don't want to see patients exposed to the drug who have no chance of benefiting from the treatment.</p>
          <p>Our Phase III study evaluating motesanib in the treatment of non-small cell lung cancer, which we're pursuing in collaboration with Takeda, has resumed enrollment, excluding patients with squamous cell malignancies.  Data comparing motesanib, which is an oral VEGF receptor antagonist with bevacizumab, a ferential VEGF specific antibody in lung cancer treatment, will be presented next week at the World Conference on Lung Cancer.</p>
          <p>We continue to be very active in advancing new programs like Sclerostin antibody, AMG 785 which we are developing in collaboration with UCB as an anabolic agent to increase bone mineral density, has entered Phase 2 studies in post-menopausal osteoporosis and in studies designed to demonstrate improved fracture healing as a result of Sclerostin blockade.</p>
          <p>Also in the second quarter we exercised our option to license AMG 423, a compound identified by our collaborator Cytokinetics which specifically activates cardiac myosin.  We're very hopeful that this approach will represent an important therapeutic advance for patients with heart failure.  Small Phase II studies support this view and we will now move this compound into larger and more definitive trials.</p>
          <p>On slide 28 you can see that this is an extremely active period for research and development at Amgen.  During 2009 we will complete five Phase III studies. One of these has already yielded data, the 136 breast cancer study, and the remaining four are on track to complete in the next few months.  All of these studies are very large. In aggregate they include more than 10,000 patients.  Completing these studies in this timeframe would be a challenge for any biopharmaceutical R&amp;D group and I wish to recognize the extraordinary efforts of our development and regulatory affairs teams, especially those involved with clinical data management and bio-statistics, who have worked tirelessly to advance these studies.</p>
          <p>Included among the Phase III programs are the denosumab solid tumor SRE study that I've already mentioned and two studies that examine the utility of Vectibix when used in combination with chemotherapy as treatment for patients with metastatic colorectal cancer. Importantly the Vectibix Phase III studies will provide the first prospective evaluation of the importance of KRAS mutations on the ability of Vectibix to improve treatment outcomes.</p>
          <p>Results from all of these studies will be available in the third quarter. Somewhat later we will view results from the TREAT study in which we've asked whether the use of Aranesp to maintain higher hemoglobin levels improves outcomes in patients with renal disease who are not yet on dialysis.</p>
          <p>Finally, we are pursuing a variety of Phase II programs in oncology and metabolic disease, data from all of these programs, once the analyses are complete, will be presented in the appropriate scientific forum. Looking forward to 2010, despite the enormous analytical workload with which we are grappling, five additional Phase III studies are on track including the motesanib lung cancer study that I mentioned, two additional Phase III studies exploring the use of denosumab in malignant disease and evaluation of the utility of Vectibix in the treatment of squamous cell carcinoma of the head and neck and a very important study asking whether treatment with Sensipar improves cardiovascular outcomes in patients on dialysis.</p>
          <p>These, together with continued progress on our Phase II programs, offer great promise to patients suffering from grievous illnesses. Kevin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much, Roger. And Arvind, we're going to have a few questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Dennis let's go ahead and open it up for the Q&amp;A session if you can go ahead and review the procedure for asking questions. And as Dennis is getting set up, I would just like to reiterate the same request that we made earlier that if you can please limit yourself to one question so everybody has a chance to ask a question. Dennis, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of Geoff Meacham with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys, congrats on a good quarter and on the strong partnership with Glaxo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wanted to ask a question on ONJ [osteonecrosis of the jaw]. I know Roger mentioned that there weren't many common features. But can you talk to maybe those patients who had prior experience on d-mab with bisphosphonates? And then second part of the question is, I know it's a different populations but to what extent can the breast data be a read-through or an indicator for superiority in prostate or in myeloma?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, with respect to the osteonecrosis of the jaw, they really are quite heterogenous and there are number of pre-disposing factors including prior oral surgery, the history of periodontal disease, specific chemotherapeutic agents that are used, including Avastin, as well as exposure to bisphosphonates. So, all of that stuff has to be taken into account and when you -- we really need to look at all of it and we'll have the opportunity to present that in the appropriate place. I don't want to try and go in and try to parse who is at greater risk or lesser risk. It's a pretty mixed bag.</p>
          <p>With respect to the predictive value of this study, I think from a Bayesian perspective, you'd have to say that having shown superiority in the breast cancer study does improve the probability of having superiority in the other studies, but it certainly doesn't destroy equipoise in those studies. Those tumors are very different kinds of lesions, they invade bone differently, so we really have to wait and see what the results are. The good news is that we won't have long to wait.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Geoffrey Porges with Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much for taking the question and also congratulations on the results. Hard to select one question. I think you guys should be having three conference calls, but apart from that, perhaps we could talk a little bit about the deal, George. Could you talk about how GSK will position this with their profit share that they have on ibandronate and then extrapolating &#x2013; going beyond that, saying what does this mean that Amgen will and won't be doing in Europe in terms of investing in feet on the ground and additional resources over there? Are you going to give the product up completely or will you have a very active role and what might that look like? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Geoff, it's Kevin, we'll probably split this one up. I'll take the first half and George will take the second and then we're going to run this call a little bit longer than normal, because there's lots of information here and we want to help you out.</p>
          <p>First question is about Glaxo's promotion of their currently marketed product, Boniva in the U.S. or Bonviva in Europe. And Glaxo's got many years of experience and they're working collaboratively with partners and they respect and understand collaboration obligations, in fact, one of the most important factors why we chose Glaxo. And Glaxo has assured Amgen that the collaboration does not conflict with their existing agreements and I think if you've got some more questions about Glaxo's views and actions, probably talking to them directly is the best thing. And George, you might take second half of the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's a great question Geoff. First of all, this is a strategic partnership. We really valued their input into our marketing plans and tactical plans and execution. So they'll have marketing people, we'll have marketing people putting their heads together and hopefully one plus one will equal more than two. In terms of field organizations, Amgen will recruit reps for specialty audiences and the degree of specialty audiences, or the importance of specialty audiences really varies by country. Some countries, specialty may account for half or more of the market where other places 10% or less. So that's going to be variable. So we will be the primary team detailing the specialty physicians, Glaxo will be &#x2013; has the sole responsibility for detailing the primary care doctors and again that varies from country to country.</p>
          <p>When it comes to national health authority access like the National Health Service, other reimbursement authorities, we'll probably take the lead in that but certainly given Glaxo's vast experience with national reimbursement organizations, we'll certainly partner with them on that.</p>
          <p>But when it comes to local health authority access entities and here you know I'm talking about for example the Primary Care Trusts in the U.K. where there are more than 50 of these that are sort of like mini-HMOs that administer the healthcare plans in the U.K., they have those people already on the ground, they are very good at what they do and we'll be tapping into their expertise. Other countries like Italy and Spain also have local health authorities, where getting access and formulary acceptance and so forth is critically important to the launch of the product. So, again we're really tapping into their expertise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Bret Holley with Oppenheimer &amp; Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. I just wanted to follow up on Geoff's question about the ex-U.S. build. I'm just wondering with the people you have on the ground for oncology now, how much overlap is there for denosumab? Are you really going to have to kind of build a new specialty force outside of the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we're going to have to add some specialty reps but also we will redeploy where necessary. If we find that we have some additional capacity for some of our specialty reps to call on endocrinologists, for example, or OB/Gyns, we certainly want to go ahead and look at that. So it will be a mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And do you have any -- you've given an idea of the spend. Do you have an idea of spend of ex-U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Chris Raymond with Robert Baird.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I know you went into some detail on the terms of the deal but can you maybe give a little bit of color on the sort of mechanisms and checks that are in place to monitor the expense of the collaboration just to ensure that costs that are real on the part of GSK are being assigned to it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we have a lot of experience with this with our Wyeth partnership and actually some other partnerships that Roger's group does and so certainly we will have different governance committees. Governance committees around manufacturing, development, commercial and certainly we will agree to a marketing plan for example on the commercial side that explicitly outlines the resources that are to be deployed and cost them out and is put together as part of a budget and that joint budget where we do profit sharing is really the alignment mechanism. And so we have a &#x2013; GSK has been a terrific partner over the years. They know how to do this. We know how to do this. So I don't really expect any major issues to arise from lack of trust in terms of accounting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Steve Harr with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a couple more questions around this deal &#x2013; or one question; sorry. Who sets the price given that PMO will be likely the first indication to launch and how is that going to be adjusted going forward? And then how are you guys going to deal with R&amp;D spending as you look at post-marketing commitments on all these different indications?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So again, they are our strategic partner, we certainly want to sit down with them on a country-by-country basis, get their input, and together I think we'll come up with a price. Ultimately, Amgen has the final say on price. But again we'll certainly seek their input and any adjustments to price will be made as a team, with again, Amgen having the final say. And I'll let Roger answer the third part of your first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I mean, we have a lot of experience with these kinds of joint development agreements and joint development committees will decide based on what's needed in order to provide the appropriate evidence demonstrating the value of denosumab, how we should do that and who should be responsible. We know that our colleagues at GSK have an enormous amount of experience. We're deeply respectful of that and we want to work very, very closely with them. At the end of the day if there were disagreement we have the final word. But I don't expect there'll be a lot of those kinds of disagreements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Yaron Werber with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, congrats again. I had a question. Roger, you noted that the &#x2013; in the ONJ study, some of the patients "showed a resolution while on therapy" Do you have a sense; is that equally in both arms because Zometa is obviously not reversible, d-mab potentially is reversible. I'm just trying to understand if there is mechanistic <mark type="audio gap" /> And then just if I can just make a follow-on sort of, George mentioned that "there is going to be further Vectibix label changes coming up soon." I'm just trying to get a sense, is that a hint of optimism on the upcoming two Phase III studies? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Guys, let's try to stick with one. I'll answer the second part of your first question. We don't try to predict clinical trial outcomes. So we're hopeful, but let's wait.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. We don't &#x2013; we have no idea what the results of the study are going to be. We'll find out when we turn over the card and that will be what drives label changes.</p>
          <p>And with respect to ONJ, again, I don't want to try and split out the difference pieces and which &#x2013; what happened to which cases. We're still in the midst of looking at these from the standpoint of the individual narratives, because there's a lot of details to these cases. I think, what I would just say is that, I was surprised by the degree of resolution that one could see in such cases. I hadn't expected that, and so we need to look at them very carefully and make sure that the adjudication process holds up. But that's kind of where we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of May-Kin Ho with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So hi, then a question on the agreement with GSK again. Can you give us a little bit more detail in terms of how the profits will be split? Is there a standstill agreement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. What's the second piece of the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Standstill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The profits will be split, May-Kin, if you look at my slide, slide eight, after taking into account the upfront payment, commercial milestones and the royalty that I referred to, we and Glaxo will split equally the development expenses and the commercialization expenses and profits in the relevant partner territories. In the emerging markets, as I noted, where we have no commercial infrastructure, they will have responsibility for the commercialization and development expenses and they will purchase the product from us at an agreed-upon transfer price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Eric Schmidt with Cowen &amp; Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Roger, could you just talk a little bit about the filing strategy for d-mab in oncology whether 136 is enough or you expect to wait for the myeloma data or we have to wait until prostate next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eric, the filing strategy will depend to a certain extent on what the results are. Certainly we would want to have two studies and in any case we're going to be seeing very soon, we expect, the results from the solid tumor study, so we will have both of those. It may be that based on those results we decide we really would like to put all three of them together. It may be that we would decide that those two would make some sense. We'll make a decision based on what the results look like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Just before we take the next question, May-Kin, you asked about standstill and I didn't answer that piece of your question. There are standstill agreements in place, reciprocal standstill agreements in place and there are change of control provisions, again, reciprocal change of control provisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Jim Birchenough with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Let me add my congratulations. And just a question on the core business. As you guys make your long-range plans, how should we think about the core business? Is it a business that you can grow in the single digits? Is the goal to keep it flat or are you just trying to limit the decline and how do you do those strategies, whichever one it is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The major objective we have in the core business is to and it's a product-by-product and I'll ask George to comment a little bit. It's a product-by-product dynamic, but certainly we want the core business to keep increasing its profit growth and in those products that we see growth, which is most of them, we're going to try to grow them slowly, and I think it's a solid foundation that we can put denosumab and other products on top of. And obviously in the core business, there's some products, Sensipar is an example that are growing quite rapidly. Vectibix and George, you can sort of comment on how you see it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so, obviously, we're not going to give you our forecast, it's an uncertain world. I think the first quarter certainly showed us that. But if you just go down the list I think EPOGEN is a product that we said it last November. We think through patient growth and some very minor price increases we can probably eek out some growth. Obviously when the composite rate roll and bundle happens, then that'll be a different set of circumstances and we think it's going to be hard to grow through that environment.</p>
          <p>Aranesp, we think we can grow this product longer term, but we have to get through the REMS first. I think we've shown when we don't have label changes or a new FDA actions that we can get things to pretty stable level and I think potentially Aranesp growth can be driven by some minor price increases and some patient growth as well, but we have to see what the REMS looks like.</p>
          <p>NEUPOGEN/Neulasta, again some patient growth. On the other hand, unfortunately some of the chemo regimens being used are less myelosuppressive and therefore there is less of a need for Neulasta. And that is the way it is and so how that nets out over time is probably the biggest uncertainty, but we think we can keep it close to flat growth.</p>
          <p>And in Enbrel, very happy with the second quarter, obviously, but we do have new competition coming. We have to be realistic that doctors will want to incorporate those new competitors into their armamentaria, so I think we'll do well to keep this close to a growth product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Michael Aberman with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey guys. Also let me add my congratulations on a great quarter. I have a question, George, for you, you mentioned in the U.S. the sales calls to be for the whole total office. And I'm wondering are you now thinking this is going to be definitely a Medicare Part-B product, and how might that help you position it in terms of co-pays etcetera versus some of the branded oral therapies like a Boniva</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So our position really hasn't changed, Michael, since the November 7 analyst day in New York. And that is that we don't get to decide part B or D, that's the CMS. This product, we do believe, should be injected by a healthcare practitioner and accordingly those products are typically reimbursed through a B mechanism, but B products can also be reimbursed through D mechanisms. So, what we don't want to do is get out in front of the CMS on these issues. So, we're ready for both.</p>
          <p>Obviously, if it's reimbursed through part B, the co-pay is a little less burdensome than through part D, particularly if you get to the donut hole. So, both mechanisms have implications for patients. Obviously on the commercial side of the business, the medical benefit tends to be a little more forgiving for patients than the pharmacy benefit. So I think if it goes part B you will see a lot of this reimbursed through the commercial &#x2013; through the medical benefit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Schoenebaum with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Hey guys, I'd like to add my congratulations too. I'll ask a question and I run the risk you may not answer, but George, I mean this sort of philosophically to get you talking, but just when I think about pricing for d-mab &#x2013; I know it's way to early, you're not going to comment specifically &#x2013; but when I think about supportive care drugs in oncology I tend to &#x2013; other supportive care drugs, I tend to think of other supportive care drugs as the comp. Can you sort of compare and contrast the clinical benefit of Neulasta versus d-mab and explain why we should or shouldn't use Neulasta as an appropriate comp when we begin to think about pricing for this &#x2013; for d-mab?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think probably the best way to think about this, Mark, were to recognize that there is an established market for products that treat skeletal-related events. By the way, there is no market for prevention of skeletal-related events so that if we got those results &#x2013; it will probably be after &#x2013; might be after we launch the product for SREs. So, that may not be factored into our ultimate pricing decision. But whenever you have market-based pricing, we've got to be competitive and so I think that's probably a more healthy way of looking at it than is this going to be priced like Neulasta, for example.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Joel Sendek with Lazard Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. I have a question about the gross margin, you indicated that it's been improving every year now. I'm wondering what the reason for that is and will it continue to improve further, and are the improvements permanent?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the question Joel. As I said, we're pleased with the progress we've made in the restructuring of our operations. That restructuring which we began in the summer of 2007 is beginning to be reflected in our cost of sales. So while our cost of sales were up on the quarter, I wanted to give you that historical or sequential context so you could see that we have been able to bring that down over time.</p>
          <p>Now, as we being to introduce new products, you should expect there will be some variation around that current level, but generally we're pleased with the progress we've made in restructuring of operations and then the efficiencies that have come from that and we're continuing to pursue further opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Eun Yang with Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This is regarding the REMS program for ESA. It's been taking a little longer than the Street has anticipated in terms of finalizing the program. Is this because of the complexity of the program or is that the fact that the limited usage has occurred already with the label changes, so the agency does not see the urgency of completing this &#x2013; finalizing the program as soon as possible?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that it's safe to say that REMS is a new approach by the FDA. I think they're being appropriately thoughtful and careful about how it's implemented. I think that the logic for REMS stands on its own and is not connected to any given sales level and we'd expect it to come out here in due course. And I think just care and the newness of the program explains the timing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Aaron Reames with Wells Fargo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. I just wanted to ask if you could provide us with a little bit of color about how we should think about patients transitioning &#x2013; cancer patients transitioning from biannual dosing for chemotherapy-induced bone loss to monthly dosing for SREs especially when there is &#x2013; this is an indication or let's say breast cancer where there is no prevention data?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure I understand that question exactly, but you know if a patient is being treated for treatment-induced bone loss for hormone ablation, which is where we've done our studies, and if unfortunately they develop metastatic bone disease, what's clear in the breast cancer case is that administration of denosumab at the much higher dose, 12 times higher dose, will reduce the frequency of skeletal-related events. That transition should be very straightforward. It's the same drug administered in the same way just at a more frequent schedule and a 2x higher dose per injection, so it should be straightforward, the transition is not problematic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Maged Shenouda with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, hi. For modeling purposes, how should we think about the launch expenses of denosumab in the U.S. and in the GSK territories and how long do you think it will take before the JV turns profitable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we haven't been given a lot of information for competitive reasons, Maged. So, let me just maybe reiterate what we've said about sales force sizing, because that's a pretty large component and again we don't give exact numbers on sales force sizing for competitive reasons. But what we said in the U.S. is that we'd have 500 to 1000 people in the field and the only thing I would say there, we would probably trend to the upper end of the range of that. In the EU we said 1000 to 1500 reps and I think particularly with now having GSK as our partner we certainly would be trending toward the upper end of that range as well, because I think one of the key ingredients of this deal is because their marginal cost of getting a rep to that next primary-care physician is lower, we can bring more primary-care docs from a marginal revenue perspective into scope. And so, we'll have more reps than we probably would have had on our own. Otherwise we really haven't discussed any other elements of our marketing plan and certainly until we have a label, our marketing plans will not be completed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mike King with Merriman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question, and let me add my congratulations. Question for Bob and perhaps Kevin, the R&amp;D spend was down fairly significantly year-on-year basis, SG&amp;A is flat. Is the R&amp;D budget appropriate for the management of the assets in the pipeline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer to the latter is yes. But let me comment on that what you observe in the difference. As Roger mentioned, last year we had $100 million payment to, I think, Daiichi Sankyo and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kyowa Hakko.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kyowa Hakko; I'm sorry, Kyowa Hakko, and this year we had a payment of 50 million to Cytokinetics. There's a $50 million swing right there.</p>
          <p>The other thing is that we had very heavy expenses last year on some of these big trials that are reporting now that are a little bit less now. So, on a comparative basis it's certainly not as extreme as just the numbers would suggest.</p>
          <p>We've said that our target plus or minus is on the order of 20% of sales for R&amp;D, it's not always going to be there and we will invest enough money to advance the pipeline. I would hope that we increase our R&amp;D spending over time, but the quarters will be lumpy and we sure will invest thoughtfully but aggressively against the assets we've got in the pipeline and keep looking outside the company. We're very, very committed to research and development and all the way from discovery research through regulatory. So, we'll invest at the right levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Joshua Schimmer with Leerink Swann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks for taking my question. Are there plans to start met prevention studies in other solid tumor indications for d-mab aside from prostate and if so which tumors? When do you expect those to begin and what are you waiting for to get them underway? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Joshua, we are deep in the midst of developing studies in the breast cancer environment. We are hopeful that we'll be able to get those studies underway before the end of the year. It just takes time to pull together all of the details. So that's an obvious place to go, of course, and then there are others that we're thinking about, but clearly prostate and breast are the most important just because of the frequency of the tumor and also the frequency of boney metastasis in that environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Dennis, why don't we take one last question as I show about 10 minutes past the hour.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir. The final question comes from the line of Geoff Meacham with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks for the follow-up. I wanted to ask you about the advisory panel for PMO on the safety side. Will there be any more &#x2013; will there be any SRE data for oncology that may be discussed by the panel and then any considerations regarding potential monitoring for d-mab in PMO? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Clearly the agency is aware of our data from our SRE studies. We've supplied that data to them, but I don't expect any discussion of those data at the RDAC meeting. That's a meeting entirely focused on the issue of postmenopausal osteoporosis and hormone ablation associated loss of bone mineral density, which is of course a similar kind of process. That's what we'll be discussing and I'm really, really not expecting to focus on skeletal-related event studies at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Roger. Let me thank everybody for your participation in our call this afternoon. If you have any follow on questions or comments, of course, myself together with the IR team will be around for the next several hours. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude Amgen's second quarter 2009 financial results conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>