<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1265488" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-11-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1616</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Michael Powell, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Tom Bartlett, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">James Taiclet, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">David Barden</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Jonathan Atkin</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Jason Armstrong</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Michael McCormack</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Ric Prentiss</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Simon Flannery</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Jonathan Schildkraut</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Phil Cusick</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Gray Powell</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Michael Rollins</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="corprep">James D. Taiclet, Chairman, President &amp; Chief Executive Officer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Tracy and I will be your conference operator today. At this time I would like to welcome everyone to the American Tower Third Quarter 2009 Earnings Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to our host, Mr. Michael Powell, the Vice President of Investor Relations. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tracy. Good morning, everyone. And thank you for joining American Tower's conference call regarding our third quarter 2009 financial results.</p>
          <p>Please note that we've posted a brief presentation to accompany this morning's call on our website, which is www.americantower.com. If you haven't done so already, you may want to download this presentation, as we will refer to it at various times throughout our prepared remarks.</p>
          <p>The agenda for this morning's call will be as follows. I will provide an introduction and highlight certain key metrics from our third quarter 2009 financial results. Following this, Tom Bartlett, our Chief Financial Officer, will go over our third quarter results in detail. And finally, Jim Taiclet, our Chairman, President, and Chief Executive Officer, will then give closing remarks, including his thoughts on current key business trends. And of course, after these comments, we will open the call to your questions.</p>
          <p>However, before I begin, I'd like to remind you that this call will contain forward-looking statements that involve a number of risks and uncertainties. Examples of these statements include statements regarding our 2009 outlook, our stock repurchase program, credit markets, and any other statements regarding matter that are not historical facts.</p>
          <p>You should be aware that certain factors may affect us in the future and could cause results to be materially different that those expressed in these forward-looking statements. Such factors include the risk factors set forth in this morning's press release and those set forth in our Form 10-Q for the quarter ended June 30, 2009, and our other filings with the SEC. We urge you to consider these factors and remind you that we undertake no obligation to update the information contained in this call to reflect subsequent events or circumstances.</p>
          <p>And with that, I will begin the call with some of the highlights of our results.</p>
          <p>Please turn to Slide Four of the presentation for a summary of our third quarter 2009 results compared against the third quarter of 2008. You'll note that we reported total revenues of approximately 440 million, reflecting growth of 8.5% from the year ago period. Our results for the third quarter of 2009 included a 6.7 million net one-time revenue item within our Rental and Management segment related to a termination agreement with one of our U.S. broadcast customers. Tom will provide additional color on our core growth for the business, excluding this one-time item and the impact of foreign exchange rate fluctuations and straight line accounting.</p>
          <p>Our adjusted EBITDA for the quarter was 304 million, which is a 9.6 increase from the prior year period. Our operating income for the quarter increased 16% to approximately 179 million. And finally, income from continued operations was up 11.5% to approximately 68 million or approximately $0.17 on a per share basis.</p>
          <p>And now, Tom, I'd like to turn things over to you at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Michael, and good morning, everyone.</p>
          <p>I'm again pleased to report that American Tower continued its track record of consistently delivering strong revenue and adjusted EBITDA growth during the third quarter of 2009. Please turn to Slide Five to review some of the highlights.</p>
          <p>Our core growth rate for Tower revenue &#x2013; which excludes the impact of foreign currency exchange rate fluctuations, straight line lease accounting, and a $6.7 million one-time termination agreement with one of our U.S. broadcast customers &#x2013; was 10.3% relative to the third quarter of 2008. We continue to generate an industry-leading adjusted EBITDA margin of 68.5%.</p>
          <p>I'd like to highlight that we have maintained this margin level while doubling the size of our portfolio in Brazil and launching our India operations. We've remained focused and disciplined while evaluating opportunities to selectively deploy our capital. We believe these investments will not only drive our core growth in our portfolio but also enhance our return on invested capital.</p>
          <p>Highlights during the quarter and to date include the construction of 267 sites across our portfolio, the acquisition of 230 communication sites in Brazil and 74 in the United States, and the purchase of 326 sites in India, which closed just subsequent to the end of the quarter. All told, just under 900 sites added over the last 90 days for about $120 million.</p>
          <p>In addition, we also re-deployed approximately $118 million of our excess cash flow back to shareholders through our share repurchase program. In fact, we purchased back almost $900 million since the beginning of 2008.</p>
          <p>In addition, our balance sheet remains in a solid position, and the strongest in the industry. Net leverage for the quarter was 3.3 times. The reduction from the second quarter is primarily a result of nearly all of our 3% convertible note holders exercising their option to convert their notes into common stock upon our redemption of the notes.</p>
          <p>We have nearly $850 million of available liquidity, which included over $225 million of cash and cash equivalents, and nearly $625 million of availability under our revolving credit facility. And finally, our recent upgrade to investment grade enabled us to raise $600 million of 4&#x215D;% senior unsecured notes due 2015, which is by far the lowest cost unsecured notes ever issued by the company.</p>
          <p>As a result of the strong business performance in the quarter, we are re-affirming our previously established 2009 outlook.</p>
          <p>Turning to Slide Six, you can see from the chart in the upper left hand side of the page that our top line growth trends remain strong. In fact, our core growth versus the year ago period would have been 10.3% on a currency neutral basis and excluding the impacts of straight line lease accounting and the benefit of the one-time customer termination agreement I mentioned earlier. The majority of our core growth has been supported by our legacy communication sites, which continue to produce solid levels of growth. Our organic growth has been strengthened by investments in new communication sites in the U.S. and abroad.</p>
          <p>Turning to Slide Seven, our recent focus has been to expand further within our existing markets while also pursuing new growth opportunities where our tower leasing expertise can provide carriers with a strong value proposition. Since the beginning of 2008, we have been extremely focused on this endeavor and are proud of our progress to date. Our team in Brazil recently completed the acquisition of 230 sites from a regional carrier. These tower sites, along with more than 600 sites that we have built or acquired, have contributed to the successful doubling of our site portfolio since the beginning of 2008. Similarly, in India, our recent acquisition of XCEL Telecom and Transcend Infrastructure has enhanced our scale within our targeted regional telecom circles and provided us with assets that will provide solid foundation to grow.</p>
          <p>We also expect that these markets will continue to produce strong growth, and in some cases, stronger organic growth than our U.S. assets. As wireless industries across the globe mature, more and more subscribers are seeking 3G or faster speeds, and as a result, our customers' needs for tower space continues to grow. In addition, as spectrum auctions are completed and our customers continue with expansions into new geographies, we will seek to partner with them. These opportunities should provide our investors with a complementary source of growth in the years to come.</p>
          <p>If you turn to Slide Eight, you can see the same positive trends in our core adjusted EBITDA growth, which was 9.2%, with an adjusted EBITDA margin of 68.5%. We are pleased to report that even including the first full quarter of our expanded presence in India and Brazil, which partially contributed to the increase in our Rental Management segment operating expenses and SG&amp;A from the third quarter of 2008, our adjusted EBITDA margin held steady at our industry-leading levels.</p>
          <p>On Slide Nine, I'd like to highlight the ways in which we are seeking to add further shareholder value by not only focusing on growing revenues but also focusing on the costs to support those revenues to drive margin and cash flow expansion. First, our legacy assets continue to produce strong operating leverage as they continue to generate organic revenue and have only experienced minimal increases in costs compared to the year-ago period. Alternatively, since the beginning of 2008, we have materially increased our international portfolios, which have introduced incremental operating and SG&amp;A costs. These costs support our future growth in these regions. However, we will remain focused on ensuring they are at appropriate levels.</p>
          <p>Second, our recent ratings upgrade enabled us to raise $600 million of new senior notes at an annual coupon of 4&#x215D;, or 250 basis points lower than the notes we refinanced with the proceeds of the offering. As a result and as example of how this upgrade will benefit us in the future, we will save approximately $11 million in cash interest cost per year on this transaction alone, which will contribute to our future sources of cash to reinvest in our core business new assets or stock repurchase program. In addition, as we reduce our borrowing costs, our overall cost of capital should decrease.</p>
          <p>Finally, we're continuing our work to ensure that we are prepared to effectuate the best solution for minimizing our tax burden. Our overall global tax strategy involves managing our cash tax liabilities in our profitable Latin American operations, as well as our tax exposure in the United States.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Slide 10, you can see the positive trends in our capital expenditure mix over the last year. Our redevelopment CapEx continues to be lower in 2009 compared to the levels we experienced in 2008, and we expect this to continue for the remainder of 2009.</p>
          <p>Conversely, our discretionary capital expenditures have trended higher, and we expect them to remain so for the balance of the year. This is a direct result of our development team's success in finding high return projects to invest in to grow the business. During the third quarter, we spent approximately $33 million on new site development, completing the construction of 267 new sites, with average day one unlevered returns of approximately 8%, with strong prospects for growth as we add additional tenants to those sites.</p>
          <p>In addition, we spent approximately $18 million on land purchases. I would highlight that the company's total return on invested capital as of the third quarter was approximately 11%, which represents an increase of 140 basis points from the beginning of 2008. The continued improvement in this metric demonstrates our ability to further maximize the return of our existing assets while selectively seeking new investments to complement our asset base.</p>
          <p>Turning to Slide 11, we've highlighted the trends of both cash provided by operating activities and our recurring free cash flow. Consistent with prior quarters, we continued to use our cash flow from operations to reinvest in our core business and stock repurchase program. During the third quarter of 2009, we spent $32 million related to investments in our existing sites, and $101 million on new communication sites, of which $33 million was for the construction of new communication sites and $68 million was for new acquisitions. And finally, we deployed 118 million through our stock repurchase program.</p>
          <p>As shown on the chart on the lower right-hand corner of the page, we're introducing a new metric for the company, recurring free cash flow and recurring free cash flow per share, which we believe will illustrate our past and future ability to deploy our excess capital into accretive investments to enhance shareholder value.</p>
          <p>Since the third quarter of 2008, our recurring free cash flow and recurring free cash flow per fully diluted share have increased 16.3% and 18.6%, respectively.</p>
          <p>Consistent with our capital allocation strategy, we will continue to focus on investing in our existing assets and new communication sites, while remaining committed to our stock repurchase program.</p>
          <p>Turning to Slide 12, American Tower ended the third quarter having generated approximately $467 million of free cash flow year to date, with approximately $850 million of available liquidity and a net leverage ratio of approximately 3.3 times.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, our strong business model, with a significant backlog of contracted revenue, prudent capital structure and approach to leverage, were recognized by both Moody's and Fitch with their recent upgrade of our unsecured credit rating to investment grade. There are many benefits that go hand in hand with being an investment-grade credit, some of which are a larger bond investor base, greater inclusion in bond index funds, and the obvious reduction in our cost of debt. Our recent 4&#x215D;% senior notes offering illustrated our ability to achieve this, and we will continue to opportunistically monitor the capital markets as we seek to ladder and further extend our maturities with lower cost debt for our capital structure.</p>
          <p>And finally, on Slide 13, we've highlighted our 2009 outlook for revenue, adjusted EBITDA, and cash provided by operating activities, which we are re-affirming. As of the third quarter 2009, we've generated approximately 75% of our annual outlook mid-point targets, including our Rental and Management segment revenue, adjusted EBITDA, and cash from operating activities.</p>
          <p>In summary, we continue to believe that the fundamentals of our business are strong, and we are actively seeking ways to further redeploy our cash towards high return investments to enhance shareholder value. Also, depending upon our investment pipeline and market conditions, we remain committed to redeploying our excess cash to investors. We believe that our capital structure complements us well and will be a source of strength for the company and its shareholders going forward.</p>
          <p>Before I hand the floor over to Jim, I'd like to point out that we will provide our 2010 outlook during the announcement of fourth quarter results, which is the standard practice for most S&amp;P 500 companies. At that time, our customers' budgets will be set, and we will incorporate any further acquisitions that may close by year end into our run rates. Jim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tom. Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us on the call today.</p>
          <p>As Tom very thoroughly described, American Tower again delivered strong operational and financial results in the third quarter. The meaningful and consistent growth in our revenues, profitability, and cash generation speaks to the sustained demand for tower space in our served markets and to the company's exceptional execution capabilities. I'd like to take a moment to commend our people from Seattle to Boston to Sao Paulo to Calcutta for their superb work ethic and commitment to customer service that makes these kinds of results possible.</p>
          <p>As an investor, you should know that everyone at American Tower, through our performance management system, has specific goals and objectives that contribute to driving company performance, as ultimately measured by recurring free cash flow per share. We believe this metric captures the most important elements of effectively managing a company such as ours. These elements include revenue growth, cost control, interest expense management, and redevelopment capital expenditures. This metric also captures the ability of the business to distribute cash beyond funds needed to grow back to investors through share repurchase by the company.</p>
          <p>As Tom noted in his presentation, we delivered approximately 18% improvement in recurring free cash flow per share in the third quarter of 2009 over the prior year period. We intend to provide this metric to you on a go-forward basis in our future earnings releases, too.</p>
          <p>Another critical benchmark achieved by American Tower during the third quarter of 2009 was the company reaching 11% return on invested capital. Our improvement in ROIC over the course of the year has been driven by two major factors, the continued solid performance of our existing assets and the efficiency with which we have been adding new assets. With respect to new assets, we have been building towers and data systems in a cost effective manner, and we have also been securing acquisitions at favorable entry prices in each of the U.S., Brazil, and India markets.</p>
          <p>Viewed together, we believe that our ongoing report of recurring free cash flow per share growth and return on invested capital will provide a well rounded picture of the effective strategic management of our tower company. Strong growth in recurring free cash flow per share and stable or increasing ROIC will indicate an appropriate balance between operating leverage, price discipline in the acquisition of assets, and the return of excess cash to shareholders.</p>
          <p>We anticipate that both our recurring free cash flow per share and our return on invested capital results will further benefit from lower cost debt financing. The company's recent elevation by Moody's and Fitch to an investment grade rating is already contributing positively to this objective. Last month's highly successful $600 million bond offering is the first step in utilizing our new position in the credit markets to extend the maturities of our debt and finance future growth initiatives with lower cost instruments marketed to a much broader investor base.</p>
          <p>Finally, we are striving to exceed our growth aspirations for the business in what continues to be a solid demand environment. In the U.S., we believe that we are positioned to benefit from years to come from consumers' appetite for wireless data services. Not only do subscribers want access to true mobile broadband, but our customers, the wireless carriers, are seeing data as essential to their future revenue growth, and they seemed to be prepared to fund the ongoing upgrade of networks that will be required over time.</p>
          <p>Almost every U.S. wireless carrier is in the midst of large scale 3G deployments and/or is planning on executing 4G as well. For example, Verizon Wireless reported 29% growth in data revenue in Q3, and it's in the process of a commercial launch of 4G, planning to cover 100 million pops by year-end 2010 and virtually the entire U.S. population by year-end 2013.</p>
          <p>AT&amp;T Mobility reported 34% growth in data revenue in the third quarter, along with 3.2 million new iPhone activations. AT&amp;T is upgrading its 3G network currently and is planning to commercial launch 4G in 2011.</p>
          <p>Sprint Nextel's Postpaid CDMA customers in the third quarter had the highest average data revenue per user in the industry at $19 each, approximately 20% higher than in the prior year. Sprint Nextel is deploying its 4G network through the Clearwire venture, and Sprint plans to offer 4G mobile broadband in 80 markets by year-end 2010.</p>
          <p>And T-Mobile plans to have 300 million pops covered through its 3G rollout by the end of this year and is moving forward with an HSPA Plus upgrade over the next 12 to 18 months, to add speed to that network. And in the Prepaid segment of the market, both MetroPCS and Leap Wireless have future 4G plans under discussion in their respective organizations.</p>
          <p>We're also optimistic about the prospects for our International business. In Latin America, we believe that there's still opportunity for carriers to grow their voice services, and that more importantly, the region is about to launch into a significant deployment of 3G data services over the next few years. We're hopeful that additional spectrum will be made available in early 2010 in both Mexico and Brazil to enable the beginning of the expansion of 3G in those countries. Meanwhile, in India, we still see significant upside for both voice penetration and coverage, with eventual deployment of data services on a national level a bit further down the road.</p>
          <p>So in summary, we like the continuity of demand that we anticipate in the U.S., and we expect that the transition into 3G data in Latin America and the substantial opportunity in both voice and data in India will provide a very positive growth environment for our international markets. Our focus now is to finish strong in 2009, lay the groundwork for further organic growth in 2010, seek and close attractive acquisition opportunities in a number of targeted markets, and optimize our capital structure to fund our growth and benefit shareholders.</p>
          <p>Thanks again for joining us in the call today, and now Tom and I will be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of David Barden with Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Good morning. Thanks for taking the question.</p>
          <p>I guess first I have to say I'm a little disappointed that you guys choose to defer putting out 2010 guidance. I think the visibility in this business and your ability to differentiate yourselves with laying out a view for a year ahead was one of the things that makes these companies different and underscores that difference. So I'd love a little bit more color around why you chose to do that.</p>
          <p>Second, with respect to the one-timer, Tom, we heard a lot about the margin being 68.5%, but when you take that out, it's actually below 67% and it seems a little off trend. You seem to suggest that that might be related to margin softness in the international operations. I'm wondering if you could kind of clarify how we should be thinking about margins on a go-forward basis.</p>
          <p>And then, with respect to the guidance and the one-timer, by reiterating guidance and then noting that you have a 6.7 million one-timer in the quarter, are you effectively lowering guidance for the year? If you could clarify that, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, David. I appreciate your first comment. But as I mentioned, we are going to be issuing guidance in just a few months time. And that's when most companies issue guidance. And you cover a lot of big companies, so I'm sure you can appreciate our stance there.</p>
          <p>With regards to the one-timer, we are also now have a lot of scaling going on with obviously India and the new acquisition and the business there. So as we continue to scale and continue to improve profitability there &#x2013; which is, by the way, EBITDA positive, I would add &#x2013; I think you'll see the kind of trends in gross margin as well as EBITDA that we've had in the past. But the increase in OpEx and SG&amp;A quarter-to-quarter sequentially was really is a result of having the full quarter, if you will, of that deal.</p>
          <p>And what was your last question, Dave?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The guidance question for 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our guidance &#x2013; I mean it's pretty broad. It's kind of interesting in terms of how the Tower companies actually issue guidance. It's a pretty broad span, if you will, in terms of what the guidance looks like and what the midpoints look like.</p>
          <p>So no, because of its wideness, we're not changing guidance. We feel very strong about where we are and how we're going to end the year, so we think we're going to end on a very strong note.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to be clear, Tom, should I subtract 7 million from the guidance or should I add 7 million to the guidance for this one timer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dave, just leave guidance alone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jonathan Atkin with RBC Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. With respect to the Transcend deal in India, I wonder if you can comment on any particular aspects of those assets you found appealing?</p>
          <p>And then just more broadly, it seems that India and Brazil is where you're most likely to make a either carrier or third-party tower acquisitions. Is that a correct assessment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regards to Transcend Jon, some of the things that we have released is in terms of the acquisition price, and we paid $20 million for the tower. So we actually bought them for about 65,000 per tower.</p>
          <p>Tenancy is pretty consistent with the existing towers there. Believe they're in kind of the one, 1.3 range. So we feel very good. Having now the management team in place on ground and having the scale that we're building there, we'll be able to add on these kinds of portfolios, we think, on a pretty regular basis.</p>
          <p>So we feel very good about this particular transaction. It's not going to really move the dial, if you will, in terms of fourth quarter margin or fourth quarter revenue. It is just 325 towers. But again, I think it demonstrates the success that our team over there is having.</p>
          <p>And with regards to where we'll be looking at portfolios, we believe that we're going to be adding portfolios in all of our markets. Clearly, Brazil and India are kind of low hanging fruit for us, if you will. Right now, we think we're in a good position to add towers there, and we've had great success. And between those three markets, international markets, I think we have just about over 6,000 towers. So we've had great success there over the last couple of years. But we're very focused on adding towers in the United States, as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In Brazil and India, do you find these are competitive bidding situations or not the case?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we've done, Jonathan, is establish a position, I think, in both those countries that is &#x2013; from a business model perspective, at least &#x2013; the leading tower company in each of those countries. And so we do get an opportunity to do some negotiated transactions along the way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on the outdoor DAS assets, I know that this is kind of nit-picky, but you eliminated the word DAS from your CapEx breakdown. Doesn't look like you've expanded that in the recent past. Is it less likely to see new investment in that in that particular area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we're still on track, Jonathan. It's a long-cycle product. I think for those that understand it, you know that there are permits, rights of way, licenses, et cetera, that you need to get. And the design and sales process to the carrier is pretty long, too. So we're investing in it. We've always said that it's a niche product &#x2013; that, like our indoor DAS, it's a nice round-out to our total solution. We're still investing in it, and it's going to be modest, as we've always said we think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then finally on the question of 2010, I understand your position about not giving quantitative guidance, but anything you can share qualitatively about the outlook for leasing growth. Does it look like it might be roughly comparable to 2009? Or would you expect any meaningful difference?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I mean, we expect the leasing environment in 2010 to be at least as strong as it was in 2009, Jonathan. And what we'd like to do is have a more accurate picture of merger and acquisition activities that we're working on, that may or may not happen the first part of the year. Also currency &#x2013; we'd want to have the most up-to-date currency to be able to incorporate into the guidance, as far as FX rates. And those are the reasons, along with our customers budgets being more available and stable, that we're going to do this in the first quarter like most other companies do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jason Armstrong with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. A couple of questions.</p>
          <p>First on just on the key customer risk you had in Mexico around some liquidity fears. Can you update us there, and maybe talk about the flow of cash payments, if that's started again?</p>
          <p>And then second, just on core growth, you guys mentioned 9.5% last quarter. That's up to 10.3% this quarter. I'm just wondering, can you step us through how much including the XCEL acquisition for a full quarter sort of contributed to that uptick? And maybe take us back to a same tower growth type metric if you can, and how that's been trending? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Hey, Jason. With regards to Iusacell, I think they're making great progress down in Mexico. They're staying current on all of their recent business that we've done with them. We did not add any additional bad debt to them in the third quarter. So we feel good about where they are, and they are paying in full. And we anticipate that going forward.</p>
          <p>With regards to core growth, I think if you look at our core growth over the last several quarters, it has been &#x2013; it ranges in the 9.5 to kind of 10.5% range. So I don't think that there are really any surprises. Yes, there was a little bit of an uptick in this particular quarter, perhaps, from second quarter, from more of the impact of the &#x2013; perhaps the full impact of the India operation. India represents about 2% of our total revenue.</p>
          <p>I think in terms of kind of same tower growth, it's consistent with where we've seen it over the last few quarters. So I think as Jim pointed out, we feel very good about getting into the fourth quarter and ending the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mike McCormack with J.P. Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Thanks. Just a couple things on the demand side.</p>
          <p>Are you guys seeing &#x2013; obviously Sprint doing a lot more on the Boost Unlimited subs. Any significant change going on the iDEN network, now that they're got sort of positive net subscriber adds on that network?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, Jim, your comment about HSPA Plus and some of the things that T-Mobile is doing there, and AT&amp;T is doing it as well &#x2013; is there anything significant for the Tower Companies, or is that more of a software upgrade?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Mike. On the Boost product, it's been successful for Sprint Nextel, we're happy to see that.</p>
          <p>I think it's burdening the legacy iDEN network a bit, especially in larger population centers in the country. And Sprint Nextel themselves announced that they were going to deploy some additional sites in the iDEN network to take care of those questions and issues. So we expect that to happen in 2010, but it will be, again, modest in the context of what a typical national carrier would do in a typical year. So it won't be the full 2,000/2,500 site kind of number probably at Sprint. But it will be a lot more meaningful than it was in 2009, which was de minimis.</p>
          <p>On the HSPA Plus, that's a UMTS upgrade that enables sort of an interim speed improvement between 3G and 4G. And the way we look at all those speed and broadband expansions, Mike, is that, yes, there are some amendments up front on some sites. Some of those amendments have revenues associated, some don't. But as those networks begin to be used by subscribers and filled up, then you end up having plenty of value amendments, and you're going to end up with cell splitting along the way as well.</p>
          <p>So as more subscribers use more bandwidth, due in part to these sorts of upgrades, we think that there'll be additional length and strength to our demand for Tower space out in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ric Prentiss with Raymond James</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Ric.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple questions for you. Maybe a follow up on David's question earlier, Tom, on the '09 reaffirmation.</p>
          <p>If we think about it, I think you said you're at 75% of your midpoint through three quarters of the year. Obviously faced a lot of FX headwind earlier in the year as well. As we look to the last two months of the year, how would you kind of frame as far as what would it take to hit the low end of your guidance? What would have to happen to hit the mid or the high end? Just kind of frame it for us as far as what the wildcards out there for what is a very wide range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ric, you want me to get into modeling questions, do you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, and 2011 depreciation and tax rate. Kind of what it would take, because it is a wide range, and FX has improved significantly over the last couple of months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When &#x2013; and back to David's question before. When I'm looking at our guidance and our midpoint, I'm not including the revenue associated with the &#x2013; this one-time event, okay?</p>
          <p>So we've had &#x2013; as we've said all along, we've had strong activity in the second half of the year. It was actually stronger than the first half activity &#x2013; from the first half of the year, in terms of signed activity. And we think that's going to provide us a strong basis going into the fourth quarter of 2009 and into 2010.</p>
          <p>So I don't want to get into the modeling issues here with you, Ric, but as I said before, we're reaffirming our outlook. We feel very good about how we're going to end the year on a very strong note. And this one-time event, even when we looked at the 10.3%, we backed out the effect of that one-time event, just to give you kind of the transparency in terms of what the real core growth of the business is.</p>
          <p>So when I'm looking at midpoints and looking at 75%, I'm not including the effect, if you will, of that one particular event.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's good to know, because it kind of &#x2013; I think people were worried that you're including that one-time in there to kind of be achieving the guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. And I specifically backed it out to give you a sense of really what our real core growth is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay, that's good. And then on the balance sheet side, obviously some very significant movement. Finally investment grade does mean investment rates. As you look out, I think, Jim and Tom, you both talked about further laddering, first steps.</p>
          <p>Can you walk us through, first, how much cash do you need to keep on hand on this business? As you look at your stock buyback program, it dropped back to I think $1 million in October so far versus a much faster pace. How do you look at managing the cash balance? How do you look at approaching the debt markets as far as changing out some further financings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ric, it's Jim. When you've got the kind of cash flow generation the business provides, and you've also got a very active kind of M&amp;A initiative going on, more or less around the world, there's no one number for what the sort of the minimum or required cash need is in a given month or quarter. We're actually managing that dynamically based on the pipeline of M&amp;A activities that we have and what we think the capital markets are like sort of in that given quarter.</p>
          <p>So that cash number is going to fluctuate. And you can see it, and you have seen it, as you pointed out, in the share repurchase activity.</p>
          <p>So when we think we need to build cash for an M&amp;A set of opportunities, the share repurchase may dip downward as far as the rate. If we've got more cash than we need to do what is in the pipeline, you'll see us turn the rate back up.</p>
          <p>So it's a pretty simple mechanism, if you will, and it's all enabled by the fact that the business throws off significant cash flows, and that we've got lots of opportunities out there that we're looking at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the refinancing aspect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We obviously don't have to do any refinancing. We're in a nice position from that perspective.</p>
          <p>We'll continue to take a look at some of those obligations that we have out in the 2012, 2014 time to see what makes sense. But the most significant items that we really wanted to refinance were the ones that we already have, the ones that matured in 2012, which is this last one that we just called, which is that $500 million.</p>
          <p>So we think we've done a lot of work on the balance sheet to continue to kick out the tenders, and we'll continue to monitor to see how we want to handle the 2012 and 2014. But there's nothing that we have to do right now relative to those maturities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And I'll just echo that it was a pretty impressive rate. It definitely opened a lot of eyes. So job well done on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ric.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Simon Flannery with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Good morning. Just to clarify on the broadcast customer, Tom, what sort of size impact is that on Q4? Is it the amount of revenues that they took? And any other commentary on other expected churn.</p>
          <p>And then I think you referenced briefly looking at your options, once your NOLs expire. Can you just give us an update on timing and thoughts about REIT status, and what you need to do to prep for that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Simon. Relative to the one broadcast customer, it's minimal in the fourth quarter. So I wouldn't expect it to have any impact at all, really &#x2013; significant impact at all in the fourth quarter. So -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to add, Tom, that was a very long-term buy out of a broadcast contract, Simon, and you know that those go for many, many years into the future. So when you take it on a monthly, quarterly basis it's not going to affect materially the churn rate or the revenues of the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And relative to the NOLs, Simon, as I've said before, we're looking to, given current course and speed, probably utilize the NOLs in the 2012, 2013 timeframe. So we do have some runway, if you will, in terms of being able to look at our various options. But we are spending a tremendous amount of time internally now working with a number of different advisors on what our options are, what our strategies are, and what our best path forward is. And when we land on what that best path forward is, we will obviously let you know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Does the growing international presence complicate that, or can you work through that? Does it make it harder for the company -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we believe we can work through that, on a number of different structures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jonathan Schildkraut with Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you for taking the questions. In your prepared remarks and in the presentation, you highlighted the size of the backlog. I was wondering if you could compare that to maybe some prior periods to give us a sense of where it stands versus kind of historical activity.</p>
          <p>And I was also wondering if you can give us a sense as to some of the application activity in the quarter.</p>
          <p>And then I'd like to ask one question on India following that. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I can take the first question. Just in terms of the backlog, I believe if I go back and take a look about 12 months ago, it's up about $0.5 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So a sizable increase in terms of year-over-year activity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the application front, Jonathan, we're seeing a nice, healthy increase in the second half of the year. Many of you know how our business process works, which is customers putting applications for sites &#x2013; either new sites or upgrades. Those can take from 60 to 90 days to get fully completed and converted into a commenced contract, which then begins to bill revenue.</p>
          <p>And so we have a very positive trend of signings in the second half of this year, which gives us some good confidence into what we're going to see as far as commencements and billings in 2010. So it's a pretty good picture right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. In terms of India, I just had a couple of questions here. You just finished this recent acquisition. And I was wondering, just in sense of how disciplined you've been in that market, if there have been M&amp;A opportunities that you guys have passed on or bid on that have gone to other people, that just were kind of outside of your required return rates.</p>
          <p>And then further along in that market, we've read a lot about some power-sharing agreements amongst some of the larger providers in the Indian market, and I'm wondering how you view those from a competitive perspective, and whether those are maybe not in circles that you are, or whether they are in fact competitive. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Jonathan. As in all the markets we've participated in over the last sort of seven, eight years I've been here, we win some deals and we've lost some deals, or some of the deals didn't trade at all, like the T-Mobile divestiture in the U.S. that didn't happen about two years ago.</p>
          <p>So, sure, the answer is we've been in situations where others may have outbid us even in India. So that that has in fact happened. But we stick to our price discipline. And we also have the long view that sometimes these things come back around. So we're not going to overpay on the first iteration. We may never see it again, but we may see it in a second iteration at a price we like.</p>
          <p>So that's how we approach it. We're going to keep the discipline in India as we have in other places.</p>
          <p>There is some tower sharing agreements in India. There are also some in other markets that we operate in. They're a portion of the site leasing traffic, if you will, in a number of markets. But there's still plenty of room, including in India, for the kind of business that we conduct, and we think we're going to be very successful there, as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for taking the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Phillip Cusick with Macquarie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Phil Cusick from Macquarie. While recognizing you're not giving 2010 guidance, I wonder if you can help us think about how you look at both the 4G builds both from Clearwire and from Verizon as it does amendments through next year? Can you help us get an idea of sort of what you're expecting over the next 12 months on them?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure, Phil. It's Jim. On the Clearwire front, the application stream that I mentioned earlier is significantly benefited by Clearwire in the back half of 2009 in our company. And so we do expect that they'll have meaningful commencements in 2010. They'll be a material new business customer for us for billings next year. And when we pull the guidance together in detail and provide it to you all in the first quarter, they'll be included in that.</p>
          <p>Verizon is active on a number of fronts, including just building out its normal couple thousand sites a year network plan. And the 4G that goes with it. Again, some of those 4G amendments on an existing network, like Verizon has, have revenues associated with those, and some can be included within the rights that are already on that tower. So we will see some applications, and we have, for Verizon LTE. Many of them have some revenue that go along with them, and that's happening now. But it's not necessarily at the game changer level yet.</p>
          <p>And again, Phil, as I said earlier, what's encouraging for us is we view the long-term aspect of our business is every carrier that steps up to 4G &#x2013; and we've basically talked to almost all of them today &#x2013; over the next two, three, four years is going to need to invest in its network in a material way. And that's going to lengthen our opportunities.</p>
          <p>So it's applications in the short term and we think important in the long term with 4G in terms of Verizon and others that have existing networks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Gray Powell with Wells Fargo Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Thanks for taking the questions. I just have a few.</p>
          <p>I know you touched on this already, but can you just kind of talk about what you're seeing in terms of booking trends in Q3 versus Q2 and possibly quantify some of this increase that you're seeing in the second half? And then what do you expect to see in terms of bookings in Q4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Gray. I mean if you take a look and as we've said the third quarter signed and actually commenced business, it's been picking up as we said.</p>
          <p>I mean I think it's consistent with how the carriers have actually been talking about their build-out plans throughout the year. Q3 was I think a very solid quarter for us in terms of signed and commence new business, and we expect actually pick that up further into Q4, as Jim was saying, which really reflects some of the new Clearwire activities.</p>
          <p>So I think we're running on a very positive track, and I think as I said before, we're really positioned well as we go into 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And switching subjects, can you just tell us what local currency revenue growth in Mexico and Brazil are tracking towards in 2009? And then with the spectrum auction in Mexico coming up, how would you expect that to impact 2010 trends?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hey, Gray, it's Jim. Together Mexico and Brazil have been growing in 2009 about on pace with the total company, on pace with the U.S. growth rate. And Mexico being a little lighter than normal and Brazil being a little heavier than normal, just based on the timing of auctions and new spectrum and new entrants in each of those countries.</p>
          <p>So for 2010, again not having the quantitative guidance here quite yet, but kind of a qualitative sense would be, together, Latin America will be around the same or potentially a shade better if we get a Mexican spectrum auction in the first part of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just a last question. Redevelopment CapEx moved lower this year after heightened levels of spending in 2008. How should we expect that to trend going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we should &#x2013; we're not giving guidance here -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; but I think you should be thinking about that on &#x2013; consistently with how we've been spending in the 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And remember, Gray, we had a project last year in 2008 with one of our Latin American customers where we committed to do some redevelopment specifically to their needs, and the lease rates were higher that went along with that. That program's wrapped up. And so, as Tom said, redevelopment in the future is going to look a lot more like it did in the back half of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That makes sense. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have time for one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our last question comes from the line of Michael Rollins with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Two follow-up questions. Firstly, just to go back to guidance.</p>
          <p>I realize there's already been a number of questions on it, but for '09, if you go back to the disclosures in the 2Q press release, you were estimating an impact from foreign exchange rates of a negative two percentage points at the mid-point of guidance. Can you give us some sense to where that is today, based on the way FX rates have moved to date?</p>
          <p>And then the second question that I have is just on revenue churn. Can you give us a sense of how revenue churn has been moving through your model? And is there anything that you see, any kind of activities that you see, that could pick up that revenue churn over the next 12 months? Or things that have happened in the past that you don't think will happen next year, that can actually reduce that rate of revenue churn? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think with regards to the FX, there was a &#x2013; on a sequential basis, there was actually a bit of a pick-up with &#x2013; relative to FX. Still, on a year over year basis, though, Michael, I think we're still pretty consistent with where we were back in the second quarter release. So I don't think there's any impact, and there's obviously no impact to kind of the core growth.</p>
          <p>And relative to churn, we still are obviously underneath the 2% level. What you may see &#x2013; and again, this is not guidance &#x2013; but what you may see going forward into 2010 is the delay in the &#x2013; some of the broadcast churn that occurred perhaps later in the year benefiting us, than we had thought, just because of the delay in the spectrum itself coming off.</p>
          <p>So you may see a bit of a pick-up on a year over year basis relative to the broadcast churn in 2010. But again, not significant, but just in response to your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Mike, if you just get a chance later, if you refer back to Page Six on the presentation that's on the website, the Q3 '09 impact of that FX was a negative 2.1. So there's a quarter left, and you can make an estimate on what you think it might be in the fourth quarter. But as Tom said, it's pretty consistent in the third quarter from what we said we thought would happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Well, thank you very much for taking time to listen to us, and we look forward to reporting results for the fourth quarter in a couple of months.</p>
          <p>Have a great day everybody. Good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's American Tower Third Quarter 2009 Earnings Call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>