<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1327395" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-07-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2866</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Rizwan Ali, Senior Latin America Telecom Analyst, Deutsche Bank</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Daniel Hajj Aboumrad, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Carlos Jos&#xE9; Garc&#xED;a Moreno Elizondo, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Ric Prentiss</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Daniel Aboumrad</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Michel Morin</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Tom&#xE1;s Lajous</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Tomas Tom&#xE1;s</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep">Carlos Moreno</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Gray Powell</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Mauricio Fernandes</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Andrew Campbell</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Walter Piecyk</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Will Millner</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Andr&#xE9;s Mora</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Christopher King</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Verena Wachnitz</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Richard Dineen</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="corprep">Carlos Elizondo</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst">Gilbert Alexander</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst">Miguel Garcia</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the America Movil 2Q Results Conference call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to introduce your host for today's conference Mr. Rizwan Ali, Senior Latin America Telecom Analyst at Deutsche Bank. You may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and good afternoon to those in Europe. It's a pleasure for us to host America Movil's second quarter 2010 conference call. Representing the company today is Mr. Daniel Hajj, the CEO; Mr. Carlos Garcia Moreno, the CFO; and Daniela Lecuona, the IR Manager.</p>
          <p>And with this, I'll ask Mr. Hajj to begin his presentation after which we'll have a Q&amp;A session. Daniel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rizwan. Good morning, everybody. Thank you for being in America Movil second quarter results conference call. And I am going to ask Carlos to give us a brief summary of the results. Carlos?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Daniel. Thank you, Rizwan for hosting the call. Good morning, everyone. So before getting into the results of our operations, I would like to start by saying that we closed last month our tender offers for Carso Global Telecom and Telmex International. We received 94.6% of historical CBT in exchange for 7.1 billion America Movil shares and 33% of TII stock which we paid for with a combination of AMX shares and cash, it was 1.3 billion AMX shares and $2.1 billion of cash.</p>
          <p>As of last week, we owned 99.9% of CGT's stock and directly or indirectly 59.4% of the stock of Telmex and 94.6% of the stock of TII. Beginning July 1, we will consolidate both entities in our financial statements.</p>
          <p>With the Latin American and U.S. economies expanding throughout the second quarter, subscribers' growth continued turn, providing support to that of revenues and EBITDA. We are at 4.9 million subs in the quarter; 31% more than in the year before. Brazil and Mexico led the way with 1.3 and 1.0 million subs, respectively, followed by Argentina and the U.S. with approximately 500,000 each.</p>
          <p>In the majority of our operations, postpaid subscribers kept on growing more rapidly than prepaid. In the six months through June, we obtained 10.3 million users to close the month with 211 million subs, 11% more than the year before. Together with our fixed lines and those of our new subsidiaries, we had a total of 259 million accesses at the end of the semester, including 27 million telephone lines, 12 million broadband accesses, and 8.7 million LA Vision subscribers.</p>
          <p>Service revenues expanded everywhere, with one minor exception, as both revenues, cyclical in nature in Questar, a slightly faster pace than GDP on average. And data revenues continued to show remarkable growth in various countries, even doubling year-on-year in some of them. Equipment revenues rose across-the-board. Revenues were up 11.9% from a year before, to 100.9 billion pesos, with service revenues expanding 10.8%, driven by data revenues, that shared of 41.6%.</p>
          <p>Through June, revenues increased 10.9% and service revenues 10.0%. EBITDA came in at 42 billion pesos. It was off 9.4%in annual terms with EBITDA margin declining only slightly from the prior year &#x2013; in spite of the faster pace of subscriber growth. In Mexico and South America margins expanded everywhere, rising nearly 10 points in Peru and almost six points in Argentina. In the first six months, EBITDA totaled 84.3 billion pesos having grown in line with revenues.</p>
          <p>At a 5.8% annual growth rate, operating profits rose less than EBITDA because of faster depreciation charges mainly in Brazil. They totaled 28.9 billion pesos in the quarter and helped bring about a net profit of 18.7 billion pesos. The latter was more than the previous year's mostly on account of the extraordinary and significant foreign exchange gains obtained in second quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Our net debt totaled 71.6 billion pesos in June. It was 11.9 billion pesos lower than in December. Even after allowing for the cash costs as associated with the acquisition of TII stock was 136.8 billion pesos. Accrued capital expenditures totaled 14.8 billion pesos and share buybacks 5.5 billion pesos.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditures are in line with the project for a year of approximately 45 billion pesos. We ended June with ample liquidity obtained partly to fund the purchase of TII stock, as you will recall, TII investors who had elected to be paid fully in cash.</p>
          <p>And partly to actively manage the liabilities of the new subsidiaries with a view to taking advantage of funding opportunities in the debt capital markets and improving its debt profile in terms of maturities and capital structure.</p>
          <p>With that I would like to open the floor for Q&amp;A. And thanks, Rizwan for taking the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Let me just start the Q&amp;A session with two questions, and then we'll open it up for further questions. Daniel, my first question was that we have seen churn in most of your markets at least large majority of markets increase. At the same time, we saw pretty significant growth on the postpaid side of the business as versus prepaid. So I'm wondering whether the increase in churn is related to you converting your high-end prepaid customers into postpaid or is there any other reason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a very good question. I think there are two reasons. Second quarter is important because in terms of churn because there is a lot of people who change their prepaid phone in maybe Christmas, January there is big sales and part of that is -- reflects in second quarter. The second thing that is very important is that we're doing a big effort to make our prepaid subscriber, the good prepaid subscriber try to upgrade to our postpaid plan. So that's mainly what we are doing in all the countries and we're having a good success doing that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and operator, we'll start the Q&amp;A session. And I will request all the participants to please restrict yourself to only two questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Thank you. Our first question comes from Ric Prentiss of Raymond James. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Two questions, first, with the Mexican spectrum auctions done, maybe if you could update us about your thoughts on the auction and your plans there to roll out further service. And then any new licenses, opportunities, Costa Rica or any other opportunities you might be looking at or are interested in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Mexican spectrum end, one part, the 1900 mega last week and beginning of this week it ends the 1.7/2.1. Telcel gained 20 megahertz in all the regions, plus 10 megahertz in three regions more. And with that, I think that we can be prepared to give the four generation data. So we are planning -- we are not exactly &#x2013; we don't know exactly when, but we are reviewing when that it would be good for Telcel to start pooling that infrastructure. I think that's very good for us, because give us the alternative to increase in the data side of our business. That is the one that is growing a lot. Other places with the spectrum where we are not reviewing, I think, we are really taking care that in other countries where we operate, we're checking when does the governments are going to auction the 4G, let's say the LTE license. And we're really interested in getting those licenses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then in the U.S. big quarter for Straight Talk, it looked like. Margins are still a little bit light. What kind of scale do you need with the Straight Talk product to get the margins back up into the teens in the United States?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the Straight Talk has been a excellent product. As the TracFone service revenue has increased substantially over 59% along with its ARPU 10 to 12, due to Straight Talk. I think it's a very good plan. We are growing a lot mostly of our growth. Last year, the growth that we have used to be in SafeLink that it's other segment of the market, it's other product and this year we are growing. I think we expect to continue to see good growth for the revenues and subscriber this year, and we also expect to see negative EBITDA compares as we continue to build the new business that is the Straight Talk. But I think this product is an excellent product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Michel Morin of Barclays Capital. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I just wanted to expand a little bit on TracFone and specifically the net apps were a little bit weaker than I think most people were expecting. And I think that we saw negative resale net apps at AT&amp;T. So I was wondering if you could elaborate as to whether or not that's a direct relationship there in terms of what we saw at AT&amp;T impacting you and whether or not that has been resolved now. And I guess tied to that, if perhaps the mix shift towards more Straight Talk during the quarter might have been the reason for the margin being weaker perhaps than what some people were expecting in the U.S. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, when you compare last year against this year's, there are two different products. The first product was SafeLink. That is a total different market. That's a product that the ARPU is around $10. And today, we are having this new product that is a Straight Talk -- sorry, this SafeLink product we are in almost all the states in the United States and it's a little bit saturated right now. It's for some type of people and it's a little bit saturated at this moment. The other one that we are doing today is Straight Talk, that it's a product that has a higher ARPU, that use more minutes. And that is being very good in the market, and that's what you could see in TracFone. I don't know exactly what were the net apps on AT&amp;T. What I can tell you is, that we are working with all the vendors, mainly AT&amp;T and Verizon with all the carriers and that our business is doing good. Now that's what I can tell you about TracFone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Daniel, if I may, with a separate question, I think Nokia is about to launch a new handset that handles dual SIM cards. It's called the C1. Have you made any plans to sell that handset? And how do you think that might impact the markets to have dual SIM card handsets sold by a major vendor like Nokia in a market like Brazil in particular where there are multiple SIM cards?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't know exactly about that phone. It's new for me and I'm going take a look. I don't think that it's good for a lot of customers. But I really need to take a closer look to see if they're going to impact or it's going to favor our -- depending on the market, it's going to impact or favor to some of the customers and some of our companies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Daniel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Tom&#xE1;s Lajous of UBS. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, gentlemen. Thank you very much for the call. I think it would be helpful if you could talk a little bit about Brazil. The ARPU was kind of low. Margin was down vis-&#xE0;-vis the previous quarter. If you can tell us a little bit about what's going on there. And how you think this can get better now that you will be integrating with your other businesses in Brazil in terms of how that integration can help the Brazil mobile business. So that'll be the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Talking a little bit about Brazil, well, I think first of all the integration with Embratel is going to be very helpful for us. It's going to help us to grow more rapidly the infrastructure so we can get more data. And that will give us a better ARPU and better customer. We're working hard. We're doing good in the market, but I think we could do much better with the quality of customers that are getting in our network.</p>
          <p>So we are being working on that and I think we can have some better results of which -- of what type of customers are coming to Claro. And I think we need to work on that. It's going to help a lot, all of the infrastructure that we have with Embratel and that will help a lot to develop more quickly all the data in some of the places in Brazil that we are not doing right now data. So I think that will help a lot.</p>
          <p>Other is our service revenue in Brazil growth, 4.3%. Our malls are growing 28%, but still the market is being very competitive and the price per minute has been reduced 33%. So that's what is happening a little bit on Brazil. Also, it's very important when you compare ARPUs, that our ARPU in Claro doesn't have the long distance. Remember that we don't have long distance and we do our long distance through Embratel. And I think that's one of the reasons why you see that our ARPU is a little bit lower than other ARPUs so &#x2013; because we don't have the long distance inside our ARPU.</p>
          <p>But as I'm saying, we are also working to get better quality of customers in Brazil. So that's mainly what we are doing, and I think with the Embratel integrations we're going to have a much better network in Brazil to get the data, because Brazil is growing very fast on data.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Daniel. And the other question, I don't know if it's for you or for Carlos, but if you guys can talk a little bit about sort of the liquidity, funding, financing, what happens now in terms of your debt, the TII debt, the Telmex debt and how that can affect distributions to shareholders, either buybacks or dividends?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Carlos?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think, Tom&#xE1;s, that the distributions are very much dependant on the basis of what is the capital structure we want to have. I think that we have talked to you and the market about our wanting to stay close to one times net debt to EBITDA. I don't think that we have changed that. So the distribution should flow from &#x2013; given that premise, okay. I think that one thing that is clear is that with the new subsidiaries, we're also getting some flexibility in terms of our capacity to provide new distributions. That is basically because of the type of the taxes they &#x2013; probably some customers they have already been paying taxes. And they have not represented any solution to shareholders in the past.</p>
          <p>So other than that, Tom&#xE1;s, basically, what we did is, what I said in the call. We wanted to take advantage of good conditions in the market, the fixed income investors have liked very much the story of the consolidation of America Movil. And we were able to secure very good financings, medium and long-terms. And we expect that all our subsidiaries should take advantage of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Rizwan. Thank, Daniel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Gray Powell from Wells Fargo. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thanks for taking the questions. I just had a couple of quick once. On your Q2 post-paid subscriber growth in Mexico, can you roughly say how much of that was attributable to wireless broadband? And then longer term, what do you think the overall opportunity is for wireless broadband penetration in your region?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we are not disclosing those numbers. We are not disclosing which of the customers are with a phone plus plan, a broadband plan. And they are using the broadband through the phone. And we are not disclosing also, which once are through the computer. So but I can tell you that in both cases, we are growing good and our data is growing a lot in Mexico.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just a second question, you saw a pretty good uptick in usage in Mexico. ARPU is slightly improved there this quarter as well. Can you just talk about the main drivers in Q2? And how should -- we should &#x2013; how we should think about those trends over the next six to 12 months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that in terms of minutes of use the, still prices are going down. We have a very competitive market and when prices are going down, in prepaid and in postpaid people are using more, and that means that you have more minutes of use. Second is that we are moving, as we are seeing a lot prepaid customers to postpaid customers and these postpaid customers are using also more. And there I think the economics are being a little bit more, are being better. So also help out that people spend a little bit more money and use more the phone. So I think those are the three things that you could see in the second quarter in Mexico.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Autumn Grey of Barclays Capital. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It is already answered. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Riznio Barned of Merrill Lynch. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's actually Mauricio Fernandes, a couple of questions, Daniel, if I may. One is, why did the margins fall sequentially relative to the first quarter on a consolidated basis if the net additions were actually slightly lower, but let's call it the same?</p>
          <p>And secondly, specifically in Central America, we noticed a significant decline in EBITDA margin. I was just wondering if that was related to a one-off effect because net additions that were higher in the quarter relative to the first shouldn't be enough to explain the whole margin decline in Central America. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first the EBITDA margin fell a little bit in the second quarter because we're &#x2013; our cost of service grew a little bit and that means that &#x2013; the places where we grow it a little bit in Brazil, maybe Colombia, a little bit also in TracFone. So TracFone is because we are having much higher, Straight Talk customers are a high-end customer. So we need to spend a little bit more of money to get this type of customer. It was a little bit more of SoftCity also. They are all very Brazil and the other places and mainly in Latin America we're doing good investments in the data in all around backbone/backhaul and a little bit also on IT. So that &#x2013; when you do the investments and you are not using and you don't have a big use of this infrastructure then your cost gets a little bit higher. But I think with the integration of Telmex International and with more and more usage that we're going to have in data in the next years I think on the months and years then I think this is going to be a very good investment. The second, in Central America, I think in Central America, we're going much better. I think our growth, in terms of subscribers are may be two times the what we used to have. And we have a non-cash provision related to our investment in Honduras, and I think we're reviewing that. That's why we only make the provision, but it's a non-cash provision and I think in &#x2013; it's around 25 to $30 million what we put. So if you take out that, you are doing more or less the same or a little bit better than what we used to do in terms of the EBITDA. So that's mainly what is happening in Central America. I think we're doing much better in the market. We are growing in all the segments; we are growing in broadband; we're growing in wireless broadband, we're growing in prepaid, in postpaid, in also TV, satellite and cable. So I think in Central America we're doing a good job. I feel comfortable with the results in Central America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Andrew Campbell of Credit Suisse. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, we are not following you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, you have a bad connection.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I don't know, Carlos if you hear him.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, he's breaking up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Andy but you have a bad connection.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from Walter Piecyk of BTIG. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. Hey, Daniel. Can you -- I mean, you talk a lot about data. I know you don't want to give out some of the numbers I think on the previous question, but can you just talk about generally in Latin America how you see &#x2013; where do you see the biggest success opportunities in data? Is it going to be PC cards? Is it going to be smartphones? And then if it is smartphones, is it reasonable to think that with the prepaid base in Latin America given that you can't really subsidize that prepaid base that heavily that the adoption of things like iPhones or some of these new Android that are out by HPC and Motorola can be successful? Or does it really have to be more mid-range or low-end products like a BlackBerry or that others would be selling?</p>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're interested in all the markets. In the PC cards, we're really interested. I think, we have a good opportunity in all Latin America, because still broadband penetration is not so high, and we have a good opportunity in that place. In the other one, I think, also that in all our postpaid base, we're going to do an effort to sell them a data plan. I think that's one of the things that we want to do is that all our customers will have a data plan. In the other side prices of smartphones are falling very rapidly, very quickly. And I think more and more people are going to use the smartphones and they are going to use data.</p>
          <p>Also in prepaid, I think, you don't have to have a plan, a data plan to use data or to go browsing or to use chat or to do, go to internet. So also in prepaid there is going to be a lot of people who are going to use their phones to -- and their prepaid phones to use data and we're happy with that. A lot of the usage, we are selling prepaid cards on the PC cards, data also. So I think prepaid is going to be also very interesting for all the young people that they want to use maybe one or two days of data or maybe they are not heavy users but they are going to use data a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then my second question is just every year in the United States through TracFone, you've had something new whether it's NET10 or Assurance or Straight Talk. What's the plan for this year as far as a new service offering in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for this year the plan is still I think we have a Straight Talk plan, and it's a very good program, and we're focusing on that. We don't have nothing right now for the U.S. What we have is to make Straight Talk very successful, and that a lot of people in the U.S. will have that plan. It's what we're focusing on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Will Millner of Arete Research. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just a question on Mexico and I guess future levels of competition there. Just the recent award of the 1700 megahertz spectrum from Nextel-Televisa, does that come with any regulatory conditions that might speed up the launch of their 3G services? And specifically, I guess I'm thinking about national roaming agreement or potentially site sharing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think -- I'm not so sure but I think what Nextel-Televisa get was not the 1900. It was the 1.7/2.1 frequency. So in 1900 I think they don't have a lot of spectrum. So I'm not so sure what they are going to do. We have big competition in Mexico. If there's going to be a new entrant in the market, well, we need to give a better service, a better quality, and to have much covered apps, to have a lot of capacity on data and that's what we're doing to prepare for new competition. In Mexico there's big competition, it's Telefonica, it's Iusacell, with Unefon, it's Nextel and it's also -- there's a new one that it's coming or there is Televisa joining Nextel. Well, what we need to do is what we do in all the other countries, that is prepare with good branding, good service, covered apps, quality, good phones, good network. So that's mainly what we are focusing on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, my second question, just on the future synergies from the group reorganization, I know you've not give any quantification so far, but it was very clear that Telefonica expected to gain significant tax synergy for emerging Telesp and Vivo in Brazil. And do you think you can create tax assets in a restructuring of Embratel and Claro that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that Claro and Embratel will do an excellent synergy. We don't give any number because we really think that the big synergies -- the big synergies -- Telmex International was running very efficient. America Movil was being running very efficient. So I think that really the efficiencies all in the CapEx, let's say, in the CapEx for the next year. So we're going to create one network where we're going to get all the services and that's going to save us a lot of money on CapEx, a lot of money on cost. Second is that we have distribution channel. They have distribution channel so in terms of the commercial type, they are going to help us a lot selling our products and we're going to help them to sell their product. So if we do that I think the synergies would be excellent, so in terms of IT also would be very important so I think there's no doubt that Telmex International and America Movil will make a very good combination in Latin America. In terms of commercial, in terms of networks, in terms of CapEx, in terms of technology so I think that you are going to see that in the next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I guess just specifically, you're not contemplating tax restructuring of Embratel and Claro?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A tax? Well I think, we're not disclosing that but also, I think in the tax and fiscal, we will be selling a lot of products between the companies so maybe there is also some tax synergies. We're evaluating that. We are not having the decision today. We need to do a lot of things in each of the countries. But also I think, in that would be a something.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Andr&#xE9;s Medina Mora of GBM. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you, Carlos and Daniel. My question is regarding postpaid subscribers in Brazil. We have seen this trend not as -- not growing as fast as in other countries. What should we expect going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I told you, is I think we need to do more in the market in Brazil. We need to have better customers in Claro and we're working on that. We are &#x2013; I think the data network will help us because we're going to sell the smartphones. We're going to sell more data plans, but we agree, we need to do more and better in postpaid with better, not only with postpaid to get the best customers in Brazil, and we're focusing on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And just one follow-up if I could, we have heard your previous guidance of subscribers around roughly 13.5 million subscribers. We have seen that number; I think it could be a little short now. Are you considering a revision of that guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think, you are right, that we are not making another budget. We're still reviewing that. But well, we have more than 10 million customers at the first six months, so the 13 or 14 million that we do I think we're going to be higher of 50 million, I think that's what our budget was, I think it's going to be higher than that. So but we haven't being review the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from James Starkman of Merrill Lynch. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I'm a retired Vice President of Merrill Lynch, and just an individual investor in America Movil. Basically, on a consolidated basis after the Telmex integration, what would be the per ADR, per share earnings have been pro forma for the current quarter? And consensus estimates by analysts was about $0.97 and as reported in billions, I couldn't find the per share figure on your Web site yet. Is that approximately what you earned for the quarter? And the consensus for the full year for most analysts was about 3 74 per ADR share, and about 4 29 for next year. Are you comfortable with those figures? And also had the Telmex consolidation taken place during this, the second quarter, what would the earnings have been?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Carlos, I don't know if you have the numbers because I don't have that number here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have the numbers and the reason we &#x2013; in order to have something that is really comparable, you need to have everything done on the IFRS. And as well as in America Movil, we already had moved towards IFRS. Neither TII nor Telmex have done that. In order to look at the specific profits and so on, we need to first move them over to IFRS which we intend to do in third quarter. So I think that giving you a number right now would be misleading in that it is really not comparable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. As reported did it work out to about $0.97 a share for the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have the numbers here with me. And as I was saying I don't think it makes sense add up things that I've done under different methodologies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, assuming it wasn't consolidated, which it was not, I'm just asking you for what the per share numbers worked out to for the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm sorry I don't have the numbers. If you want may be we can just do an exercise later after the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just a second question, after the consolidation of Telmex approximately what would be the revenues and projected profits from fixed line phones in the entire company versus the mobile phones?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again I don't want to give you numbers because we cannot add them up right now. We don't have the same methodologies. It really &#x2013; if you look at the pro forma for last year we still hadn't move over to IFRS. I think fixed-line telephony was in the range of 35 or 40, it was about 30%, it was 30%, fixed-line telephony was 30% of total revenues. Wireless voice was 50% of total revenues. And then data in fixed and data in wireless accounted for 10% of total revenues, sales revenues, pro forma for 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Right.  And &#x2013; all right. And you're quite optimistic about the second half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you optimistic about revenues and earnings growth for the second half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, we're still think that second half would be a good quarter, a good half like the first one in America Movil. And in Telmex International, I think we have a good opportunity in broadband. We have good opportunity in satellite business in TV, in fixed so I think it would be a good half, second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And lastly, the recent dividend was that just a one-time event or do you plan any kind of a quarterly distribution?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think Telmex is giving their dividend. We have &#x2013; America Movil have our own policy on the dividend and we're going to follow our policy in terms of dividend from buyback, no Carlos?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, exactly. We kind of &#x2013; I think I probably would provide our dividend payment in July and another one in November. Telmex is providing one in July.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, so you do expect another November dividend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's already been announced. That's not something that we're going to -- that's something that has been announced that we split into the dividend payment, with pay half in July and half in November.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you, okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Chris King of Stifel Nicolaus. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thank you. Just a quick question on Brazil, just wanted to talk about the potential impact of the rumored interconnection rate step-down that Anatel was discussing in Brazil of about 20% over both next year and the following year. Just was wondering if you do see that type of interconnection rate step-down in Brazil, how do you think that would play out with respect to the broader wireless market in Brazil in terms of pricing and minutes of use trends, as well as kind of a rough approximation of what it could do to your margins in Brazil over the next couple years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that in Brazil we're going to have a gradual reduction on the termination rates as we used to have it in all Latin America. So it's not going to be any different on what we have reductions in Mexico. We have reductions in Colombia, in Peru, in Chile, in Argentina. So I think in Brazil we're also going to have the reductions on termination rates. And I think what you are going to see in Brazil is exactly what you see in the rest of Latin America. There's going to be reduction. There's going to be more usage, more traffic and that will compensate the reduction on the termination rates. That's why this has been happening all around Latin America, I think all around the world and that's exactly what is going to happen in Brazil. Of course, I think we're expecting a reduction on the termination rates. I don't know exactly for how long and how big are going to be the reductions, but we are thinking that there is going to be some reductions in the termination rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Verena Wachnitz of T. Rowe Price. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. I wanted to ask you a quick question on data, data basically is now 22% of ARPU across the board. Where do you see that going over the next few years? I think the average for developed market is 32%. Do you think Latin America can go to that level, or it can get even to higher levels given as you mentioned before the low broadband penetration? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you can compare that to other countries, I think maybe in Japan is around 40% of their revenues. So I don't know exactly when we're going to get that, but I am sure that a big part of our revenues are going to come from data. I don't know the speed in how many years, but of course, we're going to reach 40% as other countries are getting right now. Now, it's exactly as penetration, penetration in some places were 100% when we use to be 60. Right now, we are more than 100% in that. So I don't think there is going to be any difference on that. In some countries we have &#x2013; well the average of America Movil today is 23. So that means that in some countries we have less than 40 &#x2013; less than the 20 and in other ones we have higher than 20.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Richard Dineen of HSBC. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Just maybe touching on the Argentina, Paraguay, Uruguay group, where your margins are doing very well there, I was just wondering how to model those going out. Do you think they're going to start to flatten maybe in the mid-40s or do you think that can go higher over the next couple of years? And secondly just on margins also in Brazil, just, they've obviously been a little bit volatile, just wondering if you might be able to give us some guidance for remaining quarters. It looks like you did I guess 29% or so in H1 average. Is that kind of sensible figure to plug in as an average for H2 and thus the full year? So anything on either of those would be great? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First on Argentina we have very good margins I think, what we were doing that is a lot of the revenue that it's come and goes directly to EBITDA, because we do all the CapEx and all the investments that we've need to do and the way we are controlling costs are being very good. You can see that exactly the same in Peru. In Peru we are also growing a lot on revenues. We are controlling cost. So these two companies are moving to the 40% EBITDA. And I think as we could do good revenues and still control the cost maybe the EBITDA could go a little bit higher. But it's going to depend a lot on the structure of the cost in each country, but I think in Argentina and in Peru, we're doing an excellent job.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, I cannot give you -- specifically in Brazil I cannot give you any detail on EBITDA, because in Brazil we are focusing still the market is there and we are focusing more on the market, on the good customers, on the data on smartphones than on what we could do. The first priority today in Brazil is to get more revenue and to get a better subscriber so that's mainly what we are focusing there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, just on that, would you suggest therefore that maybe the first quarter was a bit of an outlier and we shouldn't be necessarily trying to model from that kind of year-on-year improvement through the year? Were there any sort of unusual features about the first quarter that you don't feel would necessarily recur?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know but it's difficult because what is being very difficult for me is how aggressive is going to be the market in the second half of the year. So it's going to depend a lot on how competitive and how -- what's going to be the reduction on prices or the promotions that we're going to do on the amount of postpaid customer that we're going to get. But as I told you, the priority is today market share with very good subscribers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much, gentlemen. Appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Jennifer Leonard of Morgan Stanley. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I just wanted to follow-up on Maur&#xED;cio's question about margins. I noticed that the cost of service increased about 23% year-over-year and has also increased as a percentage of revenue. Did you see any particular pressures on cost this quarter and could you discuss how we should think about that going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Carlos, too?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The single most important increasing cost of sales, has to do with Tracfone in the U.S. because however the &#x2013; you have been migrating from products that were more of low usage to products that are of much greater usage. Daniel has already mentioned that before. So if you look at the numbers, the single place where USA is more significant because the cost of services is basically Tracfone at the end because it's gone from a model that was a low usage model to one that is a high-end model. All on that, as I may have mentioned before, I think you have some issues in Brazil and Colombia, mostly to do with the development of networks with greater data capacity. That involves more things, payment of rental links and things like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Gil Alexander of Darfil Associates. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. With reference to the last question, do you expect your cost of service to be over 20% in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Carlos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I don't know we ever been to this kind of detailed guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But it depends also &#x2013; what Carlos is saying, I think we have been very successful on the Straight Talk plans and the Straight Talk program has been driving us, the cost of service up. So if we still have a very good second quarter in terms of Straight Talk and the investments that we're doing in all the infrastructure in Latin America, maybe yes, but it's going to depends on that, no Carlos?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Michel Morin of Barclays Capital. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the follow-up. I just wanted to ask about uses of cash given that your leverage is lower than your stated target of one-time. And specifically, you're now a $100 billion market cap company. I think some investors would like to see a higher regular dividend payment. Is that something you are open minded about reconsidering a more substantial increase to the regular dividends going forward? And related to that, how should we think about buybacks, not just at the America Movil level but your view on buybacks at the Telmex level given that you are now the controlling shareholder there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Michel. Regarding the first question, as I mentioned a little while ago, the first thing that drives distribution to shareholders is the -- our capital structure, our desired capital structure. Our desired capital structure is one times net debt to EBITDA. We have -- if you look at the last three years, in each one of the last three years, we have distributed to shareholders more than 50 billion pesos. Okay.</p>
          <p>In each one of the last three years and that essentially means that we have tried to be as close as we have been able to our net debt to EBITDA target ratio. We have done these distributions in various ways. So with an ordinary dividend and it's increasing along side net income. We don't expect to change that anytime soon. The additional distributions have taken the place either of share buybacks, which were for instance quite active in 2008 or of extraordinary dividends that we have provided both in 2007 and in 2009. So I think, that again the question is how is it decided the total amount that can be distributed? And that is a function of A) the target working capital structure, I mean, capital structure that we intent to have. And B) the type of profits after taxes that you can distribute freely without incurring any new tax. Okay?</p>
          <p>So again, going back to your second question, are we thinking that we should change the way how we work the distribution to shareholders? No, I think, that we like the flexibility that we have been able to have so far with our share buybacks. And investors generally are aware that we will be returning the cash to them in either one of the forms that I have described to the extent that we can stay close to our target of one times net debt to EBITDA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Carlos. And thoughts on Telmex's own policy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Telmex's own policy, I think, they have to present this at the Board. And I think that this should be at the Board, at the shareholders assembly, the one that will end up making their decisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes Taj Hemilda of American Century. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I wanted to go back to the migration of prepaid customers into postpaid. Can you maybe give us a little more detail on exactly what you are doing to accomplish this? Are these -- is this targeted marketing to some of your higher-end prepaid customers? Are these just general offers? What are the costs? Do you have any targets in that respect? Anything you could quantify would very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, what we're doing is, we're targeting the best customers, the customers that are using our voice or data, and what we do is we are offering an upgrade to being in postpaid. It's more convenient for them, and some of them they accept, some of them, they prefer to stay as a prepaid customer. And that's really what we're doing now. When you have more services in postpaid and people wants to use those services, so that means that people are going to move. So that's more or less. Not all of them what we're contacting they are moving, but some of them, they are moving.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I may, a follow-up question, do you have any specific targets in, how can I say it, in conversion rates or anything?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We don't have any target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And a final question, I am not sure...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have -- sorry. We have a lot of our customers beseeching us in our customer care centers. We receive in Latin America a lot of customers and when they are there, they are asking for new things, and they are asking for more data and they are asking for more things then, we are offering them this type of things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. And if I may just one more question, with respect to Telmex. Thank you. With respect to Telmex and Telmex Internacional, have you provided in the past any sort of synergies or any other quantifiable targets that you plan to achieve out of this merger and if so, would you remind us what they are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We have not provided any targets. So far, we have basically said that, we believe the greatest synergies will be coming from CapEx. The fact that together we will have to spend less to get to the certain development of the infrastructure and that's basically what we have said. I think the tops of synergies are first and foremost CapEx. There is a little bit of synergies to be had on account of some efficiencies in terms of cost, but we do not expect to have is big redundancies of personnel because there is very little overlap between the companies. So we will not have that kind of synergies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I think we are going to take one more call &#x2013; one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Our final question comes from Miguel Garcia of Deutsche Bank. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. My question is regarding TracFone. We have seen a lot of volatility in the numbers of subscribers went this year from one million to less than 0.5 million, so how should we think about the rest of the year, following quarters? Was the second quarter extraordinary in terms of the low level of our net apps or is the first quarter more representative what we should see in the future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the first half of 2009, SafeLink have launched in many states and fuel a significant amount of net gains growth, almost no churn until 12 months okay, out. During the first half of this year SafeLink growth slow and began seeing churn, so that's mainly what is impacting us the net gains. Almost all of TracFone growth has come from Straight Talk in quarter two. So that's more or less what is happening, okay. We have a lot of new subscribers in SafeLink during the first half, and they are churning right now some of them. So that's mainly what you could see. We expect to see growth from other brands during second half of the year, not only Straight Talk, I think we're going to see -- in the other brands, we're going to see a little bit more of growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I conclude that something between the first and second quarter would be normal for the next quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, no, because at that end of the year it's very good in the United States. It's Christmas. It's -- maybe third quarter, it's not as good. So well, I think all overall, we're going to have a very good year in TracFone as the 2010 is going to be a very good year for TracFone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and one quick question, if I may. You already said that the net adds for the year are going to be higher than -- should be higher, right, than what you had budgeted. Now, what happens with the CapEx? Should we assume that 3 billion to 3.1 billion is something that maybe short, too for the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think we said 3.1 billion and we always say that could be 10% more, 10% less. I think we are right now in the 3.1 billion as we said, and I don't think we're going to do a little bit more than that. Well, maybe if minutes of use grow or we have to put more on data, maybe we can use that 10% to have a little bit more. In TracFone, I recommend you to see the revenue growth. It's very important that you see revenue growth. Revenue growth is 59% this year. So it's very important, not only to subscribers, no, because maybe a Straight Talk subscriber account maybe by two SafeLink subscribers. So, check the revenue, I think revenue's important. For us it's very important.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. No further questions at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rizwan, and thank you everybody for being in the call. Carlos, Daniela, and thank you, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the conference for today. You may all disconnect and have a wonderful day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>