<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1490603" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2866</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Strategist, UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Dan Kwiatkowski</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer">Daniel Hajj Aboumrad</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Carlos Jos&#xE9; Garc&#xED;a Moreno Elizondo</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Raymond James &amp; Associates">Ric Prentiss</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Michel Morin</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Rizwan Ali</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (USA), Inc.">Kevin Smithen</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="BTIG LLC">Walter Piecyk</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Brasil CCTVM SA">Alexandre Garcia</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Vera R. Rossi</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep" affiliation="COO Wireline">&#xD3;scar Von Hauske Sol&#xED;s</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Legal &amp; General Investment Management America, Inc.">Stanley Martinez</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Santander CCVM SA">Valder Nogueira</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Christopher Andrew Buck</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen. And thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Am&#xE9;rica M&#xF3;vil Second Quarter 2012 Earnings Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question-and-answer session, and instructions will follow at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to introduce your host for today's presentation, Mr. Dan Kwiatkowski. Sir, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good morning. This is Dan Kwiatkowski of UBS. And I'd like to welcome you to Am&#xE9;rica M&#xF3;vil's second quarter 2012 conference call. On the line today, we have Daniel Hajj, CEO of AMX; Carlos Garc&#xED;a Moreno, the CFO; &#xD3;scar Von Hauske, COO; and Daniela Lecuona, IR Manager.</p>
          <p>So with that further ado, I would like to pass the call over to them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. Thank you, Dan. Carlos is going to make a summary of our &#x2013; thank you first for being on the call, and Carlos is going to make a summary of the second quarter results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you again, Dan. Good morning, everyone. Again, thanks to UBS for hosting the call today.</p>
          <p>The stabilization of financial markets that had come about at the beginning of the year had led to a rough situation of very low denominated currencies and provided uncertain economic activity in the region came to an end at the beginning of the second quarter on renewed concerns about global economic growth and the economic situation of some European countries. In some Latin American countries like Brazil, the economics slowed down more, intensifying competitive pressures.</p>
          <p>In spite of the volatility in financial markets, we managed to post solid gains in the quarter that topped all estimates bar none, mostly in wireless and the wireline platform, adding 5.9 million wireless subscribers including 1.1 million that came with the acquisition of SIMPLE Mobile in the U.S. and 1.7 million RGUs. It is important to note therefore we can provide triple-play services everywhere other than Mexico and Argentina. Over half of the RGU net additions were obtained through the sale of triple-play bundles and nearly one-third through double-play packages.</p>
          <p>The net additions I mentioned before allowed us to finish the quarter with 313 million accesses, including 252 million wireless subscribers, 30 million land lines, 16 million broadband accesses, and 15 million PayTV clients. The number of accesses increased 7.8% from the year earlier quarter, with PayTV clients increasing 30.9% and broadband accesses 15%.</p>
          <p>Our Brazilian operations added 1.3 million RGUs, accounting for approximately three-quarters of the overall RGU additions. At the end of June, we had 26.3 million RGUs in Brazil, 22.7 million in Mexico, and 3.9 million in Colombia.</p>
          <p>On the wireless platform, Mexico led the way in net subscriber additions with 1.4 million, slightly ahead of Brazil, to finish the quarter with 68 million versus 63 million in Brazil. In Colombia we have 29 million subscribers, in the U.S. 21 million, and in Argentina 20 million; followed by Peru with 12 million and Central America and the Caribbean with 20 million.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we continued to grow well our postpaid base most every quarter, with the exception of Brazil. Postpaid net additions totaled 653,000 and 40,000 subs, even after 200,000 disconnections in that country.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated second quarter revenue increased 9.3% in Mexican pesos terms on wireless revenue that increased 14.1% and fixed line revenues that rose 1.7%. The comparison of these figures, particularly the latter, with those of revenue in the first quarter becomes difficult because of the movement in the value of various currencies versus the Mexican peso, and in particular the 6.1% devaluation of the real based on the peso in the quarter. At constant exchange rates, revenue growth for the period was 6.3%, led by mobile data revenues that increased 30.7% and PayTV revenues that were are up 23.4%. Fixed line data growth came in at 8.0%.</p>
          <p>Wireless ARPU rose practically everywhere on the back of mobile data. Brazil was the exception. Wireless voice revenues reflected the impact of the reduction of mobile termination rates, particularly in Brazil. On the fixed line platform, we continue to see the decline of long-distance revenues, partly on account of rate reductions mandated by the government.</p>
          <p>In Mexico, Telmex continued to pass on to consumers, as agreed at the beginning of the year, the full benefit of the reduction in mobile termination rates enacted last year. <mark type="ph" /> But instead (5:05) is rapidly gaining back those revenues that it lost on interconnection.</p>
          <p>EBITDA came in as 66 million pesos and was 3.1% higher than the year before. Service cost generally rose faster than revenues on account of increased energy charges, rapid postpaid subscriber growth, higher content cost, and the still laboring impact on operating expenditures of the major investments we are undertaking to expand and modernize on our networks. The EBITDA margin declined two points to 34.1%. In addition to we recently mentioned before and have reiterated in the past, the reductions in the margins also reflects a new confirmation of our business lines with platform now in our PayTV operations, which are lower margin businesses, becoming increasingly relevant.</p>
          <p>The depreciation of the Mexican peso on other currencies relative to the U.S. dollar resulted in a foreign exchange loss of 16.1 billion pesos that resulted in our posting a comprehensive financing cost of 17.2 billion pesos. The foreign exchange loss was smaller than the gain posted the prior quarter, so the balance for the first semester was a net gain of 3.2 billion pesos.</p>
          <p>We registered a net profit of 13.3 billion pesos on operating profits of 39.1 billion pesos, but were practically flat from the year earlier quarter.</p>
          <p>Our net debt stood at 361 billion pesos at the end of June, having increased by 29.7 billion pesos since December, and was equivalent to 1.4 times EBITDA.</p>
          <p>Our capital expenditures in the first half of the year totaled 53.2 billion pesos; and our acquisitions of equity interest, including those in KPN and Telekom Austria, 67.0 billion pesos. While we bought back 12.7 billion pesos of Am&#xE9;rica M&#xF3;vil shares. These outlays added up to 133 billion pesos. We will begin to consolidate our investment in KPN and Telekom Austria under the equity method beginning in the third quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>With that, I would like to pass it back to Dan and open the floor for questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Carlos. Howard, can you please put together a list of questions, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question or comment comes from the line of Ric Prentiss. Your line is open, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning. With 3G and mobile data continuing to increase, I was wondering if you could update us first on what you're seeing as far as the cost of smartphones. Have they've gotten down to the $100 level to you yet for good smart phones?</p>
          <p>And the second question is on your 3G networks. Can you update us as for us how much usage you're seeing per customer? Have you seen a significant increase in megabytes used per month yet? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the 3G handsets, of course, we have been seeing a lot of reductions on prices. But as you see reductions on prices in some handsets, you saw also new handsets at a high level price. So what we have been seeing is that with those new prices, there are new people who are getting in, but there are a still lot of people who want the high-end handset. So still, it's more costly. The track for us, the growth in postpaid has been more costly because there is a little bit more on subsidy because the handsets are much better handsets than they used to be. So that's one question. In other places, we have been seeing intensifying competition also. So the SAC has been growing a little bit. And the second question, what was it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The usage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The usage, of course, people are using more and more data through downloads and data through the smartphones, where it's being maybe more than 30% year on year they have been using more the data.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Daniel, I'll maybe jump in with a couple of questions myself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In Brazil, we're still seeing continued pressure on both ARPU and margins. Could you give us an idea of where you think ARPU and margins might eventually end up in Brazil and give us some kind of timeframe? That's the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What's happening in Brazil, as Carlos was saying, the economy has been slowing down a little bit and the competition has been very tough. Competition has been intensifying. And that's really the reason why ARPUs and margins have been going down. Let's say in long-distance calls maybe year over year, the reduction on prices have been maybe 50%. So there's a lot of competition there, and we hope that the competitors would be more intelligent and the market would be more rational, but that's something that I cannot tell you. In Brazil, we have been investing a lot, so we're prepared for competition. That's really what is happening with ARPUs and margin there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, and my second question is on CapEx. Could you give us an update on your expectations for CapEx post the 4G auctions and post your recent conversations with Anatel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Brazil, you are talking only about Brazil?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, just in general.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me tell you about Brazil. In Brazil, we have been investing a lot, and our budget is also a good budget for investment. We don't think we need to invest more. We don't agree with the measure of Anatel, how they do the measures because the measures, let's say in S&#xE3;o Paulo, we have the second best network there in S&#xE3;o Paulo, but they don't measure the quality of the network. They measure the quantity of calls through the call centers. So we don't agree on that. We have one of the best qualities. We have been improving a lot on quality, what we have been working a lot last year and this year. And I don't think we need more CapEx. We showed them what we're going to do on the CapEx for this year, and I think they are happy with the numbers that we show them, but that's not something that we're going to increase. It's something that we have been doing for this year and what we are going to do until the end of next year. So that's mainly what is happening.</p>
          <p>And in the CapEx through Am&#xE9;rica M&#xF3;vil, what we said is that we're going to invest around $30 billion in three years. That was last year, this year, and the next one. And I think we are more or less on that range. We don't think there is going to be a big difference on what we think for the rest of this year and the next one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question or comment comes from the line of Mr. Michel Morin from Morgan Stanley. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone. Carlos, I was hoping to drill down a little bit more on Brazil and in particular the mobile service revenue growth, which was decelerated significantly. We know that there was the MTR cut. I was hoping you might do to help us sort out how much was the MTR cut and how much was everything else, including the macro slowdown that you alluded to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there are three things that you are saying. There is lull down on the economy; people are consuming a little bit less. The cost of the MTRs, I don't know if Carlos knows exactly what is the percentage of the cost on the MTR. And then the competition is intensifying. So that's really what you are seeing in Brazil and what is happening in that market. All overall, you have to see also one important issue that in Claro, in the wireless side, we are not...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Accounting...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...accounting on long-distance. So besides the other one, all the long-distance through the wireless is through Embratel because it's where we have a license, and that's something where you need to compare apples to apples. So the long-distance is out of Claro, and all the other steps. But I don't know, Carlos, if you know exactly what the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know incoming revenues raised from incoming traffic came down by 16% year on year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Only on the MTR?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Only on the account of MTR, incoming revenues came done by 16%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's very helpful. And then if I may, in terms of margins, you alluded in the press release to the impact of subsidies on smartphones. Can you clarify then that you're completely expensing, you're not capitalizing any portion of the subsidy on your subsidies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michel, we have had the same policy from day one. We always expense the subsidies out there. We do not amortize subsidies over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's different than some competitors. We don't only do that in Brazil, we do it all through Latin America. So the subsidies through in the smartphones are total; it's an expense. We don't capitalize any.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it has been a longstanding policy for Am&#xE9;rica M&#xF3;vil's assets, from day one of Am&#xE9;rica M&#xF3;vil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Carlos, if you had to help us out a little bit in Mexico to understand the main drivers of the margin erosion there because you had good growth. So it's a little bit surprising to see the sequential decline in margin. Would you say that it's all because of the subsidy to smartphones? Hello? Hello?</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="audio gap" /> (16:30 &#x2013; 23:15)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, please stand by. We're experiencing technical difficulty. Your conference call will resume momentarily. Please hold.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="audio gap" /> (23:40 &#x2013; 34:53)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we are now connected.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Dan Kwiatkowski from UBS. I'd like to apologize very sincerely on the call dropping like that. Let's try to get to some of the callers. Operator, let's take more questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Michel, we owe you the answer in Mexico then. So, Carlos?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, before going on with the answer, we're ready to make a proposal to UBS for some very good communications solutions that we may be offering now that we are a global company.</p>
          <p>Anyway, the question that Michel had was on Mexico. I think in Mexico, we are seeing the following. On the one hand, we are seeing very strong recovery on the wireless side. We are seeing MOUs continuing to rise. They go to 267 minutes. That was the highest ever here in Mexico, and we continue to do very well. In postpaid we had, 20% of our net additions were postpaid. And these increasing &#x2013; the net additions for this year were almost 25% higher than what we had last year. So Mexico continues do very, very, very well in increasing traffic and MOUs and in gaining better share of the postpaid market.</p>
          <p>The latter part has a lot to do with our data capabilities. And obviously, the increase of data services in Mexico has continued to be very strong. It's in the neighborhood of 30% right now. And data represents now approximately one-third of service revenues in Mexico already. So Mexico on the mobile front doing very well, and they're still recovering from the loss of interconnection revenue that it had last year.</p>
          <p>On the fixed line side, what we are seeing is Telmex has continued to pass on to the public the benefits of the reduction in the termination rates that were enacted last year. And that extends, using a part of the reduction of revenues of spend eventually -- something the company agreed to by its own will at the beginning of this year, and its passing on the full benefit, which is by the way something that we haven't seen in any other countries such as in Europe and so on.</p>
          <p>One thing that is important in terms of things that have an impact on EBITDA, these things that we have mentioned before, which is we continue to invest. There is a lot of spillover into operating expenses of the investment program. So that is something that is going to be an important factor and will continue for some time. There are obviously the effects of the currency depreciation. That was important, the pesos to the real or dollar. And obviously that has an impact in subsidies because we cannot always adjust our prices as rapidly as the movement in the exchange rates. These movements were very, very quick. So they typically have an impact on EBITDA as well. And then we have, at given market conditions, we have decided to increase our contributions to the pension fund of Telmex. So that also was an important additional cost that is going on the EBITDA of the quarter against last year.</p>
          <p>So all in all, the mobile side recovering well, data very well, postpaid we continued to gain share, Smartphones, we continued to sell more smartphones. Part of the subsidiaries of smartphones given the currency depreciation and the fast pace of growth of our postpaid was one of the things impacting EBITDA on the wireless side. And on the wireline side it's basically the continued reduction of the revenues as we devolve to clients the benefits of the communication rates and we have now the spillover the investment, which is huge at the level of Telmex. The investment that Telmex is doing today to expand private data is really important. And finally we have the effect of the labor provisions that we have increased given the current conditions in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Howard, then next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question or comment comes from the line of Rizwan Ali from Deutsche Bank. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning. So I have two questions. One is about recovery in Brazil. We still see overall revenues and EBITDA decreasing in Brazil on the wireless side of the business. And so I'm just wondering whether we should expect any price elasticity kicking in, in the second half of the year, which may allow you to start increasing your EBITDA and wireless revenues in Brazil.</p>
          <p>And second question is you are now well above your net debt to EBITDA target of one. Do you plan to slowly bring down the leverage to closer to one. That's all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Brazil, Rizwan as we just said, it was on the termination rates as part of the revenues and on the margins, it's on the termination rate, plus the slowdown on the economy, plus the intensity of some promotions on the commercial side. So I think until the end of the year there is going to still be a lot of competition. And while I hope that it would be more rational, the market is not something that I cannot tell you right now. But I think the bases that we are doing in Brazil are good. We are investing. We are doing very good on the quality. We are going to invest in LTE. Our data revenues are growing also in wireless. So I think in the long term, it looks like we're going to be in good shape in Brazil.</p>
          <p>And on the other side, the whole company as in TV and having &#x2013; I remember also, Rizwan, what I told a few minutes ago. In wireless we don't account for the long-distance and its important to compare that against our competitors, plus what we are doing in TV and broadband, I think all overall in Brazil we are doing fine. Of course, we need to do a big effort on the wireless side. But all overall, I think we are doing fine. And Carlos can talk a little bit about the debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you recall, Rizwan, we had a conference call a few weeks ago basically to discuss the acquisitions that we had in Europe, and we provided some guidance. We basically said that we intended to remain within the limits that the rating agencies have imposed on us in terms of leverage, but we also said that we expected distributions to shareholders to remain roughly about the same average that we have had for the last three or four years. So I think that's basically what we are looking at. We have an eye on leverage, but we have an eye on distributions as well. And it's important you have to &#x2013; you can come up with your own numbers. We are not expecting any major deviation from this guidance anytime soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rizwan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question or comment comes from the line of Mr. Kevin Smithen from Macquarie. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It looks like you have accelerated the pace of postpaid sub growth in Mexico and Colombia, and that's partially hitting the margins there. Can you give us a little more color as to what the total number or smartphones shipped in Q2 was versus Q2 of last year, and maybe if you could give us the difference in ARPU and churn between some of these postpaid smartphone subscribers and your prepaid voice subscribers in Mexico?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. The second question again, I don't understand the second question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was trying to understand. Obviously, you're incurring the subsidy for adding these postpaid smartphone subscribers. But in the future, you should get an ARPU and a churn benefit from them. So can you tell us like a little bit, what has the ARPU of a smartphone subscriber been over the last year or so that you've had the service. And then what is the churn likely to be on those subscribers? In the U.S, we've seen obviously a big 80% increases in ARPU and about a 30% churn reduction. I want to see what that's looking like in Mexico thus far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me explain what's happening. What's happening is that in terms of postpaid, we are growing on the smartphones a lot, and we are selling new plans with bundles included, so that's helping us. Data has been growing. I think right now in Mexico, 30% of our revenues are data, so we are growing very well. Where every time people are moving towards smartphones, almost all the subscribers, all the customers are getting data plans. So I think that has been very good.</p>
          <p>And on postpaid, what we're doing today on postpaid, I think postpaid is going to grow a lot on data. It is starting to grow at this time. And what is happening is that this $100 or $150 handset is where we are moving on the postpaid side. So as they are getting better phones, smartphones or good feature phones, let's say, I'm sure that the prepaid customers are going to start to use data. And mostly in data, they are going to use mail, social networks, and those type of things. So I'm sure that in the next two or three years, the prepaid side is going to increase a lot on data. So that's the way we are seeing.</p>
          <p>Of course, your question is on, if we are selling a $500 phone on prepaid and then he's not using data and he's churning, that's not happening. On the prepaid side, we are not &#x2013; our subsidies have been very low. So we have been very careful on the subsidies on the prepaid side. And I think if we put a smartphone on the prepaid side and in the future they are going to use a lot of data. That's where we're seeing things, and it's exactly the same in Mexico and in Colombia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess, the question is really what, on the postpaid side, if you're selling a phone for $150, how much additional ARPU are you going to get over the lifetime value of that subscriber? You're going to have an initial hit as you add the subscriber to margins, but over time you should see ARPU go up and churn come down. At least that's we've seen in the U.S. and Europe. What can you say about this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>ARPU is growing all around Latin America. So you'll see that ARPU side growing, and it's because of the postpaid. So on one side, we're growing in the data. But on the other side, there are some places where it's stable in the voice. So that's what you have, and we are selling &#x2013; it's going to be very difficult because today, we are selling bundled plans. So we don't know exactly how much is on data and how much is on voice. But at the end of the day, everybody is &#x2013; I think 95% of the customers are getting plans with voice and with data included. But you could see that ARPU side growing and growing all around Latin America. Exactly, I don't have the numbers here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question or comment comes from the line of Walter Piecyk from BTIG. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Dan, can you give us an update on LTE? Are you still planning on launching in Mexico City in September, and if you have any other rollout timeline for when you'd be throughout most of Mexico with LTE? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it has been delayed a little bit. But I think in the fourth quarter, we can see some LTE products in Mexico. The rollout has been good. We want to train well. We want to have a good quality, and that's why we are delaying a little bit. The launch, it's I think at end of October, beginning of November we could start seeing some advertising in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Advertising on phones or Internet devices or MiFi devices like wireless dongles?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're going to start with dongles and really at the end of the year then we'll also see phone <mark type="ph" /> advertising (50:15).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then you also talked a lot about the postpaid...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Data plans, not voice phones, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Data plans, not voice.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. You talked about the postpaid success in Mexico. And I don't know all the breakout of gross adds. But obviously, prepaid is still the vast majority of the net adds in Mexico and most of these markets. Can you just talk about smartphones for that market? You talked about people subsidizing these expensive phones. But what type of smartphones are those prepaid customers buying? If you're only offering a small subsidy, do these customer buy an iPhone 4S, even the 3GS selling to prepaid customers because at 4,000 pesos, it's still I think probably fairly expensive for lot of those customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but as I said, on the prepaid side we have been very careful. We are really looking on the subsidies. We are checking every month what's the subsidy on the prepaid side, and this business is profitable. So I am not subsidizing a 3GS in the prepaid and they not using or they are not consuming. And I think that we are showing these type of phones because in the future I'm sure like in voice, data is going to be very important on the prepaid side. But I'm not subsidizing a lot or a very small amount of the handset on the prepaid side. The handsets are, we have handsets at $100. We have handsets or feature phones at $60 where you can use your mail. You can do social networks. There is a lot that we could do more on the prepaid side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I see in your stores for those prepaid customers, this 4,000 peso 3GS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You're saying that customers are basically not opting for that, but opting for the 60 peso or the 100 peso, whatever it is, the cheaper other smartphones at this point, or are they still buying the 4,000 peso 3GS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They are buying both. They are buying; they are different. We have very good customers in prepaid, good ARPU customers in prepaid, maybe 300 pesos. That comes out to 50 pesos per month, so it's not bad, $20 &#x2013; $25. And those are the ones that still does not have a big consumption, but we are selling both. And what I'm saying is if you want a high-end or high-priced handset, then you have to pay for that. I'm not going to subsidize that handset for you...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...on the prepaid side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question or comment comes from the line of Alex Garcia from Citibank. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning everyone. Just very quickly, can you update us on the restructuring of your consolidation of your three assets in Brazil? I just wondered if you could share your opinion if the suspension of the NET Servi&#xE7;os delisting, if that delays your plans for Brazil, and if the competition that you just mentioned that is getting tougher forces you to accelerate that consolidation? That would be my question. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what we are doing in Brazil is, we're doing the integration of the three companies. Of course still the three companies are separate, but we are doing as much as possible on the integration, as much as we can on the integration, NET Servi&#xE7;os in purchasing on the commercial side. In technological side also, we are doing one network; we have convergence on the commercial side. So we are doing well, and you can see that we are doing well because the TV and the broadband is doing excellent. And I think and I'm sure that wireless is going to be very, wireless data is doing also very good. And at the end of some time, I think all overall in Brazil, we are going to be very, very strong. So I think we have the companies, we have the base. We have a very good TV company. We have a very good long-distance company brand. We have a satellite company. We have cable. We have broadband, and then we have wireless. So I think in Brazil, we have been doing a very good a job integrating these companies, and I'm happy in the stage where we are today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And just to follow up, if I may, regarding the discussion that since day one Am&#xE9;rica M&#xF3;vil does not amortize the handset subsidy, does that work also for the handset subsidies for corporate clients or just individuals?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, in the handsets, we do expense on everything, everything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the handsets, we do as an expense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, now seeing the handsets....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All countries, all the markets, it's countries, it's markets, it's every place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thank you, very clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question or comment comes from the line of Vera Rossi from Barclays. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Can you talk about Brazil again to follow up on the wireline business? Your revenues are growing 7.6% in wireline, and we are seeing all those companies with bigger declines between like in the 12% to 13%. So first, are your customers taking more triple-play services? And who do you think and in what regions do you think you are being more successful gaining market share, in S&#xE3;o Paulo or outside S&#xE3;o Paulo? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well Vera as Carlos said, we have been doing a lot of triple-play and double-play. NET has been very successful in their markets where is NET. On the other side, we have been also doing satellite plus wireless data and wireless voice. So we have been really successful on the fixed side. Also with broadband, &#xD3;scar can tell you a little bit more about the market share and how we are doing now on the fixed side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you mentioned, NET, we are successful on the triple-play side. Around 51% of the customers of NET already have triple-play, 22% have double-play, and single-play is different. So the packages and the monetizing bulk in the marketplace, so we are launching all the triple-play products in all the regions in all the cities that NET has a presence. And as well in PayTV on DTH we've been growing pretty fast. So we already have 2.6 million PayTV customers on the DTH satellite product.</p>
          <p>Another thing for us, as Carlos and Daniel mentioned, is that the long-distance market is decreasing a lot due to the change in rates. So we need to roll more in local revenues and PayTV and broadband to compensate for the decline in long-distance. We've been doing this in a successful way in the past. But the long-distance market is accelerating the decrease. In the last quarter we see that the minutes are growing in long-distance but the prices have declined. This is due to, as Daniel mentioned, is due to competition more in mobile traffic. So we are working on all the fronts.</p>
          <p>And in corporate, it's a lot of price pressure on the enterprise. We've been a very successful network, data networks, but we've been facing a lot of price pressure on the any new contract. So, what we are doing is how we can bring more value-added to the connectivity. So we are to moving on to cloud computing, to data centers. We are going to open a new data center in S&#xE3;o Paulo, in <mark type="ph" /> LatAm (59:25), next month. So we will have more mirrors to sell. We've got value-added services. So I think the combination of the decline in long-distance and the increase in local, PayTV, and broadband, we will have a good position in the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And adding something, to &#xD3;scar's comment, is that really on the TV side, we have the best product and the best quality in Brazil. So that's really the reason that why we are growing is because we have the best product, the best content, the best quality. And in broadband, I think we are exactly the same, so that this why we're growing in that market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question or comment comes from the line Stanley Martinez. Your line is open, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Thank you for taking my question, just a couple on TracFone, if I could. Could you say what proportion of service revenue data comprises within TracFone now? You always disclose the minutes of use, and that continues to grow. But as data becomes more important, and particularly as you do your data wholesale deals with some of the other major carriers, do you think something like the data sharing tariffs that we see from the postpaid carriers here in the U.S. might be applicable to TracFone and maybe help you drive usage and revenue market share versus prepaid carriers in 3G and 4G environments, similar to what you did successfully in 2G and voice?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think TracFone has been a very successful company. Data is still small, but we are selling very good plans, as in the Straight Talk brand, and that includes a lot of data. So I think in the future, we're going to grow a lot more on data, and that's exactly what is going to happen. We have, as you know, different segments. We have the SafeLink. We have the SIMPLE Mobile brand, and then we have TracFone. In the TracFone and NET10, we don't have a lot of data. But in the Straight Talk brand, we are including data in our packages. And this is the brand that is growing and I think will grow a lot in the next months. I think it's going to be very important, data for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Daniel, could you just dimension that slightly? Is it less than 10% of service revenue growth? And again, if you think about maybe what you can do to try to spur adoption and to drive differentiation even further against some of the prepaid carriers that own their own networks, how does something like a shared data tariff package similar to what we've seen from AT&amp;T and Verizon in postpaid fit into that equation potentially?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In our Straight Talk &#x2013; I don't have the number here with me. But you could see that the new plan in the Straight Talk plan includes data, SMS, and voice, and it's a very, very successful plan. So we have being growing a lot but still more than 60%, but still very, very small the numbers. So potential that in the next months, we're going to have a good growth there. But as I'm telling you it's in our Straight Talk plan, we include voice, we include SMS, and we include data in the package.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Thanks, Daniel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question or comment comes from the line of Valder Nogueira. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys. Just to get it clear, you mentioned that your mobile service revenues in Brazil, they do not reflect the long-distance revenues. I want to double-check that information. And also I want to ask you whether your ARPU numbers for Claro Brazil do reflect long-distance revenues generated by those customers. That's to be able to better compare apples to apples to what the other operators are saying.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Valder, when you look at the aggregate number of revenues we already added, including everything I think that the right number to look at that total revenues because that's the only one that I think is really comparable to what everybody else is showing, might be showing. But remember that Claro did not have a long-distance license. So the scheme that we have had in place for a long time is one whereby Claro does the covering of long-distance services on behalf of Embratel. So we are declining to take Claro's client <mark type="ph" /> in terms of the (1:04:35) service and gets an invoice. The external location of the revenues is different because that part corresponds to long-distance services is billed as Embratel revenue, not as Claro revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But the accrued number for Claro does include whatever they consume in terms of long-distance, even though part of this revenue is passed on to Embratel, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, but it would include the interconnection fee associated with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Thank you, Carlos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question or comment is a follow-up from Mr. Alex Garcia. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thank you for taking another question. Still on Brazil, we are seeing the increasing equipment of fiber networks and planning to launch IPTV products on there, let's say whether their high-end customers are, in Q4. So I was wondering if you have any plans to upgrade NET Servi&#xE7;os networks to DOCSIS 3.0; and if you do, if you could give us an estimate on how much that would cost to upgrade a client to DOCSIS 3.0. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We will upgrade the network to DOCSIS 3.0 on the high end of the series. So that's why we have the ability to deliver 100 megabits per second in broadband. So we've been selling that product. Around only 3% or 4% has 100 megabits on all the base of NET Servi&#xE7;os. So we are doing that, we are doing in the high end of the network. Because of that, it's a mix, we don't have an estimated cost a unit. But I think it's economically better than fiber-to-the-home. So I think we have an advantage to upgrade to DOCSIS 3.0 using copper cables.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question or comment from the line of Michel Morin. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Thanks are taking the follow-up. I just wanted to see if you could talk just a little bit about Argentina. We haven't really talked about that market yet. Obviously, there were some macro challenges there, so if you can give us a bit of an update on what you're seeing in particular as it pertains to how that's affecting your margins. Thank you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The company in Argentina is that have a little bit of an increase in our cost, and the challenge is to grow revenues also at a higher pace. We are seeing really a slowdown in Argentina, but we have the company under the control cost. And in the market we are doing well, we are growing and we are upgrading some of our customers to a better plan, and it's more or less what is happening in Argentina.</p>
          <p>Argentina is a soft market today because there are a lot of pressure on costs, but the slowdown has been also &#x2013; in the last three, four months you could see that there is a slowdown in the economy, and that would make us grow a little bit less, so that's what you are seeing there. We have been good in the corporate side, in the peak corporate side, and the wireless we have very good cost control in Argentina. We are growing o the postpaid side. We are growing on the prepaid side. We're being very careful on the subsidies, and we are not increasing prices at this moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just if I can come back to Mexico quickly, the revenue performance has been very solid and you made some positive comments earlier. Do you feel that you're gaining share or is this really the economy that's lifting all boats?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's difficult to say. We don't have the numbers of the other customers. I don't know, I don't have the number, but I think that in the postpaid side we are gaining market share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, I think the last question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question comes from the line of Mr. Christopher Buck from Barclays. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, thanks for the question. I'm wondering if you can give us a little bit of color around your funding plans. I noticed that on this quarter your bank lines grew considerably, and I assume that was to fund some of the acquisitions, and I'm just wondering. In July you issued several bonds, and I'm wondering if you plan to use some of that capital to repay revolvers, or if you can make any other comments about what we should expect for the balance sheet in the third quarter. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christopher, only to add something to the question of Michel Morin, what is important in Mexico, and you could see that is number portability. And we have been gaining every month consistently number portability, and this has been accelerating that in prepaid and in postpaid. So that's where you could see where the market is going and what's the preference of the customers are. And Carlos can tell you about...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, can you repeat the question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The funding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The funding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we raised roughly $3 billion over the last month. And all of that is going to be utilized to pay down the liquidity facilities that we had drawn on to finance the acquisition of KPN and Telekom Austria. So by the end of next month, I think all of that would have been fully repaid. And to the extent that we see opportunities in the market, we may be able to do that if we want to advance some funding for the amortization of all our liquidity facilities. As far as maturities today, we don't really have any more maturities of any significance. But if there's something that makes sense from the sense of debt management, we may be able to do something. But we don't really require any more capital at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you all for attending the call and thank you, Dan, for arranging this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot, Goodbye everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for participating in today's conference. This concludes the program. You may now disconnect. Everyone have a wonderful day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>