<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1169349" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2866</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Andre Baggio, CFA, JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co.</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Daniel Hajj Aboumrad, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Carlos Jose Garcia Moreno Elizondo, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Andre Baggio</participant>
      <participant id="5">Carlos Jose Garcia Moreno Elizondo</participant>
      <participant id="6">Daniel Hajj Aboumrad</participant>
      <participant id="7">Andrew Campbell</participant>
      <participant id="8">Vera Rossi</participant>
      <participant id="9">Stephen Graham</participant>
      <participant id="10">Fernando Ramos</participant>
      <participant id="11">Walter Piecyk</participant>
      <participant id="12">Richard Denine</participant>
      <participant id="13">James Breen</participant>
      <participant id="14">Steve Malcolm</participant>
      <participant id="15">Henry Cobbe</participant>
      <participant id="16">Mauricio Fernandes</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Brad. I will be the operator on today's call. I would like to welcome everyone to the America Movil Conference Call. At this time all participants are in a listen-only mode. After the presentation, we will conduct a questions and answer session.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
          <p>Today's conference is being recorded. If you have any objections, you may disconnect at this time. Now, I will turn the meeting over to, Mr. Andre Baggio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, everyone and good afternoon for those in Europe. This is Andre Baggio, Latin American Telecom analyst for JPMorgan. And it's our pleasure to be hosting America Movil's second quarter 2008 earnings conference call. On this call, we will have Daniel Hajj, CEO; Carlos Garcia-Moreno, CFO; and Daniela Lecuona, Head of IR.</p>
          <p>Now, I would turn over to Daniel Hajj for his management presentation, which will be followed by the Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Andre. Thank you everybody for being in the call. Carlos Garcia-Moreno is going to present the summary of the second quarter financial and operating results. Carlos, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Thanks for hosting the call, Andre. Good morning, everyone. America Movil obtained solid financial results in second quarter that were supported by good subscriber and revenue growth. The Latin American countries where we operate, continued to do well economically having benefited from important temporary gains coming from the increase in the price of commodities all minerals, food stocks and decline in the cost imported manufactured good. These gains are driving an expansion of consumption that has underpinned the growth of wireless services.</p>
          <p>The second quarter was characterized by very strong subscriber growth. Our net addition, 6.1 million, exceeded those of our year before and also those registered in the previous quarter. Our subscriber base, thus reached 155.3 million subs at the end of the June, which represents a 20.4% year-on-year increase. This is after obtaining a total of 11.9 million subs in the first six months of the year. Brazil led the way in terms of net additions with 1.9 million, which accounted for 26% of the net additions for the Brazilian market in the quarter. The net additions in Brazil doubled those of the first quarter and they were 17% higher than those in a year before. The rate of growth of its subscriber base has now reached 36% in June with postpaid subscribers continuing to outpace prepaid subscribers. 3G has been a great success in Brazil and have definitely contributed to us gaining market share in postpaid market.</p>
          <p>Mexico net ads, 1.3 million also surpassed those obtained a year before, by 12%. Through June we have gained 2.8 million subs almost as mainly as in the previous 2007, to finish the month with 52.9 million subs. In Colombia we added 1.1 million subscribers in the quarter, which was 88% more than a year before. Bringing to 1.9 million the total for the first half of the year. Whereas in Argentina we increased our subscriber base by 400,000 subscribers in the quarter and 1.6 million in the six months till June.</p>
          <p>Our revenues expanded 13.6% year-on-year and 4% over the quarter to which 84.6 billion pesos. Sequentially, sales revenue growth was stronger in Mexico with 4.14%, Colombia, Ecuador and Peru, which averaged 6%. In the second quarter the Mexican peso appreciated vis-&#xE0;-vis all other currencies all over the world, we've gone about some foreign exchange gains that had an impact on operating cash.</p>
          <p>In all our major operations, MOUs have increased year-on-year, most notably in Mexico with 40% growth. We continue to see good elasticity of demand out of Mexico. In fact, it appears that outgoing projects is becoming even more responsive to price stimulus.</p>
          <p>Our EBITDA, consolidated EBITDA totaled 34.7 billion pesos in the quarter, which is 13.7% more than a year before, with the margin coming in at 41%.</p>
          <p>EBITDA margins rose sequentially in most operations. The only major exceptions being Brazil, where margins fell on accountably sharp acceleration of our subscriber growth.</p>
          <p>Through June our EBITDA was up 15.7% in analogue terms to 58.6 billion pesos. We've generated 24.6 billion pesos in operating profits, and made a net profit of 17.7 billion pesos, but it was up 25.3% year-on-year. It was equivalent to 51 peso cents per share, and $0.99 cents per ADR.</p>
          <p>Our net profit expenditure is from strong operating results and from certain foreign exchange gains that more than out grade our interest and other financial costs. We invested 36.7 billion in the six months to June, including the amount spent on the purchase of spectrum in Brazil which was in excess of a $800 million, and bought back shares worth 13.9 billion pesos. The above were all financed with our cash flow, which allowed us to reduce our net debt by 5.3 billion pesos. All taking together the share buybacks, our CapEx and our &#x2013; the reduction in net debt a total of practically 46 billion pesos. So that's quite a strong operating cash flow.</p>
          <p>I'd like to turn now the floor to questions. Andre may be we can get started. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So, first of all let's say, I would like to just ask a couple questions. In the first quarter we saw a small rebound in Mexican ARPU, which follows the decline in the previous quarter. What should we expect for the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, the recover, we spent a lot the first quarter we have some holidays in summer. What I think that the growth in the 3G ARPU subscriber, that growth in the 3G subscribers is going make ARPU growth a little bit, plus the low income people, the low segment people that is coming, I think we can sustain the ARPU that we have, right now. Maintain what we have today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And second, can you comment a little bit on the situation in Brazil. We saw of course strong additions, but weak margins. So, I would like to understand a bit of the market dynamics in that country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the issue with Brazil, we've seen &#x2013; first of all it was very significant increase in net ads, because it was double refering to first quarter. And so, that evidently had an impact on subscriber acquisition cost. But, the other thing is that in Brazil second quarter, we had very significant price reductions, that have basically to do with promotion that gave our way from free airtime. Remember, in Brazil, we are moving from what has been a very relatively high tariff low MOU combination into one that will be coming &#x2013; where we will be having lower prices with greater MOUs. Let me just point out that in Brazil, MOUs a year ago were 71 and by the end of the second quarter, we've moved them up to nearly 88. So there's been a huge increase in MOUs in Brazil and this increase has been driven by a reduction in the prices. The average revenue per minute of voice has come down in Brazil year-on-year by 25%. Okay.</p>
          <p>So that is important. We will continue to see price declines; we will continue to see important increases in profit. Remember, in Mexico, today we have roughly halved the prices and doubled the MOUs that we have in Brazil. And, it can be two countries have the same penetration, there's really no reason why we shouldn't be able to get Brazil to a situation, in which we have much higher MOUs and lower prices. So, I think that we will continue to try to get advantage from elasticity. Obviously, when you reduce prices and this is something that we mentioned last month &#x2013; last quarter, you will not immediately generate all the traffic response that you would like to see. But I think that over time we will see a very stable relationship with good elasticity response</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And also remember only to add one thing, remember that second quarter in Brazil is Mother's day. Mother's day is one of the biggest promotions that you have in Brazil. So also we have big net ads but big promotions in Mother's day, no?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot. So operator can we start now the Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> At this time, the first question comes from Vera Rossi. Vera [Morgan Stanley], your line is open. Or Andrew, I'm sorry; Andrew Campbell [Credit Suisse] your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. My question is on the regulatory environment in Mexico and given the portability has taken effect. Do you have any more clarity on what impact do you think that might have on the business, either positive or negative? And you mentioned in the press release the preliminary bindings from Cofeco on fixed to mobile rates? And can you just give us an update on what's happening with that process?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's start with the Cofeco, I think what happened is that Cofeco, preliminary said that all the players not <mark type="inaudible" />; all the carriers are dominant in their own markets. What they said is only preliminary I think in the next days, they are going to make that decision. And remember that Cofeco, they only thing that they are going to do is take that decision, then you have to go to other regulators that is Cofetel, and they have to take decision. So, we are starting what we're going to do and I think it's going to take time to decide something. It is first Cofeco, then Cofetel, then if we are not agree on the decision in Cofeco or in Cofetel then we have the chance to go to an injunction. So, well, that's I think it's not going to be a short period, it's going to take sometime.</p>
          <p>And in the other side, that the interconnection rate between mobiles that it's what they are talking about. It's being everyday, it's coming less percentage to our overall revenues. So I think &#x2013; I feel confident that it's not going to be bad for Telcel, no, so that's one thing.</p>
          <p>The second on the number portability, number portability just start, I think we do a very good advertising. I think we have the best network in Mexico. We have the best quality, nice &#x2013; we have the best technology, we are the only ones with 3G. We have the head start with iPhone. So I think that number portability it's going to be or positive or neutral for America Movil. Maybe it's going to be neutral in the first one or two months then its going to be positive because people what you see in all of the world, I think the next quarter I think you're going to see or very small positive numbers or neutral. I don't see that we're going to have as the &#x2013; more out &#x2013; I think there more port in than port outs. Net is going to be positive for Telcel.</p>
          <p>It's very important, the quality of the network; is very important. The coverage is very important. The technology and it's what all the people what is what we're seeing that all the people likes in Mexico, and I &#x2013; we're feeling very comfortable with portability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Vera Rossi [Morgan Stanley]. Vera, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Good morning, everyone. I have a question on your 3G coverage. I realize that this quarter you had a big progress in terms of covered pops. Are you ahead in terms of your plans in terms of covered pops? And my second question is that do you still plan to have all your contract users under the 3G network in the beginning of next year between the first and the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Vera. Well, we never plan to have all our postpaid customers in 3G. I think those customers are going to start changing, we are not forced them to change. But we will be very happy if they change with 3G, because 3G is going to give us more data and that means more ARPU, okay. But we are not accelerating that. You're going to see a natural migration of all those customers. The rollout with 3G is what we are expecting to have in Mexico. First quarter we do some cities, the second quarter we accelerate a lot and then in the third quarter you're going to see more acceleration. But that's more or less what we have in our budget and it's exactly what is happening in all Latin America. We don't see that we're going to invest more than the $4 billion that we have on budget and that's what you can expect. We are going to have a very good coverage of 3G, but we are not going to invest more as to what &#x2013; of what we have in our budget.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my second question is on Colombia. What do you think it will take to improve the ARPUs in Colombia, if in case you're working in this scenario, because when I look at the ARPUs in Colombia they are below the average compared to other countries with the same macroeconomic situation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me tell you what happened in Colombia. In Colombia, we have big and huge competition the last quarter of last year. We have a huge competition with Tigo and with Telef&#xF3;nica. Tigo enters the market and they reduce the prices a lot, so we have to do that to maintain &#x2013; to be competitive and maintain. The prices where low but they reduce market prices. And what you could see right now is that revenues are coming up, this second quarter are much better than the first quarter, so the elasticity is coming. We have 2% more ARPU against the first quarter of this year. So I am confident that the recovery it's going to be there. The prices are there, the elasticity is there also and you're going to see the next two quarters or a little bit more on the recovery. And I think 3G is going to help us also. 3G is not coming immediately Vera because the big amount of customers that we have in 2G against the new customers that are coming in 3G &#x2013; is coming slowly. The percentage is not so big and it's going to take us sometime to see the increase on the 3G ARPUs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just one follow-up question on the 3G migration. Approximately a year from now, what is the percentage of your traffic of your subscribers you expect to have under the 3G network?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I really don't have that number. I don't know, Carlos if you have the number, but difficult to say. The traffic, but we are prepared with capacity and it's going to depend a lot on the <mark type="inaudible" />. I think, lets say iPhone; it's bringing a lot of traffic on 3G and a lot of people on 3G. And I think that's going to give new suppliers Nokia, for Motorola, for Sony Ericsson. All those suppliers are going to improve a lot the 3G portfolio and that it's going to bring us more 3G traffic and more data and everything. So everything it's got &#x2013; I think everything it's going to come naturally. We don't have to force anything, but we don't want to force anything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you Daniel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Marchen Lada. Marchen your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. Only one question, could you please give us an update in terms of net additions for the year, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The net additions for the year, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we haven't changed our estimates; we said that if they are going to be between 21 and 22 million subscribers and that's more or less what &#x2013; we haven't changed our guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Stephen Graham [Goldman Sachs]. Stephen, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you. It's Stephen Graham from Goldman Sachs. Just a question about the reporting basis. A year ago, second quarter of '07, for example, total revenues were reported as 74 billion, 74.4 and in this release for the &#x2013; I am sorry, the report is 75.4. And in this release now in second quarter of '08, a table on page four, shows a year ago revenues as 74.4, 1 billion less than what was originally reported. And the take...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you explain again, because we &#x2013; I don't follow, here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sorry, on page four of the release that just came out. There is a table that is the overall income statement table. Right, it shows the 2Q, '08 numbers. It also shows a year ago 2Q '07 numbers. And the numbers don't match what was actually reported a year ago in 2Q '07. For example, total revenues is shown in the current release on a year ago basis, it shows 74.4. A year ago you actually reported 75.4 billion pesos for total revenue. And furthermore, the table now is labeled millions of constant pesos. And that seems odd, because I know you're not reporting in constant pesos anymore. And I'm wondering &#x2013; and also, if it were in constant pesos, the number from a year ago would have gone up, not down by 1 billion. So could you just explain what's the &#x2013; how are you &#x2013; you know, how did this table on page four &#x2013; how is the 2Q '07 column derived?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you can always call Daniela for these numbers even I know that you don't, you shouldn't call. But what I can tell you is that the numbers that we've had in this table, as we have been presenting them as through out the year, have been nominal. So what you had last year was expressed as constant pesos of whatever date this report was. This time we are only showing in millions of pesos &#x2013; nominal pesos. There is a typo on the table, so you're right in that respect. It is not constant pesos as we're reporting. It's only nominal and whatever the <mark type="inaudible" /> was last year, because last year it was reported in constant pesos...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yeah, you might want to check them, because definitely I have the two statements in front of me, and what's reported now with a year ago, don't match actually what was a reported a year ago. But I'll follow-up with Daniela. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But you can call Daniela and she can explain to you exactly, and you can check the numbers so don't worry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Alex Dumworth. Alex, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, good morning. Just a quick question, on your &#x2013; you talk about your second quarter promotions in Brazil, and just wondering whether that has a lot completely to do with the Mother's day or with the fact that Genie was coming into the market in S&#xE3;o Paulo. Or was expecting to come into the market at least sometime soon. I mean is that something that you worry about at this point. I mean, what would be your strategy once they're in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we &#x2013; I think, when you have a new competitor in the market, it's always more competition. So what I hear is that, OE is coming to S&#xE3;o Paulo at the fourth quarter of this year. We also get in, in the North of Brazil last week. As we start in the North last week. So well, we have the whole coverage in Brazil.</p>
          <p>And what we do is remember, Brazil is &#x2013; on Mother's Day, is a huge promotion day and on the Christmas season, is also a huge promotion. So the reason is that in Mother's Day everybody starts to do big promotions on subsidies, on airtime, on everything. And I think that's was &#x2013; that's really the reason why you have those numbers, why we grow our MOU and the reduction on the EBITDA.</p>
          <p>But remember, Brazil is very important for America Movil and still Brazil &#x2013; and Mexico also the penetration is low. So in Brazil as we do in Mexico as the two, three year ago or two years ago, we're looking to grow with good customers and to grow market share. And that's really our focus on Brazil right now. We have to take care about EBITDA. But at the end of day if you take care about the costs and expenses, the EBITDA if going to come if you get more revenue. So that's really what is happening, that's the strategy on Brazil, and that's what we're going to be focusing the next one or two years more in Brazil.</p>
          <p>Still 60s &#x2013; between 60 and 70% penetration for us is low. You have Argentina with a 100% penetration and Brazil is still 70% penetration. And the other important issue is that we're growing a lot our postpaid base. And when you grow postpaid base then you have more expenses, but you're going to have more revenue. Our postpaid net ads in second quarter was the highest ever in Brazil, so that's another reason why we have a little bit of the reduction on the EBITDA. But we are really happy how we're developing in Brazil and we're going to follow up our strategy there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just one follow-up on this; so should we expect the same sort of &#x2013; semi-aggressive campaign, as Genie comes into the market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That I don't know, that you have to ask OE not us, they are coming to Sao Paulo, I don't know how aggressive they are going to come. It's not only pricing, remember when you get in the market then you have to do a lot of things, not only price. You have to grow distribution, you have to have a good network, you have to have quality. And while this is &#x2013; if they have everything at the beginning plus good prices, then they're going to be a little bit more tough. But I don't think that in a big market like Sao Paulo and the State of Sao Paulo you can get everything &#x2013; all these things immediately. So you have to construct a lot there.</p>
          <p>So well, I don't know really what's going to be the &#x2013; the strategy on OE. And the other thing is they are entering in Sao Paulo, but they have other customers, other regions they're in Brazil, so if they're going to be very aggressive in Sao Paulo, well, the other ones are going to be very aggressive in their markets. So well, it's competition and then we have to see what's going to happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Fernando Ramos [GBM Research]. Mr. Ramos your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. This is Fernando Ramos with GBM. I have two questions. Firstly, your SG&amp;A has continued to increase above the growth seen in revenues. And I was wondering if you could comment on this, and if this is a result of 3G launch? Basically, if you expect this trend to continue during 2009?</p>
          <p>And secondly, I see that your other financial expenses continue to be high; you recorded 2 billion. And I was wondering if this should continue going forward. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, well the first question, the SG&amp;A, well, it's increasing. I have to check exactly what, how much, and, in each country, why we're increasing the SG&amp;A. And we can talk to &#x2013; if you can call us later to Daniela.</p>
          <p>We can see but I think its going to be mainly because the acquisition costs, that we have more than what we had last year. We have been growing more subscribers with a higher price of the handset. So better handsets with color screen, with camera, and that give us a little bit more expenses there. And if you want to check with Daniela exactly in each country and how much in each country would be &#x2013; then we can clarify to a question. And the second one what you said?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In other financial expenses, you recorded an expense of 2 billion, an increase of 155%. But there was a significant increase during the first quarter, as well. And I was wondering if &#x2013; what this is related to? What we should &#x2013; if this should continue during the next quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have mentioned before, that in the other financial, you have the effect of derivatives or forwards with which we hedge our currency position. So sometimes when you have an FX gain on the underlying position, you might have a corresponding loss on the other financial. But that's what we've mentioned before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Walter Piecyk [Pali Research]. Walter your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Daniel, last quarter we talked a lot about, I guess, Easter and now I think Mother's Day is coming up a lot. I guess my kids celebrated Father's Day in June, right? But I'm told that in Brazil Father's Day is in the third quarter. I'm also told that I guess there's going to some aggressive promotions around Father's Day, but just curious if you can just review with us some of the holidays to expect for Q3 in each of the markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What's your question; I don't understand your question. It's the holidays...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it seems like every quarter we talk about holidays, so I just want to know ahead of time what holidays that we need to plan for Q3. I know in Brazil, for example, Father's Day is in August, and I think some of the operators there have talked about re-initiating a lot of these aggressive price promotions for Father's Day?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's very difficult. You know what are the holidays, the Easters and Christmas and everything, so I don't have to tell; you can plan the holidays. The second, it's very difficult for me to tell you what we're going to do, because I'm not deciding what's happening in the market.</p>
          <p>In each market you're going to see different competition, different things. And what I'm telling you is that I &#x2013; in first quarter, I don't know how aggressive it's going to come, Mother's Day in Brazil. In Mexico wasn't so aggressive, in Brazil was aggressive. So it's very difficult for me to tell you what's going to happen in Christmas and what's going to be the promotion. So the market I don't manage. I manage America Movil, I don't manage the market. So you know which ones are the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm obviously asking because you referred during your comments as an excuse on why Brazil was weak?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No it's not an excuse. I am telling you exactly why it's happening in Brazil. It's not an excuse. And that's the decision that we take. The decision is we go more for subscribers than for EBITDA at this moment in Brazil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You have followed the company for quite sometime. You've also known, that for, in the second quarter, in Brazil is the second largest selling holiday, and after Christmas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I agree. But what I look at &#x2013; Carlos, when you look at the numbers in Brazil, you can back out the extra gross ads and unless you had to jump up in CPGA, your core margins took a big hit in Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have just been talking about reduction in prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Promotions, no?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just the only other question I have, Carlos, is &#x2013; is your leverage ratio is still at 0.6. Can you just explain the share repurchases or is there some type of limit of what you can do as it relates to retained earnings? Or is there some type of acquisitions that you are looking at that prevents you guys from taking the leverage up to 1x?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't have any problem with taking leverage up to 1x. We &#x2013; in fact today, we have already these <mark type="inaudible" /> we had with that for $2 billion. So we have the money accessible, the fact that we haven't drawn on it is because we haven't yet had the need to use it because the cash flow that we've been generating, as I mentioned in my summary, has been quite substantial. So we don't really have an issue with liquidity. We have outstanding facilities available. As of today, we have $2 billion in cash...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So why not tender, why not put like a $2.5 billion tender for stock at 50 bucks a share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have &#x2013; you know that our preference is to continue to buy in the market. And we continue to buy in the market, but we are open to various possibilities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Richard Denine [HSBC]. Richard, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Just a question on the iPhone 3G and margins going-forward; looking at your sort of mid-tier plan, I guess the 5.99 peso monthly plan, you are pricing your iPhones at kind of similar levels to AT&amp;T in the U.S., about 180 U.S. for the 8-gig and 285 or so for the 16-gig. AT&amp;T is guiding for, let say, a two to three percentage point reduction in wireless margins and 10 to 12 cents of EPS dilution this year and next due to subsidies and dealer commissions related to the iPhone. I was just wondering how we might think about this for America Movil? If it's maybe possible for you to give us similar kind of framework, at some stage, or perhaps just for now, just to talk in broad terms?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's a very good question. I don't have exactly the numbers. What I can tell you what's going to happen with the iPhone is, the iPhone is going to give us more revenue, its going to give us growth in the ARPU. At the other side we are going to have more subsidies, the iPhone is not &#x2013; it's an expensive handset so to sell it at these prices, we are going to have more subsidies.</p>
          <p>But I don't have exactly the numbers, because I also don't have exactly the amount of handsets that we are going to get from Apple and that we are going to sell in each country. It's still very difficult; they are sold out. So we don't know exactly what we're going to have for the year.</p>
          <p>But, when we have more clarity on the amount of handsets, then we can tell you exactly. Its very important, also, how many people are changing their handsets and how many people are new in the networks with the iPhone. So, we are new on iPhone, its only 15 days that we get the handsets, so we need to have a little bit more on data to understand exactly what's going to happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yes, fair enough. Just if &#x2013; I could just squeeze in one more just quickly; just, I guess, with Vodafone this morning and the macro question the relative defensiveness wireless are very much in focus. And also, some comments, perhaps close to home, from Millicom suggesting that it's seeing an impact on consumer disposable income from rising inflation.</p>
          <p>I just wanted to see if you're seeing any evidence of this in your markets and, if not yet, do you have any expectations of this going forward? I guess, particularly, as it regards data spending. So any color on that would be fantastic. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a difficult question. I think it depends a lot on the economies. I think one of the sectors that are going to be less hurt if we have a slowdown in Latin America is going to be the wireless, I'm totally sure on that. But while we have a slowdown then we're going to see that. At this moment we're not seeing anything there.</p>
          <p>What we're going to see at this moment is more reduction on prices, more growth on MOU, and the elasticity coming as that. You know what's happened in the first quarter in Mexico, the second quarter is better. What Carlos explained on Brazil, we're growing the MOU and coming are the revenues. So at this moment, we're not seeing a slowdown there. I think maybe Vodafone, because it's in Europe, having more problems on economies than in Latin America. But we are not seeing in America Movil something like that.</p>
          <p>No, we're still having that elasticity, and the elasticity is coming and the price reductions are there. And we are more or less happy on &#x2013; the postpaid customer let's say in Brazil, postpaid customers are coming, when you having a slowdown, you move from postpaid to prepaid. Last quarter we have the best quarter in Brazil on postpaid customer. So well, we are not seeing any indicators to &#x2013; of those reductions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, very much appreciate your comments. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from James Breen [Thomas Weisel Partners]. James your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. A few questions, specifically in Colombia and Peru, can you just talk about what's going on there? You seem to have good growth in Colombia overall. And in Peru it seemed that churns spiked up some, if you can comment on those.</p>
          <p>And then, just generally speaking, we've seen some revisions lately with on the inflation numbers in Brazil coming upward, and remittances coming back to Latin American and generally being down. Can you please talk about the economy in general and across the regions? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On Peru, basically the increase in churn is, we're taking the connections on our clients that we have taken on in November and December. And that they're basically, were change in the second quarter. In the case of Columbia, we're actually seeing very, very good MOU growth. If you look at &#x2013; and these are also in spite of the significant change, increasing subscriber growth that we've seen quite a substantial reacceleration of subscriber growth in that country.</p>
          <p>By just to talk to &#x2013; give you some perspective. MOUs have grown from an increase of 9.2% year-on-year in the first quarter of '07 to a steady 3.9% increase in the second quarter of '08. So we have seen a consistent expansion of MOUs in the country. And this has helped turn back what have been some declining ARPUs reported in this last quarter, as Daniel has mentioned. We have seen an increase of 2% in the ARPU in the country.</p>
          <p>Now, as in Mexico, and as we are now seeing in Brazil, we are seeing quite substantial price decline, this &#x2013; over and above what we have seen in the interconnection rates, that, as you know, fell by 50% last January. But if you look at the average revenue per minute of voice, the decline today, year-on-year, is 33.3%, okay? So we are seeing, I think, good usage growth with traffic increases basically offsetting the decline in prices.</p>
          <p>And I think that we are quite optimistic about the potential for Columbia. Columbia is doing very well economically. They are an oil producing country and they are next to Venuzuela, which again is a big oil producing country that buys a lot of products from Columbia. So the economy in Columbia is doing quite well. And, as we had mentioned before, the expansion of consumption in several countries have benefited the wireless growth. So we expect to continue to do well in Columbia. What was the third question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just, economically, it seems that some inflation revisions in Brazil upward and just wondering how sort of the state of the world, so to speak, is affecting the economics &#x2013; the economies in both Brazil and Mexico?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have seen some increases in inflationary pressures very much across the board. And, as you know, that's led to some hikes in interest rates. But we are not really seeing this having a major impact, again, at least on our market. The fact of the matter is that the countries are growing well. There is big money and partly because of the sales of our &#x2013; of commodities, partly because of our foreign investment. But the fact of the matter is investment and consumption are going at a good pace and that is driving growth and that is driving our revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then just one final question, we've been talking about the spectrum &#x2013; about the spectrum options in both Brazil and Mexico for about a year now at least, and we were supposed to see rules in Mexico months ago and it hadn't happened. What's the latest that you guys have found out in terms of when's some potential options there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Brazil, we already have the options and we have the license and we are putting &#x2013; we already pay them. So, in Brazil we already have them. And in Mexico, well, I don't know. The regulators are saying, well, what the last thing that they said was June, July. And what I'm reading in the news is that they're going to be at the end of this year. I don't know exactly what is happening and what's their reason why they are delaying things in Mexico. But, well, in Mexico Telcel doesn't need the &#x2013; immediately, licenses. So we can wait until they decide to auction them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So in Mexico, it doesn't sound like this year. But in Brazil, I think the HPN was still unresolved, is there any &#x2013; have you heard anything further there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. I don't hear anything there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Steve Malcolm [Arete Research]. Steve, you line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Steve Malcolm from Arete Research. Three questions, please. First, can you give us your current expectation on the Brazilian termination rate, regime and framework? When you think we'll get an announcement on the new framework? And what your expectations are for moves in the termination rates over the next couple of years?</p>
          <p>Secondly, on the CapEx number for the first half. Can you try and break that down into tangible CapEx spends and intangibles, which is a noticeable aspect from Brazil.</p>
          <p>And the final question, just a sort of housekeeping question on the tax rate, which came in a bit below your 28%, I think, guidance for the year in the second quarter. Can you just update us on where you taking the tax rate will turn out for the full year? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't &#x2013; what they said in Brazil is that in I think &#x2013; I don't have exactly the dates that in 2008 there's going to be cost structure, the interconnection rates but still not being &#x2013; has been done. And we're waiting for more information in Brazil about the interconnection rates. The second question, what you told me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to understand your CapEx split between the bit that goes on fixed assets side and the bit that goes to intangible. Trying to split the 26.7 and work out what the depreciable base is. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't understand the question again, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Trying to split the 26 &#x2013; your CapEx spend in the first half was 26.7 billion. I'm split that into tangible and intangible. Does that not make sense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the only intangible was the license &#x2013; the spectrum of Brazil that's there, around $800 million, the rest is the CapEx, that's the number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Clearly the intangibles &#x2013; the Mexican sort of Brazilian spectrum thing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's only the Brazilian spectrum, the $800 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the tax rate &#x2013; the effective tax rate in second quarter was 25.7%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a little bit less than our guidance. I think the guidance for the year should be &#x2013; if not changed, it should be approximately 28%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just back on the first question. I mean, in terms of &#x2013; I understand that we don't have visibility yes on what Anatel's going to do, but in terms of you're planning, are you expecting steep current termination rates or a more moderate glide path and when you plan the tariffs and the make-up of your Brazilian business going forward. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again not heard, I'm sorry. And I don't hear you very well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. I'm calling from a mobile. Just to come back on the first question with regards to Brazilian termination rates. I just &#x2013; I understand that we don't have great visibility yet, but I just wanted to understand, in your planning horizons, what you think is likely to happen in terms the directions due to change, whether &#x2013; when you look at your tariff plans, whether you should be expecting a big cut in the next two or three years or more moderate...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the best thing to do is to moderate &#x2013; to have let's say two, three, four-year planning &#x2013; the interconnection rates in Brazil are high right now and I think they will go down. And the best thing for the industry, for everybody, is to have, during the years, to slow down the interconnection. So I think that's what's going to happen and what we're going to see there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think that's &#x2013; what we're likely to see is that as time goes by and we continue to reduce share price, there is going to be much more profits on our own network, and in the mobile-to-mobile networks. So the importance of fixed-to-mobile, which is really what would be more affected by a reduction in interconnection rates, will eventually come down significantly. As you know for instance in Mexico today, fixed-to-mobile revenues are less than 10%, it's all in the 8% range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Becoming &#x2013; coming from 25% or something like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. In Colombia it's really about 5%. So I'd say that in Brazil in a couple of years fixed-to-mobile revenues will become a relatively small portion of service revenues. So they will not be affected by a reduction in interconnection rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So do you have the percentage of those revenues in Brazil at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have them right in front of me, but if you call up Daniela or myself, we'll provide them to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it can enable for 25% today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Super, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Henry Cobbe. Henry, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks very much for the call. It's Henry Cobbe from Nevsky Capital. Just a few questions if possible. The first is the pressure on ARPU in Mexico, would you say that is predominantly from promotions or is it from declining fixed-to-mobile volumes? And that's the first question. The second question also Mexico, since the launch of MNP in early July, are you seeing or budgeting for increased retention costs, as well as the high acquisition costs from the iPhone and 3G rollout? The third questions is -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wait a minute; remember that second question is we start iPhone on July, so you don't see anything on the numbers with the iPhone. IPhone starts on July the 11th.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But on retention costs for postpaid subscribers, whether you are seeing competition increase on the postpaid side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There may be. With portability what we have been doing is retaining our subscribers and maybe it's going to take us a little bit more cost, but that's the only thing that you saw in April, May, and June, to have that retention a little bit sooner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on the tariffs, in terms of what's from promotions and what's from fixed-to-mobile volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, fixed-to-mobiles that at the beginning was 10%, at the beginning of the year we reduced 10%, that's something, but well, the competition is very high. And we have been having some promotions as I said there, so we have both ARPU returns from 174 to 178. So I think the recovery on the ARPU was good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but I'm just interested actually in the fixed-to-mobile volumes, because although the 10% reduction in the rate, it seems like it's the volumes that have taken a nosedive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, fixed-to-mobile, I don't have the numbers here, but certainly they have increased, and I think that that's something that we have been mentioning in terms of the &#x2013; we're not seeing anything elasticity on the fixed-to-mobile, as I mentioned. Because basically first of all, it was not a big reduction, less than 10% reduction, secondly the people in fixed lines do not advertise that the price has come down.</p>
          <p>We ourselves do not tell our clients that calling from our fixed-to-mobile now costs less. So people are not aware of the price reduction, and therefore, they do not react &#x2013; and adjust their consumption accordingly. So we're not seeing much elasticity there. There has been a little bit of a growth, but not much. So basically what you're seeing is fixed-to-mobile continues to grow each quarter and we have seen in all the other countries, in Colombia I mentioned before, in Argentina, it's come down in Mexico, Daniel did mention we have come down from than 25% to less than 10% today's sales revenue. And I think the trend will continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the last two questions, just on MTN, as you know you maybe even watching the interesting story with Reliance and MTN and this bid that got scuttled by the Reliance Industries. And would you be interested in acquiring an African asset that's going to be further down the penetration curve, is that something that you'd be potentially interested in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, we're interesting in acquiring any company that would be &#x2013; that looks financially good for ourselves. I think we are open to anyplace that &#x2013; we'd prefer growth places like Africa, but it's going to depends a lot on the price. So that's what we have been telling and that &#x2013; and that's what we're waiting. So the &#x2013; if that's &#x2013; the price is a good price for America Movil then we're open to do anything there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then, previously you've already focused on the South America, Central America, so is it a new change that you are now looking at assets outside of your traditional area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Henry, I've been mentioning for quite some time now, but we in America Movil are open to going to all the regions of the world so long as it is something that makes sense. I think that we are capable. We have the resources. We would be keen to do it. But we are by no means in a rush.  We have been always very disciplined regarding acquisitions and we intend to continue to be so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the very last question is just on Brazilian margins. You highlighted in the report that acquisition costs have increased, and sales and marketing costs have increased again in the second quarter relative to the first quarter. And coming back to the issue of whether you would consider doing a similar new strategy in Brazil, <mark type="inaudible" /> is pursuing this quite successfully, obviously it has a lower ARPU. But the payback period versus acquisition cost is also much quicker. So I'm just interested in whether you are considering launching something similar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know exactly what they are launching and what their &#x2013; exactly their promotion, but overall, our strategy in Brazil is we think that the penetration is low. We're going to go for good subscribers. We're going to be growing it, what we do in Mexico sometime ago. And it's what we're looking in Brazil. So we are of course worried about the EBITDA, but we are not going to &#x2013; because of EBITDA and to have instead of 23% or 25% EBITDA, to have 30% EBITDA, then we're going to lose our market share of good subscribers. Sill, I think in Brazil you are going to see 20 or 30 million new subscribers in the next months or years and that we want to get more subscribers, then EBITDA will come later. So that's what &#x2013; that's actually really the strategy in Brazil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mauricio Fernandes [Merrill Lynch]. Mauricio, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Two questions &#x2013; good morning everyone. First of all, it's a bit surprising that &#x2013; that in Mexico the EBITDA margin went up to 53.5% roughly speaking, from 52% in the first quarter. There is the dilution to costs coming from new revenues from 3G but at the same time, I would have expected the handset subsidies to be higher, particularly because you are &#x2013; you have people migrating to 3G handsets. So the question is more on &#x2013; to Carlos or Daniel &#x2013; the outlook for the EBITDA margin in Mexico whether we should see it at these levels now, or come back to the first quarter's 52%? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And second question, not sure if you have addressed this already, but in terms of the CapEx for the year, if you could give us an update now, including the spectrum in Brazil, or excluding just to be clear, that would be great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Mauricio. When &#x2013; after the first quarter I have mentioned to you that we have seen a reduction in service revenues that have had a direct impact on EBITDA. And that was, as we have mentioned before, partly, on our conference, taken into consideration. So basically, what we have in the second quarter is another manifestation of that. We have more service revenues, which have a direct impact on EBITDA as well. And that's a quite expense &#x2013; that's a big change in margins.</p>
          <p>We're not in the business of forecasting our EBITDA margin on a quarterly basis, so I'm not going to be giving you any numbers. But the only thing that I said is, first quarter we said, we have abnormally low service revenues because of a number of factors, including seasonal and those had a direct impact on EBITDA as well as obviously. On EBITDA, and that's something that disappeared in second quarter.</p>
          <p>From here now on I think the only thing that is important to reiterate to you about it we have, as already said, we have launched the iPhone. Increasingly we will have more smart phones in our menu of offers of handsets. Increasingly moving from the not-smart handsets to smart handsets will represent broadly greater subsidy and that might have not so impact on margins initially which we expect that we will more than make up for with our increased output down the road. So I think the only thing &#x2013; again, I wouldn't want to get into anything predicting the EBITDA margin on a quarterly basis. We don't &#x2013; we have never provided guidance on that. But I think the underlying trends are very good and the only thing that I would make to &#x2013; adjust is that we will have, the mix of phones that we sell is going to change and that will entail from what &#x2013; various subsidies on the overall mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on &#x2013; yes, on CapEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The question on CapEx was &#x2013; the new guidance or the -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The guidance was $4 billion and we're &#x2013; yes, and we're going to stay there. We're not going to spend more than $4 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just one more thing if I may, in Colombia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>With the 50% mobile termination rate cut that happened in December, the ARPU went down in the first quarter, coupled with the seasonality. I would have expected the ARPU to increase more than the 2% Q-on-Q increase that we saw in the second quarter. I know that off-net rates represent the small amount of total traffic for AMX in Colombia, but just as a sense for the dynamics, whether you see the ARPU outlook for Colombia, given what I said?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that in Colombia one of the things is that in the quarter, the growth of the subscriber base was 4.6%; that was rather huge. And as you know all of those new subscribers will not immediately generate the traffic that we want from them, but they weigh on the ARPU numbers. So we went up 2% in the quarter even in spite of the fact that we ended up adding 4.6% more subscribers. Okay. So I think that's <mark type="inaudible" /> these things.</p>
          <p>I think that Colombia is in really good shape, as I mentioned before. The country is doing very well economically, it's growing nicely, and we are in a very good position. In our market we have nearly 70% market share and we are introducing new products, we are doing the 3G rollout, so we are quite comfortable what our prospects in Colombia so far.</p>
          <p>Thank you. Andre, I think that we have now to end the call because it's been a little over an hour.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So we're going to end up the call now. I would like to thank everyone participating in the call, especially Daniel Hajj, Carlos Garcia-Moreno. Thank you all and have a nice day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for participating in today's conference call. Parties may disconnect at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>