<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1304709" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>38</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Rob Eldridge, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Thomas J. Szkutak, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Colin Sebastian</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">James Mitchell</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Douglas Anmuth</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Youssef Squali</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Brian Pitz</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Mark Mahaney</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Scott Devitt</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Jeetil Patel</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Steve Weinstein</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Imran Khan</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Ben Schachter</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Justin Post</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Spencer Wang</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day everyone and welcome to the Amazon.com First Quarter 2010 Financial Results Conference Call. As a reminder, today's call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>At this time I would like to turn the call over to Mr. Rob Eldridge. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, and welcome to our Q1 2010 financial results conference call. Joining us today is Tom Szkutak, our CFO. We will be available for questions after our prepared remarks.</p>
          <p>The following discussion and responses to your questions reflect management's views as of today, April 22, 2010 only and will include forward-looking statements. Actual results may differ materially. Additional information about factors that could potentially impact our financial results is included in today's press release and our filings with the SEC, including our most recent annual report on Form 10-K.</p>
          <p>As you listen to today's call we encourage you to have our press release in front of you, which includes our financial results as well as metrics and commentary on the quarter.</p>
          <p>During this call we will discuss certain non-GAAP financial measures. In our press release, slides accompanying this webcast and our filings with the SEC, each of which is posted on our IR website, you will find additional disclosures regarding these non-GAAP measures including reconciliations of these measures with comparable GAAP measures.</p>
          <p>Finally, unless otherwise stated, all comparisons in this call will be against our results for the comparable period of 2009.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn the call over to Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob.</p>
          <p>I'll begin with comments or our financial results. Trailing 12-month free cash flow grew 62% to $2.32 billion. Return on invested capital is 45% up from 41%. ROIC is TTM free cash flow divided by average total assets minus current liabilities excluding the current portion of long-term debt over five quarter ends.</p>
          <p>The combination of common stock and stock-based awards outstanding was 463 million shares, compared with 447 million.</p>
          <p>Worldwide revenue grew 46% to 7.13 billion or 42% excluding the $185 million favorable impact from year-over-year changes in foreign exchange rates.</p>
          <p>We're grateful to our customers who continue to take advantage of our low prices, vast selection and free shipping offers including Amazon Prime.</p>
          <p>Media revenue increased to $3.43 billion up 26% or 22% excluding foreign exchange rates. EGM revenue increased to $3.51 billion up 72% or 68% excluding FX. Worldwide EGM increased to 49% of worldwide sales up from 42%.</p>
          <p>Worldwide unit growth was 40%. Active customer accounts exceeded 114 million. For the first time this number includes our Amazon China customer accounts. Worldwide active seller accounts were approximately 2 million, up 22%. Seller units were 31% of total units.</p>
          <p>Consolidated gross profit grew 42% to $1.63 billion and gross margin decreased 62 basis points to 22.9%. We no longer present gross profit in our consolidated statement of operations as we believe income from operations is a more meaningful measure due to the diversity of our product categories and services. Our focus is on growing operating profit dollars rather than maximizing margin percentages.</p>
          <p>Now I'll discuss operating expenses excluding stock based compensation. Fulfillment, marketing, tech and content and G&amp;A combined was $1.12 billion or 15.8% of sales, down 115 basis points year-over-year. Fulfillment was $528 million or 7.4% of revenue compared with 8.3%. Tech and content was $319 million or 4.5% of revenue compared with 4.9%. Marketing was $196 million or 2.7% of revenue, up from 2.5% in the prior year.</p>
          <p>Now I'll talk about our segment results and consistent with prior periods we do not allocate to segments our stock based compensation or other operating expense line items. In North America, segment revenue grew 47% to $3.78 billion. Media revenue grew 22% to $1.6 billion. EGM revenue grew 73% to $2.02 billion represent 54% of North America revenues, up from 45%. North America segment operating income increased 81% to $273 million, a 7.2% operating margin.</p>
          <p>In the international segment, revenue grew 45% to $3.35 billion. Revenue growth was 37% adjusting for the $175 million year-over-year favorable FX impact during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Media revenue grew 29% to $1.83 billion or 23% excluding FX. And EGM revenue grew 70% to $1.49 billion or 61% excluding FX. EGM now represents 44% of international revenues, up from 38%.</p>
          <p>International segment operating income increased 37% to $234 million, at 7% operating margin. Excluding the favorable impact from foreign exchange rates, international segment operating income increased 26%.</p>
          <p>CSOI grew 58% to $507 million or 7.1% of revenue, up 53 basis points year over year. Excluding the $15 million favorable impact from foreign exchange rates, CSOI grew 53%.</p>
          <p>Unlike CSOI, our GAAP operating income includes stock-based compensation expense and other operating expense. GAAP operating income grew 62% to $394 million, or 5.5% of net sales.</p>
          <p>Our income tax expense was $100 million in Q1 or a 25% rate for the quarter.</p>
          <p>GAAP net income was $299 million or $0.66 per diluted share compared with $177 million and $0.41 per diluted share.</p>
          <p>Turning to the balance sheet, cash and marketable securities increased $2.33 billion year over year to 5.06 billion. Inventory increased 44% to 1.82 billion. And inventory turns were 12.6, up from 12.5 turns a year ago even as we expanded selection, improved in-stock levels, and introduced new product categories.</p>
          <p>Accounts payable increased 52% to $3.62 billion, and accounts payable days increased to 59 from 57 in the prior year.</p>
          <p>Our Q1 2010 capital expenditures were $140 million. The increase in capital expenditures reflects additional investments in technology infrastructure including Amazon Web Services, additional investments in support of continued business growth including capacity to support fulfillment operations, and investments in corporate office space which we expect to continue throughout 2010.</p>
          <p>I'll conclude my portion of today's call with guidance. Incorporated into the guidance are the order trends that we've seen to date and what we believe today to be appropriately conservative assumptions. Our results are inherently unpredictable and may be materially affected by many factors including a high level of uncertainty surrounding exchange rate fluctuations as well as the global economy and consumer spending. It is not possible to accurately predict demand and therefore our actual results could differ materially from our guidance.</p>
          <p>As we describe in more detail in our public filings issues such as settling intercompany balances and foreign currencies amongst our subsidiaries, unfavorable resolution of legal matters and changes to our effective tax rates can all have a material effect on guidance.</p>
          <p>Our guidance further assumes that we don't conclude any additional business acquisitions or investments, record any further revisions to stock-based compensation estimates and that foreign exchange rates remain approximately where they have been recently.</p>
          <p>For Q2, we expect net sales of between 6.1 and $6.7 billion, or growth of between 31 and 44%. This anticipates approximately 100 basis points of positive impact from foreign exchange; GAAP operating income to be between 220 and $320 million or to grow between 39 and 102%.</p>
          <p>The second quarter of 2009 results includes the impact of our settlement with Toys"R"Us for $51 million, substantially all of which was expensed during the quarter. This includes approximately $130 million for stock-based compensation and amortization of intangible assets. We anticipate consolidated segment operating income which excludes stock-based compensation and other operating expense be between 350 and $450 million, a growth of between 15 and 48%.</p>
          <p>We remain heads down focused on driving a better customer experience through price, selection, and convenience. We believe that putting the customer first is the only reliable way to create lasting value for shareholders. Thanks.</p>
          <p>And with that, Rob, let's move to questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Tom. Let's move on to the Q&amp;A portion of the call. Operator, will you please remind our listeners how to initiate a question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We'll go first to Colin Sebastian with Lazard Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and congratulations on a very strong quarter. I wonder if you could talk a little bit about the same day delivery program, how that's playing out in cities where it's offered and is it something that could be rolled out more broadly if successful in testing in the existing markets?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Probably the best way to describe it is, you know, similar to other programs that we have related to fast shipping, meaning Prime, we're finding that customers like it. You know, we certainly think that customers like the reliability of getting, you know, their products so efficiently, so quickly. And you know, hard to say what we'll do, you know, beyond what we're doing today with same day. But we certainly think that, you know, getting a product to customers fast is important.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to James Mitchell with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions. One is with regard to the very large active customer number, that includes China but not Zappos?  I just want to check. I assume there was like maybe 5 million each from China and Zappos if you did include Zappos.</p>
          <p>Secondly, when I look at the expansion in North American operating margins in the quarter was that helped by sales of digital media and also of Amazon Web Services? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take the second part first. You know, the North America expansion was driven by, you know, a number of things. Certainly the very strong growth and then it was also driven by, you know, us being able to leverage our overall expenses. If you take a look at our global fulfillment cost as a percentage of revenue you can certainly see a lot of leverage there. And that's also true when you look at North America. We haven't added, you know, any significant capacity in North America since Q3 of '08. You know, certainly with the growth rates that you're seeing you should expect that we will be adding capacity over time there. But again, it was driven by a lot of different factors. And, you know, with a lot of different product categories growing very strong and us being able to leverage those expenses.</p>
          <p>In terms of the first part, could you repeat the first part again? It was related to &#x2013; the first part is...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the customers did that include China and also Zappos or just China and is it fair to assume that each of China and Zappos would contribute about 5 million active customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, James. You're correct the active customer number does not include Zappos but it does include China this quarter for the first time. We're not at this point breaking out the addition of China at this point. So it's 114 million active customers worldwide at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Douglas Anmuth with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, just two quick questions. Can you comment on the head count? It looks like it went up by about 1800 people on a sequential basis. It's certainly a larger number than we would have expected.</p>
          <p>And then the second one is just the tax rate being a little bit higher at 25% and is that purely just a function of higher North America profit?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first part in terms of head count, the biggest piece of that is related to fulfillment. You know, when we -- coming out of Q4, we always, you know, have certain people additions related to that. And so again, a sizeable piece of that incremental head count was due to operations and the rest was certainly in areas to help us grow as we move forward.</p>
          <p>In terms of the effective tax rate, certainly the mix of our geographies is certainly &#x2013; was making that change, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Youssef Squali with Jefferies &amp; Co.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Two quick questions for Tom. First, one of your competitors talked about seeing some weakness in Europe ex-U.K. And looking at your international margins it looks like they came a little bit under pressure, they were down about 40 or 50 bps year-over-year. Is that something you guys saw as well?</p>
          <p>And then by our estimates, the change in accounting for Kindle that you instituted in Q1 resulted &#x2013; again, at least by our math, in somewhere between 80 and $100 million of additional revenues for the quarter. Can you maybe just help us understand if we're in the right zip code there?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question, we're not breaking out individual geographies within the international segment. But what you're seeing in international is very strong growth. And we were pleased across all of our geographies, we saw, excluding the impact of foreign exchange rates, we saw growth of 37%, you know, which is certainly very good. And it was driven by, you know, a number of things. Certainly we've added many new categories and a lot of selection over the past few years. And you know, we certainly have &#x2013; we're focused on making sure that we have great competitive low prices and which is certainly fueling growth. Prime is also a factor. And you know, third party growth, you know, continues to be very strong. And so those are the factors that are driving the international growth.</p>
          <p>In terms of the change in accounting for Kindle, you know, we're not breaking out the &#x2013; you know, any precise numbers on that. But the way you should think about it is, you know, maybe a few different items. One is if you look at our overall growth rate and you look at on a local currency basis and we certainly have for the first time a full quarter of Zappos included in those numbers, as well as the change in accounting for Kindle, and if you back out, you know, exchange and those two items and you compare it to the equivalent growth rate in Q4, you did see a, you know, a few hundred basis points, you know, acceleration in growth from Q4 to Q1. So, you know, I can't give you much more of a breakout of that, but you can see that we did see an acceleration in growth there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Brian Pitz with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you comment on the impetus to begin selling the Kindle through brick and mortar stores and do you expect to make the device more widely available?  Also, just curious why the rollout is limited to so few stores. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's starting with, you know, a small number of stores but we're very pleased to be working with Target and we're very pleased to have even more customers see Kindle and have the opportunity to purchase Kindle. So that's why we're doing it. And we're very excited to do it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Mark Mahaney with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I know you may not want to talk so much about gross margins. I understand you're running the business for operating profits and cash flow, but could you provide a little bit more color on the gross margin trends, particularly in international markets, given what should be some pretty positive mix shifts since scale factors the mix shift towards the digital goods and AWS and things like that. The trends seem a little surprising, anything in terms of vendor terms, product mixes that may have explained the gross margin trends?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of international, it was primarily driven by certainly a number of factors. We continued to have lower prices and make sure that we have great competitive prices in a challenging environment, which includes free shipping offers and Amazon Prime included in that. Keep in mind that we've launched many new categories over the past few years. And so as we've talked about in the past, it takes some time to get the scale in those categories, and we're seeing very broad growth across many categories, including the new categories. And so that's certainly that mix is having an impact. And all those factors are being partially offset by very strong solid third-party growth as well as the savings that we'll get from our vendor partners. So again, those are the key drivers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One quick follow-up on marketing for the Kindle. Is there any change in your thinking of the level of marketing support you want to provide given obviously a much more competitive environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of marketing itself, you saw that it increased a little bit as a percentage of revenue year over year. And we are doing advertising for Kindle. It's certainly a product in an area that we're very excited about. And you've probably seen some of the ads that we're doing as well as doing online marketing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Scott Devitt with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks for taking the question. The first quarter operating margin was 7.1%, and at the midpoint of revenue and operating margin on a cash basis in 2Q I think it's 6.3%. So Tom, could you just talk through what the factors are that would drive operating margin down sequentially that order of magnitude?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, stock-based compensation I think you guided to 110 million and did 87 and then guided to 130 in 2Q. So what's the volatility in that line item in the first quarter and going forward? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take the second part first. The 87 is actually the equivalent of stock-based compensation and amortization of intangibles, which is 113, so it's going from 113 to 130.</p>
          <p>In terms of the operating margin, we're not giving operating margin guidance for Q2 but the implied operating margin, we do have a &#x2013; consistent with what we've done in prior periods, we have a range of operating income, and that range is 350 to 450. At the lower end of the range, it's 5.7% of implied operating margin and 6.7 on the high end. On the high end, you'd see an expansion of operating margins of approximately 20 basis points year over year. And so that's the guidance based upon what we see by looking at all the factors. And so there's not much I can help you with that.</p>
          <p>One thing to keep in mind though as I mentioned in one of the earlier questions with growth we're experiencing, we need to make sure we support that growth. And what that means is we'll continue to add capacity in our various businesses to support that growth, whether it be our retail business, our AWS business, or third-party seller businesses including FBA. And so those are things that we certainly are supporting given the growth that we're having.</p>
          <p>The other thing is we'll continue as we have in prior years. We still think there's a lot of opportunity in front of us. And so as we have in prior years, we'll make sure that we're judicious about where we make those additions, but we will add resources to make sure that we capitalize on those growth opportunities. So those are the things that we're thinking about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Jeetil Patel with Deutsche Bank Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, two questions. I guess the unit growth nicely accelerated from the fourth quarter levels and the trend line you've been seeing historically. Can you talk about whether that's more of a function of the domestic business and still seeing very good purchase frequency or international now participating as Prime has now been out there for well north of two years?</p>
          <p>And then second, just a broader question but in a world where we're going towards mobile and smart phones from a media consumption standpoint, can you talk about what is the opportunity from an eCommerce standpoint?  Do you think that it will be just as good a kind of an eCommerce oriented environment on a mobile device as you see in the desktop internet world since it's a smaller form factor, smaller screen?  How do you have to change, if you have to, in terms of how you present information to consumers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeetil, I'll take the second part of your question first. We're excited about the idea that the world may shift to a place where 3G connected devices are available to browse the net. And our view is that the more web-connected devices, whether it be tablets or smart phones, the better that is for our retail business, as you're suggesting. And we'll figure out the best way to make sure that we make it as easy as possible for customers to purchase from those devices. But we think that's it's an exciting opportunity to have a world that looks like that.</p>
          <p>In terms of your unit question, as you could probably expect, given the growth that we're seeing both in North America and international from a revenue perspective, we're seeing very good growth in units as well. And so we're very pleased with the unit growth we're seeing in both segments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess on the former question that I asked about how mobile changes the world, does that give you an advantage as you look at your recommendations capability, which you've been building in terms of that database and kind of cross-comparison of what people are buying in terms of across categories and products?</p>
          <p>And then I guess just is it international growth that's incrementally much better on units that's driving it? It seems like domestic has been good but international seems to be kicking in even more so these days than ever before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the &#x2013; again, your unit question is related to mobile or it's related to total?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, the unit growth is very broad. And so again when you see the results that we had with &#x2013; on a local currency basis, international being up 37%, this is revenue I'm speaking, as well as North America again was up 47%, 46% on a local currency basis, you're seeing very strong revenue growth, you're also seeing very strong unit growth in those two segments.</p>
          <p>And again in terms of mobile, we're going to use &#x2013; obviously try to make sure that we learn as much as we can and try to serve our customers as best we can in that environment. But it's an environment that we like. Again, the idea of having easy access from a web perspective on a wireless device is a world that we like. So again, we're going to do whatever we can to make sure it's easy for customers to get access.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Steve Weinstein with Pacific Crest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. I don't know if you wanted to disclose it, but I'm trying to get a better understanding of how much Zappos impacted the quarter. If you could at least give us a sense of what the organic growth would have been without that. I'd also love to know just if there was any other impact to the P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>I also just want to make sure the worldwide unit growth of 40%, that's excluding Zappos, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the worldwide unit growth includes Zappos and the impact on &#x2013; someone had asked &#x2013; I apologize, someone had asked that question, a similar question earlier. We're not breaking out Zappos results specifically as part of our total. But what I had mentioned was if you take our worldwide results on a local currency growth basis and you back out Zappos and the Kindle accounting change, you see a growth rate that accelerated from Q4. And that accelerated versus what we saw in Q4 excluding exchange and excluding Zappos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Imran Khan with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, thank you for taking my questions. I have two quick modeling questions and one more of a big picture question. In terms of modeling question, I think on your other operating expenses/income net was $26 million; could you explain what that was, please?</p>
          <p>And secondly, fulfillment seems like it came down quite a bit. It was 7.4% of revenue. Is that sustainable?  How should we think about that?</p>
          <p>And the long-term question is, I think in the shareholder letter, Jeff talked about how you launched 21 categories worldwide. Can you give us some sense how long it takes to ramp those categories? How long it takes to get to the peak margins now that you have experience of launching many different categories over the last many, many years?  So that will be very helpful, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Can you just repeat &#x2013; there was a part in the middle there that I missed. You said something about 7.4% and I didn't hear...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the fulfillment, fulfillment as a percentage of revenue I believe was 7.4%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was your question related to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That is down 80 basis points year over year. So I was trying to figure out if that was a one-time thing or how should we think about that?  Is that sustainable?  I was trying to figure out what's driving that leverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start with the fulfillment one first. What you're seeing there is we saw accelerated growth. And when you see accelerated growth, we're able to leverage that in our fulfillment capacity in a great way from a productivity standpoint. Also what I mentioned was we have added capacity, but specifically in North America we haven't added in a meaningful capacity since Q3 of '08. If you recall, we were building capacity and then we had a financial disruption in the market, so we ended up having some excess capacity in Q4 of '08. We've been able to leverage that capacity throughout, and so that's resulting in the productivity that you're seeing. Now with the growth that we are experiencing, you should expect that we will have to add capacity over time here to satisfy that growth.</p>
          <p>In terms of your category question, we have learned a lot over the years, but it still takes us a number of years to get the scale when we launch new categories. One of the things we have learned over the past several years is we need to make sure that we have great selection day one. We need to make sure that we're pricing very competitively day one, even though we don't have necessarily the scale or the buying tools to purchase well day one.</p>
          <p>And so what that means usually is that we'll have a lower contribution profit per unit generally early on. And as we learn those categories, we get better and better at sourcing and making sure we have the right inventory in place and all that. So it takes a number of years before we get the scale in those categories and get meaningful free cash flow out of them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Imran, in regards to your question around what's behind the $26 million of other operating expense, remember that we're amortizing intangibles in that line item. There are a number of things that go into that, but it really is predominantly amortization of intangible assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks, Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Ben Schachter with Broadpoint.AmTech.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was wondering if you could discuss some initiatives around used products, particularly in EGM, and what the strategy is there going forward. Another question would be discuss your private label strategy. Is there are any new trends there, any new categories that we should know about? And finally just for the modeling, was there any meaningful impact from video game hardware shortages this quarter?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of used products, our strategy there has been pretty consistent. We have a platform that's available for sellers to sell used product, which is the predominant use. And we try to make that experience as good as we can both for the sellers and for customers, so they can understand what the quality of the good is before making a purchase decision.</p>
          <p>We have done some private label, as you mentioned, and there's not really a lot really to speak of today about that. But again, we do have some private label product that we sell. But the vast majority of the products we sell are not private label.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Justin Post with Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, a couple things. Firstly, I know your company doesn't like to waste money and usually you have a revenue decline into the summer and you ramp up your facilities, and your people kind of in third quarter. Why earlier this year?  Do you feel really bullish as we go into the summer period?</p>
          <p>And then just to clarify, are you saying all of the acceleration on an ex-currency basis from 1Q versus 4Q is due to Zappos and Kindle amortization?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start with the last question first. No, on a global basis excluding exchange, Kindle and the accounting change we saw a few hundred basis points acceleration in growth. So we did accelerate excluding those items.</p>
          <p>In terms of capacity, we do have high growth rates right now. We have 40% unit growth, 46% revenue growth in Q1. You see the guidance for Q2. And so, as you'd expect with that growth rate, we need to make sure we have the right amount of capacity and people on hand to serve.</p>
          <p>As part of that from a fulfillment perspective, we're growing our Fulfilled by Amazon, or FBA business, which also requires capacity to do so. So those are things that we view as high quality problems. But those are things that we certainly will have to add as we move forward as well as other areas, you know, other parts of our business that are growing in addition to those two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you say that you're investing earlier this year than normal or is it just maybe a little bit of a catch up to last year?  How would you phrase that would you say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, I guess I would characterize it as we're trying to make sure we satisfy demand in our retail business and our third party business that we fulfill as well as Web Services businesses. So those are the things we're trying to do in making sure that we have the right capacity on hand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We do have time for one more question. We'll take our final question from Spencer Wang with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, a question on eBooks. I guess as you and the industry move more towards the agency model for digital books it shifts the ability to set pricing to publishers and I guess our understanding is you will also have to charge sales tax also. So it would seem that your ability to leverage low price may be mitigated a little bit. So I was wondering if you could just talk about how you would adjust your model to differentiate Amazon versus some of the other players in the context of the other two pillars: I guess convenience and selection that you're focused on.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. One of the things that we're doing is we're expanding selection pretty dramatically. When we launched two-plus years ago with Kindle, we had approximately 90,000 titles. Just recently we passed over 500,000 titles. And so our vision is as we stated when we launched Kindle is to have every book ever published in any language available for customers in under 60 seconds. And that's still our stated long-term goal. And so we're going to continue to add selection in support of that vision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that does conclude our question-and-answer session. I'd now like to turn the call back over to Rob Eldridge for any additional or closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you for joining us on the call today and for your questions. A replay will be available on our Investor Relations website at least through the end of the quarter. We appreciate your interest in Amazon.com and look forward to talking with you again next quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude today's call. We do appreciate everyone's participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>