<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1213971" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-10-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>42</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Thomas P. Chambers, Vice President &#x2013; Planning and Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">G. Steven Farris, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Rodney J. Eichler, Co-Chief Operating Officer and President &#x2013; International</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">John A. Crum, Co-Chief Operating Officer and President &#x2013; North America</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Roger B. Plank, President</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Brian Singer</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">David Tameron</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Joe Allman</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">David Heikkinen</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Leo Mariani</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Joseph Magner</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Please stand by; we're about to begin. Good day everyone and welcome to the Apache Corporation Third Quarter 2009 Earnings Conference Call. This call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>Today's presentation will be hosted by Mr. Tom Chambers, Vice President of Corporate Planning and Investor Relations. Mr. Chambers, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone, and thanks for joining us for Apache Corporations' third quarter 2009 earnings conference call. This morning you'll see we reported third quarter net income of $441 million or $1.30 per diluted share and cash flow from operations of $1.3 billion, adjusted earnings, which excludes certain items that impact the comparability of the results totaled 534 million or $1.58 per diluted share.</p>
          <p>On today's call we'll have four speakers making prepared remarks prior to taking questions. Steve Farris will kick off the session; he's our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, followed by Rod Eichler, our Co-Chief Operating Officer and President of International and John Crum, our Co-Chief Operating Officer and President of North America; and Roger Plank, our President.</p>
          <p>Today's discussion may contain forward-looking estimates and assumptions, and no assurance can be given that those expectations will be realized. A full disclaimer is included on our website. Any non-GAAP numbers that we discuss, such as adjusted earnings, cash flow from operations, or costs incurred will be identified as such with the reconciliation located on our website.</p>
          <p>In addition, we have posted some supplemental financial information for the quarter on our website as well. All this information can be accessed at www.apachecorp.com/financial data.</p>
          <p>With that, I will turn the call over to Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you for joining us this afternoon. Apache delivered solid production growth during the third quarter. Production was up 19% against the same period last year and up 8% on a year-to-year basis, compared to last year. And in a moment, Rod and John and Roger will walk through our progress during the quarter.</p>
          <p>First, I'd like to highlight three specific recent developments that we've had. The first, as you may have read, we are going to pursue the development of the liquefied natural gas export hub in Western Australia, which is in cooperation with Chevron and Kuwait's KUFPEC. The project is called Wheatstone and will give Apache a steady cash flow base for 15 years. This cash flow base will be based on production net to Apache of 190 million cubic feet of gas per day and 5,100 barrels of condensate per day for 15 years without decline. We expect the natural gas to be marketed on a long-term contract basis at Asian LNG prices. These are linked to oil prices and represent a significant premium to North American gas prices.</p>
          <p>In addition to project realization we'll have the benefit of contractual stability for the duration of the project, which enhances our portfolio balance, which is in contrast to the boom and crash volatility of North American natural gas prices. Apache's mission is to create long-term superior value for our shareholders, and this project is an outstanding example of it.</p>
          <p>Looking beyond the project &#x2013; immediate project, we have a very large prospective acreage position in Western Australia and the Wheatstone infrastructure goes right through the middle of much of it and is expected to provide the means to monetize our ongoing exploration discoveries at premium and stable oil-linked prices.</p>
          <p>The second item is the recent developments that we've had in Argentina where we signed a gas contract for $5 per MMbtu for our gas. We have an outstanding resource base in Argentina we built at a very low cost compared to others because we got in when others gave up.</p>
          <p>And it's been our belief all along that the economic fundamentals ultimately prevail. And regulated hydrocarbon prices would have to adjust to meet energy demands as they did in this country in the 1970s. The agreement is a great example of how fundamentals ultimately do prevail, creating value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>The third item I'd like to highlight is our Granite Wash play in central in our central region of the U.S. I think you might have read this morning we reported the results of our first well there, which started production at 17 million cubic feet gas a day and 800 barrels of liquids per day.</p>
          <p>I might say with these liquids you can make very good economics at very low gas prices. We control over 200,000 acres across the play, and we currently plan to drill 20 wells in 2010. We built one of the leading acreage positions in North America, which has not been over the last few years, but really over the last decades.</p>
          <p>Drilling and completion innovations continue to unlock new opportunities in the Grant Wash is a great example of that. Also, importantly, substantially all of Apache's North American acreage is primarily held by production, which allows to us pick development timing to maximize the value of our shareholders.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'd like to turn the call over to Rod and John and Roger, and then we will go into Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Steve. I will provide a quick overview of the main developments in our international regions. During the third quarter, production from Apache's international operations was 316,700 barrels of oil equivalent per day, a 4.6% increase over second quarter.</p>
          <p>The production increase can be attributed to drilling successes in the North Sea as well as a full quarter of restored production from Australia Varanus Islands. In Egypt, net production was 155,600 barrels of oil equivalent per day, a 1.6% decrease from second quarter.</p>
          <p>The net decrease was due to higher oil prices, resulting in lower cost recovery barrels under the PSC, combined with lower cost recovery. By contrast, gross BOE per day for the quarter increased by 16,700 barrels a day or 6%, from to 273,800 to 290,500 barrels of oil equivalent per day.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, Egypt region achieved new daily gross production records for gross oil and condensate at 174,600 barrels of oil per day and gross gas at 823 million cubic feet of gas per day.</p>
          <p>On the exploration side, we completed drilling and/or testing operations on six new wildcat wells, resulting in two new field discoveries during the third quarter. Four wildcat wells are presently drilling, Apache has 100% contractor working interest in all but one of these wells.</p>
          <p>Some brief highlights of the two new discoveries and significant appraisal and development wells in the greater Khalda Offset Concession area are as follows. The Chelsea 1X wildcat in the Khalda Offset Concession tested 19 million a day of gas and 650 barrels of condensate from 31 feet of Upper Safa sand and 1,800 barrels of oil per day from 38 feet of AEB [Alam El Buieb] sand.</p>
          <p>A development lease is pending approval by the government and production is expected to commence by year-end. The Prince-1X wildcat wells condensate concession logged 66 feet of Upper Safa pay. The first zone of three to be completed tested at a rate of 28 million a day and 1,100 barrels of condensate per day. Apache has a 64% working interest in this concession.</p>
          <p>In the Phiops area of the Faghur basin, Apache continues to have exceptional development results in the Cretaceous AEB formation, which has been an important driver of production growth. This quarter, our success continued with one rig completion of an existing well and two new appraisal wells. The field discovery well, the Phiops-1X was re-completed from the Safa to the AEB at a rate of 4,600 barrels of oil per day.</p>
          <p>Also during the quarter, the Phiops-2X encountered 143 feet of AEB oil pay that tested up to 7,200 barrels of oil per day. The Phiops-6X logged 157 feet of the same AEB oil pay is awaiting completion.</p>
          <p>This well extended the Phiops accumulation northward onto our Shushan concession. Production at the Phiops field is presently facilities-constrained at 6,500 barrels a day. Expansion to 8,000 barrels a day is planned by year-end, and expansion to 20,000 barrels per day is targeted by third quarter 2010.</p>
          <p>On the development side, gross Khalda gas production, which averaged 668 million cubic feet of gas per day during June, averaged 702 million cubic feet of gas per day during the third quarter and 715 million a day through September, as a result of full completion of the Salam 3 and 4 gas plants. Two shutdowns are scheduled in the fourth quarter at Shell's biogas plant, which resulted in the deferral of about one Bcf of Khalda production.</p>
          <p>Turning to Australia, net production was 48,400 barrels of oil equivalent per day a 30% increase over second quarter. Gas oil production increased by 40% and 4% respectively. This increase is primarily due to having a full quarter's, production following completion of the Varanus Island repair project in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>In our Van Gogh Oil project, which Apache operates with a 52.5% working interest, final inspection repair work's on track to deliver the FPSO [Floating Production Storage and Offloading] to the field before the end of the year. All development drilling and subsea installation is completed with first production expected by year-end. Production is anticipated to ramp up to a peak of 20,000 barrels a day in 2010.</p>
          <p>The nearby BHP Billiton-operated Pyrenees FPSO development project, in which Apache has a 28.6% working interest, is also underway with development drilling in subsea installation progressing as planned. We expect first production in late first quarter of 2010. Production is also anticipated to ramp up to a peak of 20,000 barrels a day in 2010.</p>
          <p>We broke ground at our Devil Creek gas plant in September. Earth works have commenced at the site, and all major onshore and offshore construction contracts have been awarded. We anticipate first gas from our Reindeer field in third quarter 2011. Apache operates this project with a 55% working interest. We also entered feed for the BHP-operated Macedon domestic gas development project during this quarter, with a final investment decision expected in June of 2010. Apache has a 28.6% working interest in this project.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, drilling activity has been focused on the Coniston appraisal project, with five wells having been building drilled to-date. Apache operates this project with a 45.7% working interest. Two wells in this program, Novara 3-H and Coniston 2H, have been production-tested at rates of 5,500 barrels a day and 11,200 barrels a day respectively. Additional wells will be required to fully delineate the pool in the fourth quarter. The Coniston accumulation is likely to be developed as a tie back to the Van Gogh FPSO.</p>
          <p>Last week, as Steve mentioned, Apache and Kuwait Foreign Petroleum Exploration Company announced our election to join Chevron to develop the Wheatstone Liquefied Natural Gas Hub in Western Australia.</p>
          <p>Apache and KUFPEC signed an exclusive agreement to supply gas from our Julimar and Brunello discoveries and become foundation equity partners in the Chevron-operated Wheatstone project facilities. This project unlocks 2.1 trillion cubic feet of gas reserves at two of Apache's largest discoveries and generates steady net sales of about 190 million a day and 5,100 barrels of condensate per day for 15 years at prices &#x2013; pegged to world oil prices.</p>
          <p>Apache has a net 16.25% interest in the Wheatstone phase I development. As a foundation partner, Apache will also have the opportunity to participate in future expansion of the project, providing additional options for gas commercialization. The final investment decision on the first phase of the project is slated for 2011, after the feed is completed.</p>
          <p>Turning to North Sea, net production averaged 67,800 barrels of oil equivalent per day, an increase of 12.5% from second quarter, due to strong drilling results and increased field production efficiency. Production for the third quarter ranked as the second best quarter ever for the North Sea region since Apache became operator of the project in 2003.</p>
          <p>Production efficiency for Forties field averaged 94% for the quarter, exceeding downtime &#x2013; excluding downtime for annual emergency shutdown valve testing on the main export line from the Forties Charlie platform, as well as temporary repairs to a section of 35-year old 20-inch pipe near the base of the Bravo riser at Charlie platform. Including these two downtime events, production efficiency still averaged 90%.</p>
          <p>Production for the fourth quarter will be impacted by a shutdown of the Bravo platform. The platform, which produces approximately 11,500 barrels of oil per day, has been offline throughout October, but is expected to resume full production by 6 November. The Bravo export piping, which I mentioned previously, that underwent temporary repair in August, is undergoing permanent replacement of the last 80-meter section of pipe, which will complete the line replacement of Bravo that began in 2008.</p>
          <p>On the drilling side, we drilled and completed five successful oil development wells during the quarter. These wells contributed 3,600 barrels of oil per day for the quarter and 5,200 barrels a day in September. I've noted the Forties Charlie 33 C42 well, which encountered nine meters of field pay, is well on production in September at 3,300 barrels a day.</p>
          <p>As I indicated, new oil pool discovery was made last week, with the pilot hole drilled from the Forties Alpha 40s 2110 A52 well, which intersected 15 meters of net pay in Eocene sands about 150 meters above the main Forties reservoir. This reservoir is equivalent to the Brimman sands, which occur in the Echo platform area.</p>
          <p>Preliminary estimates are five to six million barrels of oil in play, of which 2 million barrels of oil may be recoverable. This discovery will likely qualify for a small field development application, yielding up to &#xA3;75 million of supplemental corporation tax break incentive, as well as not being exposed to the PRT [Petroleum revenue tax].</p>
          <p>Finally Argentina, net production was 44,900 barrels of oil equivalent per day, down 4.7% from second quarter. The recent drilling program concentrated in the Neuqu&#xE9;n Basin continues to be successful. During the quarter, a total of seven wells were drilled and completed, adding gross production of 570 barrels of oil per day and 26 million cubic feet of gas per day.</p>
          <p>The development program in the Ranquilco field dominated the third quarter activity, with three new wells drilled and four completions, for a total production net of 360 barrels a day and 20 million cubic feet of gas per day.</p>
          <p>Most notable was Ranquilco 10-38, which encountered 312 feet of pay at an average depth of 8,000 feet and was completed in three zones in the Pre-Cuyo formation, with initial production rate of 166 barrels a day and eight million a day gas, and the Ranquilco 10-39, which had 269 feet of pay and was completed in two zones with the same formation at an initial production rate of 60 barrels a day and five million a day gas.</p>
          <p>And in addition the Suez X-20 2001, located in the Baja Guadales block tested two zones for the Cuyo formation at average depth of 3,000 feet at a rate of four million a day. This successful extends for well is stood up three or four additional locations in the field in late 2009 and 2010.</p>
          <p>In September, Apache received approval for two gas-plus projects in Neuqu&#xE9;n and Rio Negro provinces in the Neuqu&#xE9;n basin to sell up to 50 million a day of gas to a power plant for $5 per MMbtu.</p>
          <p>These two projects were the first projects to be approved by the government of Argentina to encourage development of tight and unconventional gas reservoirs to displace imported gas.</p>
          <p>The next three years, Apache will drill 12 wells in the AC field in the Neuqu&#xE9;n province and 36 wells in the EFO field in Rio Negro province to support this project. Without the higher gas prices, these development drilling projects would not be feasible. Apache Argentina has since submitted five additional projects for gas-plus approval.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to turn the presentation over to John Crum, who'll discuss activities in our North American operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rod. In our central region, we produced 88,400 barrels equivalent for the quarter, up slightly from the second quarter. We had very little drilling and workover activity during the first two quarters as we waited for costs to reflect the 2009 product prices. In the meantime, we concentrated on building and upgrading our inventory.</p>
          <p>During the third quarter, we began to measure drilling and workover recompletion program, with emphasis on oil prospects and game-changer gas opportunities. We have now ramped up activity to a present level of eight drilling and 34 workover recompletion rigs running in the region. Results from the drilling and workover programs offset the region's natural decline.</p>
          <p>We expect fourth quarter to be up even more, due to some notable new wells and a full quarter of activity. Overall, lifting costs were up 3.9% to 796 per BOE, due almost exclusively to the additional workover activity.</p>
          <p>Base lifting costs were actually down, as our cost reduction efforts continued to show. The region performed 100 workover and recompletion projects during the quarter, adding more than 1,800 barrels equivalent to production volumes.</p>
          <p>On the drilling side, with emphasis on oil production, 70% of the central region's third quarter wells were drilled in the oil-rich Permian basin at shallow depths. On the Texas side of the basin, we drilled six third core wells in our TXL North and South units. The wells averaged just over 100 barrels of oil per day each and will result in a 20-well infill program planned for the first quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>Apache has been particularly active in the New Mexico side of the basin, maintaining three drilling rigs and five workover rigs during the quarter.</p>
          <p>In the last quarter, we drilled 27 new wells that came in producing an average of nearly 100 barrels of oil per day. We have an outstanding drilling inventory, ranging in depth from 4,000 to 8,000 feet that we now expect to provide around 100 new wells per year in 2010 and '11 in New Mexico alone.</p>
          <p>In the Anadarko basin, Apache completed the Tyler number 2-55. This was the second well in a four well drilled to earn farm-in from BP. The well found 125 feet of pay in the Atoka Wash at 17,000 feet, and has been on for a month now averaging five million cubic feet of gas per day. Additional tests are scheduled in each of the two remaining BP sections for 2010, followed by an infill development program.</p>
          <p>As Steve mentioned, this morning we released results on Apache's first operated horizontal Granite Wash well. The results were great. The Hostetter 1-23H in Washita County, Oklahoma has been producing the sales for the past four weeks and is still flowing at 17 million cubic feet of gas a day with some 800 barrels of liquids. We have just completed drilling our second operated horizontal Granite Wash well on our Salez Ranch acreage in the Texas Panhandle, almost 50 miles west of the Hostetter well. Logs indicate more than 4,000 feet of hydrocarbon-saturated sand. We will begin completion operations next week.</p>
          <p>The Granite Wash has long been a core stacked play for our central region, where we've drilled hundreds of vertical wells over the past decade. As a result, we now control over 200,000 gross held by production acres in the play.</p>
          <p>Horizontal multi-frac technology has vastly improved the potential recoveries. The high associated liquids yield should make this field competitive with any other resources plays. We now have two horizontal rigs running in the Granite Wash fairway and we'll add a third in November. We would expect to run four horizontal rigs through 2010, resulting in at least 20 new wells.</p>
          <p>In our Gulf Coast region, we produced an average of 123,300 barrels equivalent per day during the third quarter. That's up 5.6% from the second quarter. Throughout the region maintained a modest level of rig activity for the quarter, three significant new wells added 2100 barrels equivalent per day, while continued hurricane recoveries and a full quarter of our Gopher field production more than offset the region's natural decline.</p>
          <p>Overall, lifting costs were up 4.6% to 1282 per barrel, driven by increased workover expense and higher than planned hurricane recovery repairs. The significant new wells for the quarter included a recompletion of the 100% owned South Timbalier at &#x2013; 100% owned South Timbalier 308, which was brought on at 440 barrels per day. Redevelopment work continues at Ewing Banks 826, as we brought on the A11 sidetrack, producing 1,200 barrels a day, with Apache holding 100%.</p>
          <p>After setting a new platform on a new fall block discovery at High Island A-376, the C1 well is now producing 1,015 barrels per day. We own 48% working interest and plan three additional wells for 2010.</p>
          <p>Hurricane restoration efforts continue, and we believe there's an additional 7,000 net BOEs to be added as repairs are completed. We expect to get most of that volume by year-end, but now have little control of the timing, since remaining work is third-party pipeline work. Knock on wood, but we've had no hurricane evacuations this year, and we don't expect any for the remainder of the year as the weather cools.</p>
          <p>Our new two well deepwater Gopher field at Garden Banks 462, which came on production in the middle of the second quarter, continues to produce strongly and averaged 98 million cubic feet of gas on a gross basis, some 39 million feet net for the quarter.</p>
          <p>We expect to be more active late this year and into the next as the region is built a robust inventory of solid drilling prospects. As such, we contracted three jack-ups and two platform rigs for our anticipated 2010 program.</p>
          <p>In Canada, the region produced 78,700 barrels equivalent per day, down 1.9% from the second quarter. The drop in production was primarily due to natural declines without supporting production from new well activity and from turnaround at Zama complex in northern Alberta.</p>
          <p>The third quarter in Canada is usually difficult to show gains, as we typically have very low activity levels in the second quarter, due to the lack of access as we go through the winter break up. Somewhat offsetting these declines, however, were the results from new wells coming on production at our Two Island Lake area in the Horn River basin, which will be described later.</p>
          <p>We drilled 17 wells during the third quarter and expect to drill an additional 19 before the end of the year. The region lifting costs for BOE were up 14% to 986 in the second quarter, with almost half of that increase associated with exchange rate increases.</p>
          <p>The remainder is due to one-off costs associated with planned turnaround activity at Zama, Virginia Hills and Snipe Lake. The region remains well under budgeted total dollar lifting costs for the year due to their cost-cutting efforts. While costs have responded to the lower product prices and the Alberta government has attempted to respond to the downturn with some royalty adjustments, conventional gas well drilling in Alberta remains challenging, with a significant portion of the cost savings being wiped out with higher exchange rates.</p>
          <p>We did drill a modest 11 well Nevis Coalbed Methane Program on high-graded prospects that generated post drill economics showing an 18% after-tax rate of return. The remainder of the third quarter conventional program focused on oil targets. We drilled 12 wells off recent 3-D seismic in our core shallow cretaceous Provost area. Post drill economics show the program generated 32% after tax rate of return. We were especially pleased with two Dinah wells that combined for a total of 270 barrels of oil per day and two Rex Channel wells that came in for a combined 166 barrels of oil per day.</p>
          <p>The region is preparing for a winter program to start late in the fourth quarter, again focused on oil. Three wells are planned for Zama, four at Midale, six at House Mountain fields.</p>
          <p>Positive results from the winter program will lead to additional 2010 wells. At Horn River, two more wells at our 50% owned EnCana-operated 70-J pad came on production at more than 10 million cubic feet gas per day each.</p>
          <p>The four wells from the 2009 program continue to produce at more than 24 million feet per day after more than three months of production. The results support our new estimate &#x2013; our new estimate of expected ultimate recoveries of over 12 Bcf per well for our 14 frac well.</p>
          <p>The six Muskwa wells from our 2008 program, which utilized six to 10 fracs per well, continued to meet expectations as well producing another 11 million cubic feet of gas per day after more than a year of production.</p>
          <p>We presently have the Apache operated 16 well 70-K pad and the EnCana 11 well 76-K pad fully-drilled and are waiting on completion operations. Completion operations in the 70-K. pad, Apache-operated, will begin in December, with fracing operations commencing in early January.</p>
          <p>First production from that pad is expected in April, but will ramp up quickly as we expect to frac all of the wells before bringing the pad on production. EnCana will immediately follow with fracing of the 11 wells on the 76-K. We should have all 27 new wells on production near mid-year 2010.</p>
          <p>Meanwhile Apache has moved to the 52-L pad, where we'll drill an additional 11 wells, experimenting with longer laterals with up to 20 fracs and wider spacing to optimize future development plans. Those wells are expected to be drilled by mid-year and will be completed in the second half of 2010. EnCana has moved their rig to the 63-K pad where they will drill 14 Muskwa wells by the end of the second quarter, again followed by completion operations in the second half of 2010.</p>
          <p>As mentioned last quarter, in support of the Horn River development, we have hedged a net 50 to 100 million cubic feet a day over the next three years at six to $7 per Mcf. We continue to find ways to reduce costs and improve rates and recoveries, which are expected to make this a very competitive play for the long-term.</p>
          <p>And now I'll turn over the call to Roger Plank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. Good afternoon everyone. I've got a touch of laryngitis, so I'll do my best to carve my way through these remarks before turning it back to Steve. Apache's strong third quarter results were driven by higher oil prices and record product of both oil and gas. Despite severe capital reductions this year, we grew daily production 3% sequentially to 607,000 barrels equivalent, piercing the 600 mark for the first time in our 50-plus years.</p>
          <p>Our balanced production mix also served us well, with equivalent realization climbing 7% sequentially with 12% higher oil prices offsetting a 1% decline in our gas price. Earnings, adjusted for the impact of foreign currency on deferred tax of $534 million or $1.58 per share, reached a high for the year during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Record production and higher realizations drove earnings 12% higher than the prior quarter. Cash flow from operations of $1.3 billion also reached a high for the year. Substantial free cash flow enabled cash balances to rise by over $0.5 billion to nearly $1.4 billion at the close of the quarter. As a result of stronger-than-planned cash flow and declining drilling costs, we've loosened up our purse strings on our capital budget to around $4.1 billion from an initial budget of just north of 3.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Turning to operating costs, our cash operating costs on a unit basis increased just under 10% sequentially, primarily on seven stacks of PRTs with higher oil prices. Excluding these other taxes, our controllable cash operating costs were up only 1.5%.</p>
          <p>With production up and prices presently above third quarter averages, we anticipate a strong finish to a topsy-turvy year. Our long-term outlook for production growth remains strong, with production plateauing at third quarter levels until we get beyond the shut-ins in Egypt and North Sea, which Rod mentioned. Production growth should get off to a fast start again next year as we bring oil online at our Van Gogh and Pyrenees developments and production ramps up at Ootla the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>Also for 2010, I'd note that we've beefed up our hedging position, particularly on the gas side, in the face of bourgeoning North American gas supplies. We've hedged an average of 410,000 MMbtu per day of our projected 2010 North American production. Approximately 90% of the hedged volume was swapped at an average price of $5.60. The balance was hedged using collars with average floor and ceiling prices of $5.65 and $7.55 per MMbtu.</p>
          <p>For reference, hedge prices of $5.60 in 2010 compare very favorably to our average year-to-date realization in North America of $4.10.</p>
          <p>On the oil side, we've now hedged an average of 35,000 barrels per day for 2010, mostly utilizing collars with average floor and ceiling prices of $65.70 to $78.50 per barrel, respectively. For perspective, these hedges represent 12% of our daily third quarter oil volumes, 21% of our worldwide gas volumes and 36% of just our North American gas volumes.</p>
          <p>Before closing, I wanted to note a subtle but important change taking place at Apache over a period of years. For most of our history, Apache has lived hand-to-mouth, largely dependent on the vagaries of the U.S. gas market for our cash flow and earnings.</p>
          <p>As our balance portfolio approach has taken hold, however, we've diversified our sources of revenue and captured new opportunities for adding value. Today, we have a growing complement of meaningful discoveries in large-scale projects around the world, each of which can really move the needle.</p>
          <p>In years past, we didn't have the wherewithal to spend $1 billion on infrastructure in Egypt's western desert to bring to market a backlog of gas discoveries. The wait for first cash flow would have been just too painful, particularly with no free cash flow at the time.</p>
          <p>However, we've evolved in recent years and having actually made that investment, we now flow, as Rod indicated, over three quarters of a Bcf of gross gas in Egypt day in and day out, with no decline for five or six years, or even longer with the addition of new discoveries.</p>
          <p>We have similar high-impact assets in Australia where our Reindeer discovery, for example, is on track to flow 60 million cubic feet of gas per day gross beginning in late 2011 for seven straight years without decline and with the potential for extending the contract further.</p>
          <p>Van Gogh and Pyrenees, while different in that production will peak in the first few years, are similar in that they are significant large-scale discoveries that once online add meaningful volumes, some 40,000 barrels per day or so net to production during the first half of 2010.</p>
          <p>Our decision to saddle up with Chevron on the Wheatstone LNG project for the feed study for monetizing our multi-Tcf Julimar discoveries is another natural step in Apache's evolution toward large-scale, long-lived impacted projects.</p>
          <p>We are cognizant of the need to balance these long-term capital-intensive projects with near-term investments that cash flow and pay the light bill, but the prize in this case is 150 to 200 million cubic feet of net gas tied to oil prices every day for 15 years.</p>
          <p>That's not just at different type of asset. It's a company-builder. Bob Dye tells me that whining about low stock price multiples is bush league, so I won't go there, but suffice it to say that somewhere along the line, Apache has grown into a very different and stronger company with a growing number of impactive high-quality assets that create a solid foundation for continued profitable growth. Steve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Roger. I'd like to close our comments by taking stock of a little bit of Roger said, where we're delivering and building a pipeline of large long-term stable and diverse energy projects.</p>
          <p>I think all of you have probably seen the chart we've been using recently showing our major organic growth projects that are expected to contribute close to 140,000 barrels equivalent of new production to Apache by 2012. And those are the big projects we have been investing in during the recent quarters. If you visualize that diagram, we've delivered the Salam gas plants 3 and 4, and the Asala Ridge water-floods in Egypt. The Gopher development in the Gulf of Mexico during this year already. And that means we've done all the work and invested the capital required and as the aggregate production contribution of those projects will hold steady for a good number of years. And as a result, we now have the benefit of those steady productions and cash flow for an extended period.</p>
          <p>As we've heard many times today, the next tier of projects in our pipeline will benefit Apache's growth next year. That's Van Gogh and Pyrenees, and also Ootla is expected to come on stream and ramp up during 2010. In addition, we have a large and growing pipeline of major products to support our growth beyond 2010. These include some of the things that Rod pointed out, Phiops discovery in Egypt; the Halyard, Reindeer, Mastodon, Coniston discoveries in Australia and our fifth Salam plant in Egypt. And we're adding to this pipeline steadily.</p>
          <p>This quarter alone, we've added the Wheatstone as a major 15-year project. The Granite Wash as a resource play with literally hundreds of locations. I might point out that this entire pipeline is organically-generated within our broad global portfolio and continues to be built through organic means; we grow through the growback.</p>
          <p>I would like to say that while major growth projects matter, Apache's real underlying momentum is all the wells we keep on drilling and re-completing across our asset base. And I know it becomes difficult to understand what on earth we're referring to as we fire away an endless series of names of discoveries and production enhancement projects around our global portfolio, but that's who we are and the real activity defines how we grow production and create value in this company and I believe we do it as well or better than anybody out there.</p>
          <p>I'd like to conclude by summarizing what I believe are our five main messages this morning &#x2013; this afternoon. On production growth, we've had record production growth for 2009. As Roger pointed out, we'll probably plateau in the fourth quarter, just because of some of our shut-ins, as Rod mentioned, but we've had great momentum in 2010 to continue to deliver growth in the years ahead. The Wheatstone LNG project gives us a 15-year steady plateau, 190 million cubic feet of gas and 5,100 barrels of condensate per day, which is stable cash flow contracted at oil-linked prices. We have entered into a contract to sell some gas out of Argentina for $5 an MMbtu, which further validates our view that Argentina for the long-term is going to be a good place to invest and we have a large resource potential in that country.</p>
          <p>We have a leading position in the Horn River basin, which keeps getting better. John pointed out we're now looking at recoveries of 12 Bcf per well with 14 fracs, and we're experimenting with even longer laterals and more fracs. That development program will grow in 2010. And finally, we drilled our first Granite Wash well that flowed 17 million a day, still flowing 17 million a day and 800 barrels of liquids. We have hundreds of locations across this play. Our initial plan is to drill 20 next year. And I'm very conscious that this is a lot of information, but we have a lot of information to report. And I want to thank you for your patience, and we'd like to turn it over to you for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> and we will go first to Brian Singer with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First question on Coniston. The wells you highlighted earlier seem to have relatively high rates, and I wondered if you could provide some more color on the resource potential there and capacity available that's leading to your decision to tie that project back versus potentially developing new infrastructure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well in Coniston, we still have &#x2013; we drilled five wells to date and probably have another two or three wells to complete delineation of structure, when the rig returns to this area sometime in early December. We currently &#x2013; from a current view of the field for the first five wells we drilled, and the test results for the two wells, which I mentioned, this is probably &#x2013; has a gross recoverable oil accumulation in the vicinity of about 35 to 40 million barrels. It's within 10 kilometers of the Van Gogh FPSO development, so it's very likely, and we of course are early in the stages of doing a development assessment, but it'd be very likely to tie it to the Van Gogh FPSO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. And then secondly on Wheatstone, you'd highlighted the potential for that project to develop 2.1 Tcf. What do you see as your discovered resource at Julimar and Brunello as well as any nearby fields, and how should we think about your interest in resource available for potential expansions beyond these first two trains?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have 2.14 Tcf, which we referenced is our kind of our P50 reserve case. We have significant upside to that. We have a lot of satellite projects in the area, which could access those production through that facility by virtue of their near proximity. In fact, it was once one of the beauties of the Wheatstone development for us at LNG is it really allows to us to bring a lot more of these previously discovered but isolated accumulations into the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have a sense for &#x2013; and maybe I just missed it, do you have a sense for what that could represent? In other words, are there numbers that &#x2013; are there discoveries that you may not have deemed commercial in the past that could now become commercial above and beyond to the 2.1 Tcf?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are a number of, in the in our Mastodon area, which I mentioned which is right next to the Van Gogh and the Coniston Mastodon area is the gas development there. Probably four projects we've identified in there would probably add up to 150 Bcf resource potential on our existing licenses. And we have others which could be delineated also in the area between the Varanus Islands and the Wheatstone central production platform on existing lands. I don't have a number that I'll give you this afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go next to David Tameron with Wells Fargo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, afternoon. Can you comment on the acquisition market? I know it's something you talked about this time last year, then prices ran ahead of you. Can you talk about your current thoughts there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think it's &#x2013; personally I think it's a little too early to tell. We are more active, as we said a number of times, in looking for and at things to buy. I think we find ourselves in a good position at Apache because we are very selective right now in terms what we look at because we've got to weigh that against the opportunities that we have on our plate internally versus things that we're looking at. And quite frankly, the real bottom line is we haven't found anything that competes with what we do for a living right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Any general feel for the market, are oil properties still tight, PV 10 type numbers, can you give me any color there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I can't say that there's not things that you can look at. And I will tell you, to be real honest with you, the value of oil to reality is really better, and the reason is because people don't have the same view of Mecca coming out there as they do on gas prices. Because if you look at a lot of things that are happening out there, and if you looked at the current day's &#x2013; the cash markets today, they don't make sense. You have to look at the strip, which is why you see an awful lot of folks out there hedging, because you have to look at the strip to make those things economic. So honestly, the value &#x2013; the value difference between oil is much smaller than the value difference between gas right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks for that. Then up in Ootla, Horn River, can you talk about what's your current well costs? What are they running?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're still working on the 10 million per well, but I think I've mentioned to some of you in the past, we tend to start experimenting and adding more fracs. We expect to get our per frac cost down to somewhere in the range of $300,000 per when we start this program, because we're going to have our own water supply, and that's been a big cost element in our past jobs; we've had to haul water in with trucks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And right now those fracs are running what six or 700?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, so all in, are we talking, are you saying you want to get to 10 million? You're not at 10 million today yet, are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We weren't at 10 million on the ones we drilled earlier this year. But again, we were having to truck water in and doing less jobs. You can imagine we're about to start on a program where we'll do 16 wells with some 14, 15 fracs per well. So that gives you some benefits of scale that we have not been able to take advantage of in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go next to Joe Allman with JP Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good afternoon everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the Granite Wash, what is your net acreage there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've got roughly 75,000 acres of net, but we're in a position to &#x2013; you're probably aware, in Oklahoma you can propose a well and with any amount of acreage in a section. So we would expect to pick up additional acreages going forward with well proposals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful. Thanks. And then back to the Horn River basin. I think John, you said something about an additional 11 million per day. I just kind of missed what you were saying. Can you talk about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I'm sorry &#x2013; I probably didn't make that very clear. We're making 24 million a day out of those four wells that we completed this year. The six wells that we did last year make it another 11 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yeah that's helpful. Good. And then sticking with the Horn River basin, could you help with the economics? What price do you think you need to get an adequate rate of return? And just help us on the decision to send some gas through LNG versus any through pipe and what the costs involved there are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we've shown you some numbers in the past in some presentations where we're around $4 at kind of a breakeven point. And obviously that's going to be a little bit of "kissing your sister" at that number, but we can make it work there, especially if we can drive out additional costs. And it tends to be a little bit of a chicken and egg thing, as the realizations go down, we drive the costs down and we try to get it over the line that way. Obviously, we'd like to get five, six, $7, that's why we've hedged some of that gas this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Gotcha. And then just very quickly in Egypt. Kind of the three types of wells that you're drilling there, Upper Bahariya, AEB and Jurassic, is the cost sort of on average for those three about $3.5 million? And remind us what the average reserves per well you're getting there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there's quite a bit of difference in depth between the three zones. Most of Bahariya development work is typically in the six to 8,000-foot range, and those wells can be as cheap to drill and complete as $1.5 million, $2 million. The AEB wells are typically drilled between 10 and 12,000 feet. You're looking at probably two to $2.5 million for those wells, and the Jurassic wells, which are &#x2013; that can be 12 to 14,000 feet, you're probably looking upwards of $3 million to drill and complete those wells.</p>
          <p>As far as the reserve sizes go, individual Bahariya wells, for instance the mature water flood areas  in Khalda, can be in the vicinity of 100 to 125,000 net barrels of oil reserves per well, but of course, we have hundreds of those wells there. Those are the shallowest wells that we can drill and complete inside of like 10 days. These range up to the higher-end reserves, which can be 200,000 barrels per well in the East Bahariya developments, which are under active water flood right now, and the primary successes there have been very significant that we developed in 2007, 2008 and again in 2009.</p>
          <p>And then lastly, the Jurassic wells, the reserve ranges there, they range all the way from the big <mark type="inaudible" /> wells, which have daily rates that can test from 40 to 50 million a day plus large degrees of condensate. The number for a typical Jurassic well would probably be in the three to five million barrels of oil equivalent per well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go to next to David Heikkinen with Tudor, Pickering, Holt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Rod. Just following up as you think about Egypt and what you've done with the water flood volumes growing over the last several years, how would you think about continued water flood growth over the next year and two years on an annual basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Water flood program we have &#x2013; currently have about 40 active water flood projects and &#x2013; other the oil reservoirs really lend themselves well to this kind of secondary recovery, and we intend to keep growing that. In fact, we've been successful in bringing up that water flood oil volume up to about 70,000 barrels a day, currently at about 160,000 to 170,000 barrels a day we produce gross. And that includes condensate. So if you back out the condensate, about half of our daily oil production, the Blackwell production of Egypt comes from water-flood secondary recovery activities.</p>
          <p>We'd like to continue to grow that, because it really flattens the normal decline that you normally see on primary-producing wells and this will give us a nice firm base going forward. These fields are, for the most part, the fields in East Bahariya, the most recent fields, which we have some 14 or 15 water-flood projects underway right now are the newest, and as a result, have very long lives of long flood production plateaus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you're not water-flooding the AEB, you're just doing the Bahariya?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Almost all the water flood activity is in the Bahariya. We had some activity of the AEB in the Khalda area but the bulk of our activity, most of the oil volume now, is coming out of the East Bahariya area which is principally from <mark type="inaudible" /> and Bahariya sands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then maybe on the Horn River basin, as you think about increasing reserves to well, I always get curious about: how do you think about original gas in place now and kind of percentage of gas recovery, and that would then lead to a number of wells per section?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, David. Some of these exercises I mentioned we're going to be doing some more experimenting between ourselves and our partner, we certainly are looking into a lot of things to increase the recovery that would you expect out of the area. I don't know that we are really changing our in place numbers.</p>
          <p>I guess there's still some debate about what that number is. But what we certainly know about horizontal and multi-frac technology is as we drill the wells closer together and put more fracs in it, we're going to recover higher percentages of the original gas in place. So the real key here is just getting to that optimum number where your spacing between the wells is getting as much gas as is economic to do and not wasting any more than possible. So, obviously we could put a frac every 50 feet and recover even more, but that's probably not economic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How do you think about the 16 wells that you're drilling, what spacing are you putting those on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the 16 wells that we just drilled were on roughly 250 meters between the wells. And then putting &#x2013; we had planned on putting 14 fracs. Now I will tell you, we drilled two wells on the 16 well pad where we went out to 2200 meters of length, where we had been at 1600 meters. So we'll be doing some experimenting on those longer-reach ones. On the new pad that we're going to &#x2013; we're going to take half of pad and take the spacing out to 350-meters and another half the pad and take it to 400-meters between wells.</p>
          <p>And that's where the real win can come from. We think we can get the frac length to connect between the two wells, if we can stretch out that space and get longer reaches, then obviously it'll take less well bores to recover the same amount of gas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on as you think about gas discovered in Australia, jumping around a little bit, what would you say your P90 resources so far, tied to Wheatstone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's probably in the 1.6 to 1.9 Tcf range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>P90 is 1.6 to 1.9, and P50 is the 2.14? That seems like a pretty tight range, is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the P50 is 2.1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is. Let's back up. The P50 is right now based on what we drilled, okay? So what you're looking for is additional gas drainage out of existing oil bores or existing in the area. With still have some other things to drill out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was thinking about distribution of what have you've already drilled, that 1.6 to 1.9, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go next to Leo Mariani with RBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon here, guys. A question about Argentina. You guys have this $5 gas-plus project that you're working on. You talked about drilling it sounded like pretty close to 50 wells between the two projects over the next three years. Curious as to how much incremental reserves and production you guys think that can drive and when you expect some of that production to come online and what the costs are associated with that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're able to bring the production online pretty quick in this area because we have infrastructure and these are all mostly in pretty mature development areas, so hook-ups are pretty quick. These wells, as you heard, are relatively shallow. They range anywhere from 3,000 to 8,000 feet in most of those gas-plus project areas.</p>
          <p>So it goes pretty quickly, just a matter of applying the capital to be able to have the rigs to do it. We've had a pretty soft capital program down there this year, which we're now ramping back up now that we've had some agreements, ourselves and the industry and other operators with the government and the labor factions there to be able to bring up production and increase investment in exchange for these incentives for increased gas pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So what's your estimate of reserves you guys can bring online with that program over the next several years? And what are the costs associated with that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It depends on the number of wells we have drilled, we report a modest decline each quarter of this year, mostly because of the natural decline in the production. We'd be able overcome that very easily by just drilling more wells. We also have a large number of water-flood opportunities in Argentina. So it's pretty straightforward economics. I mean I don't have a &#x2013; it's quite a range of the program we have down there to be able to specify a certain reserve per well number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just trying to get a better sense of what the kind of the incremental economics are. You guys mentioned that at current pricing, they don't work, but at $5 that works, so I'm trying to get a sense of where in between the breakeven is and how much money you're making.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Current pricing in Argentina, depending on what market you're selling the gas into, can range anywhere from $0.80 to $2. So $5 is a pretty good deal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I guess jumping over to the Horn River Basin here, you guys have talked about trying to bring 27 wells on in the second quarter of '10. I'm just curious as to whether or not you guys are going to have any restructuring &#x2013; production constraints at that point in time or you think you'll be able to flow all those wells full bore?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we will have to bring them on a little bit at a time if we get the results we've been getting, you couldn't bring all 27 on, obviously, at the same time, but of course we will bring on one pad at a time. We think that we're in pretty good shape on take away capacity in the Horn River Basin into 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What is your...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...first give...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was going to say what is that take away capacity you guys expect in 2010 out there in Horn River?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're still trying to put the schedule together on exactly how we'd do it, but we have actually signed up for 100 million a day of capacity through Spectra and we would expect to pick up whatever &#x2013; that's net to us, so then EnCana's done the same, so then we'd expect to pick up some additional capacity if required from spare that they have available.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Looking at Egypt, obviously you guys have had really strong growth there the last several quarters as you brought on Salam and you had a couple of oil discoveries, and got your water-floods ramped up. Just curious as to if you can kind of just talk sort of qualitatively to what the production ramp is going to look like in Egypt in 2010. Are we going to be kind of growing slower from here as just more of your oil kind of comes online or what can we expect there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the budgeting process right now for 2010, I expect that based on our &#x2013; the inventory that did not get drilled in 2009 based on our capital restrictions this year, that's all carried over to 2010 plus the new projects, I expect to return to the level of drilling activity very similar to what we experienced in 2008.</p>
          <p>Continued growth in production, as I mentioned, the Phiops field is developing, is very significant, we're very likely to the get to 20,000 barrels a day by mid-third quarter of 2010 and we expect to expand the facilities even beyond that, because it's a little bit of a remote area just to the west of our normal operating operations in the Khalda. So I expect a continued good growth in Egypt in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And gas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From a gas standpoint, yeah, I've mentioned a number of big gas wells the last couple of conference calls we've had. And we're starting to get to the point where we're getting gas back up again even with all these infrastructure improvements, and so we are actively working on Salam Gas Train 5 scenario and additional pipelining that would be coming on in two years hence or three years from now, so that's all in the works working with the government to try to develop those similar ideas. Ourselves, as well as other operators, have stranded gas in the area. Right now we're able to manage our gas streams to maximize our liquid production. So we're rotating our gas wells to be able to maximize condensate productions in the new plants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I guess, final question on the North Sea here. Obviously, you had really strong production in the third quarter. You mentioned hitting another sort of undiscovered pocket kind of adding some reserves up there. Just curious as to what you folks think the reserve upside is out there. I know you've got some pretty detailed models out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. We have a rather exhaustive development model for the Forties Field. There's &#x2013; it's almost a 5 billion barrel oil in place field, which a couple of billion barrels have been recovered and there's a significant amount of oil to be targeted to be recovered through ongoing operations, which we've been very successful at ramping up our drilling program based on application of Forties seismic to target the un-swept zones or pods that have not been swept by our long-time water-flood activity there.</p>
          <p>More and more, we continue to fine-tune our work based on our field development model. We can &#x2013; I see a very robust inventory of drilling opportunities in Forties Field going forward, even though we've drilled a number of wells this year, I see a healthy drilling program going forward with a lot of new prospect ideas such as this Brimman sand prospect, which was intentionally targeted in the field and Forties is a good place, which means it yields good opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our final question comes from Joe Magner with Macquarie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, thanks. Apologize if I missed the details earlier. Two questions. When do you think you will be in a position to provide preliminary volume growth and CapEx guidance for next year? And then second, with growing contribution from numerous large multi-year projects, what should we think about in terms of longer-term average production rates or sort of minimum rates going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're going through our &#x2013; truthfully we are going through our planning cycle right now. We should be in a position by the end of November to start talking a little bit about what we're seeing with respect to our growth for 2010. And on a long-term basis, we historically have not given long-term guidance. I think what we've said, at least at our Apache conference in Houston a year and a half ago, that based on the opportunities that we have and the projects that we have, depending on how much capital question throw at it, we can grow at double-digits for the next four years. But that is all dependent on how much capital you spend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And it appears we have no further questions at this time. I would like to turn it back to management for any additional or closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd like to thank everybody for joining us today. And I'll be in my office if anybody has any further questions after the call. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that concludes today's conference. Thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>