<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1306653" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-11-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>42</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Thomas P. Chambers, Vice President &#x2013; Planning and Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">G. Steven Farris, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Roger B. Plank, President</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">John A. Crum, Co-Chief Operating Officer and President &#x2013; North America</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Rodney J. Eichler, Co-Chief Operating Officer and President &#x2013; International</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Brian Singer</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Doug Leggate</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Leo Mariani</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Phi Dodge</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Phil Dodge</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Mark Polak</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">David Tameron</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Sachin Shah</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, everyone, and welcome to the Apache Corporation Third Quarter 2010 Earnings Release. This call is being recorded. Today's presentation will be hosted by Mr. Tom Chambers, Vice President of Corporate Planning and Investor Relations. Mr. Chambers, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon, everyone, and thanks for joining us for Apache Corporation's Third Quarter 2010 Earnings Conference Call. This morning we reported net income of $765 million, or $2.12 per diluted share. Adjusted earnings, which excludes certain items that impact the comparability of results, totaled 791 million, or $2.19 per diluted share. Cash flow from operations totaled $2 billion.</p>
          <p>On today's call, we'll have four speakers making repaired remarks prior to taking questions. Steve Farris, our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, will lead off, followed by Roger Plank, our President; John Crum, Co-Chief Operating Officer and President of North America; and then Rod Eichler, Co-Chief Operating Officer and President of International.</p>
          <p>We prepared our usual detailed supplemental data package for your use, which also includes the reconciliation of any non-GAAP numbers that we discuss, such as adjusted earnings, cash flow from operations or cost incurred. This data package can be found on our website at www.apachecorp.com/financialdata.</p>
          <p>Today's discussions may contain forward-looking estimates and assumptions and no assurances can be given that those expectations will be realized. A full disclaimer is located with the supplemental data package on our website.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn the call over to Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Tom, and good afternoon, everyone, and thank all of you for joining us for our Third Quarter 2010 Results Call. Those of you who have followed us many years know that Apache has a truly unique culture that involves a strong sense of urgency, empowerment of our employees and an independent mindset. And Apache's culture really is at the heart of how we build value and it's taken us from very humble position not so long ago to where we are today. And I don't think there's anything that exemplifies more our third quarter, what that culture is capable of delivering for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>On the portfolio side, we announced the $7 billion acquisition of three entire upstream operating regions from BP in the Permian Basin, Canada and Egypt. These three positions have an excellent fit with our existing core areas and provide us with a rich inventory of growth and value enhancement opportunities for years to come. It was July 20th, the last conference call, we were just announcing this step, and we were getting ready to get on a plane to go sell stock and debt for this important step forward.</p>
          <p>And while we truly believe that the transaction had all the ingredients to make a great deal for our shareholders, we really didn't know how the share price would react given the amount of new stock we were about to issue. Well, as most of you know, the stock actually went up by 5% in the three days after we announced, and this is opposite what generally happens. Internally, we took that as an endorsement of Apache's ability to generate value out of the transaction. Obviously, we're honored with the vote of confidence and want to assure all of you we'll do everything humanly possible to make good on this investment to create long-term value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>As of about an hour ago, we have now closed all three of the BP packages. If you haven't looked at the wire, we just closed Egypt today. So we are integrating the people and starting to get our arms around the assets. In addition, we expect to close on our merger with Mariner Energy when the vote is on November 10. We couldn't be more pleased and excited about the opportunity set we are building into our portfolio with the $11 billion in acquisitions.</p>
          <p>Through the steps we have added years of inventory to three of our core regions, and have built the right footprint in what we believe are two new areas for us: the deepwater oil exploration and LNG. LNG, for us, means the monetization of large North American gas resources at oil linked prices. We've taken these steps in our own way, which is the Apache way, and we're confident it will constitute important foundations for Apache's continued growth and profitability during the coming decade.</p>
          <p>On the operating front, in the third quarter we had a very successful quarter with production was up 10% year-on-year and our costs and expenses on a per unit basis, excluding DD&amp;A, was down 3% year-on-year. John, Rod and Roger will give you more color on our results and developments during the quarter in a moment. Before getting to that, I'd like to put 2010 in a broader context starting with where we were at the beginning of 2010 and what we look like going into 2011.</p>
          <p>If you recall in February of this year, on our 2009 year-end conference call, we were very bullish on what we perceived in the acquisition market. We had amassed over $2 billion of cash on the balance sheet, and with commodity prices at more reasonable levels, we indicated that we would be very actively pursuing acquisition opportunities. Little did we know how attractive it would become. After the dust settles and we have closed on all $11 billion of assets, Apache's share count will have increased by approximately 12% and we project we will end the year with a debt-to-cap of under 27%.</p>
          <p>Now on the flip side on the production side, we are projecting December 2010 average production to exceed 775,000 barrels of oil equivalent a day. So if you use the first quarter of 2010 as a baseline, when Apache's production averaged 586,000 barrels of oil equivalent, we're entering 2011 with a third more firepower than we entered 2010. That added firepower will give us more cash flow to exploit the 3.8 million acres we acquired across three of the most prolific core areas, Canada, Permian and the Western Desert of Egypt. And the new core areas we have added in the deepwater Gulf of Mexico has over 125 undeveloped blocks and interest in two world-class discoveries in Lucius and Heidelberg.</p>
          <p>Obviously, we're extremely excited about what we've been able to add to what we consider an already formidable base and the opportunities that they bring to continue to add long-term value to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn it over to Roger, John and Rob to talk about 2010 and '11 in a little more detail. Roger?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Steve, and good afternoon, everyone. Steve commented about how 2010 is shaping up and in a minute I'm going to give a further glimpse at what may be a truly outstanding 2011. But before delving into next year, I'd like to provide a few key highlights, financial highlights for the current quarter because we had fine results even though there were a lot of moving parts with all these transactions closing.</p>
          <p>Production was up 3% over second quarter to a record 667,000 barrels of oil equivalent. Oil and liquids were once again king, representing just over half our production but over three quarters of our revenue. Cash costs per BOE were essentially flat for the second quarter while DD&amp;A was up 3%, as you might expect, given that our acquisitions remained at prices above our historic reserve cost. Debt ended at $6.5 billion and debt-to-cap at 23%, and that excludes $1.2 billion of cash on the books at quarter's end.</p>
          <p>Also, just so our year of acquisitions doesn't overshadow the considerable progress we're making on the organic side of our business, you should know that from the first quarter to the third, our oil production jumped 17%, or 48,000 barrels per day, and over three-quarters of that growth was attributable solely to the drilling and development activities, primarily in Egypt and especially Australia.</p>
          <p>Turning to 2011, we're just now in the early stages of forming next year's plan, but one thing seems certain, our year-over-year production growth should be well into the double digits. Exactly how much our production grows depends on our ultimate capital budget, which will be fine tuned between now and the year-end. Primarily, however -- or preliminarily however, our capital budget is likely to reach or exceed $7 billion, up from around $6 billion this year. And well within cash flow at prices currently indicated for next year. We've hedged oil for 2011 to protect cash flow and insure an active capital campaign. While we believe that the supply/demand outlook strongly favors oil, with over three-quarters of our revenue tied to oil and liquid, and a flat quarter, we've hedged 64,000 barrels per day for 2011.</p>
          <p>We've used costless collars with floors between $65 to $70 to protect the downside, and ceilings between 95 to 103 to retain upside potential. We now have about 100,000 barrels per day hedged in total for 2011, or just over one-quarter of our post-merger liquids production. In addition to ensuring sufficient cash flow and capital to get after the upside on recently acquired properties, we're focusing particular attention on our extensive inventory of oil and liquids prospects for next year. I can't tell you how nice it is to have a deep inventory of oil prospects already in hand and not have to join the herd chasing after high cost oil opportunities after essentially the train's already left the station.</p>
          <p>We elected not to hedge any additional North American gas at today's low prices and we are continuing to focus capital on those international gas projects which are commanding substantially higher prices. Every day oil remains at these lofty levels means more debt reduction than earlier anticipated. Additionally, to ensure that we make a major dent in our debt, which should peak following the Mariner marriage &#x2013; Mariner merger at over $8 million, we anticipate selling $1 billion of property some time in the first half of 2011. Now we're just now in the process of determining which properties we'll be selling. So it's a bit early to tell the precise location, timing and impact of those sales. The combination of high oil prices and property sales means lower debt and greater financial flexibility, consistent with an A-rated company.</p>
          <p>With double-digit production growth pretty much a shoo-in for 2011, a portfolio that's long oil, a deep inventory of drilling opportunities and a strong financial position, we look forward to what could prove to be a banner year in 20111.</p>
          <p>John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Roger. Our third-quarter North American activity has been dominated by the efforts associated with the integration of more than $10 billion in assets being added to our portfolio this year. We closed the BP Permian transaction in the third quarter and the Canadian piece closed in early October. We took over operations of the BP Canada properties on Monday of this week and welcomed almost 300 new Apaches. We will take over the BP Permian assets December 1st. Meanwhile we expect to close on the Mariner merger next week after their shareholder meeting on November 10.</p>
          <p>Third-quarter North American production was up over 7% versus second quarter to just under 309,000 barrels equivalent per day. Fourth-quarter volumes will be up substantially as we see the impact of BP and Mariner acquisitions. Gulf Coast production increased 7% from the second quarter. Drilling activity offshore continues to be severely impacted by the permitting process associated with the post-Macondo requirements.</p>
          <p>While our Gulf region has received seven of the first 12 permits given in the Gulf of Mexico requiring both NTL-05 and NTL-06 compliance, they remain significantly behind their plans for the year. At least for now, the lack of clarity in the process makes it difficult for the BOEM to approve anything in a timely fashion. We are, however, presently running five jack-up rigs and one platform rig offshore, drilling primarily for oil targets. With permitting delays resolved, we expect to have a very strong 2011 drilling program with the addition of the new assets from Devon and Mariner.</p>
          <p>A third-quarter project of note is the redevelopment of the hurricane-damaged Eugene Island 330 field now under way. Three wells have already been drilled and are expected to add some 2,000 barrels a day, with additional drilling to extend into mid-2011 on this 63% working interest field. In the Permian region, we increased production by 21% on partial quarter BP volumes and a very active drilling program. Permian region production is expected to be up again in the fourth quarter as full BP volumes and the Mariner assets are added in.</p>
          <p>The BP and Mariner transactions allow our newly formed Permian region to add substantially to an already robust oil-prone drilling inventory with at least 3,000 new identified locations. The region was already very active in the quarter with seven rigs drilling 73 new wells, while 116 wells were completed as we caught up on a backlog of frac stimulation work. With the addition of the Mariner properties later this month, we expect to keep up to 20 rigs running in the Permian for 2011.</p>
          <p>We also reached agreement with Concho on the BP Marbob Yeso play in New Mexico. Apache acquired a 60% working interest in the operatorship of the joint properties. We have identified 800 drillable locations in the play and expect to be very active there next year. The region continues to evaluate horizontal drilling potential in a variety of well-known producing intervals in the basin. We continue to have success with horizontal completions in old water flood operations, notably north McElroy in the Grayburg formation, TXL South in Clear Fork and Shafter Lake in the San Andres where we're seeing IPs in the 250 to 400 barrel a day range.</p>
          <p>The central region also increased production by 7% from the second quarter. Importantly, this traditionally gas-prone region was up almost 29% on their oil production. The region activity continues to be dominated by horizontal multistage frac operations in the liquid-rich Granite Wash play in western Oklahoma and the Texas Panhandle. We expect to drill 40 horizontal Granite Wash wells this year. The first 19 are currently on production and producing a net 2,600 barrels of oil a day and some 40 million feet of gas. As in the Permian, we continue to look for additional applications for horizontal drilling.</p>
          <p>With this in mind, we recently tested what we believe to be the first horizontal tests of the Hogshooter wash interval of the Granite Wash play. This morning we announced two very successful tests. Each well produced at initial rates of over 2,000 barrels of oil a day and continue to average more than 700 barrels a day and 3.5 million feet of gas after two months. We expect to drill 10 additional Hogshooter tests in 2011.</p>
          <p>Our Canada region production decreased 1.8% from the second quarter. That figure will be up substantially in the fourth quarter as we add in BP volumes and ramp up at the Horn River. Our 50% owned Horn River production continues to build and reach the 100 million per day gross raw gas miles done in August and is expected to reach 200 million per day by first quarter of 2011. . We have 18 new wells on production in 2010 and expect to bring another 12 on during the remainder of the year. We will leave the year with 24 wells already drilled and awaiting completion.</p>
          <p>As mentioned earlier, our Canadian region is quickly integrating the BP properties with the help of the 300 new Apaches who moved in last Monday. While it's a little crowded in our Calgary office while we complete the space build out, we wanted to get the teams together as soon as possible. The most notable operation in the BP asset base in Canada is the Noel field producing from the Cadaman and Doyg intervals. In addition, the field appears to have significant Montney potential for which testing is now under way. Noel field production is currently at 62 million cubic feet of gas per day and is expected to reach 96 million by the end of the year and 125 million by the second quarter of 2011. The region is especially excited about the strong drilling inventory and the multitude of workover and re-completion opportunities that are available with the new BP acquisition.</p>
          <p>And now Rod Eichler will give you an update on International.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. Apache's International operations had a good quarter, averaging 359,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day with production increasing in three out of our four countries of operation. Egypt's gross production increased 3%, to 323,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day. Net production is only up slightly resulting from timing differences in the PSC cost recovery mechanism. New production from Faghur Basin fields and discoveries, as well as from a mature development lease, helped push gross operated oil and gas production above the 300,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day mark for the third consecutive quarter.</p>
          <p>Phase Two of the Faghur Basin infrastructure project, designed to upgrade capacity to 40,000 barrels of oil per day, was completed on schedule on September 30. The acquisition of BP's Western Desert assets is complete. All contracts and agreements have been finalized and final approval from the government of Egypt was received today. Closing occurred about an hour ago. Upon assuming operatorship, intelligent digging of the 24-inch Abu Gharadig to Dashour pipeline will commence and is expected to be completed by year-end. Minor modifications of the existing system will be completed during first quarter of 2011 that will allow high liquid yield gas from the Matru Basin to bypass the Salam gas plant and be directed to our existing 18-inch southern pipeline to the newly acquired Abu Gharadig plant and onward to the national gas grid via the re-rated 24-inch Abu Gharadig to Dashour pipeline.</p>
          <p>Salam gas train five and the southern pipeline loop projects should commence in early 2011. Feed studies for both the gas plant and the pipeline expansion have been completed. Negotiations to enter into EPC contracts are expected to be completed in the first quarter, with project completion forecast in late 2012. With the addition of the BP Western Desert properties, continued drilling success in the Faghur and the Matru Basins, recent production infrastructure improvements the 2011 drilling campaign is set to be a busy one, with the forecast number of exploratory and appraisal tests up over 50% compared to 2010, and total well count expected to exceed 200 growth wells.</p>
          <p>In Australia, net production decreased a modest 5% from the second quarter. Gas production decreased due to lower customer nominations, while oil production decreased due to natural decline in the Van Gogh oil field. Van Gogh, in which Apache has a 52.5% working interest, averaged 23,700 barrels of oil per day net during the quarter and the field has produced 11.2 million barrels gross since start-up in February, achieving project payout in late September.</p>
          <p>On October 4, we shut in Van Gogh production when the FPSO production seals in the swivel portion of the detachable turret mooring, or DTM, system was found to be leaking. No hydrocarbon or liquids were leaked to the ocean. The failure of all swivel seals at the same time is pretty much unprecedented and it is not an event that could have been reasonably foreseen. The result is that we have gone from a total seal failure to re-starting production in 19 days. The temporary repairs have restored partial production to approximately 25,000 barrels of oil per day gross.</p>
          <p>Permanent repairs will allow Van Gogh to return to full production of 40,000 barrels of oil per day gross by mid December. The BHP-operated Pyrenees FPSO development, in which Apache has a working interest that ranges from 28.5% to 31.5%, continued to perform well in the third quarter with net production averaging 23,600 barrels of oil per day up 2,300 barrels per day on the second quarter. Total production from Pyrenees from start-up through September 30 was 17.1 million barrels of oil gross. Pyrenees continues to produce at a steady 94,000 to 98,000 barrels of oil per day gross.</p>
          <p>Both the Halyard and Devil Creek development projects remain on schedule to deliver first gas to the Western Australia domestic market in 2011. Halyard, in which Apache has a 55% working interest, is a one well tieback of the 2008 Halyard gas discovery to our Varanus Island hub. First gas is expected in May of 2011. The Halyard project is designed for future well tie-ins expected with exploration success in the greater East Spar area.</p>
          <p>For example, Apache recently acquired a 55% interest in operatorship of the adjacent Spar field. A Spar 2 appraisal well, drilled in October, found 163 feet of net gas play in the upper <mark type="inaudible" />. Upon testing and completion, this well will be tied into the Halyard system. The Devil Creek development project, in which Apache has a 55% working interest, is 60% complete through September and on schedule to deliver first gas in the Reindeer field by November of 2011. Fabrication of the Reindeer wellhead platform is 90% complete and installation of the 16-inch onshore raw gas pipeline from the beach process into the gas plant has been completed..</p>
          <p>To expand our exploration of drilling inventory in 2011 and beyond, we've acquired eight new blocks in Carnarvon Basin via purchase of farm-in, adding over 10,000 square kilometers of new exploration acreage, thus increasing our total acreage position in the Basin by 35%. Apache will operate all eight blocks at an average drill tender of 52%. 4,600 square kilometers of new premium seismic will be acquired in the blocks starting in December of 2010. Australia continues to offers attractive gas prices for new long-term domestic contracts to further existing contracts.</p>
          <p>In addition, we made progress in monetizing our Julimar gas, signing two separate heads of agreement for 20-year supply of LNG at oil-linked prices. One of these agreements is with Tokyo Electric and the other one is with Kogas. We also continue to add growth to our pipeline with the sanction of the Massey domestic gas development project and the successful appraisal of our 2009 oil discovery at Valdez.</p>
          <p>In the North Sea, production was flat with second quarter. Increased output from our drilling program is offset by playing down time at Bravo and Charlie platforms. An active drilling program will continue in Forties during the fourth quarter. Two of the field's four platform rigs will be in continuous operation. In addition, by quarter end the Rowan Gorilla 7 jack-up will begin a six-month drilling campaign over the Echo platform. Drilling has not taken place on Echo since July of 2005. A satellite platform bridge link to the Alpha platform is progressing for installation in 2012. This project will allow expansion of critical utilities for the field including expanded power generation, fuel processing capacity, high-pressure gas compression, dehydration and most importantly, 18 new slots for drilling.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, a new time lapse, or 4D, seismic survey was completed in the Forties, with fast track process data coming available in time to influence the drilling locations previously referenced at Echo. 4D seismic imaging has driven the majority of drilling success at Forties for the past seven years. This data, along with the additional drilling slots planned for the Alpha satellite platform, should enable Forties to maintain steady production in the low 60,000-barrel a day range for the next three plus years.</p>
          <p>In Argentina, net production was up 7% from second quarter. Gas production increased 11% as a result of the successful 2010 gas plus drilling program in Neuqu&#xE9;n, the TDF San Sebastian drilling program and the increase in world demand. For the gas plus pricing program, we have signed one gas contract per 28 million cubic feet of gas per day in August 2010 with Pampa Energy. And we expect to sign a second contract with Pampa for 25 million a day this month. These two contracts are effective January 1, 2011, and specify a $5 per million Btu gas price for three years. These contracts will go a long way in pulling up our basket price at Neuqu&#xE9;n Basin, about $3 per million Btu.</p>
          <p>In support of these contracts, Apache has drills 18 wells to date in two fields in Neuqu&#xE9;n Basin with production capacity of 47 million cubic feet of gas per day. Additional wells are currently drilling and by January 1, 2011, Apache will have more than 53 million cubic feet of gas per available to satisfy these higher price gas contracts.</p>
          <p>That concludes our prepared remarks, and we'll now be happy to open it up for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of Brian Singer with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wanted to see if you can give us an update on what you're seeing in the LNG markets in terms of willingness and maybe price sensitivity to long-term contracts. And then an update on how you're thinking about Kitimat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're just &#x2013; we were in a situation where we really had just gone out to the markets because of our Wheatstone -- the Wheatstone II contracts that were signed was very important and we wanted to have that gas on the market before we really started actively pursuing contracts at Kitimat.</p>
          <p>In terms of &#x2013; right now we're very early. Of course, we have an awful lot of interest of potential buyers that want to buy gas. I don't think that there's any question and I hear it all the time that, well, is it going be gas related? There's no projects in the world that are going to build an LNG facility based on a gas price. It's going have to be based on an oil price. And it's really too early to tell what kind of &#x2013; what that slope is going to look like, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And then separately in the Granite Wash, can you add a little bit more color regarding what zones you drilled, and how you see the potential for further running room? And then the extent of the liquids content and the oil content that you saw with these two wells extending to other parts of your acreage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Brian. Obviously this is the first time we've tested the Hogshooter in a horizontal fashion. So it was really good results. This tends to be a little shallower in the sequence. And obviously has higher liquid yields. The issue, of course, is does that extend across the entire acreage base. The good news is, these wells were more than five miles apart. So it's not like this is an isolated area. So we have some 200,000 acres we control in this play, so obviously we'll be testing this with additional wells next year. We presently plan 10 Hogshooter intervals alone.</p>
          <p>We continue to test the additional intervals within the Granite Wash. You know that sequence can change anywhere from two to eight or so separate little sand intervals. And so we're going to continue to figure out where the best place to go with our future drilling. Obviously, it's liquids.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. And what do you see with current infrastructure, if there are any infrastructure constraints? At what level of rig count you could take it up to as more of a &#x2013; from a capacity perspective? How aggressive could you ramp that up, if you wanted to, next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the natural gas prices does have something to do with it. Obviously, we'd like to have &#x2013; obviously, these high liquid yields helps our economics on them substantially. But I think a lot of the infrastructure issues are associated with gas back out, and the bottom line is, at these kind of prices, conventional drilling's kind of drying up. So we haven't seen any real change. We would expect to run some 10 Granite Wash rigs next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Doug Leggate with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon, guys. I'm going to try a couple here, and I'm not sure how many of them you're going to answer. But I wanted to start off with the production guidance or the production discussion, I guess, that you had a few minutes ago. If we just look at what you're saying about December and let's assume we took Q3 as a flat rate for October, November, just as a starting point. And then run December for next year, assuming that new projects offset declines, that gets you to about a 19% growth rate year-over-year. Am I smoking something, or is that in the ballpark? And then what really do you see as the key project moving parts for next year that could change that one way or the other?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that the &#x2013; I think your math is probably pretty correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We like what you're smoking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the real question obviously is, is that -- and it always is and people don't want to hear it -- it's commodity price. Because you really have to have the capital to put on these properties. And right now, frankly, we have very good oil prices. And I don't know whether the Fed's buying treasuries is going to help the bond market -- is going to help the economy, but it's damn sure helping the oil price. And that's good news for us because 50% of our production is on the oil side.</p>
          <p>The real question besides commodity prices is what we sell and when we sell it. We're dedicated to getting our debt to cap down and that is &#x2013; we're below 27% at the end of the year. And if we sold $1 billion, I mean it would help us greatly to be down in the same category we were at the beginning of the year. And we really haven't identified those properties yet, but, I mean, we're going to have &#x2013; I mean, if you just look at the metrics, we're going to have good numbers next year. It's going to be hard not to, frankly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the answer, Steve. If I could just pick on a couple of things then. Capital expenditure on the BP assets that you've acquired -- have you identified what step up might be? I think when you did the deal you suggested BP was planning something like a $400 million or $500 million CapEx plan. What will your numbers likely to look like on those properties?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've just, in fact, all our corporate <mark type="inaudible" /> engineering group and our planning group have just now made a loop to every one of the regions including the Permian and Canada. So it's -- quite frankly, I mean, John mentioned the Yeso play. I mean, we've identified 800 locations. It's a question of how many rigs you want to run out there. This isn't a question of how much money could we spend; it's going be how much money will we spend in each one of these areas. Because, frankly, you could double that number in the Permian Basin right now in terms of opportunity sets. And the real issue is going be how do we balance that portfolio, which is going be one of our real strategic issues this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. So I guess a final one then for me is just wanted to drill a little bit on a couple of the specific assets. Egypt first of all. So the pipeline looks like it's going be taken care of next year. What is your latest thoughts in terms of how much of your 300 million a day you're going to be able to open up?</p>
          <p>And finally Mist Mountain. You never really seem to talk about that too much. Any thoughts on that 8 trillion cubic feet asset that doesn't really seem to get much of a profile? It would be appreciated. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the first part, dealing with the 300 million a day, and this is referencing the shut-in gas that we have on wells that have already been drilled and completed in the Khalda area. The existing pipeline, and I'm talking about the &#x2013; there are multiple components to evacuate the gas to this new route. One is our southern 18-inch gas pipeline that Apache has had in place for the last decade, and which connects to the BP Abu Gharadig plant and thence on to a 24-inch Abu Gharadig to Dashour pipeline. That line is old and has been de-rated and is only carrying about 40 to 45 million cubic feet of gas a day at present.</p>
          <p>Our expectation is to be able to add &#x2013; because of the configuration of gas plants downstream are slightly -- the gases are slightly different composition than what we have in the northwestern part of the desert, we're going to bring the Matru Basin gas down there. And it's our expectation that if the pipeline pigs out, it can be re-rated to its original rating of approximately 150 million a day. We should be able to add about 85 to perhaps 100 million a day into that line from our Martru Basin fields sometime in 2011. That'll be incremental to the existing gas, which is going down the line right now. That would bring it to its full capacity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the Mist Mountain point, obviously that's coalbed methane in Southern Canada. We see that project needs a substantial amount of additional research and certainly consultation before we were able to move forward and, most importantly, needs some higher gas prices. So we're going to continue to work it. It's obviously pretty exciting play with that kind of resource in place. So I don't think you'll see us massively drilling in Mist Mountain next year, though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks for your answers, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Leo Mariani with RBC Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Good morning here, guys. Wanted to get a sense if you guys have come up with sort of an approximate well inventory of projects in the Granite Wash at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have a substantial inventory, and I can tell you that the inventory is somewhat dynamic. We continue to move different wells to the top of the list, but there's in excess of 1,000 locations that we know we have out there. So it's just a matter of which ones we're going to drill first. Like I told you, we think we can keep about ten rigs running. The only issues out there to date have been access to frac equipment, and that will probably continue to be an issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And how many wells do you think you guys could drill in a year with ten rigs out there? And what do those wells cost you roughly apiece to drill?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're spending about somewhere in the 5 million range. Sometimes it's 5 million, 6 million, depends how many times we frac these things. But one of the interesting pieces we're doing, we did do a dual lateral this year. We have not completed the second lateral yet. But that could change our price structure on a per lateral basis substantially. We will complete the second lateral early next year and then we'll have some good feel for where that can go. I guess that's the &#x2013; did I answer all your questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>10 wells...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So 10 rigs. We can drill a well roughly every month. So if you had 10 rigs running, you can drill 100 wells, roughly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. In terms of what you guys are talking about in Egypt. Sounds like your Phase II with Faghur is getting ready to start up here. I guess it already has. Just trying to get a sense of what the incremental volumes are going to be from that Phase II?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Phase II &#x2013; Phase I was completed back in May and that was the initial early production facility that did about 20,000 barrels of oil per day. And that was completed on schedule. Phase II was to be able to ramp that up an additional 20,000 to get to 40,000, which was complete at the end of September. And that is what's currently producing. We have a Phase III, which is really to capture the 35 million to 40 million cubic feet of gas per day that's associated with that oil. And that will be complete probably in the second quarter of 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. Okay. I just wanted to clarify one comment that I thought I heard on the call. Did you guys say that you thought your North Seas Forties production would be in the low 60,000 barrel a day range for the next roughly three years, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I just wanted to get a sense in the Permian kind of where you guys thought you were in terms of the evaluating some of these new horizontal plays out there. Is it kind of early days for you? Have you done some test wells? Can you give us a sense of kind of where you are there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I gave you a few examples of some things we've done. And &#x2013; but I think we've now tested eight different horizons out there with horizontal wells already this year. And we're finding some interesting results. I've got to tell you I'm not ready to share all of that information, because obviously some of that's critical in as we gather up acreage around our successes. So &#x2013; but we have had good results. We've shared with you a somewhat surprising benefit of horizontal in these old water floods. We just continue to be amazed. We're drilling wells that come in at 400 barrels per day on fields that have been &#x2013; that are 60, 70 years old, and that have been water flooded and on10-acre spacing. So we think the potential for horizontal drilling in the Permian is just unbelievable, really.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just kind of looking at production real quick. I think you guys were talking about getting to just over 775,000 barrels per day in December. I guess if I just think about the math from a high level, you guys are adding somewhere around 140,000 barrels a day from acquisition and producing about 660,000 barrels a day, a little bit over that I guess in the third quarter. If I add those two up, it gets me closer to 800. Is there any declines between that 800 and the 775? Maybe your Gulf volumes expected have dropped a little bit or can you provide any color on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think &#x2013; you don't want to shoot your gun all the time. So we're comfortable with 775 right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Philip Dodge with Tuohy Brothers Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everybody. This might be a question that would be better at the next conference call, but let me try anyway. How do you stand on what you might do on the Mariner properties after the closing? And can you reveal whether Mariner itself has applied for any drilling permits either on their shallow water or even on their operated deepwater?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I can tell you that we will have some substantial activity, especially associated with the shallower water on the shelf. That stuff will be merged into our existing Gulf of Mexico shelf operation. On the other side, Mariner has got a number of applications in, certainly associated around tiebacks of existing projects that they want to get tied back to existing platforms. We expect those to clear relatively soon and be able to proceed with this work. This was stuff that would have been done by now had the moratorium not come into play. We presently do not have any wells in process for permitting to drill. And we would expect that to come in 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then unrelated on hedging, I know you seem to be doing a lot more than you were a few years ago when you would sort of reluctantly admit that you were hedging. Even though the company is much larger and therefore protect -- greater protected against risk than at that time. So I'm interested in the thinking on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Let me &#x2013; and then I'll have Roger. I think more of it's in terms of where we find ourselves. We have a absolute debt that is higher than what we have had in the past. And if you look at our financials and the same with anyone else, I mean, they are oil dependent. We're 50% of it on the production side, 75% of our revenues. We've just bought a bunch of assets we want to spend some money on. So the &#x2013; what we looked at is, is to make sure that we could protect the capital budget in 2011. And also make sure we could pay down some debt. Which is &#x2013; and we haven't found ourselves in that position in some time, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess the only thing I'd add Phil is, we've got a &#x2013; as was hopefully obvious by the comments today, we've got a tremendous inventory of things to do with all the acquisitions that we've made. And so when they do ratchet up the debt and need to make progress there. What we don't want to have happen is do that to the detriment of being able to get after the upside of these properties while continuing with our base long-term company-builder type projects. So this probably ought to be considered to some extent, because you're right about our size -- we have less risk, but to some extent ought to be considered as a one-off for an unusual set of circumstances where we want to both pay down debt and also get after the upside on these properties.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It makes sense. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Polak with Scotia Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys. Question for you on Wheatstone. With the recent sales agreement you've signed, just curious where that leaves you now in terms of how much un-contracted gas there is? How many more deals to do? And then, are you looking at sanctioning decision kind of by late 2011 there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to the volumes, the Wheatstone project, the phase that we're involved in, about 5.83 million tons per annum is the size &#x2013; the gross size of the facility. Apache's net share of that would be about 0.95 million tons per annum. To date, with the announced TEPCO and the Kogas deal, we would have placed in the market about 0.75 million tons per annum or about almost 80% of the allowable throughput volume to our share. So that's a very good start. As far as the final investment decision, that's pretty much on track for a timeline that would lead us into probably summertime of 2011, early third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and one more if I could on Egypt. Similar maybe just on Fullong 5. Wondering where your guys are at there with fraction and timing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've completed the feed studies this past quarter, the end of the quarter. And we expect in the first quarter to enter into EPC contracts. We're going through the process with the joint venture companies right now to select the vendors and do the appropriate negotiations on the price. And we expect to be done at some time in the next 120 days. It'll allow us to start construction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of John Hurling with Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, three quick ones. What's your unamortized property cost level on a dollar basis right now, post all the acquisitions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know, John, I'll have to get back to you after the call on that one. Okay? I don't have...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have the data in front of me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's fine. With the Gulf of Mexico, I mean we all hope that BOEM works quickly, but in the event that they don't, will you just throttle back or will you accelerate with more onshore type development for next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I &#x2013; the one thing I will say is, is that we are certainly not out of opportunities. In terms of the Permian Basin, in terms of Canada, in terms of Egypt. Our biggest challenge for 2011 is how we allocate the cash flow that we have. It's not in terms of looking for opportunities. It's more as making sure we spend money on the right opportunities. So the Gulf of Mexico wouldn't &#x2013; I mean, it wouldn't bother me &#x2013; I wouldn't like it because I think that's the wrong answer for the United States. But I don't think &#x2013; we're not worrying about where we're going to put the capital next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'd just mention, Tom Chambers and I were talking about this earlier, that when the guys in the regions submitted their request for capital it was between 8 and $9 billion. So when we talk about 7 or 7 plus billion of capital it's not because we don't have any more to do this. There's lots more to do, and that's really &#x2013; that number will probably go up in terms of what they could do as we do get our arms around the BP properties and the Mariner properties.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Roger. Last one for me. Normally you talk about services costs and we've heard many other companies kind of complain about the rise of frac costs. What are you seeing in your areas and how are you managing it? Because you weren't vociferous this time, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I &#x2013; you can't have $3.80 gas and have costs like we have them, not forever. And I have no idea about others' economics, but it would be very difficult in our economics to run the economics to drill just a horizontal gas well in the United States right now, and costs are a big component of that. And I will tell you, sooner or later that's going to change. That's got to change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>your next question comes from the line of David Tameron with Wells Fargo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. A couple questions. The Hogshooter. Where &#x2013; is that near the Marmaton? Is that near the Des Moines? Where exactly is it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we gave &#x2013; in the press release, I don't have that with me, we gave you the actual location of those two tests we did. But yes, there is Marmaton in the area and there's certainly Granite Wash A, B and C as well. So might want to -- the press release has the actual location...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I was trying to get more of where it's at in the stack pay. I mean, is it a above the Marmaton? Is it...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh. I'm sorry. It's high in the section. This'll be one of the shallower intervals in the section. I apologize.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And did you ever give well costs? And if so, I might have missed it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Granite Wash wells?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The two most recent well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We're &#x2013; it depends again on the well but we can spend somewhere in the $5 to $6 million range, again, depending on the number of fracs, because that's really the key in these things. Depends on whether you put six fracs or 16 fracs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then one question, I guess. Steve, you touched on this briefly, but if you think about the hurdles and constraints for the next couple years, get your program done, I mean, you said you have too many projects, but to get the program done you want to get done, what's the biggest hurdle standing in the way right now as you see it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for the most part, it's all pretty well laid out. The real decision we're going have to make, frankly, and we haven't even &#x2013; is how much money we spend in the Horn River. Because if you &#x2013; we anticipate we will be ready for -- actually get contracts on Kitimat, but we spent probably $370 million there this year, John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it was on purpose because we were really wanting to make sure from a reservoir standpoint that that reservoir is as good as what we thought it was. Obviously we found out it was as good as what we thought it was, and now it's a question of how do you balance your capital -- current capital against future opportunity. And that's going to be one of the toughest things we're going to have to decide here 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just thinking about program execution, it sounds like you have all the equipment, the people. I guess you added some people with the BP transaction, but you have the people, the equipment in place to get the program executed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean we &#x2013; we're going to spend $6 billion in 2010. We spent quite a bit more than that, I think, in 2008. So from a manpower standpoint, our organization can spend that. I can't emphasize enough the most important thing we have in front of us and the challenge is how we allocate the cash flow that we generate. Because that is key to making sure this &#x2013; we take advantage of what we bought.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's clearly number one. One challenge we've got on the Permian on the BP properties -- these properties weren't for sale thirty days before, basically, we got to them. So they weren't all put in pretty packages. So data is an issue and it is going take us a little bit of time to get our arms around exactly what the opportunity set looks like. So we've got some data challenges but we're tearing into it and we'll get after that fairly shortly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thanks for the answers. Appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Sachin Shah with Capstone Global Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Just wanted to get an update on the shareholder vote for Mariner's on the 10th? Just kind of anticipated timing of the close thereafter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. I really couldn't understand the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the question was about an update on the vote of the Mariner deal. And without getting into specifics, I think we're coming along.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure we can answer that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't have a &#x2013; right now we've got about 45% of the vote in that I understand. And you'd have to be &#x2013; I would imagine that it's pretty much in favor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to clarify. I wanted to find out the closing of the transaction after the shareholder vote.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, I'm sorry, we talked around and missed the question. It is immediate. As soon as the shareholder vote is counted and it's official, we will then own Mariner Energy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. The second question is, you've announced a lot of transactions this second half of the year? Just wanted to find out, as far as pipeline going forward, are you going be at kind of aggressive as you've been thus far?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the acquisition pipeline, I think we're going to kind of slow down here a little bit. Frankly, we don't plan acquisitions. We never have. One of them was very fortuitous for us, obviously, the biggest one we did. But in terms of going forward, we had a pretty good asset base then and I think we have a truly formidable asset base now. So we're not really out there looking to grow just to grow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You mentioned earlier about the stimulus being a positive kind of tailwind for oil prices. How does that kind of influence your thinking about getting or acquiring opportunistic assets? Or assets on an opportunistic basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you repeat the question? I'm sorry. We're having trouble hearing you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You mentioned earlier in the call how the stimulus from the government is probably somewhat of a tailwind in relation to oil prices and helping oil prices kind of move higher, and so kind of that train of thought. How does that process allow you to kind of think about acquisitions and acquiring assets going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I might just comment that my mind hasn't really gone to that yet. Because we do, as we've indicated have -- we got to make a dent in our debt. And we also have plenty on our plate from an investment standpoint. So &#x2013; and I also, having been around Apache for 50 plus years, you don't want to jinx this thing by counting on it. So we sort of look at it day-to-day and every day that goes is another day that we pay down a little more debt and put ourselves in a position where ultimately where maybe we could be back on that trail. But I don't think we look at that as imminent. But clearly at these prices &#x2013; our internal price forecast that we're using is $70 oil, so anything above that looks like gravy at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. Thank you. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no further questions. Presenters, do you have any closing remarks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I just want to say thank you for joining us today. If you've got any further questions I'll be in my office after the call. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>