<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1206189" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-02-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>43</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John M. Colglazier, Vice President, Investor Relations and Communications</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James T. Hackett, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">David Heikkinen</participant>
      <participant id="4">James Hackett</participant>
      <participant id="5">Charles Meloy</participant>
      <participant id="6">Ben Dell</participant>
      <participant id="7">Robert Daniels</participant>
      <participant id="8">Ellen Hannan</participant>
      <participant id="9">Karl Kurz</participant>
      <participant id="10">John Colglazier</participant>
      <participant id="11">Brian Singer</participant>
      <participant id="12">Robert Christensen</participant>
      <participant id="13">Joseph Allman</participant>
      <participant id="14">Thomas Gardner</participant>
      <participant id="15">Chuck Meloy</participant>
      <participant id="16">Rehan Rashid</participant>
      <participant id="17">Stephen Beck</participant>
      <participant id="18">Philip Dodge</participant>
      <participant id="19">R. A. Walker</participant>
      <participant id="20">R.A. Walker</participant>
      <participant id="21">Raymond Deacon</participant>
      <participant id="22">Doug Leggate</participant>
      <participant id="23">Jeb Armstrong</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Fourth Quarter 2008 Anadarko Petroleum Corporation Earnings Conference Call. My name is Stacy, and I'll be your conference moderator for today. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. We will be facilitating a question-and-answer session towards the end of the conference. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded for replay purposes.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the presentation over to your host for today's call, Mr. John Colglazier. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Stacy. Good morning, and thank you for joining us today for Anadarko's Fourth Quarter and Year-end 2008's Conference Call. Joining me on the call today are Jim Hackett, our Chairman and CEO and other executives who will be available to answer your questions later in the call. As a reminder, we have posted additional information in our Fourth Quarter Operations Report, available on our website at www.anadarko.com.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to Jim, I do need to remind you this presentation contains our best and most reasonable estimates and information. A number of factors could cause actual results to differ materially from what we discuss. You should read our full disclosure on forward-looking statements and our presentation slides, our latest 10-K, other filings and press releases for the risk factors associated with our business. In addition, we will reference non-GAAP measures. So be sure to see the reconciliations in our earnings release and on our website. We encourage you to read the cautionary note to US investors contained in the presentation slides for this call.</p>
          <p>And with that, let me turn the call over to Jim Hackett.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. Good morning, everybody. As you saw in last night's release, Anadarko delivered a very good quarter, as our asset portfolio showed depth and balance in managing through the challenges we faced in 2008. Looking ahead, I've not been more excited about the quality of exploration and development projects assembled in our portfolio. Even in today's price environment where we have to carefully shepherd our capital, we are pursuing a wonderful set of appraisal and exploration opportunities as we enter 2009. Our substantial liquidity also enables us to execute upon this operational program while maintaining a very strong balance sheet.</p>
          <p>I want to highlight some of the accomplishments detailed in last night's release. Firstly, exceeded investor guidance for organic reserve adds for the year by adding 290 billion, million barrels of oil equivalent of new reserves. And I'll provide more detail on this very positive news later in the call.</p>
          <p>Second, we delivered sales volumes toward the high end of guidance at 52 million barrels of oil equivalent for the quarter, overcoming the continuing third-party effects of Hurricane Ike, which resulted in approximately 45,000 net barrels per day of Gulf of Mexico production shut-ins.</p>
          <p>Third, we increased total sales volumes year-over-year by approximately 5% from retained properties, overcoming the deferral of approximately 13 million barrels of production resulting from hurricanes and other third-party infrastructure issues over the last three quarters of 2008. This year-over-year production increase was underpinned by our Rockies region, with a 17% increase in sales volumes. The Greater Natural Buttes area and Powder River Basin <mark type="audio gap" /> key drivers, with sales volume increases of about 30 and 45% respectively over 2007 levels.</p>
          <p>Beyond the revenue generated by production volume growth, our operating teams have done an outstanding job of cost control by striving for continual improvements in our drilling efficiencies. This success is detailed in the Operations Report, and it demonstrates our significant enhancements in spud to rig release times, rig mobilization times and a 12% overall improvement in the amount of time it takes from spud to spud in our core onshore-operated development and drilling operations. As a result, we've been able to maintain our level of activity with fewer rigs and without increasing capital during a year of sizable service cost increases in the industry.</p>
          <p>Turning to the exploration side of Anadarko's business, our global program continues to deliver exceptional results. As announced Monday, we made a substantial deepwater Gulf of Mexico discovery at the Heidelberg prospect in the Green Canyon area. The Heidelberg discovery well encountered more than 200 feet of net oil pay in multiple high-quality Miocene sands. This continued success of our program in the Green Canyon area validates our geologic interpretation of the subsalt Miocene trend, and strengthens our successful track record in the deepwater Gulf of Mexico.</p>
          <p>Including Heidelberg, we've now made seven major discoveries in the subsalt Miocene trends since 2005, each targeting resources of more than 100 million barrels. Additionally, Heidelberg's proximity to our Constitution spar validates the benefit of our hub-and-spoke system of multiple platforms in the Gulf by allowing us to consider stand-alone or tie back options once we conduct further appraisal work, which we expect to begin later this year. When we wrap up activities at Heidelberg, we expect to move the Amos Runner rig to spud another Middle-Miocene test at the Vito prospect in Mississippi Canyon Block 984, which we operate with a 20% working interest.</p>
          <p>In addition to finding new resources, we are moving existing discoveries forward as well. During the fourth quarter, our Board sanctioned the development of the Caesar/Tonga Complex in the Green Canyon area, which has an estimated resource range of between 200 and 400 million barrels of oil equivalent. We anticipate having our first significant volumes from this development in 2011. We expect to tie Caesar/Tonga production back to our Constitution spar, significantly reducing development costs and time to first production. Moving from the Middle-Miocene to the Lower -Tertiary, we are currently drilling the Shenandoah well, located in Walker Ridge block 52. The well is targeting Wilcox objective, and we expect to announce results shortly.</p>
          <p>We are also having excellent success in transferring our deepwater skill sets internationally, especially in Ghana. The Jubilee field is one of the top new discoveries in the world, and we've had six successes from six wells in this emerging core area, with five successful exploration and appraisal wells in the Jubilee field, and another successful exploration well at the nearby Odum's prospect.</p>
          <p>During the fourth quarter, we announced results of the Hyedua-2 well located 3 miles to the northwest of the original Mahogany-1 discovery well. And recently our partners announced the successful Mahogany-3 well located about three miles to the southeast of the discovery well. With Mahogany-3, we also discovered a new oil bearing zone that provides additional opportunities for meaningful resource addition.</p>
          <p>As a result of these step-out wells, the operator recently increased the field's estimated resources to a range of 600 million to 1.8 billion barrels of oil equivalent. In addition, we completed a DST at Hyedua-2 with strong results. The flow rates were approximately 17,000 barrels per day of 37-degree API gravity crude, and the test demonstrated that the well is capable of flowing more than 20,000 barrels per day. The results also confirmed the quality and connectivity of the reservoir.</p>
          <p>We are moving forward with the development program in Ghana, anticipate four rigs operating in the area by the end of the first quarter. This active drilling program will encompass a combination of appraisal, development and exploration wells, including the Jubilee look-a-like prospect at Tweneboa, which we recently spud on the Deepwater Tano License and the Teak prospect located on the West Cape Three Points Block.</p>
          <p>Turning to offshore Brazil, we were the first foreign operator to announce a deepwater pre-salt discovery at Wahoo. Planning is now underway to run a multizone DST towards the middle of this year, and we also anticipate throwing additional appraisal and exploration wells in 2009 on this C-30 block.</p>
          <p>Earlier in the year, we also discovered hydrocarbons in the circle well on block ES-24 offshore Brazil. However, after returning the rig to Serpa and reaching the primary objective, it appears that the results do not support a commercial stand-alone development at this time. However, the data provides valuable information and encouragement for additional exploration on block 24 and the adjacent block ES-25, where we currently are drilling the Coalho prospect with a 40% working interest. We expect results in this well near the end of the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Our US onshore exploration program in the Marcellus, Haynesville and Maverick shale plays continues to deliver positive results. Our first horizontal completion in the Marcellus was a success, testing at approximately 4.5 million cubic feet of natural gas per day. We're currently completing a second horizontal well, and have two others in various stages of drilling. We expect to continue an active program in 2009, with additional horizontal and vertical tests in the trend. We've provided some additional detail on each of these areas in our quarterly Operations Report that is available on our website.</p>
          <p>In addition to the noteworthy operational accomplishments discussed today and provided in our Ops Report, our earnings release provides financial highlights from the quarter and the year. We've restored the balance sheet, maintained our investment-grade rating and built a very strong liquidity position. We also achieved an approximate 34% net-to-debt cap ratio within the target range we set for our post-asset divestiture program over the last two years without issuing equity.</p>
          <p>We ended 2008 with approximately $2.4 billion of cash from the balance sheet, after retiring about $370 million of total debt during the quarter and closing the divestiture of the Peregrino heavy-oil field offshore Brazil. We continue to maintain additional financial flexibility and liquidity through our undrawn $1.3 billion committed revolving credit facility, which does not mature until 2013.</p>
          <p>Before we turn the call over for your questions, I want to walk you through the results for our reserve additions for the year. As stated earlier, we added 290 million barrels of oil equivalent of proved reserves, before the effects of price revisions, which calculates to replacing over 140% of reported sales volumes for the year. We spent 4.7 &#x2013; $4.8 billion in oil and gas exploration and development activities. We estimate our proved reserves at year-end totaled 2.28 billion barrels of oil equivalent, which takes into account approximately 137 million barrels of oil equivalent associated with divestitures.</p>
          <p>Price related to revisions primarily associated with the year-over-year price declines for crude and NGLs resulted in a 4% decrease in total proved reserves, which is low relative to the absolute commodity price drops year-over-year, and reflects very positively on the economic quality of our asset portfolio.</p>
          <p>Reserve additions were primarily driven by development in infill activities in the Rockies and appraisal drilling in the Gulf of Mexico. We're pleased with the capital efficiency of our portfolio, especially when taking into account that more than 30% of our 2008 capital went to long-term projects like Jubilee, Wahoo and other exploration spending that did not add reserves in 2008.</p>
          <p>We talked about this before, but with the rapid decline in commodity prices, we want to reiterate that at current service costs, the majority of our core natural gas projects onshore in the US are capable of generating at least a 10% incremental rate of return at a NYMEX flat gas price deck of approximately $5. Also at current service costs and a flat NYMEX price of less than $30 per barrel, our major deepwater projects such as Caesar/Tonga and Ghana are each capable of generating greater than 10% incremental rates of return. We're actively addressing our service costs and expect to achieve material reductions, which will bolster the return on our investments. The quality of our asset portfolio is evident also in the minimal impairments recorded for the year, as the economics of our assets held up in our field-by-field impairment test analysis.</p>
          <p>As we discussed previously, part of our risk management strategy includes firm transportation commitments and basis hedges, covering approximately 95% of our Rockies production in 2009, about 70% in 2010, and about 60% in 2011. We have no material concentration on counter-party risk from the derivatives supporting our basis management. We've locked in differentials in the majority of our Rockies production with the average price of Henry Hub less $1.25 this year, Henry Hub less $1.28 in 2010, and $1.07 in 2011. As we stated before, we're committed to an incremental 450 million cubic feet per day, a firm transportation to support substantial additional take-away capacity in the Rockies for 2011 and beyond.</p>
          <p>Operationally, our portfolio is delivering upon Investor guidance, even with unusual weather and mechanical disruptions in the Gulf of Mexico last year. We exceeded or met our 2008 targets for production growth, organic reserve adds, debt reduction and production replacement. We've also delivered significant exploration success with additional prospects identified and major opportunities ahead. We believe we are well positioned with our current portfolio of assets to manage through various price cycles, and continually delivering value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Our Board meets next week to review and approve our 2009 capital budget, and I look forward to talking with you again next week about the capital program and production guidance. We'll be sending out a news release this morning with the details of a special conference call to be held on February 11. Because we do not yet have Board approval for our capital program, we can't discuss spending plans except in a general sense today.</p>
          <p>Now we'll turn it over to the operator and open it up for questions. Stacy, if you would.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of David Heikkinen with Tudor, Pickering, Holt. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, just thinking general...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Don't tell Dan [Pickering] that she was having trouble with Pickering.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I know, she got my name though, so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That may be a first. The general spending sense, can you talk in general terms about what you're thinking going into the Board meeting and call next week for 2009 CapEx and production?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, David. I think at the end of the third quarter we had shared that we were going to be at a number that was at or around what we were spending in 2008. We've obviously dialed that down meaningfully. And we will be getting back to you with the exact number. The important thing is we still think we will grow reserves and production with that number, and keep the balance sheet intact. And that's overcoming a number of different factors that we're facing here currently which are in some ways good: in terms of the OPEC cuts in Algeria; as well as some of the fracs spread crash that we had at the end of the year on the NGL side; as well as the shut-in production that we have in the Gulf of Mexico that continues probably through the first quarter.</p>
          <p>And Chuck can address that a little later in terms of kind of when that comes on. And we've got it &#x2013; we want to make sure that we stay committed to our exploration activities in our mega-projects for development that really are going to be coming on in price environments that are very different than today's world. So I think when you put all that together, we still feel very good about where we'll come out with the metrics next week.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if you think about your long-term projects, kind of minimum commitments for '09, still about 35 to 40% of, I guess, maybe $1.5 billion? Can you put a dollar amount on long-term commitments of what the floor would be for CapEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think about 20% of it's going to go to mega-projects. Again, I won't tell you the exact numbers here yet, and about 20% to exploration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's helpful. And then on the &#x2013; I'll just ask Chuck the question on the pipelines in the Gulf of Mexico that production that's shut-in, what major lines are you tied into and how does that ramp-up through the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We really have two issues that we're dealing with David. The first is at Conger, which Shell's repairing the infrastructure there. And that should be online sometime in middle-to-late February. And then both K2/Marco Polo complex and the Constitution/Ticonderoga complex are tied into <mark type="inaudible" />, and that should be completed in and around the end of the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line Ben Dell with Sanford Bernstein. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ben.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just had two quick questions. One was on Sierra Leone. Do you have a estimate of the, a pre-dip drill estimate of the size of that prospect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ben. This is Bob Daniels. I'd say most of the things we're looking for in West Africa, the range would start at about 100 million barrels and go up from there. We're really looking for Jubilee-like accumulations with the same depositional system, and really we're looking about the same areal extent of potential reservoirs. So it could be very substantial, but I'd say that everything's going to have starting range of about 100 million barrels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my second question was just on the Lower-Tertiary. Now, there's been ongoing discussions around what sort of flow rates you need to make that economic. It seemed that higher commodity prices &#x2013; people were talking anywhere between 12 and 15,000 barrels from the wells to get the well rates economic. Do you have a feel for what flow rates you'd need at these commodity prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the Lower-Tertiary?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that number that you threw out there's probably about as good as anybody's got at this point. But I think that one of the key things you got to look for in the Lower-Tertiary is people are just getting to understand what their reservoir distribution is and the quality of that reservoir. And I think what we're working on is how do we get better reservoir quality in the Lower-Tertiary traps that can therefore deliver the higher flow rates that we would like to see. And that's where most of our effort's going.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. That's all I had. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ben.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ellen Hannan with Weeden &amp; Company. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Jim, I think you've addressed most of my questions in terms of the longer-term outlook on your CapEx spending. I was going to ask you about the &#x2013; you alluded to the creative tensions going on within the Company in terms of CapEx on the short-term versus the long-term, and balancing that between the oil and gas. I guess your comments are suggesting we'll get a better read on that next week. And the other question I had was a little bit more detailed. And that was really, you alluded to the frac spread crash, I think, in the fourth quarter in NGLs. And could you talk about what you're seeing there in terms of your income in the Midstream?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks for the question. Karl, I don't know if you want to take part...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Ellen, this is Karl Kurz. Obviously we did see the frac spreads crash. In fact, went back and looked at a couple of months ago, they were negative all through 2009. We have seen a modest recovery in those frac spreads in the last few weeks where we see ethylene and propane frac spreads for both our Rockies and Southern regions now positive. They're not near the levels we saw last year, but we do expect to be in a recovery mode for the foreseeable future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And I think the second part of that question &#x2013; and this is Colglazier. In our GPM margin for the quarter, we also &#x2013; that's where all, most of our product inventory resides. So with the massive drop in the product prices quarter-to-quarter, we also had an inventory write-down there. So it, hopefully, that's a one-time event, and go forward from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you say how much that write-down was, John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A combination of the frac &#x2013; the crash frac spreads and the inventory write-down, they're pretty evenly split between their, each of them about $30 million, plus or minus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks. Just one other question from me, and again, this may be a little early. Do you have an estimate for the development costs for Caesar/Tonga?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've &#x2013; Chuck, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The total cost was about $1.3 billion, which we have roughly 33% of.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Brian Singer with Goldman Sachs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Brian</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you mentioned 20% of next year's budget or so was on mega-projects and 20% on exploration. If we look at the remaining 60%, how do you think about the right level of onshore activity, both when you add things up relative to your cash flow, but also to ensure the type of rig rate and service cost decreases that you're looking for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chuck, you want to answer that because I think it feeds into how we're managing things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Jim mentioned earlier, we're still a little early in our budget cycle to give you an exact proportion that we're going to spend onshore and offshore. But clearly we're focusing on the gas generating assets onshore, and trying to get the best out of those that we can. And we're working diligently to reduce the amount of service costs, of course, that go into each of those investments. As John mentioned earlier, our programs in general have great economics, even at the lower prices. And those on the margin will do what we need to do to make them work for us, including not completing the wells and that type of thing. So, the split's still a little uncertain until we get Board approval. But our activities are going to be very focused on accretive NAV type of things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think, Brian, the other thing is we'll do things like drawback into the more sweeter spots, if you will, some of the better economics, and also put some pressure as Chuck mentioned on the service cost side by managing what we're doing in each area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And what type of service cut decreases are you looking for? I think you gave some return assumptions earlier in terms of needing $5 gas at current service costs. I guess, what type of service cuts are you looking for to ultimately get more aggressive and maybe move back to your original, where your original thoughts were budget-wise maybe a month or two months ago?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, this is Karl. You know, as we all do right now, we're living with 2008 service costs in a 2004 commodity price environment. And we need those two items to converge with service costs coming down with the current commodity price levels. We're actively working and negotiating, renegotiating contracts to make that happen. We expect we could see on order of 20 to 45%-type service costs for a lot of our pumping service, cementing service, and we'll get into a lot more of that next week. But the service costs usually are slow to respond. We're pretty aggressive right now to get them to respond quite a bit faster than historical.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Robert Christensen with Buckingham Research Group. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All my questions have been answered. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Robert. We love you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Joe Allman with JPMorgan. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Good morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, good. Thank you. Hey, in terms of the onshore US rig count, have you dropped it from the fourth quarter average level? And what's the plan on dropping rigs from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We dropped it pretty significantly from the fourth quarter average, Joe, for several reasons, already. The first is, as you know, there's stipulation against &#x2013; in the Rockies particularly, where those wells, or those rigs, can only work during the winter months. And as we approach the spring, we start dropping those rigs down. And through the fourth quarter, we had about 68 on average. And we're running now around 40.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You say, right now about 40?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About 40 onshore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Great. Thank you. And then a separate topic. K2 seemed to be one of the highlights in the Operations update. Could you just talk a little bit about K2, and where you're going from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's lots of good news around K2. The field performance has improved considerably over our expectations in the last year or so. And if there was any good news in Ike, I think that was some of it. We saw that the water drive, the aquifer support started to kick in. That's been a long time in coming. But with what we've seen, it will be very beneficial to our recovery, our oil recovery in the field. So with improved performance, lower oil price environment and still high service costs, the partnership has shifted its focus to a less capital-intensive artificial lift-type project. That should even further enhance our recovery and our performance, just by drawing the wells down further, and substantially lower capital investment and outstanding returns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Chuck, can you talk about the timing of &#x2013; I guess you're going to put some pumps down there &#x2013; and could you talk about the timing of that, and what kind of production rates you might see? And when you might go to get some of those reserves back?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's a little early to give you a full understanding of the project. We're working with our partners to pull all that together. And this is a deepwater project. So you could expect a little time to pass, maybe 2010 or so, before we get really good results. And then we'll &#x2013; as we pull the partnership together and get agreement on what we need to do, we will, we'll give you further details on the project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Chuck. And then just lastly on Jubilee, based on the data that you have, do you think Jubilee is closer to the 600 million barrels, or do you think it's closer to the 1.8 billion barrels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Joe, we still, we wish we could narrow the range down, but we're still drilling wells out there. And each one is targeting certain areas that can really help us. I think one that we've got going down now is going to be real important to us. But I think we're going to stick with the range right now. The thing that I keep coming back to, we drilled six wells out there, every one of them's been positive. We haven't had any negative news in the, in any of the wells, including the flow tests. So it's a very, very significant field. And we're real pleased with what we're seeing. But we just got to do more activity out there and drill more wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Okay. Thanks, Bob. Thanks, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Joe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your next question comes from the line of Tom Gardner with Simmons &amp; Company. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, I just had a question here on year-end price-related revisions. How much of that write-down was related to gas processing, ethane rejection? Was that a huge component?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Tom, this is Colglazier. As we go through there, as Jim mentioned in the conference call itself, most of the reserve revisions related to liquids. And a lot of it you saw where Algeria had some negative price revisions associated with it. Also another one out there for you, for a specific field, and that's about it. But Salt Creek and the Rockies, with the 60% drop in year-to-year pricing, some of these become challenged and they come back quite quickly at the same time. In answer to the NGL question, it's a part of it, but it's not significant. And I think that's about all we'll share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just &#x2013; you've got these mega-projects coming on. Just wanted to get an idea of proved reserve adds, when they're likely to flow through? Specifically, Jubilee, Wahoo and the EOR activity at K2? Can you give us an idea if that's a 2009, 2010 event or beyond?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the Jubilee field was sanctioning probably this year. We should see some booking taking place in Jubilee, Ghana development. With regard to Wahoo, it's a still pretty early in that one. We'll be delineating that discovery later this year and probably early next. And so that's likely 2010 and beyond event. K2, as we spoke earlier, the EOR activity at K2 is now diminished significantly, and it's most likely just an improved recovery project with artificial lifts. So those will come on as we increase the flow rates from the wells with either gas lift or ESPs [Electric Submersible Pump]?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chuck. And, Chuck, some operators are reporting drilling but delaying completion on some wells. Does Anadarko have any of that going on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we do. And we're looking at that very strongly. And in fact, we're doing some of it now. Just waiting for the service costs to get in line with our revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any particular region being affected over another in that regard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, no, it's &#x2013; we're looking at it across the board. And with our realizations in the Rockies, that would be the first place we'd look really hard at doing it. But it's going to happen across the board. It just depends on the economics of the field.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the subject of the Rockies, can you give us an update on the regulatory environment? Do you see any potential threat to Anadarko's growth story in the region with any pending regulation, if you will?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Karl. Obviously, the regulatory environment could change rapidly up there. And we see some issues that make us concerned. But right now, we're pretty comfortable we can execute our 2009 and 2010 programs as designed. As you'll hear more next week, we will be reducing our capital spending in all areas. So with that reduction and also the industry reduction in the Rockies, we think the ability to get our permits approved and continue our activity will be, we'll still be challenged but maybe not as challenged as it was before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think, both because what Karl mentioned as well as the political situation that we're in today is that I think you &#x2013; we may find again counter intuitively as I mentioned before, that natural gas becomes a preferred fuel. And I'm not sure that that permanent situation, strangely, doesn't get better over time as opposed to worse. There's at least a chance of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for that, Jim. Thanks guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of John Ragazino with Wachovia. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two quick questions on the operational side. First, can you talk a little bit about the horizontal Niobrara. I'm just wondering if you could give a little bit more color than what's alluded to in the Ops update?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We &#x2013; this is in the Wattenberg field in Colorado. We're doing &#x2013; we've now done two horizontal Niobrara tests. They've both been very successful. We're learning a lot as we go along. Both have come in at over 1 million a day. Strong looking wells, substantially better than the vertical wells, on average. Lower decline rates. And we're just continuing to work the program. Assuming that everything goes along as is currently, we hope to expand that program both this year and next. And we have a lot of opportunities. But no firm commitments yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any idea on the well costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not off the &#x2013; no. I'd rather not...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No worries. Same thing on the Eagleford. I'm just curious if you could give a little bit more color on expected IPs, well costs, that kind of thing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this is Bob. On the Eagleford in the Maverick Basin, we're in a deal with TXCO right now to where they're operating the wells. They're &#x2013; it's a drill-to-earn type of thing, and they're in the Phase II of that program. We like what we're seeing down there, but we're really early in that one. It's got a lot of work to do both on what the cost's going to ultimately get down to, and what the rates are going to be. We haven't gotten off a full frac yet on any of our horizontals that we think would be like a production stage frac. But we do see very good encouragement in gas and actually liquid rates coming out of there. And we're going to be spending more money in the Maverick to try to learn what we need to learn to see how economic it's going to be. But, so far so good down there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you very much. I appreciate it. We'll talk to you guys next week.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Rehan Rashid with FBR Capital Markets. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. On Heidelberg, could we talk a little bit more about the next steps, and maybe more importantly, implications on additional prospects nearby?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is Bob, Rehan. Heidelberg's really exciting to us in that we drilled Caesar/Tonga, and we had a targeted sand that we felt would trap up against salt. Which it did. And we think we've got a very significant discovery there. With that information and knowing the mini-basin and, that we're in, and which is the Tahiti/Tonga mini-basin, we went out and established this position in Heidelberg. And we're looking for the same Middle-Miocene sands that we have at Caesar/Tonga, trapped against a different salt-based sink line separated from the Caesar/Tonga accumulation. And encountered exactly what we'd hoped for. So I think that what it's really done, it's given us a lot more confidence for the prospectivity of that mini-basin and the adjacent mini-basins. And our ability to predict particular sands within the Middle-Miocene depositional fairways into where they should be in the trapping configuration. So I think all of this, cumulatively, gives us &#x2013; the guys are making signs here &#x2013; gives us a lot of confidence that the prospect inventory that we've built around here is very high quality. And we will be testing additional prospects in the area, probably later this year or into next year. We do want to come back and drill an appraisal well at Heidelberg, and we're trying to work that into the drilling schedule. Now, we're looking at probably second half of the year to get back and drill that appraisal well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. As you do more work on the Miocene, is your typical range still holding true, that you're thinking through, I think it was alluded to as being 100 million and change or &#x2013; barrels? Or is it growing as you understand better these mini-basins here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that our target, our minimum target size is about 100 million barrels out there. But as we learn more about it, we're able to high-grade our inventory and actually drill the things that have the better potential; either from a risk standpoint or from a size standpoint. And so, in the last couple of years we actually have seen our overall field sizes and discoveries getting bigger, and we think that's a real positive. We've had over 50% success rate over the last four years in the Gulf of Mexico. And we think that learning allows us to better high-grade which prospects we need to drill. And based &#x2013; some of that is based on the size of the ultimate trap that we're testing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then on the Heidelberg, is that going to backfill Constitution or are we thinking a stand-alone infrastructure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, at this point, Rehan, we have both alternatives to us &#x2013; available to us, and we haven't made a decision. We'll be working that. We can expand Constitution from where it is now. Or we can put a stand-alone or work with an industry partner out there as well to build a new hub type of program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Stephen Beck with Jefferies &amp; Company. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steven, are you there? Okay, Stacy, you might want to go on to the next one. Oh, you're there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I am. Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My questions have been answered. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of John Emdine with Wood Mackenzie. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey guys. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I know you touched on it a little bit, but I was wondering if you could talk a bit more about what you're seeing in deepwater drilling costs, if you've seen any downward movement in that in the past few months? And your outlook for it, I guess, in the next few?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Once again, we're seeing movement in cost. A lot of the contracts are fixed, and we live within those. But on the areas that aren't fixed, we're seeing movement. It's not as quick as we would like. And so, like we said, we're doing some things to accelerate that. We expect to see significant movement in cost with, in the current environment, in the next two to three months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we'll give a little more color about that next week on our conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I guess I've seen or I've heard numbers for spread costs thrown out there that they might come off as much as about 25%, 20 or 25%. Is that what you guys are looking at potentially in the next six months or somewhere in a different range?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess we're a little bit shy of telling you exactly what we want, because we're going to push for more than what everybody else is doing. We're going to be pretty aggressive on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I understand. And can you talk a little bit more about Shenandoah right now? And if not, can you give us an idea when we might hear a little bit more about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, John, this is Bob. On Shenandoah, we're &#x2013; at TD, we're logging, and so I would expect to hear something very soon. But right now, we're still getting all the data, and making sure what we have before we say anything publicly about it. So I'd look for that very shortly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks, guys. That's all I've got.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your next question comes from the line of Philip Dodge with Stanford Group. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thanks. Could you comment on how the new SEC definitions of reserves, at least tentative comment on how that might affect your reserves reporting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Prospectively &#x2013; excuse me, this is Al Walker &#x2013; prospectively for '09 or retrospectively for '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Both would be good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't think we've looked at it for '08, because the rules don't really allow us to. And as we look at '09...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you get at 12/31/09, how that might look?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, right now, I think we're trying to understand the implications of it as best we can. We're hopeful that the SEC will in fact go forward with it. As you probably know, that's on hold, along with a lot of other things. Assuming that the current language is used, I think it'll have impact for the booking of PUDs related to a lot of our deepwater activities. But in the past, we were a little more limited in terms of what we could do in and around the bookings of these larger fields associated with flow tests. So that's probably for us one of the bigger areas. To a lesser extent, the resource plays onshore. As you probably are aware, there you've got a little more latitude around the PUD book. And I think for Anadarko, you'll probably see us to be a little more inclined to want to go beyond just approved reserves with a disclosure. And we're still working through what that will look like. Our database is largely ready to go on that front. And my guess is we'll get that refined through the course of the year and take advantage of the broader informational disclosure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And then just as a detail, could you give us the current capacity of the Constitution facility and how much is available for tie backs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The current capacity is roughly 70,000 barrels a day of oil production, and <mark type="inaudible" /> the key constraint. And we're currently working on a production handling agreement for the Caesar/Tonga partnership that would consume essentially what's left of that, available. But then we could expand the platform going forward to additional maybe 30,000 barrels a day, which could potentially handle Heidelberg or a larger Caesar/Tonga development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ray Deacon with Pritchard Capital. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hey, Jim. I was wondering beyond these two other Marcellus wells that are drilling, what are your plans shaping up to be for 2009? And what kind of transportation agreements do you have in Blackford to be able to monetize that gas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ray, I might have Bob Daniels answer that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well let &#x2013; on the two wells that we're drilling, we announced the one. The second one I will say, we've been, we've fracked it here just recently. We're getting very preliminary results back. But it looks as good or better than the first well, and it's still unloading frac fluid. So we're real pleased with what we're seeing up there. We're going to be pretty aggressive in the Marcellus. We think that our two partnerships &#x2013; one with Chesapeake, where these two wells are, and then down to the south where we're the operator &#x2013; we'll be active in both of those areas; probably more so in the northeast area. But I think you'll see quite a few wells drilled this year, and quite a bit of news flow coming out of there. Regarding the transportation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Clay. Nothing firm on the transportation at this point. We're evaluating our options. Obviously, we'll take the lowest cost alternative that's going to get us to the best market. So we're in the evaluation stage right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Got you. Great. And maybe, Clay, maybe the same question for the Rockies, where you stand on which pipelines you guys are lining up behind over the next couple of years? And how much additional takeaway capacity are you hoping to secure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We've announced previously that we have taken space both on Ruby, which will get us from Opal into Malin, 200 million a day. And then also on Bison pipeline, it'll take us out of the Powder River Basin into the Ventura, Mid-Continent market, Chicago markets, 250 million a day there. So both of those should really help improve the basis for the overall Rockies complex and improve our netbacks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Got you. And you meant Midwest, not Mid-Continent because it's a very different realization as you know, Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I guess just curious as far as your deepwater needs, you talked about needing price concessions. Is there &#x2013; how many rigs do you see yourself looking into &#x2013; my impression was you had a lot of long-term contracts and so there wouldn't be much ability to cut your costs in '09?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me &#x2013; this is Karl again. We &#x2013; right now, we're excited about our program. As we mentioned during the call, everything we are doing in '09 we think is value accretive. We've looked at everything. We're moving some stuff around to make sure we drill in core areas. Our portfolio, both onshore and offshore is very competitive. We have new projects like the Marcellus and Haynesville and Maverick. They're competing aggressively for capital. Very excited. Our desire is to widen our margins, and make these projects even more competitive and more value accretive by getting costs down. I don't want to leave you an impression that we have to get costs down to make our projects work. As Jim mentioned, our big projects work at current cost with $30 oil. So we're working the cost side just to create more value, but not to make our projects economical.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, got it. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Doug Leggate with Howard Weil. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. That's the best attempt I've heard yet. Couple of things from me. The costs you talked about in the Rockies and the &#x2013; how you expect your IRRs to evolve over time, can you talk about where you see those right now in terms of, you talked $5 gas gets you 10% IRR. But if those costs are coming down, is it fair to assume that that's one of the last places you're going to be cutting capital given that they're relatively resilient?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Karl again. We're going to be looking at capital constraints in all areas. One of the things that we've loved about our portfolio is the flexibility it's provided. We don't want to get concentration risk in one area in particular. We'll still be active in the Rockies, but I think you'll see us increase activity in the Haynesville and Marcellus also. As mentioned, Jim said, we see $5 price still deliver better than a 10% rate of return. Chuck and his team did a real robust review recently on some of the Rockies programs. And we're using current prices, which are 4.50, and we have been still get a 10% rate of return.</p>
          <p>As we lower costs, I can't give you a good forecast of how much incremental return we get for each percent of cost savings, but it will be accretive to our program. I still expect us to be active in the Rockies. One thing that we are committed to do as an executive team is make sure that we can meet our forecast and deliver on our promises. And the Rockies is one of the best places we have to deliver latent reserves, and it's still economical. So you'll see us maintain that program and keep that engine running like we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great stuff. The only follow-up I've got is, you gave us some capital numbers for Caesar/Tonga. Can you give us some idea as to how much of an offset you're going to get in the LOE by running, taking a <mark type="inaudible" /> from Constitution?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The way we've expressed that in the past, Doug, is we've avoided almost $1 billion of cost by not having to build an additional hub, and the pass-through over Constitution, we'll do a production handling agreement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that LOE benefit is basically in the billion dollars as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great stuff. That's it for me. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jeb Armstrong with Calyon Securities. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just a question turning back to the Rockies. How would your economics look on the Rockies at $5 gas, assuming that you didn't have any basis hedges or firm transportation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think even now if &#x2013; without the firm transportation basis hedges that you're seeing the spreads come in with the lower gas price. So I still think it'd be very competitive within our portfolio, and it'll still be value accretive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think it's important to note too, Jeb, that we put those &#x2013; we subscribed to the firm transportation and put those basis hedges in for exactly this type of environment. It's not a chicken or an egg issue. Because of the projects we had, we wanted to make sure that we would protect the economics regardless. And that's why those, they were put in place initially.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's why we're subscribing to more capacity on Bison and Ruby also.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But let me make it clear on the last two questions. We still will be managing our Rockies capital spending to be prudent, not to continue to just ramp-up like we've been doing this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is a follow-up question with Rehan Rashid with FBR Capital Markets. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. On Haynesville, have you guys talked about how much acreage you have?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have about 75,000 to 80,000 net acres in the Haynesville.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All of which is basically held by production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Caesar/Tonga, the 1.3 billion CapEx, how many wells in there, or maybe just broad categorizations of the costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it encompasses four wells with completions, and then the tie back to Constitution in the upgrade &#x2013; and the Constitution facility to handle the higher pressure wells from Caesar/Tonga.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, I'd like to turn the call back over to Mr. John Colglazier for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Stacy, if I might just close it out. Thank you. This is Jim. Thank you all for joining us today. We're obviously cognizant of the challenges ahead for our industry, and continue to monitor and manage the financial conditions closely. At the same time, I think we have a lot to be excited about with some outstanding projects on the horizon and recent exploration momentum. I want to take the opportunity to remind everybody that we will have a call on February 11 about the capital and production guidance, as well as the March 10 Investor Conference here in Houston. And hope everybody has a great day, and look forward to talking to you next week. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This does conclude your presentation. You may now disconnect, and have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>