<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1226370" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>43</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John M. Colglazier, Vice President, Investor Relations and Communications</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James T. Hackett, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Thomas Gardner</participant>
      <participant id="4">James Hackett</participant>
      <participant id="5">Robert Daniels</participant>
      <participant id="6">R. A. Walker</participant>
      <participant id="7">Benjamin Dell</participant>
      <participant id="8">David Heikkinen</participant>
      <participant id="9">Doug Leggate</participant>
      <participant id="10">Robert Gwin</participant>
      <participant id="11">Charles Meloy</participant>
      <participant id="12">Brian Singer</participant>
      <participant id="13">David Tameron</participant>
      <participant id="14">Gil Yang</participant>
      <participant id="15">David Bretches</participant>
      <participant id="16">John Colglazier</participant>
      <participant id="17">Raymond Deacon</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the First Quarter 2009 Anadarko Petroleum Corporation Earnings Conference Call. My name is Akia and I'll be your operator for today. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. We will conduct a question-and-answer session towards the end of the conference. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. I would now like to turn the presentation over to your host for today's call, Mr. John Colglazier. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well thank you, Akia. Good morning everyone and I am glad you could join us today for Anadarko's first quarter 2009 conference call. Joining me on the call today are Jim Hackett, our Chairman and CEO and other executives who will be available to answer questions later in the call. As a reminder we have posted additional information in our first quarter operations report that's available on our website.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to Jim, I do need to remind you of certain aspects about the call. This presentation contains our best and most reasonable estimates and information. However, a number of factors could cause actual results to differ materially from what we discuss today. You should read our full disclosure on forward-looking statements in our presentation slides, our latest 10-K, other filings and press releases for the risk factors associated with our business. In addition, we will reference certain non-GAAP measures. So, be sure to see the reconciliations in our earnings release as well as on our website. We encourage you to read the cautionary note to U.S. investors contained in the presentation slides for the call as well.</p>
          <p>Also I am pleased to announce that Danny Hart will be returning to operations to lead one of our Gulf of Mexico asset teams and therefore he is moving out of our group. I'm sorry to see him go but sure do appreciate the hard work he put in. So, should you need any additional questions or assistance following the call, please call myself or Chris Campbell.</p>
          <p>And with that let me turn the call over to Jim Hackett.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. Good morning everyone. As you saw in the release, our employee team put together an excellent quarter, operating quarter, last quarter and we announced four significant deepwater discoveries and our sales volumes exceeded the high end of our guidance. We also maintained a focus on improving our cost structure and effectively managing our capital spending in line with our target range of four to $4.5 billion.</p>
          <p>We've significantly reduced our onshore rig count, where price realizations are weakest and continue to make improvements in drilling efficiencies throughout our major operated areas onshore. I'll discuss these items in more detail later in the call.</p>
          <p>Sales volumes for the quarter were 54 million barrels of oil equivalent, excuse me, three million barrels of oil equivalent above the high end of our guidance. We continue to see strong momentum from our programs in the Rockies, which reported sequential growth of 6% over the fourth quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Other factors contributing to the growth in sales volumes were averaging more than 900 million cubic feet per day at Independence Hub, which exceeded our internal estimates. Realizing better frac spread across the United States, which resulted in the recovery of additional NGL volumes and benefiting from the timing of a cargo lifting in Algeria. This production performance was also accompanied by significant progress on our three-mega projects.</p>
          <p>In Ghana, the partnership continues to move forward with the phase one development at Jubilee with first production anticipated in late 2010. The plan of development and unitization agreement are currently being reviewed by the Ghanaian government with approval expected in the second quarter. Major contracts have been awarded and work is proceeding on the FPSO.</p>
          <p>In Algeria, Anadarko and our partners in the El Merk project have awarded the key contracts including those for critical path purposes. The field is expected to add material volumes to Anadarko's production beginning in 2012.</p>
          <p>And in the Gulf of Mexico preparations are underway for development drilling to commence in the third quarter at the Caesar/Tonga complex, which will be tied back to our Constitution spar. This progress keeps the project on schedule to deliver first volumes in early 2011.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, our exploration program delivered strong results in the first quarter. We've announced four high impact discoveries since the beginning of the year. During the year-end earnings call in February, we told you about the Miocene discovery at Heidelberg in the Gulf of Mexico as well as the Mahogany Deep discovery at offshore Ghana. Appraisals for both wells are scheduled in the second half of 2009. These discoveries were followed closely by the lower tertiary Wilcox discovery at Shenandoah in the Gulf of Mexico, and the Tweneboa discovery in Ghana.</p>
          <p>Shenandoah encountered approximately 300 feet of net oil pay with reservoir and fluid properties more similar to Miocene reservoirs. An appraisal well is currently scheduled here in 2010.</p>
          <p>The Tweneboa discovery continues the remarkable success offshore Ghana, where Anadarko and our partners are seven for seven on exploration and/or appraisal wells. Tweneboa encountered approximately 70 feet of net pay in a large Turonian Age fan, the same age as the sands in the Jubilee field. A Tweneboa appraisal well is currently planned for the second half of 2009. The success of the exploration program reinforces our confidence in the quality of our prospect inventory and our commitment to investing in these longer-term growth opportunities.</p>
          <p>I should note that approximately 25% of our capital spending in the first quarter was directed toward the exploration component. This program continues to be active in the second quarter. We currently have three subsalt exploration tests underway in the Gulf of Mexico. The Vito prospect is a Miocene test with a projected total depth of 30,500 feet in Mississippi Canyon Block 984 in proximity to several recent industry discoveries. We operate the well with a 20% working interest.</p>
          <p>We are also drilling the Turtle Lake lower tertiary Wilcox prospect located in Green Canyon block 847. Turtle Lake is on trend with our recent Shenandoah discovery and we hold a 20% working interest in the prospect.</p>
          <p>Finally, we operate the Samurai prospect, a Miocene test that we are currently drilling in Green Canyon Block 432, where we have a 33% working interest. The well is located about nine miles from our K2 field and if successful could potentially be tied into our Marco Polo production facility.</p>
          <p>Speaking of K2 we completed drilling the Green Canyon 606 number one during the first quarter and encountered more than 110 feet of net pay confirming the southern extent of the M20 sand, which was the well's primary objective. We expect to complete and bring this well online in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, the Transocean Deepwater Millennium drillship continues to drill the Coalho prospect in the Esp&#xED;rito Santo basin. As reported to the Brazilian regulatory agency, the well encountered a hydrocarbon shows in an upper zone in the secondary post-salt target, though we still have about 2,000 feet to drill until we reach total depth in the primary pre-salt objective.</p>
          <p>Once we complete drilling operations at Coalho, we plan to move the rig to the Gouda prospect, which is also located in the Esp&#xED;rito Santo basin and has both pre-salt and post-salt objectives.</p>
          <p>During our investor conference in March, we announced our plans to drill 12 high impact deepwater wells this year each targeting gross risk reserves of at least 100 million barrels of oil equivalent. We've completed one of these wells at Tweneboa and we're currently drilling four others that I just mentioned. So, we still have an exciting 2009 calendar year ahead of us with seven additional exploration prospects in West Africa, Brazil, and Southeast Asia.</p>
          <p>Based on our discoveries today, we have increased our 2009 expected net discovered resources to approximately 350 million barrels of oil equivalent, a 50% increase from the estimate we provided in our March Investor Conference, again validating the depth and quality of our exploration portfolio.</p>
          <p>We continue to see positive results in our U.S. onshore exploration program as well. In the Marcellus shale in North Central Pennsylvania, our second horizontal well in the Chesapeake joint venture was tested and is currently flowing to sales at about 7.6 million cubic feet per day. We have two other wells that began testing at the end of the first quarter and three that are awaiting completion activities. Given the success of the Marcellus program, we're currently moving a rig to the area to begin drilling an operated horizontal well program beginning in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>In the Haynesville shale, we completed and turned to sales a short 1800 foot lateral. We've choked the well back to a restricted rate of slightly more than two million cubic feet per day and the well is still producing at about the same rate after 30 days of production. We continue to gather information to gain insight into the performance of this reservoir.</p>
          <p>In the Maverick Basin in South Texas, we had some good success in the first quarter with our third horizontal well in the Eagleford shale that tested at rates as high as six million cubic feet equivalent per day with a significant liquid component. We also completed a Pearsall shale horizontal well with test rates exceeding 10 million cubic feet per day.</p>
          <p>The E&amp;P highlights from the quarter are covered in more detail in our first quarter operations report available on our website.</p>
          <p>One of the more significant achievements of the quarter was the improvement made to our cost structure as LOE per BOE was well below guidance driven by our cost savings initiatives and higher sales volumes.</p>
          <p>We continue to make excellent progress in our efforts to improve drilling efficiencies. As an example, in Wattenberg during the first quarter, we achieved a spud-to-spud cycle time of just 66 hours. And we're continuing to improve upon that record again this quarter. Overall, in Wattenberg, we cut our spud-to-spud cycle times by more than 40% over the last year and a half. Our focus on drilling efficiencies also resulted in field records for the quarter in Carthage, Bossier, Haley and South Texas.</p>
          <p>We also continue to actively manage our capital spending through these uncertain times. This includes taking action to reduce our U.S. onshore rig fleet. During the quarter, we paid approximately $25 million in early termination fees, which shows up in the oil and gas transportation and other line in our financial statements. We've reduced our operated onshore rig fleet from an average of 58 in the fourth quarter to an average of 23 in the first quarter, a reduction of approximately 60%.</p>
          <p>For the first quarter, we reported a net loss of $0.73 per diluted share and there were items affecting comparability there broken out in the tables attached to last night's news release. In total, these items increased our net loss by $0.20 per diluted share.</p>
          <p>Turning to our balance sheet, as you know, we supplemented our liquidity position by issuing $1.1 billion of five and ten-year notes during the first quarter. The net proceeds are being used primarily for the repayment of debt maturing in September of this year. A portion of which we began repurchasing in the open market during the first quarter. We ended the first quarter with about $2.2 billion of cash and maintained full access to our undrawn $1.3 billion revolving credit facility.</p>
          <p>We are committed to our world-class exploration program and the development our mega projects. In recognition of the substantial value generated by the material future reserves and production they can provide, we'll continue to manage our portfolio and balance sheet to ensure that we have ample capital to fund these programs. Our mega projects have continued to benefit from lower supply chain costs in the current marketplace and will be starting production from late 2010 through 2012, delivering robust economics when the commodity price curve rebounds with the global economy.</p>
          <p>Our operations remain on track to deliver volumes in line with our full-year guidance and we expect to grow sales volumes 1% to 3% in 2009 while spending at least 30% less capital on projects with near term production than we did in 2008. There is no question that this is a challenging market environment for the industry. And while Anadarko's assets continue to perform very well, we too face tough headwinds on the near term natural gas outlook. We'll remain vigilant to ensure we responsibly manage through this tough period while continuing to focus on delivering meaningful value to our shareholders through the execution of our growth strategy.</p>
          <p>With that Akia, we'll open the lines up for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of Tom Gardner of Simmons &amp; Company. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Jim, some operators have been touting multi-TCF potential in the Pearsall and Eagleford shales in the Maverick Basin. I just wanted to see if this was consistent with Anadarko's view. I know it is early but could you give us a view on your economics in these emerging plays?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom I appreciate the question. I might ask Bob Daniels to give us his thoughts on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Tom, I think that clearly, the multi-TCF number from a gas in place number is there, without a doubt. I think the key question we're trying to answer is the economics out there. Our drill costs need to come down from where they are &#x2013; but we're making good progress on that. And then we need to monitor how the wells are going to perform. We've got a couple of Eagleford wells online right now. And we're bringing on the 10 million a day Pearsall well here pretty shortly and then we'll watch and see how those perform. Meanwhile, we're out there moving a rig in to drill some more wells and get some more data because we do like what we're seeing. And we recognize there is a huge resource potential there. Now, it's making it all work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Tom, I think the fact that you got gas prices where they're at kind of foreshadows why Bob is making a comment about drilling costs. I think where you're in the Eagleford with a little higher liquid content, there is obviously an advantage there today in that revenue stream.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for that. Just thinking about your onshore hedging strategy going forward, given the volatility we're seeing in the domestic markets, particularly the gas market, are you considering becoming more aggressive with respect to your hedging strategy when gas prices climb above marginal costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, this is Al Walker. I think you'll continue to see us take a cautious view of the natural gas market. I think we're going to take a pessimistic view and hope for the best. I believe that maybe better things are out there. But I wouldn't be surprised to see us continue to take some of the risk we see in natural gas price discovery off the table.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gotcha. And Jim, one last question. I want to address it to you given your involvement in the some of the organizations such as the API. Given the scope of proposals in Washington, that may affect E&amp;P, just wanted to get your view on which legislative initiatives are likely to get passed under this administration?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's clear that they want some pay fors and I think that the &#x2013; they appear to believe that there is an easy target there with regard to oil and gas companies. I think that they're running into a bit more resistance on a number of fronts than they thought they would. And of course, we thought it was a bit hypocritical to be attacking the industry you suggest that you want more domestic security from. So, we're up there fighting the good fight as everyone else hopefully in the industry is continuing to do, too.</p>
          <p>And I've always thought the one that had the most risk was really the offshore severance tax issue. But I think that's challengeable, too. And the reason why I think that has more risk is simply because it's attached to bigger oil companies than the independents. I think particularly, where you get into the independents there is &#x2013; it seems that there is a much more receptive political willingness to be flexible. But I think the Gulf of Mexico is viewed as being the territory of bigger companies as well and that's the one that we of course have had tremendous results on in the courts and I think because of that, we feel pretty good about our chances to ultimately keep most of the value that is out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks again, guys. I'll hop off.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Ben Dell from Bernstein. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Hi, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Ben.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I had really just a question around your International exploration portfolio. When you look at the Sierra Leone and your plans there in Liberia, can you give us any update if you have any desire to farm down or farm out those assets, whether that's part of the process that you're looking at?</p>
          <p>And I guess a follow-up, given the success in Ghana, would you consider taking an additional rig? I mean we've heard Devon talk about farming down some their assets and maybe letting a rig go. It seems that prices are coming off and there is an opportunity there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah Ben, its Bob Daniels. I'll start with Sierra Leone and Liberia. The potential that we see there is the same as what we saw in Ghana pre-drill. The Venus prospect that we have in Sierra Leone that we plan on drilling the second half the year is a look-alike to what Jubilee was pre-drill. So, we're very excited about the opportunity there. Now, we ended up with a fairly large interest and so we have taken the opportunity to trade some interest to really increase our position in West Africa. We're not laying it off just to lay off interest, but it's actually to spread our opportunity set.</p>
          <p>To drill those wells, we're going to take the Dolphin out of the Gulf of Mexico as soon as it's done with Samurai and it's going to come over and drill Sierra Leone. It's then going to move down into C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire and we are in &#x2013; we have just been awarded or had government approval on a block in C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire, which will spud again, same play type.</p>
          <p>And I guess what I want to say on the overall play out here is all the way from Ghana beyond our Sierra Leone blocks, we see that same type of potential, this play extends through there. The petroleum system is pervasive through that area. We see a number of these Turonian Age fans, all along the margin and we think that the blocks we've picked up are extremely well-positioned to test that concept. And we'll start that with Sierra Leone and the rig moving over there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. That's all I had. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of David Heikkinen of Tudor, Pickering, Holt. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bob, just a follow-up on that, can you give us your working interest now in the blocks in Sierra Leone, Liberia, and C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now, in Sierra Leone, we have a 50% working interest. In the Liberian, the three blocks in Liberia, we have a 40% working interest. We were just awarded Liberia Block 10 here recently. We are going to have a 100% working interest in that. And then in C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire we anticipate having about a little more than 50% interest in that block.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we anticipate &#x2013; we also anticipate getting additional blocks beyond that through some additional swaps and things that we're in negotiations on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just thinking also in West Africa, do you have any perspective on the Cosmos status or sale or anything that you can share with us would be helpful?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I really don't have anything on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, we may have something, but we're not going to tell you anyway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, kind of hopeful. And then in Mozambique, this will be my last question, does the exploratory drilling campaign that begins late '09, that is the onshore component and then you go offshore or is that the offshore component that begins late '09? Just wanted to make sure I had my notes right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The rig that I mentioned that's coming out of the Gulf it's going to go to Sierra Leone, C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire and then its going to sail around and get to Mozambique either late fourth quarter '09 or early in 2010 and we will start drilling our deepwater program at that time with the Dolphin.</p>
          <p>The onshore well needs to be drilled I think before the end of March 2010. So, we're out looking for the rig and it may spud very late fourth quarter or be in the first quarter of next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Both programs will start about the same time I guess is the short answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Doug Leggate from Howard Weil. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, everybody. Couple of things from me, first of all on your production guidance for the year, obviously Q1 is a lot stronger than your guidance but you haven't changed the full year. I'm guessing that, similar context, budget and costs coming down, you're getting a little more bang for your buck out of what you are spending. So conceptually, can you just talk about why the guidance hasn't been changed and how you're feeling about that right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll let Chuck fill in as well. But we actually, maybe in abundance of caution, as you know, we've got still production shut-in in the Gulf so the second quarter we guided down to be a little weaker because of that. And still, we have the lifting issue not repeating itself in the second quarter necessarily, but we still feel very good about the momentum we've got building. And I think, I think we feel good about our numbers and we've got to continue to watch, how commodity prices do and how our rig position sits. And I think it's too early in the year to be doing something different, frankly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Doug we do have a lot of momentum in our program. There is &#x2013; Rockies has been an outstanding result for us. We continue to see growth in all of the major fields out there with the programs that we have underway. I guess the caution we have is we haven't gone through hurricane season yet. So, we always leave ourselves a little room for hurricane season, but the momentum is good and I think we're on a glide path to hit our numbers without a lot of risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. I mean just a couple of quick follow-ups. In the Rockies, obviously, your spud-to-spud days have come down quite a bit. I guess with the liquids component in some of the fields you're operating, can you just talk a little bit about how the break-evens look right now and what are those things? I guess the contrast I'm looking for is Devon yesterday was saying that there is not a whole lot of things you can drill at current gas prices, which are NPV positive, so just kind of give us a rundown as to where things look for you guys in the Rockies right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, our focus has been &#x2013; has been where we do have the greatest liquid concentration that's in the Wattenberg field. It still has a very good economics. You may know that recently, we installed the liquids line out of the Greater Natural Buttes, which has given us a great uplift with regard to pricing net-backs to the Buttes, which has improved the economics there. They are challenged across the board as prices stay down and we've continued to lay down rigs in consideration of that.</p>
          <p>Across the board in the southern, we see the similar activity. We've been focusing on where the liquid concentration is the greatest. Carthage, Bossier and the Haynesville area continue to show reasonable economics, but they continue to be challenged if prices continue to stay low and we don't see any price decreases in our service costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The final one from me is: I don't know if you can answer this or not, but the Eagleford, some of the issues that your partner down there is facing right now, what are the &#x2013; how are things shaking out for you down there? Has there been any disruption to participation &#x2013; partner participation, funding or any of that kind of stuff? And then is it a possibility you might be able to &#x2013; or would you want to increase your position in that area? That's it from me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our partners continue to execute the program. They are in a bit of financial trouble, but have continued to execute this program. I think they view this as their star asset in their portfolio and have continued to progress the program and as Bob mentioned earlier, with the recent results, I think they have a lot of enthusiasm for this area and with both the Pearsall IPT that we saw at over 10 million a day and the results the Eagleford that have been out there that I think you'll continue to see them say this is one of their star assets and execute to their &#x2013; what their capacity is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so no prospect of you increasing your position down there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Al Walker. I think you might see us. Whether it's via any particular issues coming out of TXCO and what they do or don't do, that would be a little difficult for us to speculate on. We have a very large acreage position as it currently stands in, we think, a pretty good area, but opportunistically we could add some leases in that area in places that we currently see being equal to or better than the acreage position that we currently have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Brian Singer of Goldman Sachs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You've drilled, I think just- or completed two wells in the Marcellus but can you talk regionally within your acreage blocks what you think is prospective and how you're geographically choosing the next few locations? I guess by the end of this year's program, what percent of your acreage do you feel like you'll have a good sense regarding prospectivity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Brian. Bob Daniels again. We've got over 600,000 gross acres up &#x2013; I think it's right in the guts of the prime Marcellus play. The focus so far has been up in the northeast part of that around &#x2013; in Bradford County, primarily, and that's been driven by our partner. We have two AMIs out there. The northern one is with the partner Chesapeake and they've been very active. That's where the two wells that you mentioned have been drilled. We've got an additional two wells that have been tested and hooked up that are producing in the same sort of magnitude, so we're real pleased with that area up there.</p>
          <p>At the same time, to the south we have our operated position and we're going to be taking a rig in and starting drilling our own wells there &#x2013; our own horizontal wells, we've drilled some verticals, in the &#x2013; later second quarter or very early in the third. So we're going to be out there testing that, but given that this is an area that ranges, just for scale, from about Dallas to Houston in size is where our acreage position sits. It's going to take us some time to actually prove up all of that acreage.</p>
          <p>Now, we do think that we're going to get quite a few wells down. We may have fifteen to twenty wells down this year, horizontally, spread through the area, but it's still a very large acreage position so we've got a lot of work ahead of us and that's &#x2013; we're getting after it now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. And secondly, when you look at the strong results you and others have seen in the Marcellus, Eagleford and Pearsall, how does that impact your longer term natural gas view and maybe more specifically to Anadarko, your Rockies gas view?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Brian, we're all trying to wrestle with what are the efficiencies that we're extracting in the current environment, whether it be from horizontal drilling or better spud-to-spud cycle times and how the drop in the rig rate actually impacts onshore production and then what happens with LNG coming in and it's not a model we can easily get our hands on and that's why I think we want to make sure we stay in a good balance sheet position in the event that if it's worse than we think, but obviously, it's very weather dependent, very LNG import dependent. We have a lot of confidence that the drop in rig rates that everybody is experiencing strengthens the picture from the supply side, but, it's wonderful how responsive this industry is, but we still need the global economy to start moving the other direction to really solve this issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, this is Al Walker. I think to add just to Jim's comments briefly, from an asset footprint perspective, I think you will, over the next three to four years, see more of our activity headed in the direction of certainly the Marcellus, for the reasons that Bob highlighted. I think if that drilling through the course of this year continues on the path that we see it at today and hopefully we'll see even better in the quarters to come, don't be surprised to see us add to our capital allocation to the Marcellus.</p>
          <p>I think for Anadarko, we'll always want and have a really good both production and reserve engine in the Rockies. But being able to complement that with Marcellus, Haynesville, and prospectively, Maverick, would give us, we think, a really nice-looking asset footprint onshore and it would also allow us to be a very low-cost producer in any of those basins as we look out into any 12-month period for how we want to allocate capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And when you think about increasing capital spending in places like the Marcellus, would you think about leading to an overall increase in the budget or reducing CapEx elsewhere?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It would be a rebalancing. I'm not sure from the numbers that we are talking about this year that if we didn't see a whole lot of improvement in commodity prices next year, that we would be encouraged to take the capital plan above where we currently are spending. But you would likely see us continue a different mix as we go forward with our onshore drilling activity. That's the point I am trying to make.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not in a budget increase mode at this point. We're in a budget control mode.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Tameron of Wachovia. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good morning. Jim, just first on the CapEx comment you just made. Any chance you decrease? I mean you've laid down a lot of rigs; you're unhedged &#x2013; relatively unhedged for the back half of the year. Any chance your CapEx goes down rather than &#x2013; rather than stays flat the remainder of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's why we gave the range really and I think we're making good progress on it, but I don't &#x2013; our view was that to execute on these megaprojects and conduct our exploration program, we built up this big inventory that is so attractive that we needed to have that kind of capital available for this year. I think as we get into 2010, it becomes a little more flexible and we'll update you on that as we get closer to that period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can someone rank prospects for me? As I think about the big stuff that's drilling I mean where do you put Sierra Leone versus the Gulf of Mexico versus Tweneboa? Can you rank, as far as high profile, I guess, highest resource potential on down just some of the wells over the next nine months you'll be drilling?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Boy, that's a hard one. We don't typically try to do it that way. What we're looking at is and have said that we're going to drill 12 deepwater wells that all have more than 100 million barrel resource potential and we've got one of them down, we've got four drilling now. All of the prospects that we're going to be drilling are excellent prospects. I mean, we've built such a portfolio here that we've been able to high grade and drill the best of the best.</p>
          <p>And so to say, we like the Gulf of Mexico better than Sierra Leone or something like that just doesn't &#x2013; it doesn't really make a lot of sense to us, they're different plays. Certainly, what we see in the Gulf of Mexico and the track record we've got there, we just have a lot of confidence. We're going to continue to deliver out of the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
          <p>West Africa, we see as a huge emerging play. Based on the Jubilee success and then the follow on at Odum, Mahogany Deep, Tweneboa and then the acreage that we've been able to capture in this trend. We just see that we are going to have an awful lot of good things coming out of West Africa in the future.  And then of course we announced the Wahoo discovery last year in Brazil in the pre-salt and we see an awful lot more potential there.</p>
          <p>So, I like all of those areas. And &#x2013; end of the year, we should be drilling over in China and that's a great-looking prospect. So, I would just say our inventory is very, very deep, we high grade it, and I'd just be watching all of the wells because they all have the potential to be very significant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let me try one more thing, Bob. If besides &#x2013; I guess let me take me &#x2013; I'll go back a few years and take one of Jim's old charts. One of the spider web charts, if we were to plot that, what would be the high-risk, high reward in the upper right-hand corner?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The high risk, high rewards, yeah, I guess I'd put South China Sea in there. Mozambique is going to be in there mainly because of just lack of information out there. Our 3D that we shot last year is looking really positive. So, we really like what we're seeing, but, nobody has drilled any deepwater wells out there. So, you have got to say that that's a frontier basin, but the potential is tremendous.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. Thanks. Thanks for that color. One more question for you, Bob. The Marcellus &#x2013; at the analyst conference at that time, had you guys planned on putting a rig up there this year or is that something that's based on the recent well results you've changed your plan a little bit and decided to move a rig, or what &#x2013; has that thinking changed at all and if so, why?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think that we always planned that we were going to need to start gathering information on our operated area this year. So, the timing has probably been brought forward a little bit, and then we may be a little more aggressive in acquiring that information because of the positive things that we're seeing, but we always did have plans that, well we always said we had to be prudent about learning what the resource plays were and that was going to be our plan this year and so yes, we were planning on activity up there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. One more for Al and then I will jump off. At the conference, I think it was you, Al, you put out a maintenance CapEx target 65% at five and 50, I believe. Is that &#x2013; was that based on current service cost, was that based on future service costs, are those numbers still accurate going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that was based upon the service costs as we thought we would see them through the course of this year. Probably, not the service costs as we would see it if you were thinking about it in the 2010 context. And a lot of that had to do with the fact that as we got down to a just only a contract only rig fleet, there was a lot, a lot that had been done, could have been done, but there wasn't a lot more to do to improve day rates for the rigs that we would have running.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. So, five and 50, 65% is kind of a 2009 number, but not necessarily...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, nothing on that has changed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if anything on the completion cost and we're continuing to see improvement there, but the big ticket as you know, is more on the rig itself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Gil Yang of Citigroup. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. You've been drilling some &#x2013; just drilled a new well in K2. Can you tell us what you're learning about K2? Are you extending the downdip water contact? Have you identified the water contact? Have you extended the down dip to level of oil and what about the aerial extent of that reservoir?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Gil, it's very exciting what we've done here recently in K2. We've drilled two wells. One on the far west side of the field, which extended the contact down the field, but we also found the water contact and then as you move the most recent well would be almost due south of the original development into a new fault block, which has substantially expanded our oil in place position that is proven and known.</p>
          <p>So, we're filling up the range we indicated, the two to four billion barrels in place. And so now we have a very good picture of the entirety of the field. It's a very exciting area, we found some new sands as we went off structure, which we didn't anticipate, which has continued to grow our view of the field. We should be completing those wells later this year and get some good production performance from them. And that will give us additional information as we move forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you're thinking of just putting these wells on artificial lift now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The new wells will just be flowing to the platform with their reservoir pressure. They're going to be very strong wells. If you're referring to the EOR project, I think we have put that at these prices and cost, we've kind of put that in the background and the field itself, what we would like to do is look at some artificial lift techniques either downhole in the wells or actually in the subsea system and we are evaluating all of that right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, for the &#x2013; for the new wells you've drilled, where are those new wells that you think will flow strongly? Is right on that platform?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They'll be the two new wells, the 606 well we just discussed and the other well is on the west side of the field.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And will they have more longevity than the original K2 wells do you think, because the reservoir is different and there is more reservoir pressure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, they're just &#x2013; they're in new areas, Gil. So, they shouldn't be depleted. They should have &#x2013; they should have near original reservoir pressure. And we've also seen through time, we've seen more and more water drive support that we didn't see originally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then does that just suggest that you were pulling on the early wells too hard and or has something changed in the reservoir?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. That doesn't suggest that we were pulling them too hard. It &#x2013; the original wells, you might recall, this is a very large reservoir with a very long column, very tall column of oil, and we were producing near the top. So, as we move down the structure, and we've had the shut-in with the hurricane downtime, we've seen stronger and stronger performance from the water drive and that improves your reservoir pressure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, thanks. Second question I've got is you mentioned that frac spreads in the quarter very positive helping volume a little bit. Could you give us an idea of over the last maybe six months how the frac spreads and volumes related to each other to your account?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure, this is Clay. The frac spreads have been positive for the full year. We had expected early on that they would not be, as you remember they dropped in December near zero, but we have actually seen them hovering between $2 to $4 over the past several months and I anticipate that they'll continue throughout the year. So, it's actually been a positive surprise to us on frac spreads.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you translate that into a volume benefit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is Colglazier, Gil. When we gave guidance we thought that with the frac spreads that we were anticipating at the beginning of the year, we would, if you will, we would lose around one million, 1.5 million barrels from it. So, this is going to imply that we &#x2013; that our NGLs have increased I think we have reflected that in our guidance that it would go up about one million barrels over the year.</p>
          <p>And then bear in mind too, that when we gave initial guidance back in February, we also thought that the 30,000 barrels a day that is shut in by the third-party infrastructure offshore would be fixed by the end of the first quarter and that's now moved to the end of the second quarter. So, that's an incremental three million barrel hurdle that we're overcoming, power the momentum that Chuck was talking about earlier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And do you have better confidence that the 2Q target is going to be met than the 1Q target was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We now see that ANR, that's the Anaconda line has now started the prefabrication we had the permits that are necessary for the MMS and they'll be mobilizing here within days to begin the work on the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks that's very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your next question comes from the line of Phil Dodge of Tuohy Brothers Investment. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi everybody thanks for the comments. Just looking at the utilization of Independence Hub in the March quarter, a little above what I had expected, is that representative of what it can continue or will it come down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Phil. We did have a great month in March at the Hub. It continues to perform above our expectations. You know, we've been using about 800 million a day for the platform as our expected average run rate, giving ourselves some room for downtime and downstream upsets, etcetera. Realizing this is an incredibly large platform, all pressed, all of this gas is compressed. So, it's a very large operation, but we continue to see improvements in the way we run the field. And running over 900 million cubic feet a day on average, which is spectacular performance by our field operation. We see in the wells we have, additional capacity above and beyond the current run rate. So, we can foresee it going on for a while now and that's very encouraging to our company, it's a great backstop on our production performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, do you think it will make that in the June quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the June quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The current quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Current quarter, yes absolutely. We'll absolutely see that production performance continue through the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my other question, sort of from a different direction, how high would oil and gas prices have to recover before you would consider raising the 2009 budget?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to take this Al?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Al. You know, that's not a part of the equation that we spent much time working on, so I am afraid we just don't have a good answer for that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I hope you have that opportunity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think that, we probably would keep a little dry powder, actually, if we got a little better recovery because we think we've got real tremendous growth vehicles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess if we were to increase it at all, it would be in places where we see economics onshore being a little more robust than we currently expect them to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, where would it be specifically? You mentioned the Marcellus. Other areas or would that be the prime?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Marcellus would be probably the primary beneficiary of additional capital if we continue to see the drilling that we have today continuing. And we &#x2013; we are very optimistic about it, because it has such a good break-even cost structure and it is in a premium area for gas prices and I think followed behind that would be pretty closely our Wattenberg field. And the reason for that is that we do produce a lot of associated liquids there and in the second quarter, a pipeline that we've been waiting for to go online, White Cliff will actually start production, which will help our margins coming out of that field quite a bit, somewhere in the $6 a barrel pickup for us at the wellhead. So, those are two areas if we had a place to put additional capital, I think that's where you would see it. But for now, I think we're being fairly conservative by the way in which we're allocating capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ray Deacon of Pritchard Capital. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hey. I was wondering how many rigs do you plan to run in the Marcellus and the Eagleford Pearsall and the Haynesville for the rest of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll start in the second quarter, we'll start with one in the Marcellus and we'll ramp it up to probably three to four by year end from a company-operated perspective. And of course, Chesapeake operates the remainder of our AMI and they're in the &#x2013; they're probably in the six to seven range, Bob. Something like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Towards the end of the year, it may get up to nine or 10.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the Pearsall Eagleford area, we'll likely just have one that we'll be &#x2013; that we'll be drilling the remainder of our prospects out there and trying to size up the field. And look at its forward plan. In the Haynesville, either one or two for the remainder of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Got it. And just one follow-up on the Marcellus, what is your takeaway in the Northeast and in the other areas and do you have any plans to build out the Midstream?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ray, this is Clay Bretches. We're evaluating our takeaway options right now. There's adequate takeaway at present. But, as you know, there's a great deal of ramp up in that area. So, we're evaluating a number of alternatives, there are number of companies that are vying for our business up there, lot of projects, a lot of expansion projects. And as you know, we're right in the heart of the market center. So, we love the differentials up there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time there are no further questions. I would like to turn the presentation back over to Mr. Jim Hackett for closing remarks. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Akia and thanks to all of you on the call. And I hope you have a great day. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may now disconnect and have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>