<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1246357" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-08-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>43</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John M. Colglazier, Vice President, Investor Relations and Communications</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James T. Hackett, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Benjamin Dell</participant>
      <participant id="4">Robert Daniels</participant>
      <participant id="5">Charles Meloy</participant>
      <participant id="6">Subash Chandra</participant>
      <participant id="7">Robert Gwin</participant>
      <participant id="8">Thomas Gardner</participant>
      <participant id="9">Robert Reeves</participant>
      <participant id="10">Doug Leggate</participant>
      <participant id="11">Brian Singer</participant>
      <participant id="12">R.A. Walker</participant>
      <participant id="13">David Heikkinen</participant>
      <participant id="14">David Tameron</participant>
      <participant id="15">Joseph Allman</participant>
      <participant id="16">Robert Christian</participant>
      <participant id="17">Phil Dodge</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="corprep">&lt;Q &gt;</participant>
      <participant id="19">Phil Corbett</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Second Quarter 2009 Anadarko Petroleum Corporation Earnings Conference Call. My name is Jerry and I'll be your coordinator today. At this time all participants are in a listen-only mode. We will be facilitating a question-and-answer session towards the end of the conference. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder this conference is being recorded for replay purposes. I would now like to turn the presentation over to Mr. John Colglazier, Vice President of Investor Relations. Sir, you may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jerry. Good morning everyone and thanks for joining us today for Anadarko's Second Quarter 2009 Conference Call. Joining me on the call today, are Jim Hackett, our Chairman and CEO, and other executives who will be available to answer your questions later in the call. As we do each quarter, we have posted additional information in our Operations Report that is available on our website.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to Jim, I will remind you that this presentation contains our best and most reasonable estimates and information. However, a number of factors could cause actual results to differ materially from what we discuss. You should read our full disclosure on forward-looking statements in our presentation slides, our latest 10-K, other filings and press releases for the risk factors associated with our business.</p>
          <p>In addition, we will reference certain non-GAAP measures. So be sure to see the reconciliations in our earnings release and on our website. We encourage you to read the cautionary note to U.S. investors contained in the presentation slides for the call.</p>
          <p>And with that, let me turn the call over to Jim Hackett.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. Good morning everyone. As you saw we reported a great second quarter demonstrating the strength of our operations and Anadarko's differentiating exploration. Among other successes for the quarter, we set a record for sales volumes, significantly reduced our lease operating expenses, prudently managed our capital spending, announced a new Deepwater Gulf of Mexico discovery in June and another one last week, and we strengthened our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Total sales volumes for the quarter came in at 56 million barrels of oil equivalent. This is 4 million barrels of oil equivalent above the midpoint of the guidance we provided last quarter and a 4% increase over the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Contributing to this record performance were higher volumes in the Rockies, a run rate of approximately 890 gross cubic feet per day at Independence Hub and higher NGL recoveries partly due to the new cryogenic unit at the Chipeta plant in Utah.</p>
          <p>When we announced our first quarter results in May, we mentioned our focus on driving down costs to better align them with the current commodity price environment, and we've made a lot of progress in that front as highlighted in last night's news release. We significantly improved lease-operating expense to $4.26 per BOE, almost a full dollar below the low end of our prior guidance. This achievement represents a 12% per BOE sequential improvement over the first quarter of this year and an 18% improvement over the second quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>In addition to the LOE per BOE gains during the quarter, Anadarko also achieved record drilling efficiencies across our asset areas. In the Southern region drilling records were achieved in 27% of the wells drilled during the quarter. And in the Rockies region the Wattenberg field accomplished a 50% reduction in cycle times allowing us to run fewer rigs and still drill 32 more wells in the first half of 2009 versus the first six months of 2008. This is a testament to the innovation and dedication of our operating organization, which made excellent strides improving the cost structure of our company.</p>
          <p>With these efficiencies, we've been able to reallocate our capital such that approximately 25% of total capital expenditures are now dedicated to building upon the success of our worldwide exploration program.</p>
          <p>Last week we announced the Vito discovery in Mississippi Canyon block 984, which encountered more than 250 net feet of oil pay in Miocene-age sands. We target prospects with greater than 100 million barrels of oil equivalent of resources, and we are very excited about these initial results on Vito and look forward to working with our partners to determine the timing of an appraisal well. We operate the Vito well with a 20% working interest.</p>
          <p>In June, we also announced the discovery at the Samurai prospect located in Green Canyon block 432 about 12 miles north of our Marco Polo platform. The Samurai well encountered more than a 120 net feet of oil pay in several sands, and we expect an appraisal well to be drilled within the next year. We operate Samurai with a 33% working interest.</p>
          <p>The drill ship that we use to drill the Samurai discovery, Developer Dolphin, is now on location in West Africa to drill the Venus prospect off the coast of Sierra Leone. The Venus well is one of more than 30 identified prospects and leads on our West Africa acreage position, targeting stratigraphic traps in the Cretaceous trend. It has geological and seismic characteristics similar to our giant Jubilee Field offshore Ghana. Another of these Cretaceous sand play prospects is South Grand Lahou offshore C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire, which we expect to drill after Venus is TD'd.</p>
          <p>From C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire, we then plan to mobilize the rig to Mozambique to commence that drilling program later this year. Since our last update in May, we have significantly expanded our acreage position throughout the Cretaceous trend offshore West Africa.</p>
          <p>Anadarko now holds interest in almost 8 million acres across 10 blocks including the recent farm in offshore C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire. We will operate seven of the blocks and the vast majority of the prospects currently identified within this emerging play. Our average working interest across the play is approximately 40%.</p>
          <p>In Ghana, we expect to continue an active program with appraisal wells planned at Tweneboa, Mahogany-4 and Mahogany Deep. The Mahogany-4 well will test the eastern extent of the Jubilee Complex. And the Mahogany Deep and Tweneboa appraisal wells will further evaluate discoveries announced earlier this year.</p>
          <p>We anticipate following these wells with additional exploration tests at Teak, Owo and Onyina, all three located offshore Ghana. In addition to these identified opportunities offshore West Africa, we remain active with our pre-salt drilling program offshore Brazil.</p>
          <p>On the BMC-30 block, where we previously announced the pre-salt Lahou discovery, this quarter we plan to conduct drillstem tests in an exploration appraisal well at Lahou-2 testing multiple objectives. The well is located about five miles north of the original discovery well, and we operate the block with a 30% working interest.</p>
          <p>We also plan to participate in drilling the Itaipu prospect on BMC-32, where we hold a 33% working interest. Itaipu directly offsets Petrobras' large Jubarte development. It has been reported to hold about 2 billion barrels of oil equivalent in the pre-salt.</p>
          <p>Onshore in the United States, we continue to manage capital carefully, while re-allocating some funding toward an expanded Marcellus shale program. We are increasingly encouraged about the potential of this play from our results to-date. We drilled our first operated horizontal well, participated as a non-operating partner in six other horizontal tests, and held interest in three completions during the quarter. We'll continue to prudently ramp up activity and anticipate having three to four operated rigs and eight to 10 non-operated rigs running in the play by the end of 2009.</p>
          <p>The early success from our Marcellus activities indicates this play possesses some of the most compelling economics in our onshore portfolio. We are seeing initial production rates of between four and 8 million cubic feet per day and estimated ultimate recoveries of between three and 6 BCF per well. Also appointing a 10% pre-tax rate of return achievable at NYMEX prices as low as $2.50 per million BTUs.</p>
          <p>In the Rockies, as mentioned earlier, we completed construction of the second train at the Chipeta plant in Utah. This cryogenic unit has increased gross NGL recoveries from 2,500 barrels per day to approximately 12,000 barrels per day. In our Wattenberg field, work is completed on the White Cliffs oil pipeline to Cushing, Oklahoma, where we are delivering 10,000 barrels per day from this new access to markets for our Wattenberg Liquids. As a result, we anticipate better price realizations of at least $8 per barrel as well additional cost saving and operational efficiencies.</p>
          <p>Changing gears, we continue to advance our three mega project developments. In Ghana we conducted a successful drillstem test on the Mahogany discovery well, and it tested approximately 21,000 barrels of oil and 25 million cubic feet of associated gas per day, with results suggesting good reservoir connectivity.</p>
          <p>In July, the Ghanaian government approved the Jubilee Phase One plan of development and unitization agreement, and the project remains on track with its accelerated Phase One development schedule anticipated to deliver first oil in late 2010.</p>
          <p>In the Deepwater Gulf of Mexico, platform modifications began in the second quarter on our Constitution spur as work continues on the Caesar/Tonga development. Preparations are underway to drill two development wells in the area during the third quarter, and we expect the project to remain on schedule to deliver first volumes in early 2011.</p>
          <p>At El Merk in Algeria, construction and contract work is moving along very well, and we expect to achieve first oil in late 2011. There is additional information on our second quarter activities and our operations report available on our website. These highlights demonstrate that we've built a portfolio with a robust inventory of opportunities that is capable of delivering significant value to our stakeholders.</p>
          <p>We believe that executing upon our exploration program and the mega project developments through the current market environment will add significant value to our company. With that objective in mind, we raised $1.3 billion of equity in May and the fact that our stock traded inside of the dilution factor demonstrated that it was well received and that our stakeholders understand it was the right thing to do to build future value.</p>
          <p>We also took additional steps during the quarter to enhance our financial flexibility and liquidity. In early June, we issued $900 million of senior notes consisting of five, 10 and 30 year tranches. Pricing on these securities was very attractive relative to where our bonds were trading in the secondary market at the time. And we used the proceeds of the offerings to retire the remaining $968 million of 2009 debt maturities. At quarter-end, we had $3.5 billion of cash on hand, and no scheduled debt maturities until 2011.</p>
          <p>We continue to manage our cost of capital and beginning late last year we entered into a series of forward starting treasury swaps for planned 2011 and 2012 debt refinancings. We established these swaps when treasury yields fell to unprecedented lows late last year</p>
          <p>The subsequent expected increase in rates enabled us to monetize cash gains of approximately $550 million this quarter. It was through a process of resetting the rates on the positions, while maintaining protection from material increases in treasury rates prior to the 2011, '12 refinancings.</p>
          <p>For the summer months of June, July, and August, we expanded our commodity hedge firm to include additional fixed price natural gas swaps at an average price of $4.18, which when combined with our existing three-way costless collars for 2009, provides us with price protection on approximately 80% of our anticipated natural gas volumes over this time period. These swaps have been in the money thus far. We also substantially increased our 2010 derivative positions for both natural gas and crude oil using costless three-way collars.</p>
          <p>For natural gas, we have protected more than 75% of our anticipated 2010 volumes with a middle floor of about $5.60 and an upper ceiling of about $8.25. For crude oil we've protected about 50% of our anticipated volumes in 2010, with a middle floor of about $62 and a ceiling of approximately $84. Our current derivative position including basis swaps and firm transportation is attached to last night's earnings new release.</p>
          <p>For the quarter, we reported a net loss of $0.47 per diluted share with items affecting comparability that are broken out in the tables attached to last night's news release. In total, these items reduced our net loss by $0.09 per diluted share.</p>
          <p>Discretionary cash flow from continuing operations totaled approximately $1.55 billion benefiting from the cash generated by the previously mentioned treasury rate swap resets and the ability to use our 2009 net operating losses as a carry-back to prior periods.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, we are increasing the midpoint of our sales volume guidance for the full year by 2.5 million barrels of oil equivalent. As we have done in the past, we are providing a risk operating profile for Q3 and Q4 that accounts for scheduled maintenance and potential hurricane-related downtime. For example, we expect Independence Hub to be running at reduced rates throughout the remainder of this quarter, as we plan to perform some scheduled maintenance on the allocation separators.</p>
          <p>The performance of the company and its people are the basis for much excitement today. The portfolio we've created is truly generating the value we always believed that it could, even in a challenging financial and commodity environment. We expect sales volumes to be at least 3% higher than 2008, and we expect to spend to about 30% less on our near-term projects in 2009 relative to the previous year. Our employees are maintaining a tight focus on controlling costs and improving efficiencies, as you can see from the strong operating results that include record production, significantly reduced costs, six announced deepwater discoveries and a strong, deep inventory of world-class exploration and appraisal activities to test this year and beyond.</p>
          <p>Whether it's offshore Sierra Leone, C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire, Ghana, Brazil, Mozambique, South East Asia, the Gulf of Mexico, or onshore in the U.S., we have substantial option value and superior upside to grow our company.</p>
          <p>At this time, we are joined by the executive team and we look forward to taking your questions. So Jerry if you could open up the lines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And your first question comes from the line of Ben Dell with Bernstein. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ben.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess my first question, really I wanted to focus on Sierra Leone and Liberia. On the Venus well, what's your, do you have a rough estimate of the pre-drill that you are using and for the expected reserves? And I guess my follow-up question to that is what are the biggest risk factors on the well? Is it source, sale or reservoir?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Ben, this is Bob Daniels. I guess the best way to put the Venus prospect is, it's the same order of magnitude scale of what Jubilee was when we did the pre-drill on it. Aerially the reservoir thickness that we anticipate over there, the trap configuration, it's all the same. So it's that same order of magnitude of a target. Our biggest risk over there is probably going to be timing of hydrocarbon generation and migration into it. We know we've got the source rock up there. It's just going to be when did it generate and what phase did it generate and did it migrate effectively into this fan complex that we have identified.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great and my second question was really around the cost base. Obviously with U.S service players and drillers basically generating no earnings, how much additional downside do you believe there is to day rates and service staff as you put pressure on the suppliers right now, or are they &#x2013; they pushing back that they are already earning very little?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben this is Chuck, Ben. What we have seen is a substantial reduction in the cost base that we have had. It's region or area-specific, basin-specific, and my sense is that there is still some additional room to go in certain areas, but we are getting down to where the competitive nature of the basins are determining prices that we will achieve. And my suspicion is we may get another, 0 to 10% of reduction in certain areas, but other areas, particularly like the Gulf of Mexico Deepwater, continue to show some strength.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from line of Subash Chandra with Jefferies. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi good morning. Two quick ones here, on the Eagle Ford, any comment on, I guess almost a half a dozen wells that have been drilled, how many of them have been producing, length of time and how the wells might have held up? And second, on the cash balances on hand, pretty enormous. What plans are with that and if there are further things you might do to sell down interest and raise more cash by year-end?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Subash I'll go ahead and start with the Eagle Ford. I guess the way to put a frame around the Eagle Ford right now is that we are very encouraged about it, but it's real early. We've got the six wells that you mentioned. We have seen rates as high as 6 million equivalent out of some of those horizontals. From the Eagle Ford, we also have a pierce hole zone that we're testing out there.</p>
          <p>We've been up to 10 million a day, but what we are seeing is that some of the infrastructure is not adequate to really get good long-term data on these things, like the pierce hole well is way choked back because of the gathering system out there. So we are having to build that out, so that we can get the information we need. So, I guess to-date right now, it's encouraging, but we've got a ways to go to really know exactly what we've got.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the cash balances, this is Bob Gwin, I think in this kind of an environment, in this kind commodity price environment with these uncertainties, certainly more cash is better than less. We have a fair number of commitments on the mega projects and with the exploration portfolio in the upcoming months.</p>
          <p>In addition, I guess on the much smaller size, if we saw something on bolt-on basis in a certain field to enhance our economics or our opportunities to build shareholder value, we'd look for it. Although we love our portfolio the way it is, and so those things will be kind of opportunistic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And any further plans to raise cash between here and year-end on asset disposals or working interest sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no interest now. I think that's one of the reasons you saw the equity issuance was because that certainly precluded our need to look at things such as that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'm sorry, one final one. If you had to estimate sort of what that next year or 18 months offshore program CapEx might look like, what is the rough development number to work with?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are &#x2013; on the development side, we are using about 130 to $150 million a quarter for the &#x2013; and I think you are asking for the deepwater portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You are correct yeah. Okay, terrific. Thank you very much</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Tom Gardner with Simmons &amp; Company. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator. Hey Bob, following up on Ben's question, based on your comments on the risk to Venus, would it be accurate to assume that a success at Venus would partially derisk the C105 block off of C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think a success anywhere along here is going to help with the 30 leads and prospects we have got identified. Of course Jubilee derisked a lot of it. That proved up the petroleum system, that proved up the reservoir, the quality and the depositional systems that we have been identifying up and down this margin. So, we are kind of at the other end of what we see as the play at Sierra Leone, and any encouragement there is going to really derisk and help out everything in between. So it's not going to kill anything, but we are going to be learning a lot from this well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's good news. Jumping over to the Gulf of Mexico, can you discuss the Vito and Samurai and the likelihood that either will be a tieback versus a standalone and what's the valuation uplift, if you will, of one versus the other, in a general sense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is Bob again. On the Samurai, we are just 12 miles away from our Marco Polo platform there. We've got capacity and we have always planned on that being a tieback into that almost regardless of how big it was, just because of the capacity that we have. On the Vito well, that one's could be very significant in size, but we do have partners there that have infrastructure around us at Mars and Ersa.</p>
          <p>Shell has capacity and so we'll just have to kind of see how big that is, relative to what they have in the way of capacity on those and distance, costs, do the economics on it. But there does seem to be some capacity around that if we wanted to explore that. Of course we will be appraising both of those probably early next year, first quarterish, for both of them is what we're looking at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. One last question, can you give us an update on the Algerian tax arbitration? And how would you handle that from an accounting treatment assuming the arbitration goes your way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is Bobby Reeves. The arbitration is proceeding. It's not going to be a quick process. We are plodding down the path, and it could be 18 months to two years before we see any kind of decision from an arbitration panel. I'll defer the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and as far as the accounting treatment goes, Tom, until you actually reach resolution, we'll continue on with our current accounting treatment, which is where we record the excess profit tax in our other production tax line, and bear in mind, on the residual effect as you drop that down, that is not deductible for federal tax purposes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next comes from the line of Doug Leggate with Howard Weil. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning guys. A couple of things from me. There has been a lot of moving parts, I guess on your working interest in West Africa. Can you just kind of bring up to date as to what working interest you would expect to drill some of the wells over the next &#x2013; the next few months, and a related question, my understanding is that you might be trying to at least pursue an increased position in the south deepwater tunnel block with Ikeer. Can you maybe comment on that if indeed there is anything going on there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start first with the positions that we have now. Of course you know the positions in Ghana with the two blocks there. In Sierra Leone, the Venus flow, we are going to end up at about 40% working interest. We had partners in there originally and then we brought additional partners in through swaps to get into additional acreage. South Grand Lahou we will probably end up with about 50% in that well.</p>
          <p>The additional C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire block, that's going to be &#x2013; is it 40% &#x2013; ultimately, that we are going to end up with, and then block 10 in Liberia, we have a 100% presently; we'll probably layoff some of that. The other three Liberian blocks we are bringing some smaller interest partners in as part of the swaps to expand our position. So really we're expanding, not just laying off interest, and we'll end up with the an average 40% working interest across the entire play, when you look at it, and, but what we've ended up with is 8 million acres right through the guts of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, any comments on the sort of Deepwater Tano block?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess the main thing I would say is that that was a bid round. We did bid on that block in the bid round, and Ikeer was awarded it and we have not had additional conservations with them about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks for that. The only follow-up I have is jumping back to the Lower 48 and the Eagle Ford, it seems there has been some comments from one of your partners this morning about changes to operatorship. Can you just maybe bring us up to date as to what your plans are? I know that you guys are kind of running the show. And whether or not we'd expect you to accelerate activity down in that region.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think there is going to be any change to our plan. We did pick up an operated rig here a few months ago, I guess. We didn't have to do that, but we saw enough encouragement; we wanted to start that process, and we will probably have a couple rigs running out there to continue to evaluate the Eagle Ford and also to test the Purcell as we go on so, I don't think there is a change. What we wanted to do was have the partnership earn the acreage, spend their money to test it. And meanwhile we saw enough encouragement we wanted to start learning ourselves so we put a rig out there a little early.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great. If I could risk one final one if I may, I'd just jump into the Marcellus. You talked about, in your prepared remarks, Jim, about accelerating your activity levels towards the end of the year. What kind of rights of way do you have right now in terms of, what where you can take your volumes without running into any kind of infrastructure problems?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, this is Jeff, we have a portion of our position out there in the AMI, with private companies. You have Shell involving in production and we have access to those right of ways in the Eastern portion of our position in AMI with Chesapeake. And we are obtaining that from primarily the state and mostly along previously designated right of ways that and that means power lines or gas lines. It's a process that we are going through. In the early stages of development and exploration, what we've done is take advantage of those, put our locations as near infrastructure as possible, so we can access  connections to interstate interconnects, pipelines, etcetera as well as right-of-ways for systems and roads.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I appreciate the comments. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Brian Singer with Goldman Sachs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>With regards to U.S. natural gas, if we strip out the impacts of pipeline maintenance and potential future hurricane disruptions, where do you see your gas production heading, considering your current reduced activity in the Rockies offset by strong results you're seeing out of the Marcellus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I'll address the first part of your question which is &#x2013; the impact we are having in the Gulf of Mexico with the hub we do have maintenance and that type of thing going on in the Gulf of Mexico that will affect our third quarter.</p>
          <p>Following the third quarter we should see continued growth of our production profile; the Rockies assets are performing extremely well, and almost to the asset, particularly given how capital efficient they've become due to our rig program, they will continue to see growth in Wattenberg, Greater Natural Buttes, Powder River Basin, Wamsutter, Pineville, Jonah, We think we will continue to see growth there and then if you add the Marcellus into the portfolio as we anticipate it coming in, we'll see substantial growth in Marcellus production, so overall I would anticipate that it's up for the foreseeable future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful, and actually some of your comments layered into my follow-up, which is when you think about the Rockies portfolio specifically, can you talk about at current gas prices, but also at current low service costs, where are you seeing well economics in places like the PRB and Natural Buttes, and how we should think about your reduced activity. Is that the result of low returns at current gas prices or is a result of more having better opportunities within your global portfolio to spend capital?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's actually some of both. Each of our major assets in the Rockies, we have focused on the core areas. They have extremely good economics down to very low oil prices and they are aided to a large degree, if you take for instance in Wattenberg and in Greater Natural Buttes, with either the oil order liquids private, we see pretty considerable uplifts to our lease backs, or our net backs at the lease. So, we've had, the economics are very good in the core and that's where we reduced, we've concentrated our reduced drilling fleet in those core areas in each of those assets. In addition, it's competing now with our Marcellus position and Haynesville position as well as the international activities that we've had, so we have taken our capital, we've tried to be as efficient as we possibly can with it. And taken advantage of the best &#x2013; the best opportunities we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, for you to increase your rig count then, would you have to see substantially higher gas prices? Or I guess, given the equity financing and all, where do your priorities lie when you think about if you've got an extra $100 million to spend? Does that definitively get spent in Deepwater versus the Marcellus versus the Rockies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, this is Al Walker. I think what you would probably see is we would favor short cycle investment opportunities where we think we have got really rates of return. Today that would be both Marcellus and Wattenberg onshore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of David Heikkinen with Tudor Pickering Holt. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just wanted to speak to a couple of things on the appraisal side at, in Ghana and then also Gulf of Mexico; talked about Heidelberg appraisal, I just wanted to refresh on the Gulf of Mexico side, at Heidelberg, when will you go back out and drill appraisal wells there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, right now, we have got it on the schedule for a September spud. But there may be a little bit of sliding on that based on the rig, but we want to get back on that, and we would like to get it finished by the end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and they you'd hit both Vito and Samurai is first quarter 2010. Anything else in the Gulf of Mexico that fits into the appraisal or delineation side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, ultimately we need to get over to Shenandoah; we're waiting on from new data coming in there. Of course, I mentioned Vito, but we do want to get back over there very quickly, actually, because we did see a lot of potential on that prospect. We have got a lot of updip room and we think that one could be significant to us. So, those will be early, Samurai will be next year and then the Shenandoah will probably be later in the year as we get the data in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then on Vito, 20% interest. No, I mean you made the discovery, so no way to really increase your interest now in that updip side or just kind of expect to stick at 20%, is a reasonable expectation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would think, I mean which with Shell and Statoil, we've got what we've got.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and then on the Ghana side, appraisal drilling there, just kind of get my mind around rig activities that's for exploration versus appraisal and development drilling at Jubilee.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next three Ghana wells that we have got, that are going to be apprising, would be Tweneboa-2, where we want to see what that really can be, because we've got the updip edge of it on the first well so that could be a real key well for us. Mahogany-4 which is going to take us out to the East, and then the Mahogany Deep, which we also think could have some fairly significant resources there but needs to be appraised. So those would be the next three, then we've got the additional exploratory wells, as Jim mentioned, that will be in 2010. We've just got an awful a lot of activity still to come there in Ghana.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And at Tweneboa-2 really got updip, have a relatively small size. I mean what step of upside could you identify kind of on a, as you derisk the prospect with that well? I mean what's the range of outcomes for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, this is Al Walker, I think the best way to answer that would be Tullow operates that block and is fairly communicative in terms of their views, and I think they see something upwards approaching 1 billion barrels as potential for the discovery.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And they've talked 50 million barrels on the low side, so it's just a wide range in between that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've only drilled one well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so those are completely separate on a resource standpoint and how you think about Jubilee and Tweneboa, or I guess Mahogany and Tweneboa in the overall development. So, this well could be a larger appraisal as I think about the three that Bob just went through?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, fair enough. Okay, that was it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And you next question comes from the line of David Tameron with Wachovia. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, only a few left. But can we talk about CapEx? If you look at your full-year target that you guys threw out there, you're trending under that. Any outlook on what CapEx looks like for the full year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, this is Al Walker. Currently, our spending activities where we operate, we have a pretty good sense for. I think the two areas, both Marcellus and the Gulf of Mexico, are non-op. The activity there is a little more variable, and as a result it's not particularly easy for us to pinpoint that, because we just don't know what the activity level is going to be non-op in both of those places.</p>
          <p>The major projects, we continue to see the funding that we have talked about in the past, and I think you can continue to expect that our spending level in the Marcellus will be pretty significant as we've talked about today and in previous discussions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and then Al, if you look at compared to a year ago, your CapEx, we will call it efficiency today versus then. How's that shaping up and any regions in particular jumping out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, I think Jim made some comments to that in his prepared remarks. I think the cycle time that we are seeing in the Rockies has been probably the most impressive at Wattenberg, but that's not to take away from some of the stuff in we call it in our Southern region, where we are continuing to see record cycle drilling opportunities develop.</p>
          <p>And I continue to believe that the efficiency around our spend is going to be, we've still got some more to come there. I think a lot of the things that we hope to do in the Marcellus is borrowed from what we have learned in the Rockies with pad drilling and planning for development ahead of actually drilling the well, so as get into the Marcellus as an operator, those efficiencies that we've learned in the Rockies, we have worked pretty hard to kind of transfer that to this new play.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Okay thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And your next question comes from the line of Joe Allman with JPMorgan. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning Joe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's the timetable on a decision at the Venus prospect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The timetable on the decision?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're on the well now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, I understand, so how long is it going to take to get to TD and come out with a decision on that one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say probably 45 days to get down the boring problems, to get down, get logged, see what we have. They are not long wells out here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great and then, separate topic. Independence Hub. What's the key going forward over the next couple of years to keeping Independence Hub full?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Chuck. What we have going on is, there is a number of workovers and additional wells we'll be drilling in and around the hub on existing fields, for example, we are going to drill a new Merganser  side track. We have a Cheyenne to east well we'll drilling; we have just worked our way into a Calisto development; and we'll start &#x2013; we'll be starting all that as we move into the fall. And so through that activity, we should be able to continue to push the hub at or near plateau for another six to eight to twelve months and then see what else we can come up with to add on the back of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful and then, and Chuck, what's the production capacity now? I mean, like is the production capacity well above the 900 Bcf a day or do you think the wells are pretty much running flat out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know the hub has been running right about 900 million a day; that is where it feels good. We've had good run times and that type of thing; we push it much harder than that, we start running into run time issues, and before now we have had quite a bit of excess capacity, that's why we have been able to extend this plateau for almost two years now. And it's been online for over two years. We see that for a little while longer, and then we'll need some additional activity like we talked about and they are all set up to start in the fall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right, very helpful, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Robert Christiansen with Buckingham Research Group. Please proceed</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, what is your cost basis in the Marcellus Shale acreage? And how did you go about leasing it and when?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob Daniels now, I'll start into that. The average cost basis today for the acreage position we have is $300 an acre.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and just to get into where we started with, it was about 2005 was when we actually started the leasing out in the Marcellus. We had seen what had happened in the Barnett, and we had a team that was looking for where is the next potential shale play. We also were looking for additional shale plays, and we think there is a whole bunch of additional potential on this acreage out in the Appalachians, so that is how we ended up getting into the position originally, and then just continued building it.</p>
          <p>The other thing I would say is the $300 an acre, phenomenally low acreage price, we also got very good terms. We got five year leases, five year kickers, good royalties on them because we were in there early.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from the line of Philip Dodge with Tuohy Brothers Investments. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning, thanks. On your comment about the maintenance at Independence Hub this quarter? What is the guidance on the throughput for the quarter, can you provide us with that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we have actually given guidance specific for the hub. What we see is about a million barrels that will be lost this quarter associated with the hub maintainence quarter over quarter, and we also have...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How does that compare with the 900 normal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the 900 normal, that's gross; the million barrels is net. We also have in our guidance this quarter about three to 4 million barrels of hurricane-related downtime. And we don't know, we never know how that's going to work out; last year of course with Ike, we took almost an 8 million barrel hit, and the year before, we took very little. It's hard to know but we have given what we anticipate is sort of an average, average hurricane impact as part of our guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then the other thing I had on the relatively good economics of Wattenberg, are you going to increase rig activity there as a result?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we intend to do is increase our fracking activity, not just the rig activity we have going on, but doing recompletions as well as refracs. So we have the same effect as getting new wells but with a lot lower cost and more capital efficient.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Sunil Jatwani with Catapult. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good morning. Now that the plan has been approved by the government of Ghana, the plan of development, what's the timeline for potentially hearing about future phases in Ghana?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we anticipate is first production in fourth quarter 2010. And we would &#x2013; we hope to rebuild it fairly quickly. So we'll be getting reservoir data all along during that ramp up period. We'll digest that, that information and then make a decision as to whether it needs a second phase or how we would incorporate a second phase, whether it's expansion of existing facilities or a second FPSO potentially or another production hub of some sort. So it will take a little time to get the reservoir performance necessary to make that decision, but we certainly want to see how this reservoir responds to water injection production gas injection, etcetera, before we will make that call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18">
        <plist>
          <p>So you are saying that there is a chance that you may actually not have a second phase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we'll certainly have a second phase, but what we do for it, we'll certainly see a second drilling phase, and then the thing we'll be trying to decide and determine as well as design is what production facility performance we would have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see, and then just a quick follow-up, there has been some talk about potential farm outs from Tullow in Cote d'Ivoire. Is that potentially of interest to Anadarko?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well one of the blocks that we are talking about, CI 103, was a Tullow  block, which we took a position in in exchange for a position in Sierra Leone and Liberia with Tullow. So again that was diversifying the positions out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Phil Corbett with RBS. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning guys. I've got a couple of questions. So I'll just go through them one by one. Just picking up on the last question, should I take that Tullow have farmed into the Venus prospect. So are you guys confirming that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Second just on Liberia, have you actually sort of come up with any drill-ready prospects there? I'm just trying to get a feeling if there was a good results in on Venus, how would that impact your plans to drill in Liberia maybe next year or the year after?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say we are very close to having drill-ready prospects although from an operational standpoint, we have to spud. It is a new country and making sure we had everything done there. But we shot the 3D earlier this year, very large 3D; we've got fast-track volume in house. We've got leads from the 2D and the early look at the 3D; we have got over 30 leads across the entire area, a bunch of those are in Liberia.</p>
          <p>And so the three blocks up by Sierra Leone, the &#x2013; the 3D's shot, the fast-track's in-house, and we are working that and so we do anticipate firming up numerous prospects in that acreage. So, if we have any encouragement here at Sierra Leone, we will have plenty of opportunities and places to go next year in Liberia. Block 10, we just were awarded that, and we will be shooting 3D on Block 10 next year, so that would be a little bit farther behind, but the Venus well is not going to condemn this entire area no matter what.</p>
          <p>It's a huge area and so, it's one well, we are going to have to learn what we can from it. Hopefully it's successful and if not, learn what we can and decide what that means for the rest of the prospects out there and which one would be the next ones to drill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Just moving across Ghana, it was my understanding that the Owo and Onyina prospects, particularly, I guess, Onyina in the aftermath of the Tweneboa results, maybe wasn't as attractive as it was prior to the Tweneboa results with the lack of hydrocarbons and with the Campanian in Tweneboa. So, are you still saying that they are viable interesting prospects to you guys?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, they are still viable prospects. So, Odum is a Campanian success on the Mahogany Deep Block. The Tweneboa Campanian section was wet, very nice sand section, but wet. We think we understand why that is; we do think the Campanian has a more tortuous plumbing system, I guess, to get to it so you've really got to do some work to do your risking right. The Turonian is much cleaner. So we like the Turonian better than the Campanian but we are not writing off the Campanian in this whole play.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And finally just on Latin America, Tullow have been sort of quite vocal that some of the Latin American acreage, particularly in French Guiana, may contain the kind of sort of cretaceous stratographic traps that you've been targeting in West Africa. Is that a part of the world that you are going to be looking at if you want to expand your exposure to that cretaceous play.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've looked at it actually, and I mean we can see some similarities, but we saw &#x2013; see some significant differences. So, I'm not saying anything negative about Tullow's acreage, but it's an interesting concept, but things are not identical across the two &#x2013; across the Atlantic Ocean, I guess now, but yeah, different provenance, different source areas, and so, you really have to do your homework. It is not a direct lay down analogy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's right. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And this concludes the question and answer portion of your conference. I would now like to turn the conference over to Mr. Jim Hackett for closing remarks. Sir, you may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>I just want to thank everybody for their good questions and also want to thank our employees for a great quarter. We'll look forward to speaking to all of you at the end of the third quarter. We've got a lot in front of us. Hope you have a great day. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we appreciate your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may now disconnect and have a wonderful day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>