<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1127378" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-02-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>43</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John Colglazier, Vice President, Investor Relations and Communications</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James T. Hackett, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Thomas Gardner</participant>
      <participant id="4">Karl Kurz</participant>
      <participant id="5">Charles Meloy</participant>
      <participant id="6">James Hackett</participant>
      <participant id="7">Brian Singer</participant>
      <participant id="8">Robert Daniels</participant>
      <participant id="9">David Tameron</participant>
      <participant id="10">R. A. Walker</participant>
      <participant id="11">Gil Yang</participant>
      <participant id="12">Robert Christensen</participant>
      <participant id="13">John Colglazier</participant>
      <participant id="14">Joseph Allman</participant>
      <participant id="15">Joe Allman</participant>
      <participant id="16">David Heikkinen</participant>
      <participant id="17">Philip Dodge</participant>
      <participant id="18">Ross Payne</participant>
      <participant id="19">Clay Bretches</participant>
      <participant id="20">Rehan Rashid</participant>
      <participant id="21">Shannon Nome</participant>
      <participant id="22">Raymond Deacon</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the Fourth Quarter 2007 Anadarko Petroleum Corporation's Earnings Conference Call. My name in Eric, I will be your coordinator for today. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> I would now like to turn your presentation over to your host for today's call that is Mr. John Colglazier. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thanks, Eric. Good morning and thank you for joining us today for our fourth quarter and year-end 2007 earnings conference call. Joining me on the call today are Jim Hackett, our Chairman and CEO, and other executives who will be available to answer your questions later in the call. Consistent with previous reporting periods, we have included a lot of information in our operations report, which is posted on our website.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to Jim, I need to remind you of certain aspects in our forward-looking statement. This presentation contains our best and most reasonable estimates and information. However, a number of factors could cause actual results to differ materially. You should read our full disclosure on forward-looking statements in our presentation slides, our latest 10-K, other filings and press releases for the risk factors associated with our business. In addition, we'll reference a non-GAAP cash flow measure, so be sure to see the reconciliation in our earnings release. We also encourage you to read the cautionary note to U.S. Investors contained in the presentation slides for the call.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn the call over to Jim Hackett.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John and good morning, everyone. We delivered as you see a strong fourth quarter in a remarkable 2007. Today I want to highlight some of our more notable achievements and take a quick look at what to expect in 2008.</p>
          <p>We made a number of commitments to our stakeholders after the acquisitions of Kerr-McGee and Western Gas Resources and through solid and timely execution; we fulfilled and in many cases exceeded those commitments. I want to personally thank our employees who have worked so hard to build value for all of us by executing Anadarko strategic plan.</p>
          <p>Among our accomplishments since the acquisitions; first we've transformed our portfolio and reduced the leverage. If you recall we initially anticipated we would need to issue between 5 and $7.5 billion of equity in conjunction with the divestitures of approximately 7.5 to $10 billion of assets over 18 to 24 month period. However, asset monetization program exceeded expectations and within 18 months we generated nearly $15 billion to reach our year-end 2007 long-term net debt target resulting in the issuance of zero equity. We now have a high graded asset base geared toward more consistent and predictable production growth and less capital intensity.</p>
          <p>And we'll continue to reduce leverage in 2008 from free cash flow and other normal course activities. Second, we increased production guidance from our retained properties on three separate occasions during 2007. And we exceeded our most recent guidance by producing 13 million barrels of oil equivalent or 7% above the midpoint of our original full year projection on our retained properties. Third, we improved our cost structure throughout the year, and I will discuss this in more detail later in the call.</p>
          <p>During 2007, we also completed a conversion of our accounting method from full cost to successful efforts. This was a monumental task never previously undertaken by a company of our size, but we believe we will enhance our decision-making ability and was clearly worth the effort.</p>
          <p>Turning our attention to fourth quarter operations. As I mentioned, we exceeded the high-end of the revised production guidance by 1 million barrels of oil equivalent. The reported volumes of 53 million barrels of oil equivalent represented a 13% sequential increase over the third quarter.</p>
          <p>This out performance was primarily driven by Independence Hub and other offshore properties. Independence Hub was a significant milestone in the year with startup occurring on time and on budget. Further, we delivered on an aggressive ramp up schedule to reach our targeted peak production rate of 1 billion cubic feet per day. Although our current run rate is in the range of 850 to 900 million cubic feet per day, we continue to advise you at an 80% run time factor adjusted for our working interest at 60% and reduced by the applicable one-eighth royalties to estimate our net volumes at Independence Hub.</p>
          <p>We also achieved record production from several of our onshore fields during the fourth quarter. Our Greater Natural Buttes area achieved a high daily gross operated production of approximately 245 million cubic feet per day. Also in the Greater Natural Buttes area we bought the Chapita processing plant online in the fourth quarter adding 250 million cubic feet a day of processing capacity to the area, which will help us to further increase our record production volumes in 2008. We also achieved new gross production records at our coalbed methane properties in Wyoming's Powder River Basin of approximately 250 million cubic feet a day in late December.</p>
          <p>In addition, we have already added 200 million cubic feet a day of gathering capacity to the Basin with the completion of the first phase of the Fort Union Gathering System expansion and we anticipate doubling the original line 650 million cubic feet a day of capacity by mid-year 2008.</p>
          <p>Turning to our exploration program, they remain a key skill set in an important component of our portfolio. We announced the substantial fourth quarter discovery in the deepwater Gulf of Mexico at West Tonga. The well encountered more then 350 feet of net oil pay and three high-quality sub salt Miocene sands. We have begun unitization discussions with the Caesar and Tonga partners in our evaluating potential development program, where the discovery would be a subsea tieback to our 100% owned Constitution spar approximately eight miles to the West.</p>
          <p>We are currently drilling the Green Bay prospects, which was spud in December and is targeting the lower Tertiary with an anticipated total depth of 30,500 feet. We operate the well with a 25% working interest. We expect to spud the Sturgis North prospect this month in which we own a 25% working interest and which offsets the earlier Sturgis discovery.</p>
          <p>Internationally we had notable successes in 2007 with two large deepwater discoveries offshore Ghana at the Mahogany-1 and Shedua wells. We estimate the area has unbooked recoverable resources in the range of 200 million to more than 1 billion barrels of oil equivalent. To follow-up on the success, we're currently drilling the Odum number one exploration in the West Cape Three Points Block with a total depth of 10,500 feet. Offshore Brazil we're currently drilling our first Subsalt test at the Serpa prospect on Block 24 in the Espirito Santo Basin. This well has a targeted total depth of 19,500 feet with a 30% working interest.</p>
          <p>Those are some of our operational highlights and as John said there is more detail available in the operations report that is posted on our website. As we laid out in our earnings release, adjusting for certain items affecting comparability, we had an excellent quarter underpinned by solid production performance and improved crude oil price differentials.</p>
          <p>Earlier I mentioned our improving cost structure and I want to highlight one area in particular. Oil and gas operating expense was $4.40 per BOE in the quarter, which represents almost a 20% reduction from the third quarter and was well below our current guidance. This resulted from increased volumes with minimal incremental cost in fewer work over activities during the quarter.</p>
          <p>We look at exploration expense in two categories. The first, which consists of dry hole expense and impairment of unproved properties, totaled $178 million for the quarter. The dry hole expense of $99 million was primarily associated with the Atlas Deep and Terrebonne prospects. The second category consists of G&amp;G exploration overhead and delay rentals and totaled approximately $113 million.</p>
          <p>As a company we met or exceeded most of our internal targets such as production volumes, reserve additions and share price performance relative to our peers. Accordingly our employees were rewarded through our formula driven bonus plan. Other than this performance-based compensation, our G&amp;A costs were inline with guidance and vastly improved relative to 2006.</p>
          <p>As mentioned in our earnings release excluding the effects of divestitures, we added approximately 250 million barrels of oil equivalent of proved reserves during 2007, most of which are associated with low risk infill drilling opportunities onshore and a Peregrino development in Brazil. We ended the year with an estimated 2.43 billion barrels of oil equivalent of proved reserves, approximately 67% of which are proved developed.</p>
          <p>One detail to note on the categories on our reserve tables was that the guidance from the SEC has changed. Only new field discoveries or field boundary extensions will be classified as discoveries or extensions. Reserve adds representing new infill drilling opportunities will now be classified as revisions. Therefore, our reserve bookings in our large onshore resource play such as Greater Natural Buttes, Wattenberg and Pinedale/Jonah have been treated as positive revisions where as they would have been classified as extensions, discoveries and other additions in prior years.</p>
          <p>While we did have some favorable price revisions excluding price provisions, we more than replaced production as we earlier committed to investors. We reported production of 212 million barrels of oil equivalent for the year, which includes about 15 million barrels of production associated with divested properties. Our costs incurred in exploration and development for the year were a little more than $3.8 billion. In addition to our earnings release, we also published details of our 2008 capital program in a separate news release.</p>
          <p>We anticipate the 2008 capital expenditures including the expense exploration will be in the range of 4.5 to $4.7 billion. At our budgeted prices, which are significantly below strip pricing and equity analyst consensus estimates. We believe this is the appropriate expenditure level for Anadarko to continue monetizing the more than 7 billion barrels of net risked captured resources that we currently have in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>However, we will evaluate raising budgeted CapEx levels in order to increase our exploration and appraisal programs if commodity prices remain strong. The budgeted capital program reflects our commitment to increase activity in the Rockies to expand deepwater exploration and to continue the expansion of our midstream infrastructure.</p>
          <p>During 2008, we have guided to a production range of between 205 million barrels of oil equivalent and 210 million barrels of oil equivalent, an increase over the midpoint of the prior guidance that we issued in November. We also expect to add at least 225 million barrels of oil equivalent of proved reserves during the year and we currently anticipate E&amp;P costs incurred to be in the range of 4 to $4.2 billion.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned the capital program also includes an expansion of our deepwater exploration program in 2008. In the Gulf of Mexico we plan to drill between 6 and 8 prospects this year. Those include Green Bay and Sturgess, which I mentioned earlier in the call. We also have additional opportunities at the Heidelberg and Lyell prospects, which are located in the Miocene Fairway where we've had success with the Caesar Tonga and West Tonga discoveries.</p>
          <p>To follow-up on our success offshore Ghana and in addition to the current Odum well, the partners have contracted for rigs, who enable us to drill up to an additional 5 to 7 wells this year. Offshore Brazil in addition to the current Serpa prospect we'll be drilling four more super-salt and sub-salt test in the Campos and Esp&#xED;rito Santo basins. And we have one deepwater well planned in the South China Sea on Block 43/11 adjacent to the large Husky gas discovery.</p>
          <p>As part of our risk management strategy and similar to 2008, we see some potential volatility in 2009. The 2008 gas hedging position appears in our earnings release and gives us significant protection. To further protect ourselves against short-term downdrafts in U.S. gas markets, we have hedged approximately 500 million cubic feet a day for 2009. Using NYMEX costless 3-way collars with the floor of $7.50 per decatherm with an upside of up to $11 per decatherm.</p>
          <p>In addition, because of the potential impact Rockies Express could have in the Mid-Continent Texas Gas markets we've increased our basis hedges for those areas as well for 2008 and 2009. Again there is more detailed information attached to the earnings release. We are pleased with the results and achievements of 2007 and look forward to a strong 2008. We are also excited for the opportunity to share the Anadarko story at our upcoming Investor Conference in New York on March 25 and we'll provide additional details on our company's E&amp;P and Midstream operations at the conference. With that Eric, let's open it up for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of Tom Gardner with Simmons and Company. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jim, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a question about REX; you had a lot of success in the Rockies, your gas production now approaching a Bcf a day. How has Rockies Express moving into operation impacted your Rockies production and how will it impact it going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Tom this is Karl Kurz and Chuck Meloy is sitting here as he may join in this too, obviously with REX coming on line we've seen system pressures drop across the board in the Rockies. We've seen some very strong performance from our coal bed methane assets in the area. We're hitting record levels of production up to 700 million cubic feet a day in that. And so, we expect that continue to deload the area, obviously with the CBM, the water is the big issue, getting the water off the reservoirs, and as additional capacities are available, we will be to dewater and we expect to see continued strong performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Now I understand, weather has been a factor with some &#x2013; with respect to making additional well connections. In short, if you didn't have weather to deal or backup of system pressure, what would you be making in the Rockies? What does that look like?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, I ask that question to Chuck about every other day, and it's a hard one to answer, because, we're in the &#x2013; you're dealing with the coalbed methane, which is a desorption process. So it's a matter how quick we can get the water off, and we can tell you that the Big George reservoirs continues to perform better than we expected. So, we are not going to give any predictions on what we think it will do, but we're optimistic that the Big George will still surprise us going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Jumping down to Carthage, I understand you have that first horizontal, probably have some production data there. Has that performed according to expectations and do you anticipate dedicating a rig full time to the horizontal development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am going to let Chuck talk about what's going on in Carthage, that's an exciting story for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have actually completed two horizontal wells in Carthage, both of which are performing at or above our expectations, we are now drilling our third well and with the data that we have we fully intend to run a complete rig line during 2008 in horizontal drilling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me add on the Carthage, a little bit to the G&amp;G side, we have done some work G&amp;G wise that we think gives us a way to identify some good fairways to place those horizontal wells in. So, we're excited about our ability to target good locations for horizontal wells in the Carthage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. I will let someone else hop in. I do have some other questions; maybe I will follow up with John later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Brian Singer with Goldman Sachs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Following up on the previous question looking at CBM, with the Fort Union expansion now complete, do you see any constraints given that REX is on as well to showing consistent growth from CBM and can you put any numbers to where you see your net CBM production at year-end?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, we now are in the process of dewatering the field again as we come back out of the cold spell and the shutdown of the Cheyenne Plains and what we see is a constant steady growth throughout the course of the year, as we get these wells dewatered. We haven't put out guidance with respect to actual expectations of increases, but we see it having throughout the course, feel very confident in how the wells have performed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it will be fair to say we have the CBM budgeted for increasing like Chuck said throughout the entire year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Can you put any color on the declines you're seeing from some of the wells that you've had on for some period of time now from the Big George?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chuck, you might, on some of the wells &#x2013; I mean, we are seeing some declines, but the way it works over there Brian, you create a big pressure sink and really seeing not a lot of wells have heavy decline yet, we're still seeing some good increases in wells. I mean, I'll add on I expect to see double-digit production growth from the CBM for 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our most matured property out there is the County Line &#x2013; County Line unit, which is still increasing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Switching to the Gulf of Mexico, a couple of unsuccessful wells in addition to the successful West Tongo well. What do the combination of the couple dry holes and the successes tell you about high grading or about the Miocene program in general?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Bob Daniels, Brian. We had a real successful well there at Tonga West and we're pleased with that, the Terrebonne and Atlas well &#x2013; excuse me &#x2013; were unsuccessful although we are going to take that information and tie it back into our interpretations and see where it leads us. Overall we've got a program out there and we are targeting the Miocene in the proven fairway. We think that if you look back at our track record there we've had just a tremendous run of success. And we don't think the two dry holes after the successful well will deter us at all, it's more what do we learn from them how do we roll back into our understanding and where is the next well that we are going to drill that we'll pursue what we have learned from those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great and are you still contemplating potentially selling an interest in some of your lower Tertiary success?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have got a fantastic lower Tertiary position out there, both acreage position and prospects and we are constantly looking at what is the best way to monetize that; clearly the lower Tertiary has advanced, but it's advancing slowly and we would like to see more value created out of that portfolio. So, we are looking at all sorts of different ways of doing that. We will be drilling three lower Tertiary tests this year and we will continue to evaluate what that means for us as a company going forward and what that position can yield in a way of value to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, I might add; you have seen us in the deepwater Gulf of Mexico on our assets, the way we manage our portfolio is trying to maintain a 20 to 40% type working interest position. And I would expect us to maintain that philosophy going into lower Teritary too. So, in assets where we have a high working interest, you will see us sell down, trade, work some deals for other opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Tameron with Wachovia. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Question, looking at 2008 CapEx, it looks like I think the number you threw out was 30 to 35% dedicated to Rockies. What percentage of cash flow comes from the Rockies, if you look at your '08 budget operating cash flow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David this Al Walker. As you can imagine we don't give that type of field level data or regional data on a cash flow basis, but we do believe that we have good free cash flow coming out of the Rockies in general relative to the CapEx plan there as well as overall for the year. If you will get with us in March at our Investor Conference, at that time we'd probably give you a little more of the field level data you're looking for, but at this time until we file the K, we're really not in a position to talk about it in the detail you're looking for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Jim, can you clarify what you said about the reserve booking, you said infill drilling is now going to be classified by the SEC in the revisions category is that, is that the jist of it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is correct, and it is a change that you would not have seen us do last year or earlier years, and I might have Al expand upon why we came to that conclusion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, David we felt like from the comment letter process one of our peers went through the SEC. The SEC was pretty clear in saying that infill wells and proven reservoirs are not extensions or exploration wells and therefore using the comment letter process that they went through and the way the SEC chooses then to have the rest of us understand how to apply that we thought it was pretty black and white on this issue. And so it's not so much an interpretation on o,ur part as it is the way the SEC is asking us to be able to demonstrate in our data the fact that in field wells and proven reservoirs are not extensions and exploration wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And David we felt strongly enough about making ourselves clear on this that we went back to our consulting engineers and asked them to go through their full staff and find out if there was any exception to that issue and their view was is that &#x2013; that the interpretation they have given us about revisions is right on for what they view across the firm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah and then the only thing I would add further is that it just we feel like we more than replace our production in a process by which the reserves that we booked for the year more than exceeded the production for the year and for us that's the takeaway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks and then one final question Jim. On looking back now year and a half later <mark type="inaudible" /> Kerr-McGee and Western Gas, is there, what asset surprised you the most as far as on the upside or downside? If you don't want me to give me a downside so I'll go with the upside?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well I think, there is several, but certainly the CBM has worked out to be a homerun for us, and in general the assets that Western held were when you look at some of the monetization work we have done, and what we are planning to do with our midstream business, I think you'd have to say that had a pretty, is going to have a pretty quick payback.</p>
          <p>The thing we like about the Kerr-McGee assets in addition to a lot of operational diversity is the long dated nature of what we're doing in areas like Greater Natural Buttes and the development potential we have in some of the other areas we were lucky enough to keep and acquire. I think both of those transactions have turned out in retrospect to even be better than any of us had imagined at the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, I would like to put a plug-in for the Wattenberg asset because with higher than expected oil prices and the fact that that field generates 25 to 30% of its hydrocarbon from the liquid basis has really made the economics of Wattenberg much more attractive than we ever thought they would be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right; thanks and congrats on a nice quarter and a good year-end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line Gil Yang with Citi. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. A couple of questions, do you comment on why the tax rate was so high and why the guidance is high going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah Gil for the quarter, Algeria since the EPT portion that we record in production taxes is not deductible and Algeria therefore is not a deductible in the states. Our tax rate will above the statutory rate as long as that's in effect. Even taken that into account though the fourth quarter was a little bit higher than we'd anticipated and really that was really some true-ups as you go through the year and you're working on your state and trying to get everything cleaned up we did have some incremental taxes come through on the quarter which happened to raise that the tax rate. Looking into 2008, Gil; that is solely attributable to the Algerian EPT.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, the effect would be that the higher oil prices are the higher your taxes rates will be. Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that is correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Second question Jim is that, you've made fair comment that your LOE was down because of the higher volumes with little incremental fixed costs. What is the source of the guidance upward then sequentially going from fourth quarter into 2008 in that LOE?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a good question; I will let Chuck do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gil, what we saw through the course of 2007 was continuous improvement almost quarter-over-quarter. I give a lot of credit to our field teams and engineering teams that helped this improvement happen. We were able to pull a lot of synergy through the combination of the three companies into our field operations, which gave us a great benefit that we didn't anticipate during the course of the acquisitions. Looking into 2008, there is really three or four drivers that we see going forward.</p>
          <p>The first is, as we mentioned early with regard to CBM, financially expanding our operations out there, increasing the number of units under dewatering. And so we see a considerable increase in our water production out there, which has an associated electrical cost associated with it. So, that's one source.</p>
          <p>The second thing we have is some statutory maintenance requirements that are one-time events in both Algeria and in the Gulf of Mexico that we have coming in 2008 that won't be an ongoing operation. And then finally just across the board as we focus on our base production we are seeing more and more work overs in 2008 compared to the fourth quarter of 2007. So, the combination of those three will add incremental cost to our OpEx, all of which are substantial investments in our future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's very helpful Chuck. Can you comment on the maintenance for Algeria and Gulf of Mexico? Are they going to be lumpy or fairly evenly distributed through the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's going to be &#x2013; it's going to be mostly in the first half, but it's &#x2013; it's going to occur throughout the year essentially in Algeria we have our major central producing facilities are going through their 10-year tune up and so we will have that going, ongoing starting late in the first quarter and lasting for two or three months. And then in the offshore we are doing just general maintenance on our major platforms that have been out there for a while.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Will there be an accompanying downtime, because of those maintenance operations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's already cooked into our guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Chuck, maybe this is a question &#x2013; last question for you is can you give us an idea of what you expect from the three well program at Marco Polo what's going on with that reservoir and what's your evaluation of what the productivity of that reservoir is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what we did last year was we went back on to the platform drilled several infill wells, made completions that gave us a lot of optimism with regard to the future performance of the field. And so, what we will see in 2008 is essentially a continuation of that program. I know, we haven't released expectations with regard to the production, but the work we did last year was very profitable and we anticipate a continuation of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that just driven by the fact that the oil prices are high and so that you can target the compartments more economically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That certainly helps, but we have great looking opportunities as we learned and produced the field, we've learned a considerable amount from the field production, and pressures and that type of thing and &#x2013; we have lot of optimism with regard to its future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line Robert Christensen with Buckingham Research. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Can you please give us an update on your deepwater drilling rig contracts &#x2013; number of rigs, time remaining in &#x2013; whether they are still in the money?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We're trying to figure out who the best person to answer that is for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Daniels probably.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well actually we're using the combination of Daniels and Meloy because there is...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have number contracts with regard to deepwater rigs; I don't think we have the time to go through individual contracts on this call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Bob this is Colglazier, I will go ahead and get a schedule put up and we'll put it on the website just showing the nine rigs that we have under contract and their expiry dates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob, at a high level, we feel like the rigs are still going to be heavily utilized, there is strong demand you can see that the utilization rate of deepwater, <mark type="inaudible" /> versus rigs and drill ships, are they &#x2013; many of the rigs are substantially in the money and you have seen us extend some contracts and basically let some new contracts, so we expect to maintain our rig position going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yesterday, I read a story that of Algeria that they are soliciting foreign oil companies for participation in exploration bids &#x2013; kind of amazed by that given their windfall profits tax surprised what 18 months ago. What's your take on that and would you participate in another round?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we were aware that a next portion big round that they have planned and they are asking for prequalification for that. Of course the physical terms are going to be quite onerous compared to previous bid ramp in Algeria and it will be interesting to see what sort of competition there is for those blocks. We haven't seen actually even what the blocks are, so really it's very early in the process. We are just aware that they are going through it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Joe Allman with JPMorgan. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you good morning everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning Joe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you talk about the cost environment especially for drilling and completing wells and also talk about what kind of field level efficiencies you guys are seeing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll hit real quick on the cost environment obviously we see that deepwater cost markets are still increasing. Competition for rigs and services, we are talking about this morning we are seeing onshore probably a little bit of softening, but there are areas that it's kind of like real estate location, location, location there is some areas that we see high demand for services and costs are quite competitive for us right now. I think we have indicated we expect about a 5% increase in cost on the service sector for 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can you talk about any offsets related to the field level efficiencies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We &#x2013; we've got a program going on, Chuck why don't you talk about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well what we have seen, as we have put these companies together we've had levels in opportunities such as Cardinal Drill <mark type="inaudible" /> where we had two different &#x2013; two companies operate in the same field, we've been able to plan those. We've seen a lot of synergy offshore particularly with logistics and air services between the legacy Anadarko and Kerr Mc-Gee properties. So, we have been able to substantially offset the increases as been evidenced by our production &#x2013; our operating performance in 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay that's helpful, and then back to that issue of the positive reserve revision. Could you &#x2013; could you talk, I mean, that was a pretty big number 724 Bcfe. Could you tell about &#x2013; how much of that was related to the re categorization issue? And then how much was other stuff &#x2013; price and performance and what not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we talked about we are not going to talk about the breakout of price performance but I'll reemphasis what Jim said in his comments early that even in excluding price revisions we more than replace production for 2007 the majority of that revision is due to infill wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gotcha. And how much could you give us an estimate of how much would your production replacement have been higher if you didn't sell Genghis Khan and Knotty Head, and Big Foot. Can you just ballpark there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a good question. Daniels keeps reminding me how much he would of added this year if we had kept those, but we haven't gone back and reviewed those Joe to see exactly how much reserves would have booked, that would have been, we acquired a full sanctioning program and accessing much more detail then we currently have been.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In addition, Joe we are not really sure we have good clarity as to exactly how the drilling that has occurred, excuse me, since we've sold that has proven up additional reserves or not. So, it really would be kind of difficult for us to assess exactly what those additional barrels would have looked like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think it's fair to say that this year, we had not expected to have significant adds from the exploration side because we have delayed a lot of our drilling and we didn't have those wells coming in and the reserves from those discoveries coming into the &#x2013; the picture for 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Joe I appreciate you bringing that up, because obviously with those in our picture if they'd been included it would have been even more robust than we currently have delivered.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, gotcha. And then in terms of, like drilling in the Gulf of Mexico if are there any constraints I mean, are rigs a bit constrained in terms of drilling more wells there because it sounds like you're diversifying your international program. I think Jim, I think you said you're going to drill a North Sea well right near that big Husky discovery and you're obviously active in China and so, what are the constraints to drill more wells in the deepwater Gulf?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We &#x2013; we still see tightness in the rig market and mobilizing rigs to certain areas is still a critical planning issue for the industry. I think you referred to the Husky thing, it's in South China Sea right and then as you say I mean we are going to be active down in Brazil, and that is we are moving rigs in different places, which is with the magic of higher oil and gas prices has caused in our businesses as we don't have these regional rig markets anymore it's &#x2013; it's a much different dynamic and it therefore the control of those rigs is still a very valuable asset in our mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay guys. Okay, so &#x2013; so that is okay. So, that is a South China Sea well, not. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I got you. Okay and then lastly is, in one of your releases you talked about, acceleration of the big resource base being a big focus in 2008. Is that anything &#x2013; is that any different than what you experienced in 2007 or prior?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean it's all about converting the resource right now. And being very capital efficient in how we do it. So, as you have seen in 2007, we are going to maintain high-level capital efficiency and continue to aggressively convert that resource base into proved developed reserves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And what you see in exploration as an attempt to, as long as we can exceed our cost to capital on those projects is to still put even more on the books over time to give us even longer dated growth as well as, additional opportunities that we think we can try to convert in a variety of different ways as Bob mentioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gotcha. All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've seen a lot of value in this industry placed on discoveries and appraisals without ever bringing them into production and we like part of that aspect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gotcha. All right very helpful, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Heikkinen with Tudor Pickering. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I had one bigger picture question and when I listen to the call and the questions versus your peers, most peers have some shale gas exposure trying to get into new plays, hear a lot about Appalachian, Fayetteville, Woodford Barnett, West Texas. Do you guys feel like you missed that or are you trying to get into any new plays and would it be a surprise in '08 to say, you have started to get into shale gas resources?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob Daniels is shaler than you think, so I'll let him answer that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is Bob Daniels. We've got an onshore exploration program that we think is very robust actually. We spent last year kind of focusing down on where we think we can have the best success; we are playing some tight gas, we are playing shale gas and we are playing some fractured reservoirs, which &#x2013; we do have established positions in the Black Warrior Basin, the Maverick Basin and a very nice position in the Appalachian Basin.</p>
          <p>We are planning on drilling wells in the Appalachian Basin this year to test the shale play out there and we are very optimistic about what we are seeing from the industry activity and particularly where our acreage sets relative to that industry activity and our understanding of the shale play. So we, while we are not in the Barnett, we have been very actively pursuing and trying to understand the shale gas plays and where we may be able to get into those on a ground floor basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Where is your Appalachian acreage? Just the state even would be helpful?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Pennsylvania.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Pennsylvania, north &#x2013; south?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pennsylvania. We have got 275,000 acres in Pennsylvania and some of it's in very, very nice contiguous blocks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That &#x2013; okay, that's helpful. Second question going to K2 and kind of K2 areas what's the feed moving forward this year? Would it be soon enough to have a sanction for going forward with an enhanced solo project there or do you think that sanctioning would be more likely next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, the feed is moving forward well. We are still evaluating the two primary options, which are water injection down there for nitric injection a bit and integrated projects teams forms is moving along nicely. My expectations for sanction would be next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then the down dip well that you're drilling, testing the field extent to 30,000 feet, are you expecting to try to find the water at with that well or what's the overall good, bad or other evaluation once that's wells is at DD?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well that's in one particular fault block it's the 562 number one well &#x2013; 561 number two well. It's a down dip test. We are attempting to extend the oil column even further than we previously had and then we will move to an adjacent <mark type="inaudible" /> again it is a down dip well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Both of which are field expansion platforms.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful. The reserve potential at Serpa, just a range?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At Serpa, I think we're looking at the 100 to 250 million barrel target size.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And typically when we go into these deepwater plays, we started in the Gulf of Mexico, everything needs to be bigger than the 100 million barrel target and we've taken that internationally. Of course we have to look at the fiscal regimes to make sure that all works, but there is significant targets we are looking for there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then coming up, Gulf of Mexico lease sales continue to be pretty hot this year, would it be unusual to see similar bidding to what you guys had last year, again this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From our standpoint, I think that's a...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, would you be leasing more? Or do you think you'd farm in more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll be active in the lease sales like we always are, we don't really comment on how aggressive we're going to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah ok.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly, the industry has been aggressive and we're going to have to take that into account.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we've done Dave, as you know, is &#x2013; as you say &#x2013; we've participated both in lease as well as there is a, there is a dance that's played out after resales where people partner and we participate in as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Philip Dodge, with Stanford Group. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thank you. Two international questions, first offshore gone up, how much would you expect to narrow the possible reserve range, 200 to 1.1 billion, with this well you're currently drilling?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well this is Bob Daniels again Philip. With this well we are not going to narrow it down a whole lot because this is really a satellite to the existing discovery at Jubilee with Mahogany and Shadea. So we are going to test another concept in this one that with the additional drilling this year that we already got lined up, we think that we will be able to narrow that down quite significantly. The next well we'll drill directly after the <mark type="inaudible" /> well will be an appraisal well in the Jubilee discovery area, so we'll start that process now. We'll bring in another rig back in to drill additional appraisal wells and we think by the end of the year we are going to have very good handle on but what that range really is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay and then just curious how much reserves you booked at  Peregrino?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Al. At the field level you probably can appreciate we don't talk about what we booked but we have booked barrels in the year there and we intend to book more in '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think it's fair to say that we're going to be very paced in that regard. We have &#x2013; we will make sure that the investment dollars are going along with that and I personally wouldn't be terribly concerned about what we did there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. What would your pace allow you to report the whole thing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All &#x2013; all the reserves that we project, <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It takes several years--</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Several years--</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Around production start up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That would probably appropriate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes at 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.Yes sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and than just a final question, can you give us a &#x2013; update on the timing of the MLP offering?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is Al. As you probably fully appreciate we're in the quiet period right now with the SEC, so we sort of limited with our commentary around it. We are very committed to the MLP and believe that we will price that security issuance some time during the course of the year. Market conditions currently are such that we're watching and monitoring that to see when an optical time for us to launch the IPO would occur. And really beyond that I am afraid today we just can't say much more than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, does the SEC have all the information that's requested or you are still gathering.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No the SEC has all the information that they need and I think we couldn't use any process with the SEC as a hesitation rather I think it's more market conditions being favorable for a successful IPO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ross Payne with Wachovia Capital Markets. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First question on independent sub, obviously you hit one Bcf, its come in a little bit lower that &#x2013; lower than that on average. Where do you see it kind of being for '08? Second of all what's the average life of those wells and do you have any plans to add additional wells to those &#x2013; those projects?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well as you know, we did hit a one bc up a day type of rate; we exceeded our expectations there at the capacity of the facility. On the facility, we have talked over and over about using around an 80% runtime as a good expectation for average run rates due to the length of the flow lines and just the general facility operation. We expected to stay at the peak around 800 million a day on average for 18 to 24 months and but in doing that we're also adding additional wells, for instance right now, we are on our second Cheyenne well and we are drilling it as we speak.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Are there other plans for additionals, throughout the next two, three years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have several wells lined up to be drilled through the course of the next two or three years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And second question is on leverage. Do we &#x2013; do you have any targets for debt-to-EBITDA or debt-to-BOE anything like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think unlike last year, when we're going through the restoration of the balance sheet and we sort of guided the market to expectations. I think as we go forward we will continue, as Jim mentioned to want to reduce debt, but primarily through free cash flow and things we would otherwise be doing in the normal course which could include modest property dispositions from time-to-time, but from our perspective continuing to look at and deleveraging is important. Maintaining an investment grade rating relative to our business model is important. But I would think most of that will be both from the free cash flow and the modest divestitures that I made reference to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And one more you might have touched on this earlier but what are your expectations on price realizations on your production out of the Rockies in '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah this is Clay Bretches and we feel really good about our position in the Rockies right now. As in 2008, we have 95% of our production either transported or hedged through financial hedges, so when we take a look at that average realization relative to Henry Hub we're looking at something on the order of $1.50 below.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How would that compare to last year do you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, obviously it will be better; we have more hedge this year than we did last year. And plus the regional sales of course in the Rockies were much worse last year. So, we are expecting better things with the oncoming of REX transportation out of the Rockies, which will increase the ultimate realized price for regional sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Do you happen to know what the differential was last year between WTI and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It wasn't much off of a $1.50; I mean was it about $1.25 or something like that on our net...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He's talking about the market itself &#x2013; that's differential.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, the current differential for...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The average for the whole year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is over $3 on average. Right now it's about a dollar under on CIG versus Henry Hub, but it probably averaged over $3 lower.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right very good, thanks guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Find that number for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was $4.01 I just looked at it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because of lot of upside in terms of realization there for this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. All right thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ben Dale with Bernstein. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning Ben</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just had two quick questions. You made some commentary on the lower Tertiary. Do you have a feeling for what flow rates you would need to see to make developments economic? Obviously there has been a lot of discussion about that over the last year or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben we haven't speculated on that. There has been a lot of moving parts. What the development costs will look like. What type of flow regime you could have so we haven't really speculated on what type of flow that you need.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and my second question was just around your return on cap so obviously it's relatively low versus the peer group given the acquisitions. Do you have any particular plans to drive that up over the next two &#x2013; three years and I guess my follow on question with that is do you have a feeling for what commodity price you would be at risk of impairment in testing some of that capital?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben, this is Al. As it relates to future F&amp;D and we'll get into this in more detail in March at our investor conference. I think for '08 you'll see us continue to guide you to an 18 or less number just like we did this year and we will give you a little more substance behind what that means for '08 and beyond at that time. From an impairment standpoint as you know, every quarter we go through that process now particularly under successful efforts at the field level and it does vary by region and we aren't currently that price sensitive to either gas or oil in any area in which we currently produce.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Rehan Rashid with FBR. (Friedman, Billings, Ramsey &amp; Co). Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Real quick question on coalbed methane. On the water handling capacities, by when could we expect it to get to the 550 number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Will be the &#x2013; will be expanding the two facilities we have there through the course of the first two quarters of 2008, and that will push us up over 500.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And should we expect a proportionate increase in production as well or should that lag?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not immediately of course what you see is a very long de-watering process in the order of one year plus for these, our Big George coals. And so you will see that impact coming in 2009 and 10 that's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. So the drilling activities essentially being planned according to &#x2013; accordingly meaning that you will be able to raise the watering handling to 550.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from the line of Shannon Nome with Deutsche Bank. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning. Do you have a total proceeds number for the &#x2013; what is it &#x2013; 620 million barrels sold during the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think we've given you some indication of what we divested from the standpoint of reserves sold during the year and I think we've guided each quarter at kind of what we are looking at with the properties we've sold so, but we've never come up and communicated precisely that number Shannon and I think you wouldn't take much to calculate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right as whatever you have previously disclosed, it wouldn't be a big change for that as of &#x2013; as of the year-end?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right Shannon, I think the way to look at that is since the acquisition time we've monetized the $15 billion, and I think we've guided that &#x2013; that would entail about 900 million barrels of reserves including Canada and Venezuela and piece that went off the books in 2006, so you can kind of back into the aggregate number that way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then you disclosed 54 million barrels of extensions discoveries in the other international category. I know you said you don't want to break up Peregrino but what other than Brazil would be in that number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct Brazil would be in that number, and would be a large contributor to that number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean what other, what else is in that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>China and Algeria.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>China, Algeria. And then can you tell me I'm guessing you won't what future development cost not yet incurred would relate to that Brazil booking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Don't have that number to disclose and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Shannon, we are still out with some offerings, tendering some offers on some of the major facilities out there. So, we will give you better update on that in the March conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have in New York.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ray Deacon with BMO Capital. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hey, I guess, Bob I was wondering at Natural Buttes are you going to be able to book 10-acre space &#x2013; assuming the 10-acre down spacing works, would you be able to book reserves in 2008. And also on the Atlantic Rim maybe what kind of results have you seen so far and what, what kind of funding costs do you think you will have in Atlantic Rim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well Ray in Greater Natural Buttes we're now in our second 10-acre pilot, it's, the early results looked very good. We haven't had plans to book a large chunk of 10 acres in 2008. So, we'll watch those and that will be good piece of upside force in our ongoing business. And in Atlantic Rim it's really too early to tell, we are just now in the process of drilling the wells and begin the hookups and that type of thing, so it's really just too early to tell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Got it. Is this &#x2013; is the first pilot and the second pilot fairly close to each other in Natural Buttes or will you be able to prove that kind of larger area works let me guess?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, its spread over pretty good area actually I don't have exact distance but it's in two different townships.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Great. And I have just one more question on the blocks that were acquired next to the Peregrino discovery, when will you be able to drill those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That would likely be in a couple of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We got it. Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is a follow up question from the line of Gil Yang with Citi. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a quick question on Independence Hub the run rate is higher than your 80% or 800 million number, is that because did you exceed the volumes did you ever go over a bcf per day or did you just have higher run rate than you expected?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a combination of little bit of both, we did exceed over 1 billion a day for a short period of time, but right now our run rates have been slightly better than what we have been guiding you to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you are now running probably just under a bcf a day when it's operating in, which you are operating more than 80% of the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gil, our run rate on average has been around 900, 850 to 900 as we mentioned on the call. One way to look at Independence Hub at a bcf a day is like running full throttle, and it's a wide open type capacity and we have just not been able to push that platform that hard on a sustained basis, and that's why we've guided it to 80%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gotcha. Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is a follow-up question from the line of Rehan Rashid with FBR. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim a quick question on the &#x2013; on risk 7 billion barrels that you talk about, if I just take a 4.2 billion over CapEx for this year take an $18 F&amp;D, we're talking a long-time before we convert everything over, any particular thoughts on that front how &#x2013; how can you maybe accelerate the conversion little bit faster than that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the observation is correct. I may have misheard you but I think you meant to say risks net resources it's not..</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it's still even at a risk basis takes a long-time. &#x2013; We still look at way &#x2013; as we talked earlier is that we've been, we continue to try to focus on seeing if additional capital can be put to accelerated drilling overtime, at some of our resources basis as well as we look at opportunities overtime to monetize things, I think what you saw during our divestiture program, gave us some confidence, that for the right reasons in the right places, we may decide to do something that creates more value upfront for &#x2013; for our shareholders. And I think with &#x2013; with additional cash flow from the production growth, we are going to have more opportunities to put money back into the ground to accelerate that, every year we go if commodity prices don't reverse against us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How do &#x2013; because I come up with the 30 year number so, definitely accelerating that will be good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We are currently showing no more questions in queue. I would like to turn the call over to management for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We want to thank everybody for being on the call today and we look forward to seeing those of you that you can make it at our Investor Conference on March 25 in New York and hope you've all had a good start to the year and we're excited about where we are headed. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may now disconnect and have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>