<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1307064" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-05-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>43</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John Colglazier, Vice President, Investor Relations &amp; Communications</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James T. Hackett, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">David Heikkinen</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Robert Gwin</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Robert Daniels</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Scott Hanold</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Robert Reeves</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep">Charles Meloy</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Doug Leggate</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">David Knott</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">David Tameron</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Robert Morris</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Brian Singer</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Phil Corbett</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="corprep">R.A. Walker</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Ellen Hannan</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Ellen Hannon</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">David Kistler</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the First Quarter 2010 Anadarko Petroleum Corporation Earnings Conference Call. My name is Gerry and I'll be your coordinator today. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded for replay purposes.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to your host for today, Mr. John Colglazier. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Gerry. Good morning, everyone, and welcome to Anadarko's first quarter 2010 conference call. Joining me on the call today are Jim Hackett, our Chairman and CEO, and other executives who will be available later in the call to answer your questions. As we've done in the past, we posted additional information in our Operations Report that is available on our Web site.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to Jim, I'll need to remind you that this presentation contains our best and most reasonable estimates and information. However, a number of factors could cause actual results to differ materially from what we discuss today. You should read our full disclosure on forward-looking statements in our presentation slides, our latest 10-K, other filings and press releases for the risk factors associated with our business.</p>
          <p>In addition, we'll reference certain non-GAAP measures today, so be sure to see the reconciliations in our earnings release on our Web site. We encourage you to read the cautionary note to U.S. investors contained in the presentation slides for this call.</p>
          <p>And with that, let me turn the call over to Jim Hackett.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. Good morning, everyone. Before we get into the results for the quarter, I want to first express the sadness we feel and extend our sincere condolences to the families of those that were lost in the Deepwater Horizon accident about two weeks ago. As a non-operating partner we want to answer questions regarding the cause as much as anyone and resolution as quickly as possible.</p>
          <p>We understand this event is foremost in everyone's mind and we will discuss it in more detail with you later in the call. But before we do, I'll spend a few moments reviewing the results of our first quarter.</p>
          <p>As you saw in the press release, our producing assets delivered a record quarter with total volumes of 62 million barrels of oil equivalent. Our E&amp;P organization accomplished this while also continuing to reduce our lease operating expense per unit. With strong run rates and minimal workovers in the deepwater Gulf of Mexico, lease operating expense improved by about 19% sequentially over the fourth quarter of 2009 and by 32% year-over-year. Through these efforts to reduce LOE, we are now among the lowest cost producers in our peer group.</p>
          <p>Other summary highlights during the quarter are that we made good progress in our shale plays, announced a new deepwater discovery in a frontier basin, and drilled 3 successful appraisal wells that confirmed the resource potential and viability of several emerging megaprojects.</p>
          <p>We also closed the $1.5 billion joint-venture agreement with Mitsui in the Marcellus Shale and retired or refinanced near-term debt to further strengthen our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Our reported quarterly sales volumes increased by about 15% relative to the first quarter of 2009. Of note, sales volumes for the quarter included about 1.9 million barrels of oil equivalent from a royalty price threshold adjustment related to our 2009 Gulf of Mexico natural gas sales.</p>
          <p>Adjusting volumes for this factor still leaves us above the high end of our volumetric guidance for the quarter and represents an 11% increase over the first quarter of 2009. Due to the strong performance of our producing assets, we are increasing the midpoint of our full-year sales volume guidance by 3.5 million barrels of oil equivalent. A major contributor to our production growth was a 35% increase in our total liquids production to almost 26 million barrels compared to 19 million barrels in the first quarter of 2009. This is a direct result of the actions we took at the beginning of 2009 to focus on liquids-rich areas within our U.S. onshore portfolio. Liquids for the quarter comprised 42% of our overall reported sales, directly contributing to our enhanced cash flow margin per barrel of oil equivalent.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned a few moments ago, our E&amp;P organization did an outstanding job in the quarter of managing our assets. As a result of these efforts, we're now reducing our annual guidance for LOE by $0.25 per barrel of oil equivalent. We are and have been focused on investing in areas of our portfolio that offer the strongest economics. Given the current market conditions for oil and natural gas prices, this involves focusing on areas with high liquids yields. The Marcellus Shale, given its strong economics, is currently the only area of pure natural gas drilling in which we are prudently increasing our activity levels.</p>
          <p>The increased investments are being carried by Mitsui through the joint venture agreement that we closed in the first quarter. Currently we are producing approximately 120 million cubic feet of natural gas per day on a gross basis from the Marcellus from about 30 wells, with about 80 wells in various stages of completion. That's threefold to our net 2009 exit rate of about 40 million cubic feet per day gross.</p>
          <p>In another major shale play, the Eagle Ford in southwest Texas, we continued to see strong results with very good liquids production, which compromises [sic] about 50% of the product stream and 75% of the production value. We expanded our position during the first quarter by acquiring more than 80,000 net acres from TXCO. This acquisition also increased our working interest at 75% across all of our Eagle Ford acreage. The cost of this acquisition was approximately $1,100 per acre, which is a very competitive number relative to higher recent industry cost per acreage here.</p>
          <p>We ended the first quarter with four rigs running and have drilled more than 20 wells in this play and are driving down drilling times, reducing our cost per well and seeing good economics with EURs of over 300,000 barrels of oil equivalent per well. We've identified hundreds of potential well locations in this play, are in the process of adding two more rigs in the coming weeks, and pursuing plans to significantly expand the midstream infrastructure to capture the value we see over our 300,000 net acreage position.</p>
          <p>One of the newer areas in which we are actively drilling is the Bone Spring play in the Delaware Basin of West Texas where we control 170,000 net acres. Like the Eagle Ford and Wattenberg areas, Bone Spring has a high liquid composition. We are currently running four rigs in the play with one recent completion flowing at a maximum rate of almost 1,200 barrels per day. We also anticipate that our partner in this play will be increasing their rig count, thereby providing for an active program throughout the year.</p>
          <p>In the Rockies region, we expect to be drilling by the end of the quarter in the oil-focused horizontal Niobrara play, where we have 500,000 net acres. By virtue of several modest-sized firm outs that we completed over the last several years within our mineral interest, we have had access to industry information on the recent drilling in this shale which allows us to better de-risk the play with other people's money as we prepare for own drilling program this year.</p>
          <p>In addition to the meaningful growth that we are demonstrating with our on-shore assets, we currently remain on track and on budget to deliver first oil from Jubilee Phase I in offshore Ghana beginning later this year, Caesar/Tonga in the Gulf of Mexico, beginning in the first half of 2011 and El Merk in Algeria beginning in late 2011. The partnership has nearly completed the construction work on the 120,000 barrel per day FPSO for the Jubilee Phase I development and we expect to mobilize the vessel to Ghana in the coming week. Subsea infrastructure is being installed and completions work has been initiated.</p>
          <p>At the Caesar/Tonga complex in the deepwater Gulf of Mexico, construction activities are progressing as planned. In Algeria at El Merk, the partnership has drilled almost half of the 140 planned wells and the facility's construction is on track. Meanwhile our global deepwater drilling program continues to prove successful in advancing the next wave of mega projects</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we announced successful appraisal wells at Lucius and Vito in the Gulf of Mexico and at Tweneboa offshore Ghana. We announced that the Lucius appraisal well in the Gulf encountered almost 600 net feet of high quality oil pay in the subsalt Pliocene and Miocene sands. The appraisal well was an up-dip sidetrack approximately 3,200 feet south of the discovery well in Keathley Canyon Block 875. The reservoirs at Lucius have excellent porosity and permeability based on the core and log data recovered. We recently spud our second appraisal well, with plans to drill a third immediately thereafter as we evaluate development options for this discovery. We operate Lucius with a 50% working interest.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter we also announced a successful appraisal well at Vito in Mississippi Canyon Block 940 in the Gulf of Mexico. The appraisal well, which is more than a mile from the Vito discovery well, encountered more than 600 feet of high quality oil in fixed subsalt Miocene sands. We are currently drilling our second appraisal well at Vito as we work with our partners to transition this large discovery to development. We hold a 20% working interest in Vito, which is operated by Shell.</p>
          <p>Also in the Gulf, we are currently appraising our Heidelberg discovery. The original well encountered mechanical issues about 10,000 feet above the reservoir section and will now be re-drilled to a projected total depth of 31,500 feet to test middle to lower Miocene objectives similar to the Heidelberg discovery well in Green Canyon Block 903.</p>
          <p>Moving to Ghana Tweneboa#2 well located about four miles southeast of the original discovery well, confirmed our expectations of finding a down-dip oil accumulation and thicker sand section. The well encountered about 105 net feet of pay with just over half of the pay count being oil and the remainder gas condensate. The partnership expects to drill two additional appraisal wells at Tweneboa later this year, as well as an exploration well at the neighboring Owo prospect.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, in another of our emerging mega projects, we announced last month the successful drillstem test at the pre-salt Wahoo#1 well that floated an unstimulated and equipment limited rate of about 7,500 barrels of oil per day. Test results indicate this well will be able to produce at a sustained rate of more than 15,000 barrels per day of high-quality crude oil.</p>
          <p>We've already moved the rig to the Wahoo#2 well location to conduct a drillstem test there and expect to have results later this month. Once the drillstem test is completed at Wahoo#2, we expect to move the rig to drill the Wahoo South exploration prospect, approximately five miles south of the original Wahoo discovery. We operate this BM-C-30 block with a 30% working interest.</p>
          <p>Shifting to exploration, we announced the first deep-water discovery in the Rovuma Basin offshore of Mozambique in the first quarter. The Windjammer exploration well encountered more than 555 net feet of natural gas pay and most importantly established the presence of an active hydrocarbon system.</p>
          <p>We operate Windjammer with a paying interest of about 43%. Our second deepwater exploration well in the basin was located approximately 50 miles of the Windjammer discovery at the Collier prospect. Drilling was stopped and the well abandoned because we had reached the rig's design parameters at the top of the reservoir objective. We will continue to evaluate this and the numerous prospects and play types across our 2.6 million acres in this offshore block and have moved the rig to another location called the Ironclad prospect, which will be followed by another exploration well at our Barkentine prospect.</p>
          <p>In the Gulf of Mexico, as everyone is most certainly aware of the events involving the Deepwater Horizon drilling rig and the BP operated Macondo prospect resulted in the loss of life, a release of oil into the Gulf and a large-scale response effort. As a 25% non-operating partner in the well we have offered assistance to BP and are supportive of the unified command's role in coordinating the necessary resources to address this situation.</p>
          <p>As we outlined in last night's news release, we maintain insurance policies that are designed to protect against a portion of potential financial losses occurring as a result of such events. Our share of costs are covered up to an aggregate level of approximately $710 million less deductable. This insurance is designed to cover costs associated with stopping a hydrocarbon release, drilling relief wells, clean up and other liabilities and associated costs. Based on our 25% non-operated interest we estimate our deductibles will total about $15 million and our insurance will cover net costs to APC's working interest 25% up to approximately $178 million.</p>
          <p>It is still early in the response, fact gathering and investigation process. And as a non-operator we are not in a position to date to speculate on the ultimate outcomes or the root cause of the accident. We will remain focused on managing through this event and based on what we know today, we are not currently making any major changes or interruptions to our capital spending programs or strategic objectives.</p>
          <p>However, we will not hesitate to take action if necessary to protect the company and its financial health. We will of course continue to communicate with you as clarity is obtained throughout the year. Turning to our financial results for the first quarter, we reported net income of $1.43 per diluted share. As with previous quarters, we've included the items affecting comparability in the tables attached to last night's earnings release. In total, these items increased our reported net income by $0.62 per diluted share.</p>
          <p>We generated more than $1.5 billion of discretionary cash flow during the first three months of the year, and ended the quarter with approximately $3.7 billion of cash on hand. Free cash flow totaled almost $300 million with capital expenditures at about $1.2 billion for the quarter.</p>
          <p>At current strip prices, our projected discretionary cash flow for the year should be sufficient to cover our announced 2010 capital program. During the quarter, we further strengthened the balance sheet by issuing $750 million of 30-year bonds to fund a substantial portion of the tender offers for our 2011 and 2012 maturing debt. We retired a total of $1 billion during the first and early second quarters, approximately 920 million of which was scheduled to mature in 2011.</p>
          <p>To further support our ability to deliver upon our exploration programs and mega project developments, we've augmented our 2011 hedge positions from the schedules we provided in March. A full description of these are available in the attachments to last night's news release.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier in the call, we are raising our sales volume guidance for the full year to a range of 230 to 234 million barrels of oil equivalent from the previous range of 226 to 231 million barrels of oil equivalent for an increase of 3.5 million barrels of oil equivalent at the midpoint.</p>
          <p>At our recent investor conference in March, we laid out bold long-term objectives for the future and we began delivering upon those expectations during the quarter. To recap, we enhanced our margins by continuing to focus capital on areas with higher liquids production, managing costs and improving efficiencies. We confirmed the market value from our Marcellus Shale position at approximately $4.5 billion gross via a joint venture agreement.</p>
          <p>We maintain time and cost schedules for bringing our sanctioned mega projects on line. And so far this year, five of the seven deepwater wells drilled have either been discoveries or successful appraisals. We expect to be active during the remainder of 2010 with approximately 20 deepwater wells planned.</p>
          <p>As a result, we can reaffirm our expectation to deliver approximately 400 million barrels of oil equivalent of net discovered resources this year from our exploration programs. We also remain committed to allocating our capital dollars toward the most value accretive projects within our portfolio going forward and to make adjustments as necessary based on further developments in the Gulf.</p>
          <p>At this time, I'm joined by our executive team and we welcome your questions. So Gerry, I might ask you to open up the lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And your first question comes from the line of David Heikkinen with Tudor Pickering Holt. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jim, and just thinking about 2010, 2011 plans and beyond, as you think about any risks associated with regulation or costs for the Gulf of Mexico, can you talk about how you'd change your capital allocation or any thoughts at least -- what the spill could actually mean for Anadarko longer term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, I think it's early to try to speculate on that, but I will tell you given, the portfolio we have if we find that we need for economic reasons to do something in another part of the world, we certainly can do that and we have the prospectivity to go do that as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And as you think about -- just shifting -- realize you can't answer a whole lot of questions as far as the hydrocarbon release and relief wells. Right now, all your interests are aligned with BP. I mean, what, when you think about the path forward, how can we assess what that environmental clean-up risk would be? I mean, what are the -- what's the range of outcomes, and how long does the $710 million cover you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Again, I think, David, we can all sit here and presume what it might be. But the real key is how long the well keeps flowing. If the well is shut in, the cost escalation actually starts to go down as opposed to up. And so, I think we've got to be careful not to try to speculate as to number ranges. The -- Bob can speak to the insurance here in one second relative to kind of how we view the world out there in terms of coverage. And we feel good that we've got it in place. We feel that, if things happen and we get -- and we're blessed in this process, there might be plenty there. So, Bob, I don't know if you want to walk through any of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I'll address that, David. If you think in terms of the rate of spend that we hear coming out of the unified command at this stage of about 6 to $8 million per day, then obviously our coverage in the $178 million range would represent about two to three months. However I think it's important to keep in mind that as we start drilling the relief well, the rate of change certainly will change and the times of the expenditures are going to be somewhat variable.</p>
          <p>So we're looking at it as, based on what we see today, insurance to cover the next few months. And as Jim mentioned, there's a lot of uncertainty around how far this will go into the future and what the ultimate remediation cost will be, but the insurance piece ought to cover a couple to three months' worth of that time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Dave, just one other thing that I'm sure everybody on the phone is aware of, is there are other considerations here too. That -- Bob's discussion really assumes that there is no liability anywhere along the chain or any source of insurance outside of our own proprietary insurance. And that isn't necessarily going to be the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yeah, I appreciate it. Obviously the market's pricing in risk and just trying to put it in context. On, specifically just on the Bone Springs, you mentioned high liquid content. We've talked and heard about the Avalon Shale being a contributor there. Can you talk at all about just kind of the operations onshore and as you think about West Texas, is there a shale play that's emerging in the Bone Springs area, or how do you think about that? That's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, David; this is Bob Daniels. On the Avalon, what we've done so far is in the Bone Springs itself and we have looked at now at the Avalon, which does seem to have some characteristics that would make it attractive to test. And so we do have some plans to go out and test the Avalon shale and see what sort of producibility it may have, what kind of recoveries we would get, what type of hydrocarbons. We do plan to drill two wells in it right now. We have 170,000 acres out in the West Texas area that would be prospective for the Bone Springs and the Avalon Shale. So we will be testing it and see what we get out of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And you next question comes from the line of Scott Hanold with RBC Capital Markets. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you look at the Macondo well, are you guys from a financial perspective going to start making some accruals for some of these future costs? Or when would that start to sort of flow through the income statement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott, this is Bob. We're going to look at that really hard in the second quarter obviously. It's difficult to make accruals when you don't have an estimate of the expenses and there are a great number of variables currently. But it's something that we're going to spend a lot of time on during the second quarter process and make sure that we're as transparent and well accrued for any potential liability as makes sense at the end of the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, would you and maybe it's too early to determine this, but would you suspect that there's going to be one big accrual taken at that point in time and then smaller adjustments going forward, or how do you kind of think about doing that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Scott. This is Bobby Reeves. Let me put a little perspective on this and kind of put a package around it for some of you. Remember that Anadarko is the non-operator here, that BP as the operator is really focused appropriately all their attention on the response right now and initial investigation.</p>
          <p>Anybody that's been involved in a situation like this knows that it's extremely complicated. The investigation will hopefully give us some indication on what happened here, what the cause of the accident was. And then there are very complicated contracts involved here, indemnities, insurance coverage, the possible application of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 or other laws that really have a puzzle here that has to be figured out, and we're going to have to have some good legal minds to figure this out. We're on that process now. But it's not going to be immediate; it's going to take a little time.</p>
          <p>One comment I wanted to make about the Oil Pollution Act is that it was designed by Congress, in our opinion, to handle exactly the situation that's occurred now. The Congress imposed upon all the Gulf of Mexico oil producers to pay into the trust fund, amount, out of every barrel that we produce. That protects Anadarko and its shareholders, and we've done that. We believe it's going to be applicable. We don't know the ultimate financial outcome here and it's not appropriate for us to speculate further, but I wanted you to know that it's not an immediate assessment that we'll be able to make. It will take some time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. No, I appreciate that color, and one kind of last question on Macondo. In terms of you being a non-operator, how passive typically are you when you're a non-operator? I mean, did you -- were you part of sort of the well design on Macondo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I can take a shot at that. Not untraditionally, you actually do know what targets you're going after and remember we had firmed into this after the well had already spud. So the well design and procedures, operating procedures, were all done before we actually firmed in. When you typically approve these as a non-operator, you basically approve just the capital spending level and the targeted zones from a geological perspective, as opposed to looking at the detailed well design or procedures. We were not involved with that -- in that all in this well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Appreciate that. And one last question. In the Niobrara, you mentioned that you've got 500,000 acres. Obviously industry really talked the play up. You did mention that you think that activity has de-risked some of the play. When you look at the Niobrara, I mean, can you give us a sense of that 500,000 is there a certain percentage of that you think is going to be really good or perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've been -- this is Chuck Meloy by the way -- we've been closely monitoring all the industry activity in northern Colorado and southern Wyoming. And as you're aware, we have the land grant that goes through that area. So we essentially have mineral interest in every other section in the play. And so as the play develops from north where we've seen industry activity to right down upon our Wattenberg acreage, across that entire area we've seen encouraging results.</p>
          <p>So all of the 500,000 acres looks perspective. We don't yet know where the sweet spot is because of the lack of activity. We're just starting to gin up the activity in the area. And we've encouraged that activity through some modest farm-outs to get the play moving. And so we're prepared and should toward the end of this year begin drilling in the play and reaping the benefits of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The only other thing that I add is that that mineral interest is held in perpetuity, too. So it's not -- we have a lot of time to work on other people's money and do some of our own drilling and make this thing really work well if it has the potential to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, guys. Appreciate all the help. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And you next question comes from the line of Doug Leggate with Bank of America/Merrill Lynch. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning, everybody. I'm afraid I want to keep on the issue of Macondo just for a little while if I may. Sensitive question, but just in light of some of your comments about not being involved in the well until it was spud and so on, and also if I could bring in the oil spill trust into this as well, is there anything in the partnership agreement that is either standard or non-standard that would relate to limiting your liability to any punitive damages beyond the immediate costs associated with the block? And if so -- or if not rather, what is your understanding of how the trust will actually be deployed in terms of any limit that can be attributed to any specific incident? Or any color you can give that might limit your expenditure or your exposure would be helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Bobby Reeves again. Let me first comment again, reiterate that until we know what the causes of this accident are, it's hard for us to give a legal opinion as to the applicability of the agreement, punitive damages or anything else. There's going to be a lot of fingers pointing a lot of different ways and it's just inappropriate for us to talk about how this is going to come out. It's going to take time.</p>
          <p>As to the applicability of the Oil Spill Trust Fund under the Open ID Act that is something that will be sorted out, but as we understand it allows for third parties to make claims directly to that fund to be sorted out and then has a limitation of liability as to those who are considered responsible parties under the Open ID Act. And beyond that, there's some items to be sorted out. That will give you a brief understanding of how that works.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Doug, as you know, that's our money that we've all put in on the crude oil we produced, and so, it's an interesting opportunity. The other thing that I can tell you that is, we are mostly focused on making sure that this cleanup occurs and assisting is part of the full industry effort on this, assisting BP. But when all is said and done, we're going to be protecting the Anadarko shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you. If I could try a couple other quick ones. In relation to the same thing, Jim, you're quite averse to the equity as we know, but I'm just curious if this begins to escalate, how do you see your ability to fund your share of the potential cost?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take a stab at that, Doug. To begin with, we have substantial liquidity. As you saw, we ended the quarter with over $3 billion in cash, 3.7, and we've used some of that since the end of quarter to pay down debt, which gives us additional borrowing capacity. We've got 1.3 billion of a revolver that's committed through 2013. In addition, we're generating a lot of discretionary cash flow, over 1.5 billion in the first quarter. If it was necessary, we could choose in the future to redirect or reduce our spending, selectively sell or farm down assets. We obviously have a broad and a deep portfolio of attractive assets and I think we'd be more inclined to look in that direction rather than to the capital markets.</p>
          <p>And as everyone saw at our investor conference in March, we have a five-year plan that delivers some very good results and a series of recent discoveries that are not a part of the five-year plan that start to kick in to provide accelerated growth well into the future. So we think we've got the types of flexibility with our investment opportunities and our existing assets to deal with the size of the cost even at some of the very, very high levels that the media is tossing around out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And the last one from me. This one's maybe more business oriented, probably for Bob Daniels. The Collier well, Bob, could you maybe just speak a little bit about what happened there? My understanding was that was maybe a little bit more of a liquids target. Can you just discuss what the prognosis is and where we go forward in Mozambique?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Doug, you're right. We did hope to see the potential for liquids as we moved down to the south. Of course this was 50 miles south of our Windjammer prospect. A little bit different play type, certainly a different seismic character, which led us to that. We designed the well to handle the anticipated pressures that we would see at our total depth. And we exceeded or we reached those design parameters and we had to stop right at the very top of our objective. So what we're going to do is take all the data that we have acquired from the well bore, tie it in to our seismic and make a decision is there another location either on this prospect or adjacent to it on a look-alike prospect, I mean, we may want to come back and test. Right now, we're just tying all that data into our regional understanding.</p>
          <p>Meanwhile, we've taken the spig up and we top set the Barkentine prospect and then moved over to the Ironclad and we did spud the Ironclad prospect. They're very different play types. They're both kind of big strap plays similar to what we're seeing over in the West Africa side. Again they do have, particularly the Ironclad one, has more potential for liquids as we move to the south. This is even further south than the Collier well. So I guess the overall result of Collier is that we recognize now that we've got some pressure regimes that we've got to design for. We also have a lot of data from it that we need to tie into our overall regional understanding and we need to continue to test these play concepts as we continue to evaluate the block there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But does Barkentine have an appraisal element to it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a little bit of an appraisal element, but it's primarily an exploratory well. I think that people have drawn that conclusion because of its proximity to Windjammer. Windjammer is a toe-thrust, a very tight fold, and Barkentine is the outboard, relatively undeformed component, same age sands that we're looking for but a very different trap stop.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks a lot for answering my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of David Knott with Knott Partners. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, you mentioned aggregate insurance of I think 710 million and sort of direct insurance of 178 million. Could you give us some color on what both those terms relate to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great question, David. And I might ask Bob to do that. We were just trying gross it up for working interest is all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, if you think in terms of our coverage, it's the lesser of those two numbers. The way the insurance works is it's designed around this gross level and then it gets adjusted by our working interest. If our work interest in this well for instance was 50% then that 178 number would be doubled. And so it's really just a matter of trying to explain it so that the market could understand the coverage relative to the size of the event.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of David Tameron with Wells Fargo. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jim. Just stepping aside from I guess Macondo. I won't ask any more questions there. But can you talk about bigger picture kind of the regulatory environment in DC? We've heard some chatter that perhaps we're going to finally get some type of energy bill or another Kerry-Lieberman bill's going to come to the floor. Can you just talk about the latest and greatest?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I wish I could give you better definition around it. I think this accident complicates a portion of that because I think a central feature of both those was going to be offshore access. And I think in the current political environment, people will tread very lightly. As you know, that access was not something that was going to be provided overnight anyway. So in our view, it wasn't going to change our strategy or tactics for the next four or five years. And therefore, we see all of this as very long dated, and we weren't absolutely sure how helpful either piece of legislation would be for the natural gas story at the end of day.</p>
          <p>We still are trying to press for that or were trying to press for that prior to Senator Graham walking away from the bill. We now hear that Senator Reid may put it back up for consideration. We think the politics of the reelection process and the politics around the current environment make both of those more -- just tougher to predict that something will happen there. We still need a good energy policy in this country. We don't seem to be able to get it together.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So my -- I guess, the implication, the inference from your comments, it sounds like we're talking 2011 before anything happens given we're five months away from.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, or at least a couple of months away. I think a lot depends on how quickly we get this situation under control in the Gulf. But at some point then if they're going to take up immigration it becomes more difficult to get KGL done potentially. But I'm guessing because it depends on whether they can get Graham back in there, and Senator Graham comes back in, it changes the dynamic again.</p>
          <p>We still think, it's similar to what happened in Colorado. We still think that there are ways to get natural gas as a preferred fuel, and we think it's just a matter of time. This is a short-term issue I think more than a long-term issue. So I'm still very hopeful about even the direction that Kerry-Graham-Lieberman was taking was much more pro-natural gas. For the first time, we saw proposed Senate legislation, at least our reading of it, our understanding of it, it was going to be very positive about electric generation uses of natural gas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. No, that's good color. Thanks. And just one more question. Looking at the Rockies, you've talked a lot about Wattenberg or -- maybe Jim has &#x2013; but, talked, Wattenberg, how you can drill NGLs and liquids-rich type play. Do you have any of that ability in Greater Natural Buttes and what you guys doing out there currently?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well our liquid yield in Greater Natural Buttes is generally associated with our NGLs coming out of our Chipeta gas plant. And the economics at Chipeta have become, or the Greater Natural Buttes area in general have become really good as we focused on the core and have begun drilling just core wells. We're seeing EURs approaching 2 bcf and for 1.3 to $1.4 million of investment. So and that 2 bcf of course has a liquid yield associated with it. So the economics have become stellar in that area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Bob Morris with Citigroup. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a very quick question here. You noted that the Marcellus Shale was the only area that you were prudently increasing activity levels. How much of that is driven by the enhanced economics you receive now under the joint venture with Mitsui? Or in other words, would you still be increasing activity levels there without the benefits of that joint venture?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, the quick answer is, we're proceeding basically as if we were on our own. But we have the benefit of the economics, obviously, from what you referred to in terms of the carry. A lot of the production uplift as you might imagine is non-operated because of the activities of our partners. We would not necessarily be as aggressive as that is I think on our own, but that's each company's choice to do what they need to do, somewhat determined in some cases by lease expiration terms.</p>
          <p>In our case we've got very favorable leases for the most part. But we are not using the carry as a reason to go crazy if you will. We just think it's things we need to do get ready for when gas prices recover. And certainly with LNG imports being where they are at, and if we can continue to advance anything on the legislative front and if we keep working on, showing discipline in the industry, we can make this particular play highly attractive because we think the break-even economics on the Marcellus are somewhere around $3 at the NYMEX.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you said your break-even is at $3. Is that what you just said?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All in, below $3 all in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Without the carry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And you next question comes from the line of Brian Singer with Goldman Sachs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Couple questions. First kind of going back to oil, there was a nice increase in oil production during the quarter. It looks like the trajectory, though, is for oil production in the U.S. to fall between now and the end of the year. And I wonder how much of that is conservatism for potential hurricane disruptions or how you think about your U.S. oil and NGLs trajectory going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Brian. This is, Chuck. The trajectory is strong. We do take into account the hurricane season, which of course would impact mostly Gulf of Mexico oil production -- oil and gas production. And so that's the dip you see in the third and fourth quarter. Other than that, the activity we have going on in the Maverick Basin, the Bone Springs, the Wattenberg and in our other plays like East Chalk for instance is all focused on those very robust economics, most of which are liquid rich. So we should see that trajectory continue through time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Especially in the Rockies where you saw a sharp increase quarter-on-quarter even versus most of the rest of the quarters in 2009, there's nothing specific to say that should really fall off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we should continue to have strong results there. Particularly with the focus we have on Wattenberg, we're ramping up our rigs at Wattenberg and we have the White Cliff Pipeline available to us, which has allowed us to export with very low tariffs and enhanced the economics and we'll continue to increase our investment in Wattenberg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. And then secondly, coming back to the Gulf of Mexico, when you think longer term, and Anadarko has always very upfront in trying to push the envelope in terms of using new technology and in terms of trying to reduce lead times. Do you see any of that either at risk or do you see any kind of longer-term cost increases that would make you any less aggressive either in the Gulf of Mexico or in the deep water broadly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, you know we put such strong emphasis on our environmental and safety records, they've been strong through time, we've won many SAFE awards. We're currently the winner of district SAFE award in New Orleans. Our incident rate is one quarter of the industry rate despite our use of advancing technologies. We'll continue to do that. We have a strong record of being able to employ those safely and effectively and quickly. I see us continuing to do that through time. It's too early to speculate what regulations may come our way with regard to further safeguards or further requirements of us with time, but we'll take those into account and use them to our best abilities to maximize their value on all our investments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Phil Corbett with RBS. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. Got just a couple of questions. First of all, just on West Africa drilling campaign this year. I just wondered if you're in a position now to give a bit more detail in terms of the prospects that you might decide to drill in Sierra Leone or Liberia this year? So secondly, just going back to Mozambique. I think one of your partners sort of indicated there could be some upside to the number of wells above and beyond the four I guess you're thinking about drilling this year. I noticed that they've come up with other prospects like Galleon and Caravelle on some of their diagrams, so I'm just wondering if, what you're feeling is around extending your Mozambique drilling campaign this year? And finally just on your previous comments about spending and potentially sort of curtailing spending if you might need to bolster your financial position. Do you have a sort of a preference with regards to exploration versus fundamental production spending if you need to sort of look at the overall level of CapEx this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Philip, I'll start with the first and then I'll see if Al wants to take the last one. On Sierra Leone, Liberia, the West African campaign, there's a lot of information in the ops report that we publicly told folks that we would like to be back into Sierra Leone and Liberia and we're planning that for the second half of the year. It will probably be October timeframe before we'll get over there.</p>
          <p>We're looking at one well in Liberia, an exploratory well, and an exploratory well of Sierra Leone. We have to work up all of the data and make sure that we get partner approvals for that. And while we do have a rig targeted at this point, we're also evaluating other rig options to make sure this is the best rig to come over there. But all of that is coming together and we do have the prospects identified. Of course the Liberia 3-D that we acquired, we've got the final product in, we've got multiple prospects to come out of that. And then the Sierra Leone 3-D that we're reprocessing for the Venus appraisal is good enough to identify prospects for exploratory work, and so we do anticipate that we'll be drilling another well there.</p>
          <p>Additionally in Ghana, we have parceled out the appraisal and exploration work that we're going to be doing this year. We got the Sedco-702 coming in June. That will start with the Owo exploratory prospect, which is a prospect just to the west of Tweneboa. It's a mirror image to Tweneboa. In fact, it may be fed from the same sand system.</p>
          <p>Then we will move over to either Tweneboa appraisals or to the Oneenya prospect, but overall in Ghana we're going to drill at least four more wells, exploratory and appraisal wells. That could be two Tweneboa wells, Owo, and Oneenya this year with the 702.</p>
          <p>Then you asked about Mozambique, the drilling campaign there, we publicly said about four. We do have a drilling commitment that's beyond that. And with of course the Windjammer success, we do plan to continue with that activity. Our partnership has been in discussions about which prospects we would drill. We took the rig over to West Africa, or East Africa, I'm sorry, and we would like to keep it there to make sure that we get all of the play types evaluated, that we get any discoveries that we make appraised, and that we learn as much as we can about that block. So we anticipate that rig will be busy in Mozambique for the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Phil, this is Al Walker on the capital allocation question. I don't think we would pass along any meaningful changes in the mix that we communicated in March, which if you recall in our investor conference we talked about having an annual $1 billion or thereabouts that we wanted to spend on exploration. I don't think there's any likelihood that we would materially change that, the mix that we were referring to earlier, I think which you may have heard from Bob Gwin is that if we found ourselves needing to adjust capital spending, we might look at things across the board or in some areas where capital spending could be delayed in some of our development projects on shore.</p>
          <p>But as it relates to our exploration, so much of that is focused on oil. In most cases, we really want to continue to allocate capital along a long-term perspective so that we can deliver on that five-year and beyond plan that we talked about in March.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yeah, that's great. Can, I just want to clarify sort of the comments that've just been made and ask one quick follow-up question. So just so I understand, you're thinking about drilling one exploration, one in Liberia, one exploration, one in Sierra Leone, and appraising Venus, did I hear that correctly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm sorry. At this point we don't have a plan to appraise Venus. We're waiting on the reprocessing of the data set in Sierra Leone and that will be coming in mid year to end of the summer timeframe. Then based on that, we'll tie the well, the Venus well into it and then decide do we need an appraisal well. If we do, it would then fit in logically to the end of that drilling campaign.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great. And just one quick follow-up. Given the I guess, the relatively disappointing results for the Dahoma well, do you think that impacts on the prospectivity in the West Cape Three Points license? And I'm thinking mainly sort of sad the channel systems in the southern area of that block.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we've got a couple prospects off to the east of Dahoma. We call them Southeast Channel 1 and 2, I think. But the difference between them and Dahoma is that Dahoma was the down-dip extent of the Jubilee fan complex. And what we have been testing there was whether there were internal pinch-outs of those sands as you came up the depositional system. And what it looks like is that while we do have really good sand down there, there doesn't seem to be those internal pinch-outs or if they're there, they're farther up dip from the Dahoma prospect.</p>
          <p>As we move over to the southeast channel, they're the same age fans but they're totally not tied into the Jubilee fan complex. So it'll be more like testing Tweneboa or Jubilee originally, to where we'll go out and test either the Southeast #1 or 2. It will -- we'll roll the Dahoma well into our risking, but overall the southeast corner ones are different than Dahoma was and more similar to Jubilee original and Tweneboa.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, do we have another question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Your next question comes from Ellen Hannan with Weeden &amp; Co. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I just had a question, a follow-up on your Eagle Ford position if you would. Could you give us an idea of what you think in terms of your total resources that would be necessary to fully develop this both on the midstream and the upstream? And also the timing that you're thinking about in terms of what you need to do just to hold your acreage position with the six wells that you have running there today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Ellen, this is Chuck. As we worked on the Maverick position, you know, we have about 400,000 gross acres and 280,000 net acres. We view the vast majority of that is prospective at this time, particularly as in the Eagle Ford section, particularly the eastern two-thirds of that and we're pushing it west as we move along. So a good portion of that, if not all of it, will be perspective. We don't yet know what the appropriate well density is to develop the Eagle Ford. So it's hard to make sort of a suggested idea on what the ultimate development cost would be at this point. But what we're seeing for the money we're investing, the wells are costing us between 4 and $5 million and we're getting over 300, 350,000 barrels of primarily liquid production with those wells. So the economics are really good. One &#x2013; it's just too early to speculate on what the ultimate cost would be though, however. I can't help you there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what about in terms of the timing if you're running six rigs how -- in terms if you think about what your primary terms on your leases are or your secondary terms, do you -- are you running enough rigs to actually hold your 280,000 acres?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we are. We're actually running more rigs than we need to hold it. These are huge leases, many of them are 7, 8, 10,000 acre type leases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so we have sufficient rig line to maintain all our lease positions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's not just one per 640s, in other words.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Another question I had separate from that is to just on the follow-up, do you expect any further adjustments on your royalty price threshold like you had in the first quarter or are you essentially done with that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ellen, this is John Colglazier. What that applies to is on certain leases given back in the 2000 timeframe, the MMS and Department of Interior established price thresholds, that if the price received is below that amount, you would not owe royalty on that and be able to recoup what you had paid in, which is what happened in this case. In 2009, in the very low gas price threshold -- by the way this is oil and natural gas -- it was about -- the prices we received over the course of the year were about a nickel lower than what the MMS publishes. This actually comes out in the February-March time period. So it's an after the fact adjustment that has to be done.</p>
          <p>And so we were able to record the 1.9 million BOEs, which was about 125 million a day if you put it back into a daily amount in the quarter. So that's a one-time event. The reason we spiked it out was we didn't want to say, you know, that wasn't an operational type event and not to count it in our, you know, compared to our production guidance, and it had very de minimis impact on a net income basis, like less than a penny.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your last question comes from the line of Dave Kistler with Simmons &amp; Company. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Real quickly kind of focusing on the macro picture for a second. You highlighted $3 gas prices and being able to play in the Marcellus, reducing activity on the coal bed methane side of things. Can you walk through a little bit about where you think threshold prices are working out? And then tying it potentially to what's happening in the Gulf of Mexico, could there be any fallout in terms of ongoing support for gas coming out of there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dave, I might start with the latter part. I'm not sure I see the connection in the Gulf of Mexico as clearly as you might, so I might ask you to elaborate on that when you get a chance here. Regarding the macro, we still stay cautiously optimistic. The inventory situation is shaping up to be a little bit like last year, which caused us to hedge a fair portion of 2010. But the difference is we did that last year thinking there were going to be tremendous inflows of LNG into the U.S., and we haven't seen enough of that this year to date to be consistent with that view that we had last year. And I think there's some dynamics internationally that are helping us in that regard.</p>
          <p>But I think at the end of the day, all of us on the phone and elsewhere need to make sure that we're putting the right pressure to the industry to say that the next piece of growth is not as important as getting returns. There may be selected plays like Marcellus that work really well at low prices. But that's also part of what causes the issue. So we're being very careful on any gas drilling just like we were last year, on pure gas drilling, and we're pursuing liquids which we're fortunate to have in our portfolio. And we just got to show the discipline and then it'll correct itself and we'll be in a good place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I guess elaborating on the Gulf of Mexico impact, thinking about it in terms of is there a possibility that people are forced to shut in to do any kind of safety testing et cetera. Just to make sure that going forward, we avoid kind of the tragedies that we've been discussing quite a bit on this call already.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand now, and I don't. Our anticipation is that that isn't the remedy at the end of the day that will be used. And so, I don't -- if you're at least suggesting what I think is probable, it's not probable that that has a big impact on natural gas supplies. Theoretically could it? Yes, but I wouldn't know how to quantify that today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just one last housekeeping issue on Bone Springs. Can you walk through kind of the base economics of the play, four rigs running, you talk about adding a fifth? If we can just get a sense for what that looks like with a 170,000 net acres, looks like something that could be ratcheted up in activity pretty substantially?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, what we have is four, like you mentioned. We also see our non-operating partner -- our other partner that has a portion of this area also ramping up and that's Chesapeake, I listened to their call and they anticipate ramping up. So we should see a great deal of activity out in the Bone Spring. Our EURs have been in the order of the 350 to 375,000 barrels per well. So again, really good economics. We mentioned, I think Jim mentioned earlier that the last well had a maximum rate of over 1,200 barrels a day,1,200 barrels a day. So these are good wells, they have good economics, they have, the revenue stream is primarily associated with oil. And so, you have good base economics, 375,000 barrels for $5 million or thereabouts, works all day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Well, I appreciate the added color there guys. Thanks so much for your patience with all of us today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And this concludes the time that we have for question-and-answer session today. I would now like to turn the presentation over to Mr. Hackett for closing remarks. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Gerry. I just want to thank everybody for participating today. I appreciate it. I know lots going on in your lives and our lives too. We appreciate all the support. Just be assured that we'll continue to pursue our stakeholder interests in both our strategy and tactics as we proceed through this year and next. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may now disconnect and have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>