<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1405695" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-07-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9232</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer, SVP-Controlling &amp; Finance">Hans Ola Meyer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Ronnie Leten</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Svenska Handelsbanken AB (Broker)">Peder Fr&#xF6;l&#xE9;n</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Frederic Stahl</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Nico P. Dil</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Redburn Partners LLP">James A. Moore</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Swedbank AB /Broker/">Mats Liss</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International Ltd.">Benjamin G. Maslen</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Guillermo Peigneux</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="SG Securities (Paris) SAS">S&#xE9;bastien Gruter</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Most welcome, everybody here in Stockholm, and also of course everyone participating on the telephone conference line, to this presentation of Atlas Copco's second quarter 2011 results.</p>
          <p>We will follow a very well known format. After a few seconds more, I will hand over to our CEO, Ronnie Leten, who will go through the slides that are also available on the Web. On his comments on the first &#x2013; on the second quarter, sorry. And after that, we will have short break for arranging the questions, and then we will mix between questions on the telephone line and questions here in Stockholm.</p>
          <p>So with that, I think I'll hand it over to you, Ronnie, right away.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Hans Ola, and welcome, all of you, to our call on the quarter two results. As usual, I will start immediately with the highlights.</p>
          <p>So as on slide number two, we had fantastic orders received for this quarter. It was, again, a record. So, as it says here on the slide, a very strong organic growth in orders received coming from mining, the manufacturing, and the construction area was a bit slower, but all the rest was really going very well. What this making me really pleased to see that we also have record revenue, remember that we get good order income, but you must also get a doubt, and this time, we really had a very strong revenue with as a result also record operating profit. So that was very good that we saw these three records and I'm very pleased to see that.</p>
          <p>We continue to invest in the market densification is still the message we give to all our people in the field. So field in &#x2013; feet in the street is really an issue and a point where we push on, and of course, the product development and we launching new innovative products continuously. This time it will be the last time we will report in three business areas. So next time, when we standing here, it will be &#x2013; reporting in four legs. You will find at the end of presentation also information about the new four business areas, so you get used to this way of reporting.</p>
          <p>If I go down to the figures like I said, SEK22 billion when it comes to orders received, record high, also the same for the revenue where we come close to the SEK20 billion and an operating margin profit of 20.9%. Hans Ola, when we talk about the bridge, elaborate a bit more on that, but when you look to the operating profit, almost SEK4.2 billion. The rest, again, you can see that. And when it comes to the operating cash flow, also that I will let to Hans Ola when we have a dedicated slide on that, but as you can read, this was heavily affected by financial items.</p>
          <p>Now, I'd like to go to slide number four, when we talk about the total group development in sales. As you see, all continents came up with very high figures. You see all double-digit growth, even all above 20%, with the exception of the South America, and as we all know that that is also the region which came back the fastest after the crisis. But all regions are very strong in their development.</p>
          <p>Then let's go more specific, and we take first one on the Americans. A very strong North America, that is what we have seen, and coming from the mining equipment, but compressors, air treatment, portable industrial compressors, industrial tools that were all strong in that region. And more specifically on the U.S., we had a very strong United States in quarter two. We had a very large mining order in Mexico, but even if we exclude that, I think the region had performed very well. But we see as compared to last quarter that the construction market is, or at least our orders, is softer than in quarter one.</p>
          <p>Let me then look to South America, plus 13%, so a continuation of the development. We see there, maybe a softer growth in Brazil, because that is the biggest market, so that means also that, yes, we only &#x2013; and I can say only plus 13%.</p>
          <p>Let me then go to Europe, a very strong Europe. We saw plus 22%, still the same picture as in Q1. Strong Germany, Scandinavia, very solid, and a very strong Russia, but on the other hand, a soft Southern Europe, and of course, then you talk Spain and Italy. And so, we saw on all type of equipment, we saw good development, but again, a little bit softer on the construction equipment side.</p>
          <p>Then when you look to Africa and Middle East, there is a bit of the mixed picture. The Southern part &#x2013; Central Southern part of Africa, very strong, very solid. Of course, that comes mainly from the mining part. But then the Middle East, North Africa, and you all see the turbulence there, it's a bit softer. Of course, when you look to the figures, plus 55%, you say, what is he talking about softer, but of course it is also influenced by this fuel gas booster order we got in May and which was also announced in a separate press release in Saudi Arabia.</p>
          <p>Let me then go to Asia and Australia. A very robust Asia, increased orders received in all the markets. Maybe when you look &#x2013; you compare the plus 37% with plus 24%, you can say it is that softer. Of course, we compare with a very strong quarter one. So it is sequentially lower in this area, especially when we talk China. So that is &#x2013; but again, it is the second best ever. What we see is a bit of a softer India. That we can say that is this quarter definitely a point to take away. And we see a continuous development of the aftermarket. So that is nice to see, that our 1:1 ratios and climbing the service ladder strategy is really yielding result.</p>
          <p>And Australia, what can I say more? It continues to go driven by the demand in the mining sector. And also that was a fantastic development in quarter two.</p>
          <p>Slide number eight, you see here it's six quarters all above 20, and really, almost the last five always closing close to plus 30%. It may mean also we now go to compare with tougher &#x2013; or the comparison will be tougher because the demand is on a higher level. Then the sales bridge structure changing, so our add-on acquisitions, plus 1%; currency minus, 14%. If you do a quick calculation, SEK2.5 billion that is more or less gone in currency. But what I'm really &#x2013; see and like to see here is the price development. We see here a plus 2%. So it's robustness of the work, what we do in the market and price management. Our innovation really allows us to, yes, the cost inflations, you always have &#x2013; plus with the material, but also on the salary side, really also to bring back to the market, and volume you can see here.</p>
          <p>What is maybe another point to take away, you see here, the book-to-bill. Again, we booked another extra SEK2 billion on the orders on hand.</p>
          <p>We then go by business areas and we take compressor technique, record order intake, plus 27% organic, fantastic portable and industrial compressor sales, but also the air treatment products. We hardly talk about that but were also very strong at this time. And our late cyclical business, the gas and process, also had a very solid demand coming from energy project and air separation projects. And again, the aftermarket, our dedication to work on the 1:1 is also here paying back.</p>
          <p>An operating margin of 23.5%, very strong operating margin, the positive effect you read here on volume and of course the price. And of course, we get the negative effect, the headwind we get from the currency, and a bit of revenue mix, as we are invoicing a bit more equipment than we did in previous quarter. And last but not least, we also have bought some land in India to expand our facilities, and also we are planning to extend our manufacturing capabilities in India.</p>
          <p>I will go to slide number 12, when we talk about construction and mining technique, very strong demand in the mining industry. A bit softer on the construction site, especially when we look to Brazil, India and a bit in China, and I already talked about the record order we got from Pe&#xF1;oles in Mexico, which was always nice to get this type of big orders.</p>
          <p>Continued good development for parts and service, and the consumables, so that's a good continuous business, and we've again a margin above 20%, 20.1%, which was record operating profit for this business area. So that was, again, a very strong result.</p>
          <p>Let me then go to slide number 14, industrial technique. Also here, you see I don't know how many times I've already said record now, but its record order intake, 37% up, strong demand in all customer segments in all major regions, and these major regions are U.S., we see Europe, we say India and we say China. They were really all very strong. Otherwise, you cannot make this plus 37%, you all know that. But also what is nice to see is that even if we had a real currency headwind here as we know that this business area has most of their exposure for manufacturing in Swedish krona, had a profitability of 21.8%. So I'm very pleased to see that.</p>
          <p>So, we see also that our hard work, it is also yielding result and you can see it on slide number 15, that we really have here my favorite V-shape recovery on the operating margin.</p>
          <p>Yes, then the group total, I will not repeat more, but you see the profit before tax, plus 20%, when we compared to last year's same quarter, and basic earnings per share SEK2.46, and return on capital employed, where we are also working on 34%.</p>
          <p>So I would like now to hand over with this to Hans Ola.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ronnie. I will make a few comments on the following slides. If we start by looking at the difference between operating profit and profit before tax, that is represented by the financial net. In this quarter, we have the normal negative net interest, cost of course, of about SEK120 million or exactly SEK120 million.</p>
          <p>We have some negative currency, financial currency differences I should say, but we also, as we write in the report, we have a contribution from selling the RSC shares, the Rental Service shares, that we still own as a legacy from the divestment of that business of SEK75 million plus, all in all SEK96 million negative.</p>
          <p>If we look ahead, everything but, let's say, the interest net is difficult to predict. But on the net interest cost, we estimate that we will be looking in the next couple of quarters at somewhere around minus SEK150 million, as a relatively good guess, could be thereabouts, or slightly higher, but in that region. And then of course, we still own some Rental Service shares that we intend to sell just like we have sold in this quarter and the previous one. If we &#x2013; when we sale those shares, if the rates or the share price on those share stays as it is, it will add roughly SEK100 million, and that might happen in the third quarter, but it can, let's say, also spill over to the fourth quarter, if nothing exceptional happens, of course.</p>
          <p>If we move a little bit further down, of course, we have the tax impact, was slightly higher this quarter than the previous one but not dramatically higher. I think, again, if we look in the next couple of quarters going forward, you should expect somewhere between 26% and 27% in effective tax rate. I think that's what we can see right now.</p>
          <p>We also do what we refer to as a profit bridge versus last year the same quarter. And here, you can see, on slide 17, that the so called flow-through of organic growth, price and volume is coming down to more normalized levels. We've talked a lot about this all quarters after the crisis. And I think now with the 33%, 34%, it's coming, as I said, closer to a more normalized flow-through from the volume increase.</p>
          <p>You can also appreciate the big currency impact both on the revenue line compared to last year, SEK2.4 billion, and as much as SEK915 million on the currency. A majority of that, but let's say it's both transactional effects, meaning that there are currency effects of those SEK915 million a little bit more than half is truly affecting the margin negatively, whereas the rest, SEK400 million or something like that, is a pure translation effect that doesn't have a very big impact at all on the margin.</p>
          <p>So in other words, we can see that compared to last year, this result is about 2% negative effect on the margin compared with last year. When we look at the final column, you can see a slight negative contribution from acquisitions and divestments. And this is related to two of the acquisitions where we yet have to see that the volumes of following the financial crisis haven't really picked up yet. Orders are there to a certain extent, but we are still seeing a negative contribution from those in this particular quarter.</p>
          <p>But I think that the most important thing talking about the big currency impact is of course, look at the sequential situation. We know that our result today, 20.9%, is really with the currency rates that are prevailing in the second quarter. We have no hedge effects or anything like that.</p>
          <p>So when we look at what happened from Q1, we had a negative impact already in the &#x2013; from Q1 to Q2 of about a 0.5 percentage points roughly. And the rest of the slightly lower margin than in Q1 comes from the product mix, as also Ronnie alluded to. To a certain extent, we also had a little bit higher corporate costs in the second quarter, but that should &#x2013; again, if we look ahead, come down to a more normalized SEK150 million negative as our best estimate for the next couple of quarters.</p>
          <p>When we are on the subject of the bridges, when we look at the currency situation today as we speak, we know that that is more favorable currency rates than we had in Q2. However, it will still be negative compared to last year Q3 without any doubt. But when it comes to the effect on the result on the margin, we don't expect that to be very big at all.</p>
          <p>So when we look at the statement we made three months ago that comparing 2011 to 2010, we talked about a negative impact that could be as high as SEK1.5 billion. I would say that that still stands as a rough estimate which means that the second half of the year compared to the second half of 2010 will not, as we see it today, show very much of a negative comparison at all, slightly negative perhaps, but not much at all.</p>
          <p>If we move further, I think I'll pass on the next slide, which is looking at the same situation per business area because as you can see, the so called flow-through is very similar on all three business areas.</p>
          <p>On the balance sheet, not much more &#x2013; well, the most important change if we compare with the beginning of the year is of course on our cash holdings, which is of course related to that in the second quarter, we have paid almost SEK5 billion in dividend and another SEK6 billion in the capital reduction through a mandatory redemption of shares. At the same time, you can appreciate that the higher volumes is also translating into a slightly higher working capital.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, this big capital distribution, and now I'm on Slide 20, has not yielded a dramatic impact on our capital debt structure, so the net debt to EBITDA right now at 30th of June comes, of course, back up again, but only to 0.8%, so the funding and the debt situation is still very favorable and stable I would say.</p>
          <p>And then to a point that perhaps needs a little bit of comment as well. We talked about the cash flow and Ronnie alluded in his highlights about that it is a lower number as we referred to the operating cash flow on slide 21. And you look at the bottom, we say SEK567 million in Q2 versus SEK2.5 billion in the same quarter last year. The main impacts are to be found in the second and the third row of the slide. The change in working capital is of course quite natural since we are now growing dramatically the production levels and the invoicing levels. Actually, I would say that the change in working capital is perfectly in line with the growth of the business. So, we don't see any extra inefficiency in that situation right now.</p>
          <p>The line above, which is net financial items and taxes, has another big impact of about SEK1.3 billion. And as commented in the written report, the main explanation is that we have large bond loans in Atlas Copco and the absolute majority of those interest payments related to that falls in the second quarter and in the fourth quarter, not in the first and the third. So, that means that compared to the strong cash flow of the first quarter, SEK2 billion that we had in Q1, we now see a difference in that respect of about SEK1 billion compared to Q1.</p>
          <p>Compared to last year, man of order would then question why wasn't it the same payments of interest last year. It actually was, but at that time, we had a lower interest cost primarily due to the fact that we were paying variable, very low interest rates at that time. Now we &#x2013; as the interest rate level of the world has gone up, we have locked in the interest rates, but it also means that we pay slightly more. But the big impact is that we also have a currency financial currency hedge of the loans and the equity that we have in the group. And that has swung from a relatively large positive effect on cash flow last year to a big negative impact this year. And that explains almost the whole SEK1 billion of that difference. So we don't foresee anything of these type of flows for the coming quarters.</p>
          <p>When it comes to these rolling of the currency hedges for financing &#x2013; for the loans and for the equity, of course, we cannot predict what the future will be when we have those roll-overs. But I would say the underlying cash generation in the group is nothing particularly worrisome in this respect, so I just needed to point your attention to that. And then you can see the rest of the impact, and of course, compared to last year, we're also investing a little bit more in the plants and our buildings.</p>
          <p>So with that, we can move on. And I hand back the word for the final comments to Ronnie. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So then we come to the last slide before we go to the Q&amp;A, and that is then the outlook. And as you can read here, we expect that the demand remain at current high level. So that I would like to stop here, Hans Ola, and then immediately go to the questions, which I assume, there will be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Excellent. So we have questions coming in through the telephone conference and we will surely have questions here. If the operator can repeat the procedures for the Q&amp;A session, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you very much. I think we will start here in Stockholm then, and let the questions on the conference call get organized. Yes, first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peder Fr&#xF6;l&#xE9;n at Handelsbanken Capital Markets. A couple of questions on your outlook, please. First of all, are you talking about the sales or order volumes? And in the outlook of, call it, flattish demand on high level, could you please help us out with the split between the base business, the aftermarkets? Is it so that you have received a normal amount of large-size orders here in the second quarter and the first? That's the first question on the outlook.</p>
          <p>Second question on the outlook, obviously it's the construction that has not been growing sequentially and I guess that's also the segment where you see not contributing to demand quarter-on-quarter. Could you mention some of the segments that are contributing?</p>
          <p>Finally on the outlook, in China in particular, could you help us out there which segments are the strongest and the weakest in the quarter and ahead? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hans, I suggest you start with giving a definition about our outlook mainly...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, absolutely, the outlook is and has always been the order, let's say, the focus on the order situation, which means that what we tried to predict is the demand from our customers. It's not the projection of how much sales we will have, or revenues or indeed even order intake. It's an estimate of how the demand situation will develop from now throughout the third quarter. And so it's not the comparison with previous year either just to make that very, very clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So then if we try to explain, to answer questions, I think when it comes to the aftermarket level, which was the first one, and I've &#x2013; we also stressed it a bit, we see still a very good momentum. We have not reached 100%, 1:1 reach. We are still &#x2013; have space in climbing the service level, and you've also seen during what we said we make a new organization. You've seen also us to make specific service organization, because we really believe in that concept that we can harvest much more in the Parts and Service business, as we have already done. Without saying that we have not done a good job before, but there is more to take. So &#x2013; and especially when you take on the Asian side, it is really going in a good, very solid level.</p>
          <p>Then do we have more larger orders than we have in quarter one? I've not calculated because first, we are not the company who is really having a lot of large orders. And once we have it, we are very proud to let you know. Likely that the Mexican order and the fuel gas boost than in quarter one, when it comes to China in the air separation order we had.</p>
          <p>I think &#x2013; when I just take China as that comparison, we look to that than the big difference between quarter one and quarter two is that couple large orders we had, which we had not in quarter two. Will that say that we will not get large order in quarter three? I don't know. I know that we are working on big orders, but when they fall, I don't why. Then &#x2013; well, most probably, if I knew that I was not standing here, I suppose. So on that one, I would not make &#x2013; that is not my biggest thing, what I'm looking for, where are the big orders, although we like to say that.</p>
          <p>Then when it comes to the outlook and when you read also our document, our press release, you see that on the construction side, we said sequentially we have seen a softer development, and that's mainly coming from Brazil, India, and China where we see not the same momentum as we had in quarter two. Is it a bit seasonal? It could be. We all know that that is the, say, first months in the year. It's always a bit stronger than the other part, it could be. It could be also we all read the same index as we see also that market is not really taking off. So that is &#x2013; which segments are then contributing? Of course, mining, that is without saying. But I see still a good development in the industrial part. I will not in this time, not talk about my canaries, but they do still well. And I see also in the industrial technique side, so the general industry is doing well. And that is also what &#x2013; I see maybe it will sound maybe as a surprise but that's also what we see in U.S. I see a very strong manufacturing part in U.S.</p>
          <p>Then, yes, the weakest is, a bit, Construction segment and the strongest for me is that &#x2013; is the Mining and the Industrial part. And I see and that is also what made us talking about the outlook. I see that if we take it as a group, may be that and you listen a bit in the total demand, that maybe we comment a bit of a breathing moment, that I tried to guide us that we go more asymptotic development than constant calling linear, calling up plus 20%, plus 30%, that I think will be &#x2013; I think the world cannot cope with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We had one more questions here. Yes? Eric?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I will start with &#x2013; Frederic here from UBS. I'll start with one for you, Hans Ola. The gross margins have been going up and down last year, I think if you look at the last four quarters. Is it fair to assume that this is primarily due to the mix between aftermarket and equipment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That it was weaker in this quarter you mean or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's gone up and down I think the last four quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Now it's, of course, extremely difficult to predict exactly the timing of when you see these effects, but you're right. Our interpretation is of course that you get to a certain extent you are affected by the continuous currency slide that happens between these quarters. But the change and the mix between aftermarket and equipment sales is now starting to be quite significantly different than previous quarters, and I would say there is the main impact, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then I had a question for you, Ronnie. You mentioned your canaries. You're a bit more cautious on construction in Brazil, India, China. Could you talk a bit about the &#x2013; your canaries? What are they telling you? You mentioned the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was giving Peder already an up-start on that. I think that's small- to medium-size business &#x2013; if I see today, because that &#x2013; okay, I'm not talking further, but they were really doing very well. I think it was some are for them, so that &#x2013; and that we see in most &#x2013; almost all markets that this good development on the industrial part because that is mainly the industrial part, let me say, and that is doing well and that was also a bit of a surprise when you think and when you read about U.S., and you see then me talking what is this? What is he talking about? So that is &#x2013; yes, I can only talk what I see and they do &#x2013; the medium-size compressor do very well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we then take the next question from the telephone conference? And then, we'll come back to Stockholm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The first telephone question comes from the line of Nico Dil. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, gentleman. This is Nico Dil from JPMorgan. I'd like to ask three questions, please. The first part is really sort of what has changed in the last few weeks in the mindset of your customers, which has made just sort of take down your outlook statement? I'd just like to get a bit more flavor on your outlook statement. You highlighted in the previous comment that it's just an outlook statement for Q3. But if it's just construction equipment, which is turning a notch lower, whilst you have the growth of the company, so industrial and mining still doing relatively well, it comes across as a relatively conservative outlook statement to me. Just wondering whether I'm reading you well.</p>
          <p>Number two is, on the step-up in the revenue, if I look at it sequentially I'm just trying to understand the sequential incrementals a bit better. Even if there was 0.5% of a negative impact on the currency, you're still sitting at a sequential incremental margin or drop-through of about 15%, which seems sort of a lot lower than what we're seeing 35% sort of year-on-year. I wonder whether you can give us a little bit more qualification around that?</p>
          <p>And then, sort of lastly, looking at your inventories, you highlighted that this is a normal course of action in this type of environment. I sort of looked back in the last 13 years, and this is the second time I see such a big relative step-up in inventories. I wonder whether you could qualify that a little bit more as well. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe we can start with the last to answer that. And then, Hans Ola, if you can take revenue...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I will take then the customer mind. Yes, I think what &#x2013; when you come to the inventory and you make a more analysis, and Hans Ola had already talked about that when he was explaining the cash flow, of course, what we see when it comes to the whole mining part, there is a lot in the pipeline into our customers and to get commission. So that is the main, main reason why you see an absolute &#x2013; the business or the inventory going up. But when you take it on an aggregated level, it's relative &#x2013; and the way we calculate internally, it is in days. So, it's relative &#x2013; in relation to the business development. So, that is &#x2013; it is not getting better. I agree on that side, which I would like to see that we get some efficiency in inventory, but on the other hand, it's not getting worse. It's rather on the same level as it was before, but it's more, of course, significant more money, that one. Maybe, Hans Ola, if you can take sequential...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you talked about the sequential drop-through and I understand the question that even with currency between Q1 and Q2, why didn't you get more profit out of it? Well, the main &#x2013; I think I answered on a previous question as well that we have a continuous change of the mix of what we sell, specifically if you look at the invoicing or the revenue composition and that is that we are now catching up the output and the invoicing of some of the bigger order. So let's say big equipment, whatever the size of the order was. And that is, of course, not giving a positive impact on the flow-through.</p>
          <p>There is also &#x2013; as I mentioned, even though it's not a huge significance, but all the small bits and pieces put together, I mentioned a slightly higher corporate cost in the second quarter than the first quarter. It's not a huge impact but it still explains a few trends of the percent on that if you compare it. And as a more general comment perhaps is that we are now working at, as Ronnie has said many, many times, we are at record levels in terms of both order intake and in terms of invoicing. And of course, at such a rapid pickup, as we have seen in the last 12 to 18 months, it is of course not so easy to, every three months period, see the same efficiency in that build-up of volumes.</p>
          <p>So you were quite right in your observation that the flow-through is clearly lower than what we have seen lately, if you compare it sequentially. But it's not something that reveals for us anything of a huge surprise when you see the product mix and the other, and the speed at which we had picked up the volumes of output. So it drives a few extra costs in these processes when the increase is very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, then your question, Nico, on the customer mind change or is there a change? Okay, I'm known talking general. I don't think that there is significant much change, especially when you talk about, say, the Northern part of the world. But the reason why we really changed slightly, or say of somewhat, I should maybe use that word, is that we are very good and that our outlook is mainly that we see that we're on a very high level and we feel also that when you look to certain market, like Brazil and India that you get the bit of a softer development, so many even growing, but at a lower pace, and some of them are even falling down a bit on that.</p>
          <p>So that was the reason why we changed &#x2013; I said maybe you can express it that &#x2013; maybe the customers need a bit of breathing moment to catch up with the real recovery where we are because if you look to our figures and our segments, we are definitely above peak. And we all remember, maybe if you go to back to peak, you see how it really is increasing because you need more people, the war of talent and all these things that are definitely coming back and if that made that it takes a bit of time to do a step-up with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And next question on the telephone conference, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of James Moore. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good afternoon, everybody. It's James Moore at Redburn. One currency &#x2013; one question on currency and one on the outlook, if I could. Just trying to understand your currency comments, if we see a SEK1.5 billion impact for the year, I think that leaves hardly anything for the second half, it would be like SEK40 million. And I think your translation was 14% in the quarter. Now given where rates are, you could see 4%, 5%, 6% in the second half. Is that because you're going to see a transaction positive in the second half? Just trying to understand why there isn't perhaps a bit more headwind from currency. And in terms of the outlook, I see from the statement you talk about the fact that orders in Asia at the group level were below revenue. Is that the case that you had a negative book-to-bills in some of these countries like China or in Brazil and India?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Should I start with the currency then to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you can start there...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think you gave most of the answers yourself, James, that we have in second half of last year quite a sliding situation when it comes to basically all important currencies except for, let's say, the euro didn't move very much against the Swedish krona, but not only the dollar, but many of them. And that gives us an adjustment &#x2013; a negative adjustment also on what we refer to some times as the revaluation of receivables in the balance sheet. And that was the case second half of last year.</p>
          <p>Even though the average rates are still somewhat negative, as you say, quite rightly if they stay up today's levels, we will not have that other negative impact this year. This is why we believe that it will only be marginally negative impact compared to the second half last year when it comes to the results. When it comes to top line translation effects, yes, you're right that it will continue to be somewhat negative comparisons, also for the second half of the year, but substantially less than for Q2, just as you said yourself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, when it comes to the outlook, James, and specifically, when it comes to Asia, see the difference between revenue and orders received this quarter was more than SEK2 billion. So we had a book-to-bill which was more than 1.1. And also in Asia, it's still that we have a plus one book-to-bill area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in some of these countries, you're talking about like China, and India, and Brazil. That also hasn't gone backwards?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think if you see &#x2013; I think Korea, also and you should not &#x2013; if you take Asia, the markets I have in my head in that case is India, China, Korea, and then you take the Singapore region. They are above one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we go back to Stockholm now for a question, and then we come back to the conference call questions later? Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Mats Liss, Swedbank. A couple of questions. First, coming back to China I guess, there's been structural changes going on there, especially within the mining sector, and I was just, well, trying to get a feel of if you sort of are left behind. I refer to Joy Global's acquisition and maybe Sandvik earlier on. If you, well, could give some comments regarding that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you want to comment me that we are left behind then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean you're talking about China and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think we saw that what these movements which was going on. Now, you should see when it comes to the mining part and where we are strong in China, it's definitely not all the same segments as Joy is strong. I think we have a lot on the quarries and cements. We have I think in the larger construction work when it comes to other hydropower and other infrastructure works, where you need some special drilling, that is the main part where we are work. And then, of course, you have the other part when it comes to the mining. But that's what Joy was head-to-head to call, and our exposure to coal which is significant less than some of our colleagues nearby here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And specifically underground coal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And underground coal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sounds good. And then just about the order backlog here, if you could give some, well, indication about pricing of orders compared to what you have invoiced during the second quarter. And maybe also, I mean you show a positive book-to-bill here and if you could, well, just confirm it, that there aren't any difficulties seen in the supply chains that have affected your invoicing during the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think I said the figure when it comes to sequential improvement of the output of the factory. I think we had again a bit is around 10% why we call it. So we get definitely the factory is speeding up. And you see we had almost SEK20 billion invoice. So given the currency, you see how much volume increase it is, plus 27%. So on that &#x2013; of course, there is stress still in the supply chain for sure, that, but it is not one specific item. It's not much change compared to the previous situation. Of course, our purchase, people need to do their job. But I cannot use that as an argument that there should be more outcome. That is not -- we have done incremental investments.</p>
          <p>As you've also seen our cash flow that we have done of course these measures we have already. Some of them we had already taken last year. And actually a couple of weeks ago, we also approved couple other investments for machining tools, so this will go on. You've seen India, where we go on, we had a couple of projects going on, in China to expand, so these things are going and some already put &#x2013; are on already in practice, others there are still to come. So that works fine.</p>
          <p>When it comes to pricing, I'm rather confident. There is nothing in the order portfolio that there is something, which can really affect the margin when it comes to prices. Now I'm rather confident and that was also the reason when I was talking about the bridge to highlight that it is good price management that is a good discipline on that part that what we sell is done at the right value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's see if there are anymore &#x2013; then I think we go back to the telephone conference questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Ben Maslen. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon, Ronnie and Hans. It's Ben Maslen from Merrill Lynch. Two questions please, firstly, Hans Ola, just to come back to currency, in previous quarters you've often broken down the currency impact into kind of P&amp;L impact, and then a balance sheet effect due to the kind of negative impact of revaluation of receivables and payables or so forth. I wonder if you could give us a split for this quarter, so we can understand the moving parts.</p>
          <p>And then secondly on compressive technique, as you say, the incremental margins or drop-through in your bridge analysis has started to come down towards 35%. Is that a sustainable level do you think going forward? And then albeit to that when the large gas and process deliveries really start to kick in, how big a negative impact actually that will have on the overall CT margin? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if we &#x2013; again, I think I made a comment on one of the slides that the big SEK900 million impact with the currency rates of second quarter 2010 that we talked about SEK900 million, a little bit more than half of that is true &#x2013; you &#x2013; I think that's what you refer to when you say P&amp;L effect or margin impact or a true currency difference. And then, the other one is more when you revalue, let's say, the numbers or just translate them. Both sales and profits and everything is a little bit less than half than of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So &#x2013; and that gives the impact on the margin of about two percentage points compared to last year. When it comes to the flow-through of the incremental profit of coming down towards 30%, yes, it's impossible to say what is absolutely a normality, but considering that we are now with a 2% price increase environment right now, we have no reason to believe that that will evaporate very quickly like Ronnie said in the near future. Then I think that that is the level or round about that is the level where we can expect to be going forward.</p>
          <p>So, of course, what will impact is that we sell more and we invoice more and more of the equipment, and as you said, also more and more of big equipment. But at the same time, of course, we are growing the aftermarket and we are growing also the yellow canaries in terms of volume. So there is a balancing effect of that. With the pricing component, as I said, at this level, I think that 30% is still achievable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Maybe just a follow-up on CT. Thanks for that. The orders are running well ahead of the revenues. How fast a ramp-up would you expect in sales to catch up with the order figure through the back end of this year? I mean, it is some &#x2013; are you capacity-constrained at the moment? Will it run into next year or do you think you can do it fairly quickly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you've seen and I've already hinted when you compare sequentially quarter one to quarter two to ramp up a production, which is then already at a good level, yes, that takes time. So, you should more or less expect the same type of change what you have seen between quarter one, quarter two. I think that is a very pragmatic approach you could say. So it will take us a bit of time before we are &#x2013; yes, on a book-to-bill for one, assuming, of course, if the book-to-bill goes &#x2013; if the orders received goes further, yes, then really have another challenge on that part. But it will &#x2013; still a bit time of that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have still some questions on the telephone line. I think we have time to take one more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Guillermo Peigneux. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. It's Guillermo Peigneux from Morgan Stanley. Maybe a couple of questions. One, regarding currency again, so I'm sorry. But I'm just trying to understand, in terms of what I've seen in the spot markets what we've seen in reported accounts, there a big sort of gap between sort of currencies or the Swedish krona actually starting to depreciate, and actually your accounts saw a larger impact into the second quarter compared to the first quarter and this is obviously even if you adjust for currency movements with the last year. So I was wondering whether you could explain why this deterioration into the second quarter compared to the first one actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why the number is bigger in the second quarter compared to the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, despite the fact that the spots are actually moving on the right direction?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think if you follow, for example, the dollar development last year, you will see that it was a strengthening in the second quarter actually, and that we have not seen this year if you look at this as an average rate. So I would argue that we have worse currency situation in Q2 versus Q1 this year, and it was the opposite last year. So I'm not 100% convinced we see the same rates, but we might dive into that discussion after the call perhaps. Mattias also is prepared to help you through that I'm sure.</p>
          <p>So I can't give you any specific reason that there is a huge mix change or something like that. But when you go down to each country, each currency, of course it's not exactly the same every quarter. So that might have explained some of these movements that you have difficulty of seeing from an outside-in perspective. But this is where we stand, but I repeat again that the most important thing for us at least is to look at what are the rates now compared to where they were in Q2. And as Ronnie also said initially, they are more favorable now than what we saw in Q2. And that is, of course, giving us some comfort going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Definitely understood. I was wondering, then maybe a follow-up, and given the fact that at the moment you sort of mentioned that your pricing is running at 2% maybe per quarter, I was wondering whether that is basically what we should expect for the second half of the year, or maybe in some of your markets, you sort of still expect to increase prices, for example, mining?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think and if you look to our historical track record on that part, you would see more or less when the market is a real supply market or a demand market, depending on where you are, we will get more or less the same development as we got &#x2013; when you look a couple of years back. Of course, it is much easier when material prices and inflation is in the air to increase prices.</p>
          <p>And second, as you all know, that is one of the reasons why we push so hard &#x2013; one of the reasons why we push so hard on product development, is also to do a very good price management to sell really value to our customers. And I've already answered when someone asked me about the order book and what it's about, is the quality of the pricing on that part. I think that is more or less the same as we got, say, the last two quarters. So, you can more or less expect more or less the same development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And then last maybe on large gas and process compressors. You mentioned that there's a degree of slowdown, especially when regards to Asia. And I was wondering also were you adding capacity in China, precisely in large gas and process. Is it the case that it's just a temporary slowdown or you're basically at the moment happy with the trend in activity or with the way you're adding capacity in Asia at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't mention, if I recall, otherwise, I didn't talk about the slowdown of gas and process in China. What I only said in one of the question is that we did not get a large order in quarter two for gas and process compared to quarter one. So that is one thing. Second, to answer your question, as we've ramped up our capacity for gas and process in China, is definitely for getting already the orders on hand to get that out in a good way. Otherwise, we should have invested in capacity, maybe U.S. or in Europe, where we felt we should do this capacity increase in China.</p>
          <p>So, but on the gas and process, as already said in the beginning of the call, it's a late cyclical business and we see good orders first, but also good quotation levels especially when it comes to energy projects, air separation projects, and I'm sure also the LNG business will come back very soon, but that last one is more a speculation statement from myself talking about nuclear power and all that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All the capacity is going to add, let's say, incremental growth, organic growth or is that cannibalizing some of your European capacity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you repeat again, Guillermo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. All that capacity that you're putting up in China, is that generating organic growth on your revenues from the CT or is actually, in a way, cannibalizing some of the orders you are supplying from Europe at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The whole thing is of course to get more capacity in that area because that is &#x2013; because that is &#x2013; because we, if you have seen our track record on the gas and process one over the last five years, it is always having gone up, of course, beside the 2009 period. But we still see a continuous development in the demand for this type of compressors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I think we take the final question from the telephone conference, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The final question comes from the line of S&#xE9;bastien Gruter. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. S&#xE9;bastien Gruter from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. I've three questions. On Construction Technique, I've noticed that there was no price increase over the past quarters. I just wonder, how do you feel about your pricing for in this new division? Second question on SG&amp;A, you mentioned that you're investing in the business, but we have not seen a significant step-up in marketing expenses or R&amp;D in the quarter. So should we expect this to come in the next quarters?</p>
          <p>And final question is on &#x2013; in Mining and Rock Excavation division, we have seen a sharp sequential growth in orders over the best four or five quarters or so, and it stopped in Q2. Are we reaching a plateau in the level of demand for this division? Or is it due to capacity constraints on your side? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I don't know if I understood your first question, but I think it was about construction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you have the pricing power as far as I understood the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, in Construction Technique?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think when it comes to construction technique, which is organized around three divisions, where the majority, the largest one is our portable energy part, definitely we have pricing power with our presence and also with our product range. When it comes to Dynapac, the Rollers and the Paver business, that is another question, and we are working hard to get there, also a more &#x2013; a stronger I should say, a stronger position. But there is still some work to do. We are working hard now to increase our product portfolio in Asia and that will take us, yes, a couple, maybe a year or two years before we are on that part.</p>
          <p>When it comes to our marketing cost and design and development, maybe you don't see everything, but we definitely invest in feet in the street. So what they all said densification, dig deeper, we are hiring more and more sales people where we feel it is needed, and not only for equipment, but also for aftermarket. So, that, we do. And we also do more and more design work in the emerging markets, which is then &#x2013; I mean primarily India and China.</p>
          <p>So these investments we do. And I think the costs are going up in more less in relation to our revenue increase. So that is more or less in the same line. And if you see, if you go up plus 27%, 25%, you cannot have a design and development department going up plus 25%. You cannot cope with that increase in your design and development. But we're investing in that.</p>
          <p>Then when it comes to the mining and rock excavation, it's not capacity. I think we still can do more although in certain areas, we &#x2013; like when it comes to consumables, we are running definitely three shifts and even some of them in the weekend, but as you know we also have there last year also made an investment. We are implementing the investment, which is going on, and we do the same in China where we have also increased our capacity for mining and rock excavation.</p>
          <p>So on floor space, definitely we do not lack any capacity. When it comes &#x2013; when you compare quarter one with quarter two, where you said the orders received is sequentially not developing, I would not immediately look after any reason that that is slowing down. And that part, I have not heard that saying when it comes to the mining part.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I think we have exhausted the questions for the time being. But of course, we are ready to take further questions as the Summer progresses, should anyone be at work. But I thank you very much for today for attending both the telephone conference and here in Stockholm. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>