<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1364639" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-02</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9232</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Hans Ola Meyer, Senior Vice President Controlling and Finance</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Ronnie Leten, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Nico Dil</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Anders Roslund</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Peder Fr&#xF6;l&#xE9;n</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Frederic Stahl</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">James Moore</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Mats Liss</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Guillermo Peigneux</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Paul Butler</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Colin Gibson</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Samson Edmunds</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and welcome everybody to Operaterassen here in Stockholm and the presentation of Atlas Copco's Fourth Quarter Results or should I say welcome to another nice chapter in the saga of Atlas Copco because that I think is appropriate sometime to see it like.</p>
          <p>Without further ado, I will just repeat what we normally do, we have a few introductory words by our CEO, Ronnie Leten and then we will open up for questions-and-answers, of course, as usual and we will alternate between the Operaterassen here in Stockholm and the people that are also very much welcome to the conference call on the web and on telephone.</p>
          <p>So with that, I think I leave it over to Ronnie to take us through the report.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Hans Ola. Welcome in &#x2013; here in Stockholm and also the people listening in. Good afternoon. I would like to go through it the presentation and as usually I'll make sure I don't lose you during the presentation. So, I will refer to the number of the slides where I'm.</p>
          <p>So, I will go immediately to slide number two heading quarter four highlights. It was again, like already Hans Ola said, a very strong order growth for quarter four. We see a very solid demand in the mining business. We see a continuation in the emerging markets. And if we try to express that the sequential improvement you can say it around 4% compared to the good quarter we had already in quarter three. It's a bit annoying to say it, but it was again record operating profit.</p>
          <p>We were debating about, in other word about record, but it was again a very solid profit, but what I'm personally most proud of is what we write down here is that, this time. And it's the first time ever that all business areas had an operating margin of more than 20%. And that is something we should not forget, its maybe, let's hope that we continue to explore that debt rates, but I'm extremely proud to be able to say that.</p>
          <p>We keep investing in the market organization, feet on the street, identifying our network, setting up new customer centers. This time we had Mali, where we really make sure that we dig deep into the African market and of course, we extend over capacity in production. We also proposed a dividend of SEK 4 and at the same time, a redemption of SEK 5 per share, which is a capital distribution of around BSEK 11. And at the end of the outlook, I'll take the opportunity to give you an update and more deeper dive of our goals for sustainable profitable development.</p>
          <p>Figures in summary, I will not go through all the figures, but we see 28% organic growth, operating profit increased 64%, which I think already compared to a good solid profit last year is extra 64% is a real strong achievement.</p>
          <p>Operating margin, 20.7%, people who already read the text, you can see that this was influenced by a revaluation of an option liability and Hans Ola will take the opportunity later in the presentation to explore or explain that a bit what it is. It was a bit less than 1% that effect. And then I think another one, but I'll take that also when I talk about compressor, I think it's also we had more equipment &#x2013; sales of equipment invoicing.</p>
          <p>Operating cash flow, again a very strong BSEK 2.5 in the quarter. So, from the figures point of view, I think there are many high figures on this slide. Orders received from a geographical point of view; here what to take away from is all last three months compared to previous year are above 20%. And it's no surprise when we were talking about the emerging markets, but look this time to Europe, plus 20%.</p>
          <p>We take then Q4 for the Americans, North America; we see a continuous good development coming from a very strong mining industry, but also the manufacturing area, the manufacturing sector also really delivered very well this quarter.</p>
          <p>And if I highlight again on the percentages, you see it also plus 47%, we know also that of course, it took a bit &#x2013; quarter four last year was already a bit higher up. So, you can see that we had for the full year 50% and this time 47%; that it is really a good strong continuation in North America.</p>
          <p>South America, very stable development and also here we know also that it was maybe two quarters earlier that the increase came, so that's the reason also why we see a plus 26%, where we had the full-year 40%.</p>
          <p>Europe, a bit of a mixed view. If I start in the East, a very strong Russia I mentioned already in quarter three, but I really see good development in Russia in quarter four. And I think also 2011; it looks very good for Russia. East Europe was solid; it's still a bit soft on the infrastructure construction part of our business. And I think the further you go south in Europe, yes, the less good it is if I say <mark type="inaudible" />. We see some positive signs but not really at the level what we can say very &#x2013; that we would be very happy.</p>
          <p>Africa, very solid &#x2013; a very solid South Africa. Middle &#x2013; Central Africa was very strong I'll say, and it comes really from our mining customers. And then we had also a very solid Middle East in this quarter.</p>
          <p>Asia continues &#x2013; remains &#x2013; remain high. I think the volume is coming there. Construction and mining equipment is doing well. We see also for the small-to-medium size compressors, and you know this is my yellow canary to sense the market. It is good. Development is there, and also good development for the industrial tools mainly coming from the NBI, but also from the GI business and this in India as well as in China. And what can I say about Australia, it goes on as long of course as the mining business is developing I think also Australia is doing extremely well for us.</p>
          <p>I will go then to the sales bridge, slide number nine, the takeaways you see the first may be on the total quarter figures, the book-to-bill, one, that it's not normal, normally we would have expected in this quarter one bit less than one meaning that we will have more revenue than orders received, but even with the high revenue level the orders received were matching it so that is a very good sign.</p>
          <p>And if you take the volume figures you see also for the full-year 28% and for the quarter 27%; that means that it is a good continuation of the demand. May be the only &#x2013; and we all know as we talk in Swedish krona you see the currency saw the translation effect was a 4% in the quarter and also for the full-year. One, if we are anyhow in the record period BSEK 75 is again a record for the Group, so we never had so many orders received so that is also nice to say.</p>
          <p>Revenues on &#x2013; and then capital employed, here we see all the operating margin by the different business areas and you see the ROCE levels they're back, where they were pre-crisis and the Group here at 19.9%, which is for the year fantastic achievement.</p>
          <p>Business areas &#x2013; is solid; Compressor Technique, a good demand for stationary &#x2013; compressors &#x2013; stationary and portable compressors. A bit softer on the larger sides; so the gas and process part was, if we take it really sequentially, was a bit softer but on the other hand we saw a very solid aftermarket. So, there is a good underlying business and as already mentioned, small-to-medium size business is growing on as already before.</p>
          <p>23.7%, it's a second best ever. So, of course, some of you have been comparing with quarter three, and you remember that I said something to remember, but this 23.7% is a very solid margin for this business and it's the second best and I want to repeat that. And we also, in this quarter, we see also a higher share of equipment revenue, so the mix was not so favorable as it was in quarter three. But really the efficiency improvements, the volume, the price giving this operating margin as of this year.</p>
          <p>I'm going out to slide number 13, a fantastic CMT, Construction and Mining coming from a very strong development in equipment and aftermarket sales, 39% up organic. We also are very proud to see a good development on the equipment sales for roads and as the Dynapac in China and we announced that also a couple of weeks ago that we had a large order there.</p>
          <p>So, it's fantastic to see that, so that market is also coming and developing. And then, again highest ever, the operating margin higher than 20% &#x2013; 20.1% to be correct coming again from a good volume, good price and also working hard on always doing better. And here, we have opened the customer center in Mali and also we announced a couple of weeks ago one of our largest investment we ever did in one plant, actually here in Sweden, Fagersta for MSEK 450 in production capacity for our consumable business.</p>
          <p>I will go now to slide number 15, Industrial Technique. A very solid demand, very positive in Asia, as already mentioned for China and India, and an operating margin 21.9%. We all remember, last year when I got many questions about this business, really we have developed very well here, and of course, also coming from a good volume, but also working hard on the cost saving. And we are very proud that we also had awarded the iF design for the tool you see here on the picture, which also prove that we are also leading in design and development.</p>
          <p>And this is my favorite slide, slide number 16, where I want to show that the V-shape, although I didn't believe in that but that the V-shape is possible also in profitability terms.</p>
          <p>Then the overview of the total quarter and as well as the year, operating margins or operating profit plus 64%, for the year 53%, BSEK 13.9 operating margin it's also the highest ever, and earnings per share, SEK 8.16.</p>
          <p>I'd like to hand over here to Hans Ola, who will give you a bit more in-depth on the financials and then we come back. Yes, I think so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Just a few short comments to add on to Ronnie's. You have seen that we commented and Ronnie already mentioned that we have the specific provision related to long-term employee option plans and share performance plans in the corporate items in the quarter. It's not because we've got the few questions already, it's not related to any provisions for variable compensation, bonuses or salary increases of that sort.</p>
          <p>It's purely that the option plans that have been awarded, the options that have been awarded to managers in the group for the last years, is hedged by the &#x2013; or I should say, these options have been issued of course, at exercise prices dramatically lower than today and according to the accounting rules we have then to adjust for that cost if we would have to buy the shares and deliver them to these employees.</p>
          <p>However, we have on the other hand at the same time as we signed these options few years ago, we have also bought Atlas Copco shares, but unfortunately we are not allowed to hedge the gain on the shares against this re-calculation of the liability that has to be booked as an administrative cost. So, you will not see the good part which is an increase of the equity net of the same amount but you see gross reported the increase of the liability which is seen as a remuneration cost to employees long-term. So, it's nothing that has changed in the quarter, it's a phenomenon that we have every quarter where this is valued to the current share price.</p>
          <p>So, that is the impact which was somewhere in the order of MSEK 150 plus in the quarter, if you compare it with last year and actually if you compare it with a quarter before as well. So, I leave that &#x2013; with that. When it comes to our financial items below the operating profit, we had a relatively low financial cost of MSEK 87 in the quarter but if we look at the core interest cost that was about MSEK 130 negative. And that is somewhere in the order of what we expect also in the next couple of quarters to be. It will probably be a gradual increase from that level, so somewhere touching up to MSEK 150 is probably a good guess for the next couple of quarters, if nothing dramatic happens on the currency sides of course.</p>
          <p>When it comes to taxes, which is another repeating story, we recorded slightly below 26% as paid &#x2013; as a tax rate in this quarter and 26.3% for the year. I think, again that is relatively well the run rate of what one should expect for next year perhaps 26% to 27% is a good estimate for the coming period.</p>
          <p>Let's see if I can change &#x2013; move this, there yah, move it. Another comment that we have is that, we publish this profit bridge every time, and if some of you recall the comments we made in the last two quarters in July and October, we have pointed at this what we call the flow through effect of higher volume and prices on revenues, how much of that is actually compared to last year falling through to the operating profit.</p>
          <p>And now, you can see that, that's 39% in this quarter, whereas in Q2 and Q3, some of you remember that this was approaching almost 100%. So, we feel that we are now entering in the area, where we have more of a normal situation coming out of the very dramatic fall in the market in 2009 and then short recovery. It's perhaps more interesting to look at the &#x2013; the three business areas, but I won't make too many comments, I can only again point that that you see that all of the three business areas have come down and have &#x2013; are approaching I'd say a more normal incremental profit on volume development. So, if you add to that the corporate surprise that I just talked about then you get what we saw on the previous slide, this 39% there.</p>
          <p>When I look at the balance sheet myself, I don't see anything that surprises me. You can all appreciate that we have grown and hence the working capital of inventory receivables have gone up, but you can also see that we are accumulating cash and we will come back to that of course, later on what we will do with that. The currency impact on the balance sheet is about 4% negative. So, otherwise the increase would have been slightly higher than what you see here.</p>
          <p>The strength of the balance sheet; we have talked about a lot, and of course I won't need to comment it so much now. And you will rather see what will happen with the capital distribution come May and June, but of course, it signals that we have an earnings-to-debt ratio, that is extremely solid.</p>
          <p>Finally cash flow; another quarter that came in where we at least were expecting it to come somewhere in this region, and it's very easy to detect also here that the big difference versus last year was that we were releasing capital from the receivables and inventories and now as growth to come back, we are tying up some capital in this. And that make up actually much more than the explanation of the drop in operating cash flow.</p>
          <p>I think with that I hand over to you again, Ronnie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Yes, I'd like to say one point when we look to this cash flow is when you look to the total cash flow and you take the column, January, December 2010, 2009, and you bring this two together, it's BSEK 24 we've been able to generate as operation cash flow. As we all know that we have been investing in design and development, we have been investing in capacity, we have done the acquisitions we need to do and we still are able to deliver this amount of money, you can see what type of business we are in.</p>
          <p>Let me then quickly go to the highlights and I think for 2010 strong recovery in all business areas in all regions. I remember when I was standing here 12 months ago, I was not so sure that it will be such a fantastic year as we had we kept investing in the market presence &#x2013; densify, densify &#x2013; and also our production capacity especially in the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>Specific point, third bullet point is the investment &#x2013; continuous investment to improve the energy efficiency of our products of our customers. And this is one of the key success factors of our company that we continues drive for energy efficiency and everything what we do. And the rest, I think you all have seen this figures already in previous slides, and of course, the proposed redemption and dividend you can read yourself and you can see how much money it is.</p>
          <p>And then you here have the overall slide, where you see that from a revenue point of view, we are not back on the level where we were pre-crisis. We can say 2008, although the crisis started end of 2008, but when you take the other slide or the other graph, operating profit you see definitely that we are above the 2008 levels.</p>
          <p>So in summary, I'd say a fantastic 2010. But this is history. Redemption and dividend and earnings per share, when you look also here over the last &#x2013; I'll say 13 years, you see a constant positive development, also here you see that the last three years 2007, 2008 and '09, we had a SEK 3 dividend where we now stepped up to SEK 4.</p>
          <p>So, I think if you take it more from a development point of view, you can say that the SEK 4 was more or less in line of our performance. And then of course, we have the redemption. So, that is the figures now looking ahead and one of the &#x2013; maybe most read slides in this presentation is always then the comparison of previous time. We see still a good development in the emerging market. It goes on as it was going on in previous quarters.</p>
          <p>On top of that a strong mining industry; so that is going on also. And maybe one takeaway or a bit of a difference is that in some mature markets and more specific in North America there we see recently a very solid improvement and you've also seen when I was commenting on North America that we have also already in quarter four a very solid development.</p>
          <p>So, that was this part of the presentation, and then I'd like to go to the long expected comments from our side when it comes to the update of our goals for sustainable profitable development. But before I go to more detail on the different goals, I'd like to give you a bit of an historical perspective, where are we coming from? And what we've tried to do this in these four graphs here, is to give you a bit of a perspective of last 20 years, the last 10 years and the last 5 years. Where are we? What have we done? Is this really a good performance? And if you take the revenue growth, you see over the last 20 years, we're cruising around 8% growth.</p>
          <p>If you then take the graph below that to return on capital employed, you see a constant good development on the operating margin and at the same time a good usage of the capital employed, which also then give us a constant improvement the more it come to the recent years of the return on capital, we see we've 29%.</p>
          <p>Operating cash flow, you see above 10%. And then the dividend earnings per share where we had around 40%, but one thing when we talk about shares and dividend, I'd like to give you the figure of the total shareholders' return over the last 15 years, to say 15 years is more than 20%. And I think that is something when it comes from an historical perspective a very nice figure to remember 20% &#x2013; more than 20% for the last 50 years.</p>
          <p>But again like I said this is history, let's now look to the future of what are we going to do and what about the future? And in summary, we have tried to show here on this metrics that we are still very confident and committed to deliver more profitable, sustainable growth, that is the takeaway what you should read in this metrics. And we've tried to express this not only in financial terms, but we have looked at from an environmental point of view, from an ethical point of view, from a social point of view to come really to a full dimension to really to support through sustainable development of our company.</p>
          <p>And let me take a couple of examples, when we look here to the metrics and you look it from products and services and solution part, if you take it, we are committed to increase year-by-year the customer satisfaction. And we will do that by offering safe and reliable products but also products which should really deliver value for our customers and really reduce the customer energy efficiency &#x2013; increase the customer energy efficiency and that is a commitment we all take.</p>
          <p>We look on the operation side, which we have done environmental, ethic and social. And I take one, environment was where we said, okay we are committed to decrease our carbon dioxide emission from the operations by 20% in relation of cost, sales by 2020. We step up that. No corruption, no bribe and work with business partners, we're committed also to high ethical and environmental and social standards. That is why we believe we are in many markets where we really have to lead this process.</p>
          <p>And we make sure that our people are strong and can live that. And one of my favorite is that, we also say we increase the diversity in both gender and also in nationality, because we are a global company, and I think we are not sustainable if we only work with sweet indulgence. I think we must make sure we have leaders from all different nationalities, and the same as we are not really having all talent if we only go for a male environment.</p>
          <p>But then &#x2013; and I should not say finally but I should say we come then to the financial one where we confirm our commitment of 8% average growth as we mentioned here, annual average growth of 8% over the business cycle. And of course, we will continue to focus on operational excellence and high profitability and high returns on capital employed. And our aim is definitely to be the industrial leader in all of these different areas, and we will definitely come back during the years to come on these areas. So, I'd say to end this part of the presentation Atlas Copco is committed to sustainable productivity.</p>
          <p>So, Hans Ola let's go and talk to the audience some questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ronnie. Thank you. And we go straight into some questions-and-answers. I think that we ask the operator first to repeat the routines for the questions on the telephone line, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from the line of Nico Dil [JPMorgan Securities Ltd.]. Please go ahead, your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. I'd like to ask two questions please. One, on the progression in the margins on the Compressor Technique. I actually saw sequentially that the revenues were up by about MSEK 500, MSEK 600 at the EBIT level. The absolute EBIT level was down in this segment. Wondering what element has disappeared here.</p>
          <p>Secondly, you highlighted that the orders in portable compressors and gas and process compressors were down somewhat sequentially. Could you elaborate a little bit on where that is coming from and how you expect this to progress going forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think when it comes to the margin on CT of course, I don't know if you have comparing it with the quarter three, of course, then everything is &#x2013; has come down. But I think when we analyzed this margin, you can say it is, primarily it is a mix issue or a mix topic, especially that we had much more equipment invoicing, primarily more cash-in-process invoicing but also of course, you cannot have this type of high invoicing when you don't have in other divisions more equipment invoicing. That is, I think the major reason of this margin downwards as you say it although we should say it 23.7%, which is not a low one.</p>
          <p>Then, I think, I'd not be so much worried that when it comes to the gas and process when this quarter was sequentially lower and I had to mention because of course you see it also in the figures. It was a bit softer but there is a good underlaying quotation going on. There is many projects going on. So, I'm not so worried about that part of the business. When it comes to portable, one should not forget when we look to quarter two, quarter three we had a couple of very big orders. There was one, if I recall, back &#x2013; now I have to think a couple of months back. I think we had this big portable orders for &#x2013; of high-pressure for the <mark type="inaudible" /> project. Of course, that was in quarter three. Yes, this time we didn't get of this very large orders, so that made the comparison a bit tougher, but again the underlaying demand was there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we take two questions here now in Stockholm, and then we will return to the telephone conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Anders Roslund, Alandsbanken. I have a question regarding order intake, it's about the same as we follow the first one here. You mentioned that Asia was down in absolute terms in 4Q compared to third quarter order intake. And then, you mentioned this about the Compressor Technique, is there some sort of seasonality in the Compressor Technique business that you see a little bit higher order intake during the first couple of quarters, and then little bit lower during the second part?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is &#x2013; if you really look for the last five years and of course, all our statistics are little bit destroyed with 2008, and then 2009, but it is a bit you have dependency, when the year is good that the last two months get a bit softer and I think it's also may be a bit of an internal matter also that people are yes, maybe not so much pushing, then it comes waiting for the next year.</p>
          <p>That is one &#x2013; maybe one explanation, another explanation what we should say also that when it comes to Asia, quarter two, quarter three, I think there was a tremendous demand and we had again a couple of big orders there also when it comes to I remember one in CMT where we had one of our largest orders we ever had in Asia. So that also came in I think in quarter two or quarter three. So the comparison again was a bit different or difficult. But to say a bit of a broader answer on that. I see in the emerging market and it came also in our outlook, I see a good development, this good underlaying development going on. I think our quotation level for mining or quotation for construction, for real industry tools is still very, very solid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And perhaps we should add, I think that Ronnie touched upon it or perhaps I remember wrong. But if we compare Q3 order intake over Q2 as a group, there is a sequential growth, or there was a sequential growth of 3%, 4%, 5% and now between Q3 and Q4, it's again 3%, 4%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sequential organic growth in the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're right about the Asian comments, you're right about CTS, and that was your question. But again, these come and go a little bit in different quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peder Fr&#xF6;l&#xE9;n, Handelsbanken Capital Markets. Another question on the orders. You mentioned that one year ago you wasn't that bullish on the recovery of the demand that we've actually seen. So with that in mind, would you expect the sequential demand improvement to be around the same we saw the last two quarters or it will be below or above? That's the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. First, when it was 12 months &#x2013; here, yeah, okay, I was a little bit more &#x2013; I was rather positive, I had never expected that we would come out of this so quickly. I think we really skipped, in my mind we skipped the year in recovery. I think if I listen to the people in the field &#x2013; and the feet, and talk to the feet on the street, I think they're still rather positive on the emerging market like I already answered to Anders.</p>
          <p>The Asian market is there. I think the mining market, we all read and we see all that, I think that is a matter of getting it out and delivered, that is, the orders are for sure there. And we see also a good industrial manufacturing demand. I mentioned it when it comes to North America, I see still a good demand and if we take now another market let's say Vietnam, Indonesia, Singapore region there is a lot of projects going on, Korea, and not to talk about India and China deliberately. So that is going on. And so on that part, I believe that we will go on with a good sequential improvement. We should and that is maybe something we all of us, we need to be recalibrated. I showed you the slide in orders received, everything above plus 20%. Yeah, I'm sure when I'm standing here maybe nine months from now, I hope I can do the same, let's go for it, but, yeah, I think that will be a bit less, a bit less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The second question is, if you analyze the order book currently, how much do you think the mix would have an adverse effect on the profitability for the different division, not only equipment versus aftermarket, but also for projects primarily in the CMT business obviously?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if you take 2011 versus 2010-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think we will definitely get a slight shift to more equipment invoicing that's for sure. On the other hand I think also we will still also get some &#x2013; still some increases on the aftermarket side. I am not so much worried on that part that it will really shift so quickly, because also we get a better absorption. We need to work on all these areas. We get also new machines in it, new designs, which of course one could say yeah, but you get also material price increases, yes. But we also get new products in, that's the reason why we always drive for new products. And we will also get price increases, I mean sales price increases.</p>
          <p>So, if you take all this into &#x2013; because if I &#x2013; if you ask me straight when it comes, will you sell, if you &#x2013; will you invoice more equipment compared to aftermarket, and will that have a negative effect on the margin? If I just take that, then I say yes, for sure, if you take it mathematically. But I think, if I take it from a full point of view and assume that currencies are not playing, I think it will be the same. I'm not so worried on that part, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We move to take two questions from the telephone conference, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Frederic Stahl. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good afternoon gentlemen, it's Frederic Stahl here at UBS. I had two questions; one is more of a detail. So your stock went up a lot in Q4, and you had to revalue your provisions there. Does it work the other way around as well? If it now would drop sharply, would you take back that provision?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Hans Ola should you do it, or should I do it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. If we had another year end today, yes it would be different, that's correct. No, it is a revaluation of a liability as you say. So yes, it will move with the current share price, and since the share price was slightly higher than at 31st of December than today, yes that would be a little bit of a coming back effect on that one. However, it's very difficult to make any projection of it, because this is a live program and these options are continuously exercised also. So the volume of those outstanding options we don't really know. So, but technically, everything else equal, you're right, that there should be an offsetting effect if the share price falls, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm well aware. It's just a detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the second one, I guess is for Ronnie. Is there anything else aside from decelerating growth in Asia that you &#x2013; is there a reason why you mentioned the portable and the mid-size compressors as your canaries in the coal mine, is there a reason, why you're looking at the health of these canaries?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think the reason why I look in that one because that is the one of the product which is reacting very quickly where the customer also does not need months before he can decide to buy that. So it goes extremely, extremely quick and that is the same in China as it is in North America as any market. So the time to market or the time between quotation, order and delivery is very short, so that you can really see what is the underlaying demand for that one. And that market or that demand is &#x2013; yeah is positive, is doing well in most of the markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The question was more, is there something that worries you that makes you look at these indicators? Are you seeing some other data points that maybe indicates weakness so you go back to your canaries and check-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No &#x2013; no, yeah, okay, now I understand your question. No, the only thing is what keeps me busy today is of course what is happening in the Middle East. Of course, when just to elaborate a bit on Egypt, which is not our largest market and maybe our total exposure is maybe between MSEK 300 and MSEK 400. So it's not our largest market. But of course, what will happen in that whole region will be some investment stops. Will there will be less investments in oil and gas? And directly, will it mean that we will sell less? But okay, will it have another effect on other markets? That is what I tried to understand. For the rest, I don't see any yellow canaries who are not flying around.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that, Frederic, the reason why we comment is of course we read newspapers just like you do. And there are of course some comments about, Is there is slowdown? Is there something changing in the pace in China? And of course, we have to know how our different segments performing in order to see, is that a guess, or is it really a fact and that we do continuously. I think it's, Ronnie is probably the fourth or fifth CEO that looks at those type of product groups every quarter to see what they're doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. I understand. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from the line of James Moore. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everybody. It's James at Redburn. I have three questions, if I could. One on CT. I wondered if you could just say what the percentage was for the aftermarket mix compared to the 33% in the third quarter? Secondly, I was surprised by your currency impact. I always see you as a little less hedged than others and would have expected a negative impact in the fourth quarter. Could you give us a steer as to how you see 2011 FX impact the EBIT developing at current rates? And thirdly, you mentioned savings in IT and efficiency improvements in both CMT and CT. Most of your savings from the downturn plan are long gone. I wasn't expecting much in the way of savings. Are these the normal ongoing savings you get in the business or is there a particular phase of savings that are coming through that you could talk about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you taking the first one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No, we commented about the share of aftermarket, you're right in the third quarter. And in the fourth quarter, there is a swing of about 2, 3 percentage points. So I think around 31% in the fourth quarter compared to the 33% in the third.</p>
          <p>And I can take also, just to follow up on your currency, you were surprised that we didn't have as much negative effect as you would have expected. Well, there are of course different impacts and we are not perhaps exactly the same as any Swedish industrial in the sense that we have a very big operation in euro, not only in Swedish krona. Actually bigger operations and more cost in euro than perhaps other companies.</p>
          <p>That means that the relatively weakness of the euro is offsetting a little bit the negative impact of a strong Swedish krona. We are of course affected like everybody else by translating foreign currency numbers into Swedish krona, that is a negative impact surely. But from the margin impact, it's not such a big, big thing. In the year of 2010, it was actually helping the margins somewhat compared to the currency rates that was prevailing in 2009.</p>
          <p>But you were also more interested to look forward of course, and I can see that if the rates are as of today, we expect of course more negative impact on the operating profit in Swedish krona in Q1, compared to the same period last year. If it was almost neutral in Q4, it will probably be somewhere between MSEK 200 and MSEK 300 in Q1, if rates stay exactly as they are today.</p>
          <p>But again remember that that is primarily a translation effect. So the impact on the margin is not that dramatic. If we move to the full year, again, if currency stays exactly as they are today, we &#x2013; I wouldn't be surprised if the negative impact on the operating profit is around BSEK 1 compared to 2010.</p>
          <p>But again, having said that, that is like Ronnie commented on the margin effect of equipment sales versus aftermarket. That is taking one component of our operating profit out of the equation. There are so many other things that go on in parallel to this. There is a constant change of price management in order to reflect this worsening of the currency mix.</p>
          <p>There are savings going on, there are new products released, there are lots of activities that's looking historically, we have been able to offset to quite a large extent, if we look back over the 10 years, 15 years. So I just say that in order not to make it a mathematical exercise, that BSEK 1 immediately is also what is affecting the margins. No, it's not exactly that way. But obviously if the krona strengthens as it has done to the dollar in the last couple of weeks, we report in Swedish krona so of course there is an impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And maybe, James on your last question then &#x2013; when it comes to efficiency and cost, of course, we have cost increases and when people talk about material price increases, of course we have that. We definitely have also higher wages because you see wage inflation coming in. We pay more bonuses because it's fantastic to have this nice reserves but it also means that the commissions to sales people are higher that I think we all have. On the other hand, I think we should also say that we have &#x2013; and still are going home I think to install new systems, new processes.</p>
          <p>I think we improve our factories. We also merge factories. We have closed factories. We have done moves here and there. And I think another one we should not forget the power of our design and development of our new products. And then of course you come immediately of what Hans Ola said about the power of pricing. I think we are &#x2013; two things which we definitely are able to work with in Atlas Copco is beside the innovation part is also that the channel to market, the majority of our sales, our channels to market is direct. So that means definitely that we work hard to get part of that compensated again, and work hard with our customers. If material prices are going up, you have an easier sell to your customer, and to explain why you need price increases. And that is the unique part what Atlas Copco has that our channel to market is a direct market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks for your answers. Very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We take one question here in the room. I think, Mats.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, Mats Liss, Swedbank. Just about this extra dividend you proposed or not you, but the Board. Should we see that as a sign that you're sort of lacking acquisition opportunities &#x2013; or should we see it as you see yourself as financially strong anyway?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would have thought that the question would be asked different. I thought that, I was prepared for another answer Hans Ola, that you'd say why you're not doing more as a redemption? That is the question, what I was prepared for, Mats.</p>
          <p>No, but I think if you look to our balance sheet and also our plans, we are like, I said also in the Capital Market Day, we are fit for more. The organization is ready, we are ready for doing more organic growth, we are ready to invest in design and development we do. And of course, we will also work hard to find a larger acquisition, which fits for us. That is, I think one of my task to really look on that one. And I think, we should not deny that. Does it mean that that comes tomorrow, does it mean that it will come this year or next year that I think it's &#x2013; I think for me and that is the personal mission I've taken on, I would like to do the right one. And I think now we have a redemption of 5 and you can say, yeah, you could do if you look to the balance sheet maybe it could be 7. We said, okay. This is the way we work and that gives us certain flexibility and it doesn't destroy value for the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that you have a sentence directly quoting the Board in the report saying that without jeopardizing the capacity to finance further growth, the Board of Directors propose a redemption procedure. And this, I think summarizes what Ronnie says. No, we have not in any way taken out the question of further acquisitions, not at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So one more question in the room, if we have one. No, not for the moment at least, so we go to the telephone conference then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Guillermo Peigneux. Please go ahead your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. It's Guillermo Peigneux from Morgan Stanley. Also three questions actually. Regarding the mix on CT, obviously equipment is going to trend upwards as we move along 2011 as well. Would you see that this deterioration in the mix is initially as well for 2011, and therefore we should see margins also erode in somewhat from current levels as we move along 2011, that's for compressors? And then secondly for construction and mining equipment, Q4 turned out to be a little bit long or let's say the Q4 turned out to be a little bit more weighted towards construction equipment deliveries. Is that the case for this quarter as well or construction equipment has been in line with mining equipment or mining equipment ahead actually of construction equipment? And then, last question on incrementals, you showed us the slide with around 40% incrementals, moving into 2011 what sort of incrementals would you be expecting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. On the last one, I think I would say incremental, we will have somewhat increased. So that is also what we set in our outlook. I'm not going to put, is it 4%, 5%, 10% or 20%, I think, I'm not going to elaborate on that, Guillermo. When it comes to the mix, on CP side, I'm not so &#x2013; again as I also mentioned in previous question, I'm not so much concerned on that part of the margin that the mix will have a very negative effect because mix is one part and Hans Ola has already mentioned, we will also have geographical mix.</p>
          <p>We will get also in the equipment sales, you also get mix because you get products where we have a larger margin than others, so it's rather complex part of our business. I think when it comes to quarter four, one of the reason why we had a bit of negative, if you can say again I have to repeat 23.7 as the margin, a bit of a negative effect for mix is that we had larger gas and process invoicing. That is I think one of the major take away. The rest, I'm not so much concerned on that one. Then, I think now I have to look to Hans Ola, if he knows that when it comes to construction and mining in Q4, I think-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, we saw that there was an increase on both sides as we commented in the report. But, I mean it's clear whatever period you look at in 2010, it's mining that has been the strong driver that's clearly so, I cannot distribute exactly the growth rate on the one segment compared to the other of the top of my head. But, overall whatever was the technical impact in Q4, this has been a growth period for both segments, but again it's mining that has been the strong driver of course, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And can I ask on construction, have you seen &#x2013; other than China, have you seen acceleration in other material markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We comment on that one, we haven't seen it really for quarter four in Europe, we had not seen it and that also we comment in our outline. I think it's more the emerging market, the BRIC countries where we see a good development. I've not really &#x2013; you can always be try to be positive on that one, but I have not seen a very strong recovery in North America either. So I would say it's primarily the BRIC areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Now we have a question here in the room. We'll just get the mic there, we've got the mic, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Paul Butler from Macquarie Securities. Just a quick question on the mix in CT again. In the long-term average, what do you &#x2013; where do you see the mix being roughly between aftermarket and equipment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Today, I think you said...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>31%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In quarter four...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If &#x2013; this goes a bit recycles also. Today, we are in an &#x2013; in a mood where we significant grow faster in equipment and then you see the mix going on. I think, we will definitely &#x2013; okay will it be in 2013 or 2013 or 14, we will get maybe a less CapEx related demand and then automatically it will shift again to the aftermarket on that part. I think &#x2013; and I think we are growing and that is what I follow. I am not so much concerned on the mix more, what I'm more concerned is we do have a steady grow in the aftermarket, I mean a real steady grow and that's not 1% or 2%, but really steady grow, that is what keeps me really busy as I talk. And of course it means that the mix is a bit less here but on the other hand, we must make sure that we also make profit on equipment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I'm just trying to get a feel for with aftermarket at 31%, is that significantly above the trend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To Ronnie's point, yes, of course, we've already seen in 2007, 2008, when we were really in a boom phase also, lots of investment in the emerging markets. The aftermarket proportion were down to 26%, 27%. And it came very close to 34, 35 when equipment fell down dramatically last year. So there is the range. So anyone's guess if the pace of equipment growth will be slower, but sustainable or whether you will see big variations in it. That's very difficult to predict.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That you will find when you hear us talking about very large gas and process orders -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there is -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When you start seeing this, then you can see that the shift is that the aftermarket is going down a bit. When we come up, really we say, okay, we have large gas and process orders, and then we talk about magnitude of &#x20AC;20 million, &#x20AC;30 million, &#x20AC;40 million. But these ones unfortunately say we've not yet landed. And again, that I'm not so much concerned about because they're contributing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I think we go back to the telephone conference for, I think we have time for two more questions, and the questions that might be hanging after that, I'm sure with the Investor Relations department and myself, we will try to accommodate those questions after the call. But two more questions please then on the conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line Colin Gibson. Please go ahead, your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Colin Gibson from HSBC. Couple of questions, first of all, on the new &#x2013; new old 8% growth rate target, how do you see acquisitions in the context of that growth rate target? Are acquisitions something you need to make to achieve the target or are acquisitions the icing on the cake over and above that target? And the second question is could we just talk a bit more about I suppose partly raw material costs but also in particular supply chain constrains and potential bottlenecks for the business I suppose particularly CMT in 2011? Thanks</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think the material cost everyone also can see what the prices of copper, iron are doing. And I think eventually, it will also come and end up in our books. But again there and also in the past, I always said, I love that the material prices are high because that means that the demand is good for our products and in our way we work with design and development and the way we have the power of pricing, it is an opportunity for us.</p>
          <p>So we will get part of it, but I'm sure we have the tool or the ability to compensate on that. And there is stress in the supply chain. I've already said this, I think two quarters ago and this goes on, so lead times are stretched and we also have done capacity increases. We are in areas where we work fifteen shifts. There are areas where we're already working seven days three shifts, so there is definitely activities going on. But there is for sure a difficulty to get yeah, the products out on time. I have not heard really, I must say maybe yet such a statement from our organization that we cannot deliver within a year or a year and a half. So on that level we're not yet. Maybe we come back, Colin, I don't know.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the target, you have seen when we talked about the historical perspective over the last 20 years, we're around 8%. Also in that 20 years we had acquisitions, but and also unfortunately we had divestments, what made it really around 8%. I believe that in the 8%, what we really have now put forward, you should really take into account a certain portion of acquisition in. Of course if assume whatever, what word I can use, if we land a very big acquisition once every 10 years or 20 years Atlas Copco will do, then of course, these targets what we have mentioned here, all the financial targets, I think we need definitely to review anyhow. And maybe we will make then maybe over the last 10 years or last 20 years, maybe more than 8%. But to summarize, I think the 8% is supported by a solid organic growth, by a solid growth in the emerging market, and some close to home add-on acquisitions, that's the way you should see it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a quick follow-on question, if I could? Any opportunity, you think in 2011, as the Queensland floodwaters subside to sell more equipment in Australia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think when it comes to Queensland, I think there was majority is grow, and we all know that that is not our biggest segment in the mining side. There are some opportunities, but I think it's not some area where we said, okay this will break all the records or support other sales. I think it's not the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And then, the final question from the telephone conference please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Final question comes from the line of Sam Edmunds [Goldman Sachs International Ltd.]. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Two quick questions please. The first was just on your price increase that you put through, I was just wondering what your motivation for that was, whether it was to offset the raw material inflation that we saw or whether it's just because actually conditions are good enough that you can do it and therefore we should expect it to continue regardless of what happens to the cost inflation? And the second one was just what we should assume in terms of the SG&amp;A line as we go into 2011 whether you're back into sort of investment phase? I mean Q4 there wasn't any particular increase in SG&amp;A as a percentage of sales. Whether we're safe just assuming that that line grows in line with sales? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think when it comes to your last point what we call our functional cost, of course we keep investing, and you have heard me saying that we densify our presence and feet on the street and all that we will definitely do. But of course we do this also that the sales is going up. And that is where we have a good one hand, it's a good drive that we keep investing in the market, but we make sure that we also have efficiency out of these investments.</p>
          <p>And that's &#x2013; so I think you should see more or less the same ratio when it comes to &#x2013; to sales of &#x2013; growth of sales that one is sure. When it comes to price increases, one should know that, I think when you do as a company, opportunistic price increases it will fight back. Your customers will not accept that, your sales people will not like that. You really have to always make sure that you have a very good value proposition to do that. And then really have a good, yeah, you either will increase your productivity for the customers, but you have a good story and again that is the reason why we really want to spin the wheel of innovation, design and development very quickly.</p>
          <p>So to make sure that we, every time we come up with new products, that we have the ability to increase the value for the customer and that means also that we share some of the value of that one. In other words we increase the prices in that case. So that is the way you should see a very opportunistic way just to say, okay, we're going to the increase the price 5%, because the material price goes up. I think that is a very, very dangerous and short-term approach.</p>
          <p>Will it help us, when it comes to spare parts where we do half a percent, a percent here and there, yes, that's for sure, that we always do when the oil price goes up, of course we sell a lot of oil. Okay, the oil price also goes up because our cost price goes and that is a story what customers also accept that. So that is the way you should see this price management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, everybody from me and Ronnie. Then we thank you for coming here to Stockholm, but also participating on the telephone conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hans Ola, may I say one thing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely, Ronnie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like to wish you all a Happy Chinese New Year. Because you know, tomorrow we go to celebrate the Chinese New Year, and it is one of our largest market so tomorrow, we will be off. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>