<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1284036" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-02</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9232</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Hans Ola Meyer, Senior Vice President Controlling and Finance</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Ronnie Leten, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Hans Meyer</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Fredric Stahl</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Anders Eriksson</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Guillermo Peigneux</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Nico Dil</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Magnus Ax&#xE9;n</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Mats Liss</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Ben Maslen</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Roderick Bridge</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Johan Eliason</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Colin Gibson</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, I have &#x2013; I have the honor to open this meeting with Atlas Copco and I leave you with a speech to CFO of Atlas Copco, Hans Ola Meyer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Frederick and very welcome everybody to this combined presentation and telephone conference regarding our Q4 and 2009 report. We welcome also of course the telephone conference participants. So, good afternoon, good morning, good evening to you as well, wherever you are.</p>
          <p>We will do a very familiar format. I will hand over to our CEO, Ronnie Leten, who will take us through his comments on the report and then, we will open up for Q&amp;A's after that, and the whole program would normally take about an hour. So with that please, Ronnie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Hans Ola, and let me say good evening, good afternoon and good morning in that sequence to all of you and here in Stockholm. As usually you have seen already the presentation. I will go through it and refer to the slides, so that everybody can follow, also the ones on the phone.</p>
          <p>Let's go immediately to slide number three, which gives an overview what's its all about and you see a slight improvement in the quarter when we compare with pervious quarter or we can say sequentially. What we see and that is also what I think we felt in quarter three is noticeable improvement in emerging markets and I'll elaborate more on that one later on, but of course also from the mining industry, I think specially the last months we see a better improvement there.</p>
          <p>But still and that I think I want to &#x2013; also to give away here, I think it's still at a low investment level if we compare with previous year. What is good to see is sales of aftermarket and services is improving. So we see a slight upturn there. I think that is good to see and we also know that that is some early warning of an increase.</p>
          <p>Healthy profit margins, I would like to stress that. I think we felt that the 15.9, if we change for &#x2013; our debt for the exceptional cost we had in industrial technique, we felt that we had a good result for this quarter. Of course, we still have lower volumes than we compare with previous years and that is the reason why we also write-down here still negatively affected.</p>
          <p>Cash flow, yeah, I think it's very strong. We didn't beat record in quarter three, but it was close. So we had again a good operational cash flow also. So I think when you look to inventories and receivables and last but not least, we propose a dividend of SEK3 and a share buyback program.</p>
          <p>A bit on the figures, I will not go through it. I think you know them by now better than I know. Organic intake 9% down, of course if we compare with the cancellation, it's more or less flat, but I think if you really look to organic part, it's nine and I already said it about the operating margin, 15.9 with restructuring cost of SEK80 million. Earnings per share, 1.39, I will come back later on that one a bit more.</p>
          <p>Slide number six, if you take the geographical overview, I think it's one of the first quarters at least when I'm standing here that I can say that we have process in the quarter. So it's &#x2013; but we should also know just when you look to the figures, of course, this are not change with the cancellations. So when you look to the 25% and the 15, you should take into account some of the cancellations we had that &#x2013; in that quarter, so last year quarter. But if we look sequentially, you see definitely better figures than we had in the previous three quarters. So sequentially, we see a positive trend.</p>
          <p>The American, slide number seven. Here I can say a slight sequential improvement and you'll hear me saying that this &#x2013; it's definitely not as we would have hoped and we read all about the economy there. I think, it's still slight improved, but &#x2013; and we will stress on the slide. We see a bit better improvement in the industrial equipment. The aftermarket is keeping up, but on the other hand, you see a very soft construction market.</p>
          <p>South America on the other hand, I think that is doing well. I think especially when it comes to the mining, but if we take Brazil's more specific, you see also on the industrial part and the construction equipment.</p>
          <p>Slide number eight, Europe a bit the same picture as North America, still demand low and not &#x2013; not much real positive ones. Okay, sequentially again it is improving, but still at the low level. But again, a solid aftermarket that kept up in all business areas, I think in CT definitely, but we see it also in CMT.</p>
          <p>Then Africa, Middle East and you see also that this maybe the only region when you see sequentially it goes only from minus 28 to minus 23, that you can say it's real flat. Of course, we compare with a very solid development last year. So a very strong quarter, mainly coming from also at that time from the mining and from gas and process. So we see there not much improvement. Maybe in that area, we can say is that countries like the Levant, Egypt, Algeria are doing better there, but all the rest is rather soft.</p>
          <p>Asia, Australia and now we come to the &#x2013; the winners of the day. You see it also as written here, China, India, Indonesia, they are &#x2013; and Australia, but they kept in &#x2013; in one go, they are doing well and that is &#x2013; it's good to have that, but on the other hand, you see that Japan and South Korea is, yeah, very soft, is for the negative. But on Australia, like it is also written here, a very good development in the mining industry.</p>
          <p>Now I am on slide number 10, gives in bit of an overview, you see we coming gradually to, yeah, this is the minus eight, minus nine drop we have in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Slide number 11, gives a bit of sales bridge, it's a bit easier. What I want to stress here is on price. It's not and as I've said before, it's not that we don't get price pressure, definitely and in certain segments even a drop, but in &#x2013; if we take in total, we can say that we kept up reasonable prices and we get it gradually in price increases.</p>
          <p>Slide number 13, operating profit and here we have an overview of the different business areas and the ROCE. If we take away &#x2013; and this is 12 months, so this is the full year now, if we take away the restructuring, we would have ended up 15.1 and of course, then &#x2013; then ROCE will also look a bit better and of course if &#x2013; and the ROCE is also negative affected, in this case by our nice cash position we have. Nothing more on that.</p>
          <p>Then slide number 14. Now I am coming to the business area of Compressor Technique and what we see is still an overall demand remained at low level, so you see the decline organically versus quarter four, it's 12%. What &#x2013; if we look on that and that is &#x2013; if we take Compressor Technique and &#x2013; and it's written also here, if you take away the gas and process, which you have more &#x2013; which is more cyclical, where at this time it was weaker order intake, but if you take the other, what we call here the standard compressors, we have a reasonable good development. And even on the portable compressors, we see a sequentially a good stable development. The aftermarket goes as a clock, so that is good to see that we keep up also when it is tough in certain areas.</p>
          <p>Operating margin, I'm pleased to say that is 19.6 for Compressor Technique, as it is written there, some favorable mix, but I think also hard work from the guys over there. So I think it's good to see even if the sales has dropped. And then, last but not least, this last one, I think you have all read in December, Quincy, which will be a fantastic add-on for our business in North America, as it is one of the leading brands over there. And last but not least, we also have decided to have a new manufacturing plant in China for the gas and process business, as that is the future market there.</p>
          <p>Slide number 16, construction and mining. Here we can say on the infrastructure construction and mining we see definitely a positive development, and that we can say. And you see we're also saying is the infrastructure construction where we see it. Also the aftermarket and the consumables have a positive development, but still when we compare with quarter four of 2008, taken away the cancellations, we still see a slight drop, but sequentially, definitely an improvement.</p>
          <p>Operating margin 14.1, yeah, as I've said also already before, this is negative, affected by some under-absorptions, some cost savings are coming in. Some less favorable mix has really made the margin what it is here, today.</p>
          <p>Slide number 18, Industrial Technique, and here we have a bit of a mix, as long as Europe and North America not really taken off. Yeah, because that's the biggest market for this business area, we will have a bit of a tough time. But what is good to see is, all our effort and investments, which we have done over the last two, three years in Asia, now knowing the &#x2013; the real, let's say, boom what we have on the automotive side for China and also India, we also grabbed a part of that one. And that is also what we have seen and that make me very pleased to see that floor &#x2013; that business area. But still a drop, of course, like I said, if you don't have North America and Europe.</p>
          <p>The margin adjusted just now 13 &#x2013; 12.9 with the SEK80 million, where we had some closures in Germany and Japan. As I also said in quarter three, we need to do some restructuring work there, which maybe also, over 2010, will come in a bit.</p>
          <p>Then I go to slide number 21, the overview of the figures. I think most of you have already seen. Maybe what I can say is in the earnings per share. If we would adjust this for the full year on one hand for the restructuring, on the other hand for the one-time tax we got, we will compare 5.5 with 7.5. So that is a bit comparable figures when it comes to earnings per share. I think the rest, I think it's &#x2013; you can see the figures here. I think when it comes to tax, I think its all the same as it was before.</p>
          <p>Yeah, on the Bridge, yeah, still a drop and means also that the result is negative influenced, and you see a 28%, the flow through. I think its normal &#x2013; more or less normal level what we have here. I think it's nothing more to say on that one and by business area. Of course, Industrial Technique is a bit affected by this one-time cost we took. So that means there was a bit lower there, but for the rest I think there is &#x2013; they look all in line with the previous.</p>
          <p>Slide number 24, yeah, I think one &#x2013; and I know it's good to compare, we have a full year and if we compare 2008 with 2009 and then take a couple of figures here, what make us delivering a good cash flow, look to the inventory going from 17 billion to 11 billion. I think the guys have done a very good work in adapting the inventory level. So I think that's good. Also on the receivable side, that has been very well managed and the quality of the receivables has definitely improved. But of course, you see our cash position, as this all returned in some cash. The rest, I think, is nothing more to say on that.</p>
          <p>Slide number 25, yeah, of course, net debt to EBITDA. If you have debt &#x2013; net debt of course it's normal debt that comes to a lower figure. Then we go 26, one thing may be we can say it is 2011 where before we had a loan that we paid back already, so we did that during the quarter. And then the 2010 loan will be I think due, if I got it right, somewhere in May. So that also will be paid back, but I think on the other hand, we are rather pleased with our maturity profile here.</p>
          <p>Slide number 27, cash flow, 13.3 billion in the year. I think that is &#x2013; if someone would have told me that a year ago, I would have looked a bit with strange eyes, but I think we managed to do that. Like I said, operationally we improved very much, and second also, of course, on the tax side, we worked hard in that one with mergers also in the quarter to the level 3.6 billion operation &#x2013; operational cash flow.</p>
          <p>Slide number 29, as it is, yeah, quarter four and we close the year, maybe a bit of an overview and a look back or flashback of the year. Even during the most severe depression, we had &#x2013; we can still see that we made the same amount of profit as 2006. So I think and some people were very pleased at 2006 because we all know that 2008 was a very, very strong year and that is we have to compare with.</p>
          <p>If we then summarize a bit highlights, I think we have a very healthy, solid profitability in a very challenging business climate. We've a very strong cash flow, 13.3. Then going to the organization, even we are known as a very decentralized organization, I think we succeeded very quick to adapt I think and that is something which I should say congratulation to all my people. I think that they saw the situation and did the right measures.</p>
          <p>But I think &#x2013; and that is a strong thing if you look to point three, we kept investing. We kept investing in presence. We kept hiring sales people, service people in China, in India, in America, in South America. On the other hand, we adapted where we needed to adapt. And last but not least, product development. We had never launched so many new products than in 2009. I think that is &#x2013; saying me, okay, we are definitely fitter now than we were, let's say, 18 months back. Operating profit, adjusted margin 15.1%.</p>
          <p>Slide number 31, okay, as already announced it &#x2013; the dividend 3% &#x2013; SEK3, sorry for that, and of course, earnings per share at 5.14.</p>
          <p>Slide number 32, and this is the first time we also bring it out officially, is we have a new brand promise says here, committed to sustainable productivity and as you can read this us, we Atlas Copco are committed, of course, to deliver first productivity to our customers, which is also then giving productivity to our shareholders. But, of course take into account as it also written here responsible use of our resources is very human, and natural and our capital, so on basis which we will use now for the coming period.</p>
          <p>Slide number 34, this is always the most nicer slide and we are always working hard on that one. And I think the first sentence here I think is important. I think we expect that the overall demand is improving, but you see the last word, somewhat. I &#x2013; we have a dual growth, I think on one hand with emergence, which is doing well, the mining which is doing well, but we have a big part which is Europe and America where &#x2013; North America where we still have, yeah, a bit of a low demand on that, which then level out a bit to make me saying and improve somewhat.</p>
          <p>So, Hans Ola, I think that was the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ronnie. We continue then and I think I'll hand over the word to the operator first, just to repeat the instructions for the conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for that. In the mean time, while questions are lining up on the line, we take the first two questions here in the room in Stockholm. Let's see, if we have &#x2013; we have something here in the front here. Starting there, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon, gentlemen. It's Fredric here from UBS. Can I ask you a question about Compressor Technique? You &#x2013; you had a very strong revenues in Q4 while &#x2013; at least I think orders were bit on the &#x2013; on the weak side, and it's the fifth quarter in a row, if I am not mistaken were sales have been quite a bit higher than the orders, could you explain this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think you can go &#x2013; again, if I take away gas and process, then I think become more or less equally in compared to say &#x2013; for the standard compressor and portable compressor, if I take that and even aftermarket more or less impart, where you see the gap is in the gap division, in the gas and process division where we have significant less orders received than we have already invoiced that one.</p>
          <p>And is the orders received extremely low? No. I think, if we look over the time, I think it has a certain level, but of course, we do not have the big orders, which we use to have in China, which we have &#x2013; have in the Middle-East. These today are not there and we're eating in that order book. So the book-to-bill all except GAAP is above one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Anders Eriksson from SEB Enskilda. A couple of questions, if I may. You show again a very strong cash flow. You have a net debt to EBITDA of 0.9. You have 12 billion of cash. You will show another sort of good year in terms of cash flow, I'm sure this year. Why are you not more aggressive or why do you think the Board is not more aggressive in terms of cash distribution? Or is this a sign that you will gear up to make somewhat bigger acquisitions than we have seen in the past?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think when it comes to acquisitions, of course, we are &#x2013; and you've seen the Quincy one, if we get acquisitions like that, we'll definitely take them. And I would be lying here if I would say that we are not exploring the market on that. But you also know, it can take a while when it comes to acquisitions.</p>
          <p>Should we be more aggressive to do more? I think, if we do this 5%, I think we already come to a reasonable level and of course, organic grow also will eat a bit of our cash flow. So that makes us a bit, yeah, like you said a bit less ambitions or bit more prudent. Maybe, I don't know, Hans Ola, if you have to say more....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the &#x2013; the answer is probably that we are &#x2013; we are in the situation of a very volatile year that one might say or some might argue, well that's all behind us. But at the same time, it's not important, I think, to be fine tuning the exact cash balance and the exact leverage per quarter, perhaps it's not the focus of the company. But rather see that we have a reasonable capital structure seen as an average over the business cycles and some might see that as a slow adjustment, but I think it's a &#x2013; it's in order to keep a &#x2013; to propose a share buyback of that size, gives us a possibility to adapt the situation, whilst at the same time following what happens on the possibilities of adding businesses to the structure or seeing how much the growth will we consume in terms of cash.</p>
          <p>But, of course, I understand the question, but it's like everything else. It's a judgment of decision on one. I think, one has to take it &#x2013; a view that the capital structure should be reasonably affective over a &#x2013; over a business cycle, so to speak, I think that's wise to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. And if I may, another question on the aftermarket business in &#x2013; in &#x2013; or the mining after sales business in CMT. It seems like the mining companies ramped up their production quite significantly across most commodity areas and your graphical regions in Q4 specifically. I'm not quite sure we &#x2013; we can read that in your report or could you please quantify the growth rate for your mining after sales business in Q4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have the &#x2013; I don't have the percentage as such in my mind, but I can say it's definitely a positive one, when it comes to that. So it confirms what you said. But I think also we should see a quarter is three months, and you see, if you compared the beginning of the quarter, you see the end of quarter there is significant difference in behavior when it comes to the mining. So, it goes quick and <mark type="inaudible" /> runs quick. So that is a bit reason why we were also, for this quarter, a bit more reluctant to &#x2013; to be too bullish.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the run rate towards the end of the quarter was much higher than in the beginning of the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Throughout aftermarket, there was definitely more activity on that one...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We should see that in the first quarter then, sort of also been reflected in the margin or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah, that is &#x2013; I think, it also what &#x2013; I hope together with you, Anders, that this will continue on that one. That's a bit too early in the month &#x2013; in the quarter now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Then we take the first two questions from the telephone conference please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The first question comes from the line of Guillermo Peigneux of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead. The line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. It's Guillermo Peigneux from Morgan Stanley. Couple of questions, first on CMT, I mean if we look at slide 17, margins are now really taking off despite the higher level of invoice sales and it was something you mentioned cost under-absorption and also mix, which are reason of these margins evolving sort of flattish sequentially.</p>
          <p>Could I ask may be &#x2013; could I ask, what was the most important impact to margins, whether it was actually under-absorption or mix? And if it was mix, can you explain a little bit what happened to your mix during the quarter? It is just because you're selling more OE rather than aftermarket or is there something that is just one quarter issue that you hope is going to change in first quarter of 2010?</p>
          <p>Second question is a follow-up, maybe to Frederic's question on Compression Technique. For how long or in a way you put sales relative to backlog, relative to orders on Compression Technique? Do you think, you're going to be able to maintain the current level of sales or even increase from the current level of sales levels through 2010 or your sales, your invoice sales are going to be slowly migrating to your order sales at some point? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think on the margin-wise not taken off, I think you're already giving the answer. I think, it's a bit of mix, where we see we have a bit more equipment invoicing going on in the quarter. But...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Compared to the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Compared to the previous...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Previous quarters....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think sequentially I should say in this case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But on the other hand, I don't think there is any worry on that one, even if we look further in &#x2013; in the future and when we see also a geographical mix where you can maybe think about, yeah. But there's some more the emerging markets, it will be a lower margin on that one. I can say, this is not the case. So I think, if you compare quarters, it's always a bit here and there. And this case, it is equipment and mix to say, if &#x2013; sequentially on that one.</p>
          <p>When it comes to repeat Fredric's question, I think, of course, we have to see as gas and process had the last two or three years, a good &#x2013; good period. And of course now they're eating in their backlog and we have to see that the other part of the CT business can grow up and compensate for the negative backlog, which is generated in gas and process and that is at least the plan. Will we succeed in that? I think depending a bit on the growth, we can see in the emerging countries, and like I repeat myself here again, is what will the North America and Europe do?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, a follow-up on pricing if possible. Your order for CMT, your Construction and Mining Technique, your pricing was 0%. Have you experienced any inflection point on your pricing strategy or you are seeing prices actually going down for some of equipment for those orders that you get in? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think &#x2013; and I have also seen because when we do analysis, I think, if we look further in 2010, I think we do not have more price pressure than we had in the 2009 year. I think that &#x2013; I think is not something which we should really be more concerned on that one. I think, we &#x2013; we have increased the prices and we have been trying to get our design and development, really leveraged so that we also get the right pricing. So I am &#x2013; I am not so much concerned on that part.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, perhaps if I may add, since a couple of questions comes to the margin, specific on CMT. We referred during the report that there is a rather neutral quarter in &#x2013; from a currency effect compared to the same quarter last year. But in fact, there is a certain negative impact on the business areas that is compensated by a better performance relative to last year, on the corporate side, where the corporate hedges are &#x2013; are booked.</p>
          <p>And so, this is also a situation that we'll carry into the first quarter of 2010, where you will see or remember that both specifically from the Swedish kroner point of view, the first quarter last year was a very weak quarter, which is good for us in the sense on effect on the profits for Compressor Techniques CMT and IT. But at the same time, we will have the same phenomena that we &#x2013; we will be compensated by not having any negative impact during that period on the corporate side. So, we will be affected a little bit also on the sequential basis from the currency situation in Q1, both in CT and CMT. So that will have a little bit of a dampening effect on &#x2013; compared to the other mix changes and volume changes that you might expect to see.</p>
          <p>We have another question from the conference call please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Nico Dil of JP Morgan. Please go ahead. The line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Couple of questions please. First of all, if I look at the construction segment, you highlighted that in portable compressors, things have sequentially started to improve a little bit, we saw the same on the light construction side. I was wondering whether you can say in general that I &#x2013; if we look at residential and commercial construction exposure, whether it seems to have bottomed out?</p>
          <p>Second question is, I've seen your level of employees coming down by some 5000 people from the peak, so from 35 to around about 30,000 people, seems to imply some 15% reduction. You've come down some 18% in sales overall. And the question is a little bit, how much do we &#x2013; do you still expect to take employees out, and at what sales level do you feel comfortable that we need to get back to &#x2013; in order to get a normalized margin, which we saw in the last two years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think, maybe on the construction line, when I said sequentially portable, because what and &#x2013; I think, when it comes maybe first answer your residential area, has that been bottom out? Who knows? I will not comment on that one, but I can only comment what I have &#x2013; what I see, and that is and what I hear is, you see that some rental companies starting to buy again, and that is the reason also why the portable business, compared with a very low &#x2013; last year, see a more positive development, but it is on a low level.</p>
          <p>So that is what we meant with &#x2013; what I meant with one of these statements. When it comes to people, I think if you look a bit deeper, and that's maybe more difficult for you always see only one figure, because we have hired during this downturn if maybe we &#x2013; I should say it different.</p>
          <p>We have laid-off much more on the manufacturing side than we have reduced on the service side. On the service side, we even have reduced very limited and even now recently in this quarter actually, we have hired again much more service people. So you get a bit of a mixed view when it comes to the people. And then, we also know that you have &#x2013; you need much more &#x2013; much more service speed for the same amount of volume than you need manufacturing people.</p>
          <p>One area where we definitely will and keep reducing is in the GAP area, so in the Gas and Process, where we already have taken measures, because where we see that the demand of the output will go down and that is the area where we will do this year the most significant reduction. In all the other areas, we see gradually, in the factories, gradually re-employment. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And at what sales level would you feel comfortable to get the margins back to the range of 18 to 19%, as you saw previously in 2007 and 2008?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think this is a very, very difficult question to answer. Of course, we would like to see the demand going up, of course first you get the demand &#x2013; the orders received getting up and then you must get the output on the level, and that will take a bit of time. So we will see that for a while, we will have more orders received, if the business is coming, which will higher then our orders invoice, because we need really to &#x2013; to gear up on the orders invoicing side.</p>
          <p>But in a timing point of view and the level &#x2013; and rather on the level, you can go look back to the previous years. I think, there is no major reason why we would not be able to come close to the margins we had before giving that &#x2013; okay, we come to this level, because there is no dramatic difference in margin over the world, when you compare West Europe compared with emerging countries, it's more or less &#x2013; more or less the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In general of course, Nico, it's easy to say that, with the structural changes and the reduction of people, yes, we expect that everything else absolutely equal, we would reach the similar margins before the volumes come back exactly to the same level. But that's easy to do on a spreadsheet in Excel. And then in real life, there will be changes in the geographical mix. There will be ups and downs when it comes to the growth rate of equipment versus the other, then we will have currency swings, et cetera.</p>
          <p>So, it is, of course, impossible to stand here and say that well, if it takes 18 months, it will happen in August 2000 and so on and so forth. But yes, we also have the same feeling that if you could &#x2013; could freeze everything exactly equal to 2007/2008, we don't see any reason why we should not be able to match the margins and supersede them. But if, with the same reason, and we should probably have made 30% EBIT margin in 2008, compared to what we did in 2006, with substantially lower volumes. So it becomes a little bit of an theoretical exercise, to be honest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Thanks. So we have two questions now here in Stockholm, over there, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. My name is Ax&#xE9;n, Evli Bank. Little about on the same theme here, but looking at the current status of your inventory level and order book and so forth, and in relation to your outlook, should that be any relief absorption-wise or even an improvement, or how it will affect your production rates and so forth, or levels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the inventory, when it comes to that part, I think, yeah, we definitely have the ambition to do better, but we have seen that it has already drastically gone down. And in certain divisions, we can still do &#x2013; still do a reduction on that one. So you can say the opposite then, because that means you will really everything what you have booked, you start billing on it, that would be nice.</p>
          <p>My estimate is, giving that we get sequentially higher activity, we'll also have a better usage of our factories. And we have reduced the amount of factories, so &#x2013; which normally should result in a better absorption. That's also what, what Hans Ola said in the previous question, which will then result in a better margin, that's at least &#x2013; that's the, yeah, the point on our agenda to, at least where we're working on that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Short follow-up. Have you see differences there between the divisions, or is it the &#x2013; about the same situation both in mining or &#x2013; and Compressor Technique or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think if you come to CT and CMT, it's more or less the same case. But think about like when it comes to CT, you have the &#x2013; the gas and process one, which will around May, June when they have really to reduce, okay, they will have some under-absorption on that one. But, of course, by then I hope that some other divisions are catching up and coming on their part.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, Mats Liss, Swedbank. Just a question here on the mining activity. It seems that activity have picked up during the quarter sequentially and I guess December was the better month than October, that was my interpretation anyway. And I just wonder, could you give some &#x2013; well, indications if this have continued during January so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When I call around and with the customer centers and the visibility I have, I can say that the part of the mining is &#x2013; it is a continuation of &#x2013; of what we've seen at the end of the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's not the only sort of it, in effect that orders have been delayed during 2009 and they picked up during this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think that part &#x2013; specifically that part of the mining, yes, I think and you also have read &#x2013; most of you have read one of the interviews of our Australian General Managers, so also they were rather positive on that. So I think it is &#x2013; it is for the foreseeable future, I see a positive trend there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, just a short follow-up on the share buybacks. Previously, you have been more interested in B-shares for different reasons, and I just wonder if that's the same case as far as you can see?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That question I give to Hans Ola.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think first of all, I think we should come back to it when the AGM has granted that mandate, perhaps to talk a little bit more about how the world looks in April and May. So we haven't &#x2013; there is no, the Board doesn't state the certain strategy today, if you &#x2013; if that is what you mean and the reasoning from previous buyback programs in previous years has, of course, been to treat the mandate with the respect that it deserves because it's the shareholders money that is used.</p>
          <p>And, of course, then there has to be a proper balance, and if there is a difference of 10, 12% between the A and B share in price, and it's the company itself that buys the shares, then, of course, you have to take that into consideration at least. And that is what has been done in the previous occasions when there has been buybacks. And I would foresee that that would be the same. But I can't go further in that, because there is no strategy developed yet on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We go to the telephone conference again, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next telephone question comes from the line of Ben Maslen from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead. The line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon, everyone. It's Ben Maslen from Merrill Lynch. Two questions, please. Firstly on &#x2013; on China, there has been headlines and talk that the government are pulling back stimulus measures. Can you talk a little bit about what the outlook is for Atlas Copco in China? Whether you'd expect less government spending to hit you?</p>
          <p>And secondly, just two quick follow-ups on gas and process. What percentage of Compressor Technique sales were gas and process in 2009, and what is the profitability of that that leg of the business, relative to rest of the division? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. When it comes to China, I will do take that question and Hans Ola can look about the percent of GAP. Of course, we have to see this is &#x2013; this stimulus package is what &#x2013; I know what we all read. When I listened to &#x2013; to our people in China, they still &#x2013; they think that that measure that the Chinese Government is doing is the right one. So they &#x2013; they do &#x2013; they are not so much concerned as we read here in the &#x2013; let's call it in the Western Press. So there are still very positive when it comes to the outlook of activities, which, okay, then I may share that with them. I don't know if that is fulfilling the answer on your question, Maslen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And then we have the GAP one. So I'll &#x2013; Hans Ola is still looking for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you won't get any detailed numbers. We don't disclose separate divisions, but we have many time mentioned that, in this particular year, the level &#x2013; the proportion of gas and process and just for everybody's sake and some of you know this perfectly well, but just to repeat, that when we refer to gas and process division within Compressor Technique, we refer to a division that builds very big rather special compressors and that means that the lead time to produce them from order is very long, more than a year very often and normally no more than a year.</p>
          <p>And that's why we have this different impact when the order intake went down a little bit more than a year ago. But the invoicing keeps going for a year longer. And that's been around 12, 13% of invoicing, whereas it's been lower than that and probably more lower than 10% when it comes to received in the last period. So, that's &#x2013; that's how you see the swing there. When it comes to profitability, there is not a huge difference to the rest, to be honest, and I think we will leave it with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So we have another question from the conference call please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Roddy Bridge of Societe Generale. Please go ahead. The line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sorry just to continue a little bit further on the gas and process. I mean, you're talking about that going down, but you're also talking about a facility coming on in China and my understanding is that MAN's been expanding in this area too? Is there a worry that you're going to have too much capacity in this going forward?</p>
          <p>Secondly on CMT, I mean, sequentially your order book has done pretty well. I was wondering if you could give us a little more flavor as to what actually picking up. Is it the after-market that is really picking up in this business or is it the OEM? And if it's OEM, does that mean that we sort of see sales picking up in three to six months time on the back of this? So it was just really to sort of see how it flows through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was this &#x2013; was it CTOC or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>CMT.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>CMT, okay. Okay, yeah, on gap and the investment on that one, I think of course you know when you do this and Hans Ola has already nicely said that these are these huge compressors and you need to build up certain competence, which takes &#x2013; which takes a hell of a lot of time before you have it, because this is competence in the mind of people and that is made us deciding to do an investment in China for this, because this is where also future-wise a lot of the activities will be for that type of compressors, and that is &#x2013; is more as a strategic decision.</p>
          <p>Now is &#x2013; there is a huge investment just to give you the magnitude of that, it's around &#x2013; if I recall it, &#x20AC;10 million or something like that. So it's not that we talk very big amount of money. Of course, like &#x2013; and you are right, MAN has already done that a year and half ago when they inaugurated their plant. I think we are, for that part, maybe a bit behind when it comes to China for gap and &#x2013; for gas and process.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the pickup, I think we &#x2013; we see today the pickup. I think the question was already also asked on the aftermarket. We see the pickup in both areas. We see the pickup in aftermarket. We see the pickup also in prime equipment. So it's a bit in both areas. Of course, we all know that the pickup in aftermarket will not be crazy, where it can happen in the mining area. It can go very quick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes equipment, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think you have to see a bit, the mix of the pick up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So aren't you &#x2013; we'd be expecting it to be mainly aftermarket, they're getting in your order book at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the machinery is coming through?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can I just ask one further question, because you had quite a large sort of eliminations in your operating profit in this quarter, is it in fact telling us something about what's happening in your hedging or something like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, yes and no. If we take what you refer to as adjustment or eliminations, it's really everything of costs &#x2013; of operating costs. That has nothing to do with the three business areas. So if you call it Group overhead combined with other elements of corporate hedge effect et cetera, et cetera, that's what that portion is. If you take, Roddy, the last four or five, six, seven, eight years, you probably will see that the quarterly run rate will be somewhere between 100 and 150 negative rather consistently. Sometimes we run into quarters where there is a positive effect from corporate hedges or a negative effect from corporate hedges or there might be some other one-off event and that's exactly what happened in the third quarter. So the third quarter was not the normal where we had actually an income on that line. Whereas now I would say it's relatively well in line with what is the run rate, be it ten, 20, 30 million plus or minus over the quarters when you look at it. But 100 to &#x2013; sorry, 100 to 150 negative is probably the best estimation you can use for the future, also as it has been for the last couple of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So we have more questions here in Stockholm, perhaps? If not, we will quickly take another question from the telephone line. It looks like that Frederick, does it? Yeah. So we take another question from the telephone conference please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Then the next question comes from the line of Johan Eliason from Cheuvreux. Please go ahead, the line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. This is Johan, just to two questions. Sorry to come back to the gas and process in the CT division. But I mean, if you look at the order intake, I understand that the book-to-bill is very low for the gas and process. But if you look at the order intake, in CT its down sequentially, it's in fact the lowest order value of the whole year, and I mean, comparing with the two other divisions, Q4 was actually the highest order intake during the whole year. I mean, this sequential decline, is it all attributable to gas and process?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Say, a part is of course gas and process. I think there is &#x2013; now I'm thinking a bit of different divisions. You could say that &#x2013; what should I say. The smaller the compressors are, the better the book-to-bill is. The larger they are, the &#x2013; yeah, the more negative they are. So what I want to say with that is of course and this is &#x2013; when it comes to really big investments, I think we see that the world has not come back on that part. And that is the reason why also &#x2013; and you look the gap which is big and you talk about some tickets, say &#x20AC;5 million and more. I think these types of tickets are less. And that also means in other &#x2013; in another division which we have &#x2013; where we also have larger compressors, you see also there that they are little bit lagging behind and they have a negative book-to-bill. But on the other hand, you see then on the portable side, I think on the aftermarket, where you then see a more positive one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I may add just to that, Johan, that &#x2013; we sometimes cannot write every analysis piece in the report and perhaps this one is a little bit important. We report in Swedish krona as you well know and that gives a little bit an exaggerated or even wrong impression some time when you think about the Swedish krona from a customer point of view, is a percent or two of the total Atlas Copco turnover. So if I &#x2013; I just played with the numbers, and if you look in our sales of -order intake of CT, the best quarter of the year was actually measured in dollar was the fourth quarter. If you measure it in euro, the fourth quarter was almost the same as the second best or the best, which was the third quarter. It &#x2013; when in Swedish krona, it looks like it is very much down compared to any of the quarters.</p>
          <p>So I think our message would be that if you don't make too much of that in this as an indication of a trend, the &#x2013; if we would have adjusted the exercise I just referred to, we're looking only at the non-GAAP divisions, you would have seen even in all currencies, a slight pick up at the end of the year in received. So it is a big, big importance in the fourth quarter of these large gas and process compressors that had the lowest order intake quarter, but the highest orders invoiced quarter. So that exaggerates the picture a little bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Excellent, good comment on the currencies, I'm not too worried about the book-to-bill. I just wanted to track the order intake there. Just one minor question then, on the 5% share buyback, I mean, historically you've always kind of asked for a 10%, is there a technical reason for this or is it just that there is a message that you want to be a more prudent in what you actually will do with your balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't have the &#x2013; any statistics or what is usual. The 10%, you're quite right refers to the maximum amount of shares that the company can own of its own shares. We own about 1.1% of shares already. And I don't think that you should read in too much of &#x2013; sort of a detailed guidance whether it's five, six or seven or 8% buyback. But it is certainly an indication that the Board wants to have a certain flexibility when it comes to the capital structure, that's for sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have I think time for a final question from the telephone conference, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from the line of Colin Gibson of HSBC. Please go ahead, the line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, gentlemen. Two questions, please. Firstly, very straightforward one on the inventory cycle, it sounds as if restocking has already started at C&amp;P to some degree, I'm a bit less clear on whether you're saying that restocking has started in Compressor Technique or not. So has it, and if not, when do you think restocking really gets underway for Compressor Technique? And secondly, second question, I remember when you are in London in August, both you and Hans Ola talking quite defensively about industrial technique, and obviously having quite a lot of faith in that division, even I'm not so shallow that I expect that strategic faith to be repaid in just six months. But clearly looking at the full year data, Industrial Technique obviously looks a fair bit weaker than the other businesses you have. Over what timeframe do you think your faith in IT gets repaid, either in the form of stronger sales growth or in the form of better returns? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think when it comes to the restocking, I'm not sure, Colin, what you hint to. When it comes to our restocking or the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I try and you correct me, Colin, if I'm wrong, but I think Colin refers to if customers are starting to need more on this in that case ordering more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that is &#x2013; yeah, that is when it comes to C&amp;P that has I think started on that. When it comes to CT, we all know and you know my saying that everybody need compressed air, but bankers and consultants. So you have the very diverse customer portfolio on that one and you have customers also geographically as you have by application. So it's a bit depending where you are. I know that air separation, just to say that, there is hardly any investment there.</p>
          <p>When you then take the food industry, they go wrong. When it comes to medical, they &#x2013; in the United States they're a bit prudent. So I think it's a bit of mixed where it is. And I think geographically, I would answer in that way, that we see definitely, if I use then your wording, restocking in the emerging one, I see a good demand in India. I see solid demand in China. I see a good one in South America. But I'm still very prudent and looking forward to some more positive signs when it comes to Europe, and I'd take East Europe and West Europe together as I take North America, that one. So that is as far as I see it.</p>
          <p>When it comes to Industrial Technique, yeah, it is when &#x2013; recall that I have said it in August, and you have a good memory. I think you know also that in that business area, the leverage is very high. So if you really want to come through with a good margin, I think we need a bit of volume. And there is of course we have to see what is happening in our major markets and that is North America and West Europe and again this is not the market which is boring, but I'm rather pleased to see that with our effort, which we have done in India, which we have done in China that that yield some results.</p>
          <p>Beside that and that is what you have seen also the 80 million cost we have taken, we are really reducing, yeah, the installed capacity and the fragmentation we had in the &#x2013; on the production side. So that is where &#x2013; so we come to a lower break-even point, and that is why we're working on that. I think it will take me a couple more quarters before I will be pleased with that. But again to summarize, I need a bit of volume on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I encourage those of you that are on the telephone conference line still waiting to put the question to continue to try, but perhaps directly with Mattias Olsson in our Investor Relations department or with myself or anyone that you can get hold of. But for now, I would like to thank everybody for coming and participating, and wish you a good night, good lunch or good night wherever you are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>