<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1447168" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-01-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9232</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO, SVP-Controlling &amp; Investor Relations Person">Hans-Ola Meyer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Ronnie Leten</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Frederic Stahl</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Carnegie Investment Bank AB">Joakim H&#xF6;glund</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Svenska Handelsbanken AB (Broker)">Peder Fr&#xF6;l&#xE9;n</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Nico P. Dil</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Bank Plc (Broker)">Colin D. Gibson</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Redburn Partners LLP">James A. Moore</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Benjamin G. Maslen</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Guillermo Peigneux</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Martin Prozesky</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, and welcome to the Atlas Copco Meeting. I have the honor today to open the meeting and I will leave over this speech to our moderator, the CFO of Atlas Copco, Hans-Ola Meyer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. And from me as well, very welcome here in Stockholm, sunny, but cold. For you that are in different countries, on the telephone line, and very much welcome to you as well, of course.</p>
          <p>We're going to follow a known format here. I will soon hand over the word to our CEO, Ronnie Leten, who will make his comments on the quarter. And then we will turn back and have Q&amp;A session, both here and on the telephone lines.</p>
          <p>So I think that's enough as a welcome. So please, Ronnie, take it from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Hans-Ola. Next time, you also should say that we have a blue sky.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, yeah. Sorry about that. Sunny I said, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So welcome, all of you. And as normal, I will go through the presentation and also try not to forget to refer to the page where we are. Let's go immediately to the highlight and to talk where are we in the quarter four.</p>
          <p>For me, this &#x2013; and at the first day, we see also overall at the high level. The demand, overall, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:33) for sure, also better than I had expected a couple of months ago.</p>
          <p>Coming from good development in the manufacturing segments, seeing that in our Industrial Technique business area, but also in Compressors, but last, but not the least, we should not forget to say a very solid Mining business, which was a bit weaker that &#x2013; and already we have said that in several occasions is our Construction business, which was softer, mainly coming from China, but I will elaborate later on that.</p>
          <p>A good or I should say, a strong growth as it's said on the slide in aftermarket and that makes me very happy that our effort, what we do in this area is really yield the good results. Record output for the factories also led to record revenues. So at least, we made a record this time again. So it's great to see that. But also, if we look to the quarter, we landed several acquisitions. I think you have seen the last couple of weeks in December that we got a couple and also that we got a little bit earlier in the quarter with Schucker, which we also closed. And we keep investing in our operations, either on the design and development side, but also in capacity in Asia in our factories.</p>
          <p>We proposed a dividend of SEK5, coming from SEK4 last year and this is a total of a bit more than SEK6 billion. I'll go now to slide number three where you had the figures. I will not elaborate much on it beside maybe the operating profit and Hans Ola will elaborate later a bit more on that also, but what we see is here, a 15% increase, almost to 4.6. If we adjust for these two items here mentioned, one is restructuring and the other one is the long-term incentive program, we came to the 21.6%, 21.7% where we are really cruising these days. Then may be one, it is also the last time we will talk about our RSC shares. We sold them all and you also have heard that RSC was sold to United, so this is a closed pot. And then the operating cash flow, almost to SEK1.6 billion, which is, of course, given the growth, still a solid development. But again, there, we will elaborate a bit more later.</p>
          <p>Geographically, we take the quarter's &#x2013; if we say that the dark blue figures, all pluses, a very solid quarter, plus 16% compared to last year. And you see it's almost spread to all over with maybe Australia as the positive surprise. But again, I will talk a little bit more on that in the next slide. So now on slide number five and we take Americas.</p>
          <p>And I have already said several times that we see good development in North America. And again, you see here a plus 19%, a very solid development almost from all business areas, even on the Construction Technique side and that comes from the rental companies, which have really ordered good equipment. But also what we see and that took us here also in those Technique areas. You see, the automotive is very strong, but beside that also in the general industry as well. And again, we see also our efforts in the service also creating good growth in the aftermarket.</p>
          <p>South America, the mining and manufacturing are really developing well, it's mainly mining. We see a very solid Peru, Chile, Columbia. But on the other hand, we see a stable, gradually growing, again, Brazil. So that makes me very happy to see that. It's a bit maybe weaker on the construction side, as I already also mentioned that in previous talks, and mainly done in Brazil. But anyhow, if we take in total, a plus 22%.</p>
          <p>Europe, what can I say more? A little bit of mixed view, although you see a plus 13%. It's a very solid double digit growth. Yes, but very mixed view. First, I should say the 13% &#x2013; I should correct with the acquisition of Schucker, which is maybe around 3%, 4%. So it is a high single digit, which is still strong, but mainly coming from the region over here.</p>
          <p>Russia is doing well and a reasonable Germany. But all the other parts, the more we go south and think about Italy, Spain, France, still not much to see there.</p>
          <p>Then we come to Africa and Middle East, a plus 1%. One should say, okay, why is it so low? Mainly coming from softer southern part of Africa, but you should not look to anything. It's from the mining and some of the orders were not landed in the quarter. So if you take it over the cycles of the quarters, you would see that it's nothing something to worry about. But one thing, what I would like to say, is that we see activities coming back in the Middle East. So that is good where we had the Northern part of Africa, which was a bit weak, but we see that again there is activity coming.</p>
          <p>Asia, high order intake, strong development in India, Southeast Asia, Korea, even China, if we make exception for the construction part in China. Sales here, a plus 14% and a strong development in our aftermarket. This is an area, definitely in Asia, where we work hard and that is to make sure we strengthen our aftermarket organization.</p>
          <p>And then we come to Australia, maybe some of you will remember and you saw also that last quarter in Australia was a bit softer. But you see here, plus 63%. And that's also what I meant when I talked about South Africa. You get sometimes big orders in the mining and then they shift from one quarter to another. But still a very strong demand for equipment in the Mining business. And again, aftermarket follows accordingly. Eight quarters in a row, so you can only be happy to see that as a CEO. So we plan to go on that.</p>
          <p>Sales bridge, if you take the quarter price volume and orders received, 14%. So I think this is a solid development, a little bit less currency compared to the full year. And we ended the year with, yeah, a plus 22% organic. I think that I'm very proud of to see that. You also see the book-to-bill, we are more or less equal. And that is also something, which we had seldom. If we look back to quarter four, most of the time we had a much more higher revenue than orders received and this time, it's really on par and I cannot say that the revenue is low. So it's a good one. Maybe another part to highlight is the price development, a solid 2% and that's good when you see some inflation coming up to cover for certain costs.</p>
          <p>Then I would like to go to the different business areas. And now on slide number 11, solid good demand for industrial compressors and aftermarket and the healthy demand comes from the 12% organic growth. So that it keeps going on. We had a good operating margin of plus 23%, which is, I think a good development and also the output in the quarter was strong.</p>
          <p>We are planning or we have started, I should say, building a new factory for compressors in Wuxi, China, so as to expand our capacity there. And we also had, by the end of the year and beginning of this year, announced two acquisitions, one in China from a small compressor company in the southern part of China and then a low pressure company in Texas, Houston Services.</p>
          <p>And then, we also, from the first of January, we also created a dedicated division for air treatment, which we call Inside Quality Air. It's a business, which we had already since long, but now we felt that it needed to really having their own attention because we believe there is some potential in that business.</p>
          <p>Indus Technique, fantastic 26% organic growth, coming from a strong motor vehicle, but also a strong general industry. And again, also the service follows very well. Profitability, 23.6% and it cannot stop you to remind you, here, on the real V shape, I will go on, I think forever to think about that, but I'm really proud what the guys have done in this business area. And also, we had two acquisitions here, where one was Schucker for the adhesives equipment and one in France, mainly for Airbus business.</p>
          <p>Mining and Rock Excavation, continued high demand for equipment in mining, but also high demand for aftermarket. So it's a hard to work to find enough experienced service engineers. Revenue was high, so strong output, but the operating profit, solid 25%. That is also great to see. And here, also, we have done a couple of acquisitions, where one was in Columbia, which we took main distribution on our site. And then we had two acquisition, one in Italy and one for utility vehicles here in Sweden, but a very solid development in the Mining and Rock Excavation.</p>
          <p>Then Construction Technique, we must have some area to work on, otherwise &#x2013; so this is the area, where we would like to see solid improvement. Unfortunately, we have a weak demand, mainly influenced by demand in Brazil and in China. And that mainly also from road construction equipment. The other businesses were at a reasonable level. And we see some good development in the aftermarket. And then, the operating margin, 4.1%. Of course, if we take the under-absorption in account and also the restructuring cost, I think it would have been around 6%, 7%, that area. So like it says, 6.6%. So that is where we are on the business area, Construction.</p>
          <p>Then before I give the floor back to Hans Ola, here, the overview in the quarter, solid orders received, plus 13%, revenue of plus SEK22 billion. We don't have that every day. And a very solid operating profit and profit for the period after tax of more than SEK3 billion, giving us an earnings per share of almost SEK2.8. And I think one area, which maybe &#x2013; we hardly talk about that, but I take the opportunity now &#x2013; look to the return on capital employed of 37%. And the reason I do this is because I'm sure also, some of you will talk about our inventory. And just to open the scene for Hans Ola.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ronnie. Just some very quick comments. You see the operating profits margin, as Ronnie has said. As we wrote in the report, we have some non-repeating items between restructuring and costs for the long-term incentive programs in the group that needs to be mark-to-market every quarter. And you have heard us before say that that affects the operating profit from time to time. This time, it was negative. And if you adjust for those, it's 21.6% is the underlying operating margin.</p>
          <p>If we move down, between the profit before tax and the profit for the period is, of course, the tax charge and that equates to 24.0% in the quarter. The year end, the 24.8% is, for us, a fairly good indication of the run rate that we think will be also for 2012, somewhere between 24% and 25%.</p>
          <p>Then if we move on from there and look a little bit further, well, you can also see the earnings per share number here. And you saw also in the beginning that the full year was SEK10.68 on an undiluted basis. Sorry, that is the bottom I should press. Then as normal, we try to understand the change in the &#x2013; not only in the revenue line, but also in the profit line. And the takeout from the overall view is that there is still a little bit of negative impact on the results from the currencies compared to the situation in Q4 last year. It might seem as if it should be rather neutral if you just take a superficial look at the exchange rates in the big currencies. But of course, what affects this way of calculating a bridge is also what type of volume of revenue and results did we have in Q4 last year and how has that changed in the same currencies this year.</p>
          <p>So it will always be difficult to be perfectly exact in the, let's say, forecast of these impacts. However, I can assure you that the calculations made this quarter is exactly the same as we have used for, as long as I can remember at least. So you can also see that when it comes to one-time items, you heard that I talked about some restructuring costs, we also have some contribution from acquisitions which lies in here. So the restructuring is SEK125 million negative and then we have contribution from acquisitions that make up the rest.</p>
          <p>If we look at how it distributes over the business areas, you can see that the net of these items that tries to get to what is the, let's say, the remaining normal flow through of profit per revenue increase, you see that it's much lower than normal in Compressor Technique. It's roughly what you would expect in a strong growth environment on the other two. And then, of course, we have a not calculable number on Construction Technique. So disregard the 84%, it doesn't mean very much.</p>
          <p>If we stop here, of course, there are some effects of the mix change, as always, that we sell more of equipment than we do on aftermarket or let's say the grows of the equipment sales is stronger than the aftermarket growth. And that is noticeable in Compressor Technique. And also, when we see the distribution of where the profit is generated, vis-&#xE0;-vis, where the revenue is generated, it's not always a perfect match. So hence, that can also impact this number and it can also give a certain impact on the flow through number.</p>
          <p>Again, if we continue to grow revenues as we have done in the last quarter, then we, and I repeat, we think that with some pricing component, we believe that somewhere 25% to 30% is still what we would expect in everything else equal. Unfortunately, everything is not exactly equal from one quarter to another. But that's a little bit to round off the comments on that one.</p>
          <p>We'll move to balance sheet and Ronnie talked a little bit about that growth also carries, growth and need for capital, of course, and need for assets. We can see that in the increase of inventories and receivables, primarily in this last year. And that is rather substantial in a year's time, vis-&#xE0;-vis, September, it's somewhat higher. But it has clearly then to do with the strong sales development.</p>
          <p>From these numbers, we also get the same impression that it seems that these items are growing faster than the revenue and order growth. And that is, of course, also true, you can calculate it easily. However, the growth of equipment that is now stronger than the growth of aftermarket, the growth of the Mining business, which is stronger than the growth of the Industrial Compressor business, for example, and certainly, than Construction business, is also somewhat negative to our, let's say, use of working capital. So the mining industry has this higher than average tie-up of working capital to sales than the average of Atlas Copco.</p>
          <p>There are a couple of these mix effects that make us also look a little bit to understand really where are we. So we looked at what was the situation in a similar period after good, strong growth. And that's why we put up December numbers for 2008. And as you can see, we always strive to be more efficient, but when we look at this development, we still feel that with SEK10 billion, roughly, higher sales today than in 2008, we are persistently looking for efficiency, but we are not so concerned about the buildup of working capital that we have seen in the quarter and in this year. But there are always room for improvement. But I think it's worthwhile to put it a little bit in prospective to the numbers we have today.</p>
          <p>If I move on to the next one, well, again, it's an indication of our financial strength. It's strong. Following the rather large mandatory redemption of shares, we are hovering 0.7%, 0.8% and I think it's strong. But as we discussed, coming here, we don't feel that it's a burden to be strong in this respect in today's economic environment. So that is on the net debt to EBITDA.</p>
          <p>As a consequence of everything we have said together now, is the cash flow, you can say. And you can immediately see that compared to last year, the cash generation is not as strong and you can see that we invest for future growth and we tie up some more working capital and that basically explains the difference. So we come back to certain of these things, I'm sure, in the Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>But with that, I leave it back to Ronnie for some final remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So if we look back to the full year, I would quote 2011, which is maybe unfortunately history, but a fantastic year and why do we call it a fantastic year? If you look to our development and growth, I think I can say, it is a strong demand development. We have kept investing in presence. We have dig deeper into the markets, you can name it South America, you can name it China, you can name it Russia, you can name it Africa. We have been digging deeper into the market. I think we definitely have new technology on board, either acquired or by our own people, really business development and design, which has done good job. And I also see that we got a lot of new products on the market, which, again, gives us the possibility to penetrate deeper into the market and also take a bigger share of the market.</p>
          <p>And of course, we also have adapted. We have not only increased our capacity, but we also have adapted our capacity according where our future demands are. We also had four records. That is the reason it was not a typing error what was there. So with four records compared to &#x2013; yeah, hopefully, this period's record orders received, record revenue, record absolute profit and record operating margin for the year. So that make me saying that it is a fantastic year.</p>
          <p>And we come out with a cash flow of a bit more than SEK6 billion, given the growth &#x2013; I think because if you compare it with previous year, you can see this has come down. But given the growth, and Hans Ola has already elaborated on that one, I really see that this company is really generating good cash flow. And we propose a dividend of 5%, a solid 5%. So that's also easy to remember, if we take it to 5% for all of you. So I took that also into consideration when we proposed to the board. But again, summarized, I'm really proud of my crew and of the achievement for 2011.</p>
          <p>If we look, okay, these are the different statistics. I will not elaborate on that part. So here, you see on slide number three, the earnings, 23%, earnings per share and we talked about that. You see, a real solid development over the last 10 years of earnings per share, as well as also dividend.</p>
          <p>Then we come to the last slide, where I'm sure also most of you have been looking to and yeah, it is the same as we had in quarter three actually. Quarter four is definitely better than I expected when we were here standing in October, that's for sure. But on the other hand, we see also, if we take the global outlook, there's a lot of uncertainty still into the market. And third, we should know that we are comparing very high demand already. So that makes me saying, okay, we expected to be somewhat weakening compared to the current level.</p>
          <p>So thank you very much and I now, I think we go to questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, if the operator can just repeat the procedures for the questions on the telephone line please, first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think then we start here Stockholm this time. We have one first question. Here. Please state your name and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (28:42).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Hi, it's Frederic Stahl at UBS. I have two questions, please. One, if you could go back to the operating leverage in compressors and maybe give us an idea what was the dilution from the acquisitions and so we can see what the underlying leverage is. And then secondly, if you could specify or quantify the larger orders that you took in mining. So again, so we can get a feeling for what the underlying order run rate is in that business. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You'll start with the last one, Ronnie?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we constantly get &#x2013; I think if it is very large order, you will have made public, so you have not seen many. So I think we got several solid orders mainly in Australia. You've seen, we already got a bit of a shift &#x2013; that is an area. But if you would have asked me the question, say three months ago, I was a little bit more concerned about the equipment demand for mining than today. So that what we have also seen in quarter four that it took us also a bit by surprise that it is better than expected. But I think it came mainly from Chile, Peru, Australia and a bit here and there. Maybe you take the first one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The dilution from acquisition, it was shown in the slide, if we go back to that one and &#x2013; but I don't think that that was exactly the focus of your question, I don't know. But there is, on the acquisitions, that has been added, primarily some in industrial air and the other one in gas and process are yet with the level of demand that we are running right now or yet to produce positive result shortly after the acquisition. So you can see that there's a slight dilution on that one.</p>
          <p>Irrespective of that, we have a low flow through in the normal business if we exclude acquisitions. And I think it's very difficult and there is no clear answer that I can say. It's that component has given 0.5% and what not. But it's very clear when you see the development that we are investing heavily in the aftermarket structure in the group. And of course, there is a buildup, primarily in the east, but also in many of the other countries. And the profitability of that is not exactly in the same as in the, let's say, the steady business. That affects, if you compare at least quarter-to-quarter last year.</p>
          <p>The general growth in some areas means, of course, that we build an organization in certain aspects. And that is, of course, we have talked about it many times that how long can you grow without starting to get some kind of cost development for the &#x2013; I wouldn't like to leave you with the impression that it's a cost issue, but it's something where, of course, the mix of the business, where we grow and in what we grow, has impacted to a certain extent.</p>
          <p>So I can only go back and say, if what do we expect for the future, I think that with the 1% to 2% price increase rhythm that we have had, we still expect ourselves also that 25%-ish, perhaps up to 30% in this type of a calculation would be what we also would expect. But then, you get some quarters where one division grows much faster than the other one, et cetera, et cetera. So that's the add-on comment I can make. Yeah, we had &#x2013; yeah, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Joakim H&#xF6;glund from Carnegie. I have four questions regarding the Construction business. The first one is, if you can help us with some quantitative objectives that will come out from the SEK75 million that you're taking now. And also, more in details, what will you do in terms of restructuring? And you talked about under-absorption. Was it due to sort of inventory cuts in the division? And could you please specify more in details, how much that was in numbers? You said 6.6% in underlying EBIT margin. I assume that is putting back to SEK75 million, not sort of taking into account that you are producing at a rather low level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I didn't get that last one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The 6.6% in EBIT margin, that is sort of putting back to SEK75 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah, yeah, nothing else. Nothing else, no, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And also, looking at what you have to do in the Construction business to get back to or up to the EBIT margins that you are satisfied with, is there anything to learn from the sort of super turnaround in the Industrial Technique business? Neither of them have particularly high aftermarket and you did a really good job there. So what can we expect? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think, when &#x2013; should I take?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, no, please go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it's difficult, I'll give it to Hans Ola. I think when it comes to the, there is the quantifying, the restructuring in what we do. Of course, you have seen that over the last year, we had to do some closings. We had to do some movings of products to areas where we were used to make, but we were selling them in the other side. So we do a couple of movements, which &#x2013; <mark type="ph" /> in coking (34:48), costs money. So that is what we are doing and this is in the area, you can find them in the area of road construction and in the area of construction tools. They are there. So we also remember the, what we did, the move from some of the activities from <mark type="ph" /> Union B (35:10) to lose from United States to China. So we had a couple of areas, which we have moved.</p>
          <p>Then when it comes to the under-absorption, the majority of the under-absorption is through construction, primarily in Brazil and China. If you remember a couple of months back, when I start talking about softening there, we really have been breaking. Where on the other hand, all of us, that's a bit a cycle in that business. You expect strong demand the first quarter because that is when the Construction business is really buying. So you have to get some inventory ready and then suddenly, the business stopped. So you get almost a double dip on <mark type="ph" /> inventory (36:02). So that is what we get, that penalty you see, and that is also the reason why first, the demand is lower and also the absorption and accordingly, the profitability is lower. And that is inventory. You see also that Hans Ola explained it. He didn't elaborate it so much, but we also have a bit higher inventory in Construction.</p>
          <p>And then maybe another part that is a learning for all of us, I think, which figures you have not seen, you have a bit of seasonality in that business, more than in any of other businesses on the construction side. First, that our construction business is not as equally globally spread. Otherwise, you said, yeah, but when it's warm on other side of the world, it's cold here and vice-versa, but we are not so equally spread in that when it comes to our own presence. So that creates also certain seasonality, which we will get.</p>
          <p>Then the learning. Yeah, I think the learning is really to make sure that you have the best products. And to work hard to get the best products on the market, really have good intimacy with your customers and do these two things very quickly. And when it comes to good relation with your customers is, of course, for sure, on the aftermarket side. And that is where we have, in construction, still work to do. And that is also the reason why the result is lower than in other areas. But that is I think the two main takeaway learnings I can say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we have one more question here in Stockholm and then we'll move to the telephone line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, some quick ones, Peder Fr&#xF6;l&#xE9;n, Handelsbanken Capital Markets. Aftermarket is growing fast, as you mentioned, both year-on-year and sequentially. Could you help us out here with the magnitude? Secondly, if you look at the order that surprised in the quarter, was there anything unusual by the end of the quarter that maybe leave you with a sort of cautious outlook? Was the order spread equally among the months? And finally, on construction, please help us out how bad was China in the quarter year-on-year and sequentially. And what's your opinion on the consensus view that the tightening is easening over there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, maybe the last question. When it comes to China, when I talk about construction, I still see a good development in China when it comes to the portable energy part, which is rather spread. But when it comes to, say, road construction, it is very low. That's maybe the farthest I can go. I think it's low. It's really, I think since a couple of months, you can say that there is not much getting out of the factory. And that's not only with us, but with most of our competitors too. And you now also know the Chinese New Year, so January will also not much. I think I have to wait until mid-February to get a more qualified answer on that part.</p>
          <p>Then when it comes to the order flow over the quarter, I think it was reasonable, equally spread. I think it's not &#x2013; because you get a bit of a different &#x2013; you see North and South America, very solid Europe, but here and there, but equally spread. I think &#x2013; because it was better than, and as I already said, better than I expected in the mining part, which make on equipment side.</p>
          <p>Then on aftermarket, yeah, it is a very solid development. It is, say, a strong double-digit development. The rest, I suggest you talk to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's year-on-year, I guess. But also, sequentially, you looked at it on growth. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sequentially, you can. It's still keeping going up, that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The thing that happens in this phase is that the equipment revenues are growing faster.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what we talk about all the time with mix and what not. But the difference is that the aftermarket is not only high on year-over-year basis, like Ronnie said, it's a very stable growth. And that's exactly what we want to have and what we see if we look a little bit back. But in the short quarter, the growth was even stronger in equipment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That one, I think, and I have really said and I have to make it. You cannot expect from an aftermarket growing 20%, 30%. That is not sustainable. If one quarter goes down for whatever reason, then the quarter after that, you can do, because you don't find the people. You cannot cope to train the people. So if you run a solid double-digit, that's already very good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we'll turn to the telephone line for three questions, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have a question from the line of Nico Dil. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Nico Dil, JPMorgan. Three questions, please. First of all, record orders in Industrial Technique and in Mining, what is driving such strength today and how do you think about the future? So effectively, if I look at the Mining CapEx plans of the major miners they have put forward, there seems to be a substantial increase here year-on-year. Is that already in your orders today or do you actually expect the orders to move up here?</p>
          <p>And so there's a second sub question here. If I look at Industrial Technique, that was also exceptionally strong. I think, it was also a record quarter in order. So I wonder where you expect the weakness going forward, as you indicate that you expect your end environment to weaken somewhat going forward.</p>
          <p>The third question that I have is effectively around the margin and Industrial Technique, very strong this quarter, I thought it was the second best quarter overall. In Q1 of 2007, that was also such a strong quarter. I remember in 2010, you highlighted Compressor Technique in the sector in the third quarter was effectively reporting a non-sustainable margin. Is that currently the case Industrial Technique as well or could we effectively see a 25% to 30% incremental margin in this segment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's all difficult question, I think that Hans Ola <mark type="indiscernible" /> (43:02).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we are silent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now if you start with the mining.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we can start with mining. I think if you look to the outline, what I gave, and if I talk to, first to our own guys and also to a couple of mining companies, they still see a continuous good development. It's also a matter a bit what I explained to Peder when it comes to the question of aftermarket, can <mark type="indiscernible" /> (43:30) cope with it to bring it in. So there's a lot of discussion going on on efficiency automatization, so to make sure that all the mining companies can cope with their installation, which they get from us and from others. But for the time being, I think, we could say, normally expect &#x2013; yeah, solid development on that part.</p>
          <p>When it comes to IT, we also mentioned that this is mainly coming from a lot of investments in models from the motor vehicle industry, but also from general industry. We see a lot of transformations, so going from, say, simpler tools to more sophisticated tools, more in depth quality tools and that is also, that transformation we are leading because that is, again, is our technology where we really push them up and then also make sure that the customer create efficiency.</p>
          <p>So at the end of the day, he has a lower lifecycle cost and a higher quality in that. I think that is, when it comes to Industrial Technique, beside the good tailwind from different models, I think it's also driven by our technology, our transformation. When it comes to the margin on IT, yeah, I think look to the volume, the output, the orders invoicing what we saw. And then we should, of course, expect a good absorption in the factory, good relation to our functional costs.</p>
          <p>So I think that margin was, yeah, a solid one. So I will not, like I said in that time when, Nico, when you hint to CT, at that moment, I said that it was not sustainable. And this one, I will not deny. So this one, I believe, on the Industrial Technique. I think I can take it <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:52).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ronnie, one part of Nico's question was some of the goods segments that you just touched upon and how does that build into the outlook. I don't know if I'm right, Nico.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but that was the most <mark type="indiscernible" /> (46:08).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Also with the half of the company has a pretty good outlook here, if I'm not mistaken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But that was the most difficult question, Hans Ola, so I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, Nico, sorry that I forgot to answer on that one. That was not on purpose. But I think again, like I said and I will repeat what I said around the outlook. It is a bit the certainty, what none of us know is we can say if we take it by geographical blocks and you take Europe, what will Europe give us? How will it look? You read also a lot of uncertainty when it comes to China and construction. So what will that all bring us. And the third one, we should not forget that we are running at a very high level already. So that makes me saying, yeah, to be a bit more prudent on that part, where on the other hand, I must admit, yeah, Indus Technique and the Mining, they have, for the time being, a good tailwind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's probably very much the same situation as we felt three months ago. But the overall situation does not make you extremely positive. However, of course, we also know that Q4 sort of contradicted in some areas that uncertainty that we felt. And that is, again, a similar situation right now when you try to look ahead and not just try to project the situation in Q4 into the future. So it's big, it's more the &#x2013; the trend doesn't necessarily continue without any hiccups, so to speak. Can I put the next question in line on the telephone conference, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of <mark type="ph" /> Eric Carlson (48:17). Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. I just had a question on the aftermarket. Given the strong growth in equipment in 2011 and the fact that you are investing a lot in the aftermarket business, should we expect a year of above trend growth in aftermarket in 2012, do you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, when I look to the trend, and again, I repeat myself, I think you have a solid double-digit grow in the aftermarket. And now I'm taking globally than I think you have done a great job. And 2011 was already a very solid development in aftermarket. 2010 was a very solid development. Of course, we came out of a softer period 2009, so we could recuperate. But I see already today that it takes a hell of a lot of effort for us to really bring our service engineers up to speak and to train them. You know, when you have 100 and you need 20, then you need to train 20, but to train the 20, you need people. So you see, it is rather, yeah, demanding challenge to really keep growing constantly on the aftermarket. So I would not talk it out on that part now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. It brings it but back to your previous answer, I think very much that aftermarket growth is much more consistent and it doesn't go in leaps and bounds like the equipment goes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, one thing, maybe also I should maybe explain on that one, our aftermarket and to the people who are following Atlas Copco very closely, we are really tried to sell direct and also to do the service direct. So we don't work, say 100% with this <mark type="indiscernible" /> (50:17). Do we have distribution? Yes, that's for sure. But we really make sure that, okay, we have the contact with the customer. But that also means that we need to train and to hire the people. So you don't have that one goal, you can sell more spare parts and the sales can go up and you buy them from your suppliers. In this case, it's a full package. So that makes also that it is harder to get this extremely high growth in aftermarket. But on the other hand, it also means that we have almost no swings in the aftermarket, if one looks back to the figures in 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And the third question from the telephone line before we switch back to Stockholm?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Colin Gibson. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good after noon, everybody. It's Colin Gibson, HSBC. Two questions, please. The first question is on Construction Technique. I think you, more or less, acknowledged and answered somebody else just now that there are some bottom-up problems of that business, as well as weak end-market demand. How long do you think it'll take to turn around those bottom-up problems? You referred, I think, specifically to products and customer relationships. So how long might we expect this is going to take? Clearly, you can't just snap your fingers and fix it instantly.</p>
          <p>Second question is on your mid-market strategy. Like most European engineering firms, you've talked about growing your mid-market business over the past year or so. And I keep looking for evidence of a negative impact on your price mix of this mid-market growth strategy and I can't see any evidence of a negative impact. Does this is mean your mid-market growth strategy isn't working or does it mean it's too small to measure or is there some other explanation? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will answer the last question first, Colin. I think when it comes to the mid-market business, of course, we are developing this further and the reason we do that is also to dig deeper into the market and getting a bigger share of the market. But we see that that business is more or less growing and more or less in line with the top market business. So that is the reason why you hardly see that. But there is definitely growth in that area. Not always, just to confuse you more now, not always this mid-market is giving lower margins. So now I really confuse and when we meet later on, we can debate about that. In some markets, it's also &#x2013; I don't mind to sell mid-market products.</p>
          <p>Then when it comes to the bottom-up and how long will it take, yeah, I said that the capital markets, they give me three years to really bring it up to a sustainable level. And I will stick with that statement. There is no reason, since the Capital Markets Day and today, to get away from that. I think we do &#x2013; to work what we need to do on improving our product offer, improving our supply of spare parts, digging deeper into the market, moving factories here and there and invest in the aftermarket. So we keep doing that and, yeah, let's meet again within three years. But you will see definitely, in the meantime, some improvements for sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we take a question here in Stockholm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Thank you. Andreas <mark type="indiscernible" /> (54:12). Just a question there on China, following up on weak construction demand. If I think about the derivative of it, weak construction demand and no road equipment coming out from the factories, the derivative would be that mining would eventually slow, as China is the primary driver of mining in the world. So have you seen anything on that on the slowdown in the mining equipment segment? There were some headlines on Bloomberg lately.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have not seen on that part. So maybe it's too early or it will never come. I mentioned that, more or less, the same when I was talking to some of the mines owners, and they say we haven't seen any movement on that one when this was specifically on iron ore. So does it come or not. That is also the reason why I say, yeah, my uncertainty is the big question for me also and I think all of us, I think we should wait until maybe early March before we know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question here in Stockholm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, it's Frederic here from UBS again. One for you Ronnie. Could you maybe, on the service organization, coming back to that, maybe, rather than talking about growth numbers, maybe give us an idea on how much bigger your service in aftermarket organization is today compared to, say, a year ago or three years ago to give us a sense on how fast you're growing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think now I'm looking to Hans Ola when it comes to the amount of people, yeah, so if it's a difficult question then I gave it to him. I think, you see, you need to have the CFO for that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We just look at some of the things, but it is difficult to have a perfect number for you in tables. What is interesting if you look at 2008 when we were really in a &#x2013; it's proved to be the end of a very strong investment cycle at that time. We have increased the number of full time employees in Atlas Copco with about 2,000 people. In the same period, we have increased service engineers with 3,000 people. And they represent a little bit short to the third of total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we plan to do that further, that's for sure. And that's also an area, just to give it, but what we have agreed that we will not hold back to keep hiring even if it's getting a little bit so and so because it takes too long before the service engineer is really productive. And you never get to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we go to the telephone line, we have a few questions more. And I think we have some 10 minutes, we can have the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from the line of James Moore. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everybody. It's James at Redburn. I have a few questions. Equipment, as a percentage of groups of sales, I think it was 59% last quarter. Could you give us the number for this quarter? Secondly, could you say which regions or divisions in Compressor Technique are less profitable and growing faster that are driving the mix? Thirdly, at currency rates, would it be possible to give your best estimate for a rough 2012 FX impact to EBIT? And finally, did you think of doing another redemption for records, order sales, profits, margins, a good deal? Did you think of handing back the cash with the strong balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Hans Ola, I'll take number two and number three and you take number one and number three. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So when it comes to less profitable in CT, I think an area which is less contributing is our larger gas and processor compressors, when it comes to that equipment. So that is the main reason when you see some moves and you see us more invoicing gas and process than you will see a relative drop of the margin. I think the others are more or less in par with each other.</p>
          <p>When it comes to redemption, I hope not, and for the good reason is that we really have been growing, that we have done the right acquisitions. And of course, that we don't need to borrow, but we really create good operating margin contribution. So there is no plan like that. We have not discussed in the board, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (59:25) I don't recall any of that fund. It's really &#x2013; Atlas Copco is a growth project. And the mission given to me is beside organic growth, which is the most profitable growth you can add, is also to see either add-on acquisitions or really solid coal acquisitions and that is the mission I got from, at least from my board and I hope I can accomplish that and not have a redemption.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we can refer back to the comment we made earlier about in this moment of the world economic situation, we don't mind having a strong capital situation. And that's a follow-up, an add on to Ronnie's answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, beside that, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the &#x2013; and forgive me for not having the final decimal of the percentage, James, but it's higher than in the third quarter. If 59% was indeed what we said, then it's 60% now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Or even 61%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A bit higher, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's slightly higher percentage than it was in Q3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then the FX?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Remind me again of your question on that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>At current currency rates and we're seeing some moves there. I wondered if you could give your best estimate for the full year impact to EBIT &#x2013; I mean, a SEK1 billion, for instance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Yeah, it's less than that. For the reasons that I just explained before that it's very tricky to know how the mix, also of the profit generation, not just the mix of exchange rates movements, but if we look at what we can elaborate on the exchange rates, as we see it today versus the average 2011, we expect a positive of perhaps something in the region of SEK0.5 billion on EBIT line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just on the latest quarter, it's not that there is some positive catch up to come in the first quarter. It is more minor currencies, dragging down the picture in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's not &#x2013; the dollar and the euro doesn't give the answers to your point. So when you have swings in the underlying volume of things in currencies like the South African rand, the Indian rupee and a couple of others, it can be a little bit difficult to predict accurately what the total impact will be. And I think that's exactly what we have seen in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understandable. Thank you. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. So we'll take another question from the telephone line, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of <mark type="ph" /> Alexander Berger (01:02:15). Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi there, gentlemen. I just have two quick questions, please. One, just around the commentary that you said, orders for larger ticket items were down sequentially in the quarter in Asia and Europe. I just wondered if you thought that was systematic of general caution and CapEx budgets being tightened into the year-end or if there is anything more sinister in there? And the second question was just on your own CapEx expectations in light of your relatively cautious commentary and the uncertainty in the macro environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think when it comes to the larger orders, I've not heard anything or I don't spot anything that there is something to get that on the large order that people hold it back on them. I see, in certain areas, a good quotation level, but again, compared to previous period, maybe a bit softer, but not that it is really falling off the ship. When it comes to our own CapEx, you have seen, when you look to the cash flow overview, where you saw that we, more or less, in certain area, we have been, almost gone double from around 800 to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>1.7...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>1.7 or something, so it's almost double. So we have done a couple of expansions, primarily I think, it was here in Sweden and a couple in China. I think you can, more or less, put yourself on this same level, maybe a little bit lower because I don't recall that I've been, myself, approved a lot of further expansions beside the ones, which are already in the pipeline. So it's not that you cannot expect much more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not so easy though to say that look at our outlook and then you have a good prediction of the CapEx because it is also investing for further presence in Asia, for example, will affect these things and that's something that has longer cycles than just capacity investments. But nothing more to add to Ronnie's answer actually?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not the big issue there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are glad that we are an asset light company when it comes to....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And another one from the telephone line, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Ben Maslen. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon, everyone. It's Ben from Merrill Lynch. Two questions please. Firstly, Hans Ola, in the bridge, just on Industrial Technique, the SEK65 million kind of boost to EBIT from acquisitions or one-time items, is that the level of profitability that the M&amp;A is coming in now or is that the kind of unwind that's a negative from last year? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And then just on the working capital, we've seen a big build. I'm just wondering if there's any impacts on the margin from that at all, either positive or negative, either because you're producing ahead of sales and kind of over-recovery in your overhead, which because you're getting inefficiencies from having extended lead times, inefficiencies in the plant and so forth. Just overall, if there's any impact on the margin in any of the businesses. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the last one, Ben, I can take. I think it &#x2013; and we already talked about that I think. It has a bit of a negative effect on Construction Technique. We should not make it more complicated and mainly that is mainly in Brazil and in China, where this inventory will have a negative effect. On the orders now, Hans Ola elaborate a bit on that, what it meant, what is the reason why the inventory has gone up. I think we know that we have more mining equipment, making it, producing in <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:06:28), having our largest market in Australia, it takes a bit of time before it's there. So we still accept the orders. But it takes you more time and more capital tied up on that. So I would not take that into account for any, yeah, say next quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the Industrial Technique, yes, it's an indication of a good profitability from acquired companies. That's what you should read that profit bridge as you did, Ben. We are very happy, both from strategic, long-term view on those acquisitions that the business areas made. And it's also showing similar profitability than what we have seen in similar segments of the existing Industrial Technique business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have so many questions on the telephone line, so we take two more questions. So then we have to stop unfortunately. But as always, those of you that have further questions, please contact us after the call. So we take two final questions then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Guillermo Peigneux. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. It's Guillermo Peigneux from Morgan Stanley. I was actually looking at your order intake on Compressor Technique and adjusting by currency impact during the first half. And then comparing to your fourth quarter order intake and looking at them, your outlook statement, it looks to me pretty consistent because it seems like if we were going to do a run rate of the fourth quarter order intake, it will come out to be a slightly negative volume for the first half of 2012. That's volume growth year-over-year, I mean organic. Am I right in thinking that way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think that the comment that Ronnie made about some of the large equipment, et cetera, having a slightly weaker situation at the end of the year in the fourth quarter is giving these effects that you mentioned. So that is probably, I don't know exactly the input numbers, you deflate with and so on, but the way I read you is that the average of the first three quarters seem to be slightly higher in underlying order intake than the fourth quarter. Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the same way, we're looking at mining get sort of the same issue here, which is still slightly positive. But I mean, to be honest, it's not &#x2013; because your first half 2011 was extremely strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Your first half 2012 needs to go a lot in order to be a very strong first half, am I right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that you made an observation that we cannot &#x2013; we shared that we had a very strong first part of 2011 and, of course, that has then, in many markets, continued to be on a high level, so to speak, even at the end of the year. And hence, exactly, our thinking that to defend that high level going into next year is not going to happen automatically, so to speak. So then, of course, it's anyone's guess a little bit on the details of that. But I don't think that we can agree on your observation, so to speak.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Guillermo, that's also more or less what we see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that is also beside that what I tried to explain that we compare with a very high level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And then last question. I'm looking at your SG&amp;A and cost of goods sold, the relevant focus on that. Maybe you could, sort of highlight a little bit on your guidance regarding how do you think head count costs are going to be during the first quarter 2012 or probably do you have any visibility of first half of 2012. And same with the utility costs and probably with component costs, just to try to analyze or try to estimate how your cost picture is moving.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I handle it already when I was talking about the sales bridge and about the sales price and inflation. You get, of course, some salary inflation. That's for sure and you know also when we were elaborating on aftermarket, there's a lot of people. And that you get a certain inflation and salary increase, so that you get for sure. I don't pick up so much when it comes to see commodity price increases. So it's more on labor cost increases where &#x2013; yeah, you can be &#x2013; depending on where you are, but if you take China, it can go up to 10%, if you take Sweden, it's primarily whatever, 2%, 3%. So that's depending on which country you are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Belgium?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Belgium, we are on strike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I think then the final question on the telephone line, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Martin Prozesky. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone, and just a few quick questions, please. On compressors, the mix effect, which diluted the margin sequentially on both year-on-year, can you just clarify how much that was due to service aftermarket versus equipment and versus the small and medium orders being big in the quarter than the large orders? And second question on compressors, with the ramping of the Chinese facility in the second half of the year, should we expect a dilution effect as you're loading up that factory? And if so, if it's material, how big will that be? And then just the last question, are you seeing on the mining side, any changes or any weakness on the mining, exploration drilling orders?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take the last one first. When it comes to mining and exploration, I think when you would have asked me that somewhere in September or October, I would say, yes. Today, I don't see it. I see still a good demand for our exploration and that's also, I think a good sense on what is going on and how do the mining companies think, because that's the first one they stopped. But that is doing fine.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the mix and dilution, I think on the other hand, there is definitely a bit more equipment which has a bit of negative effect. On the other side, we are also investing into the market. If you hear me talk about presence, it's more people on the street. It's getting deeper into the market, setting up new offices. If you say we are now debating to do something in Mozambique, these things are costing. So that you should look more in that area. Therefore, I don't want to take the word, dilution, in my mouth on that part. And then your second question, I must say I missed that. That was about China factory?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You said that's starting production in the second half of the year. So will there be kind of a dilutive effect if that gets loaded up, so as the factory scales up? Or is it not material enough?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's not material enough. And of course, today, we are renting floor space and I think that new factory will be most probably inaugurated whether this September, October this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But you will not see that as an effect. And that is more for, say, with the future. And you remember, several times, I have already diluted on that what type of money we're talking here. We never talk here about &#x20AC;100 million. We talk here in the order between &#x20AC;10 million and &#x20AC;50 million, so it's not the big deal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I thank all participants on the telephone conference, as well as here in Stockholm for participating. And I wish you a nice evening and hope to see you again when it's time to talk about the first quarter results.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>