<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1184386" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-10-20</date>
    <companies>
      <company>58</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Ron Stovall, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Kenneth I. Chenault, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Daniel T. Henry, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Robert Napoli</participant>
      <participant id="5">Daniel Henry</participant>
      <participant id="6">Christopher Brendler</participant>
      <participant id="7">Kenneth Chenault</participant>
      <participant id="8">Craig Maurer</participant>
      <participant id="9">Sanjay Sakhrani</participant>
      <participant id="10">David Hochstim</participant>
      <participant id="11">Ken Bruce</participant>
      <participant id="12">Bruce Harting</participant>
      <participant id="13">Kevin Stiroh</participant>
      <participant id="14">Scott Valentin</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the American Express 2008 Q3 earnings conference call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />  As a reminder, this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to our host, the SVP of Investor Relations, Mr. Ron Stovall.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, Ernie, I appreciate that and I appreciate all of you for joining us for today's discussion.  I certainly want to apologize for the slight delay.  We had a couple of issues with our conference provider through the web.</p>
          <p>It is my job to remind you that the discussion today contains certain forward-looking statements about the company's future, financial performance, and business prospects, which are subject to risks and uncertainties and speak only as of today.  The words believe, expect, anticipate, optimistic, intend, aim, will, should, could, likely, and similar expressions are intended to identify forward-looking statements.  Factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from these forward-looking statements including the Company's financial and other goals are set forth within today's earnings press release, which was filed in an 8-K report, and in the company's 2007 10-K report already on file with the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter 2008 earnings release, supplement, and presentation slides which are now posted on our website at ir.AmericanExpress.com and on file with the SEC in an 8-K report, we have provided information that describes the company's managed basis and other non-GAAP financial measures and the comparable GAAP financial information and we explain why these presentations are useful to management and to investors. We urge you to review that information in conjunction with today's discussion.</p>
          <p>Ken Chenault, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of American Express, will provide some brief opening comments. Then Dan Henry, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer, will review some key points related to the quarter's earnings through the series of slides included with the earnings documents, and provide some brief summary comments.  Once Dan completes his remarks, we will turn to the moderator, who will announce your opportunity to get in to the queue for the Q&amp;A period where both Ken and Dan will be available to respond to your questions. Up until then, no one is actually registered to ask questions. While we will attempt to respond to as many of your questions as possible before we end the call, we do have a limited amount of time. Based on this, we ask that you limit yourself to one question at a time during the Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn the discussion over to Ken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ron.  Before Dan covers the results, I wanted to say a few words about the economic environment, the reengineering effort plan for the fourth quarter, and our perspective on funding.  Given the difficult operating environment, our business performed relatively well this quarter.  We've been very cautious about the economic outlook for most of this year and that certainly continues today.  But based on recent trends, we believe consumer and business sentiment is likely to deteriorate further, and we see this translating into weaker economies around the globe well into 2009.</p>
          <p>The market turmoil of the past few weeks is clearly going to make conditions even more challenging.  Cardmember pending in such an environment is likely to be very soft.  Loan growth will be restrained and some of that will reflect the steps we're taking to lower credit risk.</p>
          <p>Credit indicators are likely to reflect the weaker economy including a continued downturn in the housing sector. To prepare for this more difficult environment, we're moving ahead with plans that will result in restructuring charges in the fourth quarter.  Through a combination of cost reductions and revenue building actions, we expect to be able to free up a significant amount of resources that would be available to earnings starting in early 2009.</p>
          <p>We will continue to invest in longer term business building actions and programs but we're going to be very selective with our investment dollars in this environment.  Our intent is to be in the strongest possible position to weather an unsettled economy that will be with us well into 2009.  In that context, we outlined our funding position in an 8-K filed a few weeks ago and noted that we now have broader access to the Fed's discount window.</p>
          <p>The headline so to speak is this. I believe that we can absolutely stay liquid.  We have contingency programs in place that would allow to us navigate through this environment for at least 12 months, even under extreme market conditions.  By way of an update since the filing, we are now also a position to participate in the commercial paper funding guarantee programs that were recently announced by the fund.</p>
          <p>In short, we feel very good today about our overall funding position.  We expect to be in a position to capitalize on growth opportunities once the environment improves.  But for now, our focus is on staying liquid in our funding, staying profitable, and generating excess capital and investing but very selectively in growth opportunities, and we are confident that we can do all three.</p>
          <p>I'm going to turn the call over to Dan for his remarks and then we will be very happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ken.  Let me start on slide two with our top line financial information.  Revenues on a GAAP basis grew 3%.  I would note that on a managed basis, they grew 9%.  Diluted EPS of $0.74 was 21% below 2007.  This is a result of a slowing in spend growth as well as higher credit losses. ROE remains very healthy at 27.8%.  This performance is below our on-average and over-time financial targets and will continue to be as long as the economy remains weak.</p>
          <p>Looking now at slide three, we have a number of changes in reporting.  First, AEIDC is an investment subsidiary of AEB, which we closed the sale in the first quarter of this year, and we agreed to retain this sub until September of '09.  Now that we are within one year, we are going to move this from continuing operations to discontinued operations.  AEIDC has about 660 million of assets. Cash represents 340 million of that total.  We filed an 8-K on September 12, restating data back to 2006.</p>
          <p>Next is the net write-off rate. As you know, we have historically included principal, interest, and fees in our calculation of net write-off rate.  Back in the first quarter, I indicated that we would be moving to the industry standard that only includes principal in the write-off rate.  So we have done that this quarter and we have restated the prior period information.</p>
          <p>Next is the 30-day past due methodology change.  As you know, we have various cycles throughout the month. They don't all end at the end of the month.  It is the practice in the industry to take cash received after the cycle cut, which could be anytime during the month, and apply it to the oldest delinquency bucket. We had not done that in the US, and so we are now changing to the industry standard and again prior period information has been restated for that.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide four and speaking about capital, despite the impact of the slowing economy on our results, through earnings we retained or increased capital by over $600 million in the third quarter and by almost $2 billion year to date.  This demonstrates our capital generation power of our business model. We did not repurchase shares in the third quarter, and we do not plan to repurchase shares as long as the economy remains weak.  Instead, we will continue to build capital.</p>
          <p>Looking at slide five, our metric performance, billed business continues to grow faster than our competition at 8%, although it has slowed.  In the first quarter, billed business grew by 14% and in the second quarter by 12%. During the third quarter, while the average was 8% growth, September grew at 5%, and we have seen a further slowing in the first 15 days of October.  Business was stronger in international Consumer, Global Corporate Card, and GNS [Global Network Services], although we did see some slowing in the third quarter in each of these businesses. In the quarter, we added 2 million net new cards since the second quarter and 7.4 million net new cards since last year.  In the quarter, we had 4% growth in proprietary cards and 25% in network cards.</p>
          <p>If we look at managed loans, we had growth of 5%.  This is about the same as our competitors.  We are not growing faster than the industry.  This is a reflection of the economy, slowing spend, and our credit actions.  I would also note that travel sales have slowed significantly from last quarter.</p>
          <p>Looking now at slide six and revenue growth, GAAP revenue as I mentioned in the bottom right-hand corner grew at 3%; but on a managed basis, we grew 9%.  Discount revenue grew 5% based on the 8% billed business growth that we saw.  Net card fees reflect proprietary card growth and higher average fees per card. Net interest and securitization income decreased 7%.  The decline was driven by lower securitization income due to higher credit losses and a write-down in our IO [Interest Only] strip.  Net interest income increased 13% as higher net interest yields more than offset the lower owned loan balances on the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>We will see pressure on yield in the fourth quarter due to current LIBOR levels which are way off historic relationships to Fed funds.  Historically, LIBOR has been 20 to 40 basis points above Fed funds.  In early October, they were nearly 300 basis points above Fed funds and peaked at 4.59%.  This is the one-month LIBOR rate.  So we will be watching this closely and the relationship between LIBOR and Fed funds. Fortunately today, LIBOR dropped 43 basis points and now stands at 3.75%, and we will continue to watch its direction.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide seven, in terms of metrics within USCS, here billed business grew at 4%, down from 6% in the second quarter and 8% in the first quarter.  Small business growth has been higher than consumer throughout '08.  We continue to acquire cardmembers with positive economics and we encourage creditworthy cardmembers to spend, but we are managing small business spending very closely. Credit operations is limiting or stopping spending on customers with high probability of default. We continue to selectively invest in US consumer and small business and grew cards in force 4%.</p>
          <p>Cardmember loans, you can see we securitized about 35% of loans as of the third quarter of '07.  We've historically securitized less loans that our competitors, so we've had the capacity to do more securitization in a period of stress, and that is exactly what we've done this year. As I'll discuss later, approximately 50% of our funding was unsecured and 50% was done through securitization.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide eight, metric performance for international consumer, we continue to have strong metrics in international consumer, although we did see some slowing in billed business in the third quarter.  FX-adjusted growth in the first and second quarter was 10% compared to the 8% in the third quarter.  Cards in force growth and average spend growth reflect our investments in charge cards and premier lending in certain international markets.  Cardmember loans is well-controlled, although we did start to see some weakness in credit metrics in Mexico.</p>
          <p>Slide nine, Global Corporate Services also continues to have very solid metric growth, although again here billed business slowed in the third quarter.  First and second quarter growth on an FX-adjusted basis was about 10% and now we see 7% FX-adjusted growth. Cards in fourth (sic) [force] growth and average spend growth are very positive, although travel sales of 14% compare with 17% growth in the second quarter, again reflecting the slowing economy.</p>
          <p>Slide ten, Global Network and Merchant Services.  Spending growth of 8% was driven by 7% growth in US retail and everyday categories, which represent 70% of US billings and international spend growth.  US T&amp;E spending grew 2%.  Global Network Services continued to have very strong billed business growth at 29%.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 11, marketing and rewards growth of 7% reflects marketing at similar levels to the third quarter of '07 and higher rewards cost in line with volume growth.  HR and other operating is up 2%.  If we exclude the Visa and MasterCard payments which are netted on this line, it grew 10%, which reflects investments in sales force as well as investments in certain international consumer markets.</p>
          <p>Charge card provision, while increasing 72 million, continues to be well controlled.  Lending provision on a GAAP basis is up 65% with higher growth on a managed basis.  Both charge and lending reflects the impacts of the economy.  In a minute, I'll review a number of credit metrics with you.  Before I leave this slide, you'll note that the tax rate is 20%, which reflects the resolution of certain prior period items, prior year items, and the benefit of the revision of an estimate in the annual effective tax rate.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 12, the net charge card loss ratio has increased slightly across each of the businesses.  Overall, the loss rate increased by four basis points.  We continue to control spending very thoughtfully, balancing both the short-term and long-term view.</p>
          <p>Looking at slide 13, we see the charge card 90-day past due have also moved up slightly across each business.  In aggregate, past dues have increased 20 basis points, although we are seeing a greater impact on the P&amp;L from our lending portfolio, which we'll look at next.</p>
          <p>On slide 14, you can see the net write-off rate.  In the second quarter, we indicated to you that the third quarter write-off rate would increase.  The US write-off rate increased 60 basis points compared to the second quarter, and the US is up 290 basis points compared to the third quarter of '07. This rate is faster than some of our competitors' growth rates.  This is due to three reaches we've discussed before.  Small business is a higher percentage of our business and small business has a higher write-off rate, although small business continues to be very profitable.  We have a greater concentration in cardmembers and balances in Florida and California because it is a more affluent area. And due to the housing environment, we are seeing higher losses there.  In addition, we have historically had faster growth in spending and a consequent faster growth in loans, although I'll point out that in the third quarter, we are growing at the same rate as our competitors.</p>
          <p>In the US while the write-off rate in the quarter was 5.9%, the write-off rate in September was 6.1%.  We expect the fourth quarter to be higher than the third quarter and we expect the first quarter of '09 to be higher than the fourth quarter of '08.  International consumer picked up somewhat, primarily driven by credit metrics in Mexico.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 15, after only a modest increase in the second quarter, US lending managed 30-day past dues increased 60 basis points, reflecting both increases in the current to 30-day past due category and the 30-day to write-off roll rates.  Reflecting the inherent risk in the portfolio, we increased managed credit reserves by over $250 million.  International consumer 30-day past due had a more moderate increase, again largely driven by Mexico.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to capital funding and liquidity. On slide 16, you can see our capital ratios.  We believe that we have historically been very prudent in our approach to capital retention, which was very consistent with our goal of maintaining a strong A rating.</p>
          <p>Let me just speak for a moment about the rating agencies. Today, Moody's moved our parent company rating from A1 to A2, and our funding subsidiaries AA3 to A1.  Moody's previously had our funding subsidiaries a notch above all the other rating agencies.  They also reaffirmed our short-term rating of P1.  They have us on negative outlook given the current economic environment in capital markets.  This is similar to many other financial institutions.</p>
          <p>I'd also note that S&amp;P put us on negative outlook in July and we meet with them and other rating agencies periodically to update them on our financial results, capital, and liquidity plans.  We believe those plans are both thoughtful and will enable to us continue to fund in this difficult environment.  And our strong capital position provides us with the strength given the liquidity environment as well, so a combination of capital funding and liquidity plans we believe put us in good stead. Despite the environment, we continue to generate capital during these difficult times compared to some others who have taken substantial hits and needed to raise additional capital.  We will continue to generate capital and we will continue to forego our share repurchase until business conditions improve.</p>
          <p>As you can see from the chart, our capital ratios improved through 2008.  We have a well-established method with the rating agencies doing a bottoms-up calculation, asset by asset, to calculate our capital needs.  Then we keep a layer of surplus on top of that. In 2008, we are building that surplus to higher levels.</p>
          <p>I'll also note related to capital that based on a Treasury Department clarification issued today, it suggests that we may be eligible for the Capital Purchase Program.  We will be reviewing the program's details and definitions.</p>
          <p>Let me move to slide 17, funding.  Our goal is to fund ratably over the year.  We have been successful at meeting this goal in 2008, funding when many other companies could not, although we have paid higher spreads.  As you can see in the chart, we raised $23 billion year to date compared to a funding plan of 27 billion.  This funding has had a weighted average term of six years, although from a spread perspective, we have paid 165 basis points above one-month LIBOR.  In recent years, we had been paying 20 to 40 basis points above one-month LIBOR.</p>
          <p>We also are looking to continue to diversify our funding sources.  The new retail note program which began in late August has raised $400 million with maturities from 3 to 5 years.  The CD program which started a few weeks ago has raised almost 200 million with maturities ranging from three months to two years.  It is our plan to expand our funding from deposits.</p>
          <p>Turning to commercial paper, we have had full access to CP at historical levels, at similar prices, although the weighted average maturity has become shorter. In August on a daily basis, we funded 745 million, in September on a daily basis 864 million.  The average cost during that period was 2.56%.  In October on an average daily basis, we have funded 627 million and the cost has been 5.15% -- I'm sorry, 2.15%, thank you.  However, similar to other financial institutions, long-term unsecured and secured markets have been unavailable since mid-September.</p>
          <p>Now I will review our liquidity plan, which we believe is comprehensive and enables to us meet our funding needs even if we do not have access to commercial paper, unsecured, or secured markets. Looking at slide 18, as you would expect, liquidity has been an important focus for us.  On October 6, we filed an 8-K outlining the strength of our liquidity plan.  More recent announcements by the Federal Reserve further strengthen our position.  Let me review with you our funding needs over the next six months and 12 months and how we plan to utilize liquidity resources if commercial paper, unsecured, and secured markets are unavailable.</p>
          <p>So as you can see on the chart, we have a net funding need for commercial paper.  Our commercial paper is actually at a higher level, but from those issuances we're holding certain levels of cash.  So our net need for commercial paper is 4 billion, net bank time deposits is 2 billion, and we have maturing long-term debt of 12 billion.  We would meet those needs by using our liquidity investment portfolio of 5 billion, our conduit facility of 5 billion, as well as the commercial paper funding facility that is available to us.</p>
          <p>If we have to fund by 12 months, we would again have requirements of net commercial paper and net time deposits, but our maturing long-term debt would be 21 million.  So we have &#x2013; let me just modify that.  We have &#x2013; okay, so I was reading from an earlier draft.  In the first column, for six months we have 11 billion, a little lower than I said for six months.  And for 12 months in total, we would have a funding requirement of 24 billion.  In that case, again we would use our liquidity portfolio, the conduit facility, and we'd use the commercial paper funding facility which runs through April.  After that, we would rely on the temporary liquidity guarantee program where we can access we estimate $8.8 billion and then in combination with the Fed tax and discount revenue window would enable to us meet our 24 billion of funding needs.</p>
          <p>So the point here is not to demonstrate how it will play out but instead to give you an understanding of the various options we could deploy to ensure that the company can fund during a prolonged period of disruption.</p>
          <p>Over recent months, there has been a lot of discussion about the effectiveness wholesale funding model versus the bank deposit model. And while we see the merits of building a deposit capability, the reality is most people who have substantial deposits are also large capital markets borrowers.  The bottom line that is we believe we are well positioned with capital, funding capabilities, and liquidity resources to successfully navigate through this difficult environment.</p>
          <p>With that, let me conclude with a few final comments.  Despite the impact that the weakening economic environment has had on our customer spending, credit performance, and bottom line this quarter, many key business metrics that serve as an indicator of our competitive position continue to perform relatively well.  We see that in our overall billed business and cards in-force growth rates, where our performance demonstrates the benefits of our marketing and rewards investments over the past several years.  These benefits were more visible within our international consumer, Global Commercial Services, and Global Network and Merchant Services segments, where our volumes and card growth were relatively strong, although billed business growth did slow somewhat versus prior quarters.  In the US, the slowing growth in our managed lending balances is in line with the tempered spending environment but also reflects the proactive credit actions and tighter standards that we have implemented this year.</p>
          <p>In the quarter, despite the decrease in our owned loan balances, we did increase our loss reserve levels.  We believe this action is both appropriate and prudent, positions our reserve to reflect the inherent portfolio risk and our expectations for increased write-off levels, which we anticipate will rise further in the next two quarters.</p>
          <p>Our investment portfolios hold high quality securities and we did not recognize impairments within continuing operations during the third quarter. As you would expect, both spending and loan volumes slowed in the latter part of the quarter and into October as increasing stress in financial markets worldwide further eroded consumer and business confidence levels.  In addition, LIBOR rates have been particularly high in October and will negatively impact our variable debt borrowing cost during the month.  LIBOR levels in November and December will be another important factor impacting results in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, it's our belief that today's difficult economic environment will persist well into 2009.  We will be impacted by the resulting slowdown in spending as well as continued pressure on write-off rates.  However, we believe our business model will be positioned to generate earnings and free equity cash flow that will be built capital even in an economic environment that is likely to be the weakest we've seen in many years.</p>
          <p>We also believe that we have the capital strength, the funding in place, and the liquidity capacity and flexibility to effectively manage through these difficult market conditions.  In fact, our current liquidity resources, which have been enhanced by the benefits available through the Fed commercial paper funding facility and temporary liquidity guarantee program, are designed to fund maturing obligations and normal operations for at least 12 months even if capital markets are not available.</p>
          <p>We are working to best position the company to withstand the tasks that lie ahead.  Growth opportunities continue to exist in the marketplace. But over the coming quarters we will have to be even more selective with our investment dollars and work to prudently balance near-term performance against long-term profitability and growth.</p>
          <p>As we've indicated before, we will be implementing an accelerated reengineering program over the latter part of the year, which will result in a restructuring charge in the fourth quarter.  We expect the benefits of these actions to begin in the first quarter of 2009 and build throughout the year.</p>
          <p>In addition, we will also be implementing a number of pricing actions which will help mitigate the negative impact of the current credit market and economic environment.  The antitrust settlement we reached with Visa and MasterCard also provides with us a multiyear source of income that can help to lessen the impact of the environment; and when conditions improve, give us the ability to step up investments in the business.  Collectively, we believe these factors will position us for the difficult period that lies ahead.  While the current economic turmoil has negatively impacted our results, we continue to believe our business model remains strong and that we are positioned to generate returns to provide capital flexibility and strength.</p>
          <p>We have a strong position within the payments industry.  Our brand is recognized and respected around the globe.  We have shown the ability to adjust to the economic conditions, whether it be to implement defensive measures or take advantage of competitive opportunities.  Our balance sheet is appropriately positioned with capital funding and liquidity profile that provides us flexibility in these volatile times. And across all our businesses, we have instilled a strong focus on the customer, someone we need to stay close to regardless of the environment. Our ultimate goal is to ensure that American Express navigates through these conditions in the best position possible relative to our payments competitors and the overall industry.</p>
          <p>Thanks for listening, and we are now ready to take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have a question coming from the line of Bob Napoli with Piper Jaffray.  Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good afternoon.  Questions, I guess maybe a lot of questions and I will ask one or two.  The restructuring if you could quantify maybe the restructuring charge in the fourth quarter and the outlook for savings, benefits in '09 from the restructuring.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have not completed all of the work on what programs we are going to institute.  Once we do have those plans finalized, which we think will be in the near term within the fourth quarter, we will make an announcement in terms of what the reserve amount would be as well as the anticipating savings that will be generated through the restructuring programs.  But we think they will be very important in terms of enabling us to continue to generate earnings and capital in 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just on loan growth or the outlook for loan growth or shrinkage, in line with that because it is a denominator effect, where do you think peak &#x2013; I know it's very difficult to say, but if you could try to put some gauge around how high you think credit losses could go in 2009?  Is it 200 basis points above the current levels, so if you tie that into loan growth maybe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what you're seeing is as our spending growth has come down, our loan growth has come down at the same rate, which I think is a real positive.  I think that helps and it is a reflection of both the economy plus the credit actions that we are taking.  Now as that slows, it will have a negative effect on the denominator effect of the write off calculation. And as I said, we expect write-offs to increase over the next two quarters, but it is not our plan to actually forecast exactly how much they will increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Napoli.  Next question comes from the line of Chris Brendler of Stifel Nicolaus.  Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks, good evening.  Can you talk about your deposit-taking business? I take it the retail note program is on top of the deposits you already gathered. And did you regular grow deposits in the quarter? And just on a broader &#x2013; could you point out, I know you mentioned I guess or you alluded to the fact that you don't think you need to change your business model.  Why wouldn't it make sense to add a broader retail deposit capability at this point given all the assets that are out for sale right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We would agree with you that it makes sense to diversify our funding sources.  I think the note program which raised 400 million since its inception in late August and the CD program which raised 200 million in just a couple of weeks is just the beginning of actions that we plan to take to really build a broader deposit base.  We think that makes a significant amount of sense.  And we're just at the beginnings of that and it will be a focus of ours over the next year. It's something that will take time to build, but we think over time, it will be an important part of our funding base.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say the other point that is important is as we look at payments, we are diversified in a major way in payments.  If we look at how we have been able to build out B-to-B, which has a lower credit risk, I think we have been able to demonstrate that there are some very attractive growth opportunities with a lower risk profile.</p>
          <p>What I also think is important is as we look at becoming if you will becoming a retail bank, we think there are other things that go with that that concern us.  We think what is critical is that we have a diversity of our business model. From a deposit standpoint, we are focused on making progress there through the programs that Dan went through.  But I think what is important to understand is the diversity that we have in our payments business model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two quick clarifications, one is what exactly do you mean by net CP? Why do you issue CP and then just stick it in cash? And then two, are the trust metrics for the lending portfolio affected by the delinquency rate methodology change? And that is it for me today.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we &#x2013; as part of our liquidity plan, we hold cash, which is very important to us because to the extent that other sources aren't available to us, we want to have sufficient cash so that we can bridge over into selling our treasuries that are a part of our liquidity program or bridge into the financing conduit. So it is really just to give us the flexibility in the short term to start to utilize the other facilities that we have in place.  That's the reason that we hold cash.  In terms of your next question about does the change impact the trust, the answer to that is no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it on the current basis or is it on the old basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the trust is done consistent with the new basis, which is applying to the older balance where there are the collections that come in after the cycle date.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so the change you made fits in with the trust.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>You have a question coming from the line of Craig Maurer with Calyon. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, two questions. One, could you elaborate on the pricing changes you mentioned? And two, regarding the spending behavior you're seeing, you had alluded to spend shift in the states toward more commodity driven everyday type spending.  Do you think that you're losing spending from your good clients to existing debit cards in their wallet because of the type of spending that a lot of their funds are going toward now?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the pricing changes I think given the environment that we're facing, we will put pricing changes in.  It won't be broad based; it will be surgical to certain portions of the portfolio.  But we'll be putting in some pricing changes that will increase APRs for certain customers by 2 or 300 basis points.  We think it's prudent given the nature of those products and the economic environment that we face.</p>
          <p>As it relates to spending behaviors, I think for many years we have been focused on shifting more and more spend to the everyday category. We think that has been part of what has enabled us to continue to take market share in the US and certain markets internationally.  We're going to continue to push into those areas because we think it's beneficial to the long term health of the franchise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say I think that certainly what we have seen from the major issuers would suggest that we are continuing to have a very strong position with the affluent customer, and we have not seen signs of debit encroaching upon share in those categories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Even though our spending did slow compared to prior quarters, our spend was still stronger than the competition, so it appeared that we're continuing to take market share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I follow up on the pricing just quickly?  Are you doing anything on the merchant or the issuing bank side in terms of your pricing, whether it is discount rate related or cross-border fees related?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We continue on the merchant side to price based on value.  As you're aware, our discount rate would normally fall by 2 or 300 basis points a year as we push into more everyday spend categories.  But because we bring value to certain categories, we've gone back to them and repriced.  So we will continue to use the same philosophy of pricing based on value with our merchants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think at the end of the day, merchants are very focused on driving volume, and we have programs that help them drive that volume in their places of business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Sanjay Sakhrani from KBW.  Please go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, just a question, Dan.  On the higher LIBOR rates, just so I'm clear, how much of your funding is variable rate and subject to LIBOR impacts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About 70% is currently variable rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so basically that is how we should think about the impact in aggregate from a margin standpoint, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are two impacts.  One is the extent LIBOR is just higher, it affects all of our funding, but it's particularly important as it relates to our variable price products because there we're looking for a normal spread between prime and LIBOR, which has historically been about 270 basis points. To the extent that there is compression on that spread, that will affect our profitability and our margins as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How much of your assets are variable rate, 40%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of our loans, about 60% are variably priced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  Just a question on this temporary liquidity guarantee program, when does it actually kick in?  And this subject of meeting the criteria for participation, have you guys looked into it?  You do qualify, right, I'm assuming, because you put it in the chart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we do qualify.  I think there are still a lot of learnings to be had on exactly how the program will work.  What we've done is looked and seen that of our unsecured debt between September 30, '08 through June 30, '09, we estimate that $8.8 billion will mature and qualify for this program.  There may be some other aspects that potentially qualify, but based on our reading, we feel pretty certain that the 8.8 will be qualifying for the guarantee.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And it will kick in when?  I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think they have to administratively get the program up and running.  I know that the commercial paper program, they have had discussions with a number of people including ourselves and they're actually going to have registration for the commercial paper program starting I think on the 27th of October; and then I think shortly thereafter, people will be able to access it.  I don't know the exact timing on when we'll be able to benefit from the liquidity guarantee program.  I think that's all in the process of evolving.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and just one final one.  I just want to make sure I understand.  Is there is a P&amp;L impact from the charge-off rate disclosure change or were you always suppressing revenues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is no impact on the P&amp;L.  It is really just a matter of what line item it flows through on the P&amp;L.  Regardless of what line item it flows through on the P&amp;L, it really is just a matter of what people include in this write-off calculation.  We happened to be including principal, interest, and fees; and other people were only including principal.  There is no impact on the bottom line of our income statement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It just makes it easier to compare.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right, great; thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, we do have a question coming from David Hochstim with Buckingham Research. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, following up on that, in the quarter was there any effect from increasing the amount of loans that you securitized on provisioning or is that of a longer term effect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think when we do securitizations, when you look at the GAAP P&amp;L, we would be putting up reserves on the GAAP P&amp;L for all owned loans that are on our books.  And the impact of credit for the piece that's securitized is running through securitization income, which has always been the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I'm just trying to think about what you show as the loss provision, if you secure more, then the loss provision would be somewhat less?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On a GAAP basis, that's right.  But we also &#x2013; in the press release, the attachments give you what the provision would be on a managed basis.  So you can look at it either on a GAAP basis or you can use the material in the attachment to do a calculation of what it would be on a managed basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then could you also just tell again with the change in LIBOR, how much of the 100 million change in valuation of the IO is related to interest expense and how much is credit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know that we have broken that out.  I think it is both a combination of interest and credit, but I would say that credit is the thing that had the greatest impact on the IO strip.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And again just in terms of sensitivity to LIBOR, meaning elevated relative to Fed funds, there is not much IO left.  If you didn't have another adjustment in credit, there is not that much more to take as a write-down, is there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The IO strip now stands at 37 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just finally, could you or Ken provide some color on the increase in charge card loss ratios and I guess delinquency rates and how much of that is small business and how much is consumer and what's going on this cycle relative to say 2002 or 1992 in terms of the deterioration that you're seeing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we did see a tick up this quarter.  We saw a very modest increase in provision in the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Charge-offs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Charge-offs, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The year over year number, I mean there is a big increase year over year there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a $72 million increase in provision in charge card.  But when you really look at our total company, our total business, the real impact is coming from lending.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, I understand.  I'm trying to understand though because historically, charge card businesses had lower loss rates and it is quite low and international I guess even with Mexico and in corporate, but the ratio is showing a pretty significant uptick and I'm wondering if you're seeing that in consumers or small business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But the point is we have been at historical lows. We're coming off historical lows on charge card.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so is it small business that is accounting for most of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it is a combination of both.  We historically had and currently have higher loss rates on our small business portfolio than we have on consumer. But quite frankly, both of them have moved up at relatively similar rates, so there is no unusual disproportionate impact from small business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it's a major difference in the rate relative to small business and consumer, but we've seen some obviously worsening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, we do have a question coming from the line of Ken Bruce with Merrill Lynch.  Please go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good evening, gentlemen.  I understand you don't want to be overreactive to the current market environment, but I guess I would like to better understand your pricing strategy in terms of having surgical price increases on certain parts or certain products within the franchise is certainly understandable, but it looks like the funding pressure is going to be much more broad based and is going to have a significant compression in margins overall.  I'd like to know how you're going to balance between the pressure you're seeing on the funding side of the business with only maybe limited pricing power or willingness to reprice and how you're going to balance that for overall profitability, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The funding pressure is going to come. Certainly if markets stayed frozen for a protracted period and LIBOR stayed up, it would put tremendous pressure.  I think all the actions that the government is taking are designed to help thaw the freeze that we see in the markets.  If that happens, it would be logical to expect that LIBOR would start to come down.  Now last week, it was pretty stubborn and it only came down a limited amount. But today, we saw a pretty big drop in the one-month LIBOR rate.  I think it was 42 basis points.  So if LIBOR would stay at these levels four plus, that would put tremendous pressure.  I guess I would say it's my expectation that it's not going to go back to the 20 &#x2013; 40 basis points above Fed funds, but it would improve significantly from here.</p>
          <p>I guess the other thing that I would say the pricing is only a portion of our reengineering.  So our reengineering also has elements that are looking at costs, whether they be the structure that we have currently in terms of our employee contingent or whether it's looking at processes.  So we're going to obtain some benefit in reengineering from pricing but also a very significant benefit from the other actions that we're going to take on the cost side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there is a strong focus on expenses and we also believe that there are opportunities to shift more volume from offline to online.  And we think there are adjustments that we can make in our expense structure not just to deal with 2009, but in fact to have a business model that allows us to compete in a more effective way on a multiyear basis.  This is not just a situation that we're focused on revenues and making changes relative to pricing, but we in fact have gone through an expensive exercise &#x2013; extensive exercise as far as our expenses are concerned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's the piece that you'll be taking in the fourth quarter and providing some additional clarity around that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  On the &#x2013; I can understand not wanting to react to LIBOR but spreads are obviously wide as well.  How much of the liquidity backstop in terms of the ABS conduit facility and commercial paper funding facility, is that pricing already established or is that something you're going to have to go to an at-market type financing relative to LIBOR as well as spreads? And maybe separately, what is your big picture economic backdrop that you have got in your own forecast, particularly as it relates to unemployment here in the US, which is quite important?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the funding side based on our understanding for commercial paper, three-month paper, what we can estimate the pricing would be, would be about what we would pay today for three-month paper.  So we think on the commercial paper side, it will be competitive. Within the liquidity guarantee, we'll have to see what the market prices are for our rating with a government guarantee.  I don't think that has really played out yet but I would think that those are going to be at market prices. And as I say, we'll have to see how it evolves.  I don't think there will be any steep premium there in either case. There is a small fee related to participating in the commercial paper market, but it's relatively modest.</p>
          <p>Now switching over to economic outlook and unemployment, our assumption as we do our planning for next year is that unemployment will increase reasonably substantially in 2009, and we're reflecting that in our thinking in terms of where we think credit losses will be and where billings level will be. And that I might call pessimistic but probably realistic view of where the economy will be is what caused us as a management team to decide that it was appropriate to do reengineering so that we can, as Ken said, both deal with the short term but also position ourselves well for when the economy improves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We do have a question coming from the line of Bruce Harting with Barclays Capital.  Please go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you just give us an update on the ABS market and any plans to try to tap that in the fourth quarter? And then when I look at the long-term funding in the American Express Bank FSB and Centurion Bank, can you just remind us what charters you have there? And as part of restructuring when you talk about that, is that inclusive of debt restructuring?  You said you don't need a retail bank, but if you could remind us what &#x2013; how flexible are those bank charters and the ability to continue to fund longer term through those and at what cost?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Since mid-September, I think we did an issuance in the second week of September.  I don't think in the last four weeks, any major financial institution has done any long-term funding.  I think maybe Caterpillar did a small offering somewhere in late September, but basically both the secured and unsecured markets are frozen and unavailable to either us or anyone else in financial services.  No one has ventured into those markets.  Certainly I think many people are hopeful that the actions that the government is taking are designed to directly help thaw that freeze. And if the markets are open, we will access those markets.</p>
          <p>I think you could look in the early part of 2008. When many people were not able to fund, we were able to fund.  We funded ratably over the quarters based on our funding plan, even though we needed to pay up in terms of spread.  So if the markets open, we think we'll be one of the first people who have access; and if they're open, we will access them.</p>
          <p>In terms of our banks' charters, we have an ILC [Industrial Loan Corporation] in Utah, which we've had for many years.  We also have a Federal Savings Bank, FSB.  Those are our two banks. The FDIC regulates the ILC in Utah.  The OTS [Office of Thrift Supervision] regulates the Federal Savings Bank.  Both are well established institutions that have been with us for some time that enable us to fund our loan book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We do have a question coming from the line of Kevin Stiroh with Sanford Bernstein.  Please go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking my call. The ongoing credit crisis continues to move in unpredictable ways. I was hoping you could give a few specific examples about how you are responding differently during this economic downturn than you might have in previous ones.  Then I have a follow-up, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think our sophistication as a company is certainly light years better than it was in the early '90s and is substantially more sophisticated today than it was in 2001.  One of the &#x2013; each downturn is different in nature.  This downturn has had a lot to do with housing, so we have substantially improved our ability to integrate housing data, whether it be who you have your mortgage with or what geography you live in are things that we have built into credit scoring.  We also look at what industry you're in.  So if you're in an industry that's healthier, we may deal with you in a different way than if you're in an industry such as construction that is being impacted to a greater degree.</p>
          <p>We also obviously use all information that is available to us at credit bureaus, so we are very focused on not only what type of utilization you have on your line with us but the utilization you have with other institutions.  From there, we can see whether you are seeking additional credit.  So we look to integrate as many factors as we can.  What we've found is depending on the type of product you have, the level of spending you have, it could be different factors which are the most important to look at to help predict the probability of default.</p>
          <p>So we have very sophisticated models that are building in current information on a continuous basis, but we also are keenly aware of what's happening in the marketplace and building that into the decisioning at the same time.  And we're trying to balance the short term in terms of what our credit losses are, but we're also very focused on the long term, and we want to interact with our customers in a way so that we don't turn away customers who will be excellent, profitable customers in the long term.  So we're trying to work that delicate balance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think one of the important things is the micro-segmentation that we're engaged in. I think in the early '90s, we were new to the lending business with Optima.  We had a very limited product.  If you look at how we have been able to diversify our product line and also the fact that we have particularly in the US dramatically expanded our merchant coverage.  You had a situation in the early '90s that because of the limited merchant acceptance and the fact that we had a limited product line, we did not necessarily get some of the best customers.</p>
          <p>Now, the value propositions have substantially improved.  We have improved our merchant coverage. The competitive positioning of our products is quite strong and I think that that helps us in this environment.  But I think what's critical is with the range of products and customer segments that we have is to take all that Dan said and really then to bring it down to a micro-segment level, so that we are not just putting in actions that cover the entire card base.  We're really focused on micro-segmentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, and then a follow up; on page 5 of your slide deck, you show managed cardmember loans up 5% and owned loans down 9% year over year.  Could you walk through the economics of what determined the distinction in those growth rates?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, the managed growth is the growth of our entire portfolio, 5%, which is very consistent with our growth in spending.  The owned amount is managed loans less what we've securitized.  So we have securitized more receivables in 2008. And as a result, it's actually causing owned loans to be lower this year than last year.  So the managed number is reflective of the entire business.  The owned is just a matter of the fact we have done more securitization, as I mentioned before, during '08 because it's what was available.  That is causing owned loan growth to be down.</p>
          <p>From an economic point of view, whether receivables are owned or securitized, 100% of the economics related to those loans accrue to American Express.  On an economic basis, there is effectively no difference between the owned and managed loans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine, thank you.  I was wondering if you could talk a little bit about what the factors were that led you to securitize the larger fraction and why that was in your best interest in this scenario and this environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So for many years, many of our competitors have securitized at much higher levels.  We have always decided to keep our securitization levels down around 35%.  The reason for that is that we thought in stressed situations, secured lending would be more available at better prices than unsecured lending.  So now we are in a stressed situation and so we've decided to execute it against that basic plan and avail ourselves of the fact that we had more capacity to do securitizations. So this year instead of doing one-third securitization and two-thirds unsecured, we did it 50:50.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We do have our next question coming from the line of Scott Valentin with FBR Capital Markets.  Please go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening.  Thanks for taking my question.  Just referring to slide 18, the liquidity update, and thank you very much for providing that color, how much flexibility is there in determining &#x2013; this is based, next six months/12 months, but how much control do you have over the demand that you'll have for liquidity?  In other words, if utilization rates go up on credit cards or for some reason, spending goes up, et cetera, how much control do you have over the amount of liquidity you have to fund over the next 6 and 12 months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We obviously can control through authorizations and by bringing in new cardmembers what our volumes would be.  Certainly we will continue to invest and we want to continue to bring in cardmembers where we'll have good economic returns.  That obviously will be calibrated on what is taking place in the environment.  If it's more robust, we'll want to invest more.  If the economy slows down, we want to make sure that we're making investments that are getting the proper returns and therefore may moderate our investments.</p>
          <p>What you see here is what we need to meet the maturities that we have on the balance sheet.  To the extent we are having good spend growth and good loan growth, then I think in all likelihood in that situation, there is going to be access to the credit markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think if we're going to have good spend growth, it would mean that the overall economic environment is improving.  I would certainly take that trade.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To your point though that you could have greater utilization on lines but as we've discussed we are very focused on line size.  In the past year, we have had many more reductions in line size than we have in the past, and the number of line increases have been more moderate.  So we think we are being very active and thoughtful about how we're controlling spending and therefore loan balances.  I would point out we really have not seen any change in paydown rates, which is another thing that could affect it.  So we think that we have the ability to calibrate our business based on the environment and wouldn't see that causing any undue stress beyond the funding needs that you see on slide 18.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one follow-up regarding capital, prudently you've let the capital ratio rise as the economy or the environment has gotten worse.  Do you see a level where you feel comfortable that you have enough capital and you'll begin returning more capital to shareholders?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we think we have sufficient capital today.  However, given that the economy is slowing, we will continue to retain capital quite frankly until we see the economy turn.  And at that point, I think we'll go back to a process where we'll be returning capital to shareholders. We haven't changed our 65% on-average and over-time target. For many years when we were in a robust environment, we were returning more than 65%. So in a period of stress or slowdown, we'll return less than 65%. But on average and over time, we have not decided to change that 65% target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In this economic environment, we want to be cautious.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.  We do have a follow-up question coming from Bob Napoli with Piper Jaffray.  Please go ahead your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  A quick one on the tax rate, in this type of an environment, the US Card is the business that is under the most stress.  What would be a reasonable tax rate?  Could you give us -- give me a little help on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess we've said that around 30%-ish in normal circumstances would be a tax rate to think about.  Since the US is the highest &#x2013; has the highest tax rate within our mix, to the extent earnings there are lower, we'll see an impact. You shouldn't be thinking about 20% though.  It will be something lower than 30%, but I wouldn't give you a precise calculation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Your marketing spend was &#x2013; I thought you might &#x2013; one of the levers that you've talked about in the past in a tough environment to pull back on is marketing spend.  But the marketing spend was stronger than I thought it might be this quarter.  I was wondering if you could give some feel for that. Are you pulling back some levers on marketing spend given your outlook?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I would point out the vast majority of the 7% increase that we saw in the quarter on the marketing and rewards line was coming from rewards.  Marketing we held flat to '07 levels.  We thought there were sufficient opportunities to invest, whether it be in our merchant business or in certain markets internationally that it warranted keeping investment levels at a constant level.</p>
          <p>As we go forward, we'll be calibrating what amount of marketing that we want to have, which will be driven in part by how robust the environment is.  We'll continue to see rewards grow in line with the growth in spending.  Our rewards programs are really the thing that power our business, and we think it's a benefit that will help us whether it's a robust economy or a slow economy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and just one more time on your net exposure to LIBOR, the net effect on the company from the elevation in LIBOR, if you could maybe go through that one more time.  I'm not sure I was quite as clear on the effect on both assets and liabilities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so on our LIBOR, if rates go up, it will affect our cost of funds related to charge card, right, where we have no interest rate, or as it relates to our fixed rate lending products.  Fixed rate lending products make up 40% of our loans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, now if you look at the 60% of loans that are variably priced, we actually want to lock in a spread; so whether interest rates go up or down, we would be indifferent.  We would be looking for that locked-in spread.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There is no effect ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no; however, that locked-in spread is dependent on LIBOR staying with historic levels as it relates to Fed funds.  So usually, LIBOR has been 20 to 40 basis points above Fed funds.  Since we've priced to our customers off of prime and prime is driven by Fed funds, to the extent LIBOR increases beyond that historic level of 20 to 40 basis points above Fed funds, that creates compression on our spread and will affect our P&amp;L.  So it's very important for us to have LIBOR at those historic relationships.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's 100% of the fundings against the charge card?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You also have to take into consideration that 30% of our funding is fixed rate.  And you also have to take into consideration that we don't fund receivables from charge or loans from lending products 100% with debt.  Part of it is funded with capital and part of it is funded with non-interest bearing liabilities that we have on our books like the rewards liability.  So you have to factor all those aspects in, in terms of calculating the impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We do have a final question follow-up from Sanjay Sakhrani with KBW.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  I guess my question was on the tax rate to which you answered prior to that.  But maybe just another &#x2013; try this question another time.  From the deposit gathering franchise standpoint, would you guys consider the right acquisition opportunity if it was presented to you guys, and are you guys actively looking for anything? Ken, maybe you can answer that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the reality and my position has been pretty consistent here.  If an acquisition will accelerate our progress and improve our business model, we're open to it.  But I think the important thing about the focus on retail deposits is it also comes with a lot of other stuff.  And the question is what are the economics, what is the growth going forward, and how are we positioned relative to the other opportunities we have to generate growth.  And what we think is that we are evolving a funding strategy that will allow us to navigate through these challenging times. And we also think the way we have diversified the company to increasingly build our business in those areas that are not as reliant on credit balance the company's growth and risk as we go forward.</p>
          <p>And so I think what is important &#x2013; and I often give this example in the company, is to do a deal where in fact 10% of that deal is going to have an impact on your business and 90% of it is really not core to driving it and the economics are not that good.  We have to be very careful.  So my point is that we're open to a range of opportunities.  But what I'm going to be very focused on is will it generate the type of economics that we need to drive our company and will it in fact accelerate our growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks everybody for joining the call.  Take care.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Ladies and gentlemen, this conference will be available for replay after 7:00 PM today until October 27, 2008 at midnight.  You may access the AT&amp;T Executive Playback service at any time by dialing 1-800 -475-6701 and entering the access code 961476.  Again, those numbers are 1-800-475-6701 and entering the access code of 961476.  And international participates may dial 1-320-365-3844 and enter the same access code of 961476.</p>
          <p>That does conclude our conference for today.  Thank you for your participation.  And for using AT&amp;T Executive Teleconferencing service.  You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>