<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1128125" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-01-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>664</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">David Brennan, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Simon Lowth, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John Patterson, Executive Director, Development</participant>
      <participant id="3">Kevin Wilson</participant>
      <participant id="4">David Brennan</participant>
      <participant id="5">Simon Lowth</participant>
      <participant id="6">John Patterson</participant>
      <participant id="7">Graham Parry</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jo Walton</participant>
      <participant id="9">Tony Zook</participant>
      <participant id="10">Mark Purcell</participant>
      <participant id="11">Bruno Angelici</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. Welcome to AstraZeneca's review of our 2007 performance. In addition to hearing from me today which depending on how my cold goes &#x2013; John is my rescue man, if something goes down here with my throat. Simon Lowth, our Chief Financial Officer, and John will also be making more in-depth presentations filed in on the financials John, taking you through the changes and the activities that are really driving our view of our pipeline.</p>
          <p>And then there are several of our executive team up here, notably from the rest of world business is Bruno Angelici and then Tony Zook, who runs North America as well as our global marketing group. They will pitch in during the Q&amp;A session with any questions you have that are specific to them. I'm sure there will be some. We are looking forward to the review this afternoon to talk about how our business performed over the course of the last year, to talk about the prospects for the future, and then to engage in discussion with you and to answer any questions that you might have.</p>
          <p>Now, despite the increasingly challenging environment that affects the research-based industries that we are part of, I think 2007 was a year of pretty significant achievement for AstraZeneca. We made progress in all areas that we have identified as our strategy priorities. In terms of the underlying financial performance, we delivered earnings per share that were ahead of the targets that we set at the beginning of the year. This was a result of both sales growth as well as operating margin improvements when you adjust for the one-off changes that we have put in the figures.</p>
          <p>We made excellent progress toward delivering on what I believe is a comprehensive program that we are using to reshape our cost base and to improve the efficiency and the effectiveness of the organization globally. And it has affected all parts of the organization; it's not something that is exclusively done just in G&amp;A or in a particular part of the company. And that includes some restructuring in the R&amp;D area as well. So if you want to talk about that we can.</p>
          <p>I'm very pleased with the way the entire organization has embraced what I think of as a culture of continuous improvement in meeting this productivity challenge, not just in the formal restructuring initiatives but the day-to-day performance of people and the work that they do in their jobs. I think that the formal restructuring program is proceeding to plan, Simon will take you through that.</p>
          <p>We realized $300 million in benefits from the program and that's a good start toward the target we have of $1.4 billion in annual restructuring and synergy benefits that we will deliver by 2010. More importantly I think delivering on our earnings targets, reshaping the cost base, continues to provide funding for us to invest in strengthening our pipeline.</p>
          <p>Revenue investment in research and development in 2007 reached over $5 billion last year, excluding restructuring costs. And we also made significant capital commitments to increase the strength of our pipeline in terms of both quality and quantity.</p>
          <p>Clearly the most decisive step that we took was to create the new MedImmune, strategically integrating the former Cambridge Antibody Group that was part of AstraZeneca as well as our other biologics assets and put them all together after we acquired MedImmune to create a biologics business.</p>
          <p>We have now one of the world's largest biologics pipeline. And we've established AstraZeneca as a leader in biotechnology among our pharmaceutical peers. I know that some of you gathered with us in, at MedImmune in Gaithersburg, Maryland, last month for a review of the biologics business, and the feedback that we received is that you are impressed by the quality of the people there, the depth and breadth of the technology platforms, and the pipeline which now has more than 100 projects in it.</p>
          <p>In addition to the acquisition of MedImmune, we made capital investments for smaller acquisitions to access technologies and products to further strengthen our business in the fields of diabetes, obesity, asthma, and COPD, in oncology as well as an acquisition for our dental implants business. In 2007, we made excellent progress across all fronts in our R&amp;D organization, and you will get a complete update on that from John in just a few minutes on what has been accomplished.</p>
          <p>But let me say this: it has been a record year for new candidate drugs entering development as well as for the number of projects reaching the first time in man milestone. Fixed new Phase III compounds were added in 2007, bringing the total number of Phase III projects in the pipeline to ten, and on balance it's been a year of significant achievements despite the ever-challenging environment, achievements that are credit to the efforts of all of our people, all of the employees across AstraZeneca, people that are committed for making a meaningful difference to patients' health.</p>
          <p>Now let's move to an overview of the financial results for the year. Just a quick look first at sales. Sales for the full year were nearly $29.6 billion &#x2013; excuse me. That is an increase of 12% on a recorded basis or 7% at constant exchange rates; that's a good performance.</p>
          <p>The sales contribution of MedImmune, since the inclusion of MedImmune on June 1, was about $714 million. Of that, the addition of MedImmune more than offset the $413 million in lost sales in the U.S. from Toprol-XL. As you know, Toprol-XL experienced generic competition across the entire dosage range from August onwards.</p>
          <p>The five key brands delivered sales growth of 11% in constant currency, with Crestor and SEROQUEL the key drivers this year. And we are continuing to reap the benefits &#x2013; excuse me &#x2013; of our increasing investment in the emerging markets where sales were up 17% in constant currency.</p>
          <p>Moving down the P&amp;L, operating profits were just over $8 billion; that is down 4%. If you exclude the restructuring and synergy costs, operating profit was just over $9 billion; that was an 8% increase at CER [constant exchange rate]. The reported earnings per share were $3.74 for the year; that is down 5% in constant currency. However, if you exclude the restructuring and synergy costs, which was the basis for our guidance, earnings per share were $4.20, which is ahead of the target range that we finalized at third-quarter results, and that range was 3.98 to 4.13 that we set that range on the same basis. So the 4.20 was ahead of what we thought we would do.</p>
          <p>The board approved a 10% increase in the second interim dividend which was announced today, and that brings the full-year dividend to $1.87; that is a 9% increase from the dividend over last year. In addition to that we had a net repurchase of our shares of $3.95 billion last year; our target was $4 billion. So we were right on there for that.</p>
          <p>I think what I will do is stop here for now and ask Simon to come up and get into much greater detail, including product highlights for you. Then the balance of the program will be given over to John to go through what is going on in R&amp;D. Following that we will open it up for Q&amp;A, and then right at the end I will just get up and make a few closing comments. So thank you for your attention and let me turn it over to our Chief Financial Officer, Simon Lowth. Simon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>David, thank you, and good afternoon to everyone. I'm very pleased to be here today presenting to you a fine set of results and my first at AstraZeneca. I'm going to cover four topics. First, I will summarize our financial results for 2007 and demonstrate that we broadly met or exceeded the performance targets that we'd set for ourselves and communicated to you.</p>
          <p>Next, I will describe the principal drivers of this strong financial performance, focusing in particular on our progress in driving the top line growth of our key brands and markets and in improving profit margins through operational efficiencies and restructuring. I will then review our performance in generating cash and how we allocated our cash between investment in research to drive future growth and returns, and distributions to shareholders. And then finally, I'll describe our business performance priorities and the financial targets that we've set ourselves for 2008.</p>
          <p>AstraZeneca has delivered a strong set of financial results for 2007. We've broadly met or in some cases beaten the targets that we set for ourselves during the course of the year. Excluding MedImmune and Toprol in the U.S., the business delivered sales growth of 7% in constant currency terms, consistent with our goal of high single-digit growth.</p>
          <p>We reduced our SG&amp;A costs in constant currency terms; we increased our investment in R&amp;D by 16%, and we still delivered a 180 basis point improvement in our underlying operating margin. We delivered earnings per share, excluding restructuring and synergy costs, of $4.20, compared with our latest guidance of between $3.98 and $4.13.</p>
          <p>We charged $966 million in restructuring and synergy costs, slightly ahead of our estimate of $900 million for the year, reflecting the pace of our restructuring efforts. And finally, we completed net share repurchases of 3.95 billion, nearly spot on with our $4 billion target.</p>
          <p>Reported earnings per share was $3.74, down 5% on 2006 in constant currency terms. However, adding back restructuring and synergy costs of $0.46 per share, we delivered earnings per share of $4.20, and this represents growth of 7% in constant currency terms.</p>
          <p>MedImmune's contribution for the last seven months of the year was, as expected, dilutive to earnings by $0.32 per share, due to the combination of intangible amortization of $255 million and additional interest costs of around $500 million. Adding back the MedImmune dilution, the underlying business delivered earnings per share of $4.52, representing growth of 15% over 2006 in constant currency terms. This 15% growth in underlying earnings was driven by a combination of top line sales growth and operating margin improvement, and it was achieved while significantly increasing our R&amp;D investment to laugh &#x2013; to drive long-term growth and value.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to the first driver of that earnings growth, namely our progress in sustaining our top line sales growth. Despite a challenging external environment characterized by pricing and market access pressures, we achieved sales growth excluding MedImmune and Toprol-XL of 7% in constant currency terms. We believe that this was brought in line with or perhaps slightly ahead of overall market growth.</p>
          <p>Our five key brands delivered 11% growth, equivalent to incremental sales of $1.5 billion in constant currency terms. These five products now generate revenue of $15.3 billion, just over 50% of total group sales. SEROQUEL, Crestor, Arimidex and Symbicort all showed double-digit growth, offsetting the decline in Nexium and demonstrating the impact of our investments in life-cycle management, sales and marketing effectiveness, and emerging market development.</p>
          <p>I now describe in more detail the performance of our key brands starting with Nexium. Sales for Nexium for the full year were $5.2 billion, down 2%, in line with our guidance that the brand would experience a slight decline in the year. Sales in the U.S. were $3.4 billion for the full year, down 4%. Underlying volume growth was 2%, with some one-off movements adding a further 2%. There was an 8% decline in net realized prices for the year, our strategy of focusing our sales and marketing efforts on growing share in the branded segment has ensured volume growth, and it has positioned Nexium as the only product to gain share in the branded segment. However, as part of our strategy, we have increased our rebates to key customers in the managed markets, placing some downward pressure on net prices.</p>
          <p>Average net price realization has also been adversely impacted by shifts in our sales mix, notably in the movement of Nexium volumes away from the noncontract market and towards higher rebate contracts within the managed-market segment. In the fourth quarter, U.S. sales for Nexium were down 18%, with underlying volume growth of around 2% being offset by a significant price variance.</p>
          <p>The same pricing effects that we have experienced through the year were evident in the quarter, but they are exacerbated by two additional factors. Firstly, the release of the TriCare provision in the fourth quarter of 2006 contributed around 5% in the year-on-year revenue decline. Secondly, the decline in average prices that we experienced during the course of the year disproportionately impacted revenues in the fourth quarter. This is due to the fact that, in common with the rest of the industry, our average rebates for revenue recognition are based on actual invoices, which can be received up to eight months in arrears. In effect, a disproportionate amount of the average price declines experienced in the year hit our revenues in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Nexium sales in the rest of the world were $1.8 billion for the full year, up 2%, with strong double-digit growth in the emerging markets more than offsetting the declines in Western Europe, where the brand faced similar competitive pressures to the U.S. What does that mean for Nexium sales in 2008? In the U.S., we believe that we can still grow volume in the branded market but with continued price declines, although not at the kind of rate implied by the fourth-quarter exit. Overall, we anticipate worldwide sales of Nexium in 2008 will be lower than 2007 in constant currency terms, potentially by up to mid-single digits following recent developments in the PPI market.</p>
          <p>SEROQUEL exceeded $4 billion in annual sales for the first time in 2007, with mid-teen sales growth in both the U.S. and our established markets, and growth of 32% in our emerging markets. In the U.S., total prescriptions for SEROQUEL increased 10%, more than twice the market rate for antipsychotics. SEROQUEL XR received its first approvals during 2007, limited in the first instance to the schizophrenia indications. We launched in August in the U.S., and just last month we received mutual recognition approval in Europe. So those launches will roll out over the course of the year.</p>
          <p>However, it's the comprehensive program of life-cycle management beyond schizophrenia that will really drive the growth of SEROQUEL XR over time, as we add the full complement of indications: bipolar mania, bipolar depression, and the new indications for major depression and generalized anxiety disorder.</p>
          <p>Crestor sales were $2.8 billion for the year, up 33%. Crestor sales outside the U.S. grew at 45% over the year and now represent almost half of total Crestor sales. Crestor performed particularly strongly in Western Europe where sales grew 26%, with notable performances in France and Italy, and in Canada, where sales grew 43%. And Crestor launches in Japan continues to go well; the volume share had reached 8.8% by November.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., Crestor sales were up 24% for the year, due principally to the year-on-year prescription volume growth of 22%, well ahead of the statin market growth of 8%, reflecting a 90 basis point share gain in average market share over 2006. We held ground in market share in 2007, hovering around 8.6% for the year, weathering the eight percentage points in market share gained by Simvastatin during the year.</p>
          <p>Crestor's new indication to slow the progression of atherosclerosis was approved in November. Given recent developments surrounding the Vytorin enhanced trials, the timing couldn't be better for the rollout of this indication. Our aim is to restore Crestor to market share growth in the coming year based on promotional campaigns for this exciting use indication.</p>
          <p>Arimidex sales reached $1.7 billion in 2007, up 10% year on year. Sales in the U.S. were up 13%. Total prescription volume growth of 5% was ahead of the market for hormonal treatments for breast cancer. In November, the FDA granted an additional six months of market exclusivity for Arimidex taking the effective patent life out to June 2010. Arimidex sales in other markets were up 8% for the year sales in Western Europe were up 6%; sales in Japan were up 9%, reflecting the strength of our oncology business in that market.</p>
          <p>Worldwide sales for Symbicort increased 22% to just over $1.5 billion. Sales in Western Europe were up 16%, with market share up a full point. Symbicort SMART is improving our competitive position in asthma, and we're also growing usage in COPD. In the U.S. we launched Symbicort in June. We're pleased with the early uptake amongst specialists, where among our target audience nearly 75% of allergists and more than 60% of pulmonary specialists have prescribed Symbicort. These specialists are now prescribing Symbicort for nearly one out of four patients that they start on combination therapy. Clearly, we need now to translate this performance with specialists into the broader GP market, and that will be a primary focus for our sales and marketing efforts during 2008.</p>
          <p>Alongside our portfolio of key brands, our investments in building our presence in emerging markets are also contributing strongly to top line growth. Our Emerging Markets business delivered sales growth of 17% in 2007 and accounted for nearly 45% of the total constant currency sales growth outside the U.S.; and this is profitable growth. Operating contribution in these markets grew faster than sales despite the investments that we are making.</p>
          <p>I will now turn to the second key driver of earnings growth in the underlying business, the improvement in operating margin. Underlying gross margin improved by 80 basis points on a constant currency basis. Market price pressures were more than offset by efficiency gains, reduced Merck royalty payments, and the impact of prior-year asset provisions.</p>
          <p>The supply chain restructuring program is proceeding to plan, although that will not meaningfully impact our gross margins before 2009. Our focus on cost discipline and efficiencies combined with the early benefits of restructuring reduced our underlying SG&amp;A costs by 2%, and drove a 230 basis point improvement in SG&amp;A as a percent of sales. Other income and distribution costs were flat as a percent of sales. The gross margin improvement and SG&amp;A efficiencies created a potential 310 basis-point improvement in our operating margins.</p>
          <p>To fund the development of our expanded late-stage pipeline and the early-stage research needed to sustain this pipeline, we invested over half of the improved margin capacity into increased R&amp;D investment. Specifically, we increased underlying R&amp;D by 16% and R&amp;D as a percent of sales by 160 basis points. As a net result, underlying operating margin still increased by 150 basis points in constant currency terms.</p>
          <p>In 2007, therefore, we have delivered on our performance priorities for the underlying business. We have sustained top line growth and driven efficiency improvements across the business, in order to fund increased investment in value-creating R&amp;D while providing year-on-year earnings growth.</p>
          <p>Having described the performance of our underlying business, let me now turn to MedImmune and its performance since our acquisition on June 1. MedImmune sales for the seven months were $714 million, the lion's share of that coming in the fourth quarter, reflecting the seasonal bias in the sales of both Synagis and FluMist. The other income contribution is a significant profit stream, principally derived from royalties on HPV vaccines. This income contribution should continue to grow as MedImmune earns royalties on the sales of the new vaccines for HPV from Merck and GSK.</p>
          <p>MedImmune's operating profit for the seven months, excluding the impact of acquisition and amortization costs, was $126 million, with all of that profit being made in the fourth quarter, given the strong seasonality of the current products. MedImmune's operating profit reverts to a loss of $178 million once we incorporate the one-time costs of the acquisition and the $255 million amortization charge on the acquired intangible assets. Including the interest on the debt financing of the acquisition, MedImmune contributes negative $0.32 to the group's earnings per share.</p>
          <p>This breakdown of MedImmune's performance explains the impact of its partial year of consolidation into our accounts, and should provide a sound basis for your future modeling. I should stress, though, that MedImmune is an integral part of AstraZeneca, and we will not report its performance in this level of detail going forward.</p>
          <p>I will now turn to our productivity, restructuring and synergy initiatives, which are a key component of our strategy and our performance priorities. We are now managing the restructuring programs and the integration and synergy projects with MedImmune on a combined basis. The total program and its constituent parts is firmly on track to deliver the targeted benefits. Total restructuring and synergy costs charged in 2007 were $966 million, just under half of the estimated total program costs of about $2 billion.</p>
          <p>On the benefit side of the ledger, $300 million in savings have been realized to date out of the target of $1.4 billion in annualized benefits by 2010. The majority of these savings have come from our SG&amp;A cost base. In terms of phasing, I expect around two-thirds of the remaining restructuring and synergy costs will be charged in 2008. And of the anticipated annual benefits of $1.4 billion by 2010, cumulatively two-thirds will be realized in 2008.</p>
          <p>Now let's look at cash flow which will be an increasingly important lens through which we will review and manage our performance. We entered 2007 with $6.5 billion of net cash. Our EBITDA at just under $10 billion was up $389 million on 2006, reflecting a combination of top line sales growth and increased cash operating margins after funding the increased investment in R&amp;D.</p>
          <p>EBITDA growth was, however, offset by higher working capital requirements, due substantially to the entry of MedImmune and the seasonal nature of its business. Overall, we generated $7.5 billion of operating cash flow, broadly on a par with our performance in 2006, bringing our total cash available for investment and distribution to $14 billion.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the deployment of cash, we invested $16.5 billion in building AstraZeneca for the future. Most significantly, we transformed our position in the biologics arena through the acquisition of MedImmune for $14.9 billion, establishing AstraZeneca as a leader in biotechnology with one of the world's largest biologic pipelines. We continued our efforts to secure attractive new molecules for development to complement our in-house discovery program, investing a net of 549 million, primarily in our externalization activities.</p>
          <p>And finally, we invested capital of $1.1 billion in extending and improving our R&amp;D facilities and our supply chain operations. Finally, we distributed a total of $6.6 billion to shareholders through dividends of $2.6 billion and net share repurchases of $4 billion. We have met the shortfall between our available cash and our investments and distribution through increased debt, taking us to net debt of $9.1 billion at the year-end.</p>
          <p>Turning to our capital structure, our overarching objectives have been to fund the acquisition of MedImmune and our wider R&amp;D program while maintaining a strong investment-grade credit rating. We have met our investment objectives, and our ratings confirmed in July at A1 with Moody's, AA-minus with Standard &amp; Poor's, both with a stable outlook.</p>
          <p>Since the mid-year, we have completed the refinancing of the short-term debt used initially to fund the MedImmune acquisition. We've issued bonds and notes totaling $9.8 billion with maturities ranging from two to 30 years. The result has been to significantly reduce the level of short-term borrowings which now stand at $4.3 billion. The effective interest rate on our gross debt was 5.5% at the end of 2007.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, we aim to reduce our level of net debt outstanding to our targeted level of 6 to $7 billion over a three- to four-year period. Over the first quarter of 2008, our net debt will increase as we use part of our current cash balance to fund the second interim dividend and the exit payment to Merck, but we do expect to begin to reduce our net debt over the remainder of 2008.</p>
          <p>Our performance priorities for 2008 are very clear. We will sustain our investment in life-cycle management, sales and marketing effectiveness, and targeted market development to grow our key brands and markets. We will deliver further productivity improvements through continued cost efficiencies and disciplines, and through the delivery of our restructuring program. We aim to bring an increased focus to cash management ensuring that we convert growth in EBITDA into cash. And finally and critically, we will continue to invest in R&amp;D to support and build our growing pipeline, and to drive long-term growth and value.</p>
          <p>Having described our performance priorities, let me now describe how these translate into the financial targets that we have set for ourselves. The first thing I should do is to make clear the basis upon which we are communicating our financial guidance for 2008. Our targets and the guidance we are providing reflect the operating performance of AstraZeneca and MedImmune on a combined basis. As we stated at the time of our third-quarter results, we will provide earnings guidance on a core EPS basis for 2008. For 2007, we determine core EPS by starting with the reported EPS of $3.74, adding back the restructuring and synergy costs which were $0.46, the MedImmune amortization of $0.12, and Merck-related amortization of $0.06, to arrive at a core EPS of $4.38 for 2007.</p>
          <p>For 2008, restructuring and synergy costs will, as I said earlier, amount to two-thirds of the remaining program. The MedImmune amortization charge will continue to run at the $36 million per month exit rate for 2007. And in addition to the existing $0.06 of amortization related to Merck, the 2008 exit arrangements may add to the Merck amortization by up to $0.04, depending upon Merck's selection regarding the first option.</p>
          <p>As we explained at the third quarter, our core EPS measure includes intangible asset impairments. For 2007, these amounted to about $100 million. Our 2008 guidance range for earnings per share assumes a comparable level of intangible impairments. Our guidance for tax rate both on a core and a reported basis is for around the 29.5% level seen in 2007.</p>
          <p>In providing our core EPS guidance, we have had to make some assumptions about currency exchange rates. Specifically, we have assumed that the U.S. dollar exchange rates for 2008 would follow the average rates experienced in the fourth quarter of 2007, being $2.04 to the pound, $1.45 to the euro, and 6.42 krona to the dollar. As you would expect, our earnings guidance is sensitive to exchange rate movements, and there is an appendix in the handouts that provides you the sensitivities to sales and earnings from movements in each of our principal currencies versus the dollar.</p>
          <p>Over the course of the year, I intend to review the various performance metrics that we use to measure the performance of the business internally, and this may have some implications for how we communicate our targets externally, and I will keep you updated on any changes in our thinking.</p>
          <p>Our target for 2008 is to deliver core EPS in the range of $4.40 to $4.70. The lower end of the range is set to reflect some of the uncertainties we face going into 2008, for example, the potential impact of recent events in the U.S. PPI market.</p>
          <p>For 2008, we expect to achieve constant currency sales growth in the low to mid-single digits. The impact of a full year of MedImmune sales should broadly offset the further declines from a full year of generic competition for Toprol-XL. I emphasize that this sales growth is, as is our standard practice, in constant currency terms at current exchange rates; our reported sales growth would be higher.</p>
          <p>We aim to hold our core gross margin at the same level achieved in 2007 in constant currency terms with the early benefits of our restructuring program benefiting the second part of the year and largely offsetting our first price and mix effects. We will continue to drive efficiencies in our SG&amp;A costs, which together with the further benefits from our restructuring program should keep core SG&amp;A costs flat in constant currency terms. We intend to increase our investment in R&amp;D net of improved efficiencies in that function by high single digits in constant currency terms as we deliver and expand our strengthening pipeline.</p>
          <p>We expect other operating income around the same level as 2007 with growth in the royalty streams from MedImmune offsetting some declines in the company's other activities. These are demanding targets in a challenging environment, but they're targets we are determined to deliver.</p>
          <p>The board has today declared a second interim dividend for 2007 of $1.35 per share, bringing the total dividend for the year to $1.87 per share, a 9% increase. The board's dividend policy is unchanged. We will continue to grow the dividend in line with reported earnings before restructuring costs while maintaining two times dividend cover. We provided guidance for 2008 on the basis of core EPS. However, for dividend purposes, we will continue to measure growth against reported earnings before restructuring costs to ensure that we maintain our target level of dividend cover and reserves.</p>
          <p>We expect other operating income at around the same level of 2007 with growth in the royalty streams from MedImmune offsetting some declines in the company's other activities. These are demanding targets in a challenging environment, but that target we are determined to deliver. The Board has today declared a second interim dividend for 2007 of $1.35 per share, bringing the total dividend for the year to $1.87 per share, a 9% increase. The Board's dividend policy is unchanged.</p>
          <p>We will continue to grow the dividend in line with reported earnings before restructuring costs while maintaining two times dividend cover. We provided guidance for 2008 on the basis of core EPS. However, for dividend purposes, we will continue to measure growth against reported earnings before restructuring costs to ensure that we maintain our target level of dividend cover and reserves.</p>
          <p>Moving to the share buyback, when we laid our financial policy in July 2007, we emphasized that the buyback is a return of surplus capital after providing for dividends, debt pay down and business investments. We also made clear that the level of buyback will be assessed annually by the board taking into account business needs. For 2008, I can confirm the guidance that we gave in July 2007 that we expect the share buyback for this year to be in the region of $1 billion subject to business needs.</p>
          <p>I will now hand over to John Patterson, who will describe the significant progress that we've made this year in improving our R&amp;D productivity and strengthening the pipeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Simon, and good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. 2007 was a year of significant achievements as we continued to strengthen our R&amp;D pipeline with more new potential medicines, faster cycle times and a leaner, more cost effective organization. We presented our biologicals pipeline in great depth in December, so today I am going to focus on the small molecules and in particular on those projects in Phase III we are undergoing life cycle management.</p>
          <p>I plan to conclude by giving you an update on our 2008 deliverables and in doing so to cover our recently completed disease area strategy and its implications, and the record number of planned registration applications and projects that we see going through proof of concept into Phase IIb in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Over the last three years, we've invested considerable time and effort improving the quality and the speed of our development cycle. We are on track to deliver a median cycle time of eight years from start of first GLP tox all the way through to launch by 2010, and have already taken 18 months out of our achieved and planned cycles. And we believe we are well on track for upper quartile industry performance. We speeded up our programs and doubled our Phase III pipeline with a flat to reducing head count through multiple R&amp;- wide activities and initiatives across the whole breadth of our activities. One achievement in 2007 was to deliver a record number of 36 candidates that were selected to progress into development. This compares with 22 in 2006.</p>
          <p>Our efforts to reduce attrition have resulted in 24 molecules entering human development during the course of the year, double the 2006 number, which was in itself a record.</p>
          <p>Through the acquisition of MedImmune our pipeline has grown considerably across all phases, and I'll come back to the ten phases &#x2013; ten projects in Phase III in some detail later in my presentation.</p>
          <p>Taking MedImmune, CAT and our previous Abgenics alliance, we now have a highly competitive world-class biologics capability all the way through from target identification through all the key delivery technologies in discovery, process development and manufacturing to enable us to discover, develop and sell biologics with a highly skilled knowledgeable and experienced work force.</p>
          <p>During the year, we've continued our emphasis on quality, speed and cost, leading to a better R&amp;D performance. We will maintain the emphasis on quality as exemplified by the increasing number of CDs coming through preclinical testing and entering &#x2013; together with a much stronger emphasis on families of molecules in our most important areas, meaning that we will always seek to have backups and follow-ups should the lead molecule fail.</p>
          <p>We are putting increasing emphasis on maximizing the cost effectiveness in our organization and this led us last year to reduce the layers of management and increase productivity in regulatory affairs and pharmaceutical analytical development. The outsourcing of our clinical data processing activities, as well as a number of Lean Sigma-driven cost effectiveness initiatives across all discovery areas are part of the drive for more project speed and reduced complexity.</p>
          <p>We've delivered significant improvements in our cycle times through the preclinical and clinical development phases. As with all research-based pharmaceutical companies, improving Phase II and Phase III timelines is a particular challenge in the face of increasing regulatory demands and hurdles. As our pipeline matures and more products are entering late Phase II and Phase III, we are placing particular emphasis on improving the quality, speed and cost elements of those parts of the program and embedding a performance-driven culture across the whole of R&amp;D.</p>
          <p>By selecting an increasing number of candidates to enter development over the last three years, working hard to lower early attrition rates, and speeding up the projects, we've created a bow wave of projects that has now entered man and is moving rapidly towards a record number of proof-of-concept decision points in the second half of this year and early 2009.</p>
          <p>As the pipeline progresses, in presentations like this, I'll focus more and more on the clinical development project in these presentations. So let me now focus on the pipeline. As in previous presentations, I'll start with the pipeline as it was this time last year. Since then, we stopped or delivered a number of the projects. In addition, we've progressed a larger number of projects as shown by the green boxes.</p>
          <p>And then we've added even more from our own laboratories through licensing and acquisition as shown in red, so that today, looking at the total pipeline, we have 95 projects in clinical development, of which 20% in our biologics, getting us very close to the 2010 ambition that we stated at the time we bought Cambridge Antibody Technology of having 25% of biologics as the molecules offered for Phase III development. As you can see here in a graphic representation of that bow wave of internal projects, as discoveries increased its productivity and delivered more molecules, this is how it's translating into an increasing number as early human projects.</p>
          <p>I've been absolutely consistent in telling you that our strategy was to increase the outlook from our discovery laboratories and speed up delivery of the projects in our pipeline together with an increased emphasis on externalization to deliver our long-term strategic and our short-term tactical objectives. In 2007, we completed a number of transactions to help us fulfill our goal of strengthening the late-phase pipeline and delivering a fully fledged and competitive biologics strategy.</p>
          <p>Our co-development profit-sharing deal with Bristol-Myers Squibb on Saxagliptin and Dapagliflozin met a key disease-area strategic target in the diabetes and metabolism area, as well as giving us two new Phase III projects by year-end. Our Arrow acquisition broadened our small molecule approach to infection into antivirals and is complementary to our increasing infection research commitment and our capability increase in Boston.</p>
          <p>With the large molecule vaccine approaches gained through the acquisition of MedImmune, which propelled us into a strong position in biotechnology, as well as considerably strengthening our anti-infectives, respiratory and inflammatory, and cancer approaches, MedImmune gave us the long-term platform for growth and delivery in these fields that our previous licensing or smaller acquisitions simply could not deliver. Other key deals such as Palatin, Regeneron and Silence, gave us access to key discovery technology.</p>
          <p>Resulting from our internal assets, together with our externalization activities, we now have a larger, stronger, and less risky Phase III portfolio that's grown from five projects this time last year with the loss of one project and the inclusion of six others with a total of ten projects, covering nine potential medicines, one of which is a biologic.</p>
          <p>I will now update you on the individual projects in the Phase III in some detail. Starting with Saxagliptin, this DPP-4 inhibitor has both mono and combination therapy in type II diabetes. It is on track for an NDA submission in mid-2008 and an MAA in the European Union in the second half of 2009. One of the Phase III studies was presented at the ADA Meeting in 2007, and further data will be presented in June and September this year at the major meetings.</p>
          <p>We now have available to us clinical data from five of the six pivotal studies of the NDA, all of which demonstrate consistent glycemic control across the Phase III program. More than 2,700 patients receiving Saxagliptin have to date evaluated across the clinical program through Phases I to III. We've evaluated across a range of doses, across all Phases of the trial program, including up to 40 times the likely top clinical dose with no evidence of any skin lesions that might give cause for concern.</p>
          <p>Through multiple FDA interactions over the course of the last year, during which we shared with them the clinical and clinical data, to date we've been given no reason to believe that the current NDA package is anything other than acceptable in terms of safety, efficacy, and exposure. In particular, whilst we have chosen to initiate a chronic study in renal failure and share the design with FDA, this is not on the critical path to the NDA. Saxagliptin is currently on track to a mid-year filing, subject to of course to the findings as we continue to analyze the Phase III program.</p>
          <p>Turning to Zactima, the coming year is the key year for this new medicine for non-small-cell lung cancer and medullary cancer of the thyroid, both submissions being currently on track for simultaneous delivery by year-end. Recruitment into the development program is either on track or completed, with over 3,500 patients recruited. As with all cancer programs, completion of the studies will be event-driven. And subject to the required number of disease progressions, we will have a clear picture on the activity of this drug as a second-line treatment for lung cancer. In combination with Docetaxel or Pemetrexed, as well as head to head with elotonib as monotherapy by the end of the third quarter this year.</p>
          <p>We are also generating data on EGF receptor inhibition failures versus best supportive care but this time on our longer time scale. A recent pre-planned Independent Data Safety Monitoring Committee interim analysis and safety review of the lung cancer program passed without any issues being flagged to the company.</p>
          <p>Our other cell-signaling inhibitor, Recentin, an oral VEGF inhibitor, is an anti-angiogenic whose mechanism we've previously shared with you. It's being assessed in a wide range of solid tumors both by ourselves and through a clinical research and development agreement with the United States National Cancer Institute. Our Phase II/III program concentrates on first-line treatment in non-small-cell lung cancer and colorectal cancer. Those programs are on track for the first decision point in the first quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>And in addition, you would have seen presentations externally on encouraging Phase I and Phase II data in a number of tumors, including glioblastoma and renal cell cancer. This has led us to initiate a new program in glioblastoma during the course of 2007 with the intention of delivering a separate registration package in that tumor ahead of lung and colorectal.</p>
          <p>The 18,000-patient PLATO outcome study of 6140, an acute coronary syndrome is recruiting well and more than 11,000 patients are now on study. To date no significant safety concerns have been identified. The TRITON study has shown that greater platelet inhibition can lead to improvements in cardiovascular endpoints with the obvious implication for 6140.</p>
          <p>Unlike prasugrel and Plavix, 6140 is a reversible platelet inhibitor, which we believe will confer considerable advantages in the marketplace through its rapid onset and offset, reliable efficacy and therefore a much more patient-friendly profile in many real-life situations. The speed with which we are now delivering PLATO has allowed us to bring the 6140 license submission date forward into the second half of 2009.</p>
          <p>Dapagliflozin has a novel insulin-independent mechanism of action, which suggests it should be effective alone or in combination with any other antidiabetic medication across the spectrum of patients with Type II diabetes. You can expect to see the Phase IIb data at the ADA meeting this coming June. A comprehensive Phase III program is planned that capitalizes on both Dapagliflozin's broad clinical applicability and the collective development power of BMS and ourselves. The first two studies began in the third quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>4054 is an endothelin A receptor antagonist being developed in hormone-resistant prostate cancer. The Phase II data produced overall survival benefits in this hard-to-treat group of patients, and these results were obtained with a good tolerability profile. We've now started recruitment in all the Phase III studies that will test this drug in nonmetastatic and metastatic disease, as well as in monotherapy, and in combination with chemotherapy. The study program is outlined and is in your pack for completeness.</p>
          <p>PN400 is a project that we are running in combination with POZEN using a fixed combination of enteric-coated naproxen and immediate-release esomeprozol in patients who would receive a nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug for pain relief in arthritis. We expect this fixed combination to be brings us a significant reduction in NSAID-related gastric ulcers which can lead to GI bleeds, which are a significant cause of morbidity in this population. Whilst approximately 20% of NSAID patients are currently prescribed to PPI with their pain relief, over half are noncompliant with their PPI medication.</p>
          <p>The fixed combination seeks to address both the adherence to PPI therapy and the timing of NSAID release into the gut, and the overall morbidity associated with the problem. The Phase III program is now running well and the Phase II data have been committed as an abstract to DDW.</p>
          <p>The last of the small-molecule Phase III projects is a combination of Crestor with Abbott 335 fenofibric acid, a fibrate that has recently been submitted by them for registration as a monotherapy and for concomitant use of statins. A number of studies have already been completed with the free combination of these two agents. And Crestor 335 data are planned for presentation by Abbott in the first half of this year. Additional studies of both free and fixed combinations are currently in progress, with a planned NDA submission in the second half of 2009 dependent upon the status of the 335 monotherapy NDA review.</p>
          <p>Finally in this section, just to remind you from December, that the motavizumab BLA is imminent, with further supplemental packages to follow. And there is continued progress with the biologics portfolio as outlined in December.</p>
          <p>Before I move on from the individual projects, I want to highlight just three of the most important life-cycle management programs. The Crestor atherosclerosis supplemental NDA was approved and the METEOR labeling accepted in Europe. We are now able to claim that Crestor slows the rate of progression of atheroma based on asteroid which showed regression of plaques in an open study in severe patients, And METEOR, which compared Crestor WITH placebo in patients with minimal disease. The graph shows the intimal thickening as the atheroma progresses on the placebo arm and a complete lack of progression on Crestor. Crestor is now the only major statin or statin combination to have a broad labeled claim in this indication. Further data from METEOR will be presented in April, health economics on CORONA in June, and we expect the first data from the GC heart failure study in the second half of this year.</p>
          <p>We have also recently announced the Saturn study, a direct head-to-head comparison between Crestor and atorvastatin looking at plaque progression and regression, and the first patients have already entered this program.</p>
          <p>In the United States, Symbicort was launched during the year. As a supplementary program we now have approval for an actuation counter and are on track to file for pediatrics by mid-year.</p>
          <p>The next major supplemental program is in chronic bronchitis or COPD. Two major studies, SUN and SHINE, have both completed, and the Symbicort 164.5 dose met the prespecified co-primary endpoints in both studies. This graph shows the clear benefits achieved over 12 months for one of those endpoints. Therefore we plan to submit this indication by mid-year in the United States. In addition we will also be filing for pMDI formulation in Europe later in the year.</p>
          <p>Last but by no means least of the life-cycle programs are the SEROQUEL IR and XR programs. The list of submissions and approvals is extensive. Many of the studies in these programs have been presented last year or will be presented during the course of this year. In particular, the major depressive disorder and generalized anxiety disorder programs for the XR had been an outstanding success. Six out of the seven of the depression studies have generated a statistically and clinically positive result, whilst all four of the reported anxiety studies are positive. In psychiatry, consistently positive data like these are most unusual.</p>
          <p>The slide just shows you one example of a placebo-controlled depression study with a positive control arm. We are positioning SEROQUEL at the severe end of these diseases both as single therapy and as adjunct to existing therapy. Both packages will be submitted to the U.S. and European regulatory authorities over the course of the year to allow us when approved to promote these findings in both specialist and primary care settings.</p>
          <p>Having reviewed our activities in 2007 and the key later phase projects, let me now turn to the future focus of our R&amp;D activities. Following the purchase of MedImmune and our desire to rebalance our resources between small molecules and biologics in favor of biologics, we refreshed our disease-area strategy across all therapeutic areas but with specific emphasis on those areas where we had activity in both MedImmune and AstraZeneca. Our objective was to optimize our discovery investment, in particular to reduce duplication and focus on delivery of a strong biologic portfolio as well as our committed synergy and budget targets.</p>
          <p>In summary, we've decided to exit osteoarthritis disease modification whilst maintaining or increasing our biologics focus in rheumatology, COPD and asthma. In cancer research, we're exiting one of our five mechanistic approaches, that of cell-cycle blockade and rebalancing again our resources between small molecules and biologics.</p>
          <p>Our activities in anticoagulation, antiplatelets and arrhythmia, and psychiatry will be maintained but with success-related reviews. Taken overall, the effects of the disease area strategy will be to reduce our small-molecule R&amp;D head count. However, with the addition of MedImmune and Arrow and the planned increases in our biologics R&amp;D activities, overall the company's R&amp;D manpower will remain essentially flat in 2008. These changes also allow us to increase our investment in development as the pipeline grows and enters the later, more expensive phase, whilst keeping our overall R&amp;D budget increase to a high single digits in 2008.</p>
          <p>In summary, we're achieving faster cycle times with a leaner organization and a more focused disease area strategy. We've made significant improvements to our pipeline in 2007 with a record number of CDs entering first GLP tox, in spite of increasing our pre-nomination quality demand. There has been a doubling of Phase I transitions with 24 medicines entering man, a one-third increase in our total clinical portfolio and a much stronger and more mature Phase III portfolio. We're delivering our biologic strategy and supporting the marketed products.</p>
          <p>Looking forward to the rest of this year, and of course subject to data, we are on track to deliver up to three NDAs, and up to 14 Phase II projects will reach proof-of-concept decision point by the year-end, against a background of increased productivity and high single-digit cost growth.</p>
          <p>Two years ago, we set ourselves targets for 2010. As we enter 2008, we've already achieved our Phase III project portfolio target. We have in place an excellent biologics pipeline and capability. And we're well on track to delivering an eight-year median development cycle time.</p>
          <p>We expected to be in a position by 2013 to bring on average two new medicines to the market on an annual basis. We now believe that that target can be achieved based on our current portfolio from 2010 onwards. This year, through license applications and clinical data, our aim is to show you that AstraZeneca R&amp;D is fit for the future, and we are indeed turning molecules into medicines.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention and I'll now hand over to David, who is going to conduct the Q&amp;A session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you, John and thank you, Simon, for your comments. Just a few points around the Q&amp;A. Number one, please wait to get a microphone and when you do, please identify yourself just so we know who are know and to let you all know. We also have the facility to take some questions online here with some people who are on the webcast. So, we will go back and forth, so we'll start here on the floor. So let me open it up for questions here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Kevin Wilson from Citi. A question for John &#x2013; two questions for John and one for Simon, or the other way around. Simon, could you give us some more detail on the breakdown of other operating income broadly? It is clearly above the levels of previous guidance, partly due to MedImmune &#x2013; understand that &#x2013; but &#x2013; and going forward perhaps as a run rate that would be helpful.</p>
          <p>And secondly, could you make a comment on the payment you will be making to Merck whatever happens regarding the first option, in other words, the partial redemption? I think $2 billion has been mentioned by Merck</p>
          <p>And for John, could you comment on your CB1 antagonist program, given the competitive nature of this space, what other people are doing and your stage of development, why you think you are going to have a winning molecule there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right; good. Thank you, Kevin. Simon, why don't we go to you on other operating income? You want to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. If we take the Medi operating income, we showed that to you for 2007 at $169 million. That does include royalty streams from the HPV vaccines. It also includes some royalty streams coming from Abbott International associated with the arrangements that we have with Abbott for selling RSV products internationally. There are also some income from government contracts associated with the vaccine business. So a variety of sources of income there.</p>
          <p>You've seen that for a seven month effect; you can think about annualizing that, but also clearly we expect the HPV vaccines business to grow over time. That will &#x2013; could then turn back to the underlying business, you'll have seen a operating income of about 560. There is royalty income in there associated with it, for example Prilosec OTC; that is declining. We've also got some gains associated with some asset divestments and some other sources of income and some reclassifications. The AstraZeneca component we expect, as I said, to decline a little, to be then compensated for by growth in the MedImmune operating income, thus leaving that flat for this year. Obviously we can update you in future years as we go, but I think I've given you enough to give a sense of the overall dynamic. Shall I turn to Merck?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think as you are familiar, the arrangements with Merck are such that there is one set of actions that will definitely take place at the end of the first quarter in 2008, namely the partial retirement. Under that, AstraZeneca will pay to Merck a sum, which, the quantum of which is the function of independent valuation, and that will allow AstraZeneca to exit from the Merck arrangement a tranche of products associated with Astra U.S. In addition, Merck has the option to exercise the first option. If it were to do so, if Merck were to do so, the total payment is 3.3. If it did not do so, then number depends upon the valuation. But if it doesn't exercise the first option, it's likely to be towards the top end of the twos, coming up to 2.7 to 3, that sort of area. So those are the payments that we will make &#x2013; a definite payment of something under three at the end of the first quarter, rising up to 3.3 if Merck exercise the first option.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. John, do you want to comment on the CB1 antagonist?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, briefly, Kevin, when we took this agent &#x2013; and in fact there are two in the pipeline table so we have the beginnings of a family into development &#x2013; we have clear views as to what might differentiate them, but today rather than telling you what it might do, we are going to wait until we have done the Phase II work and then assuming it gets through the hurdles that we've set it, will tell you what it does do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question; we'll stay on the floor here. I have got things popping up on the screen, but you are here, so we'll stick with you guys first. Over there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. This is Graham Parry from Merrill Lynch. Just looking at your cost-saving targets which seem to have gone up and I think have been brought forward a little bit as well and you appear to be guiding to about $900 million or two-thirds of the 1.4 billion in 2008, so just three questions on this. Firstly, given that the higher savings in 2008 and apparent bringing forward is news to the market, I was just wondering why it is that you have only guided to EPS, which is in line with market estimates. Do you think the market is still underestimating the pressure on your margins from the slowing top line and generic pressure? Point of clarification: just wanted to be clear that the two-thirds of cost savings that you're talking about delivering cumulatively in 2008 doesn't mean that you expect this to be delivered by the end of the year rather than throughout the course of the year.</p>
          <p>And thirdly, can you just clarify that the timing of that realization has changed versus your original guidance, so have these been brought forward in any way? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll let Simon get to those in just a minute. I mean I think the &#x2013; the approach we've taken to restructuring and the ability to execute it are rather dynamic. So while we put a program in place and think we know how it's going to run and we kind of look for opportunities to potentially accelerate it or do more in that. I think it has influenced our guidance to some degree. But as you mentioned our top line has slowed down a little bit. So there is some &#x2013; that's a dynamic as well. There is pressure points in there. I think what we've done with the guidance has tried to recognize that there is a fair amount of volatility in the established markets which, especially given that we operate in the two classes that are the most disrupted by generic and therapeutic substitution, I don't think we can predict as clearly as we could before what the PPI and statin markets are really going to do. And I think we have demonstrated over the last couple of years that we intend to deliver or overdeliver on what we commit to on a day like this. And I think accelerating the programs gives us some flexibility in what's going to take if the top line softens up. I &#x2013; we'll go to Simon and let you have some context to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We announced a program, if you combine restructuring and synergy, the total annual benefit by 2010 of 1,400, 1.4 billion. What we said today is that we will deliver two-thirds of that in 2008. To be specific, that means two-thirds of the 1.4 is in the P&amp;L in '08. Okay? And we have seen that our restructuring programs are on track. We are pleased with the progress that we are making. And we will obviously update you as &#x2013; if we see and get some visibility on future timing. But that's for 2008.</p>
          <p>If we go back and talk about the impact of that on the overall shape and profitability of the business, we have said that we see sales growth in low to mid-single digits for 2008. We've also talked about a flat SG&amp;A. So we've got the benefit of the restructuring costs coming through, but we do have some other upward pressures on our SG&amp;A costs. We have a full year effect of MedImmune. We have increased sales and marketing investment in the markets that you saw delivering very strong growth for us, and we are investing to grow and support the top line. We do have other inflationary pressures. Litigation costs continue to rise year on year, so our legal costs go up. But overall, our SG&amp;A total cost we expect to remain flat in constant currency terms. But in addition, we are investing high single digit in our R&amp;D; we are investing for the future. And we have made a decision to maintain our operating margins at or above our target of 30%, but to put the benefits of some of that top line growth and some of the potential margin expansion into driving R&amp;D for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we'll take another one on the floor, here. Jo, and then we'll come up here. You had your hand up; we'll get you next. Okay up here; Jo, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jo Walton from Lehman Brothers. I have three quick questions. Looking at your SG&amp;A, you have done a fantastic job of bringing it down and you say that you should be able to keep it stable for this year. Can you look any longer term considering the changes that there are in the industry? Is this an area where you think that there are opportunities to continue to take out money? I guess that John is going to want to continue to raise R&amp;D, and gross margins are slightly more intractable to change. Is it going to be reasonable that you can continue to take SG&amp;A out to fund R&amp;D? That is the first question.</p>
          <p>The second one is just a quick product question, SEROQUEL XR, you say major depressive or degeneralized anxiety disorder. You had an excellent chart there showing it was as good as Deloxatine. Well, Deloxatine is a damn sight cheaper than SEROQUEL XR, so is there an issue in the brave new world that you can't get the right price for these sorts of line extensions?</p>
          <p>And the final question, I am not quite sure whether we are going to get &#x2013; whether you will be able to help here &#x2013; but with generic PROTONIX appearing quite suddenly in the U.S., you've got two dates coming up where you could get a challenge for Nexium and SEROQUEL. What sort of visibility do you have of those potential filers and whether they might launch at risk? I mean, is it you will just wake up one morning and find out that they have, or can you get a sense of whether they are likely to from your discussions perhaps with Medco or other people?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me &#x2013; I will take the first one there just around opportunities on SG&amp;A and funding R&amp;D and make some comments. I don't know if Tony &#x2013; Tony is in global marketing &#x2013; might want to comment on XR and the positioning of it vis-&#xE0;-vis Deloxatine. Or maybe John, you want to comment from a clinical perspective and then we will give some context to the third one too.</p>
          <p>I think that there are a couple of points to make about SG&amp;A, Jo, one of them relates to separating out the G&amp;A from the sales and marketing activities, and I think we have taken a very aggressive approach in trying to become more efficient in our G&amp;A activities. And in the sales and marketing activities, I think it self-corrects to some degree. You saw that in Western Europe. Last year we took out a fair amount of sales and marketing capacity in some of the markets where we didn't think we needed that much and we have at the same time added, I think Bruno said earlier today, several thousand positions in the emerging world where we see opportunities in places like China, Brazil, Mexico &#x2013; excuse me &#x2013; et cetera. So I think there is some self-correction there, but we will continue to push it because it is an area where we think the model will continue to change and it's a big part of our overall expense base relative to &#x2013; do you want to make a comment about G&amp;A and how it funds R&amp;D?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, sure. I mean I think if you ask, Jo, other opportunities, there are always going to be opportunities, and our job is to seek them out. And I think that one benefit in coming new to the company and from a different sector is that I will see things perhaps in a different way with a different perspective. I think there is an opportunity for us to benchmark ourselves against perhaps a different group than we might have done in the past. And I think that will help us understand at quite a granular level if there is more opportunity.</p>
          <p>There is further scope for us to draw on best practices that we have seen, again, in other arenas. We have made terrific strides, I think, in AstraZeneca over the last couple of years, and I think we probably got started on this earlier than many. In my mind that builds us a capability to keep ahead of the pack and adopt practices from elsewhere. I know that I want to look at that in my own area of finance, so we are doing the right activities in the right place and as efficiently as we can.</p>
          <p>We also have a program of Lean Sigma operating in a number of parts of the business which I've been impressed with, and I think there is much greater scope for applying that outside the traditional operating environment into some of our back-office functions. And in addition, I can bring in and will be bringing continued focus on cost and cash discipline. All of this gives us the opportunity to keep a focus on G&amp;A, and that is going to be important because we want to put our investments behind R&amp;D for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take the third one real quick on the specific visibility to filers for the 30-month stays. No, we don't have any particular visibility into that. You would have to ask them what their plans are. We obviously plan contingently and try to understand what's going on, but it's not obvious and it is dependent upon approvals, which we haven't seen yet. John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Jo, you posed a couple of good questions. First of all, we are not going for the broad antidepressant anti-anxiety indication. We are going to go for the bottom 20% &#x2013; most severe, many of whom will be failures on SSRIs or will get decisions on top of others. You are right. Deloxatine is a very good agent. But if you look at that graph, and you have obviously looked at it fairly carefully, you will see that it takes until week four before Deloxatine actually gets the same level effect as we were getting with SEROQUEL XR. And in fact, in the first week it was not significantly better than placebo. So we do see a differentiation in speed of onset, which we believe will also help us in this field.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. And I will take one right up here, and then I'll take one from number one from the screen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Corbin from Morgan Stanley. Just a couple of questions. Firstly on the patent challenges from Teva and Baxy, are you actively in settlement discussions with those companies at the moment, or can you talk about it in any way? And can you get a preliminary injunction ahead of them launching or giving any signal to launch or to wait for them to launch before being able to go to court and try and get a preliminary injunction?</p>
          <p>And then, secondly just on PN400, what percentage of your Nexium prescriptions that are currently prescribed with a nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory, and do you have any plans as to how you're going to price that product relative to, say, an NSAID or Nexium? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I would acknowledge that Andrew Baum from Morgan Stanley has also asked the same question about are we involved with any generic parties in Nexium and SEROQUEL for settlement purposes. I would just say we've resolved patent disputes over time with the generics both through the final court decisions of appeal; we did that with Toprol-XL, with Diprovan, with Prilosec, and at the same time we have settled. We had a settlement with Tamoxophen back then, so I think &#x2013; we look at each situation independently; we look at the strategic alternatives we have available to us. We strongly believe in the intellectual property behind both of the products, Nexium and SEROQUEL. And that's the position that we have taken to date. I'm not expert on this, but I believe for a preliminary injunction to take place there has to be some activity by them in the market for us to take action. But quite frankly it's not my area of expertise, but obviously we watch this very closely and will be at the appropriate times. Tony, do you have the information on concomitant use of NSAIDs and the opportunity &#x2013; maybe you want to talk about for PN400?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think the concomitant use of those patients that are on NSAIDs along with the PPI, David, it is in that 25 to 30% range. It is the concomitant percentage. And for us, we see an opportunity here to position &#x2013; one of the big issues with NSAID use of course is the stomach upset and potential for bleed. And that's where we think the combination of the two products brings significant advantage to patients, and that's how we will be positioning it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; good. I'll go to the phone, yes the telephone Ira Dass from Sanford Bernstein. Ira, you there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I am here. This is Ira for Tim Anderson of Sanford Bernstein. The question is, you have a substantial clinical trial development program in the form of Galaxy with Crestor. Yet I don't see that you have any hard outcome studies versus any active comparator. Many of these programs are versus the placebo. I know you're recently announced the statin trial which is an IBIS trial, but it does not have a major outcomes trial like one seen that is Vytorin, the PROVE-IT trial. And it just seems like a noticeable gap in the Galaxy program. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, John, you want to comment on our Crestor life-cycle management program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Crestor was a relatively late entrant to this field. And at the time there was a huge body of evidence that statins were giving good outcomes in a number of situations. So it was actually deemed to be impossible and unethical to do placebo-controlled trials in the major outcome areas. So what we did was we looked at areas where there was little or no statin use but potential usage, such as in heart failure associated with atheroma or coronary artery disease.</p>
          <p>In terms of positive controlled studies going head to head against other agents such as other statins, when you do the mathematics of how many patients it's going to take in such a study, the cost of doing it and the duration of doing it, I suspect many of you will still not be working by the time the answer comes out. So it was just deemed by the experts working with us as impractical to do. We have approached it on a number of questions &#x2013; a number of times for the obvious reason that you asked the question. So it's a matter of &#x2013; in the core indications, it is widely accepted by all the experts in the field that it's proven that statins, by lowering HDL, give benefits in outcomes, and that generally the more you lower the HDL, the better the outcome benefit has been. And therefore they are not prepared to let you do another placebo-controlled study in that situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right good. Back to the floor here, in the back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi <mark type="inaudible" />, JPMorgan. I just want to follow up on some of the Crestor comments just made there. We have got a launch or major push on the data from METEOR. How long should we wait before we decide whether or not that launch has been successful, that push has been successful? The exit rate in the U.S. is around about 8%, probably a bit lower on volume growth, so it's come down an awful lot. But then looking forward, on the statin study can you just give us the dose of Crestor and the dose of atorvastatin we have in the IBIS study and about how long that study is going to take if it's just starting.</p>
          <p>And then even further forward, I remember the JUPITER study looked once upon a time to be potentially a very, very big upside for Crestor maybe around about 2009, but I know it's	 slipped a bit. What's the latest timing on the JUPITER study, and how can you brand the results of that study for Crestor rather than the other statins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right; good. I will make a quick comment on the market dynamic in the U.S. I'll ask Tony, then, to make a comment, and ask John to comment on SATURN dosing as well as the JUPITER question that was asked. I mean I think, as Simon said in his comments, our aim is to see a change in that line and to begin to see it move up. It's really on the back of being able to make that claim from the METEOR data on slowing the progression of atherosclerosis. And our expectation, you know, our aim is to see that happen. I don't want to put a timeframe on it; we have assumptions built into what we're doing, but we think it does take a little bit of time, especially given the unexpected dynamic associated with the outcome of the enhanced trial. Tony, do you want to add to that? Can we get a microphone up here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, David, I guess the only areas I would add is that clearly we are going to get back on a growth trajectory. Our strategy is absolutely to redefine success within those patients fighting dyslipidemia as inclusive of LDL and HDL impact, but as well the slowing of progression of atherosclerosis. The early indicators for us is certainly physician attitude and awareness. We have been doing a lot of research to understand how physicians and our message is resonating with physicians. And the early read on that data is quite positive. They see the credibility of our message at all-time highs. They also see the relevance of the message, which is not surprising based on the noise in the marketplace. So it gives us confidence that we go into the new year with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, do you want to comment on the studies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay. The easiest bit first. SATURN is 40 milligrams of Crestor against 80 milligrams of Lipitor. It will be dosing for two years, in order to show regression or change the rate of progression of the plaques through IBIS and therefore having just started recruitment, we are talking about the 2011 timeframe. And that again is part of the issue in terms of the long-term studies there.</p>
          <p>JUPITER is going to be to some degree event driven. It may well give us that outcome study we are looking for, but of course recruitment was based on the C-reactive protein and the activities associated with that. So it is a big study; it is, after a relatively slow start, it is moving well now. But we are not in a position to give you any information regarding as to exactly when it is going to complete.</p>
          <p>And then the other one we should probably mention is a study starting up from Canada is Hope 3, which is actually looking at people who are relatively normal in terms of their lipid profile and looking at long-term outcomes in those people both with Crestor and with an antihypertensive in a two-by-two factorial design. So there are a number of approaches to this, but they all tend to come at it slightly from one side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. We will take another one from the floor and then we will go to question two over there, which is from Bollum Yusaf from UBS will be after this question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Mark Purcell from Deutsche Bank. First question; could you just provide us with the Phase III go/no go decisions you expect in the course of 2008? Secondly, could you provide us with any idea what the target product profile was on ABT-335 in terms of the renal profile as well as efficacy as well? Third, on the antipsychotic market clearly Respidol generic is entering in June; could you discuss your thoughts on the potential for therapeutic substitution pressures on one hand and opportunities to gain market share on the other? And then lastly on Recentin, could you remind us of the trials that are reporting during the first half of 2008, which dates we may or may not see and how those trials are designed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; that's plenty. The &#x2013; John, those will come to you in a minute, but maybe we'll just make a comment about the expectation on the Respidol generic and I think our expectation is that the antipsychotic market is quite unique and a product is a product there. It is not a history of therapeutic substitution in that area. And I think we expect to continue to grow our SEROQUEL franchise through the expansion to the XR formulation and the expansion of approved regulatory approvals in multiple areas including bipolar disorder as well as the claim we have now for schizophrenia and the MDD and GAD at the more severe side, as John said. And I think it's an important point. I think any generic entering the market does create some pressure, but at the same time this is a very unique class of agents. Patients are treated very, very differently on a product-by-product basis and it certainly doesn't seem like one to switch from.</p>
          <p>Tony, is there anything to add to that? All right, John, then, maybe we'll go to Phase III go/no goes, if you want to start with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, David. If you look at the back of the slide pack there is an H1 and H2 '08 news flow. So a number of those go/no goes are actually in there and I'll be happy to talk you through any of them. I think obviously Recentin is one you particularly picked out, and the answer is that in colorectal cancer from the Horizon Program, we have go/no goes rate based on the completion of the second-line Phase II study; we have go/no go on the Phase II/III study which is at its go/no go point, both of them this first quarter of the year. We are for lung cancer also in a go/no go with the National Cancer Institute cancer study in lung cancer. So all of those are first quarter this year.</p>
          <p>In terms of other projects, quarter three is Zactima where we see pretty well all the Phase III data and we will know whether we have the profile that we were looking for, for the end-of-year presentation. motavizumab has been through all its go/no goes already and the package is being put together as we speak. Just briefly on Abbott TPP &#x2013; Abbott 335, you should ask that of Abbott rather than ask it of us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Let's go to the phone then Bollum Yusaf from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I recall for your business review in '06 a slide showing that Crestor plus a generic statin is the most cost-effective two-statin formulary combo. Would you be able to still say that? And I guess a different way of asking that is how does the Crestor price compare to the Lipitor price in recent times?</p>
          <p>And then secondly on Crestor, do you have a view for 2008 as to whether the realized price goes up or goes down? And my last question is on Recentin. Given the adaptive clinical trial design, which is highly innovative but a bit different, just given that FDA guidance isn't yet out on adaptive trials, is there some risk in that program, might be that &#x2013; might the goal posts effectively change at the FDA and cause problems with your filing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I don't know the &#x2013; I will go to Tony for Crestor pricing in 2008, but let me just comment. I think the first part of your question &#x2013; and I'm sorry; we couldn't quite hear perfectly &#x2013; was around the LDL lowering and the cost effectiveness Crestor, because it lowered so much &#x2013; was that much better from an &#x2013; from a health economic cost perspective. But the question I think on Crestor, Lipitor pricing, Tony, will you want to make a comment about it in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I'll start by emphasizing what our go-to-market strategy is, David, and that is continuing to talk about the efficacy that the product brings in both LDL and HDL and now the slowing of progression. Because I think it's an important point. We believe that this is the right agent for, certainly, at-risk patients and we positioned it as such. Relative to, in broad terms, our commercial access, we enjoy fairly broad coverage for Crestor in the marketplace. We have well over 85 to 90% of covered lives are reimbursed. So we feel good about that. Relative to the impact on price, in fact we saw a slight increase in our net realized price through 2007. And we think that that trend can continue going into 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good. Thanks. John, you want to talk about the risk associated with an adaptive clinical trial, and whether it's different than the risk associated with any clinical trial? I would remind everybody here that when I talk to John about clinical trials, my question is when is it going to be finished, and he reminds me that it is a scientific experiment, that it's not a timeline and I might not like the answers, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, you've taken some of my line there, David, and the answer is it's always a balance. And in this occasion, we believe that by going into this adaptive design, we would get a very early view of decision point faster and cheaper than doing it any other way. We get a good view as to its comparable efficacy or lack of it versus Avastin, which is the gold standard in this area. And we would also get some good dose information to allow us to make a dose decision. So those are three very important things that we could do whilst building into the program a number of fallback and fail safes, and also discussing them with the regulators who knew what we are trying to do and have bought into it. And we've talked long and hard with them about what statistical penalties we may or may not pay, and how to deal with changes that we might make as a result of any decisions that come from that. So the answer is, let's &#x2013; we're in there. We're going to see the data, and when we have that we'll share it with you and with the regulators, and that's the point at which we'll see whether we've made the win or the lose. But we believe it was well worthwhile doing and it's something I would certainly do again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. While we get a microphone right up here to the middle, there is a quick e-mail question. Simon, maybe you can handle that. Pro forma sales percentages in 2007 from?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> is asking what the pro forma sales for Synergis is in 2007 are. We do not provide, we won't provide the pro forma sales for Synergis in '07. What we can say, though, is that sales for the seven months within AstraZeneca were $618 million. Sales for the fourth quarter were $480 million, and the bulk of the sales for Synergis, given the nature of the product, are in the fourth and the first quarters. Adding that together will give you a good handle on the sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. To you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. <mark type="inaudible" />. Just to carry on on Crestor. Do you keep a close eye on dynamic market shares? And essentially I am trying to get a handle on how you see patients that have been actively switched from Lipitor to Simvastatin and may not be getting to goal. When those patients are turned to a study that may get them to go, are you seeing Crestor getting a fair share of that, or are they being switched back to Lipitor?</p>
          <p>And I have a second question which is essentially looking at emerging markets and you know China is a big country, where do you see in five years' time, for example, your sales force requirements being? I mean, are we looking at 2000 reps? Are we looking at &#x2013; are you forming JVs there, and how do you actually make any money in China?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. That's great. You know what? I think I'll rephrase your first question, because I think your question is for patients that don't get to goal, what's the dynamic market share look like and is Crestor doing better than, the same as, or worse than Lipitor on the patients that do get switched. I don't know how much insight we have to who gets switched. But I'll let Tony think about that for a minute.</p>
          <p>Bruno, you want to talk about China? Bruno Angelici runs our rest-of-world operations and may &#x2013; was very involved in the strategic decision for AstraZeneca to invest in China several years ago in a way that I don't think we were planning to do at the time. So he knows quite a bit about the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me give you the context regarding China. First, China is a market which is growing at a very fast speed. It's a $17 billion market right now, and many people forecast that this market will be probably 30, $34 billion in, let's say, four or five years. Which means that China will be a market as big as Germany. So the growth rate and the development of this market has been quite spectacular over the last few years.</p>
          <p>AstraZeneca has been one &#x2013; probably the first or one the first multinational corporation to recognize that China was going to be important. And we are now the number-one prescription company in China. We have achieved last year in '07 $400 million of business, with a growth rate of 26%. If you project a growth rate like that a little bit, you will see that China in itself is the equivalent of a new product, which ought to be significant. Let me mention one thing. it's profitable. It's nicely profitable. It's a little less profitable than an established market, obviously, but we are making money.</p>
          <p>To look at your question of the future, the prospects for AstraZeneca in China are good, because we're still waiting for the listing of good number of new products. The timing in China is, shall we say, behind the timing of entering product into the market, is significantly behind the rest of the world. So we are waiting for the listing of Nexium, Crestor and Symbicort. This listing of these new products should have been hopefully in 2009. The government in China is listing pharmaceutical product every four or five years. So we will have an access to the market for all these products probably in '09 which will put us in a very nice position to continue to roll at a fast rate.</p>
          <p>Now for your specific question, we are right now 1,800, approximately 1,800 reps, commercial people, in China. And our model is to grow by it &#x2013; it has been very successful so far &#x2013; is to increase our sales force in an appropriate way covering the major city, the capital city, and as we grow we have a strategy to target exactly the different part of the country as this country is growing. So we will continue to grow and to grow, to have a strong organic growth investing and developing our sales organizations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tony, you want to make a comment about dynamic market share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I can give you some insight. First off, we don't track just on the failures only; we do look at net switching fairly closely. And in the run-up to 2007, obviously you saw the continued growth of generics Simvastatin, and most of those switches were coming at the expense of Lipitor where they almost traded equal amounts of share performance. Vytorin certainly was getting some net switching positive because of the base of Simvastatin. It was a logical alternative for physicians as they are upgrading. And Crestor was slightly on the negative side on the net switches. As we became more aggressive with our own message with the addition of the METEOR data, what we did see is some subtle changes and shifts on those net switches to the point where through the early weeks now of January, the net switches are positive for Crestor, and we are not losing on the downside to Simvastatin. In fact we are picking up some prescription activity in overall switches.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good; thank you, Tony. John, quick question on e-mail. Can you handle that one? It's Mike Ward at Namura. What's your view of recent calls for long-term active comparator outcome studies in diabetes as a requirement for U.S. registration?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer is not a lot. It would totally change the way we develop medicines for this or any other market if we have to get to the point where we know where it fits in the medical marketplace before we actually register a product rather than safety efficacy and qualities we do today. It will change not just for diabetes; it would change the whole registration process, timing and effort. So I don't believe FDA are going down that route. They have not indicated it for either Dapagliflozin which we talked to them or Saxagliptin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. All right, we will take one more question from the floor and it can't be a four-part question. One question and then we will wind up. We are going to hang around awhile, so you can come and find us if you want to. I want to respect time because we did run over a little bit, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Marietta Muse from CCT Really quick product questions. Just quickly on Horizon 1, will that also report in the first quarter in terms of actually seeing data or can you give us any feel that would &#x2013; for information that would give us a feel as to when in the first half it might report?</p>
          <p>And quickly on 6140, you said no major safety concerns. I mean, there was like 10% dyspnea in the Phase II studies. Was that not seen in Phase III or was it seen but it looks very manageable? And the final question is just really on Advert, just trying to get a feel for what switch rates you see from Advert into Symbicort. When you say one out of four new starts is on Symbicort, is that people who were previously on Advert, and generally how do you think things will pan out in the GP market in terms of going for new patient versus actually getting patients to switch over from Advert?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I just want to start by saying that you broke the rule. John, Horizon 1 report is quick, though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We said with all the Horizon, with two out of the three Horizons studies, one will complete and other one, Horizon 3, will have interim analysis there with the data safety monitoring boards for this quarter. And depending on what they say depends on what you see and what we see, by the way. And as far as 6140 concerned, there is a safety monitoring board that reviews data every month. They have seen more than 2,000 ECGs. They have seen all of the data. We look at the fallout rates and we look at the bleeding rates and that's why I said to date we have seen no evidence of any significant issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the switch rates, I don't know about switching. I will let Tony give a quick answer but when we said one out of four new patients &#x2013; were patients new to combination therapy? So from special astute switch rates, is there anything switching at this point? We don't have anything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. With that what I would like to say is, we tried to focus on what I believe are the four key things &#x2013; the four key things we need to do. We probably focused on three because strengthening the pipeline and you heard a lot about R&amp;D and what we are doing there today. And I think that we are making progress. We said we need to grow our business to be successful; we continue to do that. There is pressure on the top line, but that doesn't cause us to do anything but drive harder to make sure that we can deliver the business given the context that we have. Reshaping our business says a lot about preparing for the future. We are operating more efficiently and more effectively.</p>
          <p>The fourth initiative that we have underway is about changing the culture and behavior of the people within the company, and while we don't spend a lot of time talking about it at conferences like this, I can tell you there is a tremendous amount of energy within AstraZeneca to prepare ourselves to be successful as we approach a more dynamic challenging market in the turn of the decade.</p>
          <p>So I will leave you with that thought. I will thank you for your participation and attendance. Everyone will stay here for awhile from our group, although I do have to start a conference call in a few minutes. But please come on up and say hi. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>