<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1367843" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-15</date>
    <companies>
      <company>629</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Marcus Agius, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Bob E. Diamond, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Executive Director</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Christopher George Lucas, Executive Director &amp; Group Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">John-Paul Crutchley</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Cormac Leech</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Michael Helsby</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Bruce Packard</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Mike Trippitt</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep">Rich Ricci</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Peter Toeman</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Andrew Lim</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Ian Smillie</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Alastair Ryan</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="corprep">Antony Jenkins</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We're pretty much all here. Good morning, everybody. Thank you for coming. Welcome to this presentation of the Barclays 2010 Annual Results. We're going to follow our normal format, Bob and Chris on the podium. Can I ask you in the normal way, please do turn your mobile phones off and that way we won't be interrupted. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Marcus, and good morning, everyone.</p>
          <p>It's a real pleasure to be here as the Chief Executive at my first earnings session and it makes me think that John is missing and I have had a fantastic colleague for 15 years with John Varley, a great boss for the last seven years. I've learned a lot from John over the years and I think it's so fitting about the man that the last thing he did as Chief Executive at Barclays was to deliver Project Merlin, which took incredible time, intensity, focus and all the relationships that he could muster. So, I know I have big shoes to fill.</p>
          <p>Today is going to be as normal. Chris will give a presentation on the 2010 results and the 2010 numbers. Then I'm going to take you through a forward look at 2011 and beyond. Before we do that, I'd like to introduce to you the executive committee. My theme is execution and I can tell you that execution is a team game and we have one hell of a team here, so I want to introduce them before we start.</p>
          <p>I think all of you know Chris, who is also on the main board with me, but a member of the executive committee. But other members of executive committee, Antony Jenkins, who runs our Global Retail Banking. There is a fun fact on Antony that not many people know. He actually got in a start in Barclays in 1983 in the graduate training program. He then left for, I think, 20-plus years, 16 of them at Citibank and A.J. came back in 2006 to run our Cards business. And I think all of you, as analysts, know exactly the kind of job he performed in our Cards business during a difficult time.</p>
          <p>I'd also like to introduce in absentia, Maria Ramos. Maria is the Chief Executive of Absa. She's giving the results in Johannesburg right now. Going forward, I'm going to try and change this so she can be with us here in results. When John and I were looking for a new Chief Executive in Absa two years ago, there was only one phone call we made. We knew Maria from her time as Chief Executive at Transnet. She's a terrific Chief Executive and she and Antony together are driving the One Africa project for us.</p>
          <p>Tom Kalaris joined Barclays in 1996 after 20 years at J.P. Morgan. Tommy ran Barclays Capital in the Americas for a decade before I asked him to move to London and take on our Wealth business and you've seen the results of that with the Gamma Plan that we're executing on now.</p>
          <p>Jerry del Missier is Co-Chief Executive of Barclays Capital and our Corporate business, as well. Jerry was an original member of the Barclays Capital Executive Committee in 1997. His Co-Chief Executive, Rich Ricci, has been with Barclays since 1994. Rich took a number of years away from Barclays Capital to move to San Francisco and was Chief Operating Officer of BGI during the years when we really transformed that business into a much higher growth business in 2002, 2003, and 2004. They assumed full responsibility for Barclays Capital when I was announced as a successor to John in September. You can see from the fourth quarter numbers they're really struggling without my guidance.</p>
          <p>Sally Bott, our newest member of the Executive Committee, Sally has just accepted the role as Group Head of Human Resources at Barclays. A little known fact about Sally, she was Group Head of HR at Barclays when I was hired and drove the recruiting. So if you're looking for someone to blame, it's right here. We brought her back. It's incredible to have Sally back running our HR and being on the executive committee at Barclays, after having been away from us for a few years at BP and on the board of UBS.</p>
          <p>Mark Harding, our Chief Counsel, Mark joined in 2003 after a career at Clifford Chance and some time at UBS. Mark's responsible for our legal, our compliance, and also chairs our operating committee and is a member, as I said of the executive committee.</p>
          <p>And last but not least, our Chief Risk Officer, who many of you know, Robert Le Blanc, joined after a career at mostly at J.P. Morgan in 2004 as Head of Risk.</p>
          <p>As I said, we have a fantastic team, Chris and I, and a tremendous amount of support. And this is the team that will be here to answer questions after the presentations as well.</p>
          <p>And with that, Chris, can I hand over to you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thank you and good morning.</p>
          <p>I'm pleased to report that Barclays delivered a strong performance in 2010. Group profit before tax grew 32% to &#xA3;6.1 billion.</p>
          <p>Excluding movements on own credit and gains on acquisitions and debt buy-backs, adjusted profit grew 11% to &#xA3;5.5 billion, income increased 8% to &#xA3;31.4 billion and impairment charges of &#xA3;5.7 billion improved 30% year-on-year, resulting in a 22% increase in net income.</p>
          <p>Expenses grew 19% to &#xA3;20 billion, resulting in a cost/income ratio of 64% and a cost-to-net income ratio of 78%. I'll give you a detailed breakdown of costs later.</p>
          <p>Our core Tier 1 ratio increased to 10.8%, return on equity improved to 7.2%. On tangible equity, it was 8.7%. And return on risk weighted assets increased 26 basis points year-on-year to 1.12%.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share grew 26% to 30.4p, and we announced a final dividend today of 2.5p. The total dividend for the year of 5.5p was more than five times covered.</p>
          <p>I'll move now to Global Retail Banking, where there is growing momentum. In U.K. Retail Banking, profits grew 39% to &#xA3;989 million, including a gain of &#xA3;100 million on the acquisition of Standard Life Bank. Income grew 6% to &#xA3;4.5 billion as a result of increased volumes. Impairment improved 21%, largely in unsecured lending, and expenses grew 11% reflecting higher pension costs, the impact of Standard Life Bank, and of regulation.</p>
          <p>At Barclaycard, profits increased 9% to &#xA3;791 million, mainly as a result of improved impairment. All parts of the business were profitable. Both income and costs were broadly stable. Income benefited from business growth, which was offset by the impact of regulation, mainly in the United States.</p>
          <p>West Europe Retail Banking incurred a loss of &#xA3;139 million compared to a profit of &#xA3;280 million in 2009. We remained profitable in Portugal and France, but incurred losses in Spain and Italy, mainly as a result of margin compression. 2009 profits included one-off gains of &#xA3;183 million.</p>
          <p>Income decreased 12% to &#xA3;1.2 billion due to margin pressure and a 4% appreciation in the average value of Sterling against the Euro. Impairment charges improved 7% to &#xA3;314 million. Costs grew 16% to &#xA3;1 billion as we expanded the Cards business in Portugal and Italy.</p>
          <p>Profit at Barclays Africa increased 81% to &#xA3;188 million pounds, including a &#xA3;77 million pound gain from the sale of our custody business. The three biggest contributors were Kenya, Botswana and Mauritius. Income grew 8% to just over &#xA3;800 million. Impairment charges improved 32% to &#xA3;82 million, and costs increased 13% to &#xA3;608 million.</p>
          <p>In South Africa, Absa Group reported profit growth of 20% to 11.9 billion Rand this morning. Excluding Cards, Investment Banking and Wealth Management, which were all reported within those businesses in Barclays, profits in Absa segment grew 17% to &#xA3;616 million, reflecting appreciation in the average value of the Rand against Sterling of 16%.</p>
          <p>Bob will mention later our plan to align Absa more closely with Barclays Africa. If I look at all of our retail banking activities, including Absa, profit before tax grew 4% to &#xA3;2.4 billion.</p>
          <p>I'll now move on to Barclays Capital. Barclays Capital top line income of &#xA3;13.3 billion was down 25% on a very strong year in 2009. Fixed income, currencies and commodities contributed &#xA3;8.8 billion and &#xA3;2.2 billion came from Investment Banking. And Equities and Prime Services delivered &#xA3;2 billion. Taking into account credit market losses, own credit and impairment charges, net income grew 45% to &#xA3;13 billion.</p>
          <p>Impairment charges reduced to &#xA3;543 million from &#xA3;2.6 billion in 2009. The 2010 charge included &#xA3;532 million taken against our loan to Protium, which we've impaired as a level equal to the fair value of the underlying assets. Costs grew 26% year-on-year, reflecting both compensation costs and investment in front office trading and sales, including the build-out of our Equities and Advisory business. The compensation charge for 2010, which includes deferrals from prior years, represented 43% of income excluding own credit.</p>
          <p>The cost-to-net income ratio, excluding own credit, was at the top end of our target range at 65% as we've consciously maintained investment spend. We remain committed to a range of 60% to 65%. 2010 performance awards, excluding deferrals from prior years, were down 12% to approximately &#xA3;2.6 billion. I'll talk more about compensation later.</p>
          <p>Profit before tax, excluding own credit, grew 2% to &#xA3;4.4 billion. Average daily value at risk decreased 31% to &#xA3;53 million during the year. This reflected lower levels of client activity.</p>
          <p>Looking at the quarterly top line income of &#xA3;3.4 billion, we're pleased that the fourth quarter was up 20% on the third quarter. Within this, fixed income, currencies and commodities were broadly in line with the third quarter while Equities increased 74% and Investment Banking grew 45%.</p>
          <p>Barclays Corporate reported a loss before tax of &#xA3;631 million. Profits in the U.K. and Ireland increased 16% to &#xA3;851 million, reflecting good income performance, well-controlled costs and improved impairment.</p>
          <p>In Continental Europe, losses grew to &#xA3;870 million mainly as a result of higher impairment charges in Spain. These reduced 38% to &#xA3;345 million in the second half as we took early action to manage our risk. Conditions this year will remain difficult, though we expect impairment in Spain to continue to improve relative to 2010.</p>
          <p>In new markets, which comprises our business in India, Pakistan, Russia and the UAE, there was a loss before tax of &#xA3;612 million. This included a write-down of goodwill in Barclays Bank Russia of &#xA3;243 million as we reconfigured the business, and total restructuring cost of &#xA3;119 million, much of which resulted from the closure of our business in Indonesia. Bob will talk more about Barclays Corporate later.</p>
          <p>Profits at Barclays Wealth increased 14% to &#xA3;163 million as a result of income growth of 18% to &#xA3;1.6 billion, largely in the High Net Worth business. Impairment was broadly in line with 2009 and costs grew 19% as a result of business growth and of incremental investment of &#xA3;112 million during the first year of our &#x2013; growth plan. Total client assets at the end of December were &#xA3;164 billion, up from &#xA3;151 billion at the end of 2009.</p>
          <p>We allocate capital to business units based on an assumed core Tier 1 ratio of 9% and we retain excess capital at group center as a buffer. This results in lower group returns than the average of the underlying businesses. Returns lie at the heart of our capital allocation process, and as you can see, all of our businesses except Western Europe Retail Banking and Barclays Corporate had returns on tangible equity in excess of the 2010 cost of equity of 12.5%.</p>
          <p>The cost of equity has been at unprecedented levels for the last two years. Our latest calculation of our cost of equity for 2011 is now 11.5%, and we expect to see a decline to more normal levels over the next couple of years as economic conditions improve and market volatility declines.</p>
          <p>Moving on now to look at margins, there continues to be strong competition for deposits, which resulted in further liability margin compression. This has been offset by some increases in asset margins, for example, in U.K. Mortgages where we are writing new business at attractive margins. We remain cautious about overall net interest margins as we move into 2011, but we're confident in the strength of our market positions, especially in the U.K. where we continue to pick up market share.</p>
          <p>We've also benefited from our product and equity structural hedges, which contributed &#xA3;3.2 billion in 2010. This included a one-off gain of about &#xA3;500 million from the sale of gilts as we optimized our hedge maturities. Excluding this, we expect fixed receipts on these hedges to be broadly stable over the next couple of years. Despite benefiting from our hedges, good asset margin growth of 14 basis points was more than offset by compression of liability margins.</p>
          <p>I'll give you now more detail on impairment costs in the balance sheet. Impairment has continued to improve across all of our businesses with one exception, which is the corporate portfolio in Spain. Even this portfolio had seen an improving trend in the second half, and we expect this to continue in 2011.</p>
          <p>The most significant reduction during the year was in Barclays Capital, where single name losses are very small. In Global Retail Banking there was an overall improvement of 12% across all the portfolios. Based on current trends, we expect continued improvement in impairment across the group in 2011, albeit at a lower rate.</p>
          <p>This slide shows a breakdown of cost growth over the year. We've taken a conscious decision, as impairment improved, to reinvest in the business, and the most significant increase during the year was investment of &#xA3;1.2 billion. This included &#xA3;805 million in Barclays Capital from front office trading and sales and the build out of our Equities and Advisory business. The charge for prior year compensation deferrals increased by &#xA3;656 million, goodwill and restructuring reserves increased by &#xA3;486 million, including the write-down of goodwill in Russia and restructuring costs in Barclays Corporate that I told you about earlier. Regulatory charges include a one-off provision of &#xA3;200 million in relation to noncompliance with U.S. economic sanctions.</p>
          <p>Discretionary and contractual performance awards for 2010 exclude deferrals from prior years, but include guarantees, commitments and commissions. 2010 awards for the group, which includes deferrals to future years, were down 7% on 2009 at &#xA3;3.4 billion. This is despite profit growth of 32% and income growth of 8%. These awards amounted to 13% of group net income, down from 18% in 2009.</p>
          <p>Within this, 2010 awards for Barclays Capital decreased 12% to approximately &#xA3;2.6 billion. This represented 20% of net income in Barclays Capital compared to 33% in 2009. These awards were fully compliant with all regulatory requirements and the agreements made under Project Merlin.</p>
          <p>Part of the compensation for managing directors across the group will be delivered under a new contingent capital plan. These payments are deferred over three years and will not be made if the group's core Tier 1 capital ratio falls below 7%. The reported charge under IFRS for 2010 includes the prior-year deferrals and excludes awards deferred to future years. A reconciliation of the published numbers is in the Appendix.</p>
          <p>Moving on to look at the balance sheet, total assets grew 8% to &#xA3;1.49 trillion. The biggest increases were in cash and balances at central banks as a result of boosting our surplus liquidity, as well as reverse repo lending, which is fully collateralized. Gross new lending to U.K. households and businesses increased to &#xA3;43 billion including &#xA3;7.5 billion from Standard Life Bank. Adjusted gross leverage was stable at 20 times.</p>
          <p>We currently expect to add about &#xA3;50 billion of risk weighted assets as a result of regulatory requirements from market risks, which will impact our capital ratios from the end of the year. We continue to manage balance sheet growth carefully, while ensuring that we have lending capacity we committed to in the U.K. for 2011. In light of this expected increase in RWAs and of ongoing regulatory uncertainty, we will maintain our conservative, but progressive dividend policy.</p>
          <p>Core Tier 1 capital at the end of December was 10.8%. On a net basis, equity generated from retained profit, excluding own credit, accounted for almost all of this increase. The combined impact of business growth and increased conservatism in the way we calculate risk weighted assets accounted for negative movement of 0.2%. Bob will talk more about later, capital going forwards.</p>
          <p>We've continued to improve our funding profile. Surface liquidity at the end 2010 amounted to &#xA3;154 billion. For Basel III purposes, we estimate our liquidity coverage ratio was 80% compliant. We've raised a total of &#xA3;35 billion equivalent in secured and unsecured debt from the wholesale markets in 2010. This was a competitive spread relative to our U.K. peers. The issuance fulfills about one-third of our financing requirement for 2011, and we expect to raise roughly the same amount again during the year.</p>
          <p>So to conclude, Barclays delivered a strong profit in 2010. Profits grew 32% to &#xA3;6.1 billion. Income was up 8% to &#xA3;31.4 billion and impairment improved 30%. We've continued to manage our balance sheet proactively with core Tier 1 capital ratio of 10.8%. Returns on risk weighted assets improved to 1.1%. Gross U.K. lending increased to &#xA3;43 billion, and total dividend for the year was 5.5p, more than double the dividend for 2009. Thank you very much indeed. I'll now hand over to Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris.</p>
          <p>As you all know, I've been at Barclays now for 15 years. John and I have been partners on the Executive Committee since 1997, and he has been my boss for the past seven years. I've also been President of the Group, and on the main board of Barclays for the past five years, and during that time I've been part of all of our decision-making. So it should come as no surprise to you that our strategy remains unchanged.</p>
          <p>We continue to believe that the integrated universal banking model is the best one for all of our stakeholders. It's the model that's enabled us to build a bank that's diversified and balanced by geography, by business, by customers and by funding sources. It's the model that's enabled us to offer the best solutions for our customers and our clients, and it's the model that's enabled us to operate profitably throughout the crisis, while offering security for customers as well as stability to the financial system as a whole.</p>
          <p>As a result, we've emerged from the crisis in a stronger position than we went into it. We grew organically, as we did more business with more customers in more countries. We also took advantage of opportunities to add to our retail strength with Standard Life Bank here in the U.K., acquire Cards businesses in Europe and of course by Lehman Brothers in the U.S.</p>
          <p>What all this means is that my focus now is on executing our strategy. And by that, I mean very simply delivering on our promises, our promises to customers and clients, our promises to our owners, our promises to our employees and the communities in which we serve and of course to regulators and governments, including the promises that we made for Project Merlin. In particular, we're focused on delivering our promises in four key areas, capital, returns, income growth and citizenship. In other words making a contribution to the economy into every community in which we live and work. I'll talk about each of these priorities in turn, beginning with capital.</p>
          <p>We took a decision early on to get well ahead of regulatory demands and we did that, because we recognized the importance of being able to create stability at a time of extreme uncertainty. As a result since 2007, or core Tier 1 ratios has more than doubled to 10.8%, while Tier 1 capital has grown to 13.5%. At the same time, we've reduced leveraged from 33 to 20 and our liquidity has more than tripled to over &#xA3;150 billion. We are, today, a safer and sounder institution.</p>
          <p>Of course the key now is how we're going to operate going forward. Despite some remaining uncertainties, we now have a much greater understanding of Basel III and we can project what we think the likely impact will be over the next three years. We're not in a position to forecast our earnings, but this slide shows consensus retained earnings over the next three years and despite the net impact of the Basel capital rules on risk weighted assets, our core Tier 1 ratio climbs above 11% by the end of 2013.</p>
          <p>The minimum core Tier 1 capital required by Basel III is 7%. We've heard other U.S. and European global banks say that they consider 7% or 8% to be sufficient. Our plans are based on what we think is a realistic assumption, that a 9% core Tier 1 capital ratio will be sufficient to operate in the top tier of well capitalized banks. This gives us extra capacity amounting to &#xA3;140 billion of risk weighted assets.</p>
          <p>That capacity could allow us to grow the business organically, increase our core Tier 1 ratio if necessary, and distribute more to shareholders through dividends. To give you a sense of the magnitude, &#xA3;140 billion of risk weighted assets is equivalent to one-third of our current balance sheet. Another way to look at it is it's equivalent to &#xA3;180 billion of new lending to the small business sector.</p>
          <p>Of course we don't yet know the outcome of the independent commission on banking in the U.K. or of the Financial Stability Board's decisions on systemically important financial institutions, but we're confident that whatever those outcomes, we'll be able to manage our capital accordingly.</p>
          <p>One reason for that confidence is our own ability to generate capital. You can see from this graph that we've generated &#xA3;7.7 billion of equity since 2008. Going back to 2005, we've generated &#xA3;10.5 billion. That has given us flexibility to both pay dividends and strengthen our core Tier 1 capital position.</p>
          <p>You heard from Chris earlier that the increase in our core Tier 1 ratio last year resulted from our underlying profit performance. Net generation of equity is a key metric that we use to manage all of the businesses. In recent years, our capital position has undergone stress tests in the U.K., stress tests in Europe, as well as our own internal testing, which we take very seriously, and we carry out on a weekly basis.</p>
          <p>I compare this to the kind of workout a trainer puts you through in the gym. When you look at our level of capital, when you look at our quality of capital, when you look at our ability to generate capital, I believe we pass the capital fitness test.</p>
          <p>Our second area of focus is returns. This slide shows that the returns of 15% to 20%, in the years preceding the crisis, are well above the historical average of 11%. If you adjust for macroeconomic conditions, for corporate and consumer deleveraging and for the impact of regulation, average returns for the industry will be in single digits unless banks take action. You will not be surprised when I say that our current return on equity is unacceptable. So we're working to improve this and to deliver sustainable returns above the cost of equity. Let me tell you how we're doing that.</p>
          <p>Chris and I chair a Regular Returns and Capital Allocation Committee and this is the chart that we showed the board when we met with them last November. It breaks the businesses down into over 40 component parts to put a spotlight on each and every one. To give you an example, we broke fixed income, currencies and commodities down into more than the three obvious parts. And we did that for every single business, asking three questions: Can the business be seen as top tier in the minds of its customers and its clients? Does it earn returns comfortably above the cost of equity? And are those returns sustainable?</p>
          <p>In order to make an assessment, we've looked at returns over the last three years, returns today to spot returns, and returns expected over our planning cycle over the next three years. Our goal is pretty simple &#x2013; to eliminate or improve every business that doesn't meet our criteria on the left side of this chart. On the basis of this analysis, we're taking decisions about the future of these businesses. This is not a complete list, but let me give you a couple of examples.</p>
          <p>Our business in Indonesia was sub-scale. We could not see a way for it to generate acceptable returns, so we're closing it. In Russia, we've made a decision to focus our business on government entities, large corporates and multi-nationals, and to exit the Retail business where we were unable to compete.</p>
          <p>As you heard from Chris, we've written off goodwill of &#xA3;243 million as a result. Importantly, by focusing on Corporate and Investment Banking, we will both contribute to the development of the Russian capital markets and strengthen our leading position in Russia.</p>
          <p>Here in the U.K., we're moving away from financial planning delivered through our branch network by providing retail investment services through our online platform instead. Barclays Financial Planning was unable to deliver sufficient returns to be viable, and it also diluted an otherwise strong performance in U.K. Retail Banking. So we have announced our intention to close it.</p>
          <p>We know that our credit market exposures are one of the biggest consumers of capital, which is why we've exited almost half of them in the last three years. We've also made a commitment to reduce them significantly again in 2011. Protium is an example. Since this transaction was approved by the regulators in 2009, the capital charges have doubled. And post-Basel III, they will have tripled. So we've begun a process to facilitate an early exit and take an impairment charge.</p>
          <p>In Spain, we're clearly not earning the returns that are acceptable, but we believe we can build a business there that is top tier with customers and clients. So we're taking action to return our under-performing business to profitability and sustainable returns above the cost of equity. That action includes putting the right senior team in place and appointing a new CEO &#x2013; we announced that last week, restructuring the cost base, maximizing profitable income growth by focusing on higher-margin products and more profitable customer segments in retail banking, and by building our cash management, trade finance and risk management capabilities in Corporate Banking. By managing our business well in Western Europe, we'll be in a better position to consider opportunities that might arise from industry consolidation over the next few years.</p>
          <p>These were all difficult decisions to take, especially when we've exited from relatively new businesses in our portfolio, but they're good examples of the scrutiny we're applying and our commitment to taking action. This process should result in stronger performance and better balance across the group. For obvious reasons, I'm not going to talk today about actions that have not yet been finalized, but take it from me that we will continually challenge each business on its return profile and its customer proposition.</p>
          <p>Of course another way we can boost returns is by looking at our run rate of costs. So we've put in place a cost program, but I recognize we need more than just a cost program, so we're reviewing how we run the businesses to make efficiency and customer satisfaction core capabilities at Barclays. This starts by looking at performance.</p>
          <p>I am immensely proud of our people at Barclays and of the work they do. And I strongly believe in the philosophy of constant improvement. That has many dimensions from training and development through to managing out those who under perform. Each and every business has been challenged to review their people at every level, because we cannot accept anything less than outstanding performance given what I want to achieve.</p>
          <p>As you'd expect, we're reviewing every category of discretionary spending from travel to consulting to sourcing, you know the drill. And we're also looking at how we manage our functions, including finance, technology and human resources. We need to eliminate any duplication and see how we can do things more efficiently.</p>
          <p>Right now, for example, we're investigating the way we manage our Property and Facilities portfolio, our Procurement and Supplier Management and our Accounts Payable activities. The result will be an organization that's more efficient, more responsive to customers and clients, will run at a lower cost and is fit for the new regulatory environment. The financial impact of this is very clear.</p>
          <p>We will take at least &#xA3;1 billion off our run rate cost base by 2013, but importantly we're not waiting. We have already identified and are executing on savings of &#xA3;500 million in 2011 or &#xA3;250 million net after restructuring charges. We can see pretty clearly how the combination of fixing or exiting businesses with poor returns, reducing costs, reverting to a more normalized impairment level and growing top line income allows us to target a return on equity of 13% and a return on tangible equity of 15% by 2013.</p>
          <p>This is a realistic goal, not just an aspiration. It's based on our planning assumption of a 9% core Tier 1 capital position. As the cost of equity comes down toward &#x2013; excuse me, as the cost of equity comes down towards 10%, returns will be comfortably above that cost. And below group level, our Retail businesses are on track to deliver a return on equity of 13% to 15% and a return on tangible equity of up to 20% by 2013. And we're comfortable that Investment Banking will deliver returns of 15% of more, even after the full implementation of the Basel capital rules.</p>
          <p>Our focus on capital and returns takes absolute priority. That's very, very clear. But driving top line growth is an integral part of improving returns. And we see clear opportunities for top line growth with attractive returns that we must execute on.</p>
          <p>In our Cards business, we have a leading market position. We have the benefits of scale and we have strong technology. That's why we already generate a return on equity of 13% and a return on tangible equity of 19%, with a return on risk weighted assets of 1.9%. These are all very strong numbers at this point of the cycle.</p>
          <p>This gives us the opportunity to drive top line growth and there are two specific areas of focus. First, we're a market leader in wave and pay cards for consumers and that's because of our successful investment in technology. Second, we're investing in commercial cards where returns are higher, utilized balances are lower and the fee structure is more attractive. As a result, we expect double-digit income growth in our Commercial Cards business.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management &#x2013; it's a perfect example of a business that was not historically top tier in the eyes of its clients, but we could see a way to build it into a business that was, and to deliver top line income growth with high returns. And that's why we launched the Gamma Plan.</p>
          <p>One year into that five-year investment program, we're making excellent progress. Income last year grew 18% and we expect industry-leading compound annual growth of more than 15% over the next four years of the Gamma Plan.</p>
          <p>We've also been investing in our Equities and M&amp;A Advisory businesses, which as you know are high-return businesses that don't use a lot of capital. And we're already seeing powerful results. In 2010, we're at number two in M&amp;A in the U.S. and we're ranked in the top five globally. We advised on eight of the top 20 global deals. Just last week we were appointed corporate brokers to BHP Billiton and AIG, the merged British and Iberian Airways.</p>
          <p>And though it's still young, our Equities business had a 10% share on the Tokyo Stock Exchange last year, was fourth on the London Stock Exchange, and was the leading market-maker on the New York Stock Exchange. We expect to increase annual revenues from these business lines by &#xA3;2 billion over the next three years.</p>
          <p>We also have growth opportunities in some of the fastest-growing markets in the world. Africa presents a terrific opportunity for Barclays. GDP there has grown at more than twice the rate of the developed world for the last 10 years. Its collective GDP of $1.6 trillion equals that of Brazil or Russia. And consumer spending in Africa is growing at more than double the rate of that in the OECD countries.</p>
          <p>We already have a competitive advantage in Africa because of our existing businesses. We're present in 11 countries across the continent, including South Africa. Importantly, we're top three in nine of those 11 countries. This gives us a unique footprint in the third fastest-growing region in the world.</p>
          <p>Africa already generates 15% of group revenues. And we've taken the decision to align Absa more closely with Barclays Africa to execute a One Africa strategy, giving us better opportunities to serve clients across the continent and enhancing our competitive advantage.</p>
          <p>We're also growing our businesses in Asia. Ten years ago, 5% of the world's largest corporates were headquartered in Asia. In five years time, 35% to 40% of them will be headquartered there.</p>
          <p>Our approach in Asia, as you would expect, is to focus on those areas where we can be top tier in the minds of clients and deliver good returns. Areas such as High Net Worth business and Wealth and our Equity and Advisory businesses in Investment Banking, where we are building on the strength of our platform in the U.S. and Europe. Our revenues in Asia have grown at a compound annual rate of more than 20% over the last four years. And we expect this rate of growth to continue, with Asia doubling to become 10% of group revenues over time.</p>
          <p>Our fourth key area of focus is citizenship. I think it's fair to say that as an industry we have not done a very good job of explaining what banks do to create jobs and support the economy, or what we do to support the communities in which we live and operate. It is certainly an area where we have to do more.</p>
          <p>The role we play in job creation and growth is especially important today, because in the developed economies, economic growth cannot come from the public sector. It has to come from the private sector, and banks have a vital role to play here, and we take our obligations very seriously. So let me give you some statistics on the most obvious way that we can help and that we do help.</p>
          <p>Barclays employs 150,000 people around the world, including 65,000 people in the U.K. In 2010, we created 2,000 new jobs. Those are new jobs. 80% of those were here in the United Kingdom. We've created opportunities for almost 3,000 students in our internship program over the last three years, often the first leg to getting a job for kids from the campuses. And we've also hired 4,000 graduates, including 1,200 last year when other employers were re-trenching.</p>
          <p>So Barclays makes a serious contribution to job creation, but we also help businesses to create jobs and grow. We have &#xA3;500 billion of loans and advances extended to our customers and our clients around the world, including &#xA3;43 billion of new lending to U.K. businesses and households in 2010. Last year we helped over 100,000 people start up a business. That's 10% more than in 2009. These are critical contributions to economic growth.</p>
          <p>In addition, we support the communities in which we live and work by contributing &#xA3;55 million a year to a wide range of activities. Let me give you a couple of examples. Spaces for Sports is a community sports program we launched in 2004 with the single biggest investment in U.K. community sport from the private sector ever. That's delivered 200 sports sites around the U.K., used by 60,000 young people every week in disadvantaged communities. In 2008, we extended the program outside the U.K. and we've done this because we recognize the role that sports can play in transforming lives by building confidence and self-esteem.</p>
          <p>Room to Read is a charity that operates in developing countries. It transforms the lives of young people by building literacy skills and by supporting girls to complete secondary education. Barclays has a strong partnership with Room to Read, and our investment has enabled the creation of 250 new school libraries across Asia. But we don't just give money, we give time.</p>
          <p>60,000 of our people in Barclays act as volunteers for causes that they believe in and we encourage them by giving them time to do this. During the last five years, we've supported over a million hours of voluntary activity and helped raise more than &#xA3;75 million through matched funding.</p>
          <p>We've contributed in ways like this for many years and we do so, because we believe it's the right thing to do. I intend to bring more focus to our activities in this area to make sure their impact is as positive as possible. We know we have to do much more in this respect.</p>
          <p>I want to sum up by leaving you with this thought. The trends that I've talked about this morning in relation to capital, to returns, to income growth and to citizenship are important, because in the new environment in which we're operating, we'll see a divergence in the industry between those that are able to respond to those trends and those that are not. Very simply, the gap between winners and losers will become greater than ever before.</p>
          <p>In this new environment, we have the right model, we have the strategy, but in the end it's about execution. Execution is our priority. Execution is what is going to give us our edge.</p>
          <p>The reason I'm excited to be here in my new role today is because by delivering our on promises, delivering on our promises around capital, delivering on our promises around returns, delivering on our promises around income growth and delivering on our promises around citizenship, Barclays will be one of those to benefit as the industry evolves. Our focus, my focus, is on delivering just that.</p>
          <p>Thank you very, very much for the time. And as a team, we're willing to take your questions. I think we have a bit of time for that. J.P.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. John-Paul Crutchley from UBS. Two questions, if I can, both actually Barclays Capital related. One on Protium and one on the broader business.</p>
          <p>Firstly, on Protium, clearly that was put in place in terms of managing risk assets at the time and actually giving yourself time to work those assets over a period of time. It looks like you're &#x2013; clearly rethinking your strategy there. It looks to be &#x2013; the loan itself is obviously not in default. You mentioned the tax so it's obviously current. So, it is a third party process of course.</p>
          <p>So in terms of extricating yourself potentially from that as you're now talking to, I'm just wondering if you can just maybe give us some color around that. Should we expect the costs related to get out of that? Should &#x2013; does the loan need a further haircut where you actually have to unwind the management agreement, which could have some costs?</p>
          <p>And I have second question on BarCap and Basel III afterwards.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I start with Protium. We made the decision in November to start to look at alternative holding strategies. And we're still, as you would imagine, in negotiation with the managers. Until we've completed that, it's going to be very difficult for me to say anything more, but the decision we've made is the result of a view of the level of capital held and the return on it.</p>
          <p>In terms of how we go forward, I think we'll have to wait until we've reached agreement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>J.P., I would just add, I think your question is correct. This isn't &#x2013; the decision we've made wasn't a worry about the loan or a worry about the risk. It was the levels of capital increased so dramatically from when we originated it.</p>
          <p>So when we went through the analysis I showed you with the board in November, one of the biggest uses of capital increasingly, particularly as Basel III is implemented, was Protium. And that's when we began the discussions, but still early stages, but we've made a decision that if we can change the term of the loan, we will.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second &#x2013; the follow-on was actually on Basel III, more generically in terms of Barclays Capital, and I appreciate this is actually an industry question, not just a Barclays question.</p>
          <p>You sound fairly confident that you can actually deliver 15% ROE in a Basel III world if a BarCap model. Clearly, when you look at those businesses, they're particularly dominated by fixed-income franchises. It's very hard to get a double-digit return in terms of you know &#x2013; the implied Basel III capital in the business, and the returns those businesses are generating at the moment. Again, as I say, it's an industry issue, not just a Barclays issue.</p>
          <p>So in terms of your confidence of being able to deliver that 15% ROE, how much does it reflect what you're doing in terms of shifting the nature of Barclays Capital business in terms of other areas, versus de-emphasizing parts of a FICC business, as well over time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll ask Jerry to comment, and Rich, as well. But I would say that the two big picture things that I think are slightly different than what you're saying.</p>
          <p>One is we feel terrific about the build-out of equities in M&amp;A for exactly what you're saying, which is the opportunity to have bought Lehman Brothers and then build these businesses &#x2013; their use of capital is low. The franchises are great. So they fit the new world very, very well.</p>
          <p>But I think on FICC, the thing that you're missing is we're a flow-monster already. We have been for a while. So I think that there's industries that don't see the kind of flow &#x2013; sorry, there's competitors that don't see the kind of flows that we say that will have to adjust their model. But it's very, very different when you're an industry leader.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>J.P., the only thing I'd add is, in addition to the focus on optimizing business model, and you can think specifically, some elements of the structured Credit business aren't coming back, but they haven't frankly been a big part of our business for years. We also have the ability to manage down existing credit market exposures. And so you've got &#x2013; you still have a reasonable amount of stuck capital that gives us flexibility to focus on driving and managing to &#x2013; high returns as the rules evolve over the next two to three years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. It's Cormac Leech from Canaccord Genuity. I just had two questions, please.</p>
          <p>The first is on liquidity. I think your LCR and NSFR ratios were about 80% and 94% respectively. Just wondering, are you planning to maintain those ratios going forward? I noticed the LCR dipped a little bit from the third quarter.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, could you also give us a rough sensitivity analysis to moving those, say, like 10% or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do intend to keep them in the range. We don't have a religious view about exactly where they have to be. So they will move up and down, but you wouldn't expect to see them move dramatically.</p>
          <p>And in terms of sensitivity, it depends somewhat on the composition of the underlying assets in the liquidity pool, which we're working on in terms of how we improve the return on that. And at this stage, that's probably about as far as I will go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sure. Could I just get a second question briefly? I think Slide 31 was particularly useful, where you give us the split of equity in businesses that are below their cost of equity, in terms of the ROE they're generating and above.</p>
          <p>I was wondering, is it possible to get this same type of split for &#x2013; just for BarCap? And then secondly, if possible, to get a rough PBT split that would map to that equity split? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We're using that &#x2013; you'd probably like me to fill that slide in, too, with the names on.</p>
          <p>It was very much used as a way to show you the kind of things that the management team is doing and the quality of discussion that we're having with the board about how we take the action going forward. We're certainly not going to mention anything where we haven't made a final decision yet, nor are we going to fill those in. But understand, that's the way that we're managing the businesses.</p>
          <p>So there's no sacred cows. Every business is going through the same drill and the same process. And it's a backward look. It's a forward look. It's a look at how returns are today. And every business has to be able to provide returns above the cost of equity on a sustainable basis with a client and customer proposition that puts it in the top tier. There'll be no exceptions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Before you ask, we're not going to provide a scale either on the left-hand side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Michael Helsby from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. I've got couple of questions. Firstly, one on the group ROE target, and then secondly, on just some BarCap specifics.</p>
          <p>But I think everyone in this room would probably, if you did a poll, would think that you need to be running at a 10% core Tier 1. That's certainly the perception within the market. So I'm very intrigued why you've picked 9%, because clearly you've had all that feedback, as well. I'm just wondering if it's anything to do with the level playing field from maybe Project Merlin. So I was wondering if you could comment on that.</p>
          <p>And also linked into that, if you used 10%, would you still be happy that you could get to a 13% ROE?</p>
          <p>And on BarCap, I was wondering if you could quantify the total negative PBT impact from your credit market exposures in 2010. And also, I think you've referred to Protium and the &#x2013; clearly the higher capital. What the Basel III risk weightings are for your credit market exposures, if you look to them today. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good questions, Michael. Let me take a crack and then ask Chris to fill in, as well.</p>
          <p>We're looking at the same information you are. We know a lot of things, but we haven't had a final decision by the FSB on CFI, GCFI. We haven't had a final decision &#x2013; or we won't have a final decision on &#x2013; from the Independent Commission on Banking. So the 9% is our best judgment of where we'll be running.</p>
          <p>To put you at ease, we wouldn't change our commitments one iota at 10%. So we know these work at both 9% and 10%. We think 9% is where we'll end up. We've heard J.P. Morgan say 7%, I think Deutsche said 8%. We're saying 9%. We won't know for sure, but Chris and I were sure that when we did this drill, we could hit these targets at both 9% or 10%.</p>
          <p>In terms of the credit market write downs, if I can say it generally and then ask Chris. P&amp;L wise, other than the Protium provision, it was pretty neutral. The issue for BarCap is the capital that it's using, as opposed to the risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I was going to add to that is that in terms of profitability, if you look at the credit market exposures through the income statement, it's about &#xA3;100 million, ex-Protium, and there's very little impairment. So as you say, at P&amp;L level, it's broadly flat. And in some respects, you're seeing slight write backs at some of the asset categories. Nothing massive, but some. As you say, it's really the capital impact rather than the profitability of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I'm sorry, have you got the capital impact &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; the Basel III risk weighted assets. That would be really useful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Subtle as always, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For another time, Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I should just say, we've given you the gross Basel III impact &#x2013; Basel 2.5 and Basel III impact. And it's in there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. It's Bruce Packard at Seymour Pierce. Sorry, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You stole that microphone. It better be a good question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I just wanted to go back to that flow question about Barclays Capital and if you can give us some sort of rough idea of the real economy businesses versus maybe other financial institutions that &#x2013; the flow businesses at Barclays Capital. I mean, I know you've never given that before, but is it possible to do that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sure you can give a sense. I mean if you're asking &#x2013; is it a prop versus non-prop? Yeah. Give it a go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't break it down, sort of, per se. We obviously deal with corporations. We deal with governments. We deal with hedge funds and traditional asset managers. And it's a pretty balanced business.</p>
          <p>Now some businesses, as you can imagine, Commodities business tends to &#x2013; and foreign exchange &#x2013; parts of it are skewed towards corporate clients, and that is very much real economy. It's either hedging transactions or, in the case of commodities, a lot of the things that we do are off the back of financings, and frankly, the hedge is a critical part of driving the financing.</p>
          <p>Within the fixed income and equity world, as you can imagine, it tends to be more financial institution and government and people looking to raise money and then obviously investors looking to put capital to work.</p>
          <p>So there isn't a particular focus. I mean there are times in the cycle where one client sector is more active than the other, but fundamentally the key to having a very successful and sustainably successful flow of business in these different asset classes is actually having a very well diversified and balanced client franchise, supported by research, backed up by technology and having the capital to facilitate the underlying flow, as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I was trying to get right there. Sorry. You got the microphone stolen, okay, and then right up front.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Mike Trippitt, Oriel. Thank you. A couple of questions.</p>
          <p>I just want to clarify the point you made, Bob, about the additional &#xA3;2 billion of income. Does that compare with sort of the &#xA3;4.2 billion that you reported for Investment Banking and Equities, I think, for 2010? You talked about the incremental &#xA3;2 billion coming through in Equities and Advisory.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Equities and Advisory, it would be in that segment. So the chart where you saw FICC, Equities and Prime Services and Advisory, it would come in those two middle businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's additional &#x2013; so it was &#xA3;4.2 billion, I think the top line income for the &#x2013; for 2010, so I just wanted to make sure I've got applies with apples.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the investment spend in BarCap, &#xA3;800 million in '010, is there any more investment spend required to achieve that &#xA3;2 billion? Where are we on the actual investment schedule?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rich, you want to give an update? I think you're referring primarily to the investment in the Equity and Advisory business in Europe and Asia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rich can give you an update on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think that we've done a lot the last couple of years. I'd say we're probably about 80% to 90% through in Europe. I'd say we're probably around 70% done in Asia, so there's more to come, but I don't think you'll see the same level of costs going forward.</p>
          <p>We've got the technology built now in Europe. There's still some people to fill in Asia. Technology is being deployed on a prioritized basis to varying countries, but you'll see some more spend, but not at the levels for those businesses that we've had the last couple of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Can I &#x2013; sorry, just ask a follow-up on Barclays Corporate? You talked about Western Europe and Spain, that's understood. You talked about new markets, but I think the mainstream U.K. and Island business is still &#x2013; I think, I haven't done the calculation for '010, but certainly the first half was generating a sub cost of equity return. And I just wondered what your thoughts are on that, in terms of restructuring and refocusing, to get that back up to the sort of right level of return.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rich, the question is about the U.K. and Ireland Corporate business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that &#x2013; sorry. I was distracted. Is that &#x2013; what was the question, sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the question was, how is that performing? And is it earning comfortably above its cost of equity? Sorry. I should have repeated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. That's okay. The U.K. and Irish businesses has shown great resiliency and is now coming back to where it should be. That business has been a successful business for a very long time. We're very confident that those businesses will earn the cost of equity this year.</p>
          <p>And in general, I think you'll see some improvement around the non-U.K. and Irish businesses this year as well. We're not making forward predictions. We would hope that the Corporate Bank would be close to breakeven for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Peter Toeman from HSBC. You told us there's going to be more focus on costs and a billion coming off the run rate of cost. But in addition to that, another way cost could fall is that the cost/income ratio of BarCap could go down to say 60% from its current 65%. That would still be within your target range. I wonder, should we think about these two movements as complementary or will you get one through &#x2013; should we look at any one of them as being the likely outcome?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we were pretty clear last year when we gave you a range of 60% to 65% for BarCap. And I think that will fluctuate based on market conditions, it will fluctuate based on the level of investment spend, but we're not going to try and fine-tune it more than that.</p>
          <p>Sorry. If there's a telephone question, we can take that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question coming through from the line of Andrew Lim from Matrix. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Andrew Lim from Matrix. I've got three questions, please.</p>
          <p>Could you give us a timeframe by which we would have clarity on whether the IFRS pension deficit of &#xA3;3 billion might be deducted from capital reserves?</p>
          <p>Secondly, could you tell us what the main drivers are for the improvement in your internal cost of equity down to about 10% by 2013?</p>
          <p>And then thirdly, could you correct me if I'm wrong, but I remember the ROE target being greater than 15%, which is now greater than 13%. Is that a reduction in your target there? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start with the last one and then ask Chris to fill on in the others.</p>
          <p>I think you may be recalling that we had 15% for Barclays Capital, which we still have. We had never given a target for the group. So no, it's no change. Sorry &#x2013; it's new, as opposed to a change, I guess is the right way to say it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, and in terms of the pension, it could go there. You need to have two things happening. One, the change to the International Accounting Standards flow through. And secondly, there's a change in capital calculation, both of which could be on the cards in the sort of 2013-14 type time horizon. If that was the case, then you would have to deduct that from capital.</p>
          <p>What we've worked on and built into our plans is what we would do in terms of the existing requirements where you take &#x2013; deducted from capital the deficit reduction plan. And that is what we're looking at.</p>
          <p>I should just say that the estimated deficit of &#xA3;3.2 billion is down &#xA3;1 billion on where it was a year ago.</p>
          <p>Andrew, and I can't remember your second question. Maybe you can just repeat it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On cost of equity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The main drivers for the improvement in your internal cost of equity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, cost of equity. It's a slight increase in the risk-free rate offset by a bigger return in the equity risk premium.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've got another question here. Thank you, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Ian Smillie from RBS. Three short questions, please. Could you tell us the stock of unamortized deferred compensation at the period end that will come through the P&amp;L in future years, please?</p>
          <p>Secondly, during the period of focus on profitability through to 2013, could you give us some sense as to what you expect to happen to total assets rather than risk weighted assets?</p>
          <p>And thirdly, there's been some discussion from the independent commission on banking about some move to partial or full subsidiarisation for your key banks. In terms of scaling the issue, could you give us some sense as to what you've told them in terms of the capital and funding implications if that was to be imposed onto the U.K. banking system, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on the last one, I think our report is public, isn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I think that's a public record.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the &#x2013; sorry, the detail of the question was more in terms of the quantification of what you might have told them in variable meetings rather than in the written documentation, because I'm assuming that has been discussed between you and them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It has and, for varying reasons as you can imagine, if we were to start publishing that, it would put the relationship we have with the commission for banking back somewhat. So I think that sort of private conversation probably ought to remain so for the time being. Sorry, Ian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess there was a question on, do we give the stock of unvested comp, I think was the question. I don't think we -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've done but in broad terms if we look ahead, the impact of deferrals on each year's P&amp;L is broadly coming to zero. So your future deferrals and your past deferrals in are sort of beginning to balance each other out. So I think as I look forward, you can almost put a zero adjustment for deferral on an annual basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In '11 and '12.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>'10 was -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>'10 was just under &#xA3;700 million. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on asset growth? For the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not something we spend a long time looking at. Most of it, as you can imagine, is on risk-weighted assets, but we are looking at absolute asset growth. And as we've said, risk weighted assets are in low single digits. Normally the balance sheet grows a bit faster than that, so I would have high single-digit type number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. It's Sam Cusweil with the Medibank here. Couple of questions on Slide 28, if I may, on Basel III. First of all, on the 11.5% 2013 number, that looks like it's before the phased-in deductions. Perhaps, Chris, you could give me just a feeling of how that might be if we take it all in at that stage.</p>
          <p>And secondly, on the RWA uplift, I think that, if I remember rightly from your numbers, it's the sort of plus &#xA3;150 billion, minus &#xA3;50 billion of mitigation. Could you perhaps give us a clue as to how much of that mitigation might be the shedding of the credit market exposure you've been talking about? And then perhaps secondly, a lot of your competitors have discovered a new alchemy where you can shed risk weighted assets without revenue. Could you give us a sort of feel for that? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The 11.5%, I think if we have a fully loaded, complete in Basel III, would drop one percentage point over about five years, so 0.2% a year is our best estimate. The RWA impact, I'm going to stick with where we went into the third quarter, to say that &#xA3;150 billion gross, net of &#xA3;50 billion management actions, is still the sort of number we've got. It's gone up slightly but only immaterially. The &#xA3;50 billion reduction includes some of the work on credit market exposures we'd expect so. And alchemy, not something I understand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Alastair Ryan from UBS. Two things, one, a small request, and second more substantial. Small request, you used to give us a very nice breakdown of FICC revenues into rates and credit and commodities and what-have-you, and could we have that back, please?</p>
          <p>Second, it's in the Retail Bank, I mean it looks like there's some good momentum in the U.K., good margins on new business, deposits coming in, bad debts coming down, you're taking market share. But in the European, the Western European business, which you're still growing as well, and still putting cost into, the margin of return looks somewhat less attractive, I mean probably to phrase it generously. So why so little delta between the two at this point and should we expect more in the future? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Delta in what sense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You're still growing volumes in Western Europe, which would seem to be at best, a very shaky prospect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll ask Antony to comment probably on the compliment you got on the U.K. Retail Bank more than the Western Europe. But I just want you to rest assured, there isn't a single business in Barclays that's not going through the same process. So you will see that business, on a sustainable basis, earn comfortably above its cost of equity. A.J.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, first, for the compliment on U.K. albeit, we're very pleased with the performance of that business. And I think our ability to differentiate ourselves in the marketplace through the sort of mortgage offers we've got, savings, the branch refurbishment and so on has really started to pay dividends for us. You see that in the top line and of course, we've benefited from improving impairment. So we feel really good about that story.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe, as Bob has said, strategically we're committed to Western Europe. We believe that Barclays can build good, strong, sustainable franchises there. Of course we are dealing with the current short-term economic pressures. I will reassure the audience, though, that whatever part of Global Retail Banking we operate, we have a minimum threshold for new flow business that has to be achieved in terms of return on risk weighted assets, and that threshold is the same across the business.</p>
          <p>So we maintain it, and we look at how we're deploying our risk weighted assets against new opportunities to make sure that it's passing that hurdle rate. And so we'll continue to invest in Western Europe, because we want to build strategically, but on the flow we are absolutely getting the returns that we're looking for there at the floor. So Western Europe, very committed to that. Continue to be building that out strategically, and of course, we continue to expect very good performance in the U.K.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm just going to wrap up, because we do have to move on. And we'll try and take more questions afterwards, as we kind of leave the room.</p>
          <p>But I just want to reiterate, this is about execution. And I think when you look at the team, and it's the reason I wanted to introduce the Executive Committee. You look at the years of experience that many of us have worked together, it's an incredibly focused, together team that has executed on a lot of projects before, a lot of businesses before.</p>
          <p>So, execution is a priority. It's about capital and it's about returns having primacy, that giving us the license to invest in some pretty good top line income growth. And we tried to show you how many of those opportunities we have across the group. So we're very, very excited going forward and appreciate you coming today to listen. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>