<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1174233" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Interim 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-08-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>629</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">John Varley, Group Chief Executive</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Chris Lucas, Group Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Frits Seegers, Chief Executive, Global Retail and Commercial Banking</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Robert E. Diamond, Jr., President, Barclays PLC; Chief Executive Officer, Investment Banking and Investment Management</participant>
      <participant id="4">Peter Toeman</participant>
      <participant id="5">John Varley</participant>
      <participant id="6">Chris Lucas</participant>
      <participant id="7">Ian Smillie</participant>
      <participant id="8">Robert Diamond, Jr.</participant>
      <participant id="9">Tom Rayner</participant>
      <participant id="10">Simon Samuels</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep">&lt;A &gt;</participant>
      <participant id="12">Tim Sykes</participant>
      <participant id="13">Frits Seegers</participant>
      <participant id="14">Robert Law</participant>
      <participant id="15">Michael Helsby</participant>
      <participant id="16">Manus Costello</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome, I think, we're ready to start. I am joined this morning by Group Chairman, Marcus Agius who is in the front row and then on stage by my ex-co colleagues Bob Diamond, the Group President; Frits Seegers, Chief Executive of Global Retail and Commercial Banking; and Chris Lucas, the Group Finance Director.</p>
          <p>We're going to do things just slightly differently this morning. We will start with a presentation by Chris on the numbers in the usual way but then we are going to have Frits and Bob talk about their business areas giving you the context, giving you the performance details and giving you the outlook and then I will wrap up. The effect of that will be that we will take a bit longer in our presentations than we usually do but I hope you'll feel that that's in a good cause. We want to make sure that we cover the ground properly for you. But we will leave plenty of time for Q&amp;A at the end, I assure you, and our intention is that it'll be finished by no later than 11 o'clock.</p>
          <p>Our theme as we present to you this morning, is a theme of seeking to execute consistently in a difficult environment.</p>
          <p>So with that can I ask you please to make sure that your BlackBerry's and mobile telephones are switched off and I'm now going to hand over to Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thank you, John. We've delivered profits of &#xA3;2.75 billion during the first half after absorbing significant write-downs in challenging market conditions. Income of &#xA3;11.8 billion was at a similar level to the first half of 2007. We've controlled cost well which has resulted in a 3% improvement leading to a cost income ratio of 56%. Impairment charges were &#xA3;2.4 billion, almost half of which is accounted for by U.S. subprime and other credit market exposures. We've delivered a return on equity of 15% and maintained the cash dividend at 11.5 pence, the same level as this time last year.</p>
          <p>Turning to the divisional performance, I'll start with the headlines before giving you more detail on each of the businesses. In Global Retail and Commercial Banking, UK Retail has performed well. There was excellent profit growth of Barclaycard driven by growth in international cards and we continue to build for the future with selective expansion of International Retail and Commercial Banking. Our Investment Banking and Investment Management businesses have managed well in difficult conditions. Barclays Capital has significantly reduced costs and balance sheet exposures while maintaining strong client-facing income. Barclays Global Investors and Barclays Wealth have generated good net new asset inflows during the period. All the businesses were profitable.</p>
          <p>Going now in some more detail. In UK Retail Banking profits increased 7% with income growth of 3%, reflecting strong performances in savings and local business. You'll recall that income in 2007 was reduced by &#xA3;87 million in settlements on overdraft fees. Average customer deposits grew 7% with broadly stable margins.</p>
          <p>Our share of net new mortgage flows for the first half was 26%. The average loan to value on business written this year was 51%, and our stock of mortgages was 35%. Only 7% of the book has a loan to value over 80%.</p>
          <p>Mortgage impairment remained very low. Overall UK Retail impairment charges increased &#xA3;11 million on an aggregate loan book of &#xA3;89 billion. Costs were flat with reduction in property credits of &#xA3;48 million and the cost income ratio improved two percentage points.</p>
          <p>At Barclays Commercial Bank, profit before tax was broadly flat with underlying income growth of 4% driven by higher sales of treasury products such as foreign exchange and interest rate derivatives. Impairment charges increased &#xA3;24 million to &#xA3;148 million. As a percentage of assets this represents a three-basis-point increase to 44 basis points. Cost growth of 17% reflected additional sales capacity and product specialists as well as ongoing investment in global payments infrastructure.</p>
          <p>Barclaycard profits grew 30% to &#xA3;388 million, driven by Barclaycard International and continued improvement in UK impairment. The international businesses delivered over a quarter of these profits with a 64% increase to &#xA3;100 million including a significant contribution from Barclaycard U.S. Income increased 13% with strong growth in International cards as well as &#xA3;56 million from Goldfish, which was included from the beginning of April.</p>
          <p>The international business in Goldfish also contributed to impairment growth of 10%. There was a continued reduction in impairment in the UK Cost grew 6% driven by the growth in International cards and they also reflect negative goodwill of &#xA3;89 million from the acquisition of Goldfish, partially offset by restructuring charges of &#xA3;54 million.</p>
          <p>International Retail and Commercial Banking is reported for the first time today as three separate segments, Western Europe, Emerging Markets and Absa. This gives increased visibility and reflects the way the business is managed.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe profits grew 10% to &#xA3;115 million; income rose 46% and cost grew 38% as we opened 191 new distribution outlets. Impairment increased &#xA3;71 million to just over &#xA3;100 million mainly due to growth in the loan book and charges against real estate lending in Spain. I'll talk in more detail about impairment across the group later.</p>
          <p>We're transforming the scale of the business in emerging markets. We added 321 new branches and sales centers during the first half. This investment has impacted profits which were 13% lower at &#xA3;52 million. Income almost doubled as we expanded the business and impairments increased to &#xA3;66 million in line with risk tendency. Breakeven times on new distribution outlets are relatively short, so we'd expect to see a flow of investment return from the end of this year. In GRCB &#x2013; Absa which now excludes both Absa Capital and Absa cards, Sterling profits grew 10%. This reflects both its &#xA3;46 million gain from the Visa IPO and a 7% decline in the average value of the rand.</p>
          <p>Impairment charges increased significantly in challenging trading conditions which I'll cover in more detail shortly.</p>
          <p>Moving to Investment Banking and Investment Management, Barclays Capital reported profits of &#xA3;524 million, down from 1.7 billion last year. There was strong income growth in interest rates, commodities, emerging markets and private equity. We've continued to tightly control costs as you'd expect which were down 32%. You'll have seen the detailed disclosure on credit market exposures in our announcement this morning. There were net write-downs on these exposures of &#xA3;2 billion for the first half, of which 1.1 billion are impairment charges. This is net of &#xA3;850 million of gains from the widening of credit spreads.</p>
          <p>This slide gives you a breakdown of the net write-downs and gains on our own credit quarter-by-quarter. In May we announced net write-downs of &#xA3;1 billion for the first quarter; there were additional net write-downs in the second quarter of &#xA3;973 million. Gains on own credits in the first quarter were &#xA3;700 million. Further gains were taken &#x2013; or driven by changes in credits spreads at the end of June. This also impacted the values of our credit market exposures. We've continued to actively manage down these exposures, which have declined by &#xA3;8.3 billion. This includes sales of &#xA3;3.1 billion, which will complete in the second half.</p>
          <p>Our exposure to monoline insurers is &#xA3;2.6 billion, 86% of which is to investment grade counterparties. Only 9% of the underlying assets are residential mortgage-backed securities in the U.S. We've reflected cumulative write-downs of over &#xA3;430 million against these positions, and our marks are based on internal ratings that are consistent with or more conservative than those of the agencies.</p>
          <p>Our leveraged finance exposure reduced by &#xA3;2.4 billion to five billion largely reflecting the repayments of Alltel, which is expected to complete later this year. We've held our leveraged finance assets as originated loans, since the adoption of IFRS. Their credit performance remains satisfactory. There's more to do, but we are pleased with the overall level of disposals and also that sales have been made at or close to carrying values.</p>
          <p>Our Barclays Global Investors income grew 5% to &#xA3;987 million reflecting increased securities lending and management fees, partly offset by reduced incentive fees. Cost grew &#xA3;167 million as we set aside reserves of &#xA3;196 million to support some of our liquidity products. We did this to give additional assurance to our clients and these charges may be realized or reversed as the assets mature over the next couple of years, their impact was to reduce profits by 32%.</p>
          <p>Assets under management at the end of June were just under $2 trillion including net new assets of $25 billion which were more than offset by negative movements in the equity markets.</p>
          <p>At Barclays Wealth both profits and income grew 5%. Income growth reflected an increase in customer deposits. Total client assets were &#xA3;133 billion with net new inflows of &#xA3;3.5 billion offsetting negative market movements.</p>
          <p>You'll have seen that we've just announced the sale of our closed life insurance book for &#xA3;753 million realization a gain of 330 million. The closed life book contributed about 110 million of profits in 2007. Excluding charges on U.S. subprime and other credit market exposures, impairment for the group totaled &#xA3;1.3 billion; the largest percentage increases were in Retail and Commercial Banking outside the UK</p>
          <p>As you know risk tendency gives a full year forward view of impairment trends in our performing assets. The risk tendency we reported at the end of December has in general been a good guide for impairment charges in the first half. In Western Europe, we've taken higher charges than anticipated due to increased default levels in property and construction in Spain. We published new risk tendency numbers at the end of June. The combination of book growth and current market conditions have driven an increase of 19%.</p>
          <p>To give you some perspective on evolving trends in our portfolio here is some data of the most relevant assets starting with Spain. The substantial majority of our retail assets in Spain are residential mortgages with a book of &#xA3;12.6 billion the current estimated loan to value is 45% and we have insurance for mortgages with loan to values of over 85% at origination. Three-month arrears have increased but remain at low levels.</p>
          <p>Commercial property and construction lending totaled &#xA3;4 billion at the end of June. In South Africa on our mortgage book of &#xA3;13.3 billion, three-month arrears have gone up from 2.3% to 3.4% with a similar trend in other consumer lending. We've taken steps to reduce new lending in South Africa with lower loan to value on mortgages and vehicle finance and tighter limits on cards.</p>
          <p>Looking now at our UK assets; three-month arrears in our total mortgage book show a small increase to 97 basis points. Arrears to buy-to-let are slightly higher at 111 basis points and to put that in context about 7% of our &#xA3;77 billion book is buy-to-let.</p>
          <p>In FirstPlus our book is &#xA3;4.4 billion and the arrears performance is similar to that of our buy-to-let assets. Three-month arrears in our unsecured portfolio have shown a slight increased to 5.7%. In our corporate book property and construction represents 13% of the portfolio and as I've said earlier our corporate loan loss rate has increased but remains low by historical standards. You can see from these numbers that our lending has been conservative relative to the industry with low loan to values in our mortgage book, a selective approach to unsecured lending and the low proportion of property and construction in our corporate portfolio.</p>
          <p>Looking at the balance sheet, total assets have increased from &#xA3;1.2 trillion at the end of 2007 to &#xA3;1.4 trillion at the end of June. Derivative assets account for all of this increase, which reflects an accounting requirement to gross up assets and liabilities rather than the high consumption of capital, risk or cash.</p>
          <p>Loans and advances have increased from &#xA3;386 billion to &#xA3;450 billion. Other assets have decreased 13% with the reduction in trading assets of &#xA3;16 billion and then reverse repo balances of &#xA3;43 billion. Our overall balance sheet management is reflected in the level of risk-weighted assets, which is flat relative to the end of December.</p>
          <p>We had a Tier 1 ratio of 7.9% and an equity ratio of 5% at the end of June, relative to our targets of 7.25 and 5.25%. Following our capital raising last month these ratios would have been 9.1% and 6.3% on a pro forma basis. We said then that just over half the new equity will be retained and contribute to ratios and the rest will be invested in the business.</p>
          <p>As you know, we've announced the interim dividend of 11.5 pence and we expect to maintain future dividends per share at the level declared in 2007 until dividends are again price covered by earnings.</p>
          <p>So in conclusion, we've delivered profits of &#xA3;2.75 billion after absorbing significant write-downs in challenging market conditions. Income of &#xA3;11.8 billion was at a similar level to the first half of 2007. We've controlled cost well which has resulted in a 3% improvement leading to a cost income ratio of 56%. Impairment charges were &#xA3;2.4 billion, almost half of which is accounted for by U.S. subprime and other credit market exposures. We've delivered a return on equity of 15% and maintained the cash dividend at 11.5 pence, the same level as this time last year.</p>
          <p>I'm going to hand over now to Frits to talk about GRCB.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris. As you know our first half performance has been generated against the backdrop of extremely challenging market conditions and we expect the United Kingdom, Spain, South Africa and the United States to remain difficult for at least the remainder of 2008. We do not claim to be fully sheltered from the current downturn in the economic cycle. However well today's results demonstrate just the benefit that we are now reaping from the mitigating actions we begun in 2006.</p>
          <p>As our view of the world's prospects become more cautious we took action, which funded our risk and collections capabilities, we raised our underwriting criteria across the board; we cut credit lines particularly in Barclaycard and sought to reduce our most cyclical exposures. In tandem we accelerated our plans to diversify into faster growing international markets offering the poor prospects of higher risk adjusted returns. These decisions have been key to the performance, which we announced today. It's worth dwelling on a few statistics. GRCB as a whole generated nearly &#xA3;800 million of interim income in first half of 2008. A year-on-year increase of 13%; this is more than twice the increase in our cost base.</p>
          <p>Our overall impairment remains under 100 basis points notwithstanding the impact of economic conditions and a maturing international loan book. Our profit before tax increased by 8% year-on-year so you can see that we're delivering the rapid controlled growth &#x2013; performance whilst maintaining our cautious approach to risk. We're building a strong growth engine for Barclays, we are transforming our UK franchise. You can already see the benefit in the results of UK Retail Banking, Barclays Commercial Bank and Barclaycard.</p>
          <p>GRCB's growth rate is accelerating as we diversify into higher growth markets. We are carefully deepening our presence in existing markets across both retail and commercial and we are systematically entering new markets. We believe that this focused and deep approach differentiates us from some of our competitors, and it will yield superior risk-adjusted long-term returns to Barclays shareholders.</p>
          <p>Let me share a few examples of the progress we've made in the first half of the year. The performance of our UK businesses is hugely important to GRCB. So let's have a look at UK Retail Banking. Transformation program of this business has been underway for more than two years now. We have fine tuned the customer proposition and significantly improved our operating efficiency. Across all products we have adopted a simple and transparent positioning responding to what customers told us they wanted most. And the results, well they have full out. Today's numbers have been generated on the back of a leading share of new flows across major product categories. Most importantly, this strong performance has been achieved while maintaining a conservative and profitable underwriting stance. In mortgages, for example, our 26% share of net new lending has been achieved at enhanced margins with the conservative loan to values that Chris has already shared with you.</p>
          <p>We've also focused on growing our savings business. In the first half of the year savings balance has increased by 8% year-on-year on the back of a successful ISA campaign and market share gains. Barclaycard provides an example of our strategy of work both inside the United Kingdom and outside the United Kingdom. One of the first decisions I made when I joined Barclays was to upgrade our collections capacity and to tighten our lending criteria. We are now reaping the benefit of that decision in terms of controlled impairment and higher profitability. And with the first half acquisition of Goldfish we have added a high quality book at less than net asset value and created significant economies of scale.</p>
          <p>In times of turmoil there are opportunities to add excellent assets at highly attractive prices. We've also maintained an equally focused and disciplined approach to credit card lending outside the United Kingdom. In United States for example, we started tightening our lending policies in the first half of 2007 when the United States' economy was still going strong. As a result Barclaycard U.S. remains on track to deliver the $150 million of profit we promised for 2008. This is despite the deterioration in market conditions since we made that commitment.</p>
          <p>Turning now to our other businesses outside the United Kingdom, our international footprint is growing fast. We added more distribution outlets in the first half of this year than in all of 2007. 64% of our total network is now situated outside the United Kingdom. As Chris told you the breakeven point on new branches is relatively short and we will open a further 250 international distribution points in the second half. We added 4 million customers in the first half of the year and we will add a further 4 million by the end of the year. That is more than in 2006 and 2007 combined together. So we're making good progress in diversifying our business. This is creating a strong profitable base for the future. The buildup of the distribution outlets drives the increase in customer numbers, this then feeds through to income and ultimately into high quality sustainable profit.</p>
          <p>Today close to 50% of our customers come from outside United Kingdom. The non-United Kingdom businesses represent 36% of income. This proportion is growing fast. Over 75% of GRCB's first half income growth came from non-United Kingdom markets. We are alert to the risks of rapid growth. We're growing in a controlled way and we have a good balance between risk and controls. Non-United Kingdom profits now represent 25% of the total. Notwithstanding further growth in the United Kingdom the Non-United Kingdom share will increase as the returns from our international investments flow to the bottom line.</p>
          <p>Let's now look at another example; this one from Western Europe. Our business in Western Europe is growing rapidly. We saw income growth in the first half of the year of 46%. We have exported best practice from the United Kingdom and implemented the same conservative stance on risk. The figures on this slide provide an overview of our position in Spain where the housing and real estate sector is going through a difficult period.</p>
          <p>As Chris pointed out, the average estimated current loan to value of our &#xA3;12.6 billion residential mortgage book is 45%. Our exposure to real estate developers and construction firms is 16% of our total Spanish book, significantly lower than the 25% average for the Spanish banking sector as a whole. These statistics provide summary assurance at a time of economic stress. We have however seen rising impairment in Spain in both the consumer and corporate books and caution will be our watchword for the foreseeable future.</p>
          <p>In the second half of this year we'll continue executing to strategy. We know that economic conditions will continue to be extremely difficult and the outlook remains tough across many of our key markets. This will inevitably impact our performance. So we will continue to focus on those things that we can best control. Here's what you can expect from us. We will maintain our conservative and cautious stance to support high quality risk-adjusted, controlled growth. We will grow both the asset and liability sides of our balance sheet at attractive margins. We will expand our international network with the addition of a further 250 distribution outlets and we will selectively add another four million new customers.</p>
          <p>So in conclusion we're building a strong growth engine for Barclays. Our UK businesses are being transformed. They are delivering strong results from the back of market-leading positions and the benefits of our rapid but controlled diversification into international markets are beginning to flow to the bottom line.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll conclude and hand over to Bob to share with you his thoughts on IBIM. Bob, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Frits. Good morning, everyone. I'm sure it's no surprise to anyone here that the environment over the last 12 months has probably been &#x2013; it has been of the most difficult of any I have ever seen. We've clearly felt the pain in our businesses. We took &#xA3;1 billion of net write-downs in the second quarter in Barclays Capital, in addition to the net &#xA3;1 billion that we talked about earlier this year in the first quarter. As Chris mentioned, we provided &#xA3;200 million in support for liquidity funds in BGI. So it's been a very, very difficult period in which to mange our businesses. But we're doing that, we are managing our businesses and I think in the circumstances, that in the environment, we're doing it well.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding those write-downs the businesses in Investment Banking and Investment Management, Barclays Capital, Barclays Global Investors and Barclays Wealth, individually and collectively those businesses remain strong, those businesses remain profitable and those businesses are all increasing their market share.</p>
          <p>In the next couple of minutes I'd like to update you on three things: Our view of market conditions as we look forward; what we're doing to steer through what will continue to be difficult market environment; and a couple of the opportunities that we see looking forward.</p>
          <p>The initial market dislocation which began just about a year ago was severely exacerbated by a lack of liquidity. To put it frankly the pluming in the money markets, had stopped working. We've seen those problems gradually resolve. We've seen thoughtful interventions from the Bank of England, from the Federal Reserve, from the ECB. And the programs that were put in place, following the collapse of Bear Stearns last March are bringing back liquidity to the money markets but they are also bringing back confidence to the money markets.</p>
          <p>That improvement in liquidity, most importantly has enabled the financial system to begin the process of deleveraging and liquidation. Risk transfer is beginning to work. Assets are moving, even troubled assets, even mortgage assets to new buyers at new prices and in new structures. Now there'll still be pressure on the secondary market as this process is clearly ongoing and continued fragility in the financial system will be there as this process plays out. There're other challenges in terms of the markets as well. There is a weaker global economy and our feeling is that concern about that weaker global economy is looking for some support under U.S. house prices.</p>
          <p>There will continue to be structural imbalances, there is a serious structural imbalance between supply and demand in many of the big and important commodity markets. Oil is the poster child for that. So we don't see a return to markets like '05 and '06. We'll see continued challenging financial markets for the balance of 2008 and through 2009.</p>
          <p>So let me turn to how we've been operating in these markets and how we've been managing in this environment. We've been working hard to drive performance and in order to drive performance we've been focusing on managing our risks, managing our costs and staying close to our clients.</p>
          <p>Let me talk first about managing our risks. As we came into 2008, we had clear intentions. Intentions that we would like to maintain flat risk weighted assets. Intentions that we would like to manage down our credit market exposures in Barclays Capital by at least &#xA3;5 billion. And we have these intentions while we recognize that our clients needed to work with this and that would likely mean taking more of our clients' assets on to our books. And we also recognized that we needed to be open for business and we're going to extending more credit to our important clients. So we've recognized the need to do all this while staying open for business.</p>
          <p>Well you saw the numbers from Chris earlier. In the first six months of 2008 we have reduced our risk weighted assets below the year-end level of 2007 but we haven't stopped lending to our key corporate and institutional clients. We booked &#xA3;10 billion in new lending to those clients. And we've done that by entering into transactions that allowed us to exit &#xA3;6.3 of our difficult and troubled assets. Our total credit market exposures are down almost a quarter from the year-end 2007. One of the ways that we've done that is by segregating our troubled assets from our ongoing business and we did this quite frankly for the benefit of both, our client facing people can focus on our clients and our specialists, the staff that we put in to manage the troubled assets can focus on how to hedge those assets, when to sell those assets, how to package those assets and which clients would look to buy. We hedged where appropriate with the underlying indices in the appropriate vintages. And as I said where there has been opportunity we have liquidated positions without selling at distressed prices.</p>
          <p>We've also focused on managing costs and I know in investment banking that's always been a big issue. We have consistently said we could manage costs and that we could flux costs. More importantly we've consistently done it. We did it in 2002 with the dislocation in the credit markets. We did it in the second half last year and we did it again in the first half of 2008. Let's put this in context. In BarCap and BGI you know well that these are businesses that we've been growing at 20% compound annually on the revenue line, the cost line and the PBT line. In the first half of this year, if you exclude the support cost for liquidity funds, BGI grew while reducing cost 5%. In the first half of this year BarCap's costs are down 30%. We've been able to cut those costs while hiring selectively for future growth.</p>
          <p>But most important of all it's focusing on our clients it's been close to our clients. And doing this in an environment where many of our clients are facing some of the same challenges we in the financial sector are facing with difficult market conditions in difficult positions. The obvious place that you can see this is in BGI were we made the decision to step in and support select liquidity funds. We think it was the right thing to do for our clients, we think it was the right thing to do for our franchise. In Barclays Capital we've been staying close to our clients by continuing to lend to the right clients at the right prices. In Barclays Capital we've done it also by continuing to make strong secondary prices providing liquidity in the secondary markets for our clients, notwithstanding the difficult market conditions.</p>
          <p>The result was a strong increase in business frankly. Our foreign exchange volumes in the first half of 2008 doubled from the first half of 2007. In interest rate products our volumes were up over a third in the first half of this year versus the strong first half of 2007. Our clients are telling us consistently they appreciate that support, but it's more than them telling us that. They are telling us that by doing more business with us. Ultimately that's what's allowing us to drive the underlying strong revenue performance.</p>
          <p>Excluding the impact of write-downs each business in Investment Banking and Investment Management had stronger revenue performance in the first half of 2008 than they had in the first half of 2007 that is a real accomplishment and that is driving the underlying performance of the business.</p>
          <p>Let's look in more detail that how that played out in Barclays Capital. Unsurprisingly our write-downs had a big impact in our mortgage and asset backed business and certainly put a dent in our credit revenues. But the strength of our revenue performance comes from the breadth, the strength and the diversity of the business.</p>
          <p>Let me put this also in context for a second. When Barclays Capital was formed 10 years ago there wasn't a single business in Barclays Capital that was world leading. Even five years ago there wasn't a single business in Barclays Capital that would have been considered top three on a global basis. Well today Barclays Capital has four businesses that are in the top three globally.</p>
          <p>Our interest rate businesses, both cash and derivatives consistently perform in the top three on a global basis. Our investment grade credit business, you've seen us in the international bond tables. We've been in the top three consistently for three years now. Our commodities business is now operating at level pegging with Goldman Sachs and Morgan Stanley as the three dominant firms on a global basis. In our currencies business, in foreign exchange we're the first new bank in many years to break their way into the top three in a Euromoney survey of foreign exchange dealers.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, notwithstanding the difficult market conditions, we do see selective growth opportunities. In Barclays Capital there are areas where we are still not top three; where we believe we can continue to invest and grow and expand the franchise, so that we can be top three on a global basis. Our Emerging Markets business and our prime services business are two very good examples.</p>
          <p>I've talked to you all about the opportunity we see in the U.S. There is an unprecedented opportunity to hire talent and build in areas where competitors have been weakened. A good example is the agency residential mortgage business. It's a very large part of the U.S. fixed income business. Before 2008 we've never been ranked inside the top 10. We finished the first six months of this year inside the top three.</p>
          <p>In BGI we are already the leading manager, the world's number one manager of institutional assets with just under 2 trillion in assets under management. We're already the number one provider of exchange credit funds with our iShares business. We're already a top tier firm in scientific investing with our active equity business and our global macro business, but there are opportunities there as well for selective investment. Think for a second, what's happening to the underlying client base and the sophistication of the client base outside the Anglo-Saxon countries, in continental Europe, in Asia, in the Middle East, in Africa and in Latin America. Look also at the opportunity for us to build &#x2013; continue to build a fixed income business that would be level pegging with the top tier status of our equity management business in BGI.</p>
          <p>In Barclays Wealth, John has told you many times that we see this as one of the engines for growth in the Barclays Group going forward. High net worth assets are growing at 8% compound annually. They grew strongly in 2007 and 2008. Clients are increasingly sophisticated and London is increasingly the center to do high net worth business and family office business. We have a real competitive advantage because we are part of Barclays. It's the brand; it's the global reach; it's the universal banking model; it's the platforms and services that GRCB can provide us for our clients; and it's the institutional advice and products that we can deliver through BGI and Barclays Capital that gives us a true competitive advantage in the Wealth space.</p>
          <p>I said at the outset that the markets will continue to be challenging and they will. I think in those types of conditions, the benefits of being a universal bank are even more obvious than they've been before. The integrated universal banking model offers the best way to diversify risk, to manage capital, and to serve our clients. So our confidence going forward is borne of knowing that we have the right model, the integrated universal banking model. It's not just the model though, that confidence is also borne of the strength and depth of the management team across Investment Banking and Investment Management in these difficult markets, across the Wealth business, the Asset Management business and the Investment Banking business. This management team has been together for over a decade. They stuck together through the difficult times of 2007, the first half of 2008 and I can promise you they are up for tackling the challenges going forward.</p>
          <p>And last but not least it's borne of the culture were people have been able to stay focused on execution. So in the difficult markets that we expect over the balance of this year and in the next year, you can look for us to do the same thing as we've been doing over the last six to 12 months. Continuing to manage the risks, continuing to manage the costs, continuing to stay close to our clients, continuing to drive revenue performance, and if we can do that we continue to get a license to invest selectively in the kinds of opportunities that these markets are clearly presenting.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much for listening and it's my pleasure to hand over to John to conclude our presentation this morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bob. So what we've been seeking to do this morning is to concentrate on the short term and our theme as I said at the beginning is executing consistently in a difficult environment. In particular, we are looking at how we've done in the recent past and what shareholders can expect of us in the coming months.</p>
          <p>Although I take some comfort from our relative performance this half in managing our risks and in generating income, the decline in our profit is very disappointing. And I add to that my disappointment of the decline in our share price over the last 12 months; our shareholders have had to endure a lot. We are and we will be working as hard as we can in the period ahead to create the conditions that enable a higher price to be placed on our shares over time.</p>
          <p>If I have one message only for you today it is the following: Our short term objective is very clear to us; we must manage the impact of the credit crunch whilst maintaining strategy momentum.</p>
          <p>I will cover one other area in my presentation. I want to look at our four strategic priorities and even though these are long-term objectives, talk about what's happened recently in each area and then what we expect to happen in each area during the coming months.</p>
          <p>With conditions as they are, you need to be very clear about strategic direction. Of course, the environment tests our strategy, we must be realistic about the state of the world, but not allow ourselves to be immobilized by it. Our strategy is to achieve good growth through time by diversifying our business base and increasing our presence in markets and segments that are growing rapidly. And for all the many changes in the world over the past months, the drivers of growth in the financial services industry are substantially unchanged. I'm referring to the privatization of welfare provision; wealth management and wealth transfer; the growth of retailing banking in the developing world; the increasing use of capital markets for financing and risk management; the pursuit of yield; the demands that will be placed on the banking industry to finance infrastructure development and so on. Our strategy is designed to maximize the alignment between these sources of growth and what we have in Barclays.</p>
          <p>Our strategic priority is to remain consistent for many years as set out on this slide. And I am now going to examine each priority and talk about what you can expect us to be doing over the course of the coming months in each area, including how we will be managing the impact of the credit crunch. Of course that performance will be heavily influenced by the performance of the team sitting in front of you. I have a very good team. They know what they are doing.</p>
          <p>Now I am pleased with the progress that we've made in our UK businesses. In UK Retail Banking over the last months, we've secured good margins, the number one or number two flow position in current accounts and savings and mortgages. You know as I do just how far we've had to come since the end of 2005 to get to those positions. As you look forward you should expect us to deliver the promised improvement in the cost income ratio in UK Retail Banking from 57% in 2007 to 54% in 2010. Volumes in many areas of the UK retail market will be lower, but we are better placed to manage the effect of this because of our improved positions in market share.</p>
          <p>Whilst we've seen good asset growth this year in Barclays Commercial Bank, we sought as you've been hearing from my colleagues to be very careful with our sector exposure to ensure that we have appropriate diversification of our risk.</p>
          <p>Looking forward over the next year or two we expect loan loss rates in this part of the industry to trend higher. In Barclaycard UK where the turnaround from the weak performance of 2005 and 2006 has been significant, we've made good progress this year, regaining the number one position in UK cards and issue. But as you've been hearing from Frits our risk stance in Barclaycard UK has remained conservative. We've maintained those rejection rates of 50%. And we've been selective in our choice of risk. You should expect to see further diversification of the cards business in the future driven by further internationalization.</p>
          <p>Our second strategic priority is to develop our global businesses, mind here Barclaycard International, which I'll come to in a moment and Barclays Capital, Barclays Global Investors and Barclays Wealth. In each business the competitive field is wide open. You've seen how in the past we'd created patterns of investment in people, followed by surges in market share and income diversification. That's what we have been doing in recent years. And the fruits of that investment are helping us manage business risk today. BarCap's first half performance is shown on this slide. As you heard from Bob, our profit here has suffered from the write-downs but our income performance has remained strong. And we have maintained high levels of cost flexibility in the business. You've seen the same sort of thing in Barclays Global Investors over recent years where we have progressively diversified our business by expanding our alpha alternative assets and ETF businesses.</p>
          <p>This slide shows the income performance of BGI first half 2008 versus first half 2005. It illustrates the story of growth through diversification which is helping us generate significant profitability today in difficult conditions. The diversification of activity in both businesses has opened up new market share opportunities to us meaning that there are opportunities for composite growth even when volumes in some areas of activity are down. You can see the effect of that in the income performance of BarCap and BGI this year.</p>
          <p>We continue to think that the global income tools available to those who participate in these parts of the industry will grow over time at 10% per annum and that top quartile performance will deliver a rate of growth well ahead of this, which is consistent with the 15% medium-term growth rate of BarCap and BGI that we've talked about in the past.</p>
          <p>First off, profit in Barclay's wealth is well ahead of the full year profit in 2005 and we maintain our goal with the profits of Barclay's Wealth which I see as an important engine for future growth should exceed &#xA3;500 million in a medium-term. I should say by the way, that we plan an IBIM seminar for mid September, and we will be issuing invitations in due course. The same forces of globalization that we expect to benefit BarCap, BGI and Barclay's Wealth are generating opportunities also in our retail and commercial banking businesses.</p>
          <p>So I'll turn now to our third strategic priority which is to grown Retail and Commercial Baking activity in selected markets outside the UK.</p>
          <p>Frits just created a seismic shift in the performance and ambitions of these businesses over the last two years. That's significantly increased the growth opportunity in this part of the Barclays Group. And it's helping us to protect our financial performance today.</p>
          <p>I believe that we've enhanced our strategic optionality, yeah, because of our increased speed. What do I mean by that? Well, the best example would be to say that last year where we were seeking to acquire ABN AMRO, we were very interested in the 7 million credit card customers that ABN AMRO had. But even during the pursuit at ABN AMRO, we recruited, in just one year 2.5 million new credit card customers in to Barclays.</p>
          <p>We now have brought the same number of credit cards outside the UK as in the UK at over 11 million each. And Barclaycard international has contributed over 25% of Barclaycard's profit this half.</p>
          <p>You've heard from Frits about the growth in customer numbers over the last 24 months. The GRCB team is showing that we can enter new markets as we have done in India, in the Emirates and as we're now doing in Pakistan. And that we can expect to achieve critical mass in segments or products that offer the right risk adjusted returns through a rapid organic build out.</p>
          <p>We don't rule out acquisition. We've acquired a business in Russia this year, because we think that's the right bridgehead into an important market. But we have increased significantly. Our speed of organic growth, and as Frits just said, we're reducing simultaneously the time to breakeven in our new branches and sales outlets. And that's created new options for us.</p>
          <p>Over the coming months, we will, as you've been hearing, open and another 250 sales outlets outside the United Kingdom. And we expect the number of customers we serve in GRCB to rise to over 45 million by the end of this year.</p>
          <p>Now all of this coupled with the income diversification which Bob is driving in IBIM is helping create a very different Barclays from the Barclays at the beginning of the decade, which was dominated by sterling and by our core banking activities in the United Kingdom.</p>
          <p>Not only has the recent increase in the footprint of these businesses changed the future growth opportunities of the group, but it's also been important to helping us remain solidly profitable in the very difficult conditions of the last 12 months.</p>
          <p>Our fourth strategic priority is enhancing operational excellence and three things at top of mind here, the management of risk, of cost, and of capital. With economies around the world decelerating, it's an inescapable fact that our credit and market risk management capability will be tested hard again over the course of the coming months, so how are we positioned as we go into the downturn? We think that our risk books are relatively conservative. We've strengthened significantly the back-end processes, I am referring particularly here to collection activities. In the UK, the mix has shifted towards secured lending.</p>
          <p>We've taken for some years now a conservative stance in the UK residential mortgage risk. Our conservative approach to UK equity also dates back some years. We've taken care with our loan to value ratios in Spain as you've been hearing. We have very little exposure with an LTV of over 80%.</p>
          <p>Our commercial property book in Spain is quite small. We've been cautious in our approach in drawing the risk in our United States Credit Card business where impairments in 2008 has performed in line with expectations. We will, by having turned down volumes in South Africa, significantly reduced the future risk flow into our retail businesses, so as to moderate the impact on Absa of higher interest rates and slower economic growth. And you heard from Chris and Bob that our risk exposures in Barclays Capital are significantly reduced versus the end of 2007. These are simple, but important examples of developing over time our readiness for the downturn.</p>
          <p>We are too big in these countries and in these markets to avoid the impact of slowdown. But we hope and believe that the steps that we've taken there over the last months, and in some cases, over the last years will help our relative performance.</p>
          <p>In the area of cost management, we're trying to ensure that we have appropriate flexibility in the cost base to accommodate changes in the income and risk environment. There is good evidence of that flexibility in the first half numbers as Chris has reported to, I am referring in particular to the underlying jaws between income growth and cost growth in Barclays capital, Barclays clever investors, UK retail banking, and Barclaycard.</p>
          <p>Turning now to balance sheet and capital. In the area of funding and liquidity, we have directed a lot of attention at developing our deposit base. And customer deposits have risen by about &#xA3;25 billion since the beginning of the year. Meanwhile, at a time when the number of variables in the industry seems to exceed the number of given, we've tried to create some anchor points for our shareholders, including our new shareholders whose presence on our registrar I welcome again today.</p>
          <p>We've indicated what we expect our capital ratios to be and how we will use the new capital that we've raised. We've also indicated what our shareholders can expect for interim dividend and of our dividend policy over the coming period.</p>
          <p>We said that we intend to run capital ratios ahead of target in the current conditions. So, as you've been hearing about half of the new capital will be directed at higher ratios, that percentage and those ratio is been determined by our assessment of what economic capital we need to run Barclays in this environment, and about half in time add business growth. But it is worth looking at Barclays during the 12 months before our recent capital raising to form a view about whether we were able to keep close to customers in the way in which you been hearing from my colleagues, whilst making progress on the strategic priorities.</p>
          <p>Although we were very focused on the risk that we were managing, we've tried hard to keep executing on the strategy. Whether that was by continued recruitment into IBIM or buying a bank in Russia or by opening a lot of new sales outlets in GRCB or indeed by continuing to lend. And that was with an equity ratio at the time of about 5%, today's equity ratio is substantially higher.</p>
          <p>I've attempted in my remarks to you this morning to give you some idea of what you should except from us in the months ahead. The point I would make is not -- is not that the outlook is uncertain, what news to you is that. It's more important to say that the outlook was uncertain 12 months ago too, but we've kept executing. I think the world in which we'll be doing business over the next 12 months will be a world of economic slowdown, but not a world of widespread recession nor a world if I'd judge by our experience, today where our customers and plants will be inactive.</p>
          <p>So I finish by stressing our fixation with a safe management of the operations of the Barclays group, while maintaining strategic momentum, that's where we'll be in the weeks and months ahead.</p>
          <p>So we'll stop now and we're very happy to take your questions. Could I ask you in the usual way when you ask a question, if you could say your name and your organization that you represent. Thank you. Yes. Microphone coming.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter Toeman from HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just ask you about the mismatch between balance sheet and advances growth and WRA growth. I noted that the change in sort of Barl II models of Barclays Capital pushed down, risk weighted asset of BarCap &#x2013; but I wondered, in the future should we expect that advances growth and WRA growth should keep pace as opposed to sort of moving in different directions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank, Peter. I'll ask Chris to answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They certainly will not diverge as much as they have in the first half. The first half, we saw quite significant growth in loans and advances to customers particularly and within that we saw growth in low RWA assets, things like settlement balances, collateral balances and lending to high-quality, high-rated customers. That's no surprise; that's what we set out to do and similarly what we saw was a reduction as Bob's described as some of the higher rated assets, that &#xA3;8.3 billion we talked about. So that has led to a divergence in the first half. I don't see it following to the same extent as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question. Over here on the left. Microphone coming. Pete, would you mind passing it over? That would be great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Ian Smillie from ABN. Two questions please. Good morning. The first one is on the loan-to-deposit ratio which looks to have risen fairly sharply in the period to 124%. You mentioned in your speech, John, the increased focus on deposits. Could you give us some sense of any ceiling which you run the group to in terms of how high you're willing to allow the loan-to-deposit ratio to go, and if within that constraint whether you will be managing deposits faster or loan growth slower to get there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I take that question first of all, Ian and then come back to your second. The way we look at this, as you know, is we look at the balance sheet of the retail and commercial banking businesses and wealth business in aggregate. And we like to ensure that when we aggregate those businesses, we are net long liabilities. And the reality of today is that we are net long liabilities in those businesses, so we can export liabilities to the wholesale side of the balance sheet. That's the first thing to say.</p>
          <p>The second is that although you have seen over the course of the last 12 months, very significant emphasis in the GRCB business build on asset growth, it's important not to miss the kindred growth on the liability side. Frits has an ambition -- and I stated it is ambition but we are seeking to deliver it through time -- that as we originate a pound of asset, we should be originating a pound of liabilities. We are very conscious of the need to focus on that balanced growth. And as I say, our attention to the liability side is what's generated the &#xA3;25 billion of the deposit growth during the first half of the year. So I hope that helps answer your point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you help slightly more by giving some sort of ceiling above which you can't be comfortable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I've told you what our policy is and I've told you what our practice is. And I think you can see it pretty clearly in the numbers of the last two years actually, let alone the numbers of the last six months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. The second question is on Barclays Capital head count which went up 100, I think, in the half. Could you give us some sense of the moving parts behind that and perhaps whether there has been any benefit from EquiFirst and taking from that any sense of how much you would like to build the head count on a forward-looking basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's always hard to predict exactly where we are going to be on head count because the markets &#x2013; how the markets support hiring are a big part of that. But you are seeing movements around. We certainly reduce head count in areas that we don't think are going to be as important or profitable going forward. I suppose the subprime space is a classic example but it is not limited to that. We've added head count in areas such as commodities where we see strong growth in that business. We're still committed to bringing in talent from the campuses so that we are building the culture as we go forward. And I think what I would say you should expect to see is a modest increase over the year. But it could vary a little bit either side of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question just in front. Marvelous. The microphone moving splendidly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. <mark type="inaudible" /> UBS. Probably to exhaust this point, although that's probably a challenge to the room to fire more questions on it. But the increase in financial institutions' lending.</p>
          <p>Could you just give us a color on what that is? Is it the ACA-type financial institutions or is it HSBC-type financial institutions? And then I have a second unrelated question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ok, Alastair, we'll let Chris answer the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look at the overall exposures between loans and advances to customers and to banks, you'll find that about &#xA3;27 billion is settlement and collateral balances. And that is predominantly within the financial institutions. That bid that goes into banks are clearly the banks, the piece in loans, and advances to customers are the others which is a range from asset managers through the hedge funds. Important thing though is short-term settlement and collateral deposit balances.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alastair you have a second one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. Bob mentions oil and it's been pretty consistent over the past several years, inviting us to think about BarCap as long customer volumes and sort of underweight trending, prop trading given that the oil trend has broken down post the end of the half. Could you give us a comment on the commodities business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Listen, we are just very thankful that we were early. It was nine years ago that we began building that business. It was virtually nonexistent nine years ago. We are in a very strong position, and you're right. I have said that this isn't about the bull market in prices. And our view of oil, which has been fairly public, is that we see a range of kind of 115 to 140. There is going to be a fair amount of volatility in there.</p>
          <p>What I said in my presentation, I reiterate. There is a structural imbalance between supply and demand in many of the key commodity markets ,and the demand is real. It's going to be affected by how weak the economy or how strong is the economy and the supply <mark type="inaudible" />. But what I can tell you for sure is we are doing a lot more client business every month than we've ever done before. Our presence in the market is bigger, more important and more respected. But there are more clients doing business recognizing the risks in this business than there ever were before both on the investor side and on the risk management side, the corporate side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question. Microphone coming; yes, there we are. Simon, I think it's coming to you now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's been given to me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, would you mind giving it to Simon first, your colleague, then -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think <mark type="inaudible" /> thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, you give it to Simon, please, and then I'll come back to you, I promise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I could steal all his questions. It's Simon Samuels from Citigroup. Just, well, actually, just two or three actually, but first, just as factually, could you give us the loan to value on your new flow of mortgages in Spain, in the way you have in the UK?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The loan to value ratio on the new flow is about 60%, just less, sort of averaging between 55 and 60.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. The &#x2013; two questions. First I just wanted to see whether you might just talk around slide, <mark type="inaudible" /> page 96, that's just showing your customer loans and advances by industry grouping. The category I was just quite interested in was the construction and property portfolio that totals about 25 billion Sterling globally. But maybe more interestingly has kind of grown &#x2013; looks like about, well, annualized about 25% in the first half of this year. So I was wondering whether you could just talk about what trends you are seeing there, whether that's kind of voluntary or involuntary drawdowns, so that's the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Well, let me give a general comment, and Chris may well want to add. I think the way that we look at this is on a numerator and denominator basis, Simon. I think that by the standards of the industry in any event, and remember that our loans to customers are something like &#xA3;400 billion. Having property and construction at 25 globally out of 400 billion is subdued as to global exposure, compared with the industry. And that's a very conscious decision.</p>
          <p>If I look at our pattern of lending activity generally -- and I am going to allow Chris to comment further in a moment -- but if I look generally, what we have been doing in these markets as you can imagine is we have been very fixated with insuring where we are extending exposure into a sector that may be riskier than it has been. But we are extending to relationships that we know well. And so the lending activity that we've done in that sector is very much dominated by a long-term view of relationships that we respect and know. Chris?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was going to say the predominant portfolios are in the UK, and it has been a mix of draw-downs of existing facilities, substantially draw-downs of existing facilities with existing customers, some new business. And in Spain, there is a small balance, about &#xA3;4 billion, which has grown slowly but not more significantly than the overall book in Western Europe. So I think I would characterize it as mostly existing customer relationship draw-downs rather than new business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Simon, you had a second?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Last question really is just on &#x2013; it's actually on page 57, looking at your coverage ratios, which have kind of basically drifted down about 10 percentage points from last year from just over 60% around 50. Obviously I guess that reflects the increasing proportion of nonperforming loans that have got some collateral backing to them. So I understand the reasons for that move. My question is what would you -- I mean it's an odd trend to see given what's going in the world. Do you think there's some kind of natural trough that that number hits, so if you go back a long, long way in Barclays Group, that coverage ratio would have been historically much higher, so kind of going forward from here would you expect now a reconnection of NPL formation and essentially the formation of UPNL reserves?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's actually not so significantly out of touch with the 10-year average if you look at the numbers over a long period of time. And so what I would say and I am going to allow Chris to comment further in just a moment, but what I would say, Simon, is that are the coverage ratios performing as we would expect at this point in the cycle? The answer for that is yes, but, Chris, would you like to amplify?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will. You are right in terms of the drivers behind this are two-fold. Firstly, there is a mix change, and secondly there is the impact of what we've been doing to early stage delinquencies and in particular Frits mentioned some of the back-end processes which has the impact of getting the numbers into the NPL and the PCRL numbers at a relatively low impairment rate, so that's what we are seeing; as you go through the cycle you expect to see that increase.</p>
          <p>I look at it against the range that we see and I know it's impacted slightly by changes in the accounting from UK GAAP to IFRS, but if you look at the range we were about the last 15 years the numbers that are at 52 go somewhere between 37% at the low point and 75% at the top point and that will depend on the number of the facts including those I've just described.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. We'd like to pass it to Tom in front of you. Tom?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very, much John. It's Tom Rayner from Citigroup. Just wanted to test you out really on your sort of level of comfort with your capital ratios now. On the equity Tier 1 ratio just reported of 5%, the way I calculated it comes out of 4.6, so it's a bit lower which would leave your pro forma a little bit below 6%, I think. And the reason I am asking is not -- I am going to start asking about destructive credit markdowns but rather the trends in the nonperforming loans because ex-destructure credit if my math's all right in the first half of this year the NPLs have increased by 54% annualized, and given that the economic downturn is early stage in the UK and we're seeing obviously property market problems in places like Spain, I just wondered if you could comment on those trends together, the capital strength versus what we are seeing on NPLs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start, and I should ask Chris to give more detail. From the way we look at this is &#x2013; as I said in the remarks that I was making, we derive our view about the capital ratios that we have from an assessment of the economic capital requirements of Barclays at any given time. And we're taking a forward view of course when we come to that analysis. So we don't pluck out of the air a view about target ratios or where we want to run actual ratios as well as hit the target. We try to invest that decision with as much science as possible. And I should say that plenty of science goes into the calculation of the equity ratio at 5%, so I hear you that you disagree with us on that number, but we are confident about the consistency of the number and the rigor with which the number is calculated. So that's how we come to our view. It's unsurprising to me that we should require in these markets more capital, more economic capital to run Barclays, and that's one of the reasons why we have raised more capital. Chris?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All I would say, really, in addition to that is if you look at the economic capital, which we use as one of the tools that helps inform us as to the ratio level, you will see quite significant growth in economic capital requirement at exactly the time we would expect, which is at the beginning of the downturn rather than as we go through it, and it is that which has helped inform us as to the ratios we wish to run.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could I've a quick follow-up just on that very issue, sort of an economic capital capital, say. I noticed that the Barclays Capital is always actually doubled on the position or nearly doubled on the position a year ago. And is that simply reflecting what's happened post the credit crisis, or is that reflecting some other --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11">
        <plist>
          <p>Again it's very much, what we would expect. The -- you see the impact of the stressed environment, you see the impact of business growth, you see the impact of the diversification by asset class. So it doesn't surprise us at all that economic capital has grown although there is a convergence at this point in the cycle between economic capital and regulatory capital, which convergence of course has been amplified by what's happened in Basel 2. And anything you want to add, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you said it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question. On the aisle here -- yes, that's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Tim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning John and good morning everyone. It's Tim Sykes from Execution. Just on this point of capital, I got two questions they are slightly related. The first is just to clarify then that the target equity Tier 1 ratio remains 5.25%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you would expect to drift back towards that level by say the end of next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I know you will love us to forecast that, but you said that, I haven't.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well that that's my interpretation and we'll take it from there, and really I want to relate that Bank to Barclays Capital because Bob has a brilliant presentation and we're all sort of charmed and sweaty that things might be getting better again but the world is changing and Barclays Capital is built on leverage and deleveraging is a feature of the discussion with regulators and it's a discussion of where the market is going to go. We have an article on the front page FT today. And so return on assets is going to become an important calculation.</p>
          <p>And the return on asset of Barclays Capital is very low, it's 0.05% on today's numbers and it was only 0.2% back in the first half of 2007. So, I wonder if you could comment on the regulator's desire to see leverage reduced and the impact that that will have on your requirement for capital and the relevance of economic capital within that environment and where you would position your business within that new environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All very good questions. There is no doubt that we have recognized for a year now that going forward, banks in general and investment banks in particular, are going to operate with more capital as John just said, with less leverage. And that's how we're building the business. If you separate and as I talked about, we've moved out difficult assets, we prefer not to have those clearly into a backlog that we're managing and we're working down. But away from that you saw a significant decrease in the risk weighted assets. And I think &#x2013; what we recognize going forward is that our business model is going to have to adjust, all business models will adjust to the new environment of less leverage and more equity, and we will. It means more client business, it means more of the things that I am talking about in the commodity business, it means more of the volumes that I am talking about in the foreign exchange business.</p>
          <p>So, I think, the way I would think about it is that thank goodness we have an integrated universal banking model in the new environment. Thank goodness we recognize that those things are going to be adjusted over time. And thank goodness the underlying flows of our business. That's why I think it's so important in this difficult time to look at how strong the revenues were in those key product lines in Barclays Capital, which wasn't driven by risk, it was driven by client business. We doubled the foreign exchange volumes in the first half of the year. So the stronger the franchise, the stronger the business model; the stronger the management team, the stronger the performance that's going to be going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim, you had a second question, didn't you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not quite sure that addresses it. Maybe we will take it up offline. But I think it's a fundamental feature to move forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question behind you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Eric Chambers from <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have two questions. One is on the gain on widening your spread on own liabilities. I think in the past we have been able to reconcile this for you and for others who do this by movements in their own credit spreads. That's only worked in the first quarter when there was widening and then in April I think you indicated a narrowing. What I find difficult to interpret is why although your overall credit spreads seem to have narrowed, your gain on liabilities has widened?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we take that one first. First of all...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you actually look at the progression of it through the first half, perhaps you're right, in the first quarter, we had something in the order of &#xA3;700 million of gain. That snapped back in April as a result of spreads narrowing, but if you look at what happened to the spreads in the last week of June, they opened out again and actually have gone to a higher level than we saw at any other time in the quarter. So in terms of progression, there was about &#xA3;700 million of own credit widening impact in the first quarter and about &#xA3;150 million net in the second quarter getting to that 852.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You had a second question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm still not sure if that ties in with what I have seen of the credit spreads but perhaps we can take that up later. The second question is on your outlook for UK defaults because your risk tendency has increased slightly, but it looks like mainly from the Goldfish acquisition, you don't seem to have --  maybe because of your mortgage book you are not seeing the trends of some of the others nonsecured credits, also you don't seem to be taking much account of the deteriorating UK economy, you do have some increase in potential problem loans shown. But could you just share your thinking on the near-term outlook for UK credit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me start and I'll ask Frits to add. As I said in my remarks, our presence in this economy means that we can't sidestep neatly the impact of economic slowdown, but I do think that if you look at the key bellwethers of risk in the United Kingdom, our exposure to commercial property, our exposure to secured residential property, our unsecured exposure, particularly in Barclaycard, you can see the trends are very encouraging. So if we look at impairment levels, if we look at delinquency, the files have performed well in the United Kingdom over the course of the last 12 months and over the course of the last six months. So of course GDP growth in the United Kingdom is going to be slower in 2008 and 2009 that it has been for some time. We acknowledge that, but we believe we got ourselves into position where we are in any event prepared. And what we like to see of course is the files responding to treatment. So we would have expected and indeed we forecast very clearly that we would see through 2007 an improvement in the impairment performance in Barclaycard UK, and we saw absolutely that and as we said in the announcement today there is an improvement underlying in Barclaycard UK in its impairment line of over &#xA3;60 million first half versus first half. Frits, do you want to add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you, John. What we did force Anthony and the team tightened up lending criteria already 18 to 24 months ago. So if you look at the type of customer we are getting into Barclaycard , that's the profile of people. We turned down 50 to 55% of the applications, then we intensified collections, so if you add it all up, we have done a very good job in managing more difficult UK environment.</p>
          <p>To come back on UK mortgage book, like to add that our losses last year were zero and this year it's kind of like negligible till now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question. Over here; yes, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert Law of Lehman. Can I have three questions, please. Firstly, in terms of the impaired asset trends that you are showing, there's been something like a two billion rise in the PCRLs, I think, year-to-date. Can you give us some feel of the timing of that during the period? Is that a representative pace of duration during the first half as the slowdowns come on or do you -- is it all back-end-loaded towards the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris, do you want to comment on that first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It is, as you would expect, as the economy has deteriorated, the level of growth has increased, but I don't think I would read into that that we'd expect that to be entirely economy related. Some of it is the direct result of the actions we've taken in collections and that sort of  back-end collection process that Frits has talked about. Well would you have the second?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert, would you have the second?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Secondly, within the group as a whole I think there is -- could you comment on the effect of financing on asset sales, and so what I'm thinking about here is loan to sales where you provided financing. Has that been a significant feature for you, and if it has, what kind of impact has it had on risk assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It has not been a significant factor. We have done some financing from time to time with clients but it has been a small portion of what we have sold into the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I have one more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your can, Robert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was just commenting on the greater expense growth if you back out BarCap, I think there is been a fairly significant deterioration in expenses versus revenue, which obviously reflects in the investment you are doing in the international businesses. Do you think that's likely to continue in the short run or do you see it moving more in line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if you look -- I mean there are some areas where we have consciously invested. So if I think about where we've got negative jaws, I would refer to the commercial banking business here in the United Kingdom, where Chris has talked about the sort of investment that we've been making, as an example in customer-facing staff and the other obvious area is GRCB Emerging Markets where we have negative jaws for all the reasons that you referred to. If you then look elsewhere on an underlying basis actually I think that the jaws performance is quite strong. You've got &#x2013; if you take it just at the GRCB level and the IBIM level. And each of GRCB and IBIM, you've got 3% positive jaws.</p>
          <p>So I would say that the cost management is very much responding to treatment where we are choosing to invest -- we have an eye of course the return on that, but where we are choosing to invest -- we are prepared to give cost license in that particular business area, but generally our attitude as you would expect given the environment is one of real cost stringency.</p>
          <p>Next question; microphone coming &#x2013; yes, that's it. It's yours, Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Michael Helsby from Morgan Stanley. I've got two questions, one on the credit exposures and then just a follow-up on capital. If you look at page 40 of the press release, and just homing in on your monoline exposures, certainly, that the level of the write-downs you've taken on the A, BBB and the non-investment grade growth exposure looks very, very, very low relative to what other institutions have done. So I was just wondering if you could comment on that, why is so low. And on also on your &#x2013; if you go back a couple of pages --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, do you &#x2013; can we just take the first one first then I will be able to follow it better. Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, I think &#x2013; when I look at this, I think of two things, I say what is the quality of the underlying assets that are being wrapped, and then what is the quality of the monocline  insurer that's doing the wrapping. If I look at page 40, I think the thing that stands out for me is if I look at the asset composition you will see that there is less than 9% of the total, which is US RMBS and the vast majority of it &#xA3;14-odd billion, is CLOs, which look and are performing extremely strong and are very high quality. I then look at the disposition of the monolines themselves and I look at of that 2016 for the RMBS, only &#xA3;63 million is being wrapped by non-investment grade insurers. So I put both of those facts together. It makes me feel very comfortable with the level of exposure we've got, the total exposure we have got and the marks we've taken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob, could you just add.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Michael, I think it's just important to put the business model in context because there is a number of different ones. We've seen some big write-offs out there on monolines. Some of them because there is direct exposure &#x2013; using them as insurance for difficult positions and those have had to be written off. We had none of that. The large majority of this position, as Chris said, I think it's 19 of the 21, is away from the mortgage-related business. And when you were positioning a CLO high quality asset, and as a last part of that you take some insurance as well, it's much different, and kind of hoping and wishing where the poor positions that you can go out and get some insurance. At the end of the day, for us to have any losses here at all, we have to have defaults on both the underlying assets and the monolines. So I would look at it in that context of how small the position is in what would be considered difficult assets. And with those difficult assets, we haven't had any defaults either. So, I think it's a much different position here, from the business model point of view and it's hard to do a read across, unless you think about the business model and how the business was entered into.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, you have a second question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a very quickly &#x2013; as a pointed detail, on page 36. There has been some concern drifting in about the quality of the '05 vintage on a high grade CDOs. So I was wondering if you could give us a spilt of the 942, what's AAA rated and what below. And as I said, I just have got one more on capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Well, Michael, we have given you about 10 pages of breakdown of these numbers and to go to an 11th page is beyond our tolerance and maybe -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've tried very hard to answer your appetite for detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, it's quite important tough, I believe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's why we have given the detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My follow-up points on capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please, this is your last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It is, yeah. No, no. It's basically, there's been a lot to chatter in the market about U.S. investment banks and the capital that they are going to need to hold in the new environment. And the 10% tier 1 has been a ratio that has been punted around with the inference that if you want to have a big investment bank in the U.S., which clearly you do, the Barclays will need to get to a 10% tier 1 ratio. So just what would you say to that? Do you recognize that risk?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll ask Bob to comment but the general point I would make is that the capitalization levels decided by regulators and supervisors around the world are very much dictated by business risk and business model. I mean that's today's reality, that hasn't changed at all. So I can understand, and I know the friend that you're referring to of course, and we've heard that chatter as well. But what I expect that to be applied universally across the market, that's not what we would expect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I have nothing to add.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question, yeah, actually, Simon, do you mind if I give somebody who hasn't asked a question yet? Here we are. Could you come &#x2013; and then I'll come to you and then we'll have one last question after Simon, so then we'll wrap it up. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Manus Costello from Merrill Lynch. Hi, I had a couple of questions on your commercial real estate exposures please. Firstly, in the U.S., you've disclosed a couple of very large loans which are within that portfolio. I wondered if you could give us some more color on what those are and what your intentions are towards those assets? And secondly, in terms of the mark --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we take the first question first? And then we'll come back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm loath to go much further because it starts then getting down to specifically identifiable names and we start talking to you about what we were working out with them on individual circumstances. So I think if you wouldn't mind, I'd rather keep the confidentiality of individual names to ourselves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our hope is that you will find, that we've given again a quite a lot of disclosure by sector and by country. We've given the breakdown between big exposure in the United States and the distribution of risks beyond that. So we're trying to get you into the ballpark, if you see what I mean without going into the territory that Chris has just said we can't go into.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we just as a minor follow-up -- we've seen that there are two very similarly sized facilities or one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please bear with me. We've gone as far as we hopefully can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My second question was on the marks that you've taken on that commercial real estate book. Relative to some of the peers around the sort of 90 to 92% level, most of yours appeared to be in the 97 to 98% area. And I wondered if you could talk us through how you actually value those in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me ask Bob to comment. Our starting point here is that and it's a point that we've tried to make often actually over the course of the last 12 months is that a simple read-across is a dangerous thing to do because risk isn't generic. I mean risk management isn't generic, but just taking a simple read-across and applying it in vacuo across the whole book is quite misleading. And one of the things we've been trying to do with our disclosure today is put you into position where you can see why we held that view. But I'll ask Bob to comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean I can't. It's business model and quality of assets and one of the reasons we sat back and said we are going to give even more disclosure than anyone has given is we are confident in our marks, we have been confident in our marks and we want to give you more information. Look at the geographic spread of our business that's outside the U.S. for example. It's not in the UK and it's not in Spain, it's predominantly in Germany. We have high quality assets. This is a core business for a bank. We are in the lending and in the commercial real estate business and we have high quality assets being run in mark-to-market books. So we are quite confident to say that some other institution is marked at 92 in the sector of commercial mortgages. If you looked at the quality of our book, which we're trying to give you a look into, you would be as confident as we are on the marks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'll just add <mark type="inaudible" /> -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One where we have got specific instances of names in the market that have marked levels that we are aware of. We've clearly taken that into account and the second thing I would just point to is an important driver of the mark is the weighted average number of years to ensure maturity and you see we've given those by region and the U.S. specifically is very short term at 1.7 years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Given where we are on time, I am going to say one last question from Simon and then we will wrap it up and of course we're available to you hereafter offline. Simon [Citigroup]?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the second question as well. And in fact I should also start with, thanks very much for the actual disclosure. I think it's pretty excellent so it's pretty lucky you are all sitting down in saying that. Well done...</p>
          <p>The question actually I wanted to ask which is kind of going to back to Tim's question and is really for Bob is I imagine this is the last time we will see, if you look at the first half of '07 BarCap made a 54% return on the economic capital. I suppose it's going to be a while till we return to that number. Since then, you've obviously doubled the capital allocated to the business and the earnings power has come down. So the question really is in your view when this is all kind of shaken through, what do you think the sustainable return is for BarCap either on a reg basis or on your preferred economic basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very fair question. It's probably I should have thought forward enough to have answered it that way and I didn't when the question was asked. When we started in BarCap, our commitment was 15 to 20% returns over the cycle. We believe &#x2013; John believes, Chris believes, Frits believes, I believe that we can do in this environment for 15 to 20%. I will spot you that the opportunity for 54% return on economic capital is not there. I agree with that. The conditions in the first half of 2007 were wonderful but I think that amplifies the revenue track record in the first half of '08 compared to that but there was more capital attributed to the business so if I can simply state 15 to 20% is our expectation of risk adjusted returns whatever capital you want to use we have a second goal, which is in good years, we would like it to 20 maybe a little bit plus, and in bad years kind of 10 to 15. What we don't want to do is bad years are negative and good years are high. So it's the same commitment what we made earlier and I think what you will see in the new environment which will be more equity less leverage is the stronger franchises are operating at better margins and better market share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you all very much for giving us so much time this morning. We are now finished.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>