<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1247113" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-08-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>629</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Marcus Agius, Group Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Chris Lucas, Executive Director</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Robert E. Diamond, Jr., Executive Director</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">John Varley, Group Chief Executive</participant>
      <participant id="4">Robert Le Blanc</participant>
      <participant id="5">Frederik Seegers</participant>
      <participant id="6">Alastair Ryan</participant>
      <participant id="7">Michael Helsby</participant>
      <participant id="8">Robert Law</participant>
      <participant id="9">Paul Lee</participant>
      <participant id="10">Lee Goodwin</participant>
      <participant id="11">Robert Diamond, Jr.</participant>
      <participant id="12">Sandy Chen</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen good afternoon and welcome to this presentation of the interim results of Barclays for the first half of 2009. Thank you very much for coming and thank you in particular for the accommodation you're showing to us on what is a very busy day for results. We do appreciate that.</p>
          <p>We are going to follow the format you're now familiar with. And there'll be three presentations, starting with Chris Lucas, our Group Finance Director; followed by Robert Le Blanc, our Group Risk Director; and then John Varley, our Chief Executive. That will be followed by, as you'd expect a Q&amp;A session when those three would be joined by Bob Diamond, our Group President and Frits Seegers, Chief Executive of GRCB.</p>
          <p>So with that format let's get going. And if I could just ask you before I off the platform to just check that your mobile phones are switched off. Thank you very much. Chris?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and thank you, Marcus. We've delivered profits of &#xA3;3 billion in the first half. And at the same time, we strengthened our capital ratios, reduced our balance sheet and leverage and improved our liquidity. We've achieved this as a result of very strong income growth, which has enabled us to absorb further credit market losses and rising impairment in a weak economic environment. The strength of this performance is thanks to the diversification of our business model, the universal banking model.</p>
          <p>In general, my comments today will compare the first half this year with the first half of 2008. Starting with the Group as a whole, profit before tax was &#xA3;3 billion, up 8% year-on-year. There was very strong income growth of 37% to &#xA3;16.3 billion with especially strong performances in Barclays Capital and Barclaycard.</p>
          <p>Impairment charges for the Group increased to &#xA3;4.6 billion. The annualized loan loss rate for the first half was 144 basis points, assuming constant currency rates and balance sheet size. Robert will talk in more detail about our impairment experience and outlook later.</p>
          <p>Costs grew 30% to &#xA3;8.7 billion with the majority of growth attributable to the Lehman acquisition. Costs grew at a lower rate than income and the cost:income ratio improved from 57 to 54%.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share were 17.5p and the return on equity was 10.1%. John will talk about how return on equity goes later.</p>
          <p>I'll take you through the performance by division now, starting with Global Retail and Commercial Banking. Net profits for the first half were &#xA3;1.26 billion. Income grew 14% in difficult market conditions with growing impairment and pressure on deposit margins in the low interest rate environment.</p>
          <p>Turning to the individual businesses. U.K. Retail Banking delivered profits of &#xA3;268 million. Income decreased 8% as strong income growth in mortgages and consumer lending was more than offset by deposit margin compression. Impairment increased to &#xA3;469 million, mainly in U.K. consumer lending as a result of the weak economic environment.</p>
          <p>Costs grew 6% reflecting the non-repeat of gains from the sale of property of &#xA3;65 million and increased pension costs of &#xA3;54 million. On a like-for-like basis costs fell 4%.</p>
          <p>There is net new mortgage lending of &#xA3;2.2 billion in a market which grew by just &#xA3;1.1 billion. And we advanced &#xA3;6 billion growth over the half. Mortgage balances grew to 13 &#x2013; grew by 13% year-on-year to &#xA3;84 billion.</p>
          <p>Our risks were well controlled. The average loan to value in the U.K. mortgage portfolio on a current valuation basis was 44% and on new lending it was 46%. Mortgage impairment charges were &#xA3;35 million on an &#xA3;84 billion pound book and just 1.2% of our mortgages were over 30 months &#x2013; sorry over 3 months in arrears.</p>
          <p>We also gained new customers and one market share. Our Golden ISA attracted over 500,000 customers in the three months after launch. Savings accounts grew from 11.7 to 13 million year-on-year. And for local business, which serves customers with a turnover of less than a &#xA3;1 million, we lent 27% more during this half than in the same period in 2007, before the credit crunch began.</p>
          <p>At Barclays Commercial Bank there was good income growth of 5% reflecting strong fee income and sales of risk management products. Profits declined to &#xA3;404 million as a result of growing impairment and margin compression.</p>
          <p>New term lending was &#xA3;7.4 billion, though overall loans and advances were 7% lower than the year-end largely as a result of the decrease in overdraft balances as businesses deleverage.</p>
          <p>There was significant impairment growth to &#xA3;467 million, though we continue to benefit from the diversification of our loan book. We have relatively low exposure to leveraged finance and the property and construction sectors and our largest single charge year-to-date was &#xA3;25 million. Costs were well controlled where the rate of cost growth at 9% was higher than that of income growth, mainly as a result of the increase in pension charge of &#xA3;35 million.</p>
          <p>In Barclaycard, there was very strong income growth of 42% to just over &#xA3;2 billion, which was driven by growth in customer balances of 19% and lower funding costs. About 40% of the revenues came from our international businesses. The broad-based income growth was offset by higher impairment charges of &#xA3;915 million, resulting in profits of &#xA3;391 million, an increase of 1%, though growth was much higher if you take into account the Goldfish transaction in the first half last year.</p>
          <p>The majority of impairment was in U.K. Cards and Barclaycard U.S. In U.K. Cards balances grew by 1% and in Barclaycard U.S. balances increased by 57% in constant currency terms. We've maintained conservative approval criteria, and our approval rates were 44% in the U.K. and 39% in the U.S. Cost growth was considerably lower than income growth at 10% and the cost:income ratio improved from 45 to 35%. Total new lending in the U.K. including Barclays Capital, was &#xA3;17 billion during the first half, as we continue to support our customers.</p>
          <p>Results for GRCB Western Europe include Russia for the first time. Strong income growth from Western Europe of 38% to &#xA3;886 million was driven largely by a higher net interest income across Spain, Italy, Portugal and France. Customer deposits grew 6% from the year-end and are 45% higher than the first half last year, as a result of expanding the distribution network.</p>
          <p>Impairment charges increased to &#xA3;301 million. Two-thirds of this was in Spain in our property and construction portfolios and cards business. Spain continued to operate profitably supported by good income growth. Cost growth in Western Europe was lower than income growth, resulting in an improvement in the cost:income ratio from 66 to 63%. Profits in Western Europe of &#xA3;31 million were impacted by a &#xA3;35 million loss in Russia, resulting largely from increased ruble funding costs.</p>
          <p>On a like-for-like basis, profits were broadly stable. We expect the sale of a 50% stake in BVP, our life and pensions business to CNP Assurance to complete in the third quarter. The partnership will significantly enhance the insurance products we offer to our retail customers in Spain, Portugal, and Italy, and we expect a gain on sale of about a &#xA3;100 million.</p>
          <p>In emerging markets, income grew 29% to &#xA3;529 million. The growth was well balanced between retail and commercial, and was broadly based across geographies with an especially strong performance in Africa. Impairment of &#xA3;213 million was more than double the same period in the prior year. All of this was in the retail segment in unsecured lending and cards, particularly in India.</p>
          <p>Cost growth of 43% reflected an investment in people, infrastructure and the distribution network in the prior year. Taken together, this resulted in a loss in emerging markets of &#xA3;86 million. We continue though to believe these markets will generate good returns over the medium term, and our investment leaves us well placed to benefit from economic recovery in these markets. Our pace of ongoing investment will be determined by that recovery.</p>
          <p>At GRCB Absa which excludes Absa Capital and Absa Cards, profit in sterling was down 17% to &#xA3;248 million. Income grew 15% to &#xA3;1.2 billion, though most of this was accounted for by a strengthening in the rand against sterling</p>
          <p>The cost:income ratio improved from 60 to 55%. Impairment more than doubled from 125 to &#xA3;295 million driven mainly by higher delinquencies in retail banking, especially in mortgages. The rand sterling exchange rates were responsible for &#xA3;37 million of the increased charge. We remain cautious about the economic outlook in South Africa and have adopted a defensive approach to credit there.</p>
          <p>Moving on to investment banking and investment management, where there were profits of &#xA3;1.4 billion with income growth of 52%, reflecting first &#x2013; an excellent first half in Barclays Capital following the integration of Lehman Brothers' North American business. Profits of Barclays Capital doubled to just over &#xA3;1 billion, driven by very strong income growth which was broadly based both by product and by geography.</p>
          <p>There was a strong performance in the U.K., Europe and Asia, and a transformation in the scale of the U.S. business which delivered around 40% of total BarCap revenues. We saw especially good growth in interest rates, credit products, equities and prime services, as a result of strong client demand in these areas. Profit would have been &#xA3;2 billion excluding losses on own credit of &#xA3;900 million.</p>
          <p>Top line income grew to &#xA3;10.5 billion, which is more than the whole of 2008, taking into account credit market losses, losses on owned credit and impairment. Net income was &#xA3;4.2 billion. Losses on own credit of almost &#xA3;900 million compared to an &#xA3;850 million gain taken in the first half last year. This reflects the tightening of CDS spreads and their volatility along with the divergence from the underlying cash credit spreads used to price the notes we issue. Our credit market exposures have reduced by 30% since the year-end, through the sales and pay downs of  &#xA3;6.3 billion at or close to our marks, write-downs of &#xA3;4.7 billion, as well as foreign exchange and other movements of &#xA3;1.6 billion.</p>
          <p>We increased write-downs of our commercial real estate books by &#xA3;1.5 billion, resulting in average marks on these loans of 69% in the U.K., 77% in the U.S. and 84% in Germany. We've also increased provisions against monoline exposure by &#xA3;1.4 billion to a total of &#xA3;3.1 billion, and as a result our coverage ratios have increased from 17 to 27%.</p>
          <p>Costs at Barclays Capital grew 89% to &#xA3;3.2 billion, with the inclusion of the Lehman business as well as the targeted investment to extend our equities and M&amp;A franchise funded by income from these two businesses. Despite this investment, headcounts reduced by roughly 1,000 to 22,000 since the year-end. The cost to net income ratio improved 2 percentage points to 75%.</p>
          <p>We announced on June 16 that we'd accepted an offer from BlackRock to purchase Barclays' Global Investors business for $13.5 billion based on the BlackRock stock price at the time of the announcement. The offer comprises 37.8 million new BlackRock shares and $6.6 billion in cash. Barclays will be represented on the board and will retain an economic interest of just under 20% of the new BlackRock Global Investors which will be the world's largest asset manager. Our shareholder vote on this transaction is on Thursday and we expect it to close around the end of the year, subject to shareholder and regulatory approval.</p>
          <p>Looking now the performance of BGI, profits of &#xA3;276 million were up 4% year-on-year. The income and expenses were broadly flat, and costs included the break fee paid to CVC of &#xA3;106 million. Assets under management in dollars were up 12% at $1.7 trillion, and there was very strong net new asset inflows including iShares of $108 billion.</p>
          <p>At Barclays Wealth, profits declined to &#xA3;75 million, reflecting the sale of the closed life business in 2008 as well as the cost of integrating the private investment management business from Lehman. This has now been renamed Barclays Wealth Investors. On a like-for-like basis, income was broadly in line with 2008 at &#xA3;627 million. Total client assets of &#xA3;134 billion were in line with year-end adjusted for the impact of exchange rates.</p>
          <p>In Head Office we reported profits of &#xA3;330 million as a result of net gains of &#xA3;1.1 billion from debt exchanges completed in the first half. Net interest income declined largely as a result of additional costs of funding arising from dislocation in the money markets, and we expect these costs to reduce significantly in the second half.</p>
          <p>Moving on to look at margins, with the exception of emerging markets our asset margins continue to improve across all of our banking books. The improvement has been offset by liability margin compression. About two-thirds of this was mitigated by product hedges which contributed &#xA3;671 million. In addition hedging the impact of earnings volatility on the Group equity contributed &#xA3;527 million. Hedging was expected to mitigate about half the impact of margin compression in the second half assuming that interest rates stay at current levels.</p>
          <p>Across GRCB and Barclays Wealth, the aggregate net interest margin has increased from 2.02% to 2.14% year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Turning to the Group balance sheet, total assets have reduced by &#xA3;508 billion since the year-end. The slide sets out a breakdown, the reduction in loans and advances was largely at Barclays Capital, especially in relation to financial institutions. We believe that adjusted gross leverage gives a more useful view of the balance sheet and if we look at the balance sheet leverage excluding a derivatives gross up, assets under management, settlement balances and goodwill adjusted gross leverage improved from 28 times Tier 1 capital at the end of 2008 to 24 times at the end of the first half. It would have been 20 times on a pro forma basis taking into account the sale of BGI.</p>
          <p>You'll recall with the derivatives gross up represents receivables and payables with the same counterparties. These are subject to netting agreements and on a U.S. GAAP basis the balance sheet would be a further &#xA3;500 billion smaller. The derivatives gross up has declined by over &#xA3;400 billion since the year-end partly due to the elimination of 115,000 of certain contracts during the first half at no cost and with no capital impact. We expect to continue making further reductions throughout the year.</p>
          <p>Turning now to liquidity, as you know retail and commercial banking and Barclays Wealth have no reliance on wholesale funding. We've improved our liquidity profile this year by strengthening the balance of secured to unsecured lending, extending the maturity profile of our unsecured funding in wholesale and increasing the size of our liquidity buffer. We issued benchmark bonds without government guarantees totaling the equivalent of &#xA3;5 billion in a number of currencies including sterling, euros and U.S. dollars.</p>
          <p>Across the Group we've increased the balance of cash and liquid assets that we hold to meet any unexpected outflows from &#xA3;36 billion at the end of December to &#xA3;88 billion at the end of June. Barclays Capital has bought all its additional funding costs caused by market dislocation. It manages liquidity position to be self-funding from wholesale sources and to ensure that potential cash outflows in a stressed environment are covered. BarCap has also increased the average term of its outstanding unsecured liabilities from 11 to 15 months during the first half.</p>
          <p>We've also significantly strengthened our capital ratios since the year-end. Our core Tier 1 ratio calculated in line with the new FSA standard definitions was 7.1% at the end of June. On a pro forma basis this would have been 8.8% taking into account the sale of BGI. Our Tier 1 ratio was 10.5% and our ratio of total capital to risk rated assets was 14.5%.</p>
          <p>So in summary, we delivered profits of &#xA3;3 billion in the first half and at the same time we strengthened our capital ratios, reduced our balance sheet and leverage and improved our liquidity. We've achieved this as a result of this very strong income generation, which was more than twice the increase in credit market losses and impairment. The strength of this performance is thanks to the diversification of our business model.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much indeed. I'd now like to hand over to Robert</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris. Good afternoon. I'm going to comment on the changing economic conditions we've seen and how they affect our business through credit impairment. I'll look at our main portfolios and at market risk and then describes some trends and our outlook.</p>
          <p>During the first half of this year there's been some further weakening in GDP, unemployment and property values across many economies. U.K. GDP was expected to fall by about 2% this year and it's now generally expected to fall by about 4%. Unemployment has moved up faster than expected and will continue to rise through this year. The trends in the U.S. are similar and house prices in both economies have declined, but not as much in the U.K. as generally expected. Those economic trends affect our portfolios and they pushed our impairment higher in our expected range.</p>
          <p>Let me review our impairment for the first half. In February I shared with you our planning range for impairment this year and I explained that our range was based on three conditions: that the economy would reform at the consensus level, a steady FX rate and a constant balance sheet. On that basis we expected a loan loss rate of between 130 and 150 basis points for the year on our loan book which doesn't include available for sale assets. That range implied an impairment charge of between 3.4 and &#xA3;3.9 billion for the first half. Our actual impairment charge for the loan book was 3.9 billion.</p>
          <p>So to compare this to our planning range, with the steady FX rate from last year the impairment charge would be 3.7 billion. And when we use a constant balance sheet for loans and advances, the comparable loan loss rate for the first half was 144 basis points. This is at the higher end of our range as we indicated to you in May, even though economic conditions were weaker than consensus. The reported loan loss rate of 165 basis points occurs mostly because our loan balances have declined by &#xA3;43 billion. This reduction in loans and advances has occurred across both GRCB and IBIM with the biggest reduction in Barclays Capital.</p>
          <p>Chris has given you the impairment charge by business, and this slide shows the composition of our impairment charge over time. In the first half of this year, retail credit in the U.K. has remained at about a quarter of the overall charge. International retail impairment has increased as other economies have slowed. And U.K. and international commercial have both increased.</p>
          <p>Charges against credit market exposures are a smaller proportion. And impairment against loans and other credit in BarCap has increased. These trends were all consisting with our expectations and reflects the broad stress in credit markets.</p>
          <p>I'll now review our major credit portfolios starting with our mortgage businesses. Looking at loan to value. A clear majority of our U.K. mortgages continue to have a current value LTV below 70%, although the drop in house prices has pushed the distribution slightly higher. Only 12% of our mortgages have an LTV above 90% and our exposure to negative equity remains at a very low level compared to the industry. Our mortgage book in Spain is also very low LTV and makes up 89% of our total retail exposure in that country.</p>
          <p>In South Africa the market has used higher LTV lending although Absa has stayed in the lower range for the industry. In U.K. mortgages, three month arrears have edged higher but remain much lower than the industry. And looking at the number of repossessions, our experience is also well below the rate in the industry. We have 783,000 mortgages in the U.K. and only 225 are currently in repossession.</p>
          <p>Although overall credit card spending has been decreasing in the U.K. our credit balances have been stable. In February, I said we expected the environment to be tougher for retail credit and this has been the case. Our delinquency rate has increased, as have charge off rates although both of these remain at the lower end of the range for the industry. These trends have been driven by increasing unemployment, bankruptcies and voluntary arrangements, as we have seen across all our unsecured lending in the U.K.</p>
          <p>The trend is similar for loans where balances are stable. With rising unemployment we are seeing higher delinquencies and the charge off rate is also increasing. However we've begun to see some improvement in early delinquency for recently originated loans.</p>
          <p>The commercial bank can be examined in three categories: our core commercial areas of larger business and medium business where the loan loss rate is below 150 basis points; asset and sales finance and property-based lending are showing a loan loss rate of 150 to 300 basis points where you would expect to see that kind of impairment at this point in the cycle; and our sponsor leverage book is where we expect to see the highest impairment rate. The overall reported loan loss rate for these businesses moved up to 143 basis points in the first half from 77 basis points in the second half of last year.</p>
          <p>Looking at our loan balances, we've built most of them in the core parts of medium and larger business which are lower risk. There are much smaller balances in asset and sales finance and very small balances in our property book because we've kept tight limits there. And we have steadily reduced our limits on sponsor leveraged over the last three years. So this has been a shrinking book for us.</p>
          <p>Potential credit risk loans are a good indicator because they reference all of the assets that are in credit difficulty. They basically include the non-performing loans and our level three watch list. For these areas, PCRLs remain fairly moderate, which reflects the good asset quality of the book. For the U.K. commercial bank in the first half the five largest impairment charges total 81 million pounds, and the next five total 49 million pounds.</p>
          <p>Moving now to our U.S. card portfolio, our credit balances have come down as the result of the weaker dollar and because we've significantly reduced open market recruiting. Our delinquencies and charges off have moved higher, although by tightening our policy rules last year the number of accounts entering delinquency has started to stabilize. Both of these rates are in line with our planning expectations. They will trend higher as our portfolio matures but we expect to remain at the lower end of industry levels.</p>
          <p>For the GRCB international portfolios of Absa, Western Europe and emerging markets, I will deal with retail and commercial lending together.  In South Africa delinquency rates and impairment have risen, particularly in the home loans and vehicle finance areas. Last year, Absa was the first bank in that market to significantly tighten lending criteria. And as a result, there have been signs of improvement in the performance of new retail lending.</p>
          <p>In Spain, the unemployment rate has almost doubled from last year and is approaching 20%. Of course this has flowed through to impairment, seen mostly in the credit card and personal loan books. We have a mortgage book of about &#xA3;15 billion in Spain and arrears are even lower there than our very good performance in the U.K. On the corporate side in Spain we have a couple of large exposures, however in general we avoided the large syndicated property deals in that region.</p>
          <p>In emerging markets, our retail book has diversified across 14 countries. The increase in impairment in emerging markets has been mostly driven by retail in India and the UAE where book growth, economic slowdown and portfolio maturation have been important factors. In early 2008 we saw deterioration in those portfolios and immediately tightened credit criteria. Over the last 12 months we've cut new business volumes by 80% in those two areas. And total retail balances in emerging market were down 15% in the first half. Overall, across these regions we expect a lower rate of impairment growth in the second half.</p>
          <p>In BarCap the reductions in loans and advances has been mostly in cash collateral advanced to counterparties and portfolio exposures, which together declined by &#xA3;48 billion. The impairment charge in BarCap has increased in the first half with roughly the same share across the three components. For loans and other, about 100 million was in the private equity book. For the available for sale assets, a big part of the impairment charge arose from one name. We also note that watch list balances have been broadly steady from the end of last year, although there's been some weakening in these names.</p>
          <p>In the first half for BarCap, the five largest corporate impairment charges totaled &#xA3;398 million, and the next five totaled &#xA3;93 million. For the Group, our credit risk loans include all our retail and commercial non-performing loans as well as assets like the ABS CDOs in BarCap where we have taken impairment even though no events of default have occurred. In the first half of '09 the CRL balances increased in most sectors. However the balances for ABS CDOs have declined due to dollar weakening. They're all reported as CRLs, so the underlying balances will not grow further.</p>
          <p>The charges we have taken have moved our impairment stock 34% higher to just over &#xA3;8.8 billion, and as a result our overall coverage ratio has moved up to 44.3%. Our commercial real estate portfolio comprises property loans held in the trading book at fair value together with a small book of CMBS securities. The portfolio has been under pressure from falling commercial property prices during a period of low market activity and from the impact of the recession on tenants. Our exposure has decreased &#xA3;2.9 billion during the first half, which includes write-downs of just over &#xA3;1.4 billion mostly on the U.S. assets as well as disposals and the effects of currency moves. The valuations these assets properly reflect market conditions and we take comfort from the LTVs and the geographic spread in the portfolio, although additional write-downs are likely in the second half as difficult market conditions persist.</p>
          <p>For the monolines I'm showing our net exposures in U.S. dollars because the assets are mostly in that currency, and that exposure was broadly unchanged in the first half of the year partly through smaller moves in asset prices. In the first half we increased credit provisions further, reflecting weaker monoline credit. The important points here are that the underlying assets were originally AAA rated and although they've been downgraded, they're all still performing. Our portfolio is focused on better quality assets, particularly the CLOs which make up about two-thirds of our book. These CLOs continued to perform and because they have strong structural support 94% of them remain AAA or AA.</p>
          <p>U.S. RMBS assets are 9% of our exposure and the monolines guaranteeing them are now sub-investment grade. There has been restructuring and commutation with the monolines. Taking account of those factors we have increased our credit provisions to a total of $4.5 billion, and as Chris has mentioned, this increased our coverage rate to 27%.</p>
          <p>Moving to market risk, it's helpful to understand trends in the external environment. If we held a hypothetical steady FTSE position through the first half, that steady position would have shown increase in DVaR as market volatility increased from the start of the year. And if we held a hypothetical steady currency position in dollars against sterling, the DVaR would also have increased as market volatility moved higher during the first quarter. So these two steady positions would have led to higher DVaR over time, even though the positions would not have changed in any way.</p>
          <p>BarCap's actual DVaR increased during the first quarter as we positioned more risk and as DVaR trended higher because of volatility moves in the external market. After reaching a peak toward the end of the first quarter, we have reduced some trading positions and BarCap DVaR has moved lower through the second quarter.</p>
          <p>It's also important to understand the source of trading revenue and for that we look at the distribution of daily trading profit or loss from market making and trading activities. This shows there we just over 30 trading days at BarCap where profitability was between 0 and &#xA3;30 million in the first half. The distribution of trading P&amp;L shows that most trading days were profitable and that there were few days of trading losses.</p>
          <p>Now when we adjust that trading P&amp;L by adding fees and commissions, we get total income, and this distribution is even further to the right. The clear majority of profitable trading days on the right-hand side is the result of a customer driven trading and risk management business. The BarCap business is not focused on proprietary trading.</p>
          <p>Let me now close with some comments on trends and our outlook. Most Western economies remain in recession. The U.S. was earlier to slow down and it will probably be earlier to recover, although unemployment will still continue to rise. We know that unemployment will lag recovery and that retail impairment will lag unemployment. There are still high levels of household debt and we expect retail impairment in most markets to continue to rise through this year and into next year.</p>
          <p>For Barclays, we have positioned many our retail portfolios defensively over a number of years and for our main books such as mortgages in the U.K. and cards in the U.K. and the U.S. Our impairment levels continue to run at the low end of the industry. And in these larger portfolios there are signs that recent vintage lending is performing better and that early delinquency rates and roll rates into later delinquency will soon start to stabilize.</p>
          <p>For wholesale credit, many of the same factors are relevant. Many companies are being run to preserve cash and they've been reducing inventories, cutting the expenses and delaying spending. Corporate downgrades, restructuring and defaults have increased and where companies are closing, the residual value of remaining collateral is much lower. That causes a drop in recovery rates, which will remain an important driver of commercial impairment going forward.</p>
          <p>When we enter recovery as companies try to rebuild and restock, there will be further stress on corporate cash flow. We therefore expect an increase in late cycle defaults and individual large company default has become a greater risk.</p>
          <p>Finally let me give you some comments on our impairment outlook for the second half of the year. In February we shared with you our planning range for this year because we expected a large step change in the credit environment from '08 to '09 and we wanted to help explain that large change. When we look ahead now we expect more of a continuing trend rather than another large step change. We note that the analyst forecasts for full year impairment are across this range, and the center part of this range from 9 to &#xA3;9.6 billion seems reasonable at this point.  Of course we should keep in mind that currency moves and economic developments could affect our retail and wholesale trends.</p>
          <p>Stepping back, when I look at the bigger picture compared to six months ago the economy is weaker than expected and there is still volatility and uncertainty. However, I believe that while our industry continues to face a lot of challenges the range of possible outcomes in better defined today. We plan to update you on our trends when we provide the next the interim management statement.</p>
          <p>Thank you and I'll hand over to John now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Robert. Good afternoon. When we presented to you at the time of our full year results in February, I said that our objectives for 2009 would be staying close to customer and clients, managing our risk and maintaining strategic momentum. Many of my remarks today will be aimed at those areas. So I'll talk about income because that reflects our relationships with customers, I'll talk about capital because that reflects risk and I'll talk about the shape of the Barclays Group because that's the first expression of strategy.</p>
          <p>But before going there I want to review our performance this year against the scorecard that I gave you in February. I said then that we were interested in the quantity of RWAs and the returns they generate and the size of our balance sheet and the scale of leverage, in growing customer liabilities in line with growth in customer assets, in the relationship between income and cost and lastly in maintaining capital ratios, well in excess of the FSA minimum levels.</p>
          <p>So I'm going to look first at how we've done on these. I'll talk about our thoughts on return on equity versus cost of equity later in my remarks. On RWAs our regulatory balance sheet has fallen by 6% since the year-end. Annualized returns on assets are broadly flat. We've reduced the gross balance sheet materially and as a result adjusted leverage, as you've been hearing from Chris, is down quite significantly since the end of 2008 and very significantly against the end of 2007.</p>
          <p>We've improved the loan to deposit ratio by 9 percentage points to 129%. If I look at the relationship between income and cost, our cost:income ratio has improved by 3 percentage points, and the positive jaws between income growth and cost growth was 7 percentage points.</p>
          <p>Our objective of managing capital ratios well ahead of regulatory minimum is being achieved. We started 2009 with a Core Tier 1 ratio of 5.6%, and that was 7.1% at the end of June or 8.8% if adjusted for the sale of BGI.</p>
          <p>Turning then to my key themes of plans, risk and strategy, at the heart of Barclays is a broadly based set of businesses. The strength and breadth of our relationships with customers and clients is clearly observable in our income performance in the first half. Income grew 14% in GRCB and 52% in IBIM. Income diversification has offset the write-down and impairment impact of the banking crisis and of the economic crisis.</p>
          <p>Protecting our ability to serve customers and clients in chosen markets around the world, and with it the preservation and strengthening of a broadly based income platform lay at the heart of our decision about recapitilization in October of last year. Our income performance during this crisis gives me confidence.</p>
          <p>The first half income story at Barclays Capital is shown on this next slide. As you can see there's a lot of growth with material amounts of income across the waterfront. The new areas of notable growth and contribution amplified of course by Lehman are equities, investment banking, commodities, currencies and prime services.</p>
          <p>The income growth in GRCB both in 2009 and since the crisis began in the summer of 2007 has been dominated by its international businesses where income growth was 33% in the first half. GRCB's international businesses now account for about 40% of its income. It's the strength of that income performance over the last three years that's enabled us to invest heavily in the build out of distribution channels. We now have some 3,000 sales outfits and branches outside the United Kingdom.</p>
          <p>There is a cost of course, cost from the investment in branches and people and cost from the impairment growth attributable to maturing asset books. We must strengthen the profit performance and returns of our Western European and Emerging Markets businesses, although we should recognize that the path that we've taken here over the last three years have put the development costs into the P&amp;L account rather than into the balance sheet via acquisition.</p>
          <p>As usual we've operated on a pay as you go basis. The new Western European and Emerging Markets businesses have been profitable over the period 2006 through 2009, notwithstanding the rate of investment and notwithstanding also the impact of harsher economic on their profit performance.</p>
          <p>With the downturn in the global economy we have moderated quite significantly this year our rate of investment in people, distribution channels and assets in these businesses. But we're clear that the trends which led us to make these investments will continue. They will grow faster than our businesses in developed markets due to the increasing use of financial services by consumers and businesses in them and to the steady homogenization of customer demand there, which will benefit well known banking brands.</p>
          <p>The further development of GRCB's international business is an important part of our diversification strategy. So we've incurred these investment costs with our eyes open, understanding the surge in profits that will follow from the normalization of impairment in due course, given the scale of our international businesses which now serve about 30 million customers.</p>
          <p>Turning now to risk. We see risk and capital as two sides of the same coin. It's been very important to strengthen our capital ratios during this half, and I have already explained how they've grown. Of course profit generation is intrinsic to a bank's ability to protect and grow its capital ratios. Barclays has continued to generate profits in every reporting period since this crisis began. Since that time two years ago, we have generated total profits of &#xA3;12 billion.</p>
          <p>As we look forward we have an eye on developments in the area of regulation. And even though none of us yet has the detail we know that one consequence of this crisis is a requirement for more capital and less leverage. But remember that Barclays began the process of increasing capital and reducing leverage well over a year ago. Our Core Tier 1 ratio has increased by over 4 percentage points on a pro forma basis since the end of 2007. And as I have explained our leverage has fallen significantly since then. These actions will help us manage future regulatory impacts.</p>
          <p>In the area of funding we've been steadily building liquidity in anticipation of the introduction of the FSA's new rules. And in the context of future levels of market risk capital we make the assumption that the regulatory decisions will, as they should recognize a distinction between capital required support proprietary trading which is not our focus and capital required to support the risk management and funding needs of our government and corporate clients, which very much is.</p>
          <p>We've been developing the mix of earnings in Barclays Capital to take account of the changing regulatory environment. The regulatory balance sheet supporting the business of Barclays Capital was lower end June versus end December 2008 notwithstanding the very large growth in income and profit.  That's because of the prominence of low capital intensive client driven flow business which has been boosted both by the Lehman acquisition and by the market share gains created by the upheaval in the global investment banking sector.</p>
          <p>First half top line income in Barclays Capital significantly exceeded 2008 full year income. And notwithstanding the unusually buoyant conditions that we saw in the first quarter of this year, top line income in the second quarter at Barclays Capital exceeded that of the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Let me make one further point here before I move on to talk about strategy. Some commentators have a particular view about the nature of investment banking. I'm showing on this next slide the names of some of the clients on whose behalf we've been active recently. This is all the matter of public record. This work by Barclays Capital supports real economy activity, helping plants with their financing and risk management needs and driving as a result investment jobs and economic growth.</p>
          <p>I'm going to talk now about my third theme which is maintaining strategic momentum. It's an important subject not least because we're very conscious of the role that banks must play in economic stabilization and regeneration. Our strategy as you know is to increase the growth potential of Barclays by diversifying our businesses. Notwithstanding the uncertainty of the economic outlook and the attendant uncertainty about the development of regulation, we have a clear view about the future direction of the Barclays Group.</p>
          <p>In GRCB our goal is that the profit contribution of our international activities will in time equal that of our U.K. businesses. We're seeking to ensure that profits in our African businesses including Absa will continue grow through time. We have ample opportunity to develop our Western European retail and commercial banking businesses. A good example of that would be via our new joint venture in life and pensions with CNP who chose Barclays as one of its preferred distribution partners across Spain, Portugal and Italy.</p>
          <p>And in due course we'll be seeking grow the Asian businesses of GRCB which are still underweight. That objective underpins the investments that we've been making in India, Pakistan and Indonesia over the last two years. These are high growth economies.</p>
          <p>In IBIM we've been developing our businesses in the areas where we have been geographically underrepresented over the years, in particular Asia and the United States. Our wish to increase exposure in the United States, which accounts for some 40% of the income in the global financial services industry today, is benefiting significantly from Lehman's acquisition. We also intend to create global platforms out of the principally national platforms in equities and M&amp;A that we acquired in Lehman.</p>
          <p>In the first half of 2009 over 50% of the Group's income was generated outside the United Kingdom and it's a strategic priority for us to grow that percentage in the future. If I then look at the shape of the Group by business line, the Lehman acquisition, the sale of Barclays Global Investors and the current impact on GRCB's profits made by the compression of liability margins and rising impairment will skew the relative contribution of investment banking for awhile. But as we've said before our intention is that over time and in circumstances where Barclays Capital continues to grow about two-thirds of the Group's profits will come from GRCB and Barclays Wealth.</p>
          <p>We believe that the investment management industry will continue to grow. Through our equity holding in BlackRock Global Investors we will maintain exposure to that growth but in an independent vehicle, which we see as the advantage model of the future and structured in a way that avoids related party issues.</p>
          <p>I want to finish by talking about dividends and goals and then a word about the outlook. At this year's AGM the chairman announced our intention to resume dividend payments before the end of 2009. So going forward we intend to make four payments of cash dividends each year. For the second half of 2009, we intend to make an interim payment in December and a final payment in March of next year. But we want to maintain strong capital ratios. We therefore expect that the proportion of after-tax profit distributed through dividends will be significantly lower for the foreseeable future than the 50% payout level which we've operated in recent years.</p>
          <p>We promised that we would update you today on the subject on goals. We have an output goal relating to total shareholder return and an input goal relating to economic profit. Our output goal remains unchanged. It's to produce top quartile total shareholder returns over time. On a TSR basis Barclays was the best performing share in the first six months of this year against our domestic and international peer group which is important given what a tough time our shareholders have had over the last two years.</p>
          <p>Our economic profit goal is unlikely to be met principally because of the increase in required regulatory capital. And we believe that in the future total shareholder return will be sensitive to items which are additional to economic profit. These include the items on the scorecard I referred to earlier.</p>
          <p>Within that list, our principal input goal going forward will be that our return on equity would exceed our cost of equity. In the short term, that requires ensuring the returns are at least equal to the cost of equity which is currently 12.5%. So this is the way in which we will judge our performance over the period between now and the end of 2010. In the medium term a return at the rate only of the cost of equity is inadequate and we will seek to ensure that the former exceeds the latter through time.</p>
          <p>A few words on the outlook for regulation. Given the experiences of the world over the last two years, the managing of systemic risk looms large in the minds of governments and regulators today. I willingly acknowledge that there were excesses in risk, leverage and reward in the banking sector. This industry got many things wrong and there is much to be sorry about. So there must be change and there will be change. But that change should not provoke the throttling of the important aspects of the market economy. That's because a properly governed market economy encourages thrift, innovation, creativity and enterprise and the world needs those things as it recovers.</p>
          <p>Two final points. First, domestic lending. New lending by Barclays to U.K. households and  businesses in the first half totaled some &#xA3;17 billion and all within acceptable risk parameters. That 17 billion is to be compared with the &#xA3;11 billion for full year 2009 that we announced in April. If I look for example at lending activity by Barclays Commercial Bank to U.K. businesses, our credit approval rates this year are averaging about 90% again within the right risk parameters. We are committed to lending to creditworthy borrowers. That's our job, and this is a good time for banks to lend and Barclays is open for business.</p>
          <p>Secondly current trading and our ambitions for the rest of 2009. The trends that lie behind our operating performance in the first half of this year were again observable in July. And whilst we are realistic about how difficult the environment is and will remain, we're committed to delivering by virtue of our continued emphasis on serving the needs of customers and clients, another year of solid profitability.</p>
          <p>Despite the tumultuous events of this crisis which believe me have been humbling for all of us here, we've been able to remain independent and profitable. We've strengthened our balance sheet and managed our risks tightly and we stay close to customers and clients. We're a British company but with an increasingly international footprint and earnings base. I think our strategy has helped us weather the crisis. We want our shareholders, our customers and our employees to continue to benefit from it.</p>
          <p>Thank you then very much for listening to what we have to say. We know that this is a busy day for you as the Chairman said, and our intention is to finish this meeting by about 2:30. So we're happy now to take your questions and if you could in the usual way just identify your name and the organization for whom you work. Let's get going, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So question here, Peter, microphone coming. In the &#x2013; yeah, there we are, hand up, fourth row. Coming to you, and I'll go to JP afterwards.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have been struggling to understand the movement of the Group risk weighted assets, particularly BarCap. I mean I think it is creditable that risk rated assets have gone down. But the DVaR number for BarCap has sort of doubled over where it was a year ago. And I think the market risk weighted assets have been about the same. I just wonder if you could provide some light on why the WRA movements have been so favorable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter we'll certainly try. I'll ask Chris to comment and if Bob wants to add, so be it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the trends are pretty much all in BarCap as you say. There's about a &#xA3;20 billion FX impact. And then the balance is by looking at particularly credit market risk weighted assets and the credit element of risk weighted assets, and reducing those. Those are the main drivers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob, anything you want to add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I suppose in general I would say that I think job one is allocation of risk and allocation of capital. And I think some of the areas that we found to be able to tighten up have been around some of the collateral arrangements that we've had. And I think as Chris said the markets were favorable for that as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Did you have another, Peter or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it possible to gauge the impact of Lehman's on the BarCap numbers for WRAs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's quite difficult, Peter just because the businesses have become fungible now. I mean what we have said to the extent that this is helpful to you is it we &#x2013; about 40% of the income in Barclays Capital is now coming from the United States. A lot of that of course is Lehman originating. And Bob you had a view earlier about what you think approximately the PBT contribution would be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The PBT and revenue contribution is about a third. And it's going to be harder and harder, so remember that number. It's going to be harder and harder going forward as it's so well integrated.</p>
          <p>I think the other thing I would say is that everything else being equal the Lehman acquisition has been positive to capital and risk ratios in the sense that it was giving a big, deep scale client base in the U.S. to businesses that already existed, so more distribution. And the businesses that really came on big time through that of cash equities, of advisory and of secondary credit trading are really flow business, they're not balance sheet businesses.</p>
          <p>So I would say, although it's very hard to put numbers on it, I apologize, we actually can't. The Lehman acquisition was a positive acquisition in the sense of all those ratios.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And when we did the original planning for it, we had a view of the marginal RWA increase of about 10 billion. And I think we've operated well below that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you mind passing the mic behind you to JP?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>After the &#x2013; sorry, losing my voice a bit here. It's JP from UBS. Two questions if I can. One's on Barclays Capital and one's on also pool of GRCB. I'll do Barclay's Capital first.</p>
          <p>Bob, I just wonder if you can help us a bit, just not necessary with these numbers, but just thinking about BarCap and costs that related to revenues? Because they clearly if you just look at costs on there for BarCap in the first half versus total revenues it's about 30%. BarCap historically was around 60. If you look at on the net to revenue numbers, about 50. And then it was obviously a very unusual first half period in terms of revenues and the other &#x2013; a very strong January as well. But it appears to be that you're growing sort of the marginally higher cost income areas but less capital intensive, but it feels like at the moment your cost number looks like artificially lower against what we might expect it to be as a normal run rate.</p>
          <p>So I just wonder if you could maybe just as talk around what you're seeing in terms of costs and revenues? And how we should think about it? Not necessarily for the rest of the year, but just how it plays out from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean I think it's early days for that. But I think JP to your point, so what was the pleasant surprise there and what was the unpleasant surprise?</p>
          <p>I suppose the pleasant surprise was clearly top line revenues. I think, to John's point, that's the Lehman acquisition, that is a better competitiveness and strategic positioning, and frankly it's outstanding execution by the team.</p>
          <p>And I think, going forward, I'd like to think those are sustainable. Actually I shouldn't say it that way, I do believe they're sustainable. You certainly want to haircut the second half, as I've always said, for the seasonal factors. When we plan, assuming everything else is equal, then we plan the second half as like five months instead of six because of the summer impact. And I think December will have a bigger impact since all banks now report in December. But basically it's sustainable with that haircut in it.</p>
          <p>And I think one of the things that went well was reducing the legacy assets by a third. &#xA3;12 billion fewer in legacy assets, about half of that by sales in the market. And so the optimist would say that we believe that's going to be a smaller impact going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Chris is just going to add on on costs, and then we'll come to your GRCB question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think my comment on costs is you've seen the cost:income ratio come down marginally. Within that here's a lot of moving pieces. There is the finalization of the integration of the Lehman business. There's also the build out of the M&amp;A and equities franchise outside of the U.K., which is coming out of that income flow.</p>
          <p>So I think that sort of rate of 75% is a reasonable go forward rate for cost:income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And your second question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm just trying to pull together what you're really leading to in GRCB. Because I mean you're very clear John, you indicated that you'd like GRCB outside the U.K. to pulled equal with the U.K. in time. But obviously no time reference on that. Coupled with clearly you're pulling back, in the short term, it appears from Robert's comments and the risk-asset numbers coming down, that you are pulling back there quite materially in the short term.</p>
          <p>I'm just wondering, given that you made the comment that what in advance of what you've been doing is building out organically, so you don't incur the goodwill charge in terms of the balance sheet, which is probably less relevant in the current environment. So do you really think you can achieve what you want to in terms of ambitions without a material step forward in terms of inorganic activity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It does appear very hard to make the math work on certainly in both of our lifetimes I imagine at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>JP I'll make a couple of comments. And I'll ask Frits to add what I say. And I think that the starting point is this, that you can see, mostly through organic growth, how quickly we have been able, since we created GRCB, to grow the business base. So we've gone from about 34 million customers in the world in summer 2006 to about 49, 50 million today. I mean that is rapid growth and most of that has come through the organic line.</p>
          <p>So I think we've demonstrated to ourselves, with income of course following that build out, we've demonstrated to ourselves that we can move fast and with appropriate aggression in the organic environment.</p>
          <p>Would we ever rule out an acquisition? We never rule out acquisition. I mean, you and I have had that conversation many times before. But are we reliant on it? I mean, my answer is no. And I made the remark in my presentation that you can imagine a time &#x2013; I can certainly imagine a time and I'm excited about it &#x2013; when the fog lifts in terms of economic slow down, when we are suffering less impairment, and where we have then a very broadly based business in GRCB, capable of increasing significantly revenue per customer.</p>
          <p>I mean that's what we have to play for. Even if we're developing what we have at the moment, without growing it further, there is a lot of juice in that particular pot.</p>
          <p>Frits, do you want to add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just one comment. I think that if you look at the valuation of assets, they have come down dramatically. And so if you build a branch, it used to be a better decision a couple of years ago. That's why we built 1,400 over the last couple of years. But if you look at the price of a branch, so let me give you one example. Take Italy, the price of branches have dropped from about &#x20AC;9 million per branch to 2.5, 2.2. That says it all, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Over on the left-hand side, here comes the microphone. Ian good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, thanks. Two questions please, the first one on BarCap. For 10.5 billion clean revenues, could you give us some quantification of how much of that would come from own-account  revenues? I know it's not a concept that you've given numbers on historically, but the DVaR disclosure suggests that there was some degree of positioning going on in the business including the changed shape post-Lehman's and the improved disclosure of some of your competitors. I was hoping you might be able to give some guidance there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean as a general comment, it's probably not the specificity you want, but we really like to put the risk into the businesses. So it's very difficult to strip out what the contribution of risk versus client flow is.</p>
          <p>I think what I would point you to is that in the second quarter the revenues were just ahead of the first quarter, and there was a significant drop off in DVaR. So I think if there's one thing I would point you to in terms of what we've been talking about in terms of client flows, it is the strength of the second quarter, where most of the industry would say that conditions weren't as good and our DVaR was significantly lower in the second quarter versus the first quarter, as you saw in Robert's chart, and the revenues were up.</p>
          <p>The second thing I would say, which I think is important, is the number of clients who do more than &#xA3;1 million a year in business with Barclays Capital increased 67%, which is an awfully big increase. And it's been increasing at about 34% each year since 2004. So it was double what was already a pretty significant rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you had a second question did you. Then I'm coming to the back, promise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bob. I was kind of hoping I might get a slightly clearer answer to the first one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well Chris or Robert, if you'd like to take a shot?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The work we did for the analysis &#x2013; the seminar we did at BarCap showed, across the industry, 75 to 80% of revenues were client driven rather than proprietary trading. That was the sort off best number we could get.</p>
          <p>It's our feeling, and it is really a feeling, because you intermingle businesses, that we have a slightly higher level of customer flow business than that 75 to 80%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The second question was on GRCB. You pointed out correctly that there's an expectation of higher impairments as a development cost, given the rapid rate of franchise expansion over the last two or three years. Given the slowdown in investment which you've signaled from here, does that suggest that it's quite difficult to grow the top line without taking on credit risk? Because I would have hoped to have seen perhaps better signs of tentative sources of revenues drivers simply rather than capital and credit risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ian , again let me just make a comment, and then I'll ask Frits to add. The &#x2013; it would be true of a lot of the customers that we have brought to Barclays over the course of last years in the international businesses you're referring to, that we have at the moment quite a limited relationship with them. And that's where the opportunity like &#x2013; very often actually, that is an asset-based rather than liability-based relationship. Big, big opportunity there is how we would see it.</p>
          <p>So we're not reliant just on development through the asset side of the balance sheet. Indeed, we're very attracted by development through the liability side of the balance sheet with those very customers. Frits?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you John. Obviously when your expense are not working the way we have done, we're now using that to acquire very specifically premiere customers. So we have had phenomenal growth in our premiere liability base.</p>
          <p>The second thing is that, because we have so many branches outside to United Kingdom, and not only in the United Kingdom, our commercial bank customers are coming to us, because we can help them outside of the United Kingdom. And you should not underestimate the competitive advantage which we have because of that &#x2013; because many companies here in the U.K. export. It can be the local business, can be medium business, can be a larger business. And that trend will continue, I believe, and we're benefiting from that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question at the back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Is this on yet? Thank you. It's Jon Kirk at Redburn. Can I ask you to expand a little bit on the balance sheet restructuring, because there's certainly been a lot of progress I think in the first half, but I'm interested in how much further you think you have to go from the point of view of leverage, derivative book contraction, and also the liquidity position of the bank?</p>
          <p>And on that latter point, could you give us some idea of what the carry cost is of that liquidity pool and whether you think that liquidity pool needs to get bigger from here, or even shrink?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay, fine. We'll ask Chris to comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll do the balance sheet, start off with that. The &#x2013; as you know, the vast majority of the reduction in balance sheet came from the reduction in the derivatives gross up. That is the result of two things; some things that are within our control, namely the number of open contracts we have; and the pieces that are outside of our control that are less controllable, which is to do with the changes in FX rates, changes in credit spreads, and changes in interest rates. When we look at the impact of the 115,000, that was material, but it was not anything like the 400 billion that comes down from those exchange rates.</p>
          <p>I would say that what we've seen at the 30th of June in relation to that piece is closer to the sort of mean than where we were at the end of the year. So therefore I would expect, from on a movement in rates perspective, not to see a massive amount more. What we will see is continuation of the work to cut down the number of open contracts, both bilaterally and with exchanges. And that's where I'll see &#x2013; I think you'll see the difference.</p>
          <p>Of course, in terms of the second part of your question, the gross ups don't really impact the leverage number, because we back them out, so they flow on both sides. But we said we wanted to work the leverage down, and we have to 22 times or 20 times on a pro forma basis. Directionally, we still want to drive it down further, but clearly we've made quite significant improvements, and therefore, I think the rate has &#x2013; the rate of improvement will slow down.</p>
          <p>In terms of liquidity, it's a difficult question because the regulators are still finalizing their rules. But we believe that that sort of &#xA3;88 billion is a reasonable proportion, and quite a significant proportion of anything we'd need to have by &#x2013; in to the regulators.</p>
          <p>The costs &#x2013; about 0.5% I think on it, that sort of number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think the important point is, just to add to what Chris said, I mean the costs are being borne by the businesses, yeah. I mean, they're in the first half numbers, because we've made quite a significant step change as you can see from the figures that Chris has referred to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Is this still on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes, please go on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it still on? Yeah, it is. Sorry, just a very quick one for Bob. Could you <mark type="inaudible" /> spreads are evolving within your businesses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's so many different ways to go after that. Clearly, the credit spreads are much tighter from their wides. I think that's part of what you're referring to. You &#x2013; frankly you see it in our and other banks' own credit as spreads tighten.</p>
          <p>I think the other part you might be referring to is the bid offer spreads, and I think they differ by business. But I think the position we're in, in terms of our position with clients and position of market share, we haven't seen a significant change in that over the first half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was a question &#x2013; yes, here. Alastair, here it comes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. It's Alastair Ryan at UBS. I think I'm just being thick on the BarCap costs thing. So you've 10.5 billion of revenues, and three and change of expenses in the half year, which compares with Bob's sort of historical guidance of 65% edge cost income and what Chris just mentioned of a &#x2013; I think I've missed, which is now that you're looking at costs relative to income after impairment charges.</p>
          <p>So the sort of absolute cost number in the first half is very low relative to what you're pointing us to as a run rate of revenue. So just whether sort of non-compensable income has been generated in the period? And how quickly that normalizes?</p>
          <p>Secondly, on the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we just try and take that question first of all, Alastair. Chris?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the pieces in there is &#x2013; the 10.4 is the clean income. From that, you have to deduct own credit and credit market exposures will go through &#x2013; gets it out to about 6.08. From there you deduct the impairment of 1.874. And it's that number over 3.176, the cost line that get to me that sort of 75% line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. But just to &#x2013; so if you did another 10 in the second half, which I know you're not making that forecast, typically your cost number would be a considerably larger number, because you're effectively saying that the credit market write-downs, being -although they're a legacy issue &#x2013; are stripped out of the compensable revenue base when you're considering accruing through your staff.</p>
          <p>Is that a basically &#x2013; just because the 3 billion cost number is only 30% of &#x2013; is less than 30% of the underlying revenue number you've given us, versus a much higher industry run rate and your own guidance. So I just &#x2013; just so I haven't missed something there, you basically &#x2013; the credit market write-downs effectively come out of the comp base?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the purposes of the calculation we've done, yes. These &#x2013; within those numbers are accruals for compensation, as you'd expect. But that's very different from where you end up making the payments. But that's how the maths work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it would also be true to say, wouldn't it, Bob, that the cost:income ratio of the business has changed a bit as a result of the Lehman's transaction. It's a higher cost:income ratio model as a result of the head count that we put in, particularly into the mergers and acquisitions business. I mean you're familiar with that, as we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll also say we always strike cost:income after taking provisions or any write-downs. And I think you're right, they were probably higher in the first half than they're going to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And then just to clear up on Chris's last point. I think similar companies &#x2013; I certainly wouldn't be in a position to mention &#x2013; have got a much higher sort of cost of their liquidity base than 50 basis points. Given the steepness of the curve, 50 bps doesn't feel like a lot. So could you just define that liquidity for us, and how you think about the cost of running it? I mean 88 certainly feels like a comfortable number to be running, but the cost of that doesn't feel as high as other people are experiencing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that is the difference between the sort of yield we're making on that asset pool and what we would think we would be able to make elsewhere. That's how we get that number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Any &#x2013; are there any further questions? Yes, at the back, Michael it's just coming to you now. And then I'll come to Robert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you sir. Michael Helsby from Morgan Stanley. Just two questions.</p>
          <p>Firstly, in the center, in the corporate center, there was quite a big swing on the net interest income line. I think you put it down to money market dislocation. I just want to &#x2013; is that a one-off swing that'll just bounce back in the second half? Or is that something a bit more a sustainable? And -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Can we take that one first of all, Michael? Chris made a comment about that in his presentation. We'll just go....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the numbers you see there for the net interest income is a loss of about &#xA3;500 million. From that you've got to deduct a reclassification, which flows though.</p>
          <p>So that total sort of cost I had in my mind is about &#xA3;380 million. Of that, about 250 relates to LIBOR base rate mismatches and a mismatch between three month and overnight Euribor. Those numbers, which total about 250, have narrowed considerably, and we'd expect a much smaller level of that cost coming through in the second half.</p>
          <p>The balance is just more generally the cost of funding increase that we've taken at the center. That I feel will be reduced, but will still be quite significant. That's about120, &#xA3;130 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just secondly, Bob, thanks very much for giving us a steer on the Lehman revenue. But there's clearly a lot going on in your business. You're taking market share. There's sort of client activity levels have been high. And also the wider spreads that you've talked about.</p>
          <p>I was wondering if you could give us some kind of indication about what type of contribution the bigger revenue from volumes and spreads have had in terms of the incremental revenue pool that you've generated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good luck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's very, very hard. I think John touched on it earlier when he mentioned two big contributions to the dramatic change in revenue in BarCap.</p>
          <p>First and foremost, it's the transformation of the Lehman's business. And I think you've got to step back and put it in the context that rarely have we ever seen two firms that were operating at the very, very top of their game combined with so little overlap. So, you had Lehman, just the U.S. piece, probably the most valuable &#x2013; it was the highest quality piece, most valuable. But brought us businesses that we weren't in in cash equities and advisory. But most importantly, if you did the surveys, probably the premiere client franchise in the U.S.</p>
          <p>And on the BarCap side, we're sub-scale in the U.S., where Lehman was sub-scale in Europe. And BarCap has arguably the premiere client franchise across the U.K. and Europe, if you look the Greenwich Survey or the Orion Survey. And it had incredible strengths in commodities and FICC. I mean, if you look at our FICC numbers, fixed income currencies and commodities, we think we're second only to Goldman Sachs, and quite close.</p>
          <p>So you've combined these two businesses where there was very little overlap, we didn't need to take on the assets, the integration was very quick. And so it truly was &#x2013; I know it's a big word, but it was transformational.</p>
          <p>The second thing that John talked about is the dislocation in the market. And I've talked about this at the Investor Day. But for the first time &#x2013; fixed income currencies and commodities are a great example. Even in the first quarter, over 50% of the revenues in fixed income currencies and commodities went to five firms.</p>
          <p>So there's been a consolidation and a better positioning. And I went through the number of clients doing over &#xA3;1 million. We've seen a huge increase in the number of clients who are doing over &#xA3;10 million. So it really is the client franchise, not the bid/offer spreads. We haven't had a big widening in FX or any of those businesses, so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert, there we are. And then come to you straight afterwards. Sorry to keep you waiting. Robert, on the end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert Law, Nomura. Can I have two questions please, one brief one?</p>
          <p>Could you quantify how much your funding is now from what you might call government sources? I'm aggregating it all up. Central Bank funding, the SLS, and the special guarantee scheme. And how that's moved over the first six months of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not allowed to disclose...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's why I'm asking to give the total so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. But the &#x2013; explicit there is some liquidity support in terms of the SLS that we used at the behest of the government. And there is some liquidity usage of some of the Central Bank facilities, particularly in the U.S. Small, single billions of pounds.</p>
          <p>There is also the government guarantee scheme that we did use, and we raised about just over &#xA3;22 billion on that scheme pre-April of this year. Since April, we've not used it at all. We've used the unguaranteed funding that we've been able to raise ourselves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And secondly, could I ask you to expand a bit more on the margin indications you've given in GRCP? You've talked about the hedge I think limiting half of the expected liability decline. Could you give us some idea of what either of those numbers is? And the overall effect on the margin, I'm looking for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine. I'll ask Frits to comment and Chris may want to add.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I did expect the question. So in the U.K. RB, our spreads went from 1.4 to 1.43 on the asset side. In the commercial bank, it went from 1.5 to 1.62, and the spread on liabilities dropped from 1.89 to 1.26. It's in the package, actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the hedge?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the hedge drops to 50% in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I don't have the margins, but I have it in absolute numbers. The compression in the commercial bank and the U.K. retail bank is about &#xA3;460 million. There are some other pieces, but those are the big pieces.</p>
          <p>The hedge &#x2013; the product hedge, which is the one that's driving most of the impact, had a gain of 670 million. So the gross compression was about &#xA3;1.13 billion.</p>
          <p>So the hedge worked to about 60%. It started nearer two-thirds, but as interest rates came down and more deposits were put into the sort of close to zero basis, our hedging ratio fell to about 60%. That's the number we think will be about 50% going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what's the kind of duration on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it was three years at the beginning of the year, so average is about 2.5 then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert, could you pass the mic forward? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul Lee from Hermes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just return to the Barclays Capital costs issue, and just approach it from a different direction? Which is just can you make some comments on your progress in ensuring the integration of risk management measurements and cost of capital into the remuneration of all the relevant staff there?</p>
          <p>And also talk about &#x2013; a little about the alignment of time scales for performance measurement for them, with appropriate time scales for measuring performance for clients and for shareholders? I'm asking not least in the light of reports that you're out in the market offering guaranteed bonuses at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, facts are always helpful. There are stories about guaranteed bonuses, and there's stories apparently I've heard today about bonuses that we haven't said anything about. So what are the facts?</p>
          <p>The hiring this year was very specific. John and I talked about it at the beginning of the year, which is this is a year about returns, not growth. But we had one big opportunity that we're pursuing, and that's to roll out the equity and advisory business that we acquired with Lehman in the U.S. throughout the U.K., Europe, and Asia. And we've hired 2,000 people so far this year to accomplish that.</p>
          <p>But I'd point out the facts are important. Our head count's down over 1,000. So we found ways to reduce staff by over 3,000 people in order to fund that initiative. And I think that's the culture that we have, is that we're constantly looking for areas to cut and become more efficient.</p>
          <p>So head count's actually down just over 1,000, but we have hired 2,000 people for that initiative. Less than 10% of those 2,000 people had any guarantee at all. And that's not the spin that you'll read in the paper. And one of the things that makes me so proud of the team is that we got out knowing we had this initiative and knowing we had the support of John and the executive committee and the board and began in January. And so the 2,000 people and the quality of those, we could not hire that many people at that quality in this market because now it's hotted up a little bit. So we feel terrific about the fact that we got out and we executed quickly and people are joining Barclays Capital because of the opportunity. And it is frustrating to get some of that spin in the paper. Less than 10% of the people that we've hired this year had any guarantee at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob, will you just comment about the risk adjustment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, frankly risk adjustment has always been a part of our comp process. So with a lot of talk out there about comp, what I would say in terms of principals is pay for performance not for failure. Performance has to be risk adjusted and we believe that the higher earners should have a large proportion of deferral and that should defer over time, preferably in equity. That's always how we've approached this. And the timeframe is simultaneous, there's no gap between evaluating our people and evaluating our clients.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we've got about three minutes to go before 2:30. So we've got time for two more questions. There's one coming to you now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Quick one. Lee Goodwin from Fox-Pitt Kelton. Actually I had a question on impairments, maybe this is one for Robert. Thanks very much for the disclosures and granularity, but I maybe just got a little bit confused about the guidance. It looks as if you are guiding that you're comfortable with the analysts' range of around &#x2013; between 9 and 9.6 billion for the full year I think. I just wanted to be clear that that &#x2013; whether that includes the credit market asset impairments from the first half. And also whether you wouldn't might translating that into basis points for us. And then also I just invite you to look ahead to next year because you haven't said anything about next year. I understand it's very difficult, but when I look at the trends in the first half or some of the impairments it's quite worrying frankly, there's been quite an increase in a number of areas in the loan books. So, perhaps you could review on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the invitation to comment so broadly. We'll have Robert cover &#x2013; we're not going to give a basis point update and Robert's explained very clearly in his remarks why we're not going to doing that. But I'll let him comment on the consensus point you raised.</p>
          <p>Just the policy point as you know, I mean I know you're &#x2013; all of us are very familiar with it, but we have to keep our eye on the consensus numbers. And if ever we are massively out of line with the consensus numbers, in terms of our expectation versus them we have an obligation to comment. And what Robert has been trying to do, we're hoping it's helpful to you, is to say that's what we see as the range. Do we feel an obligation to comment because it looks wildly wrong? We don't. Robert?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I won't take too much time. To put some context around the 9 to &#xA3;9.6 billion, it is total impairment, so it includes everything that goes through impairment. There are of course write-downs that we take on other assets that doesn't go through &#x2013; that don't go through impairment. So it doesn't include some of the legacy assets that are fair valued through trading book.</p>
          <p>The trend that we see is for the increase. You'll remember we had &#xA3;3.9 billion of impairment on the loan book in the first half plus another 650 on available for sale. So about 4.5 billion in the first half. So the range of 9 to 9.6 gives you that context. So we are seeing it increasing both on the retail side and on the wholesale side and that gives you a flavor of where it is.</p>
          <p>For 2010, we haven't made any comment on that. And we are not really thinking about it in basis points terms at this point because we think doing it in pound-sterling is actually a more defined number. It does mean that we have to consider what economic developments are from here, but also what currency moves are. And that's worth just spending 10 seconds on. 60% of our impairment charges are taken outside the U.K., broadly speaking. So if there are 10% currency moves somewhere that could have a 6% move on the impairment range. And the range we've given you doesn't move by about more than 6% on its own. So there are other variables that may come into play here, but we're trying to give you if we can be helpful a pretty tight range from where we see things today based on today's economy, today's currencies and as John had said if those things start to move we'll update you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One last question if there is one. Yes, Sandy, here comes the mic. Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Sandy Chen from Panmure Gordon. The &#x2013; just a follow up, thanks for the disclosure on the monolines. The &#x2013; given the post 30th of June sort of downgrades on a couple of key monolines and indications that CLOs and other &#x2013; some of those other asset classes have gone through more downgrades. Are you expecting that you'll face further charges? And those wouldn't be in the impairment charge line and they come out of the top line I take it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll ask Chris to comment on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. In relation to the second part of your question they don't go through the impairment line, they go through the trading line because of the fair value...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Base from which we carry them. The write-downs that we've taken up to the 30th of June reflect the conditions up to the 30th of June if we include the MBIA downgrades. There have been changes since then and particularly in terms of AmBank, which will not pick up because those are second half events.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you all very much indeed for sparing the time to be with us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>