<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1168110" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>809</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Magdalena Moll, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Dr. J&#xFC;rgen Hambrecht, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Dr. Kurt Bock, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Dr. Stefan Marcinowski, Member of the Board of Executive Directors</participant>
      <participant id="5">Magdalena Moll</participant>
      <participant id="6">Jennifer Barker</participant>
      <participant id="7">J&#xFC;rgen Hambrecht</participant>
      <participant id="8">Ronald K&#xF6;hler</participant>
      <participant id="9">Nobert Barth</participant>
      <participant id="10">Kurt Bock</participant>
      <participant id="11">Thomas Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="12">Neil Tyler</participant>
      <participant id="13">Sophie Jourdier</participant>
      <participant id="14">Rhian Tucker</participant>
      <participant id="15">Fraser Hill</participant>
      <participant id="16">Christian Faitz</participant>
      <participant id="17">Andreas Heine</participant>
      <participant id="18">Stefan Marcinowski</participant>
      <participant id="19">Paul Walsh</participant>
      <participant id="20">Themis Themistocleous</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon ladies and gentlemen. This is the Chorus Call Conference operator. Welcome to the BASF Interim Report Second Quarter Results 2008 Conference Call. As a reminder, all participants are in listen-only mode and the conference is being recorded. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity to ask questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>This presentation may contain forward-looking statements. These statements are based on current expectations, estimates and projections of BASF management and currently available information. They are not guarantees of future performance, involve certain risks and uncertainties that are difficult to predict and are based upon assumptions as to future events that may not prove to be accurate. Many factors could cause the actual results, performance or achievements of BASF to be materially different from those that may be expressed or implied by such statements. Such factors include those discussed in BASF Report 2007 on pages 106. We do not assume any obligation to update the forward-looking statements contained in this presentation.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, at this time, I would like to turn conference over to Ms. Magdalena Moll, Head of Investor Relations. Please go ahead madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Nadine, and good afternoon ladies and gentlemen. On behalf of BASF I would like to welcome you to our second quarter 2008 conference call. This is the 19th consecutive quarter of year-on-year sales and earnings growth at BASF. And our portfolio mix has once again shown good strength.</p>
          <p>With me on the call today are Dr. J&#xFC;rgen Hambrecht, our Chairman of the Board of Executive Directors, and Dr. Kurt Bock our Chief Financial Officer, and Dr. Stefan Marcinowski, Member of the Board of Executive Directors responsible for the Agricultural Solutions segment and for the Coatings division.</p>
          <p>Dr. Hambrecht and Dr. Bock will review our second quarter financial performance. Then Dr. Marcinowski will lead you through the excellent results in Crop Protection, and afterwards, all three gentlemen will be available to take your questions.</p>
          <p>Now, just the usual reminder; today's conference call is limited to really one hour because one of peer companies will start its conference call at 4 p.m. and I would like to ask you to please limit your questions to only one at a time. We have posted the numbers and charts which will be discussed during this call, as well as the press document on our website at basf.com/share.</p>
          <p>With this, I would like to hand over to Dr. Hambrecht.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Maggie. Good afternoon ladies and gentlemen, wherever you are. In the second quarter 2008, BASF again posted new records for sales and earnings.</p>
          <p>Sales rose by 11% to &#x20AC;16.3 billion. Disregarding negative currency effects, sales increased by even 19%. EBIT before special items amounted to &#x20AC;2.4 billion, 19% more than in the second quarter of 2007. Earnings per share were up 34% to &#x20AC;1.39. Of course, remember that this figure is adjusted for the stock split.</p>
          <p>Between the beginning of 2008 and June, we spent &#x20AC;1.1 billion in share repurchases and thus completed our &#x20AC;3 billion share buyback program for 2007 and 8, ahead of schedule. In July, we started a new &#x20AC;3 billion share buyback program, scheduled to be completed by mid-2010.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, these are excellent results. Price and volume increases especially in light of the current macroeconomic environment, beating all benchmarks. Even more important, is that our confident outlook for the year remains unchanged.</p>
          <p>Now, Kurt, will take you through BASF second quarter results in more detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks J&#xFC;rgen and also good afternoon from my side and thanks for joining us. I am going to start by talking about our P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>In Q2, we were able to increase volumes by 5% and prices by even 15%. Agricultural Solutions achieved the highest percentage volume growth, but demand in chemical activities also remained robust or increased. Only Functional Solutions recorded a slight decrease due to weaker demand in the North American automotive and construction industries.</p>
          <p>BASF's strong organic sales growth of 20% was partially offset by the weak U.S. dollar and related currencies, which had a negative impact of 8% on sales. Overall, portfolio changes of minus 1% had only a minor effect on second quarter number.</p>
          <p>Second quarter EBIT before special items rose to &#x20AC;2.4 billion, an increase of 19% compared with the same period last year. Net special charges amounted to about &#x20AC;50 million and were mainly related to restructuring measures expected in 2008.</p>
          <p>The financial result improved by &#x20AC;27 million to minus &#x20AC;38 million, due to income from the valuation of derivatives at fair market value. Income before taxes and minority interests rose by 20% to &#x20AC;2.3 billion.</p>
          <p>The tax rate was 41% compared with 45% in the second quarter of 2007. This lower rate mainly resulted from lower tax rates in Europe, for example the reduction of the German corporate income tax in 2008.</p>
          <p>Non-compensable foreign income taxes on oil production rose by &#x20AC;246 million to &#x20AC;577 million in the second quarter of 2008. Of this increase about &#x20AC;50 million was due to the German corporate tax reform. The rest is attributable to the steep increase in the oil price.</p>
          <p>The average crude oil price in the second quarter 2008 was $121 per barrel compared with just $69 per barrel last year. In euro terms, this corresponds to an increase of &#x20AC;27 to approximately &#x20AC;78 per barrel.</p>
          <p>Minority interest amounted to &#x20AC;73 million and were primarily related to our partners in the Oil &amp; Gas and the Chemicals segment. The increase resulted from Gazprom taking the stake in the German Wintershall subsidiary that holds exploration and production rights to onshore concessions in Libya.</p>
          <p>Net income rose by 27% to &#x20AC;1.3 billion. Earnings per share climbed by 34% to &#x20AC;1.39; this increase was also supported by our share buyback program.</p>
          <p>I will now talk about our segment performance. Our second quarter interim report provides an in-depth information on our segment results. So I will only focus on the highlights and most important changes compared with the second quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>In Chemicals, the strong sales growth was driven by all divisions. However, price increases were not sufficient to completely offset higher raw material costs. Earnings in petrochemicals decreased mainly due to lower cracker margins as well as due to scheduled maintenance shutdowns completed in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Although sales is Plastics segment rose, earnings declined compared with the second quarter of 2007. Performance Polymers business was impacted by lower demand particularly in the North American automotive and construction markets. Due to higher raw material costs, most of the product lines suffered from margin pressure. In Polyurethanes earnings matched the high level of record in the second quarter of 2007, thanks to persistently robust demand in Asia and Europe.</p>
          <p>Sales in Performance Products matched last year's level. Earnings growth was driven by the strong performance in Care Chemicals and reduced fixed cost as a result of our restructuring efforts. This significant increase in raw material and energy costs put pressure on margins for acrylic monomers and paper binders.</p>
          <p>Sales in the Functional Solutions segment rose 2% in the second quarter. Earnings in Coatings almost matched previous year's level. Higher sales of automotive coatings in Europe, Asia and South America compensated for weaker demand for automotive coatings in North America.</p>
          <p>Earnings in Catalysts and especially in Construction Chemicals were significantly impacted by weaker demand from customers in North America.</p>
          <p>Agricultural Solutions had another very successful quarter. Stefan Marcinowski will elaborate on these results in a few minutes.</p>
          <p>Sales in Oil &amp; Gas rose strongly by 41% as a result of higher natural gas production, increased volumes in natural gas trading and higher oil prices. Natural gas production from Siberian Yuzhno Russkoye field currently stands at 40 million cubic meters per day. In Libya, oil production declined slightly. With new exploration licenses in Argentina and Chile, Wintershall continues to expand its activities in South America.</p>
          <p>Income from operations increased again due to a higher contribution from E&amp;P, whereas the gas trading was negatively impacted by the time-lag effect. This is now the fifth quarter in which we have reported insufficient earnings in Natural Gas Trading. And this will continue until the trend is reversed by a decline or at least stable oil prices.</p>
          <p>Taking a look at the net income statement for the Oil &amp; Gas segment, EBIT improved by 44% to &#x20AC;1 billion. Net income increased slightly by 5% to &#x20AC;202 million. These gains were achieved despite higher income taxes on oil production and increased minority interest resulting from our asset swap with Gazprom.</p>
          <p>EBIT before special items in Other improved by &#x20AC;202 million to &#x20AC;13 million. This includes earnings resulting from hedging for raw material prices that are not allocated to the business segments. The valuation of the BASF's option program at fair value also contributed to this improvement.</p>
          <p>I will now briefly discuss our cash flow statement which refers to the first half of the year. At &#x20AC;2.6 million, cash provided by operating activities was &#x20AC;140 million lower than the same period of 2007. The level of net working capital rose as a result of the expansion of our business.</p>
          <p>Cash used in investment activities amounted &#x20AC;1 billion. We spent &#x20AC;1 billion on additions to tangible and intangible assets. This was again below the corresponding depreciation and amortization of about &#x20AC;1.3 billion.</p>
          <p>During the first half of this year, BASF bought back shares for &#x20AC;1.1 billion, thus completing our &#x20AC;3 billion share buyback program 6 months ahead of schedule.</p>
          <p>Our forecast for 2008 is based on the following macroeconomic assumptions, which we updated at our recent Chemicals Segment Day in London. We continue to expect global economic growth of 2.8%; the assumption for chemical production growth in 2008 has been reduced to 2.4%. We assume an average oil price Brent of $120 per barrel and an average dollar/euro exchange rate of $1.55 per euro.</p>
          <p>Despite an increasingly challenging economic environment with high raw material costs, we are confident that we will achieve the goals we have set ourselves for 2008. We aim to increase sales and to improve EBIT before special items slightly.</p>
          <p>Now let me hand over to Stefan Marcinowski who will lead you through the results of our Ag Solutions segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kurt and good afternoon to everyone. In the second quarter, sales for our crop protection products grew by 21% on euro and on a currency-adjusted basis, by an even stronger 30%.</p>
          <p>The positive business development was triggered by persistently high prices for agricultural commodities and strong demand for our innovative crop protection products. Strong volume growth of 24% and price increases of 6% more than offset negative currency effects of about minus 9%.</p>
          <p>EBIT before special items improved by 51%, thanks to price increases and a larger share of highly profitable products, above all, our fungicides.</p>
          <p>Our fungicides business grew by 36% or 44 on a currency-adjusted basis. Our insecticide and herbicide businesses were impacted by the weak U.S. dollar and continued pressure on the U.S. non-crop business.</p>
          <p>On a currency-adjusted basis, we posted record double-digit sales increases in all regions. In Europe, high demand in the fungicides segment, especially for cereal fungicides, resulted in the strong sales increase. In North America, the crop business performed very well, driven by strong demand for fungicides and herbicides. The wet conditions in the Midwest contributed to increased sales of our plant health product, Headline. The U.S. business with non-crop applications, however, remained under pressure.</p>
          <p>High demand for our fungicides and herbicides, especially in Brazil, triggered the strong growth in South America. We saw unusually high &#x2013; we saw unusually early orders for the new season, for soy and corn in particular.</p>
          <p>In Asia Pacific, strong growth, in particular in India and Japan, especially with our soybean herbicide product, Pursuit, and our rice fungicide, Arashi.</p>
          <p>Our profitability target is to reach an EBITDA margin of 25% before special items, which we will achieve in 2008, despite very unfavorable exchange rates. Significantly higher raw material and energy costs as well as major increases in registration costs, especially for the European market, will force us to continuously increase prices.</p>
          <p>In the mid-term, we expect consistently high demand for our <mark type="inaudible" /> innovative crop protection products. Therefore we will expand our capacities for important active ingredients. Besides our capacity investment for our new herbicide, Kixor, we will additionally spend more than &#x20AC;150 million in capacity expansions for products such as our fungicides F 500 and boscalid as well as for fipronil and metazachlor.</p>
          <p>Finally, I would like to give you a short update in our activities in the area of plan biotechnology. Our joint efforts with Monsanto to increase yields of major crops are progressing rapidly and successfully, and we will provide you more details on that in autumn. The situation with regard to the approval of our starch potato Amflora is rather different. Even though we have met all the requirements placed on us in this long process, and even though Amflora has repeatedly been shown to be safe for humans and the environment, the EU Commission is still delaying its approval. We have therefore filed an action with the European Court of First Instance in Luxembourg against the EU Commission for failure to act. Since we are committed to plant biotechnology, we will continue to invest in the development of this key technology and we will fight for its acceptance.</p>
          <p>And with this I would like to hand over to Maggie to take us through the Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Dr. Marcinowski. And we are now moving into the Q&amp;A. We have our first caller, this is Jenny Barker from Lehman Brothers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Obviously a very low underlying tax rate, 21%, I believe the indication for the full year is about 25%. Could you just talk about what tax rate you use in your own medium and long-term planning please, the old days it used to be 34% but I understand that's out of the window now and I am trying to work out what the best new number is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jenny, may I ask you to say that, you were very hard to hear at the beginning, could you repeat the front part of your question again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am sorry. Can you hear me now? Okay. Yes. Underlying tax rate, okay, ignore the non-deductible oil part, underlying tax rate 21% in Q2, indications for the full year I believe 25%. As you look forward in your own companies planning, what number are you using for the medium and long-term please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jenny, I think we have answered that same question already when we talked about the Q1 results. Guidance hasn't really changed we are looking at a tax rate slightly below 30%, underlying we have now let's say profit mix which is very much tilted towards Asia, and in Asia obviously we have a much lower tax rate than on average.</p>
          <p>You asked about the long-term tax rate situation that is pretty hard to predict frankly because tax regimes changes in many countries frequently, but I can tell you for instance in Asia we have certain tax holidays that after a couple of years will basically move us to the let's normal tax rate in some countries, so it might go up a little bit, but there might be other developments in other countries which will compensate for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So would you say 30% that is a good number to use for long term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we're coming to the next question and this is from Ronald K&#xF6;hler MainFirst.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. I have a question regarding to your hedges <mark type="inaudible" /> hedges. Just to clarify that a little bit, I would guess these are mainly the <mark type="inaudible" /> hedges for the cracker which means your cracker margin is depressed because you are using actual prices but you book hedging gains in others? Is that right and can you kind of quantify these hedging gains in Q2?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes Mr. K&#xF6;hler you've got it. It's basically right. What it sense really is that we moved the hedging reserve to others starting this year in Q1. This was a minor effect in Q2, obviously a little bit, higher effect. We have to keep in mind, however, that we are talking here about fair value accounting. So what happens really is that at the end of June we mark-to-market all our positions and that leads to partly unrealized gains from those hedging position and I think it's just prudent to not simply assume that this will all materialize over time. It could, and we're trying hard but it's not necessarily the case. So that means that to a certain degree we have understated the earnings of the Chemicals segment but again keep in mind unrealized profits we are talking about here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can you quantify that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really. I mean it's a more sizable number in the second quarter and we don't really want to give out individual position. What we can is when you talk about raw material cost and the increase year-over-year, we have spent about &#x20AC;1 billion additionally in 2008 in the first half for raw material prices based on raw materials based on higher prices without the volume effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Nobert Barth, from WestLB.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Nobert Barth speaking, Mr. Hambrecht, perhaps a little bit to understand your unchanged guidance but I think you can only understand if you take a quite conservative view on the second half because if you have already reached plus 15% in the first half year, and if you also think that last year there were some maintenance shutdowns that cost more than 200 million, even if I am not very bullish on the economy which I think clearly to understand. I have problems to follow that, because my calculation comes clearly to a double digit increase already. Can you explain a little bit what your estimation is behind the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it is about &#x2013; let me refer to our last discussion where after the first quarter, you all said maybe BASF is too optimistic, don't you see the market what is happening out in the market. Now we are a little bit pessimistic obviously to what you are saying. I think what we are, is as realistic as we can be, this is for the time being. It's very clear going forward that we see some weakening in the growth rate in the global economy. Especially in North America is sacrificing from the automotive and the construction industry. We have some infection in Europe, Southern part but all the UK and Ireland, and in the North, Denmark which will have some impact on our business. But these are the things we need to take into consideration going forward.</p>
          <p>Second piece is if you look very carefully to the raw material prices, we still have the gap between what we purchase for in gas and what we get for if we sell. And this is &#x2013; the entire piece is, as Kurt already mentioned in his speech, is postponed and you don't see even a further margin decrease in the third quarter. And we will have to see how this further develops going forward.</p>
          <p>Cracker margins again depends very much on the &#x2013; naphtha prices are developing over the period of one quarter, it's very clear that we buy actually very &#x2013; basically day-to-day on the resin prices whereas our products, we are reporting of &#x2013; managed by quarterly prices. There is a major delay and we will have to see how this works out. So all in all, to finalize it, I think we have a realistic picture going forward. And surely what we would like to do is we would like to deliver what we promised.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I may add only for clarification, because I saw the oil upstream business only up by 21% in sales; given the higher oil price, that's not very much. It looks that the oil production, and Mr. Bock mentioned already a slight decrease, but it looks to be roundabout minus 10%. Was that in the Libya one-off or will that continue in the next quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>May I take that compliment, I think we have here, first of all it's a correct observation. We know we have now our Dubai license is out, it's no longer running. We have one specific case in Libya offshore. We have some at this very moment the entire production has stopped because of technical reasons run by Total. And of course, if you look into <mark type="inaudible" /> this is now going down to a certain extent and going forward this certainly tells you a little bit of a shift in the composition in the E&amp;P business from oil towards gas.</p>
          <p>On the gas side you have seen with &#x2013; at this very moment we are producing basically 40 million per day &#x2013; cubic meters per day which translates into almost 60% of the capacity, maximum capacity of 25 billion cubic meters per year, and what we are chasing for and this we will reach only in the second quarter about next year. So, it tells you a little bit of a structural change here, which is a little bit negative for a certain period of time, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So we come onto the next question and this comes from Themis Themistocleous from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. It's actually Thomas Gilbert. I have a question on the agricultural business. 6% price increases, correct me if I am wrong, but I think last year F 500 pricing was very weak. I know it was mainly the Latin American season, but can you just in general talk to the 6% price increase, how much of that is F 500 recovery?</p>
          <p>And are you &#x2013; when you have mix changes in pricing does that show up in volume or in price or is the price increase reflecting the fact that you sell a higher proportion of higher value products? And what is actually really the list prices, quoted prices being up? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we do not comment on individual products and their performance or pricing structure. But the thing which I can confirm is that in the fifth quarter in a row we have had increased prices in the overall portfolio, which I think is a very good track record. And also for the next quarter we are aiming to increase the prices due to the facts which I have mentioned, that energy prices are going up on one hand side, and on the other hand we have also to incorporate higher registration costs, especially here in the European environment. And there was favorable condition out there in the market, we are also optimistic that this price increase will continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We come onto the next question, which comes from Neil Tyler from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Question reverting back to the petrochemicals business. One of the earlier questions mentioned that the shutdowns' impact in the second half of last year. You mentioned in your statement there were some maintenance shutdowns in Q2. I wonder if you could help us with a quantification of that, and detail perhaps whether you have brought any maintenance forward from the latter part of the year &#x2013; that would normally have been scheduled for the latter part of the year into Q2. And if so, or if not, whether there'll be any impact of maintenance shutdowns in petrochemicals in H2 this year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me tell you that in the second quarter yes, we had some shutdowns in entire Chemicals operations. That was partly cracker, a plant shutdown in <mark type="inaudible" /> and we had also a PDH propane dehydrogenation unit in Spain out for too long. And in some areas too, now going into this quarter, in the third quarter we had some shutdowns especially in Indonesia, but not to the extent we had it last year. It is very clear, so there should be a slight improvement from this regard going forward, but you please take into consideration again, and again and again I have to say this, we really are suffering somehow from weak cracker margins and still this is prevailing for the time being.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And good, and thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Sophie Jourdier from Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, morning. I just want to understand a bit more the decline in the Functional Solutions division both in Catalysts where you've seen a decline and your nearest competitor, Johnson Matthey had a very positive statement the other day, what's different with your business.</p>
          <p>And second on the Construction Chemicals, really what has changed since the first quarter when you were still reasonably comfortable that business could be pretty defensive, even despite the difficulties in the construction market? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will just take the Construction Chemicals and Kurt will then comment on Catalysts. I think very generally, Sophie, yes Construction Chemicals is now suffering a little bit also in the U.S. We have had a better performance because we are not that match involved in residential, more in the public area and infrastructure. This is still reasonably well. However, going forward, we do not see major projects coming on top. And we have, very generally speaking, here also raw material issues, transportation issues which we cannot pursue at this very moment.</p>
          <p>So all in all, if you look around the world, we have weaknesses in the industry. Generally, this is U.S., it is Southern Europe. We have just talked about it, it has been a little bit also in Japan. But it should be over. So going forward, I see basically one major area where we have some weaknesses, and this will not become much, much better going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well with regard to catalyst, let me add that &#x2013; we had a slight volume decrease in North America which is a bit surprising given the situation of the automotive industry and partially shutdowns, which we saw in Q2. We also see a shift in the cars which are produced, more smaller cars and less bigger cars. And I can only tell you that an SUV is a much, much bigger catalyst than the small car and a bigger catalyst is much more profitable for BASF as well. And I would assume that we'll probably have a higher U.S. exposure than some of our competitors. Let me add that in Europe and especially in Asia, we saw a still healthy growth and in Asia for instance, very nice double-digit volume growth for our business.</p>
          <p>On the cost side, margin side, I can add that we saw a steep increase in some of our raw materials, which we cannot on &#x2013; cannot pass it on immediately to our customers, and that holds particularly true for the refining catalyst business we are for instance in <mark type="inaudible" /> there is just one supplier globally and we have long-term contracts with our customers which we do not want to break because we have a very, let us say, trusted relationship which we want to maintain and that will take some time to work through that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just quickly add on, just on the U.S. automotive market, the one thing that is helping Johnson Matthey, we understand is the heavy duty diesel market. Is it that that has slowed as well in the U.S. or is it simply that you don't have such a large position as Johnson Matthey in that business. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't comment on them. I think we have a good position which we can still improve that way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Now I would to ask Rhian Tucker from Credit Suisse, to put her question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. A question on pricing across each of the divisions. You had very good price growth across the Group as a whole, 15% in Q2. Can you take us through a little bit your pricing strategy in the second half by division? Which division do you think it will be easy &#x2013; be necessary or easy to push through price increases? Or which divisions you don't think it's so necessary or you think you'll struggle a little bit more? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rhian, we can't tell what goes in each individual division, but let me put you a little bit along the segments. I think in the Chemicals segment, I have already touched the most important single piece in the business in principle, the cracker margin. And second one, I can also comment on this Butanedione where we have, let me say, more competitor coming into the market. You know the areas where it is more difficult to push prices.</p>
          <p>So all in all, the rest, I think we are looking forward to get the prices up to the level which are necessary to keep our margins if possible to further improve even in the <mark type="inaudible" /> we are not just trying for increasing prices, we would like to sit down with our customers and find better solutions for them and for us. And I think this we have, let me say, in our portfolio, quite a few examples, which demonstrate that we take the concerns of our customers here.</p>
          <p>Now getting to Plastics, here we have in polymers a favorable situation in Performance Polymers certainly, it takes a little bit more time to get to get the raw material price increases through, touched especially by the immediate.</p>
          <p>Looking into our Performance Products, this a very mixed bag, certainly in the area of Care Chemicals, we have favorable conditions in vitamins, which will continue. But also in other areas, like detergents and formulators, acrylic dispersions, you know about the weakness in, let me say, the surplus in supply in the acrylic chain, which certainly does not disappear. On the other hand, we have a rather good business if it comes to super absorbers and also our adhesives business.</p>
          <p>In Performance Chemicals, here we have structural issues in the textile, leather and paper industry which are, to a certain extent &#x2013; yes, also holding us up to any pushed prices through to the extent. The rest, I really have to say is in good shape and what we try to achieve is to decrease our fixed cost base, especially in this area and we are rather successful.</p>
          <p>Functional Solutions, we have already talked about, and finally, Agricultural Products, I think Stefan has commented already on to this. And please keep in mind, Agricultural Solutions and Crop Protection business, we look at this on a yearly basis and not on a quarterly basis. It will not help, and you have seen it in first quarter and second quarter. Last time, you have asked us why did you underperform? Now you can say we have clearly outperformed our competitors. And this is exactly what I am saying. We'll get it from a yearly basis and you will see that we are on a very, very good track to push our innovative &#x2013; innovative products, so it doesn't matter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So if we say...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I already told you yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead and finish.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, if we were to say that price increase is around the same order of magnitude for &#x2013; we saw in Q3 &#x2013; Q2, coming into Q3, would that be about correct or would you say slightly less than that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, it is general estimation, I think it's very, very difficult. If you look throughout the year, usually what you have; first and second quarter are strong, third quarter are weaker quarters. So I don't know how this works out. So may be some of that which is not very expressed this year, however, very generally, usually third quarter price increases are lower compared to the rest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We come to the next question from Fraser Hill, Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good afternoon. It's Fraser Hill from Merrill Lynch. Just wanted to return to your comment on the production volume from Yuzhno Russkoye. You talked about I think 40 million meter cubed a day. I think that compares to a number here in your presentation from the Oil &amp; Gas Investor, they have 33 million.</p>
          <p>So are you saying it &#x2013; I probably missed your answer earlier, are you saying that you think you can reach the plateau production earlier? Do you think there is going to &#x2013; perhaps some increase your target level of production out of that field. And maybe after answering that, if you could also provide us with some comments on the cost out of Russia, how you've seen those developing this year and maybe how you see the outlook for E&amp;P costs into the next year or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, the current daily production is about 40 million cubic meters per day. Our forecast for the year 2008 is 13 billion cubic meters and plateau production is at about 25 billion, which we will achieve in 2009. And that is our current plan since this is about geology, you are never completely sure that there are some surprises or not but right now I would say we are on track to achieve this.</p>
          <p>With regard to costs, when we see &#x2013; see as an entire industry, we see a steep increase in construction costs et cetera, and you are aware of that but again this is most probably already within our budget and plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We're now coming to Christian Faitz from Oppenheim Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks for taking my question. Just briefly can you please give us at least a qualitative assessment for your chemical activities? And that is all your chemical clusters, how these <mark type="inaudible" /> performance in Q3, meaning April, May, June period, from many of your key customers we hear that June was exceptionally weak. Did you see this in your sales and volumes mixes as well? And then a second brief question, do you see any impact in your chemical activities in China from the Olympics? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Very clearly, we have not seen this in June, very, very few exceptions. But I think we should not exaggerate things and really looking from a monthly point of view, it is rather useless, I would say. We have not seen this, and for us the second, moving into China, yes there are certain activities especially hazardous chemicals which are limited in transportation, shortly before June and shortly after the Olympic Games, which may have some impact in third quarter. But also this is very, very limited. We talked about TDI and these kind of products. But all in all, this should not have a major, major impact on our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And there is also no precursors which you need for your core production or let's say client industries who aren't producing during this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No major impact on this &#x2013; also on this end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we would like to ask Andreas Heine to ask his question, from UniCredit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Only a small one left, the first the CapEx budget in Agro you had mentioned two projects which you have to invest, and although you are rather low CapEx budget, be up for several years, is it just this one project. And the second thing, in polymers science (39.33), I know you had maintenance shutdowns in TDI and MDI. Had that impacted the earnings in polyurethanes in the second quarter or was that leveled out by producing ahead &#x2013; producing more to counterbalance this shutdown of the plants?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me try to take the second one first and then comes Stefan. Partly looking into TDI and MDI, yes we had the closure on the Intel site in <mark type="inaudible" /> and we had also the turnaround in China. All in all, I have to say this had a minor impact on our business performance in plastics but not to the extent that I would really name it as a specific issue. Now Stefan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well the expansion and the investment in our crop protection segment is indeed above average at the moment, due to the fact that we are, on one hand side, investing for the new herbicide Kixor, which is a wonderful compound complete resistance against glycoside, ready for the season and the campaign 2010. And at the same time, we are doing the expansion for our fungicides, FI500, and Boscalid plus for the Fipronil and Metazachlor.</p>
          <p>So indeed, we are, at that moment, above the average investment budget that we usually have but the major &#x2013; the major future driver for crop protection is not so much investment seal and concrete, but that's the ongoing R&amp;D investment that we are keeping up. And that is, I think, also the  lifeblood where the new products are coming from. And the investment for new product usually is smaller than what you have invested before through R&amp;D.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now I would like to Paul Walsh from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much indeed. I just wanted to come back to your suggestions that you're going to get prices up in crop moving into next season, we've heard high single digit from Syngenta we heard 2 to 3% Bayer. Just getting your thoughts on where you might put yourselves. And secondly, just on the M&amp;A front, obviously there has been little rumor in the market, we've had Dow's move for Roman Haz, could you just remind us what your strategy is on M&amp;A both as regards to businesses you might be looking for and assets you still have for sale for example the spyronics business, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I did not really get to first question by the way but let me start with second one may be you can figure out this because I couldn't hear very well at the beginning now let's take second one which was very clear and M&amp;A activities, I mean first of all proactive portfolio management is on our priority list number three as you know innovation number, number one, organic growth by investment number two and then proactive portfolio optimization. Certainly a major key part of our strategic management, here I really have to say, you know our priorities nothing has changed here, absolutely nothing has changed and I really cannot contribute to any kind of rumors, speculations to a certain extent, I get the impression that it's almost the textbook of investment banking, we are just trust reading soldiers (44.08) and BASF is a good name on one hand to get in the serial discussion and secondly to dress up supply, I really have to say, we have to step away from that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very clear and just coming back to the first question, I have apologies for any disturbance in the line, within your agricultural business, in terms of the price increases you are seeking for next season, what kind of level of price increases we heard Syngenta talking about high single digit and Bayer talking about 2 to 3%, just wanted to get your view on that please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think needs to look into this segment a little bit more in detail I think what is going all taking office all the plant health segment and it obvious that if you can show to the farmer that is might get a 5% or 10% increase in yield through this treatment, that of course translates directly into additional profits for the farmer and that is I think in from that point of view obvious that there is a good pricing policy with those products. But I would not like to now put any number out there, as I said before we have five quarters in a row successfully increased prices in this segment, we have not seen any limit at that moment. Products are short out there and we are therefore also doing this de-bottlenecking investment to meet this trend for the season 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we are moving onwards Oliver Schwartz and I'd appreciate if you could go back to this one question per person.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'll try to do my best. Quick questions regarding regional development, if we took June development or June business conditions would you expect the region North America to move in to a loss in the second half year as eChem business is, as it is in the Northern half, gear to the Northern Hemisphere. It's not so contributing too much to the EBIT line. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No clearly no, absolutely no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now Kristof Figer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question on your Vitamins business. You have mentioned you reported that you have benefited from Vitamin volume and price increase in the second quarter. When you talked about some potential impact in China, now given the significant of Chinese competitors in this field, can you exclude that this is because of temporary strict environmental regulation in China and can we be sure that these will not go away and we'll be sustained again after the Olympic Games in Beijing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take this one, vitamins business, I think it's a structural issue and one should not expect China to reduce their demand on environment regulations, tax economy, going forward you will see this coming up more and more and more they rumors, what you need to do. And the second topic is, there is a shortage in certain vitamins anyhow, even if you taken consideration for Chinese, so overall what we consider this will be a business which keeps on going.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we have the next question again Themis Themistocleous from UBS I am wondering if he's here yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah and it's actually Themis this time, thank you. Just a quick question about, Dr. Hambrecht. I'm trying to reconcile the comment about challenging business environment and between 5 and 10% percent volume that you showed in your profound (48.08) divisions, how do you explain the very strong volume growth in the challenging environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean there are quite a lot of different aspects if you look into where we have grown the most, it's certainly in the area of, chemicals and plastics and going small list and just see our volume increases you see where nature go and it is certainly out throwing in R&amp;D. Challenging business environment going forward is referring to our customer industries I have to say and my biggest concern is the inflationary tendency, the respective real income decrease of the consumer. And this will have an impact on our customer industries. We see already structural problems, in the automotive industry if you just meet, what was just announced in North America, General Motors closing down, even Nissan is now closing down, all this will have an impact, second one is construction industry and you can continue, furniture industry, paper industry, textile and leather industries. These are the industries which are hit the most.</p>
          <p>On the other end we have very positive aspects, and this is way I believe, we now are going forward, we will grow in volume above the average of the industry and this is why we are saying we will increase our sales and on the EBIT level, earn a slight increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you think effectively the volume growth you see in this on the back of market share gains?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Partly market gained, yes share gained, no doubt looking out especially also in Asia but partly we even, we changed our market share because we want really value before volume. This is June for example, for the Styrene business but also for, for assets and don't forget we also have looking into for example, ecochemicals. Stefan is just indicating system, since to be. We are plan house and new business segment, we have developed over the last years, instead of contributes it contributes to our growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we are moving on to Richard Harvey from Larry's Capital Management .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I was wondering &#x2013; perhaps this was already covered but with respect to your CapEx budget for the coming year, what amount is it and also what percentage of it is for maintenance as opposed to growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, what you can expect for next year is CapEx in the same order of magnitude as this year maybe a little bit higher as I already talked about early July because cost of investment has gone up quite substantially. So it might be a little bit higher but still most probably it will be low depreciation.</p>
          <p>Now if you look into the CapEx then most is foreclosed and maintenance here again used to handling this rather differently. Let me tell you that we are spending quite a lot of money in maintaining our plant which is directly expensed as far as we can.</p>
          <p>So, all in all, just to give you an idea for the side <mark type="inaudible" /> we have investments, CapEx in your terms up to about half a billion and you have maintenance in the same order of magnitude which is mostly directly expensed so that you have an idea, we will keep our plant state-of-the-art and try to run them out as much as we can. And this &#x2013; preventive maintenance is one of tools we are using.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, if I can just clarify this a little bit, we just happen to think about this in a unique way. So, you are saying that much of your maintenance expenditures are in your normal operating profit expense, but of the total CapEx which would not be just &#x2013; like it would be in the amount in the cash flow statement spend for property, plant and equipment. What percentage of that would be for maintenance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I do not have these figures with me. Most as you said is in the expense and there is a certain maintenance if you have a turnaround a cracker there &#x2013; certain parts are &#x2013; surely then you would say under maintenance. But I don't have this figure, it's a minor figure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Ronald K&#xF6;hler from MainFirst.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Again, actually looking at you acquisitions done in 2006 Construction Chemicals and Catalysts, obviously you have criteria for acquisitions that should be earnings-enhancing, at least in the third year. I just wonder, we see here a down turn really driven by a macroeconomic scene but nevertheless could you confirm that these acquisitions are still contributing to BAS's net earnings side according to your deepest definitions of acquisition criteria?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me first address the old one approach, but quickly go into this, the first one is certainly, it's a starting point, because we have talked about this morning with the journalists as well. Now when you enter into acquisitions certainly you have basic assumptions, nothing has changed with this basic assumptions going forward, this will hold true. However we have not anticipated certainly what happened now in North America with credit crunch and the <mark type="inaudible" /> deriving from this, this has certain impact on our business. Overall we will achieve what we wanted to achieve, but Kurt may comment on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, from your question was more specifically are we making this goal of being accretive in year three. I'd say yes. We are happy with what we have acquired. They are performing up to our expectations from into 2008. It is more challenging both in construction and in automotive than we had expected two years ago. But I think that it is not a surprise to anybody who knows what those two industries, but also <mark type="inaudible" /> in both cases, and I am not talking about Catalysts and Construction Chemicals. The underlying theme is still very, very relevant which is about innovation, good market growth structurally and gaining the market share by offering better products and better customer service.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Neil Tyler, JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes hello again, just a quick follow-up question on your working capital performance. Just following up from the first quarter, obviously a less positive working capital development during Q2, unsurprisingly given the price inflation. And I wonder if you are able to give any sort of steer for the second half year or is it just in terms of percentage of sales or in terms of your expectations on the balance sheet of the working capital development?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I am supposed to take this question. We had &#x2013; the efficiency of our working capital management has further improved because the day's outstanding growth of inventories end receivable has come down. Again I have to say however it should be the growth &#x2013; the absolute growth of the business led to a higher working capital need a slight increased couple of hundred millions. And as I have said before in other conference calls, you have to keep in mind we are the talking here quarterly numbers, sometimes it's really depending on certain closing day of the month whether it is the last day or the first day of the week, something like that. Our goal is for the second half of the total year to achieve last year's number in terms of operating cash flow. And I think we are well on track to achieve that number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and that implies you hold on to the improvement in days outstanding, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what we try to very much to achieve, yes, absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question comes from Jenny Barker, Lehman Brothers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, just coming back on the Stefan's last point, 10% growth in volume growth in Chemicals, 9% in Plastics, can you comment &#x2013; do you think that there was some inventory building along the chain supporting this level of demand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jenny, we started with you and we finish with you. But let me tell you let me tell you at this end what we see, basically there is not a lot of inventory, just the opposite in most of the areas. But I do not see this volume increase in Chemicals and Plastics coming from, let me say, some kind of pre-buying, and putting it into inventory. This is minor, minor, minor issue which is in China, on the TDI of course, there was a little bit of re-buying. But let me tell you this, now we getting into micro, micro, micro-management, this is not really essential.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen this brings us to the end of our conference call. But before we close, I would like to invite you all to our next event. This is our Biotech Field Trip to crop designing event close to Brussels in Belgium on September 16, 2008 and I send out invitations to &#x2013; ready today till lunch time, so you should be able to register by tomorrow.</p>
          <p>And for today, I am glad to thank you for joining and for participating in the discussion and should you have any further questions, all of us on the IR team will be happy to help you. So with this I say have a nice afternoon and good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the conference call is now over and you may disconnect your telephone. Thank you very much for joining, good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>