<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1483900" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-26</date>
    <companies>
      <company>809</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Vice President-Investor Relations">Magdalena Moll</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman-Executive Board">Kurt W. Bock</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO, Head-Corporate Controlling &amp; Corporate Audit">Hans-Ulrich Engel</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Redburn Partners LLP">Tony G. Jones</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Cheuvreux SA (Germany)">Martin R&#xF6;diger</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">James R. Knight</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Baader Bank AG">Norbert Barth</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Jaideep Pandya</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Chris D. Counihan</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Neil C. Tyler</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Commerzbank AG (Broker)">Lutz Gr&#xFC;ten</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Paul R. Walsh</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Andreas Heine</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd. Germany">Christian Faitz</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Andrew G. Benson</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Richard Logan</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="MainFirst">Ronald Koehler</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (UK)">Peter A. Clark</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Jeremy M. Redenius</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS AG (Broker)">Thomas Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Jean G. de Watteville</participant>
      <participant id="22" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Laurent G. Favre</participant>
      <participant id="23" type="analyst" affiliation="DZ Bank AG (Securities)">Peter Spengler</participant>
      <participant id="24" type="analyst" affiliation="equinet Bank AG (Broker)">Nadeshda Demidova</participant>
      <participant id="25" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Martin J. Evans</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. This is the Chorus Call conference operation. Welcome to the BASF Interim Report Second Quarter Results 2012. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>The presentation includes forward-looking statements that are subject to risks and uncertainties, including those pertaining to the anticipated benefits to be realized from the proposals described herein. This presentation contains a number of forward-looking statements including, in particular, statements about future events, future financial performance, plans, strategies, expectations, prospects, competitive environment, regulation, supply and demand. BASF has based these forward-looking statements on its views with respect to future events and financial performance.</p>
          <p>Actual financial performance of the entities described herein could differ materially from that projected in the forward-looking statements due to the inherent uncertainty of estimates, forecasts and projections, and financial performance may be better or worse than anticipated. Given these uncertainties, readers should not put undue reliance on any forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Forward-looking statements represent estimates and assumptions only as of the date that they were made. The information contained in this presentation is subject to change without notice and BASF does not undertake any duty to update the forward-looking statements and the estimates and assumptions associated with them, except to the extent required by applicable laws and regulations.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, at this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Magdalena Moll, Head of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you, Jason, and good morning, ladies and gentlemen. On behalf of BASF, I would like to welcome you to our second quarter 2012 conference call.</p>
          <p>We are pleased with the business development in the first half 2012, where we exceeded the exceptionally high sales and earnings before special items of the first half of 2011.</p>
          <p>With me on the call today to explain the results are Kurt Bock, our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, and Hans-Ulrich Engel, our Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>Kurt will summarize the key financials, highlight important milestones of the quarter, and conclude with the outlook for the full year 2012. Hans will subsequently review the segment results of the second quarter in detail for you. Afterwards, both gentlemen will be happy to take your questions.</p>
          <p>We have posted the charts and the speech, as well as the press documents on our website, www.basf.com/share.</p>
          <p>And now I would like to hand over the call to Kurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you, Maggie, and good morning and welcome also from my side.</p>
          <p>The world economy experienced a turbulent first half of 2012, and we saw uncertainty increase in all regions. The deepening of the euro debt crisis overshadowed the global business sentiment in the second quarter. Concerns were also raised by the slower growth in China. All in all, chemical demand weakened more than expected earlier this year, both in the developed and the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>In this challenging environment, BASF was able to deliver a solid second quarter. At &#x20AC;19.5 billion, sales were 6% higher than a year ago. Our top line benefited from the weaker euro.</p>
          <p>In Agricultural Solutions, we experienced excellent demand for our innovative products and delivered an outstanding quarter, the best second quarter ever. In Oil &amp; Gas, our strong growth was supported by improving production volumes in Libya.</p>
          <p>In our chemical businesses, however, volumes could not be maintained compared to the very strong level of the previous year's second quarter. During the course of Q2, we saw a swing towards lower raw material prices. This triggered cautious customer behavior and order delays. Overall, prices were stable.</p>
          <p>EBITDA came in at &#x20AC;3.1 billion, up 4% from last year. EBIT before special items at &#x20AC;2.5 billion, significantly exceeded last year's second quarter. Special items in EBIT amounted to minus &#x20AC;261 million and included restructuring charges as well as the impairment of an oil and gas field development project in Norway.</p>
          <p>The tax rate increased to 39%, mainly due to non-compensable oil taxes in Libya. This burdened our net income.</p>
          <p>Adjusted earnings per share decreased by 9% to &#x20AC;1.60.</p>
          <p>Overall, in the first half of 2012, we were able to exceed the exceptionally high sales and earnings before special items of the first half of the previous year.</p>
          <p>In the second quarter, we achieved several important milestones. With its robust local industries, India is set to become a pillar of growth in Asia Pacific. In order to ensure local supply for growing markets and industries, we have decided to invest &#x20AC;150 million in a chemical production site in Dahej, on the west coast of India. The new site will be an integrated hub for polyurethane manufacturing and also host production facilities for care chemicals and polymer dispersions for coatings and paper. The start-up is planned for 2014.</p>
          <p>The acquisition of Novolyte Technologies was the latest in a series of strategic steps to strengthen our technology position in battery materials. The integration of Novolyte's electrolyte formulation activities now positions BASF as global supplier of lithium-ion battery electrolytes with production sites in Europe, the United States and Asia Pacific.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, we acquired the polyamide polymer business of Mazzaferro Group. We are thus further strengthening our production presence with regard to engineering plastics and polyamide polymers in South America, where demand for polyamide in the automotive and extrusion industries is growing strongly.</p>
          <p>And finally the outlook. In our last quarterly conference call on April 27, we reiterated our full year ambitions to exceed the previous year's record levels of sales and EBIT before special items. In the first half of 2012, we were able to surpass the exceptionally high sales and earnings level of last year.</p>
          <p>However, the recent weakening of the global economy, which we see reflected in our order books, led us to become more cautious in our 2012 macroeconomic assumptions. For 2012, we now expect global GDP to expand only by 2.3%, down 0.4 percentage points from our previous assumption. Industrial production, we now see at 3.4% and chemical production at 3.5%, a reduction of 0.7 and 0.6 percentage points, respectively.</p>
          <p>Our assumptions for the Brent oil price is $110 per barrel and the &#x2013; with a dollar/euro exchange rate at $1.30 remain unchanged.</p>
          <p>Given the weak demand outlook, we now expect volumes in our chemical business to be flat in the second half of this year compared to the first half. Consequently, EBIT before special items in our chemical business for the full year 2012 is expected to come in below the level of 2011.</p>
          <p>How is BASF addressing these challenges and the significant political and economic uncertainties? First and foremost, it is our objective to protect margins and to create value for our investors, which means, as you all know, value before volume.</p>
          <p>Our operational excellence program STEP, which we announced in November 2011, is on track to deliver &#x20AC;1 billion of earnings contribution annually by the year 2015. Wherever possible, we will accelerate actions and evaluate our cost base and expenditures. We're continuing to optimize our working capital, as demonstrated by a strong cash flow development in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Due to the uncertainty around the development of businesses in Asia, we will slow down the planned build-up in personnel, particular in the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>For BASF Group overall, our target is unchanged. We aim to exceed the 2011 record levels in sales and EBIT before special items in 2012. Furthermore, we expect to again earn a high premium on our cost of capital.</p>
          <p>And with this, I will hand over to Hans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kurt, and good morning, ladies and gentlemen, also from my side. Let me highlight the financial performance of each segment in more detail and focus on the respective business developments in comparison to the second quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>Sales in the Chemicals segment slightly declined mainly due to lower volumes, plant turnarounds and the effects of an earnings-neutral swap agreement for different grades of propylene in the U.S. As you might recall, since Q3 2011, we now swap like-for-like propylene which does not show up as sales anymore.</p>
          <p>Feedstock sales to Styrolution and to the recently divested fertilizer business contributed positively to the top line. EBIT before special items declined significantly due to lower margins.</p>
          <p>In Petrochemicals, sales decreased due to weakening demand in the course of the quarter. The scheduled eight-week turnaround of our cracker in Port Arthur, Texas negatively impacted volumes. Raw material prices started to drop from record levels and consequently, prices for all product lines went down. As expected margins were under pressure, this led to a significant drop in earnings.</p>
          <p>Sales in Inorganics increased significantly, driven by feedstock sales to the divested fertilizer activities, as well as the startup of a new sodium methylate plant in Brazil. EBIT before special items came in above the previous year's quarter.</p>
          <p>In Intermediates, strong demand from important customer industries, such as agrochemicals and plastics, as well as positive currency impacts, resulted in significantly higher sales. Nevertheless, margins were under pressure as rising costs for key raw materials could not be fully compensated by higher prices. Accordingly, earnings came in below Q2 2011.</p>
          <p>Sales in Plastics were slightly higher compared to a strong second quarter in 2011. Favorable exchange rates were the strong support. Continued weak demand for polyamide precursors resulted in lower volumes. Overall, EBIT before special items was considerably down but improved compared to Q1 2012.</p>
          <p>In Performance Polymers, sales remained below the prior year's quarter. Polyamide precursors were impacted by lower textile fiber demand in Asia. Engineering plastics benefited from healthy demand from the automotive industry in North America and Asia. Based on lower volumes and lower capacity utilization, EBIT before special items was significantly below last year.</p>
          <p>Sales in Polyurethanes increased. Lower volumes in TDI and MDI were mostly a result of scheduled turnarounds at several sites. While volumes went down for basic products, prices could be partially increased. Specialties were driven by strong demand from the automotive sector. EBIT before special items was slightly below the level of the previous year's quarter, due to the turnaround and higher raw material costs.</p>
          <p>Sales in the Performance Products segment came in slightly higher. Volumes were down due to a generally weaker economic sentiment. However, we were able to increase prices and we profited from currency tailwinds. Earnings were significantly down due to margin pressure, given weak demand and higher raw material prices.</p>
          <p>In Dispersions &amp; Pigments, positive currency effects and slightly increased volumes resulted in higher sales. In North America, sales increased significantly, driven by strong demand and higher prices. Europe experienced lower volumes, mostly due to weaker demand for pigments. EBIT before special items was down mainly due to unfavorable product mix.</p>
          <p>In Care Chemicals, sales declined as a result of cautious customer behavior in anticipation of falling raw material prices. Consequently, volumes were below the previous year. Margins were under pressure, hence, EBIT before special items was down significantly.</p>
          <p>In Nutrition &amp; Health, sales increased in all businesses and regions, except for Europe. Overall, volumes were in line with Q2 2011. Favorable exchange rate effects and price increases positively contributed to the top line. As a result of higher raw material costs, earnings could not be maintained at the previous year's level.</p>
          <p>Despite challenging market conditions, sales in Paper Chemicals increased, thanks to slightly higher prices and a positive currency development. Volumes, though, were negatively impacted by measures to streamline our portfolio. Nevertheless, EBIT before special items came in higher mainly due to our continuing restructuring efforts towards fixed cost reduction.</p>
          <p>In Performance Chemicals, sales rose due to successful price increases, as well as currency impacts. Volumes were down due to weaker demand. Earnings were up.</p>
          <p>In our Functional Solutions segment, sales increased mainly due to portfolio effects and currency tailwinds. Demand from the construction industry in North America rose slight. Earnings, though, declined due to higher raw material costs and lower results in precious metal trading.</p>
          <p>Catalysts' sales rose, mainly attributable to continuous strong demand for mobile emission and chemical catalysts. Slightly higher volumes, however, could not fully compensate for the higher raw material costs, as well as the lower trading results in precious metals. As a result, earnings were below the strong quarter of the previous year.</p>
          <p>Sales in Construction Chemicals were up due to successful price increases, as well as positive exchange rate and portfolio effects. Volumes increased in North America and Asia but remained below the previous year's quarter in Europe. Earnings before special items were up given higher prices and improved margins.</p>
          <p>In Coatings, we saw a strong demand for automotive OEM coatings and industrial coatings. Margins were mostly maintained, thanks to successful price increases in all regions and the optimization of our raw materials portfolio. EBIT before special items, however, came in slightly lower than in the previous year's quarter due to higher fixed costs.</p>
          <p>Our Agricultural Solutions segment delivered an outstanding quarter, with sales increasing by 22% year-over-year. High demand for our innovative products in all indications and in all regions drove significant volume growth. The positive pricing trend was intact for the fourth quarter in a row, and the stronger U.S. dollar led to a tailwind on currency.</p>
          <p>EBIT before special items reached a new second quarter record, putting year-to-date earnings ahead of the full-year 2011 figure. In Europe, positive business momentum continued, especially in Central and Eastern Europe, and in the United Kingdom. Our Clearfield herbicides made a strong contribution and our new fungicide Xemium is living up to its blockbuster potential. Moreover, last week, it got approved for use in crop protection products in the EU-27, which will help us to obtain registrations for Xemium-containing products in additional countries.</p>
          <p>In North America, significant sales growth was supported by excellent demand for our Plant Health products and for herbicides, mainly Kixor. The prevailing drought condition in the Midwest USA did not impact our sales for the quarter, but is certainly something to watch out for.</p>
          <p>Sales in South America also developed very well, as high demand for our Fipronil insecticide and for F500 overcompensated weather challenges affecting the South of Brazil and Argentina. In Asia, sales were strongly up versus the previous year's quarter, driven by higher herbicide sales in India and by strong fungicide sales across the region.</p>
          <p>Sales in Oil &amp; Gas continued to grow strongly, driven by higher volumes, both from exploration and production, as well as natural gas trading. EBIT before special items increased significantly. Net income came in slightly below 2011, due to higher taxes. In exploration and production, sales were up by 122% mainly due to the resumption of oil production in Libya. Thanks to additional capacity in the export pipeline, we could temporarily raise our oil production in Libya from an average of 70,000 barrels in Q1, up to roughly 80,000 barrels per day in Q2.</p>
          <p>Strong volumes and higher prices in euro led to substantially higher earnings. Sales in natural gas trading increased strongly due to higher prices and volumes. Earnings grew significantly due to higher volumes and prices, as well as due to income from the OPAL pipeline.</p>
          <p>Sales in Other decreased significantly due to the divestment of our styrenics activities into the Styrolution joint venture, as well as the sale of our fertilizer business.</p>
          <p>EBIT before special items improved substantially because of positive valuation effects associated with the long-term incentive program for executives. Special items in Other included provisions for potential asset devaluations and restructuring cost, which we will allocate to the respective businesses as soon as the measures are implemented.</p>
          <p>Let me now conclude with our cash flow for the first half of 2012. Cash provided by operating activities came in at &#x20AC;3.5 billion in the first half of 2012 and we recorded a strong free cash flow of &#x20AC;1.8 billion.</p>
          <p>Net working capital increased by &#x20AC;700 million. Cash used in investing activities amounted to &#x20AC;1.1 billion. As planned, CapEx was up by 32% at &#x20AC;1.7 billion. The net proceeds from acquisitions and divestitures amounted to &#x20AC;430 million. This included the proceeds from the sale of our fertilizer assets in Q1, as well as &#x20AC;278 million which we paid for various smaller acquisitions.</p>
          <p>Financing activities led to a cash outflow of &#x20AC;2.2 billion, mainly due to dividend payments to shareholders of BASF SE and minority shareholders in group companies. Net debt decreased by &#x20AC;700 million to &#x20AC;11.5 billion in comparison to the end of the first half in 2011.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention and we're now happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you, gentlemen.</p>
          <p>And ladies and gentlemen, I would now like to open the call for questions. As always, I would like to ask you to please limit your questions to one at a time, so that we can take as many questions as possible, but at the same time, I would like to encourage you to rejoin the queue for a follow-up question.</p>
          <p>And now Jason is going to explain the procedure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I would like to announce the first question comes from Tony Jones from Redburn. Good morning, Tony.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, thanks for taking the question. I just will ask one, as you request. With a cautious outlook, your lower outlook for chemical production, the message here seems to be that you're moving a little bit more towards cost cutting, a little bit more cautious, which feels quite appropriate. But what should we think about in terms of CapEx? And with forecasting &#x20AC;3.5 billion of CapEx this year and that's just probably trend off, if anything, in the next few years. Do you think that your CapEx plans might slow and if so what businesses might get affected? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Tony. Thanks for the question. Actually, you're quite right, we are a little bit more cautious with regard to cost. When we look at CapEx, however, I'd say that we continue to spend as planned. Our CapEx budget is based on the mid and long-term assumptions for the expected growth inside the businesses and regions. And I think those assumptions are still valid, so we see no reason for the time being to cut back any of our CapEx programs. Actually, they are in full swing and the &#x20AC;3.5 billion is probably a good estimate for 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is coming from Martin R&#xF6;diger from Cheuvreux. Good morning, Martin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Thanks for taking my question. It's on Care Chemicals. You talked about cautious customer behavior, waiting for lower prices, so margins are under pressure and earnings significantly down.</p>
          <p>Can you elaborate a little bit on this? Because I wonder why this defensive business has such a strong swing? Is it more the surfactants business or is it the <mark type="ph" /> super salt (22:05) business which is affected? So any thoughts about why this is just a de-stocking effect and not continuing, that would be very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Martin, thank you for the question. I think it's an important topic because it's not that easy to understand, frankly. It's all about surfactants, to make that quite clear. And obviously the Care Chemicals business is also driven to a certain degree by raw material cost. We all know that lauric oil, palm oil is a major ingredient. Just looking at the price development of lauric oil over the last couple of years, shows you the volatility and, let's say, the sequence of events. We had a record price in 2011 of $2,300 per ton. It has now come down to less than 50% of that price. And obviously, this is also reflected in our sales numbers because surfactants and fatty alcohols are, let's say, a function, to a certain degree, of the underlying raw material cost.</p>
          <p>What we have also seen and that is the question about de-stocking and underlying demand, what we have also seen in 2011 is that the very high cost of our products, not just of our products, but of the entire industry, posed a major issue to our customers, who obviously as you all know, are not on a position to automatically pass on these higher costs to their consumers, end consumer customers.</p>
          <p>So, what has happened then is that some customers have tried to reduce the intake to change some formulation, if possible. In some cases, they came back to us and said, okay, we need a much lower price in order to justify buying from BASF. And I think, I mentioned this in my little speech when I talked about value before volume, there have been cases where we basically said okay, we understand what you're saying but I think, it's not in the medium or long-term interest of BASF. And if you have a better and more affordable source, that's okay with us as well. So, there were a couple of businesses where we basically said, we will not compete based on that price.</p>
          <p>What is very important, the underlying trend for the business is a very healthy one. Actually, we're fully on track with regard to reaping the benefits from the acquisitions of Cognis' synergies but also in terms of growth paths, business plan. We just compared what we had expected when we made the acquisition about two years ago and where we are today and I can assure you, we are still well above of what we expected to happen about two years ago. But we had this huge and frankly also, I would say, unexpected surge in demand prices and profits in 2011 and compared with that, it's now weakening a little bit.</p>
          <p>I hope this helps.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then we're moving on to James Knight from Exane. Good morning, James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Yes, thanks for taking my question. It's about shorter term momentum in the <mark type="ph" /> core, the Bund (25:21) industrial areas. Could you give us a little bit of a better feel about how markets looked in June and July?</p>
          <p>Obviously, you've seen the comments on downgrading GDP estimates, comments from the order book et cetera. Have you seen any maybe shorter term relief in the de-stocking from the recent oil recovery? Do you expect that to be sustained, et cetera? And just some feel for the current industrial momentum in your more industrial businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, James, it's a core question really and this question and the answer to that actually led us to our guidance that we said, we, at best, expect second half to be flat compared to first half.</p>
          <p>So, when we talk with our businesses around the table and ask each and everyone, what do you see, do you see a pick-up in demand, do you see any restocking behavior at your customer level? The answer was <mark type="indiscernible" /> (26:21), no we don't see this. What we see is a flat development. We don't see a decline but we see a flat development for, I would say, most of our industrial businesses, as you descried then. And that is a pretty recent observation which I just related to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we're now coming on to Norbert Barth from Baader Bank. Good morning, Norbert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (26:47). My question is related to the previous one. So, Kurt can you a little bit, still elaborate? You mentioned that you realized that already in your order book, how it was continuing and also especially the typical summer dip, do you realize that this year, it's perhaps very, yeah, a big one compared to last year one? And also, I think if we see, especially Asia and China in particular, it looks that you also were a little bit disappointed from the growth in the second half and also saying that perhaps growth coming not back to that level, what we have seen before. So, can you a little bit also elaborate on especially China, Asian situation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Norbert, thanks for the question. We don't see any different pattern right now with regard to the famous summer dip. We have this kind of seasonal development here in Europe but actually it's now much more balanced by other regions because our business in North America and Asia has grown and obviously these guys work on a different schedule, so to say.</p>
          <p>Yes, Asia and particularly China has been a little bit of a disappointment. We knew that Q4 was and would be weak and we expected that Q1 could still be, let's say, in a recovery mode and not a great quarter. But Q2 now continues on that path and actually, volumes Q2 compared to Q1, a slight increase but nothing to write on about. And this is a new development for us because apparently in Asia and in China, we have been in a growth mode. And we don't see that growth for the time being.</p>
          <p>Again, when I talk about flat development, for the next couple of months, this includes the regional development we see in China .In Asia currently, could there be an upside surprise? Yes, that's possible because the governments have obviously recognized that they need to do something and there were various stimulus measures already implemented. At the same time, we've also seen that people are very, very cautious with regard to inventory levels.</p>
          <p>I know that we have talked about this now for quite some time, and you might ask when do you see de-stocking over? How down can it go? But everything we have seen now is that again, people try to reduce their inventories. They order in smaller quantities, higher frequency which tells me, which tells me, if there is a pick-up in demand and economy turns around, there could be a typical surge in demand that we have seen in earlier times of uncertainty as well.</p>
          <p>So, all in all there's a high level of uncertainty right now and our crystal ball is probably not better than anybody else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we are moving on to Jaideep Pandya from Berenberg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning, gentlemen. My question is more on your downstream businesses. I mean for a couple of quarters now, you've said that you couldn't offset raw material prices, while some of your peers, depending on the business we pick, have in the meanwhile at least been in a situation where prices offset raw mats. So, is this a matter of concern for you? And I mean, what are you trying to do here, because especially in Performance Products and Functional Solutions are two areas where we hear this comment of prices not being able to offset raw material costs. So, if you can shed some light there. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Jaideep, this is Hans. I'll try. Raw materials in fact play an important role. What we've seen now quarter-over-quarter is basically an increase, which in part is currency-driven. That certainly has an impact on our business. You're referring specifically to Performance Products and to Functional Solutions. If you look there, we're down in the value chain. The prices there for raw materials do not compare necessarily to what you see up in the value chain. So, they do not compare to the ethylene price or the propylene price or the naphtha price. Look at something like titanium dioxide which we've seen increasing in price consistently. If you compare today's price, that is at <mark type="ph" /> &#x20AC;3.40 (31:38) per kilogram to the price that we had in the second quarter of last year where it was roughly &#x20AC;1 lower than where it is today. You can imagine what kind of an impact that has.</p>
          <p>Let me give you another example, that plays a role in the Functional Solutions area, which is the price of rare earth that we've seen at levels during the last 24 months, that range from below $10 per kilogram to roughly $150 per kilogram. So, significant swings there. And as I've said, further downstream, prices can be significantly different in their developments compared to what you're seeing upstream.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Chris Counihan from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning and thank you for taking my question. My question's more financial-related. Another fantastic cash results. It seems like growth CapEx isn't really taking a huge step up from here. Given the current environment, the limited forward order books, the limited customer confidence, does it make it more difficult to do a major acquisition from here? And maybe you could discuss some of the alternatives for using the balance sheet, including executing the buyback? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris. I think you're right, our cash flow was quite good in Q2. In terms of acquisitions, acquisitions in our case are not cash-driven. We don't get nervous because all of sudden we find, oh we have more money in the till. It's really about strategic fit and financial attractiveness.</p>
          <p>You have seen in the past this pattern, that every other year, BASF steps forward and come up with another medium-sized acquisition. I think it's too early to say something specific here, but when you look at our strategy which we have published November last year, this was very much about operational excellence, commercial excellence, R&amp;D innovations, sustainability.</p>
          <p>So we have a full plate how to improve BASF further on, and how to increase and improve our competitiveness. And we are not sitting here by any means, eager to do something just for the sake of acquiring company.</p>
          <p>If something would become available at an attractive price, we would be looking at it and then make up our mind. But it's not that we are nervous here and gee, let's do something about it. And yet we have other ways of dealing with excess cash and for that reason we initiated a new share buyback program. We got approval from our shareholders in May. It needs to be seen when to apply it. But in the past, I think it's fair to say that this program was very, very effective and on average, when you look at the pattern over 10 years, we bought back BASF shares for about &#x20AC;500 million to sometimes even &#x20AC;2 billion a year.</p>
          <p>But again, this is then, a decision which we will take when we have a little bit more visibility and that kind of visibility we don't have yet to the extent necessary, there is this high level of uncertainty I already talked about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would now like Neil Tyler from JPMorgan to ask his question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. A quick question on the asset devaluations, I wondered if you could talk a little bit more about those. You said you're going to allocate them across divisions later in the year, but specifically, the process through which you've gone to reach those conclusions, as to which asset have been devalued and whether or not we need to consider any sort of material impact on things like depreciation going forward from here. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Neil. This is Hans. I'm taking that question. First of all, the one asset impairment that we've done in the course of Q2, which is one for a Norwegian oil field in which we have a 10% activity of &#x20AC;80 million, that is already fully allocated to the Oil &amp; Gas segment. We then have roughly &#x20AC;100 million that is related to a variety of restructuring and environmental remediation measures in the second quarter of this year which then, during the course of the year, will be allocated to the respective divisions. Will that have an impact on depreciation? I'd say, in the grand scheme of things, a relatively small amount as a result of that and nothing that's really &#x2013; that we need really to worry about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. So there wasn't a specific sort of watershed moment when you decided that market conditions have triggered any of these, any of the &#x2013; within the &#x20AC;100 million that you referred to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, if that question goes to goodwill that we have on our books, we run the respective tests. And as I said, there's nothing to worry about. These are really specific, individual situation in the entire system where we've taken the decision, as I said, for restructuring and remediation purposes, to make the reserve of &#x20AC;100 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Lutz Gr&#xFC;ten from Commerzbank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks, good morning. Just one question, to get a bit of feeling on the current trading situation here. On Chemicals, you've reported volumes being down 14% in the second quarter. Could we get an adjusted number here, adjusted for the propylene swap, and also adjusted for the maintenance shutdown in Port Arthur? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Hans. The impact adjusted in the Chemicals segment from the swap as well as the turnaround of the cracker is in the order of magnitude of 6% to 7%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And now we move to Paul Walsh from Morgan Stanley. Good morning, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, Hans and Maggie. From my side, to what degree did the maintenance shutdowns depress operating profit in the Chemicals and Plastics business in the second quarter? I wonder if you could put some numbers around that with Port Arthur and Ludwigshafen down? And are there any further maintenance turnarounds planned for rest of the year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul, the number is about a high two-digit million number. We will have additional turnarounds in the second half, but since we always have turnarounds in every half of every year, I don't think this has any material impact on the year-over-year comparison 2012-2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andreas Heine from Barclays. Good morning, Andreas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. One question on the price in raw material trend. We read now for several quarters that it is difficult to pass on the raw material prices. Now it seems that raw material prices are at least flattening. Looking to the second half of this year, do you see a closing or still a widening of the gap between your price trend and your raw material cost increases or stabilization there? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, Andreas. Welcome back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good to see you on a call again.</p>
          <p>Prices, I mean, we have made a claim that we push up prices as fast as we can and that's the reality. We never said that it is a 100% perfect solution. So, what we have seen over the last couple of quarters is a small margin squeeze in almost all businesses. I think that's quite natural if you have these steeply increasing raw material cost, and overall, also this very, very high volatility.</p>
          <p>The name of the game now is, since raw materials have softened a little bit, to maintain, if not widen margin business. Obviously <mark type="indiscernible" /> (40:13) as our customers. And I referred already to the, let's say, cautious behavior with regard to placing orders. But obviously, that's our goal now to widen margins.</p>
          <p>It's too early to say to what extent we will be successful. This is obviously driven by competitive pressure in our various markets. And frankly, it doesn't help that in some markets demand is relatively weak.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is coming from Christian Faitz from Macquarie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, gentlemen. Just a quick question on oil. I remember that still under the Gaddafi regime, you had entered into discussions with the Libyan government regarding more favorable tax conditions. Is there any chance that the new government is open for talks for contract renegotiation? Any update on that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Hans. Yeah, as you correctly recall, we had discussed with the National Oil Corporation, a change there in the contract regime.</p>
          <p>Negotiated contracts are basically on the table, but at this point in time, I don't see any imminent movement in that direction. The key focus of the National Oil Corporation at this point in time is really get production volumes up, get exports up. There's not much talk about adjusting contract conditions at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew Benson from Citi is our next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you very much. Just carrying on from James's question, really. In terms of the current trading environment for the industrial chemical divisions, you cited both de-stocking because of the oil price coming back, as well as change in the demand picture and a change in the ordering patterns. I presume that it came from June.</p>
          <p>Can you just give a little bit more detail and try to give your best guess, if you disaggregate the de-stocking effects from any underlying weakening in demand, where you think we are. Because obviously that's got an &#x2013; if the bulk of it's de-stocking, then that won't go on forever. Just to try get a bit more flavor of how you think the weakness that is evolving is structural or temporary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, I think this is a core question, and it's extremely difficult for us to answer that particular question. And because we &#x2013; as I alluded to, we very often don't get the total visibility. Sometimes our customers don't know either what's going to happen in their market. Sometimes they don't want to tell us exactly what they plan to do, just to keep us on the edge, so to say.</p>
          <p>We would expect that de-stocking has come to a level now where it's very, very difficult to continue doing that because this has been going on now for quite some time. People are again extremely cautious due to the uncertain times.</p>
          <p>But I don't have any precise data, and I know it's a little bit frustrating. I'd like to give you those, but we simply don't have them. We cannot really differentiate between what is underlying demand pattern and what is a de-stocking effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you would have thought, though, that the de-stocking component of any demand weakness pretty much can't continue now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is our assumption, and it frankly has been our assumption for quite some time. But as I said, I think it has now come to a level where people are really bare-bone, and would have to come back in a quite dramatic way, if all of a sudden a demand in their customer industries or underlying served markets surges all of a sudden.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Richard Logan, Goldman Sachs. Good morning, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning and thanks for taking my questions. Yeah, with regards to the STEP program, I wondered how much saving you have made so far during the first half. And also, if there's scope to bring forward some of the cost savings, if the situation deteriorates further in terms of the economic environment? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On STEP, as you know, we announced STEP late in the fourth quarter of the year 2011. It's a program under which we want to see an annual contribution from 2015 going forward of &#x20AC;1 billion.</p>
          <p>There is actually &#x2013; with respect to STEP, there are, let's say, minor effects that we will have in the year 2012. You may recall that we have the NEXT program. And in NEXT, we said by the end of last year, we were at an impact of &#x2013; positive impact of &#x20AC;800 million, increasing to &#x20AC;1 billion in the year 2012. As a result of that. There's roughly &#x20AC;200 million coming from NEXT, which will then be sort of closed as a program, and then STEP will follow. And if you look at the cost that you have at the beginning for a project like that, and the return typically low in the beginning and then increasing towards the end of the program.</p>
          <p>Do we accelerate any activities under the STEP program? No, not at this point in time. As I've said, it's roughly 500 different measures that we intend to implement over time in all different areas of the business, in all different regions that BASF covers.</p>
          <p>But what we do is &#x2013; and I would put that in the category of good housekeeping &#x2013; obviously, in times of higher uncertainty, what you do is you watch the cost that you can manage closely. And this is exactly what we're doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question now comes from Ronald Koehler from MainFirst.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. I have a question on currency effects. Obviously, you guide for 1% change, &#x20AC;40 million EBIT effect. There might be something coming up in the future, at least. So my question is a bit two-fold. How much did you already recognize from the currency effects on the EBIT line, or was it mainly hedged? And let's say, when will your hedging policy allow to have a bigger impact on the bottom line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ronald, as you know, yes, we are providing the figures on U.S. dollar-euro change, the currency effect that we have. Currently, on the sales level, it's roughly 5% in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Yes, we do hedge our planned sales as well as our book sales, roughly out for one year.</p>
          <p>Will there be a positive impact on EBIT as a result of, in particular, a stronger U.S. dollar? Yes, there will be. Can I quantify that at this point in time? No, I cannot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to clarify, you didn't have any positive effects so far on the EBIT line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the EBIT line, if so, only minor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question now comes from Peter Clark from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Thank you. It seems like there's a belief de-stocking's going to come to an end here, and that clearly helps your guidance for the chemical volumes. H2 being similar to H1 or the same as H1.</p>
          <p>I'm just wondering regionally, within that guidance &#x2013; because obviously, Asia will be important in the de-stocking story, but clearly you're making it &#x2013; obviously, it's still very soggy. Europe probably deteriorating, I would have thought. I don't know whether seasonality kicks in here, whether it's in the guidance or not. And then North America, you have the maintenance shutdown, but again there's a risk of something happening by the end of the year.</p>
          <p>So I just want, regionally, in terms of the volume guidance, how it all squares. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's very hard to say if we have a different regional pattern with regard to demand right now. Europe is slow and weak. Asia has slowed down quite severely.</p>
          <p>The only difference we see is in the U.S. where demand is still, I would say, growing nicely. Although the expectations they have there also changed. When you ask people today in the United States what they see compared to what they saw three or four months ago, they will probably say we are much more cautious today. And you already alluded to the fiscal cliff later this year, and nobody knows what's going to happen after the November elections.</p>
          <p>So no major difference. Actually the one, I would say, brightest spot right now is the U.S. where we had &#x2013; and I think Hans explained this &#x2013; where we had the effect of the turnaround, which was a big bite out of our sales and earnings in Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so actually you're pointing to the &#x2013; I mean, to me it seems like the guidance is pretty challenging. It does rely heavily on the de-stocking ending.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, that's up to you to make that assessment, whether it's challenging or not. We're basically saying we see no indication for a pick-up of demand compared to the situation we have seen over the last couple of months. I mean, that is essentially what we have been saying here.</p>
          <p>And with respect to visibility, we therefore say that, okay, this indicates that most probably, the second half will be kind of flat compared to the first half.</p>
          <p>We do have &#x2013; yes, we do have seasonal effect for instance in Ag. Less so in Chemicals. But we also have to keep in mind that the fourth quarter of last year was a pretty tremendous weakening in the Chemicals business as well, and it's not very likely that this is going to repeat itself into the fourth quarter of 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So this brings us to Jeremy Redenius from Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Thanks for taking my question. I noticed some very large volume growth in Ag Solutions, and I just wanted to check, is your perception you're gaining share, or are you growing with your markets? And also is your view that you're pricing in line with what your competitors are doing? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeremy, pricing is good. Actually, we are very satisfied with regard to the development.</p>
          <p>The market share, too early to say, because we haven't seen all the data. Couple of competitors already came out.</p>
          <p>Our volume development is based on a couple of new, innovative active ingredients and some good, new formulation. So we have a good underlying business here. But I cannot answer you the question whether this is a market share gain or not. It feels a little bit like it could be, but again, I'm very cautious to make that assessment at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we come to Thomas Gilbert from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Question around the battery business. You've done a lot of bolt-on technology acquisitions, electrolytes, membrane separators, cathode materials, licensing agreements. What seems to be missing is anode materials, as long as you tell me you don't have that. Are you or is the package ready now to put a lot of capital behind it? So that's the first part of the question.</p>
          <p>The second part of the question is, is this new business unit loss-making in a sense that it dilutes the Functional Solutions margins in a way that an analyst would notice, i.e., is it meaningful, the run rate of the losses and when do you expect it to break even? And of course, will there be acquisitions in this area still?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Thomas, this is Hans. A number of questions, I'll try to take them one by one. As you're correctly stating, we've made a number of acquisitions in the first half of this year, the Evonik acquisition, the Novolyte acquisition, acquired electrolyte business from Merck. On top of that, a participation in Sion Power, so a lot of activity happening there, you're mentioning rightfully.</p>
          <p>We have no anode activities. We're focusing at this point in time on cathode material. We're building a plant there in Elyria, Ohio which will start up in the fourth quarter of this year. Could there be further activities in that field? Yes, certainly there could be. Do we want to become a self-producer or a better reproducer? That is clearly not within our strategy.</p>
          <p>You then asked, with respect to the losses from the battery materials business and is that anything that is noteworthy from an analyst perspective? It is a single-digit figure in the quarter. We expect that to continue for quite some while because we're building a business, we're starting a business up here. We will have meaningful sales from our cathode materials plant in Elyria, only from the beginning of 2013 on, and I think that should give you the picture.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Jean de Watteville from Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Good morning, everyone. Jean de Watteville. Pretty basic question, I'm sorry. Just a clarification again on the volume guidance.</p>
          <p>As far as I'm concerned, the volume guidance sequential basis, H2 versus H1, is kind of new because of &#x2013; or rather unusual because of the obvious seasonality factor and particularly with the effect of de-stocking and so on. Can you &#x2013; the way I understand it and please correct me, is that what you're basically telling us is that on a seasonally-adjusted basis, you don't see a change of environment. Can you please confirm that?</p>
          <p>And just to be helpful to us, can you tell us what stable volumes would mean in terms of year-on-year volume growth in the second half? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's not completely new that we give some kind of sequential indications. We have done that before, especially in very volatile times and it's sometimes not very meaningful and not very helpful to have this year-over-year comparisons. And just to reiterate again that we confirmed our outlook to make this quite clear. Change of environment, you wanted to have a confirmation. Yeah, that's what we see. We don't see a change of environment for the time being. This could still lead to a volume gain over last year. If we continue to have a reasonably good business in Q4, because you know that Q4 of 2011 was very weak, even weaker than normally because there was a lot of de-stocking going on. I hope this clarifies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it does. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The next one is Laurent Favre from Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, and thank you for taking my question on Oil &amp; Gas in Libya. I think you were saying that you've managed to temporarily increase the market share for the export facilities and which is why you managed to produce a bit more than what you were thinking three months ago. What is &#x2013; or what should be our assumptions for the second half on this? Do you think that you will have to go back to the first quarter run rates or do you think that what you managed to do in the second quarter can be maintained, if not be increased? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Laurent, this is Hans. As I said in Q2, we were lucky we got more capacity in the export pipeline than what we had actually expected, so we were able to produce 80,000 barrels per day. Our expectation is that we will be able to produce, on average, 75,000 barrels per day in the second half of the year. And that always with a proviso, our field can produce up to 100,000, but we are limited by the capacity of the pipeline and the terminals. There's a lot of work that's being done on them, but so far so good. And we are working with 75,000 on average per day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, ladies and gentlemen, we are coming down to our last three questions. The first one is coming from Peter Spengler from DZ Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thank you for taking my questions. Actually most has been answered already. But regarding the other segments, so does the current or the Q2 fully reflect the new structure without styrenics and fertilizer business, especially in the EBIT before special items, you booked there &#x20AC;13 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, I used to be the specialist for Others. I'll pass this on to Hans and he will <mark type="indiscernible" /> (59:12) question now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Peter, happy to answer that question. When you look into the Q2 figures, you have in Other, one significant positive item and that is actually a valuation of our long-term incentive program which, as a result of share price development in this quarter, contributed positively. Other than that, Other reflects the current status of Other, let me put it this way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, now we are moving on to Nadeshda Demidova from equinet. Hello, Nadeshda.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, I have a follow-up question on Plastics. For polyurethanes in Q2, if you exclude the maintenance cost, the implemented price increase sufficient to compensate increased raw material prices. And after two quarters of year-on-year lower earnings in polyurethanes, how realistic is year-on-year increase in earnings for polyurethanes and for Plastics as a whole in 2012, as it was targeted by you at the beginning of this financial year? Are you still optimistic probably due to still strong demand from the automotive sector?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Polyurethanes, as you know, it's an interesting and good business for BASF. Underlying demand essentially is good. And you mentioned automotive, which is a very important customer industry, what we have seen over the last couple of quarters is increased supply actually, especially in the emerging markets and this drove down margins in some areas and we have seen different developments in different businesses.</p>
          <p>What I can say, I mean we don't go here in to too much detail, but what I can say is that our strategy, which we started late in 2011 to keep up prices, again value before volume, and to be very, very cognizant of this relationship between volumes and prices and margins, has worked quite well. We lost volume actually in Q1 in polyurethanes because we had pushed up our prices where they stuck to a very high degree. Still, there's a difference between TDI and MDI, and MDI is relatively weak for the time being.</p>
          <p>Again, this is very much supply-driven and less a demand issue. And we have seen this obviously before, because the new capacity comes on stream, this is almost a big chunk of material which needs to be absorbed by the market then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but your prices are still sufficient to compensate higher <mark type="ph" /> Vincent (01:02:04) prices and so on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't really comment on specific margins, I mean for specific products, that would lead us probably into the wrong direction. We are trying very hard to bring up prices whenever possible, let's put it that way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the final question is from Martin Evans from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I think this is the last question. I'll try not to be sort of too negative. But I just want to ask about this Care Chemicals performance with reference, I guess, to your expectations at the time, the Cognis acquisition because &#x2013; are you disappointed at all so far, to have to talk about earnings significantly below the previous level and lower sales and margins when, I guess, one of the major competitors in this field, Croda, appear this week to have reported exactly the opposite, in other words, higher margins and higher volumes, and so on. Is there an issue of market share loss temporarily from your perspective or does this simply relate to the integration process and thus, you would expect Care Chemicals to rebound quite strongly? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Martin, I'm not sure if you listened the first question which was exactly about Care Chemicals, and I guess, a pretty lengthy answer. What has happened there with regard to raw material costs, lauric oil, steep increase in 2011 driving up prices but also our margins. And then the more cautious customer behavior in 2012, and then the prices for raw material coming down, leading to even more cautious customer behavior and our strategy, value before volume.</p>
          <p>I'm not sure about these comparisons. We have heard this story before. We couldn't find a single case where we lost and we checked into this in a very detailed way. We couldn't find a single case where we lost market share. Maybe we were just not competing with the same products here. What we saw is basically a subtle weakness in our business for surfactants and fatty alcohols, which by definition, by the way, are not real specialties. These are pretty commoditized products. They go by the price per pound or gallon, essentially.</p>
          <p>With regards to our expectations, we were frankly positively surprised in 2011 by the tremendous development of the Care Chemicals business when volumes and margins took off in a very nice way, which was much ways above our business plan, which we had developed before we made the acquisition of Cognis. Now it has come down a little bit compared with a very good year 2011. It's still at a level which is very good and actually below what we had expected for 2012, to happen back in 2010.</p>
          <p>Having said that, that doesn't mean that we are completely satisfied with this development, don't get me wrong here. We're working very hard to look into further opportunities to create synergies and cost savings. And we are certainly also looking at individual markets and try to find out how to compete even better in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>This is an ongoing exercise. I think, all in all, the team has done an excellent job integrating Cognis work and then running the business and we are very satisfied with the results overall. Nevertheless, from time to time...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...we have a little bit of a blip that happens.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="25" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So, ladies and gentlemen, this brings us now to the end of our conference call. I would like to thank Kurt Bock and Hans-Ulrich Engel. And we will also inform you that we will report next time on our quarterly results and this is our third quarter on October 25, 2012.</p>
          <p>At this point, I would also like to use the occasion to invite you again to our Automotive Investor Day which will take place on September 5 in London. Kurt Bock and our board member, Wayne Smith will basically outline to you the importance of the automotive industry to BASF, our cross-divisional customer approach and our wide-ranging innovation capabilities. So, we are very much looking forward to welcoming you at this event. The registration page will go online on Monday of next week, so you can all please sign up.</p>
          <p>And yeah, Kurt just reminds me, I'm happy to announce that we will provide you, the reading time is not too long, in the meantime, with our factbook, mid of August, our factbook will be online as a PDF version and you will get a final hard copy printout at our Automotive Investor Day and I hope it will help you in your everyday analysis of BASF.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Which by the way, is a great read if you go on a summer vacation on the beach. It's the perfect reading material.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I can attest that it's true. Thank you for joining us in the call this morning. Should you have any further questions, please do not hesitate to call the Investor Relations team and we'll be very happy to help you with any further open questions that you may have. So, goodbye and hope to see you soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>