<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1365948" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>809</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Magdalena Moll, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Dr. J&#xFC;rgen Hambrecht, Chairman of the Board of Executive Directors</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Dr. Kurt Bock, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Rhian Tucker</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Norbert Barth</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Hans-Ulrich Engel</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Christian Faitz</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">James Knight</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Thomas Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Lutz Gr&#xFC;ten</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Oliver Schwarz</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Sophie Jourdier</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Peter Spengler</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Ronald K&#xF6;hler</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Andreas Heine</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Annett Weber</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Tim Jones</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Martin Evans</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Martin R&#xF6;diger</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Harald Gruber</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst">Jochen Schlachter</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst">Jeremy Redenius</participant>
      <participant id="22" type="analyst">Nobert Barth</participant>
      <participant id="23" type="analyst">Laurent Favre</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the BASF 2010 Annual Results Conference here in Ludwigshafen. At the same time, I would also welcome all of those who are watching the web cast or are listening in by conference call.</p>
          <p>BASF, as you have seen this morning, ladies and gentlemen, presents itself in excellent shape. And the Group generated record results in 2010 and is also very optimistic for 2011. This means that BASF aims to significantly exceed the record levels of sales and earnings that we achieved in 2010.</p>
          <p>With me this afternoon at this conference are J&#xFC;rgen Hambrecht, our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer; Kurt Bock, our Chief Financial Officer; and Hans-Ulrich Engel, Member of the Board, and amongst many other responsibilities, he is responsible for Oil and Gas.</p>
          <p>J&#xFC;rgen will start off the presentation talking about the performance of BASF in the year 2010, the successful implementation of our profitable growth strategy, and the progress we made in achieving our strategic objectives.</p>
          <p>Subsequently, Kurt will review the 2010 financial results. And then the conclusion will be made by J&#xFC;rgen again with the outlook for 2011. Afterwards all three gentlemen will be happy and available to take your questions.</p>
          <p>Now let me remind you that, as I said, we are webcasting this event. We posted for you the charts as well as the press documents on our website basf.com/share. I also wanted to ask you to please switch off your mobiles and your BlackBerries because they could cause some problems with our microphone system.</p>
          <p>And finally, I would like to draw your attention to our disclaimer which you see here on the chart. So with this, I would already like to hand over to J&#xFC;rgen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you that you are joining us this afternoon at our headquarters here in Ludwigshafen. Some of you are still missing, because the snowfall obviously in Frankfurt Airport, what I'm hearing, I am not sure. I have not seen snow here, but might be in Frankfurt. And some of you have come from Frankfurt, so I'm wondering maybe the car is easier.</p>
          <p>Now let me start. The title of our presentation today puts it in a nutshell. BASF is in an excellent shape. We hit record sales of almost &#x20AC;64 billion, up 26% compared to 2009. EBITDA at &#x20AC;11.1 billion and EBIT before special items at &#x20AC;8.1 billion, reached record levels each.</p>
          <p>The EBITDA margin in 2010 climbed to 17.4% and is well on track to reach the EBITDA margin targeted, and you know about this, 18% by 2012. Besides the strong recovery of the world economy, the excellent business performance in 2010 is also attributable to our strict cost reduction efforts. Our efficiency program NEXT is running at full speed and had contributed about &#x20AC;600 million to earnings by end of 2010.</p>
          <p>We increased net income by 223% to &#x20AC;4.6 billion and reached an adjusted EPS of &#x20AC;5.73. In 2011 we will continue on our path for profitable growth and strive to significantly exceed the record earnings level of 2010 based on the assumption, however, that operations in Libya will be restarted in a reasonably short period of time.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter has been supported by a strong performance over almost all business. I will briefly highlight a few points. Kurt will give you more details on the business development of these segments later.</p>
          <p>Sales in Q4 increased by 25% to &#x20AC;16.4 billion compared to last year's quarter. EBITDA on record level in the fourth quarter of &#x20AC;2.7 billion. And despite one-off costs of more than &#x20AC;200 million not recurring in 2011, EBIT before special items increased by 19% to &#x20AC;1.8 billion.</p>
          <p>However, significantly higher fixed costs were caused by the long-term incentive plan and an extra employee bonus for the extraordinary management of the crisis during the last two years. In addition, we used the strong margin momentum into 2011 to intensify cleanup work towards year-end and by accelerating maintenance, restructuring and nonrecurring items.</p>
          <p>Net income climbed to &#x20AC;1.1 billion, up 142%, and adjusted earnings per share were at &#x20AC;1.39, &#x20AC;0.33 higher than in Q4 2009.</p>
          <p>As you know, shareholder return is of utmost importance to us. The board proposed this morning to pay out a dividend of &#x20AC;2.20 per share, an increase of &#x20AC;0.50. This reflects an attractive dividend yield of 3.7% based on the share price at end of 2010.</p>
          <p>Moreover, BASF is still a very consistent, long-term value for its shareholders. Over the past 10 years the average annual return on BASF's stock was almost 14%, clearly outperforming the German and the European stock markets, as well as MSCI World/Chemicals Index.</p>
          <p>2010 was a record year for BASF due to our operational excellence, the successful execution of our long-term value-creating strategy, and the extraordinary performance of the entire BASF team. Many thanks to all of the employees I want to say this year because, let me say, starting 2008 leading towards the end of 2010 was super excellent performance, which I have to say was the best experience in my lifetime in BASF.</p>
          <p>Looking into the future, I am confident that we are well positioned for further solid profitable growth. As you know, our growth strategy builds on three pillars. We have leading positions in growth industries in emerging markets, and we certainly will strengthen these into the future.</p>
          <p>We will continue with our active portfolio management, driving the portfolio even closer to the end customers. And we will grow organically via numerous product and systems innovation, as well as innovations out of our mega trend work. Overall, our target is to outperform global chemical production growth by at least 2 percentage points per annum and achieve an EBITDA margin of 18% by 2012.</p>
          <p>As already shown in the past, we are consistently delivering on this promise. On the next slides, I will highlight important developments for each of these three pillars. And please allow me to take a little bit more time than usual on this three pillars.</p>
          <p>First pillar, leading positions in growth industries and emerging markets. Our strong presence in emerging markets will further contribute to BASF's cause. And we use the term emerging markets as defined by Dow Jones.</p>
          <p>We almost doubled our sales in emerging markets in absolute terms during the last five years to &#x20AC;14.5 billion, which is about 27% of our total sales in 2010, excluding oil and gas, which is very much, more than 95%, based on Europe.</p>
          <p>We will further spur organic growth in these countries by increasing our sales forces, strengthening regional R&amp;D, specific focus on D, and investing in new production capacities. From 2005 to 2010 investments in emerging markets amounted to &#x20AC;3 billion. From 2011 to 2015 we will invest further &#x20AC;2.6 billion in new capacities.</p>
          <p>Special focus of our growth strategy will be in Asia Pacific, as almost two-thirds of future growth in the chemical industry will come from this region. Between 2005 and 2010, we increased our sales on average by 14%, 3.5 percentage points more than the market average. In 2010, we achieved sales of &#x20AC;12.5 billion, well above the pre-crisis level, generating already roughly a quarter of BASF Group sales, excluding oil and gas, in Asia Pacific.</p>
          <p>Over the years we have significantly increased profit contribution out of Asia. In 2010, we reached an EBITDA margin of 14% in this region, based on about 60% local manufacturing content. The rest comes out &#x2013; basically out of Europe.</p>
          <p>In our strategy 2020, we aim to grow sales on average 2 percentage points faster than the chemical market by first developing and marketing innovations in Asia for Asia. It means R&amp;D spending. Investing &#x20AC;2.3 billion over the next five years to generate 70% of our sales through local production and I don't need to go into the projects, which you are aware of, and by strengthening market focus through industry and customer target groups. By 2020 we project sales of more than &#x20AC;20 billion and substantially higher earnings contribution from this region.</p>
          <p>Second pillar of our growth strategy is our proactive portfolio optimization. Here are two examples. After Ciba, Cognis is now our first step in moving our portfolio closer to end customers. In December last year, we successfully closed the acquisition of Cognis. Cognis performed very well in 2010. On a pro forma basis, Cognis would have contributed sales of about &#x20AC;3 billion and EBITDA of &#x20AC;550 million and an EBITDA margin of approximately 18%.</p>
          <p>Given the attractive enterprise value of &#x20AC;3.1 billion at closing, we are confident that this acquisition will generate substantial value right very early on. Currently we are fully on track with the integration process. At the end of March we will be able to give you a detailed overview of the planned integration process, the cost and the substantial top line synergies, as well as cost synergies as I said in March, not today. We still have to inform our people beforehand.</p>
          <p>With Cognis we have significantly improved our market position in many attractive businesses, especially in personal care, as shown in this chart. As a leading supplier in these markets, we will be able to define market standards in close cooperation with our customers. We will operate more efficiently and more effectively, and finally reach more customers all over the world, generating top line growth and synergies.</p>
          <p>Secondly, Styrolution. At the end of November 2000, we announced the plan to form this 50-50 joint venture with INEOS. The new company will be the number one globally in Styrenics. The company will have sales of about &#x20AC;5 billion and more than 3,000 employees. The joint venture will offer the broadest product portfolio and will have a strong footprint in all major regions.</p>
          <p>The carve-out of BASF Styrenics activities into separate legal entities was already completed as of January 2011. The establishment of the planned joint venture, which is subject to approval by the appropriate antitrust authorities, is expected in the second half of 2011. And last, but not least, Styrolution represents the first step in our value-creating divestiture process.</p>
          <p>Our active portfolio management is clearly paying off, as demonstrated by the EBITDA development over the last 10 years. As you can see here, EBITDA, excluding others reached &#x20AC;11.7 billion in 2010, up almost 50% compared to the full-year figure 2009, clearly above the pre-crisis levels, and well above the crisis level of 2001. We achieved this excellent results due to the continuous optimization of our portfolio, as well as our sustained and relentless efforts to increase operational excellence and to reduce costs. Today we are clearly on a new level of performance with substantially reduced earnings volatility, but this is a topic we have talked for length with each other.</p>
          <p>Innovation is the third pillar, an important cornerstone for the continued, profitable growth of BASF Corp. And here I am not talking about abstract ideas in the lab. It's all about marketable solutions, which meet the needs of our customers today and tomorrow. Let me just take one example out of many others, nine, on the right-hand side, Xemium, a product of our Agricultural Solutions segment.</p>
          <p>You remember maybe a year ago I talked about Kixor, a new herbicide which was successfully launched in 2010, and continues to thrive with unprecedented success. Today I would like to introduce to you a new product that nicely complements our strong fungicide portfolio, Xemium, a next-generation carboxamide with blockbuster potential.</p>
          <p>As a pioneer in this product last year we are about to launch a new carboxamide, which can be used for all fungicide segments. We will help our customers with Xemium-based products for field crops, and as well also offer products for specialty crops such as vegetables and foods. Xemium products can be marketed to a wide customer base due to its broad range of application and efficient and long-lasting disease control.</p>
          <p>The data submission process is underway, and we expect regulatory approval in time for market launch from 2012 onwards. Xemium will be a global active ingredient, which we plan to gradually introduce in more than 50 countries and more than 100 crops. Thus we are optimistic that Xemium, again, will play out its blockbuster potential and generate peak sales in excess of &#x20AC;200 million.</p>
          <p>So innovation, we see significant growth and value creation potential. Today, we value our innovation pipeline with net present value of &#x20AC;21 billion. And I don't need to talk about what means net present value here. The biggest value contribution stems from R&amp;D projects in Agricultural Solutions, Performance Products and corporate research, especially planned biotechnologies. Thanks to rigorous R&amp;D controlling, we generate a high success rate. The expected commercial value of our pipeline is about 50% of NPV.</p>
          <p>In 2010 sales with new products on the market for five years or less exceeded our target of &#x20AC;6 billion by 2015. We target annual sales of about &#x20AC;8 billion from product innovations.</p>
          <p>And now I will hand over to Kurt who will provide more details with regard to Q4 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thanks, J&#xFC;rgen, and also good afternoon from my side, ladies and gentlemen. As J&#xFC;rgen already mentioned, 2010 was a record year for BASF Group. And also in the fourth quarter, we posted new record numbers. At &#x20AC;16.4 billion sales reached a record level for fourth quarter, and we are up 25% versus the fourth quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Volumes dropped 4%. Volumes excluding oil and gas grew by 8%. We continued to raise prices, also compared with the third quarter of 2010, in order to protect our margins in view of rising feedstock costs.</p>
          <p>EBIT before special items was the second highest ever in the fourth quarter. It was broadened, as already mentioned, by several one-off costs at year-end due to intensified maintenance, accelerated restructuring and other nonrecurring items.</p>
          <p>Significantly higher fixed cost has been caused by our long-term incentive plan and a special employee bonus, which J&#xFC;rgen already mentioned. On top, harsh weather conditions towards the year-end impacted all construction-related businesses.</p>
          <p>Net income at &#x20AC;1.1 billion is a new record for fourth quarter. It was partly due to a tax rate well below the annual average, given tax credits in Asia, tax refunds and deferred tax income. Adjusted EPS were &#x20AC;1.39, up &#x20AC;0.31 compared to Q4 2009.</p>
          <p>On the next slide I will highlight the financial development in the fourth quarter in more detail. After many unusual quarters due to the crisis, seasonality is now dominating the development in most businesses once again. Therefore, I will mainly focus on the comparison to the fourth quarter of 2010, also fourth quarter 2010 with previous year's fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>First, Chemicals. In our Chemicals segment increases in volumes and prices, as well as positive currency effects, led to strong sales growth in all divisions. EBIT before special items rose significantly compared with the fourth quarter of 2009. This was due to higher capacity utilization, as well as increased margins for basic products. Demand also remained strong toward the end of the year, but we incurred one-off items, especially for accelerated maintenance.</p>
          <p>Inorganics sales grew compared with the previous fourth-quarter mainly as a result of higher volumes and prices. The business environment was favorable, particularly in the electronic, chemicals and inorganic salt businesses. Earnings reached the level of the fourth quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>In Petrochemicals demand rose for all products. Prices rose considerably as higher raw material costs were passed on. This contributed to the strong sales growth. There continued to be some supply bottlenecks, particularly for acrylic acid, solvents and plasticizers.</p>
          <p>Following an improved availability of cracker products in the third quarter in Asia and North America, supplies also increased in Europe. Thanks to high demand, our plans are operating at high capacity utilization rate. Earnings significantly surpassed the level of the previous fourth-quarter.</p>
          <p>Sales in Intermediates improved considerably year-on-year, thanks to higher demand and prices. Our capacities are fully utilized for product in the butanediol value-adding chain polyalcohols and numerous amines. The increases in volumes were a major factor in our strong earnings growth.</p>
          <p>Now to Plastics. In Plastics demand for our products continued to be very high. Sales grew substantially compared with the previous fourth quarter. We were able to pass on higher raw material costs to customers, particularly in Performance Polymers.</p>
          <p>Positive currency effects contributed to sales growth. However, our business with customers from the construction sector weakened due to harsh weather conditions. Thanks to higher volumes, and despite higher feedstock costs, income from operations before special items improved compared to previous year.</p>
          <p>In Performance Polymers the positive trend continued into the fourth quarter; however, we saw a significant decline in demand for foams for the construction industry. Sales growth was driven by strong volumes, price increases resulting from higher raw material costs and positive currency effects. Despite higher expenses resulting from plant shutdowns, earnings increased substantially.</p>
          <p>While prices remained stable, sales in Polyurethanes rose mainly due to increasing volume and positive currency effects. Sales volumes increased in all business areas, in particular demand for specialties as TPU and Cellasto were good.</p>
          <p>Higher raw material costs, particularly for benzene, negatively impacted our margins and earnings, which were below the level of the fourth quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Now I'm coming to Performance Products. All divisions in this segment posted a rise in sales thanks to higher volumes, positive currency effects or increased prices. Additional sales growth of 6% resulted from the inclusion of the Cognis business as of December 9.</p>
          <p>We saw a bit of seasonal slowdown, but the business environment remained favorable overall, with strong momentum in all product lines.</p>
          <p>In Q4 earnings were up more than 40% compared with the previous year, but lower than in the third quarter of 2010. Towards the end of 2010 we intensified our restructuring measures, accelerated some maintenance projects, and incurred higher cost for employee bonuses.</p>
          <p>To cope with higher raw material prices, we continued to raise our sales prices. Finally, synergies from the Ciba integration were realized as planned and contributed positively to earnings.</p>
          <p>Special charges of &#x20AC;117 million resulted primarily from the Cognis acquisition and accelerated salary restructuring in the paper chemicals business.</p>
          <p>In January and February 2011, we have seen strong sales and earnings momentum. Looking ahead to the first quarter of 2011, we are confident to top the level of earnings of the strong first quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>In dispersions and pigments, we posted significant sales growth, thanks to the ongoing high demand for our products. Higher raw material costs could not yet be fully offset by price increases. Furthermore, earnings were negatively impacted by integration and restructuring measures. Moreover, earnings decreased compared to the third quarter of 2010 due to seasonal effects in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Sales in Care Chemicals increased substantially, thanks to a continued favorable business environment, as well as the acquisition of Cognis. Demand for our hygiene products, as well as detergents and cleaners, was at levels not seen before.</p>
          <p>Earnings were well above the level of the fourth-quarter of 2009, but below the previous quarter due to seasonal effects. Special charges were primarily related to an inventory step-up following the Cognis acquisition.</p>
          <p>In Nutrition and Health, which is a new division, as you know, sales were higher than in the fourth quarter of 2009. Strong demand and the inclusion of the acquired Cognis businesses contributed to the increase in sales. Earnings did not match the excellent level of 2009 due to higher raw material costs and higher fixed costs mainly due to the bonus packages. Special charges were related to the Cognis inventory step-up.</p>
          <p>In paper chemicals volume were below the level of the fourth quarter of 2009. Higher raw material costs could be largely offset by price increases. Earnings improved compared with the fourth quarter of the previous year. In addition, we continued with our restructuring efforts. Following the divestiture of the European starch business, we announced the closure of our production of optical brighteners in Grenzach in Germany planned for 2011.</p>
          <p>Volumes and sales rose in Performance Chemicals. Demand was critically dynamic from the automotive and the plastics processing industries, especially for our plastic additives, a business, which we largely acquired from Ciba, as you know. Earnings were above &#x2013; far above the level of the previous fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Now I am coming to Functional Solutions. Volumes in Functional Solutions were significantly higher than the same quarter of 2009, reflecting the global recovery of our automotive customers. Demand from the construction industry increased slightly, primarily owing to the robust building activity in Asia. Nevertheless, harsh weather conditions, as mentioned before, towards the end had a strong negative impact on our Construction Chemicals business. The price increase of 10% also reflects higher precious metals prices.</p>
          <p>EBIT before special items was lower than in the fourth quarter of 2009, and much lower, as you notice, compared to Q3. As mentioned before, higher bonuses, accelerated maintenance, as well as higher raw material costs contributed to this. In addition, precious metals trading generated lower earnings.</p>
          <p>After the holiday slowdown, we started into 2011 with very good momentum. And for Q1, again, we expect to exceed the earnings level of the first quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>Now to the individual divisions. Catalysts sales increased substantially mainly due to higher sales volumes of mobile emission catalysts and also chemical catalysts. In addition, sales from precious metals trading almost doubled to &#x20AC;654 million. Earnings, however, decreased due to the above-mentioned factors.</p>
          <p>Our Construction Chemicals business in Europe and North America experienced a seasonal slowdown with, again, unusual harsh weather conditions. That is the fourth time and the last time I mention this.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, we were able to increase sales year-on-year especially in Asia and other emerging markets. Earnings did not match the level of the previous fourth quarter, mainly as a result of personnel-related provisions, intensified maintenance and restructuring efforts.</p>
          <p>Volumes and sales in Coatings increase year-on-year in all business areas. The positive trend seen in previous quarters continued for automotive OEM coatings, automotive refinish coatings and architectural coatings. We have not yet been able to fully pass on substantially higher raw material costs, earnings therefore declined despite higher volumes.</p>
          <p>In Agricultural Solutions sales in the first quarter significantly exceed the level of the same period of 2009. Lower prices for certain products, particularly some fungicides were offset by significantly higher demand for our products across all indications.</p>
          <p>Sales in Europe were slightly below the level of Q4 of 2009. In the traditionally strong year-end business in France, demand for crop protection products declined. Sales in North America rose, mainly due to higher volumes in herbicides.</p>
          <p>In South America, we had a good start into the growing season. Increasing prices for soft commodities led to higher demand for sodium fungicides in Brazil and Argentina. In Asia our sales increased, thanks to higher demand from growth markets such as India and China. In particular, businesses of our products based on our fungicide F 500 were very successful.</p>
          <p>Due to higher expenses for research and development, as well as the expansion of our business activities in growth markets, EBIT before special items was only slightly below the previous year's quarter.</p>
          <p>And, finally, Oil and Gas. In Oil and Gas, sales increased in comparison with the previous fourth quarter. Lower sales volumes in natural gas trading were more than offset by higher selling prices for natural gas and higher crude oil prices.</p>
          <p>EBIT before special items and net income after minority interests were significantly higher as a result of higher oil prices. Valuation adjustments on oil and gas licenses in the North Sea resulted in special items.</p>
          <p>In Exploration and Production, production volumes of oil and gas matched the level of the fourth quarter of 2009. Sales rose due to higher crude oil prices. The average price for Brent crude oil was $86 per barrel compared with $75 last year.</p>
          <p>In euro terms crude oil prices climbed to &#x20AC;64, which is an increase of 26%. As a result of higher prices earnings exceeded the level of previous year's fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Sales volumes in natural gas trading did not match the level of the strong fourth quarter of 2009. Overall sales grew, thanks to higher prices for natural gas. Margins were negatively impacted by the time lag effect for the adjustment of our sales prices according to our purchase prices, which led to lower earnings year-on-year, a mechanism which is well known by all of you.</p>
          <p>In this context let me give you a brief update on the situation in Libya. Over the past days events have been developing very rapidly. Our foremost concern obviously is the well-being and safety of our 453 employees. We have advised all employees to remain at home. In the meantime, we were able to allow most of our experts and their families to leave the country. A few delegates voluntarily stayed in the country, in Libya.</p>
          <p>As a precautionary measure, we stopped our production of oil and gas at the beginning of this week. At this moment it is very uncertain when we can restart the production. And as you can imagine, we will continue to monitor the situation very closely.</p>
          <p>Now I will try to explain the position Other. In Other income from operations before special items decreased by &#x20AC;190 million compared with the fourth quarter of 2009, despite the improved earnings of our Styrenics business. The main reason for the decline was a significant increase in provisions for the long-term incentive program as a result of the 30% rise in the BASF share price over the course of Q4, something we had hoped would happen, but could not predict when we last met here at the end of October.</p>
          <p>Positive special items resulting from the allocation of restructuring expenses to the operating divisions in the first quarter were significantly lower than the previous year.</p>
          <p>Let me briefly discuss our cash flow in 2010. At &#x20AC;6.5 billion operating cash flow was again pretty strong, of which &#x20AC;1.4 billion were generated in Q4. The very high after-tax earnings more than offset the increase of &#x20AC;1.7 billion in net working capital requirements due to the expansion of business volume in 2010. Free cash flow amounted to &#x20AC;3.9 billion.</p>
          <p>In 2010 we stuck to our priorities with regard to the use of cash. We spent &#x20AC;2.5 billion for capital expenditures. Net cash out for the purchase of Cognis amounted to &#x20AC;0.6 billion. We paid &#x20AC;1.6 billion in dividends to our shareholders, and we used &#x20AC;2.3 billion for our repayment of debt, which includes the refinancing of &#x20AC;1.9 billion of debt taken over from Cognis.</p>
          <p>Despite the Cognis acquisition, dividend payments and capital expenditures, net debt increased by only &#x20AC;562 million compared to the end of 2009.</p>
          <p>Let me finally briefly turn for our balance sheet. Compared with the previous year, total assets rose by &#x20AC;8.1 billion to &#x20AC;59.4 billion. Therefore, &#x20AC;4.1 billion were related to the acquisition of Cognis. This includes accounts receivable and inventories of &#x20AC;0.9 billion.</p>
          <p>The first time consolidation of Cognis led to a goodwill of &#x20AC;600 million, as well as an increase of provisions for pensions by around &#x20AC;0.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, currency effects like some due to the appreciation of the U.S. dollar and the Japanese yen relative to the euro inflated our asset base by roughly &#x20AC;2.2 billion in 2010.</p>
          <p>Our equity ratio improved from 36% to 38% and is, I think, rock solid. Furthermore, with our A rating and a very balanced maturity profile of financial debt, BASF continues to have a very strong financial position.</p>
          <p>And with that I would give back to J&#xFC;rgen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, ladies and gentlemen, let me conclude with the outlook 2011. Obviously, the strong global economic rebound in 2010, supported by major economic stimulus packages and programs and strong growth in Asia, the global economy will continue to recover in 2011.</p>
          <p>However in industrialized countries the austerity programs necessary to trim public spending will start to dampen the growth. Dynamic increasing raw material costs and the uncertainties in the northern part of Africa and the Middle East are risks we really have to closely follow up.</p>
          <p>In 2011 we expect GDP growth of 3.3%. Growth will be weaker in the industrialized countries, 2.2%, but production in most of these countries will reach and partly surpass pre-crisis levels.</p>
          <p>We expect global chemical production, I guess, without pharmaceuticals, to grow by 5.2%. And for 2011 we expect an average oil price of $90 per barrel and an average exchange rate of $1.35 per euro.</p>
          <p>Global chemical production will continue to grow in all regions, particularly strong in Asia, approximately 10%, and especially strong in China with about 12%. All customer industries show normalized solid growth, especially strong in the automotive and information and communication technology industries.</p>
          <p>If we translate all this into the outlook of our businesses in the respective segments, this means in Chemicals we expect sales in 2011 to be slightly above the level of 2010. However, additional capacities, especially Middle East and Asia, will increase pressure on margins, especially for cracker products. Earnings are therefore expected to be slightly below the level of 2010.</p>
          <p>In Plastics we expect sales and earnings in 2011 to slightly exceed the levels of the previous years.</p>
          <p>In Performance Products in 2011 we expect stable demand. And driven by Cognis' acquisition substantial sales growth we aim for a strong increase in earnings.</p>
          <p>In Functional Solutions, we expect rising demand from our customer industries, especially construction and automotive. We aim for a significant increase in sales and earnings.</p>
          <p>Agricultural Solutions, we will continue our successful innovation strategy in 2011. We aim for a slight growth in sales and earnings. Based on our assumption regarding oil price in euro, we aim in oil and gas for a significant increase in sales and improvement in earnings. However, we base this assumption on a restart of our operations in Libya in a relatively short period of time.</p>
          <p>Finally, to the overall consolidated outlook of 2011, we expect &#x2013; welcome &#x2013; so this is the final word I have for you. Looking into the future, but this is a promise also, we expect to achieve in 2011 significant increase in sales and EBIT before special items, a high premium cost of capital, significantly higher sales and earnings in the first quarter 2011 versus previous-year's quarter.</p>
          <p>We stick to our medium-term targets. And we stick to our dividend policy, which I do not have to repeat to you, you know about that.</p>
          <p>And with this, thank you very much for your attention. And we just step into question and answers now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we would now like to move to your questions. We would like to ask you first to please limit your questions to maximum two at a time so that we can take as many questions as possible. Of course, you are also welcome to rejoin the queue for a follow-up question.</p>
          <p>Also, please press the button on your microphone so that everybody in the room can listen and also the web cast works well.</p>
          <p>So I think we are starting off with Rhian Tucker. Then I have Norbert Barth, and then I have Mr. Faitz, and then we move on to James Knight.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. One general question, one specific question. The more general question. Looking at BASF as a whole, and raw materials, in principle you should be more isolated from raw material increases than other firms in the industry because you have production of oil and because you have production of petrochemicals. The only stage, in theory, you're missing is the refinery stage, and naphtha prices are fairly reasonable in Europe anyway.</p>
          <p>Can you, just looking at BASF as a whole, give us a rundown on how you see the whole business margins going because of raw materials, i.e., do you see &#x2013; do you think that's true that you're more isolated from raw material movements?</p>
          <p>The second question is very specifically about the Catalysts subdivision. You said you saw weaker earnings in precious metal trading. But you also said you saw a doubling of sales in precious metal trading. Obviously that implies very substantially weaker margins. And some of your competitors saw pretty good results in precious metal trading. Can you talk us a bit through that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let me start by taking the first one and Kurt will take the Catalysts piece. Generally you are right. One can say BASF has a certain natural hedge by being in the oil and gas business. However, this is purely reflected then on the Oil and Gas business. We transfer all products at market price. So what you see in all the other businesses certainly is market reflective. So all in all, I have to say the natural hedge might be about 50%.</p>
          <p>Yes, we are lacking the refinery piece, which is not very attractive and not very profitable anyhow. So we sold this business, as you know, in the past. All in all, we are a little bit better off, but it's not these super big advantage you may look at going forward, as we transfer prices at market price. And with this, Kurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Rhian, as you probably know, when we acquired the Engelhard operations, we also acquired the trading business, which we continue to operate, very successfully I have to say. They are in a couple of different businesses. One is simply, let's say, kind of, margin trade. You buy and sell almost at the same time as you get your margin and you certainly write higher volumes. But also keep in mind higher prices last quarter mean that in principle we also should have higher earnings.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we also have a little bit of a proprietary trading operation, which is quite successful, which was also positive in Q4, but less positive in the fourth quarter of 2009, and that basically explains what I said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I didn't understand why your earnings were substantially weaker in Catalysts in Q4 than &#x2013; it was something that was in the report.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I said is we have higher volumes and higher prices in precious metals. That does not translate automatically in higher earnings, because we also have proprietary trading where we take positions. Sometimes we are very successful and sometimes we are slightly successful. In Q4 we were slightly successful in that operation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps two questions, one regarding write-off. Second regarding more or less the outlook statement. Can you explain what happened in Latin America with these write-offs on receivables, and amount what it was? And perhaps also on I think there already was write-downs on a license in the North Sea? And give a little bit background there, how that should develop.</p>
          <p>And second question about generally the outlook statement. First, you said what I was a little bit &#x2013; what I think it is quite optimistic, saying you want to significant increase your EBITDA in 2011.</p>
          <p>Would imply that it means at least double-digit. And if you generally see that you already have 17.4% EBITDA margin already, and you are looking for 18% in 2012, and also now you taking charge for CEO, is that not a little bit too less ambitious? So do you think about revising that figure or what can we expect on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now as you have addressed this to Kurt, I just hand it over to Kurt entirely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. As you can imagine, we discuss this quite a bit internally, what kind of outlook we should provide for 2011. And what we said is what we believe we can achieve.</p>
          <p>What I have to stress again here, this was all based on certain conditions which we also described with regard to overall economic development, exchange rates, oil price, et cetera. If the year develops in a completely different way and fashion, we will probably see different results. But based on what we see today, we are quite optimistic for 2011.</p>
          <p>And as I said in my little speech, we also started into 2011 with very positive momentum, which I think is also important to keep in mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was this write-off issue on South America and the North Sea.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, maybe Hans takes the Oil and Gas piece, and I'll take the South American piece, which is actually related to a customer, which is pretty big and pretty important, and we had simply, let's say, receivable issues and we had to write off receivables with regard to that particular customer. That is pretty much behind that. It was unfortunate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Question Inaudible]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was a sizable amount, and that reflects &#x2013; it's reflected in the earnings in South America, which were not at a level which we would like them to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Here we go with the levels asset write-off. As you know, we acquired the assets in December of the year 2008. We did our purchase price allocation. We only found out about the fact that certain assets in there that we had allocated certain values to did either not quite perform to our expectation or had less reserves than were originally expected for these respective assets.</p>
          <p>What you can do is you can write-up the other assets where we have significant fines, five in the North Sea coming with the Revus portfolio during the course of the year 2010. So I'd say there is a certain imperative with respect to the assets where you make your allocation, and on the other hand, you can write-up and show the improved value for the others.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So then the next question comes from Christian Faitz, and that I have James Knight.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. You kindly shared with us how the year started in Performance Products and also Functional Solutions. Would you mind sharing how Plastics and Chemicals started? And I am also particularly interested in agrochemicals, how the year started there in terms of volumes and pricing? Of course, last year Q1 was not exactly the most up in the quarter. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me &#x2013; we split this. Kurt will take the ag and I will take Chemicals and Plastics. Also, in Chemicals the start of the year was very favorable, and the same applies to Plastics. However, in Plastics, and you have seen this in the fourth quarter already, there is margin pressure on certain product lines, especially TDI at this every moment as aromatics have increased very substantially, raw material price have increased very substantially.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think in ag it's always very early to talk about as season we are still in February, but so far the start has been pretty good. What is our major effort right now is to really bring up prices. As you noticed, in 2010 we had some price decreases. I think the conditions for this effort are quite good. Because soft commodity prices have gone up, polymers are quite positive for 2011, and that is what we are pushing for. But, again it is very early in the season and so far we are well on track.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you see prices picking in agchem?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's too early to say. We are pushing very hard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of questions. Going back to ag, could you describe what your Headline Advantage program is, and whether that's going to be utilized or extended this year as well?</p>
          <p>And secondly, on the Coatings business could you just talk about the input cost margin dynamics there, how quickly you would expect to recover margin in that business this year, maybe differentiating between the industrial and deco side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the second part and Kurt will then address the Headline piece in agchem. Coatings, a very substantial increase in raw material prices. Some of the raw materials are the super-high titanium dioxide, for example. Difficult to push through. The automotive industry, for example, now just talking about one of the industries, is really being tough, very tough at this very moment. Therefore, I think it will take some time to get the prices further up. Mostly you can just do it only via innovation. Yeah.</p>
          <p>If it comes to decorative, this is a little bit more easy, as we have all our decorative business mostly in Brazil, and not here in Europe. Now, Kurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Headline is a fungicide. And the nice effect of that fungicide is also that it has a huge enhancing effect, which is quite positive for the farmer. But for the farmer this only kicks in if the crop prices are above a certain level. And that is really the precondition for making Headline a success. With that respect, I think we are quite optimistic for 2011.</p>
          <p>But then the farmer would basically decide, okay, I have the extra cost, but those costs are justified, essentially because I will have higher yields, and that is then a very easy calculation obviously. And we suffered a little bit with Headline in 2010, early 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we are now moving to the next one. This is Lutz Gr&#xFC;ten, then Oliver Schwarz, Sophie Jourdier and Herr Spengler. So we start with Lutz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Then there is Thomas also.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thomas, I apologize, just a little bit later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Waiting for a long time already.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have not forgotten about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Lutz Gr&#xFC;ten, Commerzbank. Thanks for taking my question. First of all, regarding Libya, you have decided to run down the production in Libya. Just technically how long does it take to ramp it up again? If you make the decision on one day, are we talking about days or weeks?</p>
          <p>And the second question regarding the cash flow, given the strong performance in 2010 and also the quite sound outlook on 2011, what are your thoughts on relaunching the share buyback programs again? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Hans-Ulrich with regard to production and then Kurt with regard to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. As you rightly said, we shut in the production in the beginning of this week. And the way it is shut in, we are expecting roughly a week to restart it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, with regard to the share buyback programs, as you know we stopped it in 2008 when the financial crisis hit us. In May of this year when we have our shareholders meeting, we will not ask for renewal of the buyback program, because we don't see a need right now. And we mentioned this before, we have currently a net debt position which is comfortable, but we would also feel a little bit better if we were able to &#x2013; or will be able to reduce our debt load, and that would be our first priority in 2011. And then we have some other ideas about R&amp;D and CapEx.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me come to Oliver Schwarz, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First thing, coming back to your ag guidance, I'm still trying to understand why that guidance is what I see as rather conservative as you guide for flat sales and earnings improvement.</p>
          <p>So if we take into account that your prices would be stable you would be guiding for just slight volume increases. Or either &#x2013; of if those prices would decrease further you would be guiding for, let's say, mediocre sales increases due to higher volumes, which I think is a given.</p>
          <p>It seems to me that the inventory levels in the supply chain seem still to be a topic. Is that a correct assessment?</p>
          <p>And my second question is a pure P&amp;L related one. The tax rate was remarkably low Q4. Do you have a guidance for the year 2011? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those to Kurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I'll start with the tax rate, and you are right, our underlying tax rate in Q4 was quite low, and I mentioned a couple of fast special factors. So please keep in mind even if you deduct those special factors, we still had a record net income for a fourth quarter, but that affect is maximum above &#x20AC;100 million in Q4.</p>
          <p>The problem with special events that you cannot really predict them, because sometimes it depends on sealing a deal with the tax man, when they do their tax audits, for instance.</p>
          <p>But if you just look at these issues right now the underlying tax rate for BASF fluctuates between 20% and 25%. Our guidance has been pretty much in the order of magnitude of 25%. If you look at the entire 2010 year it's pretty much now 20%. This also reflects a stronger earnings contribution, for instance, from Asia.</p>
          <p>We are still in many countries, we enjoy tax holidays due to our large investments, which might disappear or be reduced over time. But all in all of the 20% to 25% I think is a good guide for the underlying tax rate.</p>
          <p>With regard to AP, ag business, that has to be your assessment whether our guidance is cautious or too optimistic. I can only tell you it's very, very early now in 2011. We see &#x2013; as you mentioned, we see some positive underlying trends, which might provide us with a little bit of tail wind, but again it is too early to say. And what also holds true, and this is something J&#xFC;rgen mentioned, we continue to invest in R&amp;D and market development also in 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you quickly comment on the inventory levels you see?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not aware of any special inventory situation at the beginning of 2011. It has been &#x2013; or was an issue early 2010, as you know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So this brings us to Sophie Jourdier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Sophie Jourdier from Citi. Just a couple of questions. First, two, if I'm allowed. Was that allowed? I think I missed the introduction.</p>
          <p>Just regionally you have given us a good sort of flavor through the divisions in the beginning of this year. But regionally into the U.S., Europe, China, just what you're seeing at the moment, particularly on your chemical activities.</p>
          <p>Then if I was allowed a second one, you mentioned raw material shortages in quite a few of your product areas in your statement. I wonder whether you could just elaborate on which the materials and really what can be done to resolve that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, now this is &#x2013; takes us a little bit longer, if you want us to go through the business and region at the same time. Let's try to do it in a very rough picture. And as always, we will talk about Europe. Kurt will talk about North America, and I will talk about Asia and contribute maybe a little bit also a little bit about South America. So why don't you start Hans-Ulrich.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. With Europe being roughly 60% of our business, I think it is fair to say that pretty much everything that we said with respect to the overall BASF Group is also reflective of what we see currently in Europe.</p>
          <p>So what do we see currently? We see strong demand across the entire portfolio. We see some regional differences. In particular Eastern Europe has picked up strongly already during the year 2010, and that goes also the same way into the first quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>We see some weakness in parts of Southern Europe. But overall if you look at the business that we have in Southern Europe that is nothing that we are too concerned about. And we see solid good demand in Western and Northern Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think all of us are pretty much aware of the overall economic picture in North America. I don't really want to dwell into that one. What we see in our industry, we had very good start actually into 2011, positive momentum, going into the new year.</p>
          <p>The big question mark I still have is the construction industry whether that industry will finally turn around or the real estate market will turn around maybe over the course of the second half of 2011. That would really provide a boost.</p>
          <p>So far we don't see any indications for that to be happening. I think that is pretty much our biggest concern, but overall the manufacturing industry in North America has recovered remarkably well after the crisis in 2008 and early 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Sophie, let me try by tracking a little bit our customer industries, because this translates into our growth at the end of the day. Now if you look into Asia I would say automotive strong, 8% about. If you just take Japan out, Japan of course will be lower, but also in a rather high area about 7% even for Japan. If you look into ICT industry, Asia about 12% to 13%, what we see.</p>
          <p>Textile industry rather strong, about 8% to 9%. If you look into payroll industry also 9%, 10%. Food industry also 8% to 9%. Now always talking about without Japan. You really have to confirm this, otherwise the picture is a little bit different.</p>
          <p>If you look into construction it is also between 7% to 8%. It translates really for the Chemical industry into growth of 10% in Asia Pacific. And as I said before, about 12% in China. And if you go then into the countries this is a rather strong picture throughout Asia. If you look into South America, things are also rather positive also in construction, and in almost all industries. Think of one where we have an issue around the world is a little bit of an exception in Asia where there is a strong really paper industry. There is a restructuring story, but South America, much better compared to Europe and North America.</p>
          <p>Now you also talked about raw material shortages. If we look into raw materials and real shortages, I have to say on the upfront certainly are things, and maybe Ulrich is going to complement this. But what is really short is our cracker products. We have a very extraordinary situation at this moment. I don't know whether you're aware of this.</p>
          <p>Ethylene and propylene, especially in North America are in a ratio which we never have seen before. It has ethylene about $0.44 per pound and propylene well above $0.70. With butadiene we are reaching already $1 almost. And so propylene and butadiene, especially butadiene globally, propylene especially in North America but partly also in Asia, are relatively short. But then it comes to aromatics where we cannot talk about real shortage, because it is the middle of the gasoline pool, and therefore, I think this is not an issue we should talk about.</p>
          <p>Other products are short because in high demand. If you look into certain &#x2013; and you are aware of the rare earth topic, which is exaggerated to a certain extent certainly. If you look into natural products, for example, palm oil and these things are very high also highly speculated still. There is not a real shortage, but there is also not a lot of surplus. So as we go forward I think we see &#x2013; in the first quarter at least we will see raw material prices going up.</p>
          <p>Whether this will continue in the second half into the year, I have personally my doubts, but Hans-Ulrich, what is your comment on this? He is responsible for purchasing, and he knows it better than me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The share comment is an easy one, you are absolutely right. Maybe one addition. What have we seen in 2010? We have seen shortages here and there. And as J&#xFC;rgen said, as a result of high demand. And as a result of high demand, not only with respect to these specific raw materials, but also due to the fact that in the entire supply chain there was a lot of capacity taken out, including transportation capacity. And as a result of that it was here and there difficult to get access to the raw materials. At this point in time I would say the key issue in our portfolio is the rare earth situation, where we have covered our base at a high price, I would say. And the question is how will that go forward. What will happen with the export quota in China? How quickly will we be able to find other solutions and other suppliers of raw material rare earth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we move on to Peter Spengler.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. In the past you were a net gainer of a rising oil price, as far as I can remember. Would this apply if leap year action will be discontinued for the whole year? That is my first question and second question is also on oil and gas. You booked something like &#x20AC;16 million net income in 2009 from your North African operation in Oil and Gas. So maybe you have the number for 2010 already at hand? And I suppose that your net cash is much higher than this amount, since it seems very low actually for this large operation. Maybe you can elaborate a bit on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have not yet done the calculation with respect to the overall impact on the BASF Group. Maybe Jurgen or Kurt can help there. With respect to 2010, the net earnings after-tax and after minority interest is in the range of &#x20AC;70 million. And if you look at it from a cash perspective, always keep in mind that we have a situation in Libya where basically the sales are taxed in the order of magnitude of 93%, 94%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Either we do not guide on impact integrally for BASF Group from the oil price. We just guide with regard to Oil and Gas business. And therefore, I think it would be misleading if we talk about the entire BASF Group, because this is very difficult to find out and have very &#x2013; as I have talked before, what is a direct impact. As we transfer at market price, this is certainly something which is almost impossible to calculate out. But you know our sensitivity in Oil and Gas, which translate into $1 per barrel plus/minus &#x20AC;100 million in sales, and EBIT 35. And if it comes to earnings after-tax, it's is about 12. This is the guidance we are giving. And this includes, of course, Libya. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we are coming to the next group of four. There is Mr. Gilbert, then Herr K&#xF6;hler, Herr Heine, and Annett Weber.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you very much. Thomas Gilbert from UBS. Thanks for the two questions. The first one is, if you look into how in which hedging position you have entered 2011 on  naphtha, and now assume that the North African situation escalates, what does that mean for the hedging result, and also the result in the Petrochemicals business for the first quarter? Just the direction would be great under that scenario.</p>
          <p>And the second question, as you know, we are always intrigued by the vocabulary of the BASF guidance. You have to help me out on this again. Chemical production growth this year is seen at 5.2% by the Group. You aim to beat Chemical production on average trend line by 2%, yet you guide for sales slight increase in volume for 2011. There is two possible scenarios. A, you don't have the capacity to match market growth in 2011, or you are very conservative. Which of the two is the case, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The last one is a difficult one, but I think we need to help you out a little bit here. We will certainly outperform in growth. So this means slightly is going up to 10%. Yes? It helps you a little bit. Not always very sharp, but this is directional. And it helps you quite a bit. Significant this be above, yes? As we said, slight increase in sales. If we add on top Cognis it is certainly significant. This is how you have to translate it. Now with this, I would like to hand over hedging to Hans-Ulrich.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the hedging result, to the extent we are hedged and looking at the oil price development that we've seen over the recent days &#x2013; I think last time I looked today Brent was at $114. One thing is for sure, our hedging results will go up. But don't overestimate the amount that we actually hedge. In raw materials, since we are looking at it on a net basis, that net basis meaning we are looking at our exposure, we are then looking at the hydrocarbons that we produce ourselves in our Oil and Gas business. And when we also look at the fact to what extent can we pass on raw material prices under our respective contract formulas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The last sentence is very important to understand. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes to us from Ronald K&#xF6;hler and then I have Annett Weber. And I have marked down <mark type="inaudible" /> --Tim Jones, <mark type="inaudible" /> and Martin Evans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. The first question is on Performance Products. Obviously, you have a rather positive guidance here of a significant increase. I would be interested in seeing a little bit &#x2013; if you could elaborate a little bit if we would strip out Cognis contribution and if we would strip out Ciba symmetries, would you be still optimistic for the business to see an increase, despite higher raw material costs? That would be the first question.</p>
          <p>Second question is on seasonality and Chinese New Year. Obviously, China is getting bigger and bigger for you. So Q1 is, let's say, I would call it the low quarter in China due to Chinese New Year. How will that impact actually your business? Should we be aware of that? Is it getting more significant as China is getting more significant or how should we go for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will take both of those. Let me first say that I am not able to differentiate any longer taking Ciba out and so forth. No, this is impossible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in Ciba synergies obviously. You target cost savings &#x2013; so meaning excluding cost savings and excluding Cognis consolidation effects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is not -- again, Ciba synergies are part of our business now. It is now more than one year. It is basically almost two years now that we have that, so I don't want to deduct Ciba. If we take Cognis out, certainly Cognis as we said as a guidance for the year, it has been &#x20AC;3 billion sales. It has been &#x2013; I don't recall, I think it was in EBITDA terms &#x20AC;550 million, and an EBITDA margin of 18%. This is a guidance we can give at this very moment.</p>
          <p>Looking into further details, I think I would just refuse to do so. On the other hand, I have to say, Performance Products are constantly increasing, improving. Their overall performance is now, I have to say, I cannot differentiate with pigments which has been within BASF and pigments which have come from Ciba &#x2013; all these additives which have been from BASF and pigment additives which have been come from Ciba anymore. On the other hand, these business are developing very nicely as we more and more move some business out of Ciba business away from being commoditized towards systems solutions. And certainly we would even grow Performance Products without that.</p>
          <p>Second, seasonality with regard to Chinese. I think Chinese New Year, this is basically always overdone. So we do not see &#x2013; very significant, this is one week off, a little bit of preparing before hand, so to speak. January usually is a little bit stronger, February a little bit weaker. So if you take the entire first quarter there is not a lot in Asia which makes a really big difference. If there are crisis years, however, this has an impact, much stronger than we have it when you have rather constant costs. So I do not think that this has major impact on our Q1 results and sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So now we come to Andreas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One question basically on Others again. In Others, there were a profit booked. Is that in relation with Styrenics or a rebooking on bonuses from the Others line to the operating lines? And then you have separated the assets for disposing groups and the liabilities for disposing groups, and the difference between is &#x20AC;400 million, is that what you can expect by putting Styrenics into the joint venture as a cash proceeds from the joint venture?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not completely sure if I have got your second question right about the disposal group for Styrenics. What we do here is basically an accounting rule to follow that we separate all the assets and the liabilities of Styrenics in one position in our balance sheet. And that obviously is then what will be moved into the joint venture which we will form with INEOS.</p>
          <p>The mechanism, how we transfer and at what price, I don't think we have discussed this publicly. But as J&#xFC;rgen said, we are very, very optimistic for the formation of the joint venture and to create a very competitive, very solid, rock solid new enterprise. And we will talk about this as soon as we have more information to provide, because as you know, right now we are in the process. We have to apply for antitrust approvals, which may take some time as well.</p>
          <p>And in [Foreign language] or Others, as we say, yes, there was an effect which we already had in 2009 that we reversed provisions which we made under Others, because now we learnt or we decided what specific measures will be applied. And this then moves to the operating segments and divisions, and that number was lower than what had happened in 2009. Apart from that, the major issue in Other was really our long-term incentive program. As you know, that is an options program, and that is very much driven by both the BASF share price and the out performance of the Morgan Stanley Global Chemical Index. And in both respects we delivered quite nicely over the course of Q4.</p>
          <p>And as I said before, we did not &#x2013; we could not predict that to happen when we met here in October or talked on the phone. So the share price increase of 30% really made a big difference with this position Other. Then it is a mixture of many, many small items, as you all know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so now this brings us to Annett Weber.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I've got two and a half questions. The first question relates to &#x2013; it is an understanding question. Did you mention &#x20AC;100 million impact from the weather disturbances in Q4? Was that a net profit figure or an EBIT or special items figure? Then the second question relates to the maintenance costs that you mentioned several times that hit your earnings in Q4. Could you possibly give us the number for Q4 2009 and the number for Q4 2010, i.e., the EBIT impact that you lost or additional costs that you incurred due to the maintenance shutdown? And the second or third question is the percentage of your contracts that currently allow for at least quarterly pricing or cost pass-through, if you have a rough estimate for this &#x2013; for the Chemicals activity, ex oil and gas obviously?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kurt, the first one. I really didn't get this first one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first one was about the one-time items in Q4 with regard to maintenance, the harsh weather conditions &#x2013; it is the fifth time that I mentioned this &#x2013; and the bonuses. Actually I cannot tell you exactly what the weather influenced. What we can tell you, all in all, we had an effect of about &#x20AC;100 million coming from higher bonuses, which we had not provisioned for before until Q3, because first of all, our results came in slightly higher than we had expected and we tried to provision for the employee bonuses on a pro rata basis. And secondly, as J&#xFC;rgen said, we had a special bonus of &#x20AC;50 million, which we already decided upon in Q4. That is one effect. And the other effect, including the &#x20AC;100 million, is essentially really the maintenance fees, which we talked about, the accelerated maintenance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think &#x2013; looking into your face, you would like to have a direct figure. We don't have this, because this is a mixture of CapEx spending additional maintenance work and delayed sales, yes. Delayed sales, which moves into the first quarter, and then we had the contract question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And again, since you asked about it saying understanding how this works here, the long-term incentive program, i.e., the options program, that is booked in Others. That is very, very important to keep in mind. Then your other question was really what is our ability to pass-through higher feedstock costs. How long does it take us? Do we have long-term contracts in place?</p>
          <p>As you know, in Europe in the past we pretty much had quarterly pricing mechanisms. That is pretty much the past history. Most of Europe moved actually to monthly pricing. We are talking here about basic chemical products essentially which are traded based on price only. And there it is all about supply/demand. We do a very, very small calculation to understand what is our, what we call, pass-through factor. How long does it take us to pass on higher feedstock costs. And again, it depends on supply/demand in those markets, but normally within one quarter, two to three months, we are normally in a position to pass it through.</p>
          <p>Having said that, there are other businesses, take automotive, OEM coatings, where we have long-term contracts and fixed prices. And obviously then it becomes quite tough to talk with our automotive customers about higher prices, because there you turn around and say, okay, I didn't hear what you said. But this is an ongoing process. For instance, we talk now very, very vigilantly about rare earth, which is a real major cost driver for our Catalysts business, automotive catalyst business. And certainly we try to pass on these higher costs to our customers, but obviously this takes a little bit more time. And therefore you also see the profit shifting a little bit on our P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>Chemicals doing relatively well, or very well actually, and the businesses further downstream still coping with some of the price and cost increases, which by the way is &#x2013; again understanding for you, which is also caused by the fact that internally we pass on our raw materials at market prices. That is very important to keep in mind. We pass on our internal captive supplies at market prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So now we are moving on to Tim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you. Tim Jones, Deutsche Bank. Two questions, if I may. I think that is the rule now. The first one is on polyurethanes. You mentioned in your statement that pricing was broadly flat in 2010. But I just don't really understand the problem with this business because if I look at it, it is going oligopolistic. You've got pretty much four Western companies that are disciplined, essentially theoretically controlling the market and yet none of them can seem to make a huge amount of money when raw materials go up. So is it just because of construction or was it something else that is happening? So that is my first question.</p>
          <p>My second one is a bit shorter. And simply it is debottlenecking. Obviously, industry, particularly in the upstream industry, is making huge amounts of money at the moment. And there isn't an awful lot of capacity coming on stream, apart from in some chains. How much do you think you could add in your key product chains where you are very tight through debottlenecking, say, in the next 12 or 18 months? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim, I will try my best to answer this. First of all, with regard to Polyurethanes, there are two major factors. One is what you mentioned, construction industry certainly had a major impact in fourth quarter &#x2013; application for the construction industry. Very special weather conditions in Europe as well as especially in North America, which is still the case up to today. And the second one is really looking into raw materials. So raw materials have gone up, especially benzene and toluene, let me say, in a record speed, which is almost &#x2013; very difficult to pass those things through. Then I am not sure whether you have been here, TDI is certainly a little bit longer than we anticipated this earlier. But I think it is just going now to drop and coming back. NDI is becoming better. So all in all high-growth rates. Not a lot of capacity coming on stream, so I am rather optimistic concerning those things.</p>
          <p>Debottlenecking, the second topic. You know, we always say that we want to have productivity gains by about 3% per year. This is on average true, but it is not in our product lines possible. So sometimes you have to invest. It takes a little bit of time. We have certain product lines where we have been able to increase our capacity rather substantially beyond what we have as main rate capacity. Just to name one, it is acrylic acid, where we constantly are inventing, let me say, ourselves somehow. But all in all, Tim, I cannot say that this is applicable to all product lines. Still, it is room to grow. And it is our ambition to really get to 3% productivity gain every year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the next four questions come from <mark type="inaudible" />, Martin Evans, Martin Roediger, and Mr. Redenius. Okay, with so we start with <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Two questions. First, your mention of a single Latin American customer causing a receivables write-off large enough to be noted in your annual analyst meeting does raise eyebrows and suggests an opportunity for a significant process improvement to reduce the risk of an event such as this recurring and I wondered if you might just explain what the process improvement is that you doubtless have already implemented In response to this event?</p>
          <p>And then, second, somewhat related to this, if you could explain the change in net working capital? If my calculation is correct, the $1.7 billion increase in net working capital over the course of the year is in spite of an 11-day increase in days payable from 27 to 38 days. And I'm sure that a part of that is increase in raw material pricing but perhaps you could explain what your standards are, your targets for days inventory and days receivable and days payable, and how we might expect to see those evolve over the course of 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can assure you this topic in South America didn't just raise eyebrows in our case, it also increased our blood pressure quite a bit. And we are working very hard to make sure that it is not going to happen again. I don't want to go into too many details about what the experience tells. You shouldn't wait for too long if you have an issue with a customer. Sometimes there is still hope. And we provide additional products and financing in that case, it was simply too much and we learned from that. But it is &#x2013; really it is an isolated incident, which has no importance for other regions or other businesses which we operate.</p>
          <p>And in terms of net working capital, yes, you are right, we had slightly higher payables &#x2013; receivables &#x2013; no, payables at the end of 2010 that was a positive effect for the net working capital position. In general our goal is to improve what we call days outstanding, both for receivables and for inventories year-over-year. We made progress again in 2010. We measured this based &#x2013; isolating the price factor, obviously, which we cannot really control. But if you just look at volumes, which we tried to do, we have been able to reduce our inventories on hand quite nicely in 2010.</p>
          <p>Receivables to a certain degree is also a function of growing the business volume. Obviously, we improved in terms of receivables of days outstanding. And we have to go essentially to improve in both respects receivables and inventories by about 2 days in 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Martin Evans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. Martin Evans, JPMorgan. Just on the Functional Solutions division again. And I hear what you say about sort of one-off costs and so on to some extent in Q4. But is there any sense to which you are possibly slightly disappointed with this division, given the high hopes at the time of both the Engelhard and the Degussa Construction acquisitions, which I think from memory, totaled around $8 billion plus. And is it a case that possibly, particularly maybe on Catalysts you are finding it more difficult and more challenging to manage than it appeared at the time of those acquisitions? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We share this now, because Kurt takes care for the Catalysts, but let me touch, I think, and make a general remark. You may say, yes, we are a little bit disappointed, but this is due to the fact that we just acquired and then we went into the crisis with both industries, which was not foreseeable. This is to start with. And unfortunately construction industry is not really coming back. We had a minus growth rate still in 2010. We should not forget. We do expect growth in 2011, about 3% growth globally now.</p>
          <p>So I think it is going to change step by step by step. We had to restructure. This takes also a little bit of time. But we are doing rather well in this and you will see that this will improve. With regard to Catalysts, just as a side remark, we have taken out a lot of new technologies from the Engelhard acquisition you cannot see in this business directly which is, for example, also in electro-mobility, but also in totally other parts, cosmetics and so forth. So all in all, I think we have not been dissatisfied, besides the effect of just acquiring and then moving into the crisis.</p>
          <p>A similar question was in the past Ciba, which has changed now, because business entirely &#x2013; the business scope of our portfolio is much more broader. It is much more direct and it is just in the center of where growth is today.</p>
          <p>But, Kurt, could you comment also a little bit on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, frankly Martin sometimes I'm wondering whether it would be better to just open up our books and present our Catalysts business as it is, and then we don't have that discussion. Because I understand your frustration, you can look at two of our competitors, but not at our BASF numbers. We have the benefit of being able to do that.</p>
          <p>We very, very thoroughly look at what is going on in our competitive environment. And I can tell you that we do not lose any share. We do not lose any margins. We have first-class technology. We know exactly what platforms we compete for and how successful we are, where we win, why we win. If we don't win, why. It is all very, very carefully monitored. And I think we are in an excellent position from a technology point of view.</p>
          <p>This was really a marriage in heaven, so to say. BASF's long-term commitment to Catalysts research and then the more development, market-oriented focus of Engelhard, bringing this together has really yielded excellent results for BASF.</p>
          <p>In terms of margins, the problem which we're facing here, we only look at EBIT and you have to keep in mind that that business is broadened by very, very high depreciation levels due to the purchase price.</p>
          <p>If you take that into account, that business generates an excellent, excellent EBITDA. It competes on technology, which is really something we like. It's based on, what we call, mega trends, people want to drive. And we have some very nice secondary effects, like now looking at the battery business, which is pretty much an offspring of the Engelhard &#x2013; old Engelhard activities, which we developed further on. And are now in a position, for instance, to build a plant in Ohio for battery materials. Something we had not envisioned a couple of years ago, and something which I would say would probably have been difficult to implement for BASF without that step of acquiring Engelhard.</p>
          <p>So all in all, we are very satisfied with the business. There is always homework to do, no doubt about it. We are constantly working on our cost base. And finally, I have to say the business environment provides a little bit of more tail wind. The automotive industry has come back. We have an excellent position in Asia.</p>
          <p>We are market leader in Asia. If you take into account that we also run very large joint ventures in Asia, both in Korea and Japan. And we also see now that the chemical industry &#x2013; chemical catalysts business is coming back finally. So I think we are in a good position to further grow, and also have excellent earnings from that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good chance to comment a minute because Tim has asked this question with regard to debottlenecking and capacity creep. Chemical catalysts, and this you don't see in the catalysts business, is about catalysts. Running our process with more higher efficiency, higher yield, less side products, lower energy, this is the key to success within the catalysts business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next questions are coming from Martin R&#xF6;diger, and then I have <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Martin R&#xF6;diger from Cheuvreux. Two questions. First on nutrition and health. You mentioned in your report that Vitamin E showed lower margins. Is this a pricing issue? And what is going on with the other vitamins in your portfolio and the market in general?</p>
          <p>Second is on Agro. And I was a little bit wondering that price pressure obviously is accelerating while your volumes is moving up very, very strongly in Q4. Did you buy market share or what's going on in this very favorable environment where crop prices are extremely high?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the first one, and Kurt will take the Agro piece. With regard to nutrition and health, yeah, on the vitamins side, especially Vitamin E, we had, let me say, a rather tough competition, especially in China, which is still continuing, but improving. But this is very specifically in Vitamin E, less so in the other areas, and so we are optimistic going forward. Kurt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Agro, I hope I got the question correctly. I mean, we had excellent volume growth in Q4. As we all know, Q4 is a basically small quarter for the Ag business, but we had excellent double-digit volume growth in Q4. And price pressure, I talked about this before, we experienced price pressure starting early in 2010. Also as a cleanup side effect from too many inventories out there in the field. That doesn't seem to be the case in 2011. And we have a pretty good overall environment, as we have mentioned before. Soft commodity prices have gone up. Farmers are more optimistic, so that all in all the conditions in 2011 are much better going forward than what we experienced 12 months ago. You don't look happy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think to be very clear, we are enthusiastic about the business also going forward, so there should be no doubt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> If I look at the growth rates in Asia, which you have mentioned overall for different industries, and then if I just look at the raw material situation, do you think there is a tangible risk right now that if raw materials keep going up that we might see a little bit derailment of the economic development, especially in Asia, where you are very bullish, or let's say, you are very positive? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And the second question is related to Performance Products. Here pigments basically had longer lead times last year and the chain was quite empty. Would you think that the back orders have more or less gone now, or would you think there are still a lot of back orders here?</p>
          <p>And then just on Cognis. I mean, you're still guiding for a rough &#x20AC;3 billion. Fundamentally this is a very good growth business, so I was a little bit surprised why the guidance remains the same when it is part of the BASF family now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just try to answer this getting directly into Cognis. Of course, and we will come to you, as I said, end of March when we have designed the integration plan. And then we will tell you about cost synergies and top line growth synergies. For the time being, what can we blame? At the end of the year when the Cognis acquisition is not yet done, and not knowing about the business, we are in the midst of talking with each other intensively how to make the best out of it. And this takes a little bit of time. So therefore, I would like to ask you to wait a little bit and you will get all kinds of information. I am here very optimistic.</p>
          <p>So second, Performance Products, pigments, pipeline, filling. I have to say not all Intermediates are really filled up yet. This will happen over time step by step by step. But there is still some work to do. And lastly, with regard to looking into the growth in Asia and the risk of having even shorter raw materials, I would say now let's really focus on the raw materials, which are important to BASF.</p>
          <p>There is first of all oil and it's gas. These are the basics. And then you can talk a little bit about precious metals. Rare earth we talked before, so we don't have to touch it anymore. I do not see a real shortage in oil, and I do not see a real shortage in gas either. So the question is what part or what portion is speculative?</p>
          <p>Now if you look into &#x2013; now let's just talk again about Libya. If Libya really are to stop the entire manufacturing, this is maximum 2 million barrels per day. I'm just saying it has been 1.7 million &#x2013; I'm just saying maximum 2 million. But there is still capacity out from the OPEC countries of about 5 million per day. Now this is readily available, right at the very moment? Maybe not. So you may see a little bit of more volatility going forward to towards this end.</p>
          <p>But principally I think there is an adder of $9, of $10 to almost $20 per barrel risk. And going forward, assuming that the situation in Middle East would smooth down very substantially, I personally believe, and I am not godfather, but I personally believe oil prices will go down. And this is why we have in our calculations US $90 per barrel. You may say, crazy, these guys, never will it happen, not today, $114. How can this be? But we should go back and think about 2008 and the years before. There have been huge ups and downs. And we know with speculation the bubble explodes. The way down is very, very fast.</p>
          <p>Now I am not predicting this at this very moment, to be clear. But going forward I think it was reasonable to have this US $90 per barrel. And if you think about what we had average in 2010, this was $86 per barrel or $80 flat in average, yeah, right. Last quarter was $86. This is very reasonable and reflecting the additional demand, which comes out of Asia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So then we moving on to our next question, Harald Gruber, and then <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you, Harald Gruber, Silvia Quandt Research. I have two issues. The first is touching the cash flow. Can you just tell us what the net working capital requirement in 2010 would be without Cognis? I saw working capital requirements adjusted for Cognis, but not the creditors.</p>
          <p>And secondly, linked to that, what is your perspective for 2011 when we consider capacities are mostly fully loaded, and therefore also incurring possibly not too much volumes for materials to be used versus 2010. So that's the percentage change, of course.</p>
          <p>And secondly and finally, what is your view on free cash flow in 2011, when you also take into account, of course, higher dividends pay out, not too much effort, again, on refinancing debt, and possibly lower networking capital requirements? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kurt, would you like to start with regard to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I try to start with the Cognis effect. Please keep in mind we acquired Cognis on December 9th, so the effect was &#x2013; on cash flow was minimal, because when we consolidate this number doesn't going to cash flow, but it goes into other positions within our cash flow statement as part of the &#x2013; essentially the acquisition price, which we paid for the assets obviously. And Cognis had, I have to say, a pretty good system in place how to manage their working capital. There is always room for improvement, which we try to do. So all in all, I don't see a special effects are coming from the Cognis integration in 2011 with regard to cash needs.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow, that's obviously a little bit more difficult question to answer. First of all, we made a statement &#x2013; kind of a forecast about earnings. You can calculate our depreciation levels based on the announced investments for 2011 and beyond. Net working capital very much depends on business volumes obviously. But as I said before, our goal is to improve further on. There should be probably a slight increase of networking capital financing, but really a slight increase. And then it is all about the investments which we have to deduct, so I would foresee that again we will have a very positive net free cash flow, which we have had also over the past, almost 10 years now. And that is all that would go to generate cash for our shareholders at the end of the day. But we don't really provide that number here publicly. Actually we have a plan in place, but ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jochen Schlachter and then Jeremy Redenius.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jochen Schlachter from UniCredit. Just two more technical questions on the debt side. What is your optimal level of short-term debt, relative to your total debt load? Well, of course this partly relates to your usage of the CP program in the US. And the second question is given that you have two or a couple of bulky cash outflows to cover in the first half, do you plan to visit the bond markets in 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Short and long term we try to optimize our interest expense obviously and also risk profile. What you see right now is that we have a lower share of short-term debt than we would like to have. That very much reflects what happened between 2008 and 2009. And you are aware that we went to the bond market in 2009 to raise additional capital at times of very high uncertainty. You might say there is a benefit of hindsight. This was too early. We should have waited.</p>
          <p>But, frankly, from our point of view, the margin for error was simply too small, too slim, so we said as soon as the markets opened up, BASF went to the market, raised some money with bonds, which from today's point of view are frankly relatively expensive, but just think about the alternative if the markets had really collapsed. And I tell you in 2009 there were times when, hard to understand today, when people got really scared of what was happening in the financial markets.</p>
          <p>So essentially we have more bonds on our books than we should probably have. And we cannot really take too much advantage of the short-term commercial paper program where we have excellent, excellent interest rates, as you can imagine. And having said that, that means that in 2011 I think one bond expires. And then we have to make up our mind whether to test the bond market or whether to fund short-term. This is very much a question of risk profile and interest-rate expectations, and we will make that decision at that point in time when the bond expires.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So this brings us to Jeremy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Jeremy Redenius from Sanford Bernstein. I have a question about operational effectiveness. When markets are tight I understand demand may be strong, but from the supply side as operational effectiveness decline in the industry are your assets able to produce less than they were before in some cases? And are you seeing this being an issue for you or suppliers as well? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is a question, which is very difficult to answer. I have to say if we look into our operations, and maybe this has to do with the overall approach we have taken throughout the crisis, I think we have managed very, very well. Operational effectiveness and efficiency has increased. Availability of plants is there. We stopped, however, a few capacities which we will not bring back on stream. Others may do, but we will have those operations closed.</p>
          <p>To give you an example, we talked quite often in the past about our SP dispersion plans around Europe where we closed down almost 40% of our capacity, which had been in surplus anyhow. So we will look to open this up.</p>
          <p>Operational effectiveness, as a matter of fact, I think is &#x2013; we have quite, I would say, improved. However, we are looking to the industry, yes. Maintenance work has been postponed in 2009. Therefore, you see a little bit more outages in the industry. And I really believe this will continue to a certain extent. What we really did to the year-end also is really accelerating our maintenance. We also reduced it a little bit. Now we have accelerated this to the year-end. Also, in order to have a super start in 2011, as the margin momentum in most of our business has been very, very positive. And some of our customer's seasonality, especially in Performance Products, towards the year-end have even asked to postpone some of the sales into 2011, and help us to do this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we are coming to our five last questions. There is one from actually Bill and I have one from Christian Faitz and one from Norbert. I have two questions via e-mail. So we start with Bill, and then I am plugging one from e-mail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. My two questions in some ways piggyback on Jeremy's. I didn't quite catch what your outlook is for capital spending in 2011. And, second, could you also talk a bit about capacity utilization? It is surprising that in 2010 the capital spending for PP&amp;E was flat with the previous year. Perhaps you could explain to what extent your plants are operating at over 90% on a nameplate basis, therefore where you have a pricing tail wind that could be expected in your markets and where capacity increases would be economically sensible? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to CapEx spending, just looking into one year does not make sense from our perspective, where we always refer here to a five years timeframe. And looking into 2010 &#x2013; sorry, '11 to '15, it is &#x20AC;12.6 billion, what we anticipate. It's an increase. And most probably we will have an increase in 2011 compared to 2010. I am not talking about specific figures here. With regard to the &#x20AC;12.6 billion, about &#x20AC;8.2 billion is coming from chemical activities. But we still have a very heavy load on our oil and gas business, infrastructure for gas transportation, which is the rest of it, yeah.</p>
          <p>So capacity utilization you know that this is a question I am always refusing to answer, because I think it is the number which people fiddle around quite a bit. I have to say, yes, we have some product lines which are heavily loaded. You know about the shortages in acrylics. You know about the shortages in also alcohol, for example, and plasticizers and so forth. But there are also others which are, let me say, a little bit more loose and long. For example, Styrenics is long &#x2013; or styrene, not Styrenics, styrene is long.</p>
          <p>Looking into what you can read out of 90% plus capacity utilization is awfully difficult. Because is this nameplate, is it real, is it just convincing your competitor that you're bigger than the others? It does not make sense. So, yeah, there are products which are short and will remain short going forward. There is supply, pricing and margin momentum quite substantially. And there are others where we have to struggle a bit going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we plug in a question from Chris Willis, a long-term follower of BASF. He says, J&#xFC;rgen, congratulations on a great run. You mentioned &#x20AC;600 million of cost savings from efficiency programs. How much of that was from legacy BASF businesses, and how much was from acquisitions? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Talking about mix. Mix does totally exclude acquisitions. We have acquisition management totally separate from our next excellent target program, which is basically looking into BASF. So what we will report on is, for example, Ciba integration, where we have the cost target of &#x20AC;450 million, as you know. This is well on track, but this is totally separate from this &#x20AC;1 billion which is not only cost, it's also top line growth in some areas coming out from NEXT.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Christian Faitz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. Again, Christian Faitz from Macquarie. The question is actually twofold. First of all, in answer to James Knight's question you said that the car industry has problems accepting higher coatings prices, for example, for car coatings. Do you see this in other areas in your talks with the car industry as well? I am thinking about catalysts, plastics, whatsoever.</p>
          <p>And the second product question in that context is, I mean, if the car industry wants to pass on all the price hikes they have to face, whether it's the car supplier or the OEM manufacturer to their customer, I would guess the average passenger car would go up from &#x20AC;20,000 to &#x20AC;25,000. Do you see that the customer is willing to accept this, especially in the rather shaky times? And how do you tackle your pricing structure in that way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think generally speaking the automotive industry is very often the most difficult one to cope with. Tradition of having longer-term pricing mechanisms. Therefore, it's more difficult to push things through. The most important thing is, and this I mentioned before, is you need to offer something &#x2013; innovation, cost savings. You know about our coatings process, for example, where we save quite substantial amounts. And if you are able to share it, you then can also cover raw material increases.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, I have to say also with regard to catalysts there are mechanisms to take this into consideration, and this very especially on rare earth, what alternative do they have? If there is no rare earth anymore they need to accept a higher price. So I think there they are learning together with us, but our solution is not just the price. It has to be a little bit more. It has to be added value, and we will try very hard to achieve this. Whether it's catalysts, whether it's plastic materials for intake manifolds or for seats or what you have, or it is coatings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So there came one question in from Richard Logan, Goldman Sachs. If the oil price remains above $100 per barrel during the whole of 2011, how confident is BASF that it can pass through higher raw material costs to customers, excluding oil and gas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Difficult to predict. We will do our utmost to achieve it. And there are quite a lot of product lines where this is possible. Sometimes, as Kurt has mentioned, it will take time. And as we just talked about automotive, it may take us more than a quarter once in a while. But if you offer a differentiation potential with your products, you will be able to pass those things through. And market momentum for the time being is very strong. The other part is, if oil price stays very high, inflation, as you said, as the car, for example, with refrigerators, what you have, will go up &#x2013; inflation will go up and will eat into our overall growth rates. And then we have to look into what are the consequences out of it? Early &#x2013; too early to predict.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then the final question from Nobert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, a question on oil and gas. This week there was, I think, a statement from President of the Russia Gas Association saying perhaps the second stream of Nord Stream perhaps will not be built. Is there something behind that or is it only typical political discussion because you know better than me? And secondly, there is also often speculation about your contribution on South Stream. Can you elaborate a little bit on that? And the third part of this is regarding in the old what we have already discussed, often contract with Gazprom regards about gas spot prices. So it looks like a German competitor has failed. Have you been more successful, can you tell us about something?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to answer head-on. But now this has become three questions in one, and I have to transfer this to Hans-Ulrich.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let's start with question number one. I also read the newspaper, here is my conclusion based on the comment that Nord Stream will not be built. Either there was a mistake in translation or the statement was made very, very late at night. In any case, all I can tell you is with respect to the first pipe, it's being built, 1,000 kilometers of pipe are laid. There is 200 kilometers left. And we think that the first pipe will be laid completely sometime in the month of April, which then will give us the time to test. And there will be first gas in, as planned, on October 1, 2011, for the first pipe.</p>
          <p>And I am also sure since there is a significant part of the second pipe already laid, both in Russia and in Germany, that we will see gas in in the second pipe by October 1st of the year 2012. With respect to our contract portfolio, we have flexibility in our contract portfolio, both on the Eastern side and on the Western side. With respect to competitors, I cannot comment what kind of conditions they have.</p>
          <p>But if you look at the result of our gas business in the fourth quarter, you see that, yes, we have 20% less EBIT compared to Q4 of the year 2009. But I'd say overall in a difficult environment we did okay. Your third question was the South Stream question. That's asked many, many times, comes often. All I can say with respect to that is there are no concrete projects with respect to South Stream.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A final surprise for Laurent Favre in the back. Please put your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually it is two questions. It's on oil and gas, E&amp;P. You've talked about significant sales growth in E&amp;P for 2011. Now with pricing from $80 to $90 per barrel, you already get above 10%, so I'm just wondering excluding Libya, were you factoring in production growth?</p>
          <p>And then I think you made a comment on not being able to write-up assets on the E&amp;P side. Is that comment, I guess, reflected in the reserves down 1% year-on-year? In fact for some assets, you are now more positive than you were.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The second part of your question, I will have to ask in a second again to specify that please for me. On the first part of your question, did we plan an increase overall in our oil and gas production in 2011, yes, we did. Now with Libya we will have to see what the outcome will be and how long the production will be actually shut in. And on the second part of your question could you please be so kind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The write-up, will this be reflected &#x2013; as we do not have the right to write-up, whether this is reflected in the reserves?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That will be reflected in the reserves once we are able to show it in our reserves. At this point in time the five activities that I've mentioned earlier that we found in the year 2010 are not yet included in the reserves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So, ladies and gentlemen, this concludes our conference this afternoon. But before I let you go, I have to give you a couple of important dates, namely we will next report on our first quarter 2011 results on May 6, 2011 at 8.30 in the morning. The reason why so early because this is also the day of our Annual General Meeting. And then we will have a conference call.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, I would also like to invite you to our next events. We will have an Oil and Gas Investor Day that will take place on May 23rd in London, and a couple of days later on May 25th in New York.</p>
          <p>And furthermore, ladies and gentlemen, we will go west. Namely, we invite you to our annual roundtable on agricultural solutions on August 8, 2011 in the US. And I think it will be a great pleasure, because Monsanto will join us for the day. And also they have invited us that we can visit their field trial &#x2013; their trials in Illinois. So you're all very welcome to join us for this.</p>
          <p>So at this point, I think in the name of all of us, I would like to say thank you for coming today and thank you for listening via the Web. And should you have any further questions that we couldn't answer right now, then the entire IR team will be very happy to help you. So with this, we would like to say goodbye and so have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>