<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1243111" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>809</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Magdalena Moll, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Dr. Kurt Bock, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Dr. Hans-Ulrich Engel, Member of the Board of Executive Directors</participant>
      <participant id="4">Rhian Tucker</participant>
      <participant id="5">Andreas Heine</participant>
      <participant id="6">Peter Clark</participant>
      <participant id="7">Neil Tyler</participant>
      <participant id="8">Martin Evans</participant>
      <participant id="9">Sophie Jourdier</participant>
      <participant id="10">Martin Bruderm&#xFC;ller</participant>
      <participant id="11">Christian Faitz</participant>
      <participant id="12">Ronald K&#xF6;hler</participant>
      <participant id="13">Joe Dewhurst</participant>
      <participant id="14">Nobert Barth</participant>
      <participant id="15">Martin R&#xF6;diger</participant>
      <participant id="16">Karan Khemani</participant>
      <participant id="17">Tony Jones</participant>
      <participant id="18">Matthias Cornu</participant>
      <participant id="19">Fraser Hill</participant>
      <participant id="20">Paul Walsh</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. This is the Chorus Call conference operator. Welcome to the BASF Interim Report First Half Results 2009. As a reminder, all participants are in listen-only mode and the conference is being recorded. After the presentation there will be an opportunity to ask questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>This presentation includes forward-looking statements that are subject to risks and uncertainties, including those pertaining to the anticipated benefits to be realized from the proposals described herein. This presentation contains a number of forward-looking statements including, in particular, statements about future events, future financial performance, plans, strategies, expectations, prospects, competitive environment, regulation, and supply and demand. BASF has based these forward-looking statements on its views with respect to future events and financial performance. Actual financial performance of these entities described herein could differ materially from that projected in the forward-looking statements due to the inherent uncertainty of estimates, forecasts, and projections and financial performance may be better or worse than anticipated.</p>
          <p>Given these uncertainties, readers should not put undue reliance on any forward-looking statements. Forward-looking statements represent estimates and assumptions only as of the date that they were made. The information contained in this presentation is subject to change without notice and BASF does not undertake any duty to update the forward-looking statements and the estimates and assumptions associated with them, except to the extent required by applicable laws and regulations.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, at this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Magdalena Moll, Head of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. On behalf of BASF, I would like to welcome you to our second quarter 2009 conference call. BASF showed a robust performance in the still challenging business environment, and our comprehensive measures to reduce costs and improve efficiency are paying off.</p>
          <p>With me on the call today are Dr. Kurt Bock, our Chief Financial Officer, as well as Dr. Martin Bruderm&#xFC;ller and Dr. Hans-Ulrich Engel, both members of the Board of Executive Directors. Dr. Hambrecht cannot be here today. He had an appointment and he sends his best regards. Dr. Bock will explain how BASF is managing successfully through the crisis, review second quarter performance and describe what we currently see ahead. Then Dr. Engel will update you on the status of the Ciba integration, the targeted cost synergies and the next steps. Afterwards, all three gentlemen will be available to take your questions.</p>
          <p>Just as a usual reminder, today's conference call is limited to approximately one hour. Therefore I would like to ask you already now, to please limit your questions to only one at a time and then re-queue, so that we can take you for a second time. We have posted the presentations and the press documents on our website at basf.com/share.</p>
          <p>And with this, I would like to immediately hand over to Dr. Bock.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks, Magi and also welcome from my side. At our first quarter analysts' call three months ago, we indicated that visibility was very low and that we saw no signs of improvement ahead. We also predicted that the next couple of quarters would be extremely challenging. This assessment is still valid today. What we have seen is that business activity stabilized or even improved somewhat in the course of the second quarter. However, our customers continue to be very cautious and are conducting business with us on short notice. And there is still a long list of economic stress sectors. Increasing unemployment and possible tax increases will burden private consumption. The financial system is still fragile and the availability of credit poses a threat to economic recovery. It is also likely that the effect of stimulus packages will fizzle out. We are still in the midst of a global crisis with major impacts on most industries, including the chemical industry.</p>
          <p>In 2009, we expect global chemical production to return to the level of 2005. This means that we will be confronted with overcapacities in many areas, which will put continuing pressures on margins. Short-term measures alone will not be sufficient to solve the structural problems of the chemical industry. Capacities need to be taken out of the market permanently, and this is something that the entire industry has to contribute to. BASF has been at the forefront of consolidating the production base. Since beginning of this year, we have either closed or divested six plants, especially the Coatings and Styrenics Divisions. You can be sure more will follow shortly.</p>
          <p>Let me now show how we have coped with this challenging business conditions in the second quarter. In terms of cash generation, we once again successfully improved. Operating cash flow amounted to &#x20AC;1.6 billion, after &#x20AC;2 billion in the first quarter driven by further reductions in net working capital. BASF's chemical activities continued to be affected by weak demand and pressure on prices. In Q2, earnings from chemical activities fell by almost 50%, compared with the same quarter last year, but improved compared with the first quarter.</p>
          <p>In contrast, Agricultural Solutions again delivered an excellent performance. On April 9 we acquired Ciba, which is now included for the first time in our figures. Integration already resulted in significant one-time costs of around &#x20AC;300 million in the past quarter. This includes the amortization of the step-up on inventories and the write-down related to Ciba's IT SAP system. Given the continuously weak economic climate, the seasonal nature of our business and the integration charges related to Ciba, we do not anticipate an improvement in earnings in the second half of 2009. Consequently, it's unlikely that we'll reach our goal to earn our cost on capital in 2009.</p>
          <p>I assume all of you are already familiar with our Q2 numbers, so I will only highlight some key figures. Year-on-year EBIT before special items dropped by 53% to &#x20AC;1.1 billion. This included strong earnings from our Agricultural Solutions segment. The decline in earnings for the entire BASF Group was mainly attributable to the significant drop in volumes and margins in our chemical activities. On top of this, earnings from Oil and Gas halved as a result of the sharp decline in oil prices.</p>
          <p>Net income amounted to &#x20AC;343 million, down 74%, and earnings per share dropped to &#x20AC;0.37 per share compared with &#x20AC;1.39 in the second quarter of 2008. We further increased transparency. We are reporting an adjusted EPS figure for the first time today. Adjusted for special items and depreciation on intangible assets, earnings per share amounted to &#x20AC;0.79 compared to &#x20AC;1.54 last year. You can find the reconciliation of these figures on page 33 of our quarterly report.</p>
          <p>For 2009, we have set ourselves a target of generating a cash flow -- cash inflow of at least &#x20AC;1 billion by reducing net working capital. By the end of the first quarter, we had exceeded this target by &#x20AC;500 million. A &#x20AC;2.3 billion free cash flow was, again, high, mainly due to the further improvement in net working capital. We are striving to improve even further, but the pace of net working capital reduction is likely to be slower. Cash used for the Ciba acquisition amounted to &#x20AC;1.7 billion. For the payment of the 2008 dividend, BASF spent an additional &#x20AC;2 billion in cash.</p>
          <p>Let's now look at the business development in the second quarter in more detail with emphasis on major changes compared to the first quarter of this year. This is the third consecutive quarter with volumes steeply below last year's levels. Sales declined by 23% year-on-year with volumes and prices dropping 18 and 13% respectively. The sales decline was partially offset by portfolio changes, in particular Ciba, which amounted to, for roughly 5 percentage points. And positive currency effect as a result of the appreciation of the U.S. dollar.</p>
          <p>Compared with the first quarter, volumes, excluding Oil and Gas, volumes went up by 17% reflecting the restocking after drastic demand destruction in January and February of this year. Prices came down further by 2%, indicating the weak supply/demand situation in almost all of our businesses. The highest volume improvement we saw in Asia, where volumes already exceeded the 2008 average.</p>
          <p>I will now briefly explain the business development of the individual segments focusing again on Q2 versus Q1. Chemicals benefited from improved volumes, particularly in Asia. In Europe and North America demand for cracker products remained low. Naphtha prices continued their way up. It remained difficult to pass on higher raw material costs to customers via prices increases and so margins remained unsatisfactory. Better Asian demand and the end of the destocking in the textile value chain lifted volumes in intermediates, in particular in the butanediol value chain. Our measures to reduce fixed costs and to optimize production processes contributed strongly to the sharp increase in earnings since March.</p>
          <p>Volumes in Plastics increased by more than 25% with prices further weakening. Major customer industries such as construction and textiles as well as all regions, especially Asia, contributed to this upward trend. Volumes of polyamide, TDI and MDI started to recover in the second quarter, but prevailing overcapacities made it difficult to pass on higher feedstock costs, especially for benzene, toluene and propylene. Nevertheless, segment earnings were positive again thanks to higher capacity utilization rates and successful fixed cost reductions.</p>
          <p>Improved demand in most business resulted in higher volumes in all divisions of the Performance Products segment. We managed to improve margins overall and our continued efforts to reduce fixed costs are showing effect in all divisions. The activities of Ciba, which are reported as a separate division in this quarter, posted a significant loss before special items. Special items of almost 300 million reported in this segment alone were mainly due to the amortization of the Ciba inventory step-up and the partial write-down of Ciba's IT system, which will be replaced by BASF's SAP platform. From Q3 onward, Ciba's businesses will be integrated into the new divisional structure, which Hans-Ulrich will explain in a few minutes.</p>
          <p>Functional Solutions continued to be impacted by the weak automotive industry. The mobile emission catalysts and the OEM coatings businesses were affected by continued low vehicle production combined with a trend towards smaller cars and engines.</p>
          <p>The construction industry showed a mixed picture with good demand coming from emerging Asia and the Middle East, while Europe and North America experienced only a subdued seasonal upturn. Fixed cost reductions and restructuring measures, especially in Coatings and Construction Chemicals, contributed substantially to the positive earnings swing.</p>
          <p>As we have often pointed out, we think in half-year periods rather than in quarters in the Crop Protection business. We had an excellent start into 2009. Here you'll see the performance comparison of our Ag business the first half of 2009 versus the first half of last year. Higher prices, positive currency effects as well as the acquired Sorex business more than offset a slight decline in volumes.</p>
          <p>Adverse weather conditions in North America led to delayed cultivation, and the season for cereals and canola started late in Europe, resulting in lower usage of our products. At &#x20AC;711 million, EBIT before special items reached a new record level in the first half of 2009. We are confident that our Crop Protection business will again exceed our own internal EBIT and EBITDA margin of 25% at least.</p>
          <p>Seasonally lower sales in Natural Gas Trading were mainly responsible for the 30% drop in earnings in the Oil and Gas segment to &#x20AC;506 million. Besides warmer weather conditions, lower demand from industrial customers and power plants resulted in a substantial reduction in volumes and Natural Gas Trading. Volumes in Exploration and Production increased slightly thanks to higher production from the Siberian gas field Yuzhno Russkoye, which also means a swing to more gas production. Driven by a 33% increase of the oil price to US$59 per barrel, earnings in E&amp;P almost reached the high level posted in the first quarter. Non-deductible oil taxes included in earnings were &#x20AC;226 million, up from &#x20AC;154 million in Q1 and down by &#x20AC;351 million compared to Q2 2008. Net income after minority interest was &#x20AC;181 million in the Oil and Gas business compared with &#x20AC;230 million last year.</p>
          <p>Let me now highlight a few topics in Others. Styrenics sales increased by 17% compared with the first quarter 2009 as a result of higher volumes in all regions. Earnings more than doubled in the second quarter, in particular thanks to our ongoing restructuring measures and to the contribution of styrenic polymers. The higher costs in Others were mainly caused by higher accruals for BASF's options program following the share price increase. On the other hand we also confirmed currency hedging not allocated to the divisions were lower versus the previous quarter. Compared to the same quarter of last year, however, earnings in the second quarter of this year dropped substantially, mainly due to significant unrealized losses from currency hedging, as well as expenses related to BASF's option program. In contrast, the result of the prior year quarter contained high, again, unrealized earnings from raw material hedging explaining the swing in earnings.</p>
          <p>Now turning over to our financials, you can see the impact of the Ciba acquisition on our balance sheet. It resulted in additions to total assets of &#x20AC;5.7 billion. This figure comprises 1.6 billion in tangible assets &#x2013; thereof 0.8 billion in goodwill. &#x20AC;2.1 billion in tangible fixed assets and approximately &#x20AC;2 billion in short-term assets mainly inventories and receivables. Net debt of BASF Group was &#x20AC;14.3 billion compared to &#x20AC;10.2 billion at the end of the first quarter. The increase reflects the acquisition of Ciba. Without Ciba, net debt would have increased by &#x20AC;1.2 billion to &#x20AC;11.4 billion. Looking at this figure you also have to keep in mind that in May BASF paid out &#x20AC;2 billion in dividends.</p>
          <p>Now let me hand over to Hans-Ulrich, who will give you an update on the Ciba integration before I will conclude with the outlook for 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kurt, and good afternoon everyone. We are now coming to the integration of Ciba which we acquired on April 9th of this year. First, I would like to reemphasize that despite the current challenging market environment, the strategic rationale for the acquisition of Ciba remains unchanged. In the acquisition of Ciba, BASF has become the leading player in specialty chemicals in the following areas. In the global plastic additives market we have achieved the leading position as the largest producer of light stabilizers and antioxidants. We have created a world-class coating effects materials provider, and can now offer our customers the entire product range from resins and pigments to additives. The combined paper chemicals business offers the broadest and most comprehensive portfolio of paper chemicals, including process, functional and coating chemicals.</p>
          <p>With the restructuring of the business announced from the outset of the acquisition we are taking the lead in the urgently needed consolidation of the paper chemicals market. In addition, promising niche businesses in attractive growth markets, like UV protection, biocides or chemicals for oil field and mining are now strengthening the BASF portfolio. During the discovery phase, we defined the allocation of the Ciba businesses to the segment Performance Products and started to implement the structure as of July 1, 2009. In order to best serve our markets and customers, we have chosen a market approach in principle rather than a value chain approach. You will find an overview of the integration of Ciba's businesses into BASF structures in today's presentation documents; therefore I will not go into more detail here.</p>
          <p>In the past three months we analyzed Ciba's businesses in detail. The discovery phase fully confirmed the strategic fit of the acquisition and also revealed some interesting differences in the way Ciba and BASF were running their businesses. Ciba's businesses were, irrespective of their size, organized as global business units. These businesses are being integrated into our regional business units in order to ensure good ongoing customer relationships, as well as to realize a maximum of synergies. Ciba offered a very broad portfolio of products and services. BASF will differentiate the portfolio and implement appropriate business models for the specialty parts of the portfolio, offering the full range of products and services and access to the outstanding expertise of the company. Whereas in the commodity part of the business, a lean and reliable business model will offer standard setting quality and reliability at, most importantly, competitive prices. BASF will also focus the combined R&amp;D activities on the most promising growth markets and concentrate research in a limited number of research centers. Applying BASF's Verbund concept, there is ample opportunity to improve the global production set up and logistics network of the combined businesses.</p>
          <p>BASF will also apply its best practices to functional services like Procurement, IT, Finance and Accounting and HR. These service functions will be integrated into BASF's global competence centers, regional functional units and shared service platforms to provide high-quality services and use economies of scale.</p>
          <p>In order to fully exploit the potential of the joint businesses, extensive restructuring measures are required. Restructuring plants include a reduction of approximately 3,700 positions, the majority of which will be eliminated by the end of 2010. Driven by the consolidation of corporate functions, roughly 60% of this head count reduction will take place in Europe. BASF is currently reviewing strategic options, restructuring, sale or closure for 23 of the 55 former Ciba production sites worldwide. Nearly half of the sites under review are in Europe, where Ciba had the majority of its production sites. Final decisions about these sites will be made by the end of the first quarter of 2010. The remaining 32 production sites will be optimized or restructured as part of BASF's global production network. By the end of 2010, we will have also closed more than half of Ciba's 70 sales and administrative offices and research sites. The review of these sites is still ongoing in order to achieve maximum synergies. At the beginning of the discovery phase, we announced target cost synergies of at least &#x20AC;400 million per year equal to 10% of Ciba's 2008 sales. We are now confident to attain this target by 2012 with &#x20AC;300 million on an annual basis already achieved by the end of 2010.</p>
          <p>Cost synergies stem from consolidation of corporate functions and site closures as well as the optimization of marketing and sales structures, R&amp;D and procurement. These main categories will contribute roughly equally to the cost synergies achieved by 2012. The synergies are associated with corresponding integration costs. We expect total cash costs of approximately &#x20AC;550 million. A major portion thereof will be severance costs. The remaining part is largely attributable to site optimization and the implementation of the ERP system. In 2009, we estimate to incur cash costs of &#x20AC;150 million. In addition to cash costs, we expect non-cash costs in the amount of about &#x20AC;500 million. The final amount will depend on the result of the purchase price allocation, which will be available by Q4 of this year and the number of sites we will exit from. In 2009, we will incur non-cash costs of about &#x20AC;400 million, of which &#x20AC;300 million were already recorded in the second quarter 2009 as special items. These are related, in particular, to the step-up of inventories and accelerated depreciation of Ciba's IT system.</p>
          <p>Our target is to keep the integration phase as short as possible in order to fully concentrate on profitably growing the combined businesses. We therefore plan to conclude all major structural integration measures by the end of the first quarter next year. To be more specific, implementation of BASF's SAP system and go-live in all regions going hand in hand with the harmonization of processes, migration of finance, accounting and HR services to BASF's service platforms, restructuring of legal entitles, completion of major rebranding activities, decisions on sites currently under review.</p>
          <p>As you can see, we made significant progress over the last three months with the integration of Ciba. The detailed integration roadmap is clearly defined. We have about 80 teams worldwide involved in the integration work in order to get through the integration phase as quickly as possible. With that we will fully deliver on the strategic targets of the acquisition, the synergies announced and concentrate on the profitable growth of the joint businesses. With that, back to you, Kurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks Hans. Finally to the outlook of 2009, I'm sure you all have already seen this, anyway the business environment is extremely difficult due to the global economic crisis, and this will present BASF with some exceptional challenges in 2009. All segments except for Agricultural Solutions are affected by the recession. However, the indications are that the situation is stabilizing at a low level. In North America the slump appears to be bottoming out and China is again beginning to see stronger growth. Nevertheless, a sustained upturn is not yet in sight. Restocking in several industries and regions as well as economic stimulus packages are improving demand, but generally only in the short term. The global financial system remains fragile; overcapacity and rising unemployment are also depressing the situation further.</p>
          <p>In view of the current economic environment and the expenses resulting from the Ciba integration, we anticipate a significant decline in sales and earnings in 2009. Therefore, BASF is unlikely to earn its cost of capital. We will, therefore, continue to forcefully execute our operational excellence by acting quickly and decisively. We will continue to tailor production to reflect worldwide demand. We will further maintain strict cost control, spending and capital discipline, in order to secure our strong cash flow and solid financing. And at the same time, we will ensure our future growth by keeping R&amp;D expenditures at a high level and by investing into high growth markets like China.</p>
          <p>Thanks for your attention and we are now happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very gentlemen. And we are now coming to the question and answer session. And the first question is coming from Rhian Tucker [Credit Suisse].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thanks for taking my question. I was pleased to see in the presentation a sequential progress from each of the divisions. The EBIT improvement in some of your divisions, particularly Chemicals, Plastics, Functional Solutions was pretty impressive. Can you go through that sequential quarter-on-quarter EBIT improvement, and try and give us some clarification on how much of that was due to restructuring and how much was due to, let's say lower raw materials or some other form of margin improvement? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rhian, I will try to give you a general answer and maybe we can then become more specific looking at Plastics, which is quite an interesting development in Q2. What we can say, there was really no relief from the fixed costs side in the second quarter. Actually, we had quite a margin squeeze, because our fixed costs have gone up quite dramatically when you compare it with Q1 and we were not able to pass on those cost increases simultaneously to our customers. So, the EBIT increase improvement is partially due to the higher volumes, which we had and higher capacity utilization rates and most importantly we made quite some progress with regard to our costs. This is an ongoing effort as you know and we estimate that in the first half of 2009 we are able to manage down our fixed costs by somehow &#x20AC;0.5 billion. You don't see this reflected immediately in our bottom line, because at the same time, we are still incurring very, very high cost of idle unused capacities as you can imagine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, particularly in the Plastics business, I basically can add what Kurt said, we had a strong volume development in Q2, that was very much driven from Asia, because we have certainly, particularly in China, by the stimulus program a stronger demand, which is however to question how sustainable it is because the stimulus program is very much front loaded now with loans going into the industry and very much infrastructure driven, not so much consumer oriented, for that reason a lot of the customers cannot give indications for the future. We have on the other hand done quite some restructuring also in, particularly in the Styrenics business. You have read that we have taken some measures there. For example, to shutdown part of the capacity here in Ludwigshafen, on the polystyrene side and we have also announced that we are going to close or divest the styrenics monomer plant in Korea. I think these are clear messages into the market that we have to go on restructuring measures and bring supply and demand more in balance again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Andreas Heine [UniCredit MIB (HVB)].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I have a question regarding your outlook for the second half and your earnings. I assume that you are referring to the EBIT after special items, as this is the base for the calculation of earning cost of capital. If you go to the EPS adjusted value, strip out special items and depreciation of intangibles, is that also true that then the second half will be worse than the first half, and does that only in effect the seasonal effects you have? So, high earnings in the first half of agricultural products, or does it also mean in general that the conditions for the industrial business will worsen in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Mr. Andreas, that's a tricky one. Actually the adjusted EPS, we are providing as a service to you. We have no intention to guide you on adjusted EPS, I mean that is really your job, I think. With regard to not earning our cost on capital, that clearly reflects also our special items, because that calculation is based at the end of the day on our bottom line total income, including special items, EBIT after special items, and seasonal effects you are aware that we have seasonal up tick always in the first half with regard to agricultural products and also the natural gas business. Those businesses will have weaker second half normally. We also expect that the fourth quarter will be better than the third quarter, but frankly again our visibility is still very, very limited, we can only witness that our customers are also very, very insecure ordering on a very short notice. So it's extremely difficult to become more precise with regard to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was more referring to the line you have chosen as follow-up, seasonal effects, and secondly, the heavy load of the restructuring will be in the second half. So, this &#x2013; all of that included means, that the second half will be worse. So, it's not referring to any...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When we talk about our business, we always talk about EBIT before special items, that is the number we guide normally and we are quite skeptical that in that respect, the second half would automatically become better than the first half of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's all I have. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually you asked now three questions, not two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Peter Clark from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. It's just on the Ciba. You make it quite clear the business is still in loss, I'm just wondering if that is on an underlying basis. And you also obviously, regarding the Ciba, Q1 you said it was in loss there, obviously one of Ciba's peers has reported numbers that showed a better Q2 on Q1. I'm just wondering what the trend is? So trying to get the clean number in Ciba on EBIT in Q2 and whether it's better than Q1, 2 thrown in 1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is Hans Engel. And unfortunately as you know, we don't provide information on EBIT figures below the segment level in our respective segments. But it's fair to assume that with respect to Ciba, there is a significant loss in Q2, you've seen us recording 300 million in special items, which heavily burdened the business. On the underlying performance I can tell you that, if you look at it on a Q2 to Q2 basis, in other words you compare Q2 2009 to Q2 2008, the sales are down by roughly 25%, which is about the same as you can see overall in the performance products segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are now coming to the next question from Neil Tyler from JP Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon. A question on capacity, <mark type="inaudible" /> (32.46) Bock you mentioned the heavy burden of under absorbed costs, I wonder if you could talk a little bit about sequential developments in operating rates, to as much &#x2013; I appreciate as much detail as you can give really, where you stand at the end of &#x2013; stood at the end of June, versus the start of April in terms of operating rates, both of &#x2013; I suppose may impact more usefully, of available capacity, so to post your closures both permanent and temporary? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, certainly Neil. At the last call we said that our capacity utilization rate is well below 60%. That was at the end of Q1, also reflecting a very, very weak start into the New Year, January was just horrible. In Q2, utilization rates came up naturally given the volume trend and are now slightly above 60% and if you ask then about a trend within Q2, the June was a little bit better than April. But again is that a trend, we don't think so. This is just reflecting very short-term order coming in from our customers and we cannot really identify any clear trend looking at those numbers. So, all in all we are still operating about 20 to 25%, about below normal utilization rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Martin Evans from Cazenove. Please go ahead Martin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. Kurt, just a question on the potential restocking, we obviously heard a lot about destocking, which appears to be, in most areas largely over. In previous cycles, if you get a sort of mini buying frenzy, as customers try to restock quickly, and given inventory level is very low and utilization rates very low, that of course is possible again this time. Do you think that could happen later this year, which essentially could create some shortages of chemical products which will obviously work in your favor in terms of prices? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Martin, you're certainly right. We have seen this in the past. And what we experienced, what we call a normal business or chemical cycle. I'm not sure we are seeing or facing right now a normal cyclical development, right now. This is the deepest economic crisis we have ever seen. Are our customers concerned about lack of supply? I'm not sure, I don't think so. They certainly look at raw material costs. They have noticed that feedstock costs went up quite a bit in some areas, they spiked recently like benzene. That might propel one or the other customers to buy some stuff, ahead of maybe further price increases, but all in all it looks to me that &#x2013; like our customers are pretty relaxed about the supply situation. They are certainly not relaxed about the demand, market situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the next question comes from Sophie Jourdier from Citigroup. Hello, Sophie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Yes, just on capacity again. You mentioned that in the first half you've closed or divested six plants. I just wondered across your major product ranges, whether you've seen any competitors do the same and if so, could you just &#x2013; if you could just highlight those areas? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that was hard to hear. Can you repeat that again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh sorry, is that better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Whether we have seen any competitive what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you mentioned you closed down six sites or divested six sites in the first half. I wondered in any of your major product ranges whether you have seen similar moves by &#x2013; made by any of your peers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Magi, it's Martin Bruderm&#xFC;ller. I have some comments on the plastics area. I think there you had seen some movement in the whole Styrenics area there I would say across the board you have measures from some Japanese players, also Dow has closed something in China. So I would say all the players are looking into their capacities and shutdown minor competitive plants for the future. I think one other measures &#x2013; measure which is reasonable to mention is the decision of Invista to shut down its built-in facilities on nylon. I think this is also a very clear message of the market leader in the Nylon 6,6 to shutdown. So I think across the board, we can see that minor competitive assets will go out of supply in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sophie, let me just add one topic here which is really about the general picture, when you look at for instance the cracker capacity, much capacity has been taken out of the market, many plants has been idled. It needs to be seen what's going to be restarted and you know for instance that we shutdown one of our crackers here in Ludwigshafen.  In general, we believe that BASF as one of the bigger companies and certainly a market leader in many cases has a certain responsibility to also go ahead here of the pack and just do the things which we think are necessary right now to adjust capacity. Sometimes it's painful. We have seen in the past that ultimately other companies will follow through, and I think in general we can say that BASF has quite cost effective production side, especially when we look at our competition right now. So let's assume that some of our competitors are operating almost at cash loss right now and that might propel further shutdowns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, we're moving onto Christian Faitz from Oppenheimer Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. I just have a question on the agro sides, if my numbers are correct your fungicide business performed better in H1 compared to the respective businesses of your main peers. How do you explain that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that can be easily explained by the good products we have in our pipeline, our portfolio. We have a very, very competitive fungicide product pipeline, as you know we are actually very proud of our portfolio here and it worked out quite nicely. And frankly, Mr. Faitz, we had expected even a little bit of a better business.  We saw a certain slowdown over the course of the second quarter partially for instance due to the drought in Argentina, which has affected our business. But all in all we are very pleased with the development of our Ag business in 2009 so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's very helpful to know.  But again I would have expected a worse performance looking at the weather conditions in the Northern Hemisphere.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, that we disappointed you...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can't do anything about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if you disappoint me, I might have a follow-up question on the chemicals side. Do you feel you could run into a summer dip looking at extended holidays at some of your major customers versus the previous years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is no indication for a real summer dip. As Kurt already mentioned, I think customers throughout the portfolio are ordering smaller quantities, shorter terms. So, that means they basically do not have longer planning, and so we don't see across the board something like this in a very distinct manner this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, we're coming to Ronald K&#xF6;hler from MainFirst.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding your <mark type="inaudible" /> rate. Actually, I heard <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ronald, it is impossible to hear you, you probably...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sorry, okay. I'll try it again. Actually it's regarding your cracker utilization rate, I heard that your crackers in Europe and in Asia are currently fully utilized and I guess that it's obviously due to unplanned cracker shutdowns in Europe, even some good demand that you could think about restarting your smaller cracker in Ludwigshafen, any chance to look at that?</p>
          <p>And in addition obviously is the part cracker is right now in a disadvantage using naphtha versus others using cheap raw material natural gas. How do you see that disadvantage going on in the future? And is there any risk that you will stay with uncompetitive cracker in North America for longer time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So first on Asia, Nanchang is several months almost fully loaded. This is in correspondence to the quantities we see increasing in Asia, mainly in China. Once ending Ludwigshafen, we have two crackers, this is the older one, small one, with 200,000 roughly and another one 420,000. And we have shutdown in most part the small one to fully load the big one and this is one of the reactions we can do in Liverpool, which gives us quite some flexibility to react to external market conditions.</p>
          <p>In the moment we don't see any indication to startup the small one again, but we certainly have this flexibility once it would pickup. But we expect that we go on with this situation to run the bigger cracker full out in Ludwigshafen for the next month. Maybe if Kurt, some comment on Port Arthur.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, maybe I'll just add quickly, a few comments on Port Arthur. You're certainly right, it's no real big fun to crack naphtha, given the price that ranges between naphtha and natural gas. But you &#x2013; I think your numbers are clear that our cracker complex in Port Arthur is quite a complex or complicated animal, where we can do much more than just cracking naphtha. We have a very good C4 stream there, as well which is actually short right now. So, I think the overall complex is doing relatively well. What we are working on is really feedstock flexibility. We think we can provide more flexible feedstock for that cracker was relatively low investment and that is one of the ideas we are tempering right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Joe Dewhurst from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. I just like to actually ask about the auto-catalysts business. And just, first of all any views around when that might return to stronger profitability, and whether there is anything you can do from an internal point of view, say from self-help that would also improve profitability in the segment? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think Mr. Dewhurst, I think you asked about the Catalysts business right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had very bad connection.  Catalysts is in a tough situation as you can imagine, simply reflecting the difficult situation of the automotive industry. The only region where in automotive Catalysts we see a good business development is really Asia, that's growing very nicely. And as you all know, this year China will already produce and sell more cars than the United States, which is, I think it's quite a dramatic change we are facing. North America still very weak, which is further impaired by the trend to smaller cars and smaller engines, as I mentioned in my little speech.</p>
          <p>What is important from our point of view, we are not losing market share. But we are certainly disadvantaged for the time being by having a relatively high exposure to the North American market. And it's too early to say when that market will ultimately recover. We really don't want to speculate on that and all the messages we get from our customers in North America are also very short-term focused.</p>
          <p>There is another piece in our Catalysts business, which is really Chemical Catalysts. And Chemical Catalysts had a very difficult second quarter, basically reflecting the lack of investment in the chemical industry. And also the fact that maintenance spending has been cut by most companies and that is then reflected in the reduced need of catalysts. Also certainly driven by lower volumes, if you produce less you also need less catalyst replacement in your chemical plants. What is doing very nicely right now is refinery catalysts, that's the third leg of our business. They had a good first half in 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Nobert Barth from WestLB.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. One further question on possible shutdowns in the future, because you mentioned there will be further following this year. Can you a little bit more elaborate about the lines &#x2013; the main product lines, where you expect that and where you believe you could be at your utilization rate at the end of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer to the second question, I simply don't know. If I knew, I might even tell you, but I really simply don't know. The answer to the first question, shutdowns, I mean we have a certain process, how we go through this. We make a decision, then we talk with all the affected employees and communities and then we go to the public and we should really stick to that process, it has served us very well in the past. I can only ask you for your understanding here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from Martin R&#xF6;diger from Cheuvreux.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Concerning the financial result in the second quarter, I've seen strong income from companies accounted for using the extreme method of 60 million and other income from participation of 69 million. Can you elaborate what's behind these figures and what is a good run rate for modeling?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is basically income from equity consolidated companies. That is very hard to model, because it very much reflects how these companies are doing. It can change from quarter-to-quarter. We never really guided on those specific earnings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And there is nothing &#x2013; no major points to mention here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What has changed over the last two years is basically that we have now a major operation in Russia, that is our gas exploration and production activity, which we conduct together with gas, from its called Yuzhno Russkoye. And that is consolidated at equity and those earnings fluctuate to a certain degree, also depending on the currency development, ruble versus euro, which is quite volatile as we have all witnessed it over the last few quarters. And that partially explains the swing in the equity result.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Karan Khemani from Cazenove.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Mr. Bock. Can you comment on your glyphosate product and what headwinds if any you experienced in the first half of this year within Agricultural Solutions? Secondly, in the recent environment where Middle Eastern capacity expansion is underway, can you confirm if you're net long ethylene and net short propylene? And as a business how well hedged are you? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have one question. So you might pick, because there are so many other people still waiting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am good if any of those are answered. So, Mr. Bock, I'll leave it to you to answer it, whichever one you prefer answering.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's make it very short on the first one, we don't comment on individual products. And as you know, we are not a glyphosate producer. We are not in that business line. And with that I would hand over to Martin and he will speak to the second question quickly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You mentioned capacities coming on stream from Middle East this is right. I think it started last year and will continue over the next year with more and more capacity coming. This is mainly first generation derivatives based on the olefins which is not so much in the overlap of BASF portfolio as you know, as we are no longer in the poly-olefins and polypropylene business. There's a sight overlap with the ethylene glycol businesses certainly flowing into China. The effect markets over there put local producers certainly a little bit under pressure. However, China will remain a net importer for those products.</p>
          <p>So, it is not so much a threat for BASF as the overlap with our portfolio is relatively low. In total, you are right, we are basically a C3 based company. So, we are &#x2013; on the other hand, use the C2 we produce in major sophisticated products. So, not in polyethylene and ethylene glycol mainly, but in higher value-added products and we have a very short position on selling on the market, it's roughly only 5% of the ethylene BASF produce which is sold into the market. And on the other hand we are pretty much a C3 based company and with this we basically use our own material and additionally buy C3 on the market and I think this gives us a relatively comfortable situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Tony Jones from Redburn. Please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, good afternoon. Just a quick question in terms of your split between fixed and variable costs. You've been quite clear that you've been working really hard to try and reduce your fixed costs position through the first half of the year. And my sort of original assumption was that, it was at low 30's to high 60's ratio. Just wanted to understand whether that's changing now substantially, especially with some of the margin improvement we've seen from Q1 to Q2?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that hasn't really changed essentially, that's still pretty much what we see. I mean, frankly since variable costs have come down year-over-year, because we have seen a dramatic drop in raw material costs compared with last year. The share of fixed costs naturally goes a little bit up, in terms of breakeven point it hasn't really changed compared with last year.  Frankly given the fixed cost improvements that we have made over the course of the last six months, we might even have been able to bring it down slightly, not including the cost of idle capacity, which I mentioned early on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Matthias Cornu from Exane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Good afternoon and just like to come back on capacity question. So, you mentioned overcapacities in many markets like polyamides, TDIs, Styrenics, or cracker products. I just wonder if you expect more pressure on prices going forward and maybe a less favorable balance between prices and actually rising raw material costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gee, that is the, the essential question are do we gain pricing power or not over the next couple of quarters, it's simply too early to say. We have seen some businesses where improved volumes have helped us quite a bit and we clearly favor as a company, what we call a value over volume strategy, pushing for better margins and better prices and not just trying to sell stuff so to say. But it's really too early to say when the inflection point will happen that we will really regain pricing power as we have seen it in 2007 and 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Neil Tyler, JP Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hello again. The second question on Ciba, could you just explain quickly the &#x2013; how the step-up in inventory impacted the underlying result.  So, whether that meant that the Ciba was absorbing higher cost inventory in the second quarter, please. And the other part of the question on Ciba is, is it right to interpret your slight change in guidance as really just being driven by the more significant restructuring charge at Ciba, than anything else that's changed over the last three months?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Neil, this is Hans. I'll address the first part of your question. Inventory step-up and underlying performance, you don't see that in the underlying performance because the inventory step-up is shown in our special items and forms part of the 300 million that we booked in Q2.  The 210 million inventory step-up that we have is fully reflected in the Q2 special item results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But it's not the amortization of the inventory step-up. The inventory itself been revalued upwards and therefore being booked through cost of goods sold at a higher level, or am I my misunderstanding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's a &#x2013; sorry this sounds again, I think that's than a misunderstanding on your side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your second question was whether our guidance is basically driven by Ciba?  No, that's not the case. We are looking at business fundamentals. Or &#x2013; the underlying businesses trends, which we see across all of our businesses, certainly incurring now the special costs from Ciba doesn't help, but frankly we already had a good feeling or estimation for the magnitude of those costs when we provide the guidance for Q1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Q1 earnings call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I understand. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Fraser Hill [Merrill Lynch Global Securities].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I just wanted to come back to the cost saving comment that you made half a billion in the first half of this year. Is that half a billion in the context of the next cost savings that you announced at the back end of last year, or do you now envisage that you can put that little bit more out of the cost base as dictated by the severity of this crisis. Should we expect more than a billion or is it now 0.5 billion achieved from that 1 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next program aims at saving about 1 billion at the end of 2012, the savings which we have achieved so far in 2009 only partially reflects the next program. A good portion of those savings have nothing to do with next, I give you just one example, travel expenses have come down throughout BASF by 40 to 50% worldwide, and that makes quite a difference to our bottom line as you can imagine. So we are trying to cut back on all, what we call, unnecessary or discretionary costs, plus the restructuring efforts which we have mentioned, the shutdown of plants et cetera, and that goes behind the next program but what I can say the next program is well on track to achieve its target by 2012 as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a follow up question from Sophie Jourdier [Citigroup].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks very much. I just wondered visibility is low, but looking into what you're seeing in July.  The volume recovery you've seen through the second quarter, whether that's being maintained and what you're seeing on raw material costs going into the third quarter? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Raw material costs are a concern right now, with the dollar price, the oil price is pretty high and after reflecting this, we don't need high oil price frankly. Given the situation of our economy and of our company, and the volume improvement in Q2 that is compared with again a very, very weak Q1 and the terrible January &#x2013; month of January. And we are still at a very low level and we are still very cautious to interpret this as anything, which could only come close to being sustainable. What we see, we believe is basically restocking effort by our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul Walsh from Morgan Stanley would like to put the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Just really on strategic solutions for any businesses that you see as non-core, obviously the paper and leather markets in particular. There has been a lot of speculation as to how that's going to pan out particularly in Europe over the coming 12 months. I just wondered if you could be drawn on any comments on where you see opportunities to consolidate markets to bring pricing power back into the equation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, what you normally see in this situation is that people are thinking about consolidating capacities and sometimes it could create opportunities for BASF as well. In terms of restructuring, we have two businesses where we publicly announced that we are thinking about doing something differently, that is our Styrenics business and also our textiles and leather businesses, and these are ongoing projects where we cannot really comment at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just follow-up on that and just ask is Europe the main focus for you in terms of those markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, these are global operations actually and when you talk about textile and leather, the major part of the business is already in Asia, including major pieces of our production as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we have two final questions. One coming from Ronald K&#xF6;hler, MainFirst and the second one from Tony Jones, Redburn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just again on the guidance actually, you obviously changed that earning of cost of capital fund increasingly difficulty to unlikely, coming back to the question that was asked before, is it not driven by more special items, though you actually said no, which means did you see anything negatively changing in Q2 versus your previous expectations? Can you little bit elaborate on that, what is operation or where was your original planning?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sorry Mr. K&#xF6;hler that I cannot help you any &#x2013; any better here. We can only comment on what we see right now. It's still a very, very weak situation. If we get the price on the upside that's fine with us, but right now we prepare ourselves for continuously difficult operating conditions and we implement this throughout our company with regard to costs, et cetera, and the change in guidance. I mean you quoted us correctly. From today's point of view, it's pretty unlikely that we are on our cost of capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But the change is driven by that the upturn was not as strong as you had hoped so to say when you last time provided the guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean you know that we are very cautious people. I mean when we said it's a very, very difficult to run our costs of capital, we had nine months to go. Now we have six months to go and that makes a big, big difference in terms of how much time do we have to still earn our cost on capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Final question is from Tony Jones, Redburn Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just quick question on pricing and contracts for your &#x2013; for some non-spot business, normally my understanding here is that the way this works is that the pricing is adjusted retrospectively, usually indexed to some feedstock and I understand that used to be on three months lag, but you've now reduced that to one month. Does that mean, as we go into Q3, we should start to see some of the pricing increases for some feedstock filter through to your revenues? Is that the case, or are we seeing customers breaking these terms, because there is a lower buy power &#x2013; lower pricing power in the industry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is very difficult to answer, because this is really a mixed bag. You have all kind of contracts and on one hand specialty business. We definitely don't link to raw materials because we really want to decouple from raw materials, because we want to have certain (1.01.15) margins. On the other hand some commodities have certainly a price link and this is sometimes a month delay or it is a kind of an average about the last month. So, this is also very difficult to basically say something across the border for the portfolio.</p>
          <p>There is one major change, I think we have seen this is the olefin pricing in Europe, which was quarterly pricing, which now in this situation obviously I think in the favor of all the market participants, basically changed to a monthly price. So, this is a major change, but I think this allows all the market participants to react more flexibly in that respect and maybe one remark, which is, I think something that maybe changed before the crisis. This is how to handle take or pay contracts in both directions. I think across the industry there is also some leverage on that, that you basically say that you have a particular situation in the crisis, where some volume take ups are not in bad intent of a partner. In both ways, either you sell or you buy, so that you try to arrange and you get over the crisis together. But maybe that is few hints how about pricing power, because it is very, very difficult to give a general statement across all the portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, that's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this brings us to the end of the conference call, ladies and gentlemen. Before we close, I would like to invite you, however to our upcoming event. This is our Agricultural Solutions round table. It will take place in Frankfurt on August 3rd, in London on August 4th, and then in New York and Boston on August 11th and 12th. There we will present our good performance in Agricultural, as well as our biotechnology activities and then you will also have the opportunity to discuss the BASF's performance over the second quarter with Members of the Board.</p>
          <p>For today, I would like to thank you for joining us. And for participating in the lively discussion, and should you have any questions left, but I think we have covered quite a lot here, then please call us and any member of the IR team, we'll be happy to help you. Thanks again and have a good day. Bye, bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>