<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1141935" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-05-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1023</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Ralph Edmondson, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Paul Adams, Chief Executive</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Ben Stevens, Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="4">David Hayes</participant>
      <participant id="5">Paul Adams</participant>
      <participant id="6">Eileen Khoo</participant>
      <participant id="7">Neil Withington</participant>
      <participant id="8">Ben Stevens</participant>
      <participant id="9">Adam Spielman</participant>
      <participant id="10">Robin Pagnamenta</participant>
      <participant id="11">Jonathan Fell</participant>
      <participant id="12">Elise Badoy</participant>
      <participant id="13">Erik Bloomquist</participant>
      <participant id="14">Virginia Heeribout</participant>
      <participant id="15">Rogerio Fujimori</participant>
      <participant id="16">Charles Manso de Zuniga</participant>
      <participant id="17">Patrick Schwendimann</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the British American Tobacco First Quarter Results Conference Call. My name is Stephanie, and I will be your coordinator for today's conference. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I am now handing you over to Ralph Edmondson to begin today's conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us. I am Ralph Edmondson, Head of Investor Relations. And welcome to the first quarter 2008 results call. With me today are Paul Adams, Chief Executive, and Ben Stevens, Finance Director. In a few moments, both Paul and Ben will give you an overview of the results.</p>
          <p>On our website, bat.com, you'll find the slides that accompany the presentation together with the earnings announcement released earlier today. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity for you to ask questions. The conference call will give you instructions on how to ask those questions later. And I'll now hand over to Paul Adams.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Let's first look at the headlines and then some of the detail behind them. Reported group cigarette volume for the first three months rose 1.3%, due mainly to the absence of the negative one-off factors we saw in the first quarter last year, such as the impact of the high level of trade buying in some markets at the end of 2006.</p>
          <p>At this point, it is worth remembering that we disposed of some businesses last year, primarily some cigarette brands in Italy and the Chesterfield trademark in Southern Africa. Our organic volume growth was therefore, 1.6%.</p>
          <p>Looking deeper into these results, it is clear that our brand mix is improving with an increase in our higher margin brands led by our continued strong Global Drive Brand growth. The Global Drive Brands grew 23% led by Pall Mall up 31%, Kent up 30%, Lucky Strike up 16% and a solid 8% growth on Dunhill.</p>
          <p>Brand migrations accounted for around one-third of the 23% rise in Global Drive Brands and that was largely Pall Mall in Pakistan. The growth of our Global Drive Brands has resulted in premium volume rising 6%, value for money rising 7%, and low price offerings being 8% lower.</p>
          <p>Premium volume now accounts for around one-third of group volume. The improvement in mix is reflected in revenue growth up 14% at current at rates and 6% at constant rates of exchange.</p>
          <p>Profit from operations excluding exceptionals grew 18% at current rates of exchange and a strong 10% at constant rates. After two years of currency headwinds, we are now benefiting from the appreciation against sterling of many of the key currencies in which we operate with the exceptions of the US dollar which is broadly flat and the weaker South African rand.</p>
          <p>Of our associate companies, ITC and Skandinavisk continue to perform well but Reynolds American had a difficult quarter with adjusted earnings down 11% reflecting lower volumes during the first quarter.</p>
          <p>The Reynolds American unadjusted results included the benefit from the termination of a joint venture agreement this year. The associates contribution excluding exceptionals rose 3% at current rates of exchange to &#xA3;114 million.</p>
          <p>Reynolds American has recently announced a $350 million share buyback program over the next 12 months which we have agreed to participate in to maintain our share holding at 42%. Adjusted diluted earnings per share rose 17% to 28.4 pence. Ben will discuss the drivers of adjusted earnings per share growth in a few minutes.</p>
          <p>Looking at revenue and volume in more detail, every region saw revenue growth at constant rates and each region with the exception of Latin America saw volume growth during the quarter. In Europe the absence of the effects of the speculative trade buying in Russia on last year's volumes together with higher volumes in Romania, Switzerland and Spain resulted in Europe's volumes rising 3%. Higher volumes, pricing and improved mix drove revenue up 8% at constant rates and 19% at current rates.</p>
          <p>Asia Pacific benefited from good volume increases in Pakistan and Bangladesh, despite lower volumes in Vietnam and Malaysia. The 4% rise in volume translated into a 6% rise in revenue at constant rates and 10% at current rates.</p>
          <p>In Latin America volumes were down 4% at 36 billion, with declines in Brazil, Mexico and Venezuela only partly offset by the increase in Chile.</p>
          <p>Higher prices resulted in revenue growth of 1% at constant rates across the region despite the weaker volumes. Stronger currencies resulted in a 10% increase in revenue at current rates of exchange.</p>
          <p>Africa and Middle East saw volume increases in Nigeria, Iran and Turkey partly offset by declines in South Africa. Improved product mix, higher volumes and pricing were behind the 7% increase in revenue at constant and current rates. In America Pacific, volumes were up 1% and revenues rose 7% at constant rates, mainly due to Canada. At current rates revenue was up 22%.</p>
          <p>Looking at profit on the same basis, the 10% rise in profit at constant rates on volume growth of 1%, reflects improved pricing and product mix, together with cost savings in many markets. Favorable exchange rates added a further 8% to profit from operations before exceptional items.</p>
          <p>In Europe, profit was 16% higher at constant rates, mainly as a result of the excellent performances in Russia, Romania, Switzerland and Spain, partly offset by profit decreases in Germany and the Czech Republic, following the industry volume declines in those markets.</p>
          <p>Asia Pacific's 4% volume growth drove a 9% improvement in profit at constant rates, mainly attributable to strong performances in Pakistan, Vietnam, Bangladesh and Malaysia.</p>
          <p>Latin America's profit decreased 1% at constant rates, although it was 7% higher at current rates, following the impact of lower volumes. Brazil posted lower profit in local currency as price increases were not sufficient to offset the impact of lower volumes, higher excise and the timing of marketing investments.</p>
          <p>At constant rates of exchange, profit in Africa and Middle East improved by 7%, although the weaker rand pulled back profit growth to just under 6% at current rates of exchange. In South Africa, volumes were lower following the termination of the Chesterfield license at the end of 2007. However, Dunhill continued its strong performance, while Kent performed well following the brand migration. Profit was ahead in local currency.</p>
          <p>America Pacific benefited from a significantly stronger contribution of &#xA3;64 million from Canada. Overall share was down 1.2 share points to 52% as the decline in the premium segment was not offset by the growth in the value for money brands.</p>
          <p>Q1 last year was also depressed by higher direct distribution and trade costs. Volumes in Japan were flat, but share grew, driven by the strong performance of Kool and growth of Lucky Strike.</p>
          <p>At this point, I would like to hand over to Ben Stevens, who in his new role as Finance Director will take you through the drivers behind the growth in adjusted earnings per share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Paul. The strong profit performance, up almost 10% at constant rates of exchange, was the main driver behind the growth in adjusted earnings per share. Net finance costs at 95 million were 37 million higher than last year, 15 million in net interest and 22 million in foreign exchange differences and fair value changes.</p>
          <p>The increase in net interest is mainly driven by the translation of the group's euro interest cost, as we hold a substantial proportion of our debt in euros to match the currency of the underlying earnings. The foreign exchange differences and fair value changes are principally due to an 11 million charge due to the stronger Swiss franc, which has meant a revaluation of our Swiss franc debt that is in place to fund our Swiss franc assets.</p>
          <p>Consistent with our previous treatment in 2005 when we excluded a gain of 23 million, we have excluded this charge from the adjusted earnings per share calculation. The balance relates the higher than normal foreign exchange movements due to recent market volatility.</p>
          <p>On this adjusted basis, net finance costs rose from 58 million to 84 million and impacted earnings per share by 3.6%. Associates had no impact on adjusted earnings per share while the lower underlying tax rate of 30.8% benefited adjusted earnings per share by 2%.</p>
          <p>The lower tax rate arises from a change in the mix of profits and the reduction in the national tax rates in several countries, this is in line with the 30% to 31% guidance given to you at the preliminary results presentation in February.</p>
          <p>Minority interest of 48 million were 5 million higher than last year but had a negligible impact on adjusted EPS.</p>
          <p>The share buyback program recommenced in March but at the lower annual level of &#xA3;400 million a year. The share buyback benefited earnings by 2% and the calculation was based on 2,015 million shares. We have maintained the share buyback program through the closed period.</p>
          <p>We announced last week that R&amp;R had breached the 30% level, but following shareholder approval and a waiver by the panel, they are not obliged to make an offer to the remaining shares</p>
          <p>Finally, favorable foreign exchange boosted adjusted EPS by 7% to 28.4 pence, a 17% increase over the prior year.</p>
          <p>That concludes the opening remarks. And we will open up the telephone to questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. The first question comes through from the line of David Hayes from Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning gentlemen. I have two questions if I can? Just first on the European pricing per unit for the strong number, again if look back over the last five quarters, the average is about 4.7% organic increase that's been pretty consistent over this course as well. Is that a kind of 4.5% plus what we should be expecting, moving forward in Europe now? Or is there anything you would warn against me thinking about that moving forward through the rest of the year?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, just in terms of phasing on A&amp;P [Advertising and Promotion] spend and cost savings, you mentioned a couple of markets where A&amp;P was slightly higher I guess in others it's down. Can you just give us a feel for whether you're thinking that quarterly wise A&amp;P and cost saves will be pretty constant, pretty consistent or whether there's going to be some lumpiness to either of those two lines or whether this quarter particularly was high or low in either of those areas? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks David. Yeah, pricing per unit in Europe; to try to forecast what the pricing per unit will be going forward is always tricky because it depends on what the competition do, but to talk about pricing, pricing momentum tends to be good. It is still continuing. I think it's slightly sticky in terms of Spain and Germany at the moment but generally I would say pricing momentum is good. While it doesn't seem unreasonable to use that assumption going forward but with the obvious caveat that we don't know what pricing will be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of A&amp;P spend, it's a fair question. As we look out over the year, if you remember last year we were slightly heavy weighted to the second half of year than is normal. That will continue in 2008 but won't be quite so heavily weighted toward the second half. In terms of the first quarter, A&amp;P spend was up generally versus the first quarter of last year but would be a slightly lower percent in that quarter for the year as a whole, if I'm making sense. So it was up but we think as a percentage of the year it was slightly lighter than normal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which, if you take it that we are going to be more front-loaded, front-half loaded than last year and the first quarter was slightly light, it might give you an indication about the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Okay and cost saves, are they pretty constant quarter-on-quarter? I mean I know you don't talk about that in numerical terms in the quarters, but no particular lumpiness? Is that going to be evenly spread?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There will always be some lumpiness on costs by quarter-by-quarter. As you know, we don't like to look at our results quarter-by-quarter too much, I know you have to. But no, there is nothing untoward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes through from the line of Eileen Khoo from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. Good morning. A couple of quick questions. One, if you could give us any update on Canadian litigation, have there been any developments there?</p>
          <p>And also just in general, what you're seeing in emerging markets. I mean, is your premiumization strategy pretty much still working? Do you see any slowdown in the last months or are things still pretty much going strong there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Eileen. Neil Withington is here, the General Counsel. So why don't I let him answer the first question and I'll handle your question on emerging markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. No significant developments in Canadian litigation to be concerned about. There have been filings in New Brunswick of a recoupment case based on similar provisions to a local statute to that enacted in British Columbia. But that's at very, very early stages and the issues that it presents are very familiar to us. And in fact, there was a win in Ontario in a fire safe class action called Ragoonanan last week. And so, things pretty much in steady state.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On emerging markets, no, I don't see any change to -- or threat to our premiumization strategy. It was interesting. I was looking at the numbers just before I came down on our Global Drive Brand growth in Latin America and our Global Drive Brands in volume terms grew in Latin America by 8%. And that was despite a very slight decline in Pall Mall, so it's not Pall Mall that's driving that 8% growth in Global Drive Brands. And so the balance would be premium orientated. So we haven't seen any sort of slowdown, anywhere really in terms of our premiumization strategy; which is not to say that it won't happen, but it hasn't happened yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes through from the line of <mark type="inaudible" />. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I have just a few questions. First of all, just in terms of the brand migration in South Africa. I know Benson &amp; Hedges' market share was about 6, 7% and you've converted that now to Kent. Maybe if you can just give us an idea of the rate of success of that migration, that's the first question?</p>
          <p>The second one, just one in terms of the share buyback. You have bought back only &#xA3;35 million worth of shares in the first quarter. Will you accelerate that in order to achieve that 400 million for the full year?</p>
          <p>And the final question just revolves around the reason why you're participating in the share buyback scheme of Reynolds America. Is that maybe, I don't know if I read between the lines, but given the problems that are actually facing the growth brands, is it sort of a vote of no confidence in the stock? I mean why you are not keeping your existing shares in the company? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Early days on the Benson &amp; Hedges to Kent migration in South Africa, but it's tracking well. We are certainly hitting our retention rate targets and its doing well so no issues there.</p>
          <p>I'll let Ben talk about the share buyback program and the rate of the share buyback program. But just to pick up on Reynolds American, we participated because as we've often said, we are happy with our 42% shareholding, which means we neither want to see it go up nor go down. So we were happy to participate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the share buyback, of course, we had access to inside information in January and February because of the STK deal. So we couldn't go into the market in January and February. So we started again in March and you can anticipate the share buyback coming through at about 40 million a month for the next 10 months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes through from the line Adam Spielman from Citigroup, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. A question about Canada, obviously you had a strong result driven as well as I can see by low like-for-likes in the year earlier quarter. As you look forward, should we expect local currency profit, which I suppose is Canadian dollars in Canada, to be up on year earlier quarters? And I suppose I'm trying to get to the question do we think we've finally stabilized profit in Canada?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you are right. We did have first quarter, a good first quarter in Canada, Adam. I think there were couple of one-off factors, I mean, we had four more selling days in Canada in the first quarter of this year relative to last year, which tended to push volume and therefore revenue slightly higher. And we have got the benefit of price increases. And you're quite right there were some higher costs in the first quarter of last year including some one-off costs. So slightly flattering.</p>
          <p>I know everyone is very anxious for me to call the bottom of the Canadian market and I'm not doing so yet. Simply because I have a great respect for the challenges that that business is facing in Canada in terms of the down trading, the smuggling and the pricing environment. So cautiously optimistic in Canada, I think we are seeing some encouraging signs, we saw whilst quarter on -- first quarter on first quarter share was down. First quarter share on fourth quarter share was up and that share growth has been driven by John Player standard and Viceroy coming into the markets and doing well. So we're certainly encouraged by their performance but I will wait a few more quarters before calling it, Adam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough, and is there any sign that the government's taking &#x2013; or the governments are taking the First Nations' sales more seriously now than they were or are they still fairly inactive?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think they give us a sympathetic hearing but they haven't done anything yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you the next question comes through from the line of Robin Pagnamenta from Times. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Robin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was just wondering given the proportion of your earnings that are earned overseas, has any consideration been given to shifting your domicile outside the UK?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we are going to wait and see what the government comes out with. We are consulting with the government, we're being involved and our views are being heard and so we'll wait to see what comes out from the government. And I think we remain cautiously optimistic that something sensible will come out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but it definitely sounds as if it is something that you will -- you have been thinking about then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I wouldn't say that we have been thinking about it, but we clearly recognize the issue and the thing to do is to try and consult with them and give them our views, and let them know what could be the potential ramifications for British business and then see what comes out. So, we haven't given it any serious consideration yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes through from the line of Jonathan Fell from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jonathan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a quick one from me. Comments on Australia referred to increased competitive discounting activities and I think we had something like this around the same stage of last year. I'm just wondering, if you could expand on what was happening there and how you are responding to it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The pricing situation is &#x2013; or the discounting situation in Australia is still rumbling on. It's a lot better than it was last year. The level is not so intense or the pervasiveness is not so broad, but it is still there. And it's crimping us a bit and inhibiting our ability to move up, but we are managing it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is there any particular competitor who is causing that or is it everybody?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the issue is when someone starts pricing activity, there are two laws about price wars &#x2013; not that this is a price war, but one, everybody hates it and secondly, no one admits to starting it. So, other than the fact that it's, we tend to be more sinned against than sinning, I would say in Australia, I won't point the finger any more than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes through from the line of <mark type="inaudible" />. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Most of my questions have been asked. Just one last one, in what seems to be a very benign environment for the tobacco companies, are there any major tax excise increases that are programmed for the rest of the year that you can tell us about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think there's anything out there that's substantial that we need to worry about that we know about at the moment, but of course with excise, you never quite know what's going to hit you around the corner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We've got just follow-up question from the line of Adam Spielman from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thank you very much. Very simple question for modeling; it looks like we should be modeling with Tekel acquisition to occur in the middle of the year. Is there any reason to do anything different with STK? I mean, I know you're subject to EU regulation, but is that the best thing to model it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's very difficult to say, because we are waiting to see what happens to competition clearance from the EU. If everything goes well, then we could easily do the deal by the half year, but we've just got wait and see, I'm afraid</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, Ben.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes through from the line of Elise Badoy from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yes good morning. I just had a question on the outlook for Russia, given the forthcoming potential tax increase in '09 and '10. It looks like -- I mean I saw some press article suggesting that the scope of the increase might be even higher than originally anticipated. And I was wondering if you have any comments to make on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're very well positioned Russia. I mean Russia has the advantage of being a growing market where we are growing share on the back of our premium portfolio. It's also an up-trading market. So we have no particular insights to offer you on that. But we are very comfortable with the position in Russia. The only other thing I'd say on Russia is that we had a stunning first quarter in Russia. But of course the comparators will get more difficult during the course of the rest of year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The scope of increase looks like it was higher. I was wondering given the inflation levels in Russia, etcetera, if you had any views that actually the numbers that are being put in, talking about over 24% I think increase in every year. I was wondering if actually given the inflation, etcetera, if that was really the goal or if those numbers are looked a bit high?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Inflation is, from memory, about 10% in Russia. But the currency is appreciating and we are doing well. So I am not sure that there is a particular issue there for us in Russia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next comes through from the line of <mark type="inaudible" />. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning guys. Just a couple of questions on the Global Drive Brands. I jumped on the call late so maybe you've given these figures but bear with me. Just you did 23% volume growth I think in the quarter but there was a lot of migration going on there. I appreciate it may be a difficult number to come up with given that migration. But do you have a feel for what the underlying growth in the Global Drive Brands was ex that migration effect and perhaps what you think you can do moving forward on the Global Drive Brands? What percentage of the total volume is now Global Drive Brands?</p>
          <p>And finally, it may not be a big number, but presumably your 800 million cost savings that you're projecting over the next five years, any further migration into Global Drive Brands and benefits of scale that may provide would not be included in that 800 million figure? Would I be right in saying that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, <mark type="inaudible" />. Let me give you the numbers. Global Drive Brands were a shade over 40 billion in the first quarter. That equates to 25% of group volume. Migration was about 2.3 billion, which would have brought the 23% down to 16%. We've often talked that if we look medium to long-term volume growth of the Global Drive Brands, it should be around high single-digit, a well known phrase, but we think that applies to Global Drive Brands as well. So, excluding migrations 16% was a good quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the saving side, the marketing economies of scale from having a bigger proportion of our Global Drive Brands in the portfolio, obviously, aren't part of the 800 million. But having a more Global Drive Brand based portfolio does allows us to make savings in overheads of course and some of the above market savings we're able to extract particularly in terms of, say, brand management and things like that, are part of the 800 million savings. So, I think in summary, the 800 million excludes any marketing spend savings from having a higher percentage in Global Drive Brands but will include some overhead savings from having a more consistent portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you the next question comes through from the line of David Hayes from Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, gents, just a couple of quick follow-ups. Just on Japan, the top line looked pretty healthy, you talked about flat volumes and pricing, but if we look at the organic, it looks like it was flat, profit wise. Are you seeing a change there in terms of competitive intensity? And I guess in terms of a wider question, I mean, PMI are already talking a good game about increasing Marlboro brand support etcetera. Are you seeing anything from them any different at this early stage of the year? Or is it pretty much business as usual in that sense? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just to generalize first and then come back to your specific question. I mean we went into the year, recognizing that two things had changed. One because of consolidation and the Philip Morris spin off, competition had got bigger and stronger. So we were anticipating a much tougher competitive environment. The other thing heading into the year was of course concerned about the economic slowdown and how that would impact us, particularly in developed markets, less so in emerging markets. I have to say so far so good. We haven't sort of noticed any sort of major increase in competitive activity, which perhaps is a reflection that it was pretty competitive last year as much as that anyone has got slacker in 2008. And so far not really being impacted by the economic slowdown and that what impact that may have on consumers in terms of buying and uptrading, so, so far so good on both of those things.</p>
          <p>In terms -- so hopefully that puts some context on Japan, where we've seen a sort of heightened level of innovation particularly around menthol products in Japan from both of our major competitors there. Haven't had a major affect yet, but it's early days that they would be the first to say that. But we're still growing share. Our volume is flat in the declining market. I think costs may slightly go up, I mean remember that there is still a big program on running to the end of a large program on age verification on vending. It's clear that more volume will be sold through the convenience channel in Japan going forward and that may tease up trade costs around that particular channel, not in any huge way, at least as far as we're concerned. As you may remember from our trip to Asia in May last year, we are relatively strong in convenience channel. We saw that move in convenience channel two years ago and we've been building relationships and putting in place contracts with the convenient chains over the last two years. So whilst I think costs will go up and certainly our cost will go up as well in terms of handling that increased volume through convenience, I don't see it is being a substantial increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks very much, cheers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, we've got no further questions in queue. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We've got a question coming through from the line of Erik Bloomquist from JP Morgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Erik.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to follow-up on two things. One with respect to the volume growth, organic growth of 1.6% is a terrific number. I was wondering if you could do two things, one talk to us about the split in that volume growth between premium and value-for-money and low price. And then secondly, talk about how that affects the outlook for volume growth in the year.</p>
          <p>Second question in respect to Latin America, it looked like there was a 3% negative price mix in that market. It is that something which you attribute to A&amp;P spend in markets like Mexico and Brazil? And is that something where there is going to a continued impact through the rest of the year or will that follow the phasing you described earlier in the call? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Erik. If you look at our volume split, premium is now around about 32% of group volume and increased by 6.2% first quarter on first quarter. Value-for-money is around about 35%, that increased by 6.6%, Q1-Q1 and low price is around 1/3 and that decreased by about 8% Q1-on-Q1.</p>
          <p>And I think you are sort of saying at the moment, we still see premium growing for the balance of the year. Not sure it's going to be growing at 6%, but still see growth for premium for the balance of the year s we improve our mix, but that's all subject to whether there is any marked consumer slowdown, which we haven't seen yet.</p>
          <p>In terms, I am not quite sure I understand your question on Brazil. I mean the issue was that we were making sort of if you like super profits in Brazil last year, because we had taken price increases ahead of excise. And so, we had the sort of very benign pricing situation in Brazil for about the first seven, eight months of the year. And we are not enjoying that now, because the excise kicked in, in the second half of last year. So that sort of super normal profits has gone away which is the main sort of issue for us in Latin America relative to last year. But not sure, I'm not sure I understood your question around A&amp;P.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll circle back with Ralph later then. And then with respect to foreign exchange, is it something that we should expect to be again sequential like it was last year? Or is it something that appears, given where spot rates are now that we could continue to see benefiting through the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. If spot rates stay where they are now you will see some benefit for the rest of the year, but you've got to remember that Sterling declined during the course of last year. It didn't all happen on the first of January and therefore we are going to be lapping some more difficult comparatives in rest of the year, but as things stand at the moment, current spot rates, we see an FX gain for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but we should see the benefit of FX moderating as we go through the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Somewhat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question come through from the line of Virginia Heeribout from Natixis. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good morning. I have three question actually, first one on Germany. So you said in your press release that profit is down in Germany. Just wonder if it is in local currency or at current rate of exchange? And if you can give us some details about what's happening in Germany and what's the outlook for the rest of the year?</p>
          <p>Second question, about Latin America, you have volumes down 4%, I understand mainly driven by Brazil. Can you give some details about what drove -- what has driven this volume decrease and what's the outlook for the rest of the year? You also speak about timing in terms of marketing expenses in Brazil, can you talk about what are your -- what are your plans for the moments in there?</p>
          <p>And last question about the profit in Turkey, I just wonder if you have been making loss in this market or not? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay! Leading us around the global on those questions. Let me just talk about Germany outlook, perhaps Ben can answer the questions on profitability. In terms of the outlook on Germany, I think Germany is going to have a tough year; I am talking for the industry in 2008. We have the roll out of smoking bans. We have the impact of the increase in age of smoking from 16 to 18 years, which I think happened in the third quarter of last year, so that's rolling forward. And we have the Schengen Agreement which meant that there are no border controls between Germany and Poland, for one. So there is some concern that the level of duty not paid product being consumed by German consumers would increase. So, that was, sort of on the negative side, and so far I have to say those concerns, those worries have not transpired as strongly as we thought. But they're still there, particularly around the smoking ban and its roll out.</p>
          <p>So, the market was down 3 to 4% in the first quarter. I think we'll be lucky if we see for the year that the market is only down 3 to 4%. We saw on the other hand price increases in value for money at the beginning of the year and for roll your own, which was helpful. But we've yet to see price increases on high-end premium brands, high priced and premium brands. That still remains an issue. So that's the sort of the outlook for Germany. The main issue for us in the first quarter was reduced volumes and a little down trading.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Just in local currency terms, Germany's profit were down somewhat. You've got to remember though that the price increase only came through at the end of the first quarter on roll your own. So we're anticipating a slightly better performance than that for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Latin America, yeah the reason why the volume is down in Latin America is because there was some thumping excise increases in Venezuela and Brazil, which led to higher prices in the fourth quarter of last year, which is rolling through into the first quarter and indeed for this year. So that's principally why the volume is down in Latin America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have the marketing expenses. We are tweaking our DSS operations, but it's not significant in terms of the performance out of Brazil. And in Turkey we are breakeven now in terms of our local business there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, we've got no further questions in queue. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have a question coming through from the line of Rogerio Fujimori from Credit Suisse, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Two questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there, two questions please. First were there any material trade inventory movements in any of your top markets in the quarter? First question.</p>
          <p>And the second on margins. Obviously the performance in the first quarter was very good. So my question is whether this is a sustainable and a good rough indication for the full year, or should we bear in mind the marketing step-up in the second quarter for any extra cost in the balance of the year assuming the global competitive environment remains okay? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. On inventory movements, I think the only significant one is in Switzerland where we had very good shipment share, because we are putting in a new EAS system in Switzerland. So we shipped a bit of volume at the end of the first quarter, just to make sure that we overcome any potential hiccups on implementing that system and that will reverse out in the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think also we &#x2013; along with our major competitors we -- there was quite a bit of trade load in the fourth quarter of last year in Czech Republic, which meant that the industry sales were well down in the first quarter in the Czech Republic. But those are the two major ones. I am not sure we'd call the Czech Republic a major market though.</p>
          <p>Was there another question? Remind me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. On margins, the first quarter performance was obviously very good. So just trying to get a sense if it's a good indication for the full year or should we bear in mind timing of marketing or if it's good rough indication for the full year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Operating margin was 32 -- over 32% in the first quarter which was up from 31% in the first quarter of last year. I think that was slightly flattered by the timing of marketing spend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes through from the line of Chas Manso from Dresdner Kleinwort. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Chas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was wondering whether you would help us tease out the one-off in Q1? What's your sense of the profit impacts of last year's one-offs both positive and negative?</p>
          <p>Second question would be on innovations, like you also menthol capsule in Japan. Could you just update us on what innovations you've brought through in this quarter or where you have been focusing more on migrations this time?</p>
          <p>And I suppose the last one would be on price increases really trying to tease out between price and mix, I suppose, but post the usual January cycle whether there has been any notable price increases in your portfolio in the last couple of months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gosh, well let me just do price/mix. I mean there were lots of price increases happening either at the end of last year or the beginning of this year. But the sort of the normal price increase that one would get so there is nothing that sort of stands out. The good news is that the price increases are occurring and continue to occur, but there is nothing sort of special or big price increases that's worth mentioning.</p>
          <p>In terms of innovations, I mean, we are focusing on Kent Nanotech, bedding that in, in Eastern Europe. And we continue with Kool Boost in Japan and we're rolling out the resealable pack or what we call, "The Walrus pack" the resealable pack for Dunhill in two or three markets. So, the innovations that you know about we are focusing in on rolling those out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we are not really able to tease out every individual's movement in the markets. But remember Russia did very well against first quarter last year because of the loading at the end of '06. And Brazil did not so well as the start of last year. So, I guess those two wash out somewhat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if I was trying to characterize the first quarter which maybe the underlying question you have, Chas, I mean it is a good first quarter and driven by the volume growth, we don't anticipate we'll see for the year. But there is nothing sort of untoward or particularly different in our costs or our marketing expenditure. So, it's a fairly sort of ordinary quarter other than the fact that we got more volume and that lifted the quarter. I think over the balance of the year, over the next nine months, you won't see the sort of growth over those nine months that you saw in the first quarter. The growth will slow down, but not to any untoward degree.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes to you from the line of Patrick Schwendimann from ZKB. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick Schwendimann, Zuercher Kantonalbank. I have a question regarding the Richemont rand growth could you update us on your planned listing in South America? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>South Africa, I think you mean. I think we have no further information from R&amp;R on what their plans are, so everything stays much as it was at the year end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So for you it's still a wait and see?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And we got the follow-up question from the line of Eileen Khoo from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello there, just another quick question on your Group tax rate for this year? Could you just remind us what your guidance is for this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We anticipate the tax charge, the underlying tax charge to be between 30% and 31% for the year which is pretty much where we were in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but then there will be an extra deferred tax charge for Tekel right? Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That was a 20 million deferred tax charge for Tekel which we'll pick up when we do the acquisition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, we've got no further questions in queue. So I'll hand back to the host to conclude today's conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you everyone for tuning in. I supposed just to finish, to try and summarize the first quarter. I can do no better than to use the quote that Jan du Plessis used in the announcement which is that, "The year has clearly got off to a great start with profit growth in all our regions. While the normal caveats about not reading too much into any particular quarter still apply, the Group's unrivalled spread of business between developed and developing markets should continue to serve shareholders well." Thanks very much for listening. Bye, bye now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for joining today's call. You may now replace the handset.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>