<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1339692" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-10-21</date>
    <companies>
      <company>63</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Mary Kay Ladone, Corporate Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Robert L. Parkinson, Jr., Chairman, Chief Executive Officer and President</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Robert J. Hombach, Corporate Vice President, Chief Financial Officer and Treasurer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Bob Hopkins</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Robert Parkinson, Jr.</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Kristen Stewart</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Bruce Nudell</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">David Lewis</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">David Roman</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Michael Weinstein</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Rick Wise</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Lawrence Keusch</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Matt Miksic</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Ben Andrew</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to Baxter International's third quarter earnings conference call. Your lines will remain in a listen-only mode until the question-and-answer segment of today's call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this call is being recorded by Baxter, Inc. and is copyrighted material. It cannot be recorded or rebroadcast without Baxter's permission. If you have any objections, please disconnect at this time</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to Ms. Mary Kay Ladone, Corporate Vice President, Investor Relations at Baxter International. Ms. Ladone, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Sean. Good morning, everyone, and welcome to our Q3 2010 earnings conference call. Joining me today are Bob Parkinson, CEO and Chairman of Baxter International; and Bob Hombach, Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>Before we get started, let me remind you that this presentation, including comments regarding our financial outlook, new product developments, and regulatory matters contain forward-looking statements that involve risks and uncertainties. And of course, our actual results could differ materially from our current expectations. Please refer to today's press release and our SEC filings for more details concerning factors that could cause actual results to differ materially.</p>
          <p>In addition, in today's call, non-GAAP financial measures will be used to help investors understand Baxter's ongoing business performance. A reconciliation of the non-GAAP financial measures being discussed today to the comparable GAAP financial measures is included in our earnings release issued this morning and available on our website.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to turn the call over to Bob Parkinson.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mary Kay, good morning. Thanks for calling in this morning. I'm pleased to announce that our third quarter results reported earlier this morning exceeded the guidance that we provided last quarter, with adjusted earnings per share of $1.01 per diluted share. On a reported basis, worldwide sales increased 3%. And on an organic basis, sales increased 4%, which compares favorably to our guidance range of 1% to 3%. While Bob will provide more details on the third quarter financial results and outlook for the remainder of the year, as you saw, we are reconfirming our earnings guidance at the high end of the range that we provided to all of you last quarter, which now includes adjusted EPS of $3.96 to $3.98 per share.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we continued to make progress on numerous fronts despite a continuing challenging environment. First, as we've discussed, Baxter and the market more broadly have been operating through a transition period in the plasma proteins market. And beginning in the second quarter, as you know, we implemented some specific actions to stabilize our share position.</p>
          <p>I'm encouraged with the progress that we're making with our demand creation activities and commercial strategies, as evidenced by improved global demand for GAMMAGARD LIQUID. And while we'll continue to face some difficult comparisons related to healthcare reform and the termination of the WinRho agreement, our volume growth has accelerated. Distributor inventory levels of GAMMAGARD remain balanced with underlying demand, and we finalized agreements with the majority of our U.S. customers with terms that now extend through the end of 2011.</p>
          <p>As I've mentioned in the past, we remain confident that the plasma business will be an attractive growth vehicle in the coming years, due to an increase in end user demand resulting from deployment of additional sales resources for those indications that remain underdiagnosed and undertreated, Baxter's introduction of new and proprietary administration technologies, expansion of new indications such as MMN, and of course the significant opportunity of a potential Alzheimer's indication.</p>
          <p>Over the last several months, we continued to enhance our market leadership with a number of commercial achievements, a few of which I'd like to highlight. First, a new five-year contract with Novation, a leading healthcare supply contracting company of VHA Incorporated, the University HealthSystem Consortium, or UHC, and Provista. This agreement provides Novation members access to Baxter's broad portfolio of products, including IV solutions, drug delivery, and parenteral nutritional products, large volume infusion pumps, and IV administration sets and components.</p>
          <p>We also announced in the quarter a manufacturing, supply, and distribution agreement with Kamada for GLASSIA, the first and only liquid alpha1-proteinase inhibitor. Under this agreement, Baxter acquired commercial rights to GLASSIA in the U.S., Australia, New Zealand, and Canada. Under a separate license agreement, we've been granted the right to process GLASSIA, and will seek necessary regulatory approvals to do so. GLASSIA was approved by the FDA in July 2010 and was recently launched in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Also in the quarter, we announced a collaboration between Baxter and Takeda for the development, production, and supply of cell culture-based influenza vaccines for the Japanese market. During the quarter, Takeda was selected as a recipient of a subsidy from the Japanese government to support an investment associated with the development and production of pandemic influenza vaccines. Takeda plans to apply for additional government funding under a second supplementary budget and further expand its collaboration with our company.</p>
          <p>And finally, we launched a number of new products during the quarter, including ADVATE in Brazil. the U.S. launch of TachoSil, an absorbable fibrin sealant patch for use in cardiovascular surgery, and the launch in Europe and Canada of the first and only 30-gram dose vial for GAMMAGARD LIQUID and KIOVIG. This new dosage form is the most frequently prescribed dose for primary immune deficiency patients and will enhance user convenience.</p>
          <p>Finally, I'd like to highlight that we continue to fund all of our key late-stage R&amp;D programs, as evidenced by a number milestones which occurred during the quarter. For example, we continue to extend our leadership position in hemophilia in recombinant proteins with the initiation of a global Phase I-II clinical trial studying the safety and tolerability of BAX-817, a recombinant Factor VIIa therapy for the treatment of hemophilia A or B patients with inhibitors. And we've also dosed the first patient in our Phase I-III clinical trial for BAX 326, a recombinant Factor IX treatment for patients with hemophilia B.</p>
          <p>Also during the quarter, we completed our Phase I recombinant Von Willebrand clinical trial, and we expect interim safety and tolerability data to be presented at the American Society of Hematology meeting in December of this year. In addition, we expect to initiate a Phase III trial in 2011.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we announced the approval in Austria and the Czech Republic for PREFLUCEL, our seasonal influenza vaccine manufactured using Baxter's proprietary Vero cell technology. Starting in the fourth quarter, we expect to submit for approval in additional European countries through a mutual recognition procedure.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, we completed enrollment in a Phase III clinical trial of GAMMAGARD LIQUID and KIOVIG for the treatment of multifocal motor neuropathy, or MMN. The trial includes approximately 40 participants and is being conducted at clinical sites across the U.S., Canada, and Europe. Given the required 15-month follow-up period, we expect to complete this trial in 2011.</p>
          <p>Interim data from a Phase III clinical trial of HyQ was recently presented at the European Society for Immunodeficiencies meeting in Istanbul, Turkey. HyQ is an immunoglobulin therapy facilitated subcutaneously by recombinant human hyaluronidase. Interim analyses show that 28 out of 29 HyQ study participants with primary immune deficiency were able to infuse immunoglobulin under the skin using a single injection site at infusion volumes, intervals, and rates equivalent to their previous IV administration of immunoglobulin. As you know, we expect to complete this trial by the end of the year and file for approval in 2011.</p>
          <p>We continue to advance our Phase III GAMMAGARD LIQUID trial for Alzheimer's. To date, we've randomized over 220 patients, and are on target to complete enrollment in mid-2011. With an 18-month follow-up period, we currently expect to complete the trial by the end of 2012.</p>
          <p>And finally, we recently finalized our IDE [Investigational Device Exemption] application for our home hemodialysis clinical trial and submitted it to the FDA. Upon acceptance of the IDE, we plan to start clinical trials in the U.S. later this year or early 2011.</p>
          <p>These achievements which I've just summarized depict just a handful of the programs in our pipeline that will present great opportunities for Baxter in the years to come.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'd like to ask Bob to review our third quarter financial results and guidance for the year in more detail. And then I'll come back and provide some closing perspectives. Bob, if you would.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bob, and good morning, everyone. As Bob mentioned earlier, we are pleased with our financial performance in the third quarter, with earnings per share of $1.01 per diluted share, which exceeded our guidance range of $0.96 to $0.99 per share. This was largely the result of continued momentum in the Medication Delivery business, improvement in antibody therapy and plasma protein dynamics, and our continued focus on expense management.</p>
          <p>Let me briefly walk you through the P&amp;L by line item before turning to our financial outlook for the remainder of 2010. Starting with sales, worldwide sales totaled 3.2 billion in the third quarter and increased 3%. Excluding foreign currency, sales increased 4%. Sales growth in the U.S. was 4%, led by double-digit revenue growth in Medication Delivery. On a reported basis, international sales increased 1%. Excluding foreign currency, international sales advanced 4%, as strong double-digit sales growth in antibody therapy, plasma proteins, and biosurgery products was partially offset by soft sales in Europe across several product categories, most notably vaccine revenues.</p>
          <p>In terms of individual business performance and beginning with BioScience, global sales in the third quarter totaled approximately 1.4 billion, which was comparable to the prior-year period. Excluding foreign currency, BioScience sales increased 3%. Within the product categories, recombinant sales of 526 million were flat to the prior year on a reported basis. Excluding foreign currency, sales increased 2%, driven by robust sales of ADVATE, particularly in the U.S. where revenues advanced in double digits. However, this performance was largely offset by lower sales in Europe given the results of the UK tender and our decision to lower RECOMBINATE inventory levels in the U.S. channel as we remained focused on driving conversion to ADVATE. Excluding these factors, recombinant growth was approximately 8% on a constant currency basis.</p>
          <p>Moving on to plasma proteins, sales in the quarter were 346 million and increased 5%. Excluding the impact of foreign currency, sales increased 8%. As you know, approximately 50% of the plasma portfolio is comprised of a broad array of proprietary products, including FEIBA, an inhibitor therapy; ARALAST, a treatment for hereditary emphysema; and FLEXBUMIN, albumin provided in a flexible plastic container.</p>
          <p>Contributing to the performance in this category was growth of ARALAST, double-digit growth of FEIBA, and strong demand for albumin outside the U.S. This was partially offset by lower sales of plasma derived Factor VIII and U.S. albumin sales. While we continue to see strong volume growth for albumin in emerging markets such as China, market demand in U.S. continues to be below last year due to lower hospital admissions and surgical procedures.</p>
          <p>In antibody therapy, sales of 336 million were flat to the prior year; and excluding foreign currency, sales increased 2%. U.S. sales were 230 million, reflecting a decline of 4% versus the prior year. Strong volume in the quarter was more than offset by the impact of our commercial strategies to stabilize share and a seven percentage point impact to growth related to healthcare reform and year-over-year comparison to WinRho. Outside the U.S., antibody therapy sales of 106 million increased 9% as we continue to see strong growth in volume across the regions, which was somewhat offset by lower prices, particularly in Europe.</p>
          <p>Sales in Regenerative Medicine, which includes our biosurgery products, totaled 130 million and increased 19%. Sales excluding foreign currency grew 22% and continue to reflect healthy growth across the core portfolio and approximately 15 million in incremental sales related to the ApaTech acquisition completed earlier this year.</p>
          <p>Finally, revenues in the other category within BioScience were down 40% to $49 million due primarily to a difficult comparison related to advanced purchase agreement revenues recorded last year and lower sales of the NeisVac-C vaccine.</p>
          <p>In Medication Delivery, sales totaled 1.2 billion, an increase of 5% on a reported basis. And excluding foreign currency, Medication Delivery sales grew 7%. In the U.S., sales were strong and advanced 12%, while international sales excluding the impact of foreign currency increased 2%.</p>
          <p>Turning to the product categories, IV therapy sales totaled 417 million in the quarter and grew 5%. Excluding foreign currency, sales increased 7%. Strong U.S. sales, which increased 18%, resulted from increased demand, particularly for nutritional products due to competitor supply issues as well as improved pricing.</p>
          <p>Global injectable sales advanced 8% to 469 million. Excluding foreign currency, sales grew 9%. Contributing to this performance was strong growth of select premixed drugs and multi-source generics, as well as significant growth in certain enhanced packaging offerings such as our MINI-BAG and MINI-BAG Plus products.</p>
          <p>Infusion system sales totaled 213 million and increased 2%. Excluding foreign currency, sales increased 2%. Strong sales of Sigma SPECTRUM pumps more than offset lower COLLEAGUE and Access set revenues.</p>
          <p>And finally, anesthesia sales totaled 127 million and increased 3%. Excluding foreign currency, sales increased 5%, driven by growth of both SUPRANE and Sevoflurane globally despite declines in surgical procedures.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Renal, third quarter sales totaled 594 million and increased 3% on both a reported basis and when adjusting for foreign currency. U.S. sales increased 2% as improved PD growth offset lower HD revenues. International sales increased 3%. And excluding foreign currency, international sales increased 4%.</p>
          <p>Global PD sales totaled 487 million and increased 3% on both a reported basis and after adjusting for foreign currency. This performance can be attributed to building momentum in PD patient gains in the U.S., resulting in 5% growth in U.S. PD revenues. In markets outside the U.S., patient gains in Latin America and Asia partially offset slower growth across Europe.</p>
          <p>And lastly, hemodialysis sales of 107 million increased 4%. Excluding foreign currency, HD sales increased 5% as CRRT [Continuous Renal Replacement Therapy] sales, the hemofiltration business that we acquired last year, offset lower sales of dialyzers in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Turning to the rest of the P&amp;L, gross margin for the company was 51.5% in the third quarter, which improved sequentially by 20 basis points. However, the third quarter gross margin is 130 basis points lower than last year's margin of 52.8, which is largely a result of the healthcare reform impact and cost inefficiencies driven by lower volume throughput in the plasma and vaccine businesses.</p>
          <p>We successfully leveraged SG&amp;A, which totaled 670 million in the quarter and was comparable to the prior-year period. Excluding foreign currency, SG&amp;A increased 1%. In addition, SG&amp;A as a percent of sales was 20.8% in the quarter, the lowest level in several years, reflecting sequential improvement of 90 basis points and improvement year over year of 60 basis points. While we continue to aggressively manage general, administrative, and discretionary spending across the company, we're selectively investing in several key promotional activities aimed at demand creation, new product launches, and driving future growth of our higher margin products.</p>
          <p>R&amp;D spending of 207 million declined 9%, which can be attributed to the impact of foreign currency, completed clinical work on several programs, and lower milestone payments to partners. It's important to note that we continued to invest in all key R&amp;D programs across the product pipeline. In fact, excluding the factors previously mentioned, R&amp;D spending on key programs increased in mid-single digits.</p>
          <p>The operating margin in the third quarter was 24.3%. And despite our challenges in a difficult macro environment, this is a new historic level for our company. The operating margin increased sequentially by 160 basis points and improved 20 basis points versus the prior year as a result of our disciplined focus on cost management.</p>
          <p>Interest expense was 24 million compared to 23 million last year, while other expense was 5 million as miscellaneous expenses more than offset foreign currency gains.</p>
          <p>The tax rate was 21.1% in the quarter, 240 basis points above last year, primarily due to a change in earnings mix between higher tax and lower tax jurisdictions.</p>
          <p>And finally, as previously mentioned, adjusted earnings per share was $1.01 per diluted share, an increase of 3%.</p>
          <p>Turning to cash flow, cash flow from operations was strong in the quarter and exceeded $1 billion. On a year-to-date basis, cash flow from operations totaled approximately 2.1 billion and includes the first quarter pension contribution of $300 million. Excluding pension contributions from both years, on a year-to-date basis cash flow from operations improved by more than 300 million versus the same period last year. This represents a 17% increase in cash flow.</p>
          <p>DSO ended the quarter at 56.2 days, which was lower than last year by two days. This is largely due to improvements in international DSOs as our DSO in the U.S. is less than 30 days.</p>
          <p>Inventory turns of 2.4 reflect an improvement versus last year, primarily driven by better turns in both Medication Delivery and BioScience.</p>
          <p>And lastly, during the third quarter we repurchased 3.6 million shares of common stock for 161 million. On a net basis, this amounts to repurchases of 2.7 million shares or 128 million. Year to date, we've repurchased 26.3 million shares of common stock for almost $1.3 billion; or on a net basis 20 million shares for over $1 billion, in line with our objective for the full year 2010.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me conclude my comments this morning by providing our financial outlook for the fourth quarter and update you on our full-year 2010 guidance before turning the call back to Bob. First, for the full year 2010, as you saw in the press release, we expect adjusted earnings per diluted share of $3.96 to $3.98. By line item of the P&amp;L and starting with sales, we expect full-year sales growth excluding the impact of foreign currency of 2% to 3%. Based on current foreign exchange rates, we now expect reported sales growth for 2010 to be in the 3% to 4% range.</p>
          <p>For the full year, we continue to expect gross margin to decline approximately 100 basis points from the 2009 gross margin rate of 52.4%. Given current foreign exchange rates, we now expect SG&amp;A to increase modestly year over year, and R&amp;D to decline in low single digits versus 2009. As we mentioned previously, we will continue to intensify our focus on managing costs throughout the organization.</p>
          <p>We continue to expect interest expense of approximately 100 million and other expenses to total approximately 25 million.</p>
          <p>Given our mix of earnings, we now expect our tax rate to approximate 20%. And finally we continue to expect a full-year average share count of approximately 595 million shares.</p>
          <p>From a cash flow perspective, we now expect to generate cash flow from operations of approximately 2.8 billion.</p>
          <p>Now to expand on the full-year sales assumptions for each of the businesses; first on a constant currency basis, we continue to expect mid-single digit sales growth for Medication Delivery. For</p>
          <p>Renal, we expect sales growth to be in low single digits on a constant currency basis. This is somewhat lower than original guidance primarily due to lower than expected HD sales. As for BioScience, we now expect sales excluding foreign currency to be approximately flat, which is an improvement from our guidance provided last quarter.</p>
          <p>For the recombinant business, we now expect growth for the full year to be in low single digits, which includes the impact of healthcare reform, results of the UK tender, and anticipated reductions in RECOMBINATE inventories. Second, we now expect plasma protein sales to be flat, and antibody therapy sales to decline in mid-single digits, reflecting stabilization in our share position, improving demand, as well as healthcare reform and the difficult comparison related to the termination of the WinRho agreement. Third, we expect regenerative medicine sales growth to exceed 20%, reflecting the ApaTech acquisition and double-digit growth in the base business. And finally, we expect the other category within BioScience to decline approximately 20%, reflecting lower revenues associated with advance purchase agreements and other vaccines.</p>
          <p>For the fourth quarter, as we mentioned in our press release, we expect earnings per diluted share of $1.09 to $1.11, and sales growth excluding the impact of foreign currency of 1% to 2%. Based on current foreign exchange rates, we expect reported sales to be approximately flat to the prior year.</p>
          <p>I would point out that we expect sales growth to slow in the fourth quarter due to a number of factors, including the difficult comparison related to H1N1 revenues, the anniversary of the SIGMA distribution agreement and CRRT acquisition, as well as lower recombinant revenues resulting from the UK tender and reduction of RECOMBINATE inventories.</p>
          <p>As always, I'd be happy to take any questions on our financial performance and guidance during the Q&amp;A, but now let me turn the call back over to Bob for his closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bob. Before we open up this morning's call to Q&amp;A, I'd like to briefly comment on some the organization changes that were announced last week, both in terms of some of the structural changes as well as changes in leadership.</p>
          <p>First, as you know, we announced that our Renal business will be combined with Medication Delivery to form a new business sector, Medical Products. While the go-to-market channels and the clinical differentiation will certainly remain separate and distinct between these businesses, the back ends of the two businesses are actually remarkably similar. As a result, this new structure I believe will enhance both our effectiveness and efficiency over time. Peritoneal dialysis solutions and IV solutions are comprised of similar product development and manufacturing technologies, as are the disposable set and electronic instruments utilized in their administration. There are a significant number of similarities and synergies not only in product development and manufacturing but in supply chain and regulatory and quality systems as well.</p>
          <p>Rob Davis, whom you all know and who has been running the Renal business, has been named President of Medical Products. Peter Arduini, who served as President of Medication Delivery over the past five-plus years, is leaving Baxter to assume the position of President and COO of Integra Life Sciences. I'm convinced that this new integrated structure for the Renal and Medication Delivery business units will pay significant dividends for our customers and the patients that they serve, and also for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Ludwig Hantson was named as the new President of the BioScience business segment. Ludwig replaces Joy Amundson, who served as President of BioScience over the last six years, a period which saw significant growth and where BioScience was the major contributor to Baxter's overall success during that period of time. We're very fortunate to have an executive with Ludwig's pharmaceutical experience. He spent the last 22 years of his career at Novartis and J&amp;J before joining Baxter earlier this year. Baxter's specialty pharmaceutical new product pipeline is the strongest that it has ever been. And as we prepare for multiple new product launches in the coming years, Ludwig's capabilities and expertise will make a tremendous difference. And I'd certainly be happy to expand on that if you'd like during the Q&amp;A this morning.</p>
          <p>So with that, why don't we open up the call for the Q&amp;A?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have Bob Hopkins on the line with Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, can you hear me okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We can hear you loud and clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bob. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, so I just wanted to start out with some questions on BioSciences. First of all, on the slight change in thoughts on the recombinant line, first of all from a macro perspective, should we read into what you're saying that that line item should decelerate from the 2% growth that you put up here in the third quarter? And then more specifically, could you just, if you would, try to quantify the impact of the UK tender and of the RECOMBINATE inventory reduction and how long that might be a drag? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Bob. Let me start and then Bob and Mary Kay can maybe add some additional information to try to be helpful. If you adjust for, as we said in the comments, both the UK tender and the reduction in RECOMBINATE inventories in the U.S., overall RECOMBINATE sales globally grew in say the 7% to 8% range in Q3, which is pretty consistent to what it has been running. Our sales outside the U.S., again adjusted for the UK tender, in all other OUS markets actually grew fairly strong double digits. So the momentum in the business continues. The loss of the volume in the UK tender clearly is meaningful. I think we had annualized sales in the UK, Mary Kay, correct me, of approximately $100 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Approximately over...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A little bit over that, a little bit. So frankly, Bob, how much of that we ultimately lose is still being sorted out. That tender occurred in two different waves, and not all the patients have converted. Obviously, we're watching that very closely over time in terms of things like inhibitor formation and the like.</p>
          <p>So relative to the dynamic in the U.S. then, this is really a continued effect of conversion from RECOMBINATE to ADVATE. Actually, ADVATE in the U.S. in the third quarter, correct me if I'm wrong, I think grew double digits.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so it's evident that a couple of our wholesalers are overstocked on RECOMBINATE and they have reduced their inventories during the third quarter. I would tell you for the fourth quarter, we would expect that to continue, in answer to your question. So as we move into the fourth quarter, that inventory reduction that I described will continue. We're going to continue to incur the impact of the UK tender. But the rest of the dynamics globally of the RECOMBINATE business and the hemophilia business I think continue to be pretty strong. Do you want to add to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Bob, this is Mary Kay. I'd add that we have a difficult comp last year in the U.S., where I think we saw double-digit, 11% growth in the fourth quarter. So you should expect Q4 sales in the RECOMBINATE category to actually be lower than the prior year. And that's a result of the destocking opportunity that Bob is talking about as well as the UK tender.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just one follow-up also on BioSciences. I was wondering if you could quantify the impact of the Octapharma situation on this quarter. Was there any benefit that you saw from that, and just some thoughts on that and how that might impact the business going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was really little to no impact in our third quarter results, Bob, as a result of that. We've reflected modest impact in our fourth quarter guidance that Bob took you through. I think it's still too early to project what the longer term impact of that will be as various regulators are taking various positions on that and so on. So you're probably as close to that as we are; but in terms of our own results, little to no impact in the third quarter, and modest projection in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Modest being like 5 to 10 million area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Less than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say slightly higher than that globally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Globally, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have Kristen Stewart on the line with a question with Deutsche Bank. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Kristen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was just wondering if you could just maybe give us a little bit more color on some of your commentary on the end markets within IVIG. You had expressed a little bit of confidence in what you're seeing. And then also, can you just give us an update on how much in terms of the percentage of outstanding contracts you have secured up for 2011 as we look down the road, and just think about how 2011 may shake out for IVIG, specifically to the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kristen, this is Bob Parkinson. Let me kick that off, and we'll do a team response here because there are multiple aspects of your question. Let me start with the second piece. I would say the majority of our hospital contract business, as I think I touched on in my prepared comments, is actually secured now through year end 2011.</p>
          <p>And in terms of market dynamics, I think we would characterize the underlying market growth to the best of our abilities to quantify this in the U.S. probably mid-single digits in IVIG right now. Clearly, it's more robust OUS, probably approaching high single digits. Bob and Mary Kay, do you want to add any facts to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's pretty accurate. We have seen some good growth, Kristen, coming out of the PPTA [Plasma Protein Therapeutics Association] data that you all see, as well as we've talked about this in past. We track our own redistribution data, which has shown an acceleration in volume as well, which is sales of our product going from the distributors to the end user and into the hospital channel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. And then can we just get an update on SIGMA? I know this quarter you guys had said you had pretty good sales there. Where do you stand from a manufacturing standpoint of just ramping up production of the pumps?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not going to quantify existing production capacity, Kristen. Suffice it to say that we have been and are continuing to ramp up production to convert as many of the install base of the COLLEAGUEs as we possibly can over next two years. It's still too early to tell I think in terms of what the share shifts may or may not be over time. But we're doing everything we can, putting all the resources at ramping it up as significantly as we can. So I'll just leave it at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you also just commented on some of the impacts of healthcare reform and WinRho. Can you just remind us what that was for the IVIG business again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob or Mary Kay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It had a seven point impact overall on the antibody therapy line, and that's the combination of WinRho and healthcare reform.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Bruce Nudell of UBS is on the line with a question. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Could you remind us in aggregate how much in dollars of the healthcare reform accruals that you've made so far this year?  And I know you were very conservative in how you constructed that, assuming almost entire conversion of hospitals and institutions that were eligible for 340B. And how much of that has actually occurred, and is there a potential for a reversal of that accrual?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bruce, this is Bob Hombach. Yes, we continued to accrue just towards the number that we've been projecting up to this point. We're still at a stage where the visibility to how many hospitals are actually going to avail themselves of the opportunity to sign up for 340B is still not crystal clear. We project about 40% of those who could have applied have applied. But there still is time for them to do that as we approach the end of the year. Unfortunately, this one is not going to become clear to us towards the end of the year and maybe not even by the end of the year. So at this point, we continue to accrue towards what we had originally projected.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. So the reversal, if it occurs, has to occur next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we'll take a view. There is the aspect of the retroactive nature of this potentially back to January of 2010. But I believe if hospitals don't sign up by the end of this year, that may not be available to them, and that's certainly something that we originally factored into our accrual. So that we would certainly adjust for as we end this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I guess of the 80 million or so healthcare reform, how much is 340B related and therefore uncertain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say a significant portion of it is 340B related.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the biggest impact, as you know, Bruce, there was the Medicaid rebate impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then there's the increase in the discount to those 340B entities that were already a 340B entity. And then there are these new eligible entities that Bob was talking about where we believe about 40% have already signed up, and that was the biggest piece of our healthcare reform impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so about 40% of that has been exercised you know of?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And my only other question is with regards to recombinant demand in the United States, do you think PPTA data is a decent surrogate at this time for underlying volume demand in high single digits at this instant?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think our view on that has been that looking more at the rolling 12-month data versus the month to month or quarter to quarter is a better view. But yes, I think that mid to high single digit underlying growth is reasonably accurate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think Bruce, too, if you go back to our investor conference, we talked about recombinant sales growth in I think the 6% to 8% range, but that assumes slower growth here in the U.S. in the mid-single digit, probably 4% to 5% range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now, last year looks stronger than that from PPTA data on a rolling basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that would be correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and is home dialysis a 510(k) or PMA [Pre-Market Approval]?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, what was that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is the home dialysis IDE, is it a 510(k) or a PMA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our assumption currently is a 510(k).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>David Lewis of Morgan Stanley is on the line with the question. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob, just coming back to IVIG here for a second, obviously the number was much stronger than we were expecting. So can we just first of all talk about rebate activity? You talked about it being targeted off the second quarter. Did you see an expansion of rebate activity at the company, and should we expect a further expansion heading into the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When you say rebate activity, specifically what are you referring to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You talked about targeted pricing. Our sense is that you've used rebates as a method for engaging in targeted pricing with customers. I think surgical strike pricing, something like that, was your commentary off the second quarter. I'm just wondering if we've gone from surgical strike pricing with rebating and targeted price cuts to a broader action in the third or fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not really, I think that the activities we've undertaken are very much in line with what we've been messaging from the start. And yes, there are contracts that involve rebates, David. But no, I think what we've executed really over the last three to six months here has been very much in line with what we described to all of you at the outset.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, so just maybe two more quick questions and starting with one follow-up. So in this particular quarter, Bob, if you had to describe the source of upside for your IVIG business both U.S. and worldwide, do you think it was concerted expectations? Was it better share gains? Maybe give us more color on what you think drove the relative upside.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the actions we've taken clearly were very effective, and they were effective very quickly. The price premium on GAMMAGARD, clearly we closed that very significantly. And the market was very, very responsive to that, not only in terms of retaining volume in the short term, but allowing us to secure contracts, as I mentioned in my comments, now for the majority of our U.S. hospital business out through the end of the year 2011. So I think that's probably the primary aspect of the stronger volume that we reported in the third quarter in the U.S. Clearly, volumes outside the United States continue to grow very nicely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dave, I would add, there was a lot of assumptions that went into our original guidance reduction. And if you remember, we had said at that time that the market growth was in low single digits. Clearly, we're seeing that market growth has accelerated, as Bob mentioned, to mid-single digits, as well as we had assumed additional share loss, which obviously we're not seeing that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect, and just one last financial question. Just to give two dynamics in the quarter that did the opposite of what we were expecting, gross margins were better but tax rate was much higher. And maybe the question is about the sustainability of those gross margins. And back in your LRP late last year, you talked about the expansion of tax rate for your company in the next three to four years. Is this the first sign of that in your mind or is this more about mix?  And so net-net, what we can expect as it relates going forward in terms of gross margin and tax rate trends? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start with the tax rate. Clearly the mix of earnings this year has been quite a bit different than we originally projected. The underperformance in Europe really across all three businesses in a place where we've got pretty efficient tax structures has negatively impacted the rate; and on the other side of the equation, very strong performance in the U.S., particularly by Medication Delivery in a high tax environment, so it's primarily a mix shift there. We did anticipate some of that as we go forward here, but this has happened to a larger degree. So as we look into 2011, we'll have to evaluate the Europe/U.S. mix of earnings as we think about the tax rate going forward.</p>
          <p>In terms of gross margin, clearly the stronger performance in the quarter by the BioScience business and what I would characterize as the faster recovery in the IVIG space in particular certainly helped margins. As we go forward here though, we are going to be faced with starting to feel the impact of the slowdown in collections and slowdown in throughput in the plasma business starting to roll out to our P&amp;L given the long inventory hold periods as we started taking those actions late last year and early this year. We're starting to feel the impacts of that as we go into fourth quarter, and that will be a headwind as we go into 2011 on margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>David Roman is on the line with a question from Goldman Sachs. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wanted to see, Bob, if you could update us on your latest thoughts on the pharma tax for next year. I think you provided some numbers earlier this year. And then any thoughts on how that might flow through just from an accounting perspective. And then I have one follow-up on the plasma business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so we've estimated at this point the pharma tax is going to be 30 to 40 million, and at this point don't know for sure what the geography is going to be on the P&amp;L for that one. I think the med device one a couple years down the road is a little clearer, that that's an excise tax that probably ends up in SG&amp;A. But the pharma tax between revenue and SG&amp;A is still an open question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then from an operating expense perspective, you called out SG&amp;A as one of the lowest levels it has been in several years, R&amp;D also as a percentage of revenue. I know currency has an impact there. That also was fairly low as a percent of sales. Maybe going forward, could you just help us think about the sustainable level of discretionary spending?</p>
          <p>And one of the other things you talked about earlier this year was pulling back on some of the wild-card type investments in that R&amp;D line. Did that have any contribution this quarter? And is 6.5% a number in R&amp;D to think about, or is seven, where you had been running?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it will stay in that range going forward, David, the 6.5 to 7% range. As we commented, every one of our major programs remain fully funded. I think Bob commented that in fact of our significant programs, actually our R&amp;D in the quarter actually increased mid-single digits versus last year. The reduction was largely associated with the culmination of a couple of key programs, one of which is the flu program. So our level of spending on our flu vaccine programs is down significantly. Also, some payments to partners and a couple of R&amp;D collaborations and so on were the significant contributors to the lower spending level in Q3.</p>
          <p>But I don't think you should interpret the Q3 results as at all a change in strategic direction. I think it's important that we maintain some level of, call it exploratory or early-stage funding. I think that's very important. We're committed to continue to do that going forward. I don't know, Bob, if...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would just add on the R&amp;D a couple things. One, from a foreign exchange standpoint, our R&amp;D spend, almost 50% of it is outside the U.S., primarily in Europe. So FX has a slightly bigger impact on the R&amp;D line than it would have on SG&amp;A and other.</p>
          <p>The other thing I would say is the exploratory funding, which is modest generally, is really where we rationalized this year initially. Plus we took a charge in the fourth quarter of 2009 to rationalize some of our R&amp;D operations, primarily on the device side, and so we're seeing the full benefits of that coming through as well. So I think those two factors have driven that down.</p>
          <p>On the SG&amp;A side in terms of sustainability of the discretionary spend actions that we've taken, as we indicated, we're really focused on the back office G&amp;A lines to try to constrain spending, particularly around head count growth there. But we continue to fund the promotional activities around demand creation and new product launches that we think are going to be important to drive the top line going forward. So we don't think we've compromised that aspect of our spend at all here, and still room to continue to drive some cost reductions</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike Weinstein of JPMorgan is on the line with a question. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for taking the questions. First, maybe just turning to the Med Delivery business, I was hoping you could just shed a little bit more light on the growth in the U.S. for IV therapies, which was up 18%. And then infusion systems, which was up 8% despite obviously the issues with COLLEAGUE. Both very strong numbers, and I think particularly infusion systems with what was going on with COLLEAGUE. So maybe you can help us out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let me kick this off, Mike. This is Bob Parkinson. A number of different pieces. Obviously first of all, at a high level, we're very pleased with the growth of our Med-Del business, particularly in the U.S. We were advantaged in the quarter to some degree by some competitive supply issues, particularly in the area of nutritionals and some of our multi-source generics and so on.</p>
          <p>I also commented in my prepared comments and I highlight the contract that we signed with Novation. And we've probably picked up a little bit of business there as well, which certainly is sustainable going forward. So the nutritional business continues to do very well, not just in the U.S., but on a global basis, which is helpful, as you know, in terms of margin profile. And what are the other pieces that I'm missing?  Those are really the biggest pieces.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've definitely seen some good pricing improvement in the base IV business. And as I mentioned in my comments, some competitor issues on the nutritional front in the U.S. provided opportunity there as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I would just add, Mike, IV Solutions year-to-date are up double digits in the U.S. That's driven by some of the market share gains I think Bob was discussing as well as the improved pricing environment. And then Bob mentioned the nutritional competitive issues that we're picking up some share there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the infusion systems front, we have some competitive wins with the SPECTRUM pump, and that continues to do very well in the marketplace. So while customers are currently evaluating their options as we provided them with the COLLEAGUE transition guide only in September here, during the quarter, again, we did see some competitive wins and some nice growth with the SPECTRUM pump.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Before we get to January, I want to make sure we're thinking generally about 2011 correctly. It seems like on the call here you highlighted a few items that will impact the P&amp;L. There's obviously impact from healthcare reform next year. You talked about lower throughput for plasma proteins, and that's starting to show up maybe in the fourth quarter and into next year. And then lower growth within recombinants, which is obviously a high margin business for you, as well as a couple other items. Should we be thinking about 2011 after margin gains this year, 2011 in which we'll probably not see operating leverage down the P&amp;L, or is that still possible?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's too early to call that, Mike, frankly. But yes, look, there are headwinds. And if you look at some of the dynamics that we continue to manage through and we've incurred in 2010, they just don't all go away come December 31, as much as we might like that. So while we continue to be optimistic about the future in many ways and for many reasons, there are a number of these headwinds that are going to continue.</p>
          <p>The other thing I would tell you that you didn't mention is just the underlying surgical procedure volume and so on. One of the things that as you look in the detail of the quarter that was softer than we had anticipated was our biosurgery business. When you adjust out for the ApaTech acquisition last year, the rest of our biosurgery business was about 9, 10% growth for the quarter, which is lower than what it has been, and frankly I think is an indication of the continued softness in underlying surgical procedures.</p>
          <p>So I'm not trying to paint too negative of an outlook here, but I think we have to be realistic as we go forward to say a lot of positive things going, but there's going to be some headwinds that are going to be sustainable. And I guess maybe to close where I started, it's too early to project what the net effect of those are, but I think just a lot of variables we all need to continue to watch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I appreciate it; one last follow-up. With you locking in a lot of your 2011 contracts for IVIG at this point, can you give us a sense of where those are coming out for pricing relative to 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, without being too specific for a lot of reasons, let me just give you some general direction, Mike, which hopefully will be helpful. We had, going into all this let's say a year ago, probably I would say high single digit price premium on GAMMAGARD versus the rest of the products in the market. That premium has closed significantly. We still are the premium product, but that premium has closed fairly significantly. And I would tell you the contracts that I referenced that we've now signed extending through the end of 2011 have really been at what I call the touch-up prices, so we didn't need to offer additional price discounts to secure that volume. So hopefully that gives you enough input you can put your arms around it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's good. Thank you, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Rick Wise of Leerink Swann is on the line with a question. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Bob. A couple things, one just a high level follow-up. Post the management changes and the combination of the Med Delivery and Renal businesses, I'm just curious what you've charged Rob with doing in combining those two businesses, and what you see the opportunities are. Do you think there are going to be incremental sales opportunities because of bundling or customers? And maybe talk, if you could, about your thoughts about what kind of margin, operating margin benefits you think we could see, if any.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great question, Rick, and again I'm not going to quantify the potential margin enhancement opportunity at this stage. Having said that, clearly I wouldn't have made this change if I didn't think there weren't meaningful opportunities here. And I would start with by saying I think the biggest opportunity is as much effectiveness, enhancing our effectiveness as it is in terms of taking cost out. Both are opportunities. But let me give you some examples of that.</p>
          <p>First of all, bundling, you mentioned that. I don't see any bundling opportunities. In terms of go-to-market, detailing PD solutions to nephrologists will always remain a separate and distinct activity for detailing SUPRANE to an anesthesiologist. Those will remain separate and distinct. But I think in the back end of the business, starting with manufacturing, you don't go &#x2013; and very few of our solution plants around the world manufacture both IV solutions and PD solutions.  Manufacturing was a separate organization that also reported to me and now that has reported into Rob as part of the consolidation of Renal and Med Del.</p>
          <p>So I think the integration of manufacturing and supply chain where there are, as I commented, significant overlap in similarities between the Renal business and the IV business &#x2013; and again, not just on the solutions but on the disposable sets and the instrumentation, whether that's an infusion pump or a HOMECHOICE cycler, tremendous synergies there. And the strategic objective of this is really to enhance effectiveness. And I'll just give you one example, and then I'll stop and not belabor the point.</p>
          <p>But in terms of R&amp;D productivity, to focus our R&amp;D efforts and integrate where historically we've had fragmented R&amp;D supporting the Renal business versus the Med Del business, given the fact that the core technologies are oftentimes very similar, I believe by bringing those together, there are significant opportunities to enhance our new product development, frankly. And so clearly that has an effect over time on accelerating the revenue line. Now having said that, I think there also are structural synergies, cost synergies that over time we'll figure out how to take cost out as well. And so this is really dual objectives. How do we enhance our effectiveness? There are many ways I think we can enhance our top line growth while taking structural cost out of the business. And I think Rob, for a lot of reasons, is the perfect guy to oversee those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. PD's results, Bob, also looked pretty encouraging. We've talked to a bunch of nephrologists that are thinking that home dialysis PD and home HD are going to benefit from the new reimbursement rules, but it's going to be a more gradual increase. Are we seeing something, some moves ahead of the new reimbursement? Maybe give us some sense. Are you more optimistic about driving PD penetration from whatever it is, 7 to 8%, to 10, 15%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, well, a couple of comments. Yes, we are seeing encouraging signs that there already is movement. If you look at our PD patient growth in the U.S. through the first three quarters of the year, it's the strongest that it has been in years. And I think the primary driver for that is the market getting ready for reimbursement change. And I do think you're right, Rick. It will be gradual over time, but it will be sustained and it will be meaningful. And so yes, we're starting to see already encouraging metrics that would indicate that that's coming about.</p>
          <p>It's interesting as you just read articles, even in the lay press and so on, this theme of dialysis in the home. Frankly, whether that's PD, which clearly plays to a Baxter strength, or home hemodialysis, which is our number one R&amp;D program in the Renal business, are clearly aligned with that trend that's underway. I think it's becoming increasingly recognized. There was an article just a couple weeks ago I think in the personal section of The Wall Street Journal that did a good job of describing some of the dynamics here. Whether it's patient convenience, whether it's cost of delivering the therapy, or at the end of the day enhancement of clinical outcomes, there's a lot more people and both patients and clearly nephrologists that are thinking about providing these treatments in the home environment. So this macro trend, if you will, clearly is playing into the strategies that we've defined in the Renal business.</p>
          <p>But back to the last part of your question, too early to quantify this, but I think it will over time continue to accelerate the growth of Renal, which is frankly the bet that we've been placing over the last few years. The Renal business, as you know, has been relatively flat over the last few years. But we felt that there was long-term change that existed here and we're at the early stages of it, so we're encouraged by those developments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Last quick one, I know most of your cash is OUS. I'm hearing talk about a tax holiday possibility. If that would happen, what would your redeployment priorities be in the U.S., and maybe just any update on your thoughts about the portfolio and acquisitions to leverage some of these changes you're talking about?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'll take the tax holiday. I think that's a fairly recent piece of news that's being discussed more actively. I think it's too early to really know whether there's a good chance that's going to happen. You're right; the majority of our cash is offshore. And certainly any opportunity to bring it back in a tax-efficient manner would be attractive to us. But I think it's way too early to be thinking about that concretely. In terms of...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, Rick, nothing new on the BD M&amp;A from an acquisition front other than our intent, which continues to be what I've described before. I spend a lot more of my time on this. Clearly, we have the financial latitude to do some things. And I'm hopeful going forward that we will, but they're not the things you can become aware of until we finalize them and communicate them. But the strategic intent remains there and the financial flexibility to support that clearly is there as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Larry Keusch of Morgan Keegan is on the line with a question. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Perhaps for either Bob, as you think about gross margin on a go-forward basis, can you just review with us what are the puts and takes that we should be thinking about as we think for the fourth quarter and on a go-forward basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to do a Frick and Frack here, or Bob and Bob?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, why don't you take it? I've got a few things. There are lots of elements to this one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think the underlying dynamic of higher margin products growing faster over time I think very much is still intact. There are some nearer term things in the fourth quarter that we are going to have to deal with. I mentioned the inefficiencies in manufacturing and collection of plasma beginning to impact the margin here. That will play out into 2011 as well.</p>
          <p>Foreign exchange does have an impact as well. At times when currencies on the dollar is stronger against foreign currencies, we do hedge. And so that tends to have lower sales but margin stays the same, so the margin gets a benefit. As the euro and other currencies have appreciated against the dollar here, that will be a little bit of a drag in the fourth quarter as well. So it's not a significant move, but it is enough to shift things one quarter to the next.</p>
          <p>So as we go forward, I think the plasma dynamic and FX are two things that could be headwinds here in the near term, but certainly the underlying dynamic of mix driving margin benefit I think is still very much intact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I really can't add anything to that. The mix component, clearly the margin differences of our core businesses remain fairly significant with the higher margin BioScience business. So clearly stabilizing the growth, particularly focused on plasma proteins, is critical there. So we'll see how the business mix and the business unit mix play out going forward.</p>
          <p>The business units in our Medical Products business, nutritionals, anesthesia, and so on, as you know, Larry, continue to be a promotional priority. So to the degree of business units and businesses that are higher margin can grow faster, that continues to be the area of focus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is it safe to assume that just given very nice margin expansion we've seen in Medication Delivery that we probably shouldn't be thinking about those magnitudes on a go-forward basis either?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably not to the same degree, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just separately as I think about the overall portfolio of the company, I guess I just want to understand, Bob. How strategic do you think the vaccine business really is to Baxter over a longer time period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it continues to be of significant strategic interest to us, and we've talked about this before. Clearly there have been fits and starts with last year's H1N1 situation and so on and so forth. But even in the third quarter, and I commented on this, our collaboration with Takeda. I believe that we are going to figure out ways to monetize our Vero cell technology, but in ways that aren't necessarily conventional in terms of producing and selling directly to on the market our own vaccines, and I think the collaboration with Takeda is a good example of that. We continue to have dialogue with other countries who are and continue to be focused on preparedness and with not so much an H1N1 but still the concern about H5N1 where our technology has some particular advantages.</p>
          <p>I think the registration or the licensure in the third quarter in Europe of PREFLUCEL, our influenza vaccine, is also very encouraging, and we're going to move forward to get that product registered throughout the world, including the U.S., and participate in that market as well. Then there are some other vaccines which we commented on in our last investor conference that are in our pipeline and so on.</p>
          <p>So yes, I continue to be very interested, Larry, in the vaccines business. And so I know looking at the sales, the revenue results every quarter and so on, it's a mixed bag based upon what is particularly happening at that point in time. But don't interpret that as any less interest in terms of the strategic value of this business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, terrific. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have Matt Miksic on the line with a question from Piper Jaffray. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Matt Miksic, thanks for taking our questions. I wanted to discuss some odds and ends here and follow up on a couple things that you've talked about, Bob. One was on the combination Med Delivery and Renal. I don't know if you've talked about what some of the front end/back end opportunities are. Can you quantify any of those?  Have you quantified them?  It sounded from Bob Hombach's comments that you've maybe already started to see in this quarter some of the benefits of that. Some color on that would be helpful, and then I just have a couple quick follow-ups.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, look, we haven't really incurred any benefit from that change. It was just recent and in terms of the Med-Del/Renal integration into Medical Products, if that was your question, Matt. And we haven't quantified specifically what the opportunity there is long term. But as I commented, I think it was in response to Rick's question earlier, you don't make structural changes organizationally lightly because it impacts a lot of things. And we would not have done it if we didn't think there was not material opportunity that was represented by this organization change.</p>
          <p>And as I said before, it's going to manifest itself in a couple different ways: I think enhanced R&amp;D productivity; improved commercial focus and prioritization. It will help accelerate the growth of our revenue line over time. But there also are structural cost advantages that will be incurred where we have overlap and redundancies in a lot of the back-end components of getting product to market in both the Renal and the Medication Delivery business, both in the U.S. and on a global basis. So that benefit will cascade out over time. It will be evolutionary. But again maybe to close where I started here, we wouldn't have done it if we didn't think the opportunity was reasonably material over time, but I think it's premature to quantify that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, is that something that you think you'll be able to put some numbers to or some more detail to maybe when you talk about 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so just something that just buried in there will be some flexibility that we'll see the general benefit from I guess is the way to look at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think that's right</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then one follow-up on &#x2013; you talked about volumes, procedure volumes, hospital admissions having an impact, the general thing that's impacting everyone else having an impact on Regen Med [Regenerative Medicine]. I'm wondering how to reconcile what has been a gradually improving U.S. say IVIG market with that dynamic just because I remember when the IVIG market was slowing, I think we were scratching our heads thinking is it admissions, is it patients going to see the doc less; any way to reconcile that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's a tough one. I just think there are so many variables in the IVIG market that make it much more elusive to track down with underlying procedures unlike say Medical Devices, like our biosurgery products.</p>
          <p>Whether it's adjustment of inventory in the channel, whether it's change in the channel from hospital versus pharmacies, whether it's reimbursement pressure for very expensive therapy where there are various reactions but then over time settling out, an array of competitive dynamics with suppliers that a year or so ago may have been out of the market but get back in, there are a laundry list of variables. And I just think it's really difficult to associate underlying surgical procedure or hospital admission volumes with what's going on in IVIG. That is really analytically a tough one to connect the dots.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then finally on pumps, just I don't know if you had talked about what to expect here in the rest of the year. I guess we're getting to a point soon where you're going to start replacing COLLEAGUEs with SIGMAs potentially or are going through that process. This was a pretty strong quarter. Should we see some moderation in the fourth quarter?  I guess how should we think about the rest of the year in pumps?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we've been replacing COLLEAGUE with SIGMAs now for the better part of the last year since we did the deal I think with SIGMA. Clearly, that has accelerated to some degree as a result of the consent order that was finalized a couple of months ago. It's very early on. We've seen very little, if any, share shift frankly; in other words, hospitals opting to go to a competitor versus waiting for their SIGMA pumps and so on. But I would emphasize that's still early. So as we go into fourth quarter, Mary Kay, help me out here. Are there some dynamics last year? I don't want to miss them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sequentially, we expect it to be just as strong, Matt. But remember, year over year we started selling SIGMA in the fourth quarter of last year, so we do have a difficult comp to the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so sequentially tough &#x2013; I mean year-over-year tough, but no wobble here we should see all of a sudden in terms of this FDA process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, customers are just now giving an indication, an early indication. The actual activity is going to be in 2011 before we really see any actual swap-outs or refunds and so on, which will be something we have to factor into our guidance on 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then last on Renal, you talked to I think one of the earlier questions on the opportunity there for PD. Do you have a number where pump &#x2013; PD penetration is currently in the U.S., Bob? Or I don't know if Rob is on, but any update as to where you think it is, and maybe a number as to the next couple years? Where do you think it could go?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't want to give you a number. I think actually over time, there will be a new metric. It won't be PD penetration. It will be home therapy penetration, and that's an orientation that aligned with our strategic intent, with the development of home HD, very much aligned with the change in reimbursement practice. So I think the historic metric of PD penetration will become increasingly pass&#xE9;.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough, thanks again for taking the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Matt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Sean, we have time for just one more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question is Ben Andrew with William Blair. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two quick questions. Mary Kay or Bob, maybe can you help us understand what's going on with your pace of collections in plasma? Have you dialed that back up, or are you still working on your raw materials inventory?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say in the third quarter, collections were still down year over year, so at this point we've made no change to collections.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just finally on the home hemo side, Bob, you were talking a fair bit about that on this call. Do you think that the first study coming out of the IDE is going to be an in-center study or an in-home first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will be an in-center.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In-center; and so how long do you think that will take to run and when can you start on the in-home trial?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what we're finalizing, Ben, with the FDA. We just submitted to them the finalized IDE. And once that's accepted, we can provide with you the details on that clinical trial design.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so it will be at least a 510(k) Class IIb filing, but there's some uncertainty whether it will turn into a PMA over time. Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't believe that we believe that there's any uncertainty at this point. We believe it's a 510(k) based on our discussions with the FDA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's conference call with Baxter International. Thank you for participating, everyone have a wonderful day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>