<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1239296" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-26</date>
    <companies>
      <company>810</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Alexander Rosar, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Werner Wenning, Chairman of the Board of Management</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Sachin Jain</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Arthur Higgins</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Patrick Thomas</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Christian Faitz</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Friedrich Berschauer</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Richard Vosser</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep">Klaus K&#xFC;hn</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Rim Bennani</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Fabian Wenner</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Florent Cespedes</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Thomas Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Jean De Watteville</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Bruce Nudell</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Mike Leuchten</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Jo Walton</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Tero Weckroth</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Andrew Stott</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst">Daniel Wendorff</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst">Martin Fl&#xFC;ckiger</participant>
      <participant id="22" type="analyst">Naresh Chouhan</participant>
      <participant id="23" type="analyst">Blake Arnold</participant>
      <participant id="24" type="analyst">Ronald K&#xF6;hler</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to Bayer's Investor and Analyst Conference Call. Throughout today's recorded presentation, all participants will be in a listen-only mode. The presentation will be followed by a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Mr. Alexander Rosar, Head of Investor Relations at Bayer AG. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Cleo. Good afternoon, everybody. Also, on behalf of my colleagues, I'd like to welcome you to our Q4 full year 2009 conference call. With us today on the call are our CEO, Werner Wenning.</p>
          <p>Today, joining from the Board of Management side are Marijn Dekkers, Klaus K&#xFC;hn and Werner Baumann; and our subgroups today are represented by Arthur Higgins from HealthCare, Friedrich Berschauer from CropScience, and Patrick Thomas from MaterialScience.</p>
          <p>Before handing over to Mr. Wenning for his introduction, I'd like to draw your attention to the forward-looking wording, which governs our call.</p>
          <p>Thank you. Mr. Wenning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. In 2009 in the most challenging business environment we have seen for decades, we generated record sales in HealthCare and CropScience and achieved the third highest underlying EBITDA in Bayer's history. In the last couple of years, we have systematically driven the company forward. Our restructuring projects and the integration of Schering are now complete.</p>
          <p>The improvements in our working capital management boosted net cash flow to a record &#x20AC;5.4 billion in 2009. During 2009, the business recovered steadily. By Q4, underlying EBITDA was back to the pre-crisis levels. This underlines the strength of the business and makes us optimistic for 2010 and beyond.</p>
          <p>This morning, we published new mid-term financial targets with a clear focus on profitable growth. We have again committed to long-term performance targets despite the continued uncertainty resulting from the financial crisis.</p>
          <p>In other words, the improvement process at Bayer is ongoing. This optimistic forecast is the key reason why we are proposing that the AGM declares a dividend of &#x20AC;1.40 per share, the same as for 2008.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, now, let's take a brief look at the 2009 figures. I assume that you are already quite familiar with our numbers. So I will just comment on some of the most important ones, with all the sales data adjusted for portfolio and currency effects.</p>
          <p>During the fourth quarter, the upward trend in our business was confirmed. In Q4, we saw a strong business expansion at HealthCare and CropScience and a slight increase in sales at MaterialScience.</p>
          <p>Group sales improved by 3% and underlying EBITDA by 11.5% to &#x20AC;1.5 billion. Q4 underlying EBITDA matches pre-crisis levels and was the strongest fourth quarter in the last five years.</p>
          <p>Core earnings per share at &#x20AC;0.90 exceeded last year's level by 27%. Special items amounted to 451 million in the quarter and 766 million in the full year.  Higher than expected legal charges and the accelerated finalization of our running restructuring programs were the main reasons for the higher than originally anticipated amount.</p>
          <p>Restructuring projects are now finalized thus we do not expect to incur special charges for restructuring programs in 2010.  The continuous optimization of our cost structure and further efficiency improvements certainly will remain part of day to day business practice.</p>
          <p>HealthCare had a strong finish to a successful year. Sales in the quarter grew 6% against a strong base in the previous year, driven by both our pharma and our consumer businesses.  We are particularly pleased with HealthCare performance in the emerging markets.  The emerging seven, the BRIC countries plus Mexico, South Korea and Turkey, they grew by an impressive 17%. And in China, we were even more successful gaining more than 40% in the People's Republic.</p>
          <p>In Pharma, sales improved by almost 7%, driven by the performance of our key brands. The YAZ product family advanced 6%; and Mirena 3%; Nexavar was up 24%, Kogenate 9, Avelox, 18, and Betaferon, 6%,</p>
          <p>Our OTC business expanded 5% in the quarter mainly driven by a fast growing ex-U.S. business. In the U.S. we were coming off a very strong Q4 '08 that was largely driven by promotional campaigns in the U.S. and buying ahead of price increases in Q1, '09,</p>
          <p>Medical care gained market share in various countries around the world. Business was up 4%. The Animal Health market is stabilizing and consumer demand seems to be normalizing. Here we grew sales by 3%.</p>
          <p>HealthCare's underlying EBITDA in the fourth quarter advance by 5% to &#x20AC;1.154 billion, both Pharma and our consumer health businesses contributed to this increase.</p>
          <p>CropScience also saw a strong finish to the year. Sales were up 6% in the quarter. The increase was driven by higher volumes, that over compensated for the effect of a 4% drop in prices in the quarter, due to aggressive selling by competitors. For the full year prices at CropScience were up a little over 1%.</p>
          <p>In crop protection, Q4 sales improved by 7% with growth in all regions. The strongest growth was achieved in Latin America where business advanced 10%. In Brazil business improved 10% as well. In Asia-Pacific we grew sales by 5%. In North America we advanced 6% due to earlier orders for our herbicides. Sales in Europe improved 7% driven by our fungicides and seed treatment products.</p>
          <p>The top line of environmental science grew 3% due to business growth in both the professional and consumer units. BioScience recorded a sales decline of 3% due to lower cotton seeds sales.</p>
          <p>Underlying EBITDA at CropScience declined 9% mainly because of the world currency impacts and lower selling prices.</p>
          <p>At MaterialScience, sales increased 1% to &#x20AC;2 billion, higher volumes, up 19%, we almost entirely offset by lower selling prices which diminished sales by 18%.</p>
          <p>In the more meaningful quarter-on-quarter comparison, sales were almost on par with Q3. We saw somewhat softer volumes due to the seasonally lower economic activity at the end of the year. Also there was a small improvement in selling prices. This pattern was very consistent in all our major businesses.</p>
          <p>On the regional perspective we are encouraged by the growth of the business in Asia Pacific. They have increased 30% year-on-year with volumes of all major products well above pre-crisis levels. The strongest recovery we were experiencing in China, also in Europe and to a lesser extent in NAFTA the sequential improvement is visible. Compared with the lows at the at the end of 2008 or the beginning of last year, volumes and prices are recovering, however business activity is still significantly below pre-crisis levels.</p>
          <p>Underlying EBITDA in the quarter was almost four times as high as for the prior year quarter at just over &#x20AC;200 million. Essentially lower selling prices were offset by our volumes, savings and lower raw material and energy prices.</p>
          <p>One of the most remarkable achievements in the quarter was cash generation. Net cash flow improved by 85% to almost &#x20AC;1.8 billion. We kept close control over our capital expenditures. Free operating cash flow was raised to almost 1.3 billion, nearly four times the previous year's figure.</p>
          <p>In the full year 2009, net cash flow improved to a record 5.4 billion, an increase of almost 50% compared with fiscal 2008. Operating cash flow, free cash flow advanced to 3.8 billion, more than double the amount generated in 2008.</p>
          <p>These are truly outstanding numbers and evidence of the major progress achieved in our working capital project. Cash inflow from improvements in trade working capital amounted to 800 million. This is in line with the target we set ourselves for 2009.</p>
          <p>Net debt at the end of the year amounted to 9.7 billion, a reduction of 1 billion compared with the end of the third quarter or 4.5 billion from the end of 2008, including the conversion of the mandatory convertible bonds.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, please allow me some comments on our full year results compared with our targets. In fiscal 2009, HealthCare which has had growth in all divisions, mostly at pharma probably a little behind market growth. It generated the underlying EBITDA margin of almost 28%. This is exactly on target despite negative currency impact.</p>
          <p>CropScience further increase sales and market share. We achieved our sales target of 2 billion with new active ingredients. In terms of earnings, we were unable to match 2008 performance due to higher raw material costs and negative currency effects.</p>
          <p>For MaterialScience, it was a very difficult year, as expected. We initiated a record broad response to the sharp drop in demand. These actions helped profits to recover in the course of the year. We are particularly pleased to report that the subgroup managed to improve net cash flow and achieve a positive free operating cash flow.</p>
          <p>Group sales fell by 6% to 31.2 billion and we limited the decline in underlying EBITDA to a little over 6% or if adjusted for currency effect to a little less than 5%.</p>
          <p>I am sure you would agree that we navigated the economic downturn with considerable success making 2009 operationally one of the three best years in Bayer's history. Even more impressive was the amount of cash we generated. This enabled us, as already mentioned, to reduce net financial debt to 9.7 billion, a bigger drop than expected.</p>
          <p>Please allow me to also put 2009 performance in a little broader perspective. Since 2002, we have more than quadrupled group underlying EBIT and improved the EBITDA margin by nine percentage points.</p>
          <p>This upward trend was largely driven by consistent strong improvement in HealthCare. In 2009, we generated an underlying EBITDA margin of 28%. We are fast approaching the margins of our European peers. Whilst in CropScience greatly improved its performance and achieved its 25% margin target in 2008. Over this period, MaterialScience demonstrated its earning power by generating 18% EBITDA margins in 2005. This is a clear cyclical business, something we have never denied. However, the decline of margins in 2009 was unprecedented and should be viewed as exceptional.</p>
          <p>Having, achieved our margin targets, our main focus for the future is on creating value through profitable growth, thus balancing the need for investments in growth and further earnings improvements. We plan to continue investing primarily in our R&amp;D pipeline, in BioScience and in emerging markets.</p>
          <p>We are now &#x2013; what are now our concrete financial plans for 2010 and beyond?</p>
          <p>2010 Group outlook projects portfolio and currency adjusted sales to grow by more than 5%, underlying EBITDA to improve toward &#x20AC;7 billion and core earnings per share to increase by about 10%. Our estimates are based on an exchange rate of U.S. $1.40 to the euro.</p>
          <p>The capital budget is 1.4 billion, D&amp;A I expected to total about 2.6 billion. The R&amp;D budget is set at &#x20AC;2.9 billion. We are also optimistic for the years beyond 2010. For 2012 we expect to achieve steady currency and portfolio adjusted growth of approximately 5% annually. We plan to raise underlying EBITDA to around &#x20AC;8 billion by 2012. We are targeting on average 10% annual improvement in core earnings per share, which would mean an increase to around &#x20AC;5 per share.</p>
          <p>We expect all our subgroups to grow sales and improve underlying EBITDA through 2012.</p>
          <p>HealthCare plans to grow at least with the market in 2010. This corresponds to a portfolio and currency adjusted expansion of about 5%. We also intend to increase underlying EBITDA. Beyond 2010, we aim to continue growing at least with the market through 2012 and to steadily improve underlying EBITDA.</p>
          <p>For CropScience, we anticipate slightly above market growth in 2010 equivalent to a portfolio and currency-adjusted increase of approximately 4%. We are targeting a small increase in underlying EBITDA. However, the business environment is currently more difficult than we assumed in our planning. Looking beyond 2010, we aim to continue to grow at least with the market through 2012 and to further improve underlying EBITDA.</p>
          <p>We anticipate a continued recovery in demand in our MaterialScience business. In light of this we aim to increase sales by more than 10% on a currency and portfolio-adjusted basis in 2010. We're also targeting a substantial increase in underlying EBITDA. We expect to report somewhat higher sales in Q1 than in Q4 last year. In light of further increases in raw material costs, we expect first quarter underlying EBITDA to come in roughly level with the preceding quarter. Provided the economic recovery continues, we expect MaterialScience to return to its pre-crisis sales level of more than &#x20AC;10 billion by 2012. We also plan to considerably improve underlying EBITDA through 2012.</p>
          <p>We expect significant news flow concerning our Pharma pipeline in the course of 2010. On Xarelto we expect to finalize the EINSTEIN DVT, the ROCKET AF and the MAGELLAN clinical trails in the course of this year. Let me reiterate that all these studies remain fully on track.</p>
          <p>Please allow me to also update you on the Complete Response Letter for the prophylaxis of Venous Thromboembolism [VTE] in patients undergoing total hip or total knee replacement surgery. We and our partner J&amp;J are currently gathering the necessary information requested by FDA in its Complete Response Letter. We are in regular contact with the FDA to review our progress. We currently plan to submit our response to the Complete Response Letter as well as our application for stroke prevention in patients with atrial fibrillation in the second half of 2010.</p>
          <p>In Nexavar, the completion of the NExUS trial investigating Nexavar in lung cancer is expected. We plan to initiate Phase III clinical trials in breast cancer during the year. Additionally, we expect data from VEGF-Trap-Eye and to announce phase transition with Riociguat and Regorafenib.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, in the most challenging year for decades we managed to grow our business to new record highs in HealthCare and CropScience, generated the third highest underlying EBITDA ever in the group, and we achieved a record net cash flow. We are optimistic about our future. This is clearly expressed in our new detailed financial outlook until the year 2012.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, in recent years we have changed the face of Bayer. In the course of this year Mr. Marijn Dekkers, our new CEO, and Mr. Werner Baumann, our new CFO, will take up their duties. Expect the new management to be as committed as we have been to driving the company forward with a clear focus on performance. Marijn Dekkers and Werner Baumann took part in the entire target setting process.</p>
          <p>That ladies and gentlemen, concludes my remarks. We are now happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Operator Instruction]. The first question comes from Mr. Jain. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Sachin Jain from Merrill Lynch, I assume that was me. Couple of questions, couple of product questions and a couple of questions on 2012 guidance. On products, Xarelto, just wonder if filing timelines in orthopedic, just to check that it's essentially requirements of long term data and I wondered if you could clarify whether the clinical trial sight issues are now resolved or still ongoing?</p>
          <p>Second question on the Yasmin franchise just wonder if you could comment what percentage of franchise you assume you can protect from YAZ plus within your 2012 guidance and whether that guidance include any European generic competition?</p>
          <p>A specific question on MaterialScience with the 2012 guidance, just wondering whether pre-crisis sales levels would be associated with pr-crisis margins, i.e., EBITDA back at 1.5, 1.6 level?</p>
          <p>And then my final question: how dependent is the 2012 target of 8 billion on economic recovery and a return to pre-crisis levels within MaterialScience? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sachin first Arthur will answer your HealthCare related questions &#x2013; pharma related questions. Arthur?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sachin. Regarding Xarelto and the complete response, I don't think many of you on the call today will be surprised with the delay. You're all very aware of how in recent times the FDA has become very conservative in terms of the approval of new chemical entities, particularly if that entity is a first-in-class agent that has the potential to be used in large chronic populations off-label. So I don't think too much of a surprise.</p>
          <p>Let me assure you, we are in regular contract with the agency. As we mentioned today, as things currently stand, we plan to submit our response to the Complete Response Letter and very importantly our application for stroke prevention in the second half of 2010. We remain confident with our partner J&amp;J that we will obtain approval for Rivaroxaban in acute indications.</p>
          <p>And as to the second part of your question, Sachin, you will recall in our July 14 last year press release, we did mention that the agency was requesting additional information on our record study sites. We are working with the agency to provide that. So that's the situation with Rivaroxaban and Xarelto.</p>
          <p>Turning now to your question on the YAZ family. Let me take this an opportunity to say that we are facing some challenges currently with our YAZ franchise in the U.S. Overall we were very pleased with the performance of YAZ and the Yasmin family in Q4 were we saw growth of approximately 6% but we are under some pressure in the U.S. The U.S. currently accounts for approximately 40% of global sales. Specifically to your question, we expect that YAZ plus will address a significant proportion of that exposure to a generic, which I will remind you with our agreement with Barr, Barr is not allowed to come to the market under our agreement until July 2011, and we are currently in the process of getting registration for YAZ plus in the U.S. So...</p>
          <p>And your second part of your question was did our 2012...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It was &#x2013; do you see any European generic to YAZ within that timeframe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not assuming any European exposure to generic, and again, I would remind you, again a very different situation exists in Europe where in many countries this is a self-pay and the exposure, even if a generic did come, which again, we are not expecting, would not have the same impact that it would have in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Let's come to your MaterialScience related question. Patrick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Sachin, I think your question was referring to 2012, and expected margin ranges. In term of EBITDA margin I would expect, as you suggest, to return to the range 14 to 16%.</p>
          <p>I think you then had another question which I didn't quite catch relating to margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the final question then was, if you do assume MaterialScience back at pre-crisis high, kind of 1.5 to 1.6, '09 HealthCare and CropScience EBITDA add up to roughly 6 billion. If I add 1.5 to that, I get to 7.6. Your guidance is 8. Just wondering why you're so cautious on HealthCare and CropScience given you're assuming MaterialScience back at pre-crisis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sachin of course, that in our guidance for 2012 MaterialScience improvement and the recovery plans represents an important part and as I said this afternoon during my speech we expect that we will be back on the half-year 10 billion level, which was the pre-crisis level in Bayer MaterialScience, in 2012. So of course, there is a relation between our guidance for 2012 and the recovery in Bayer MaterialScience, yes, of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I guess my question is, if that is the case, which is not assumed in consensus, consensus being, I guess, more positive on both HealthCare and CropScience progression, just wondered if you could provide any color on those two divisions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We also said what at least what is our expectations for HealthCare and for CropScience because perhaps it is too important. I would like to repeat that what I said this morning and this afternoon. Outlook 2012 for Bayer HealthCare sales we expect, that is our best estimation for the time being, a 5% steady currency and portfolio adjusted growth annually through 2012. Of course, here we are going to expect that we are able to successfully launch Xarelto, YAZ, YAZ plus protection and so &#x2013; we really believe that with our very strong pipeline and the launches of new active ingredients over the last couple of &#x2013; during the last couple of quarters, we will be able to gain and to at least the mentioned growth rates.</p>
          <p>On EBITDA, as I said, we believe that we can further improve our Bayer HealthCare margins while &#x2013; and of course, this is one of our targets, while balancing on one hand the need for investment in growth and on the other hand, of course, for profit improvement.</p>
          <p>Going to CropScience, you know that we achieved the 25.1% margin in the record year for the whole industry in 2008, and going forward, we aim to maintaining this high performance level and we consider a margin corridor of 23 to 25% an ambitious, but of course, yet achievable long term goal. We have decided not to give the new margin target for these specific years.</p>
          <p>And going to MaterialScience, in the past we had reported mid cycle EBITDA margins of approximately 14 to 15%. Given the continued economic recovery which we expect that this will happen, we aim at matching again this performance level going forward. Coming from 6% in 2009 this would mean, as I said, substantial or considerable increase to our earnings and so we feel comfortable with our targets and let's see what we can really achieve.</p>
          <p>I hope that this clarifies a little bit our guidance for 2012 or for the coming years and now I would like to ask Arthur to give one comment on our relation on Yasmin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sachin, just to make it clear, and I know you are very familiar with this, but just for the avoidance of doubt, I want to make it clear that under our agreement, Barr will have a license starting July 2011. They can of course decide, if they wish, to go at risk. Just for clarification here, they have the right to go at risk, but under our agreement they will not have a license to launch the product until July 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Faitz. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I guess that's me. Question Christian Faitz, Oppenheim, thank you. Two questions on Agro and MaterialScience. In CropScience, can you talk about the impacts of the phasing you foresee in the first quarter? Why would there be a severe phasing if we still have one month in Q1 to go and this is March the most crucial month I guess, with fairly favorable crop weather at the moment, at least in Europe?</p>
          <p>And then in MaterialScience, how long is your current order book visibility, can you maybe talk about that a little bit? And do you see any negative effects from a potential phase out of government incentives that last year helped some of your key customer industries? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Mr. Faitz, let's start with CropScience. Herr Berschauer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for this question. You know our business very well so you might remind that I make quite often the comment talking about Q1 in 2009, which was a very exceptional one, excellent sales because at that time commodity prices still had been extremely high. Secondly, weather condition was positive and so it was very important that at that time the industry, our customers still had been under the impression of product allocation in the industry, you remember Q1 last year. So it was already our planning that Q1 this year will behind Q1 last year due to very specific situation in Q1 last year.</p>
          <p>Now, talking about Q1 this year, you watched of course the weather situation and it's very obvious that we had a significant delay in planting. We have an extremely strong winter in the Northern Europe also in North America. So it's very clear already that we will have a significant phasing from Q1 into Q2. So January and February have been rather weak. We expect a very good March. We need to see how much we can catch up. But it's already clear from today's perspective we will have a phasing from Q1 into Q2 and most likely also from Q2 into Q3. That's the present situation.</p>
          <p>If we have a detailed look on our sales figures, Southern European countries are on target and we are clearly behind in Northern European countries like Germany, like France, Netherlands, Belgium, Nordic countries and so on. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, now BMS. Patrick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Christian, as you know, the trend that we were seeing when we last talked was smaller order sizes and that certainly continued. So there is still quite lot of volatility in the order flow. The visibility has improved a little bit and what's more important is probably talking to customer about what's going on and how they see the world.</p>
          <p>If I talk about government stimulus packages, then to be honest, the U.S. packages are only really starting to kick-in now, particularly around the construction sector. What we're seeing in the U.S. is that there is a new insulation standard being set in the U.S., particularly for government buildings, which would roughly, if implemented over the next five years, double the quantity of polyurethane  used building insulation and there's a lot of retrofits and spray foam applications that are coming out that.</p>
          <p>Also in the U.S. the Cash for Clunkers scheme has been replaced by a number of other schemes including one that has just been launched, which is encouraging people to buy EnergyStar compliant refrigerators and freezers which is quite a significant government scheme, and we're seeing that boosting sales, particularly on rigid foam polyurethane into the refrigeration industry.</p>
          <p>In Asia the switch in government subsidies moving from the sort of spade-ready projects that we've talked about before, more into domestic consumption subsidy. And in the appliance industry again the government are supporting the purchasing of first time refrigerator buyers and to give you an idea, both Hia who are the number one in the Chinese market and Madia who are the number two, grew during 2009 throughout the year and have told me they expect 15 to 20% further growth in 2010. And in fact Hia are going to start up seven new production lines on refrigerators and this is the reality. The government stimulus is continuing but in a different part of the economy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Vosser. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it is Richard Vosser here from JP Morgan. Couple of product related questions. On Riociguat, just wondering when we're going to find out more about the data in COPD and whether you'll be taking the product forward in Phase III in this indication. And also for the interstitial lung disease, when we will hear &#x2013; when that Phase III will start essentially?</p>
          <p>And on Xarelto, just wondering with your better visibility, whether you could &#x2013; let us say whether we should expect the EINSTEIN-DVT data to be ahead of ROCKET this year? I think we've sort of got a mid-year guidance. Is there any clarity on when we can expect both of those studies would be very useful.</p>
          <p>Then on Betaseron, just it appears from your sales trends that Extavia is having a very limited impact in the U.S. Just wondering what impact you are factoring in from Extavia in 2010?</p>
          <p>And then a question on working capital, please. You've done exceptionally well to improve the working capital which is really substantial cash in 2009. Just wondering how you see your working capital development ongoing through 2010? Whether you can take &#x2013; improve it further? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let's start with your products related questions. Arthur?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Richard, let me start with Riociguat. As you are aware, we mentioned it. We had a <mark type="inaudible" /> signal in our Phase II on interstitial lung disease with Riociguat and we will make a decision as to whether we'll move into Phase III this year. We are also analyzing our data from COPD, I wouldn't say anything more at this stage, but both sets of data are encouraging and we will update you during the year about our decision. But clearly these are two additionally importantly indications and we will obviously look at that on that basis.</p>
          <p>Regarding Xarelto, you are correct that EINSTEIN and ROCKET are basically neck and neck, I wouldn't try and predict which will come first, but they are both on track and I'm very pleased, as you heard from Mr. Wenning, that all of our chronic studies are progressing on track and that we are, as I mentioned earlier in position for the submission of spa and DVT in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>In regard to Betaseron, I think your observation is correct. To date we have seen minimal impact of Extavia in the U.S. We've commented in previous calls that Extavia in Europe, with the exception of Germany, has had a rather modest impact. But I would like to take this opportunity to give you some perspective on our guidance for Betaseron for the year. Clearly, it is too early to judge the full effect of Extavia in the U.S. We may also face a potential launch of new oral MS drugs during the course of the year, again too early to predict their impact. And we do have some tender business that we have to monitor very closely.</p>
          <p>For that reason, as we did last year, we'd like to give you some guidance. But as you'll recall last year that guidance had a tendency to be conservative. But let me give you what I believe is our conservative position at this stage and we'd like to guide towards a decline of Betaseron sales in the mid to high single digit range and clearly we will update you on that as we progress during the year. So I hope, Richard, that's the answer to your three questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. How about now working capital. Klaus K&#xFC;hn?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Richard, regarding working capital performance, last year we announced a program to improve working capital performance, so independent from business developments by roughly 1.6 billion over two years. We achieved in 2009 the target of improving the performance by 1 billion. So for 2010 we still expect an improvement and we had a relatively flat business development, so in 2010 we expect a further improvement in performance but not to the extent which we have seen in 2009 but some of that additional performance will be probably eaten up by in our plan, bigger business growth so that overall we will come let's say part of that will be eaten up, we will have a lower contribution from the working capital overall, but still an improvement in working capital performance. So my best guess is for the full year that we will have a better gross cash flow, but not an improvement rather improvement in net cash flow due to the change in working capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Mr. Bennani. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon gentlemen, Rim Bennani from Exane BNP Paribas in Paris. I do have three questions. The first one: can you comment a little bit on the price list at the start of the year in crop protection given flattish grain prices and has the start of the year &#x2013; the difficult &#x2013; more difficult start of the year changed anything in competitive behavior?</p>
          <p>Could you as well comment on the opportunity in herbicides with additional contracts for your LibertyLink in 2010 and can you help us maybe quantify in that for 2010 and '11? And these are my two questions, actually. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Herr Berschauer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your question. Pricing, we need to start with probably a little bit about the present situation of commodity prices. We are facing presently very low prices in cereals and other and mainly even wheat. Also corn prices are rather low, soybean prices are presently reasonable, but we are expecting a record soybean harvest in Latin America which could result in some price deterioration.</p>
          <p>On the positive side, we have really good prices in coffee, in citrus, in sugar and also in rice, but unfortunately, cereals, corn and soybeans are the more important crop, so with the present situation commodity prices are still under, let's say reasonable level but by far behind the higher record level of 2008 and also beginning of 2009.</p>
          <p>So that's the present situation. Commodity prices are very volatile and so that's the situation. We need to get adapted; so let's wait and see how these commodity prices will develop.</p>
          <p>In terms of pricing it's obvious that we are not in such a favorable position like in 2008 and '09 when these commodity prices have been extremely high so it's presently much more competitive. Difficult to track how the situation will be in half a year but we start the business in 2010 with commodity prices overall more or less reasonable but not really exciting.</p>
          <p>Your second question in terms of LibertyLink these sales, if you want public information of our contracts with our partners, we are ramping up this businesses there's no doubt, but we agreed with our partners that we would not disclose details here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Wenner. Please go ahead and state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon. It's Fabian Wenner from UBS. I want to quickly follow-up on Xarelto. Can you briefly explain why exactly it takes a year to collect record study site information and market surveillance data? I understand some of it might have to do with the long-term data that the FDA might want to have a look at. So if you could just confirm that.</p>
          <p>And then secondly when can we expect the NExUS results this year? Is it still about Q3? And can you remind us when the study was fully enrolled?</p>
          <p>And secondly on thyroid cancer for Nexavar as well, could you give us a rough timeline please, maybe complete enrolment? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Arthur.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fabian, what was the third question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thyroid cancer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all on Xarelto, I can understand the question but you've also got to understand and I think most of you do, this is an iterative process. We are working with the agency. They have every right to continue to ask for additional information, or additional approaches and as you mentioned we do have the challenge that they also know they are going to see chronic data very, very shortly. So again I don't think there's too much of a surprise here.</p>
          <p>As to NExUS, the study is fully enrolled since Q1 '08. It's event driven. Maybe we will see it this year but again, it's event driven.</p>
          <p>And on thyroid cancer, I am not sure have the exact dates. We can get back to you on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Cespedes. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen, thank you for taking my questions. Florent Cespedes, Exane BNP Paribas. A few quick product questions. First of all on Nexavar the Q4 seems to be a bit soft. Is there any reasons behind that? Could you update us all where you see some upside for Nexavar going forward?</p>
          <p>Second question on Xarelto, could you give us the sales strategy of the last year and also is it a fair assumption to say that we should see at least the headlines of the long term studies during the second quarter this year?</p>
          <p>And last question on M&amp;A for the HealthCare is there any areas where you see some opportunities? Animal Health seems to be high on the list due to the high &#x2013; the concentration in this sector but is there any other areas? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Arthur, again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all we had, we thought, a pretty good quarter on Nexavar, 24% year-on-year growth. I think you were talking about quarter-on-quarter and I would not read too much into a quarter. We remain very confident that we'll see robust growth in Nexavar in 2010.</p>
          <p>As to Xarelto we gave guidance of between 20 to 30 million for the full year. I would remind you that it is not our intention to give quarterly updates on Xarelto sales. We will give you an annual number and we'll tell you how well we did that against that number. I mean we'll do that until we have the chronic because again I want to make it very clear, we see the acute indication simply as a training opportunity for the multi-billion chronic. But the answer is we've come in at &#x20AC;24 million, really in the middle of our guidance and we are prepared to give guidance for the full year 2010 and that is between 50 to &#x20AC;70 million and that is only of course, outside of the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the timing of -- at least the headlines of the long-term trials, could it be possible during the Q2 or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean again, as we said we're going to submit the chronic data this year so you can assume that you'll get exposure to that at the appropriate medical conference later on this year.</p>
          <p>And as far as M&amp;A, again, I think for the benefit of time all I would say is we will continue, as we always do to look at appropriate opportunities. We are not in a need to do M&amp;A to drive our business, but if we find the appropriate opportunity we will certainly look at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Gilbert. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon. Thomas Gilbert, UBS in Zurich. Three questions, one financial and one CropScience, and one MaterialScience.</p>
          <p>First a financial question, the guidance for the non-operating result, around about 900 million, can I just try to figure out the components? You've got pension costs of 436 million and they are rising constantly over the last seven, eight years. You make losses in your affiliates and you've got hedging losses, that means a negative result well in excess of 0.5 billion, implies a very low interest cost on the debt. Is there anything in the pensions or the affiliates or the hedging losses that is much more positive in 2009 than what I'm assuming? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is CropScience in Latin America. Could you remind us or quantify what as a percentage of your Brazilian sales, how much of that is via barter or via using a vendor lending model?</p>
          <p>And also in terms of pricing in Latin America, Syngenta had double digit price declines in Latin America in the second half as well that of course they price in dollars and the real was weak against the dollar and the real was even weaker against the euro. So I am just wondering whether the pricing is it merely a function of passing through the currency in your dollar pricing?</p>
          <p>And then finally on MaterialScience, the guidance for both sales and EBITDA sequentially is a bit underwhelming given that normally the business is seasonally very strong. Is that mainly two components: very weak construction and winter effect and rising raw materials? Do I understand correctly, is that why you don't &#x2013; will not expect a pronounced seasonal effect Q1 versus Q4? Thank you for taking these three questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let's start with the question related the operating &#x2013; non-operating results. Klaus K&#xFC;hn?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Herr Gilbert, our guidance for non-operating results overall is roughly minus &#x20AC;900 million, we just give you somewhat better than 2009 driven by couple of factors. The first is we will have reduced, let's say, interest burden, roughly now we think about 450 to 500. But also the interest portion on our pension as this will be lower because at the end of last year we had a lower interest rate which determines basically the expense for next year on the interest portion so that will be also short by roughly more than 50 million and we do not expect a significant negative effect from currency hedging or for currency effects in the financial result next year so these are the components.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. CropScience, Latin America, pricing...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Pricing are basically of course in the same game as our major competitors: Syngenta and BASF and we are facing the same problem as they in terms of the ratio of Brazilian real versus U.S. dollar. As you know, pricing is done in U.S. dollars.</p>
          <p>For your question in terms of barter, we have presently or last year sales in Brazil including BioScience and EnvironmentalScience of exactly &#x20AC;724 million. In barter the business represents around about 10% of this business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And MaterialScience, Patrick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thomas, I think your analysis is spot on. We have a situation where sales will increase in quarter one. We will see some pricing effects which will be in the positive direction on TDI and on polycarbonates. I think that is the strong up story. I think there's going to be an offset with raw materials that's going to be incredibly unpredictable. So that's where we came at it from the point of view of giving level guidance in terms of EBITDA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Mr. Watteville. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. This is Jean De Watteville from Nomura. I have three questions, two on corporate action and one on MaterialScience.</p>
          <p>First one on corporate action, can you give a bit of color about the pricing environment outside of Latin America? Can you confirm whether you see pricing pressure, notably in Europe and North America, and if you could also give a bit of colors by product category. That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is on margins in crop protection &#x2013; CropScience, sorry. I understand you don't give a quantified guidance for this year and obviously, we understand that lower prices should be negative for profitability. Can you talk through the positives, particularly lower raw material prices and the lag effect of the productivity programs you've implemented on that division?</p>
          <p>And the third question is on MaterialScience, can you provide an update on where you are on those capacity expansion programs that you've been running in Asia last year? What level of operating rates have you reached and should we expect any material volume impact from these programs in 2010? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Let's start with CropScience and pricing outside Latin America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pricing outside of Latin America, Europe, the last period we've been able to increase prices nicely in Europe. This year, it's a little bit more of a challenging market situation, but we still will be able to increase prices in Europe. In North America, it's little bit depending on the product particularly more difficult in herbicides, in fungicides and in insecticides more on the positive side.</p>
          <p>And your last question in term of positives in terms of our business for 2010, raw material our numbers so far, show a relief of whatever 20 to 30 million; so it will not be dramatic in 2010 in terms of raw material costs.</p>
          <p>On the positive side, as you have seen, our performance of new products has been very, very good last year, and we are expecting also good performance of our new products in 2010, since this new product has significantly higher margin compared to our old portfolio, so that's, I think, clearly on positive side.</p>
          <p>And of course we have still some savings based on our restructuring programs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>BMS: CapEx, Asia, higher capacity, volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let's just rewind a tiny bit. We had a full year in 2009 on NDI and NDI unit started early in the year and has pretty much run since then at full rate. That's 350,000 tons and the plant is effectively sold out. TDI is the plant under construction but will be mechanically completed at the end of this year and will start up at the beginning of 2011 and that's 250,000 tons.</p>
          <p>The key difference is on polycarbonate where the entire world market has shifted somewhat. Pre-crisis Asia represented 55% of the world market for polycarbonate. It is now about 65%. So our very strong position there is extremely important with our plants in Map Ta Phut in Thailand and our plants in Caojing and we have now successfully got both 100,000 ton lines running in China and we expect them to be fully utilized at the current demand rates which are extremely high.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you are fully utilized already now in Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Nudell. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Bruce Nudell from UBS in the States. On Xarelto, just listening between the lines, it sounds us though the substantive issue remaining with regard to the orthopedic application is really the reticence of the FDA to unleash a broadly applicable drug for a narrow indication. Am I garnering the sentiment in that regard correctly?</p>
          <p>And to follow-up on that theme, is there any risk whatsoever that the clinical trial issues that impacted the orthopedic application are also extent in the chronic application such as AF or treatment of VTE?</p>
          <p>And thirdly relative to the rates of orthopedic surgery that you have in the countries in which Xarelto is currently released, how would you qualitatively describe the penetration? Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Arthur, Xarelto again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bruce, I think you summarized it perfectly. And I think I will move on to the clinical trial discussion and make it very clear to you that we obviously understand that the FDA has &#x2013; not just with us, but with every single filing, increased their scrutiny oversight, so rest assured that with our chronic studies we are going back and making sure that we have no issues and we're confident that we do not have issues.</p>
          <p>In regard to orthopedic surgery, here what was very important and I guess very consistent was our concern about any use off-label. We are sticking very specifically to the indication that's approved: knee and hip, and not exploring any other surgical indications for the agent. And as you heard previously, we estimated that market at about 300 million, and as we finish this year at 24 million and that's obviously got a higher exit rate, I think we're penetrating, last year, 2009, and we're looking at 50 to &#x20AC;70 million this year, I think we are actually penetrating that available market reasonably well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next quarter is from Mr. Leuchten. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Michael Leuchten from Barclays Capital. Arthur if I just could follow-up on the Xarelto question once more. When you guided in the middle of 2009 that you were going to resubmit the filing by the end of 2009 that seemed to imply that you were going to use the ATLAS and EINSTEIN extension data for that filing. Now you've seen the data and you are pushing out the resubmission even further. Was that just a coincidence in terms of the trial read outs for ATLAS and EINSTEIN and you were never going to read that or is it just not enough for the FDA?</p>
          <p>And a question on Nexavar: it looks like the U.S. growth is kind of flat sequentially as is Japan. Can you just split out where the growth is coming from rest of the world, which countries you are launching into 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you can understand, I think we've really tried to be as transparent as possible. We are in discussions with the agency and I don't really want to get involved in more of a debate, but I think again, it was all captured by the fact, I don't think there was too much surprise in terms of what's been happening with Xarelto.</p>
          <p>On the Nexavar, let me give you the breakdown of Nexavar by geography in the fourth quarter. We have done that historically and I think it's helpful. Our total sales in the quarter were 159 million, 38 million was from the U.S. with a growth rate of plus 9%; Europe, 68 million with a growth rate of plus 20%; Asia Pacific, 37 million and here we have Japan at 20 million growing 65%, China at 10 growing 43% and as I mentioned, the total was 159 at 24%. So I think that gives you a sense of where the growth is. One of the things we will look at this year is how can we improve the growth rate in the U.S., but outside of the U.S. there still seems to be excellent momentum in Nexavar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Walton. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. It's Jo Walton from Credit Suisse. I have got some questions on the pharma division. Kogenate has now shown four quarters of about 3% growth on an underlying basis. Middle of last year, you thought that that would return to high single digits and it's obviously an important franchise for you. Can you update us on that? In the Annual Report it does say that there was strong growth in Latin America in the fourth quarter and that suggests that there was presumably a decline elsewhere, so I'm looking for some guidance going forward?</p>
          <p>Also more broadly on the pharmaceutical margins, you've had a very strong improvement in the profitability of that business with the acquisition of Schering. Are the benefits of that now coming to an end or are we going &#x2013; or can we see some more improvements in operating margin? I'm concerned that maybe this year we see some improvement, but next year you'll be ramping up your costs to start the promotion of Xarelto. So what sort of operating margins can we get to?</p>
          <p>And then on special items, you say that you're not going to have any more restructuring, but in general, should we just assume that there are no special items in the current year? If so I am finding it difficult to get from a core EBIT of plus 10% to core net income of plus 10% because I can only see a sort of stable level of deductions and obviously I have to have a growing level of deductions, if the earnings are not going grow faster than EBIT or EBITDA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let's start again with HealthCare and Kogenate and pharma margins, Arthur.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jo, first of all I think we should take some comfort from the performance of the total franchise Kogenate plus Helixate in the fourth quarter, which was a 9% growth and our guidance for 2010 is that we'll be back to a mid single-digit percentage range.</p>
          <p>In respect to your comment on the outlook for margin, I think it's really important here that we put this in perspective. Firstly in our pharma business we are truly fortune to have eight significant late stage assets that will be launched between 2011 and 2014, so I believe it's only prudent that we invest in innovation at BSP, so what you should expect from our pharma business is that we will continue to grow in line with the market and that the bottom line will grow broadly in line with the top line, but that will give us the resources to invest in this innovation. I am confident we will accelerate both top and bottom line growth from 2012 onwards.</p>
          <p>Special items?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Special items, you are right. We have just explained that we finished at the end of 2009 our restructuring programs. Restructuring means the integration of Schering was successfully done, finished. We achieved over 800 million on synergies. We finished the river program on BMS and we finished the so called new program and you are very familiar with the details in Bayer CropScience and of course it's day-to-day business as I mentioned to further improve our cost structures, to improve our efficiency and I am pretty sure you recall that last year we announced HealthCare in health and pharma the Horizon program which is related to a continuous improvement in cost structure. This program is going on over the last couple of years. And &#x2013; but we cannot exclude that we would not get special items in the coming years due to legal costs and due to impairments, both issues are not part of our cost guidance not having special items next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But coming and maybe heading to that it is clear that if the improvements underlying EBITDA and have no special items that it clearly will have a stronger growth and reward the EPS in the next year but in our core EPS, we exclude again the special items and therefore this brings again let's say the improvement in underlying EBITDA and the improvements in core EPS in line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Weckroth. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, this is Tero Weckroth from Kepler in Z&#xFC;rich. Two questions please.</p>
          <p>Firstly on the animal health side, it was hinted in the release that there might be interest for a M&amp;A activity there. The question is, do you want to keep full control of that business wherever that might end up? I don't think there's in HealthCare business much of a history of joint ventures but there are other assets of approximately the same size in Europe facing the same dilemma, so could you consider a joint venture here?</p>
          <p>Then secondly on the MaterialScience business, it would be extremely helpful for forecasting if you give, could give us some kind of guidance absolute or relative on the raw material costs in 2009. I think I have the numbers of the half year but how that developed during the second half would be very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, first Animal Health. You know that what happened in the market in 2009 we saw two very important consolidation activities and we also mentioned last year that it was our intention to be very active in the Animal Health market and we participated in one time &#x2013; let's say in one transaction. So what we are going to do now is we are considering all our options and keeping in mind the consolidation process. How we can keep and this is the main question, how we can keep our Animal Health business on a sustainable rate, on our actual profit levels and of course it is always our intention to keep full control.</p>
          <p>BMS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sorry, on raw materials the bridge in 2009 for a full year would show a positive effect of about 850 million on raw materials and energy. That was offset by a price drop of 1.2 billion and a volume drop of nearly 0.5 billion. The remaining gap in the bridge is made up with a quarter billion of cost savings. Just to give you a feel for the quarter development, quarter three to quarter four the variance on raw materials was negative again about minus 25 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perhaps a follow-up on here. I remember a year ago, it was very clearly stated that Bayer will focus on cash flow in 2009. Would you feel it is justified to say that perhaps the inventory levels at the end of 2009 in MaterialScience were lower than they were at the end of 2008 and obviously calculating from that the impact of or timing of the impact of again higher raw material prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the working capital assumption you stated is correct. During the year we increased the gross cash flow to about 125 million versus quarter four '08. Net cash flow increased by 40% to just over 300. In the full year the net cash flow of 850 was 9% above the prior year despite the 700 million drop in EBITDA and the delta working capital contribution was positive 180 in the fourth quarter and 530 million for the full year. I think that bridges all directions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, extremely helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Stott. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Andrew Stott, Merrill Lynch. Two quick questions, one for Dr. Berschauer, on your R&amp;D costs for CropScience, can you just provide some guidance please for this year and maybe the medium-term?</p>
          <p>Secondly, could you remind me of the split in your overall sales in crop protection between pre-emergent and post-emergent? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Herr Berschauer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, R&amp;D costs, just a second. Last year in 2009 we had R&amp;D costs of &#x20AC;653 million in crop protection out of this, around about 500 million, in ES, a little bit below 30 and in BioScience a little bit above 120. And our budget for this year what we are aiming is R&amp;D costs in the range of 700 million with the main target increasing our spending in Bioscience.</p>
          <p>Pre-emergent, post-emergent it's &#x2013; I don't have the exact number in my mind. It's probably a split, half-half, I think that's the rough number, ja.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Wendorff. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Daniel Wendorff from Commerzbank. And thanks for taking my questions. I have three actually, one for the Bayer Schering Pharma business, I was just wondering whether you could give me a hand as to the level of sales in Germany you generated and how you see in German healthcare measures coming in going forward and whether this would have any impact on your business?</p>
          <p>Second question regarding the MaterialScience division again, I was just wondering how the capacity utilization in regions outside of Asia would look like and how many sites are still mothballed, if at all?</p>
          <p>And lastly on the CropScience business you mentioned that the planting season in the northern hemisphere is delayed into Q2, I was just wondering how this would change the planting pattern also in H2 if at all? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. BSP and the level of sales in Germany, Arthur?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Germany you can assume it's approximately 8% to 10% of global sales. Clearly we are monitoring the healthcare program here in Germany, but I think this is not so dissimilar to the challenge that we faced in terms of what's happening in the U.S. We'll know what the final recommendations are when they're final.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We need more perhaps one comment about Germany and the political discussion, as you know. What we need is more competition. We need a more competitive market and we are not afraid about competition. Now BMS, capacity utilization and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Let me just start Daniel on the polycarbonate side. We only have mothballed plants on polycarbonates at the moment and you will remember last time, we talked about over 200,000 tons mothballed. Now we're down to about 90,000 tons of mothballing on polycarbonate. That's one line in the U.S., and that's one line in Europe, both relatively small lines. At that level of mothballing, our global utilization is close to 90% or above so things are fairly tight at the moment. So I think the very sharp growth in China has really been much higher than we expected.</p>
          <p>On TDI our total global assets are running fully and are almost above 90% so in the case of TDI asset that's very high because TDI assets tend to be slightly more unreliable than any others.</p>
          <p>On NVI our capacity level was not so high. You'll remember we brought on a large 350,000 ton unit in China which is running fully because of the Asian demand. We've just brought on another 160,000 tons that was mothballed last year in Germany because demand has picked up and we need to do some maintenance on two other units in Europe. But globally NVI is somewhere between 80, 85% occupied for our assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. CropScience, Herr Berschauer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The effect of the very cold winter on planting in Northern Europe, the effect will be very, very limited because in Europe we are planting mainly winter cereals; it's already done in the autumn. The same is true for rapeseed so the impact on the Northern European planting will be very, very limited.</p>
          <p>In terms of planting behavior, it really depends much more on commodity prices. Farmers wait until the very last moment to finalize the decision, for example, in U.S. whether they are going to plant soybean or corn is one example, but this depends really on commodity price not so much on the long winter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Fl&#xFC;ckiger. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon, gentlemen. Martin Fl&#xFC;ckiger from Helvea Three questions please.</p>
          <p>One on CropScience. First, you've talked about the business environment currently being more difficult than expected. If I remember correctly, about three months ago at the Q3 conference call you were talking about the top line growth guidance in crop protection saying that you were looking at 2 to 3% with a 50-50 split in terms of volumes and pricing. I was just wondering whether we could come back to this statement and compare how you see things today, whether pricing is still around 1 to 1.5% for 2010?</p>
          <p>And also with respect to the different evolutions in EBITDA margins within crop protection and Environmental Science and BioScience, if you could talk a little bit there which way you see &#x2013; where you see the biggest dynamics in 2010 for the two business units?</p>
          <p>And talking about EBITDA margins here in CropScience; could you talk also based on your current expectations, say given current ForEx rates, what your current expectations are with respect to the currency impact on EBITDA in CropScience.</p>
          <p>Then second questions is on MaterialScience, sequentially underlying EBITDA was down about 15% in Q4 due to higher operating costs, according to your press release this morning; could you elaborate a little bit on this and give us a picture of what the sequential impact here was?</p>
          <p>Also with respect to raw material prices, I think you mentioned the 25 million, but can you give us or could you put a percentage number on top of that, please?</p>
          <p>And then third question is on CapEx and working capital, both in CropScience and MaterialScience. You've given CapEx guidance for the entire group, if I remember correctly, &#x20AC;1.4 billion for PP&amp;E. Could you provide us with a split for the various segments here and particularly BCS and BMS in 2010?</p>
          <p>And then with regards to working capital, could you give us an indication where working capital stands in percent of sales at the end of 2009 for both CropScience and MaterialScience? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, a couple of questions. Let's start with CropScience. Herr Berschauer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A lot of questions. In terms of CropScience I'll try to be short. First of all EBITDA margins, the BioScience business presently is dilutive and will continue to be dilutive because we have significant investments in R&amp;D. ES due to the following situation we are much more profitable in the professional business and profitability in consumer is lower. Overall, ES profitability is on the level of crop protection. Crop protection is in the range of, of course, Bayer CropScience.</p>
          <p>Currency impact, based on our planning, more or less flat. Of course it depends on the actual development U.S. dollar, Brazilian real and other important currencies.</p>
          <p>CapEx in 2009, our CapEx has been on a level of 346 million, 300 of tangible, 46 intangible and our planning for 2010 is in the range of round about 320, could be a little bit lower.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps I can add some numbers on CapEx. We expect this year as I said 1,440 million and only CapEx &#x2013; only PP&amp;E of costs, 460 in HealthCare, as Mr. Berschauer mentioned between 320 to 330 in Bayer CropScience perhaps a little bit less and in Bayer MaterialScience around 500 and 160 in our service companies, which adding up the numbers we are coming to the 1,440.</p>
          <p>In regards to BMS and the sequence Q4, Q3...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Q3 Q4 sequentially Martin, yeah, you are right. Earnings down 15% due to higher operating cost. The actual bridge looks like about minus 15 million on the volume plus 50 on price. Minus the 25 you referred to on raw materials and then an increase in year end maintenance and some of the unrolling of contingency measures. For example, we went on shot time working in Germany but that actually ended in October. So we were back to full labor rates during November and December for the year. So there were quite a few effects, which were locked into contractual positions with the short-time working and we were only able to keep those going not until full end year but to October. So that was a bit of the reason for the kick up in December.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now working capital, Klaus K&#xFC;hn?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes for the change in let's say trade working capital, we consider the trade working capital for the sub groups so roughly in HealthCare we had a positive cash flow contribution of roughly 300 million, in CropScience a negative cash contribution the same magnitude roughly minus 300 million and roughly 550 million positive cash flow contribution from BMS and then the remainder from reconciliation also positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, sorry; that was 2009 if I understood you correctly, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course I was wondering also for modeling purposes going forward what we should assume in terms of working capital as a percentage of sales for at the end of 2009 and what the outlook is for BCS and BMS here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, I think we don't guide on working capital as a percentage of sales. We don't think that is the right interpolation to that, but secondly we've said overall that the performance &#x2013; the performance will further improve for the top group in 2010, but that will be probably eaten up again also by the growing business that was basically more than the guidance which we will give for the group. We haven't given guidance anyhow beyond that, specifically. It's very difficult to do that also by subgroup. Sorry, we're not going to provide these numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cleo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Chouhan. Please state your, company name followed by our question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Naresh Chouhan from ICAP. Just a single question from me on the guidance, if you take your HealthCare guidance and your CropScience guidance and back out what level of EBITDA we need from BMS to get to a 10% core EPS growth, we get to a EBITDA level of around &#x20AC;500 million. You did &#x20AC;450 million in just the second half of 2009 and you are expecting &#x20AC;200 million in the first quarter 2010. Can you give us some insight as to why you're so conservative on the outlook for MaterialScience and your guidance in general? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We &#x2013; I believe we were very transparent with our guidance for 2010 and the following years and perhaps to avoid any kind of misunderstanding, we are not committing ourselves to a range &#x2013; to an average cycle margin at BMS in 2012. What we are going to say is that we expect that in 2012, we will be back with around 10 billion turnover back on pre-crisis levels. But we are &#x2013; as I said we are not committing ourselves today to let's say this is famous mid-cycle guidance of 14 to 15%. We believe our guidance is quite clear and has the right balance of chances and opportunities of our business. So this is all that we can answer for today to our short and mid term guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Arnold. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, guys. Blake Arnold from Robert Baird. Thanks for taking my questions. Real quickly on Nexavar, could you maybe talk to where you stand currently in the reimbursement...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Naresh...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Blake.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Blake, you have to speak up a little bit. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you guys maybe talk to where you stand currently in the reimbursement process in China? And then also we recently saw a price increase for Nexavar in the U.S., how does this compare to your pricing strategy in other geographies? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You're talking about Nexavar reimbursement in China. This is a dialog with the Chinese authorities. I wouldn't expect it to be concluded in the short term. We remain confident that over time that we will receive Nexavar reimbursement in China but no targeting of a specific date.</p>
          <p>As to the U.S., we did take a 7.5% price increase in January. That really reflects again our economic assessment of the value that Nexavar is offering in both kidney cancer and liver cancer and a similar situation happens where we are able to take free-price for example in Germany and probably there are very few other examples of markets in the world that we are able to actually take price increases for Nexavar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. K&#xF6;hler. Please state your name, your company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes hello, it's Ronald K&#xF6;hler from MainFirst. I have three questions actually.</p>
          <p>The first one is on currency: can you describe how your hedging is and if you have any expectations based on today's currencies what will be the impact on sales and underlying EBITDA the first question?</p>
          <p>The second question is on consumer health: obviously if you look to the full year 2009 growth rate, we saw North America relatively weak versus Europe. Is that a destocking theme which was more expressed North America or really the behavior or the competition is stronger in the U.S. and can you little bit elaborate if there is rebound possible especially in the North American market on the consumer health side?</p>
          <p>Last question on Bayer CropScience: you stated actually that you saw price pressure in herbicide and fungicide. I am not surprised by herbicide. I am a little bit looking to the fungicide area and wondering where this price pressure is coming from. Obviously BASF has lost one patent protection but I am not sure if that was an impact. Can you a little bit elaborate on the pricing development in the fungicide North American market you pointed out and then what you would expect here going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's start with the currency impact. Herr K&#xFC;hn?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Mr. K&#xF6;hler, currencies, first of all hedging policy has not changed. We basically hedge on forward basis roughly half of our anticipated net cash inflows for currency on a yearly horizon. This has not changed and &#x2013; but this doesn't currently play a major role. If you look at this year's exchange it maybe to previous year's exchange for the real and the dollar some currencies have quite nicely appreciate from the previous year, let's say, crisis levels.</p>
          <p>Overall the sensitivity has not changed that much. You could say that a 1% change in the overall basket of our currencies would have an impact of roughly 200 million in sales and roughly 50 million on EBITDA. So and basically dollar &#x2013; and then if you compare this &#x2013; combine these both, they would roughly represent a little bit more than half of these numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, before we are coming to consumer health, crop and herbicides, Herr Berschauer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The question was I think fungicides, so last year we faced some pressure in fungicide pricing. This was mainly true for corn fungicides because last year the market expectation &#x2013; expected a significant demand for corn and fungicides at the end of the day weather condition was not really supportive so there are still some stocks in terms of corn fungicides. On the positive side in our portfolio we have an excellent portfolio in terms of innovative product. Product specifically mentioning here <mark type="inaudible" /> so our fungicides portfolio is really strong and very innovative. This is really positive for our pricing in the fungicide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And consumer health destock in U.S., Arthur?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ronald, I think you &#x2013; we had talked about that during the year. Clearly we saw the most severe destocking in the first half of the year in the U.S. Actually consumption since the first quarter has actually been tracing pretty positively in the U.S. The fourth quarter is a little difficult to judge because of some seasonality of sell-ins in Q4 last year in anticipation of first quarter price increases in the U.S. And I would &#x2013; if I was trying to say to you my outlook, in the aggregate, we were obviously indicated that consumer care will grow above market in 2010 and I expect the U.S. to be a pretty solid performer there. In fact, I think you will see a very nice recovery in our U.S. business and you will see that as early as the first quarter.</p>
          <p>But maybe just finishing because I would like to just mention, that we are very confident in our full year outlook for 5%, currency adjusted growth in HealthCare, but we do expect some softness in the first quarter in our pharma business as we discussed related to YAZ in the U.S., but you will see again, as I mentioned, a very solid performance in our consumer businesses and again I think you will see a good performance in the U.S. in particular, but in summary, our outlook for HealthCare is one that we feel is very achievable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cleo, are there any questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me Mr. Rosar, this is the last question. Please continue with any other points you wish to raise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, dear friends, also on behalf of my colleagues I'd like to thank you for being with us on the call. We all thank you for the interest you have demonstrated on a meanwhile late Friday afternoon in Bayer and its prospects. We are now saying goodbye and hope to be meeting you soon again, especially during our upcoming financial investor conference here in Leverkusen on the 16 and 17 of March. Auf Wiedersehen</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the full year and fourth quarter 2009 results investor conference call of Bayer AG. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>