<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1299460" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>810</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Alexander Rosar, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Marijn Dekkers, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Richard Vosser</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">J&#xF6;rg Reinhardt</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Sachin Jain</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Werner Baumann</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Patrick W. Thomas</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Jeremy Redenius</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep">Sandra E. Peterson</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Andrew Baum</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Jo Walton</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Florent Cespedes</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Thomas Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Andreas Heine</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Ronald K&#xF6;hler</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Martin Fl&#xFC;ckiger</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Michael Leuchten</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to Bayer's Investor and Analyst Conference Call on the Full Year and Fourth Quarter 2010 Results. Throughout today's recorded presentation, all participants will be in a listen-only mode. The presentation will be followed by a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Mr. Alexander Rosar, Head of Investor Relations of Bayer AG. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Clare. Ladies and gentlemen, dear friends, it's a great pleasure for me to welcome you also on behalf of my colleagues to our conference call.</p>
          <p>With me on the call are Marijn Dekkers, our CEO, and Werner Baumann, our CFO. And from our sub-groups, we have J&#xF6;rg Reinhardt for HealthCare. CropScience is represented by Sandy Peterson, and MaterialScience by Patrick Thomas.</p>
          <p>You have received a lot of information this morning including the annual report, our Investor Relations &#x2013; and the conference slides. Marijn Dekkers will start off our conference call with a brief summary of the main developments in the quarter and during 2010. Please understand that we have to close our call at 4:30 latest.</p>
          <p>Before handing over to Marijn, I'd like to draw your attention also to the Safe Harbor statement. Thank you. Marijn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alexander. Ladies and gentlemen, I would like to summarize 2010 as the year in which Bayer was operationally on track. The global economy recovered surprisingly quickly from the deep recession in 2010. And in this environment, we raised group sales to an all-time high of &#x20AC;35.1 billion. EBITDA before special items came in at &#x20AC;7.1 billion and core earnings per share were up 15.1%.</p>
          <p>We essentially, as a result of that, achieved the targets we communicated for 2010. We also reduced net financial debt by &#x20AC;1.8 billion to now &#x20AC;7.9 billion by further increasing our operating cash flow. With regard to Q4 in particular, we are pleased to report that operationally the business improved with positive momentum into 2011.</p>
          <p>So overall, 2010 was a successful year for Bayer. However, earnings in 2010 were partly supported by unexpected developments. For example, the MaterialScience sub-group returned to the pre-crisis level much more quickly than anticipated. And currency effects were also clearly in our favor.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, the performance of HealthCare and CropSciences did not meet our expectations. In addition, reported earnings were significantly reduced by high special charges. Reported earnings per share declined by 8% versus the prior year. I'm convinced the Bayer has good growth prospects in all of its businesses, and our key priority going forward is to strengthen our innovation capability and to successfully commercialize our innovation, especially Xarelto.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we invested a record &#x20AC;3.1 billion in R&amp;D, up 11% over the previous year. In addition, we will further expand our business in the emerging markets this year where we're already enjoying above average growth. The restructuring measures we announced in November are creating the financial headroom we need to systematically invest in these opportunities and to further leverage our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Over the next three years, we are planning to invest a total of approximately &#x20AC;15 billion in R&amp;D and capital expenditures to further fuel &#x2013; and fuel our growth. We are also confident for 2011. Our outlook projects 10% core EPS growth.</p>
          <p>So, let's now take a brief look at the Q4 figures. In my comments, I will concentrate on the sales data adjusted for portfolio and currency effects. Group sales in the quarter grew by 8%, driven by higher volumes. Higher selling prices contributed 2% to the increase. Adjusted EBITDA rose by 12% and core earnings per share by 6% to &#x20AC;0.59.</p>
          <p>Net cash flow advanced by 10%. Reported fourth quarter earnings were diminished by substantial special charges. &#x20AC;825 million were mainly due to impairments and asset write-downs, &#x20AC;67 million were incurred for litigations in the United States and &#x20AC;62 million for restructuring in HealthCare. As a result, reported group EBIT dropped by 86% to &#x20AC;51 million. After a non-operating result of &#x20AC;-237 million, we recorded a pre-tax loss of &#x20AC;186 million for the quarter, a net loss of &#x20AC;145 million and earnings per share of &#x20AC;-0.18.</p>
          <p>From a regional perspective, the strongest growth was achieved in the emerging economies. In Western Europe, business gained 4% and in the United States, business declined by 1%. The emerging markets however accounted for now 38% of group sales. In these markets, we extended our sales by 19% with the strongest growth achieved in the emerging Asian markets and Latin America. These figures clearly demonstrate that we are well positioned in the emerging markets and that our significant investments there are paying off.</p>
          <p>Gross cash flow of the Bayer Group advanced in the fourth quarter by 37% to &#x20AC;1.4 billion in light of the improved operating performance. Net cash flow moved ahead by 10% to &#x20AC;1.9 billion and free operating cash flow by 11% to &#x20AC;1.4 billion. As a result of this strong performance, we were able to reduce net financial debt in the quarter by &#x20AC;1.2 billion, compared to the previous quarter, to now &#x20AC;7.9 billion at year end.</p>
          <p>Let's now move on to the performance of our sub-groups. The challenges that impacted the performance of HealthCare during the first nine months were also felt in the final fourth quarter. At Pharma, sales were impacted by the negative effect of healthcare reform, and the earlier than anticipated genericization of YAZ in the US. Business in the US declined by 15%. Ex-US, we registered the sales increase of 6% driven by the strong performance in the emerging market.</p>
          <p>Overall, Pharma sales advanced by 2%. Adjusted EBITDA grew by 5%, including a gain from the settlement of the patent dispute with Teva concerning YAZ. Consumer Health sales were up 1% compared with the prior year quarter. The drop in sales of blood glucose monitoring systems in the United States caused by the difficult market situation was offset by growth in the over-the-counter and Animal Health businesses.</p>
          <p>The decline of 16% in adjusted EBITDA of Consumer Health was mainly due to higher investments in marketing and sales. So ladies and gentlemen, we are proud of our achievements in the development of key Pharma pipeline projects. We successfully completed important pivotal studies for Xarelto, including ROCKET-AF and EINSTEIN-DVT. In the meantime, Xarelto has been filed for stroke prevention in patients with atrial fibrillation in the US and Europe, and for treatment of deep vein thrombosis in Europe.</p>
          <p>Towards the end of the year, we reported positive Phase III data from the VEGF Trap-Eye program in wet AMD and CRVO. We gained approvals for Beyaz, Natazia and Safyral &#x2013; Safyral, and a new oral dispersible formulation of Levitra. Significant cancellations include Sagopilone, Bonefos, and L19-SIP. We expect important news flow from our Pharma pipeline also in 2011. This includes the expected completion of major Xarelto studies, ATLAS and EINSTEIN-PE, this summer, additional data from the VEGF Trap-Eye program and from Nexavar studies.</p>
          <p>The Magellan study in which we are studying Xarelto for the prevention of VTE in medically ill patients has been completed, and we're planning to present the data at the Annual Meeting of American College of Cardiology on April 5.</p>
          <p>CropSciences saw a strong finish to the year with sales up 10% on the quarter. The increase was driven by higher volumes. Selling prices added one percentage point. At Crop Protection, Q4 sales improved by 8%; supported by the positive market momentum, compared to Q4 last year, our business expanded strongly in Latin America, particularly in Brazil. Sales improved by 22% and 26% respectively.</p>
          <p>In Asia Pacific, we grew sales by 14%. In North America, we spent 3% due to new product introductions. The sales decline of 10% in Europe resulted mainly from weaker herbicide and fungicide sales in France. The top line of the Environmental Science, BioScience segment grew 20% in the quarter, mainly driven by the strong performance of our BioSciences business. Adjusted EBITDA of CropSciences advanced to &#x20AC;270 million, including a one-time income of &#x20AC;44 million from the execution of a license agreement and the divestments of some older active ingredients.</p>
          <p>The improvement in the business performance of our MaterialScience sub-group continued in the quarter. Sales at nearly &#x20AC;2.6 billion were up 22% year-on-year and only slightly below the third quarter level despite the seasonal business slowdown in Q4. The expansion of business over last year was due to a considerable increase in demand in our key customer industry. This enabled us to significantly raise volumes and selling prices.</p>
          <p>We registered the largest absolute volume gains in Europe and Asia Pacific. The improved business situation was also reflected in earnings. EBITDA before special items of MaterialScience rose markedly in the fourth quarter of 2010 to &#x20AC;297 million, despite the negative impact of &#x20AC;160 million from higher raw materials and energy price.</p>
          <p>So, so much for the fourth quarter. Now let me comment briefly on our performance against our targets for the full year 2010. Group sales rose by 8% to a record &#x20AC;35.0 billion, exceeding our target of a 5% increase. EBITDA before special items came in at &#x20AC;7.1 billion, and was therefore in line with our target, which was to exceed &#x20AC;7 billion.</p>
          <p>Core earnings per share were up 15.1% compared to the target of an increase of more than 15%. We thus achieved our sales and earnings targets for the group. Net financial debt was reduced by &#x20AC;1.8 billion to &#x20AC;7.9 billion. These achievements were essentially attributable to the strong recovery in the MaterialScience business in 2010 and also to positive currency effects.</p>
          <p>So, ladies and gentlemen, we are proposing that the Annual General Shareholders Meeting declares a dividend of &#x20AC;1.50 per share. We believe that this proposal reflects the improved operating performance of the Bayer Group last year, and on this course, that we are optimistic for the future.</p>
          <p>Now let me discuss 2010 for the three sub-groups. For HealthCare, 2010 was more difficult than expected. Pharma sales came in below our expectation. Over-the-counter and Animal Health most likely exceeded market growth and achieved their sales targets.</p>
          <p>Adjusted EBITDA of HealthCare was in line with our last earnings target update, but short of the guidance we gave at the beginning of the year. CropSciences clearly missed its targets in fiscal 2010. Sales and earnings came in below 2009, mainly due to very difficult market conditions in the first six months.</p>
          <p>The second half of the year developed more favorably with encouraging positive momentum into 2011. And for MaterialScience, it was a stellar year. The recovery was more pronounced and much faster than we had anticipated, and we are very pleased that MaterialScience clearly exceeded even our upgraded target. So what are now our concrete plans for 2011?</p>
          <p>We expect the global economic recovery to continue in 2011. However the pace of expansion is likely to be slower than in 2010. The major emerging economies, especially China, appear set to continue driving global economic growth. However, global economic and political risks will most likely remain high during 2011.</p>
          <p>We have based our budgets on a US dollar exchange rate of $1.40 to the euro, and an average crude oil price of US$80 per barrel. We are fairly optimistic for the development of our key markets during 2011. We expect the growth rate for the pharmaceutical market to be in the middle single digits, driven by the emerging countries. We expect the Over-the-Counter and also the Animal Health market to grow around 4%. The Diabetes Care market will probably see only very slight growth due to continuing pressure on prices in the United States.</p>
          <p>We foresee a positive trend for the global seed and crop protection market in 2011. Assuming normal weather patterns, we anticipate robust market growth for agrochemicals as well as for seed and trait. We expect a further strengthening of MaterialScience main customer industries. The automotive industry will most likely continue along the road to recovery. We anticipate robust expansion in the global electrical, electronics industry, and we predict a distinct recovery in the construction and furniture industries in 2011.</p>
          <p>In this total context, we can look to 2011 with considerable optimism. For the group, we are targeting a currency and portfolio adjusted sales increase of between 4% and 6% in 2011. Based on our currency assumptions, we therefore expect to report group sales of between &#x20AC;35 billion and &#x20AC;36 billion. We aim to increase EBITDA before special items to over &#x20AC;7.5 billion. Core earnings per share are expected to improve by about 10%.</p>
          <p>We can confirm our target for 2012. We expect group sales to again grow by approximately 5% and to achieve EBITDA before special items of approximately &#x20AC;8 billion and core earnings per share of around &#x20AC;5. We're planning significant investments in our business. During the next three years, we intend to invest a total of &#x20AC;15 billion in capital expenditures and R&amp;D. This year, we are budgeting capital expenditures of &#x20AC;1.5 billion for property, plants and equipment.</p>
          <p>We expect our research and development expenditures in 2011 to match the record level of 2010, which as I said before, was approximately &#x20AC;3.1 billion. We are targeting higher sales and earnings in all our sub-groups in 2011. In 2011, HealthCare plans to increase sales by a low-to-mid single digit percentage, and to achieve a small improvement in EBITDA before special items.</p>
          <p>In the Pharmaceutical segments, we do not yet expect sales to resume growing with the market in 2011. We plan to increase sales by a low-to-mid single digit percentage and to raise the EBITDA margins before special items. In the Consumer Health segment, we anticipate above market growth in sales. We expect sales and EBITDA before special items to increase by mid-single digit percentage. In 2012, we aim to accelerate the pace of growth, especially in Pharmaceuticals, thanks to our new products and to improved EBITDA before special items in both HealthCare segments.</p>
          <p>As already mentioned, we anticipate favorable market conditions for CropSciences and are therefore optimistic for 2011. We expect to improve sales in both CropSciences segments and to grow at least by a mid-single digit percentage overall. We plan to expand EBITDA before special items at a higher rate than sales.</p>
          <p>In 2012, we again aim to grow sales at least with the market and further improve EBITDA before special items. For MaterialScience, we plan to raise sales in 2011 by a mid-single digit percentage and to increase EBITDA before special items at a higher rate than sales. Provided that the market environment remains favorable, we plan to further increase sales and EBITDA before special items in 2012.</p>
          <p>So ladies and gentlemen, I'm sure you would agree that our operating performance remained on track during 2010. We are optimistic for the future and are targeting a further improvement in our performance.</p>
          <p>That concludes my remarks. We will now be happy to answer any questions you may have. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Mr. Richard Vosser. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Richard Vosser here from JP Morgan. Thanks very much for taking my questions. A couple of Xarelto related questions to start with, please. By my calculation, I think you could have heard back from the FDA in terms of whether you've been granted a priority review or not for Xarelto in the stroke indication. I wondered if you could give us some clarity there. And then related to that, I wondered if you could give your thoughts on the fact that the complete response letter could be answered in July.</p>
          <p>And if you haven't got a priority review, the stroke indication could be around November. What do you think &#x2013; what's your planning assumption in terms of what the FDA would do in that situation? And then finally on Xarelto, whether you could give us an idea of when you're targeting ATLAS to be presented. And then one quick question on R&amp;D spend or innovation spend from &#x2013; in terms of the &#x20AC;15 billion. Does that work out at about &#x20AC;10 billion in terms of R&amp;D spend?</p>
          <p>And if that's correct, that seems to imply flat to slightly growing R&amp;D spend over the three years. And that's despite Xarelto spend tailing off. Could you give us an outline where this spend will be targeted both, I suppose, in Pharma and CropScience and of course Materials as well? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you Richard. We'll ask J&#xF6;rg Reinhardt to answer your Xarelto questions first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Regarding regulatory situation in the US, so far we have not heard back from the FDA in terms of priority review, so we would assume a normal review time of 10 months for Xarelto in this path indication, which should then lead on to the situation you must you just described, meaning that the six months review clock for the VTE indication would be before that time. I personally believe that the FDA will look at these two submissions independently. They are pretty familiar with the product by now, and I believe that they will deal with both indications independent from each other.</p>
          <p>The other question you had was on ATLAS. As you know, we believe and this is a study that is event-driven &#x2013; we believe that the study should be completed around summertime, which will mean that after a decent analysis of the data, we should be able to present to the results towards the end of the year, early next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then regarding your question on the R&amp;D, we are planning just like last year, to spend in 2011, approximately &#x20AC;3.1 billion. And if you take the &#x20AC;15 billion for three years, two-thirds of it R&amp;D, one-third capital investments, that's around &#x20AC;10 billion. So in that -ballpark number, that &#x20AC;10 billion, we have room to go up in the budget in 2012 and 2013, which is most likely the situation. Healthcare, CropScience, MaterialScience, the ratio, I don't think will change significantly, course the areas of emphases might change but not the overall ratios. Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Sachin Jain. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Sachin Jain from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Thanks for taking my question. Just three, if I may. Firstly, just one clarification, you mentioned that Magellan had completed. Do you have data in-house and can you just clarify your intentions for headline press release out of ACC? Secondly, you've briefly commented on a risk ratio the 2012 guidance at &#x20AC;5. I wonder if you just discuss that number in the context of consensus at &#x20AC;5.40, where do you see the major differences in-house versus where the market is?</p>
          <p>And is Xarelto still a major swing factor in terms of your thought process on that number for next year? Thirdly, and finally on MaterialScience, wondering if you can just comment on the demand environment, operating rates there, the lag to comment on growing EBITDA first quarter despite higher costs. And if you could just clarify the cost statement for the first quarter, given that I think your planning assumption slide was based on an oil price of $18, clearly we're higher than at the moment. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Your first question on the Magellan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Magellan, well data are in-house, it's correct. We're still in the process of analyzing these. We are in discussions with the ACC regarding potential headline release. However, as you kind of mentioned, they are very strict in terms of the rules that they apply for an event like this. And for the time being, being four weeks ahead of the presentation, I cannot commit that we will be coming to an agreement to submit any or propose any headline data. So bear with us, if you can do it. We will otherwise, you will see the data on April 5.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then Werner Baumann, our CFO, on the guidance for 2012 EPS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Sachin. I think if you look at the &#x20AC;5.40 versus the &#x20AC;5. You have to bare in mind that, first of all, for the entire planning period between 2011 and 2013, we work on the basis of $1.40 to the euro and that is not necessarily yet I think fully reflected in the analysts' estimates. So you will have a technical difference in virtually all guided numbers compared to some of the projections, which are out there. Secondly, I think on a business-by-business group comparison, the projections specifically on the CropScience are very, very bullish. These are, I think, the main drivers compared to our &#x20AC;5 per share guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. And then MaterialScience, Patrick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Sachin on the demand side, we're seeing a fairly strong development, pretty much in line with our historical growth rate. So on MDI about 7%, TDI now approaching around 5%, the polyol is still in line with that, polycarbon is around about 6%. The supply situation is not too uncomfortable at the moment. I think on utilization we're at about 85% on MDI, 90% to 95% on TDI and probably virtually sold out on polyethers at the moment. On polycom, it's the overall utilization around about 90%. So that doesn't give too bad an environment from point of view of price.</p>
          <p>So although we see significantly increased oil price, and current pricing in the market doesn't reflect that, we're pushing through price increases of quite significant proportions. So on TDI, MDI and polyethers, the price increase is &#x20AC;0.30 to &#x20AC;0.35 about &#x2013; a kilo has already gone out into the market. And on polycarbonates at &#x20AC;0.40 a kilo price increase has already been announced. So our assumptions in our guidance are that the market will allow us to push those prices through. And certainly with this increased oil price, certainly by the end of quarter two, I would expect to see us get prices in line with feed stocks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Mr. Jeremy Redenius. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this Jeremy Redenius from Sanford Bernstein. I have one question for each segment. First of all, is there anything you could do to give us an update on the latest <mark type="inaudible" />, any update on the trial recruitment? And could you also combine that with Pfizer's Sildenafil? And when do you expect to file in PAH and CTEPH?</p>
          <p>And second on CropScience, just wondering if you can give us an update on the pricing dynamic in the market there. We've heard a little bit about price increases selectively from Syngenta and BASF in, for example in fungicides &#x2013; low single digit order of magnitude, but also some competitive statements about trying to gain market share. And I wonder if we could get your take on how you see that developing.</p>
          <p>And thirdly on MaterialScience, I guess, could you give us any indication if you're seeing any pressure from the potential start-up of the Saudi Cayenne plant for polycarbonate? And then also if you're seeing any pressure from Jantai and their activities with Borsad Chem Europe, if in both situations these are &#x2013; they're being rational actors in the market. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we will figure out, here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, there's a little bit of good news here. The trial recruitment, at least in the PAH trial, is going better then it did last time. But still I mean it's a very complicated trial. We have simplified a protocol, we've added some new centers, but still we do expect that study, as well as the other study, to be completed end of the year, beginning next year. We stated in 2012, which would then also lead us, if the studies are positive, to submit and file in 2012. I believe that should cover the question. You had something else, which I didn't quite understand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeremy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I &#x2013; also I'd asked about the CTEPH.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No, that is not recruiting as fast as PAH, but we also believe that that study should give us data in 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then Sandy Peterson on the pricing environment in CropSciences?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, first of all, let me comment on 2010. As you know, on average, our competitors lost four to five percentage points on pricing in 2010 and ours on average was about -1%. In the fourth quarter, we started seeing a little improvement on pricing and selectively, we were able to take growth price increases in some cases. I think the challenge in 2011 is going to be first of all, on the herbicide market, we're still going to have significant pressure from generic glyphosate, which is really going to keep the market from increasing pricing. But I'm hopeful that we'll see selective improvement in pricing in fungicides and also insecticides as we are bringing new products in the marketplace. The question is really how these will stick over time and through the &#x2013; as the year progresses. So we're hopeful we'll some better pricing environment in 2011 than we saw in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Sandy and then Patrick, the environment with <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think the best way of looking at it, Jeremy, in polycarbonates is the utilization rates are above 90% at the moment. So the Saudi Cayenne facility will be absorbed pretty fast by the market growth, which I forecast to be in the 6% to 7% range. And I don't see any irrational behavior around that. In the polyurethanes arena, <mark type="inaudible" /> have kind of gained control of one and another. They've been announcing price increases along with the rest of the market. Of course with growth rates being relatively high, these capacities will be absorbed quickly as well.</p>
          <p>TDI grew by 13% in 2010, MDI by 18%. TDI will continue &#x2013; we've forecasted around about 5%, which is 1% above historical growth, and MDI is about 7% to 7.5%. So I don't think these capacity additions will be a problem in terms of price income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Andrew Baum. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's Andrew Baum from Morgan Stanley. Three quick questions. Firstly on Magellan, do you have an SPA to get US regulatory approval both if it shows superiority, as well as if it shows non-inferiority versus Lovenox? Second, perhaps you could talk some of the recent management changes you've made within the company, especially within Consumer and I understand also in emerging markets. To what extent there's scope to augment revenue growth within those areas as a function of the new management structure. And then finally if you could say something about the incremental SG&amp;A commitments to roll out Xarelto for the atrial fibrillation indication within Europe. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So Magellan and I assume, Andrew, that your management change question was also related to HealthCare or Bayer in general?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean you can talk to &#x2013; specifically it was HealthCare, but I'm interested in emerging markets, and I am sure you'd have interesting things to say on the broader topics as well. So I'd love to hear those as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let's start with the management changes. Andrew, I think you're primarily referring to the recent recruitment of Erica Mann who is going to replace Gary in Consumer Care. Erica has a background, which has given her a significant experience in some of these, let's say not mainstream markets. As you've seen, she was running the Pharma business for Wyeth in South Africa but also in Australia. And now recently, given move to the US. So she has experience in different parts of the world, which will actually help our Consumer Health business to focus more than what we did in the past on some of these emerging markets, especially in Asia.</p>
          <p>As you know, probably we are present in some of these markets but not really at a level of strength that we would like to be. So for example in China, we're still relatively small and we need to actually invest more and get our act together. You also saw that the fourth quarter of last year was relatively weak in Consumer Health, which have to do with the fact that we keep on investing in our infrastructure in these markets over proportionally.</p>
          <p>Other than that, we have streamlined our regional set-up. We have taken out a management layer, especially with an impact on the emerging markets. We have now most of these markets report directly to the President of the Pharma business because we believe that a business like in China or like in Asia Pac needs to have direct access to the main decision makers in the system in order to speed up our movements there.</p>
          <p>I believe that this change, together also with the fact that now Latin America reports directly to Andreas, should lead us to simplify, speed up, and make sure that there is enough emphasis on those important markets, which are really going to drive our growth going forward much more than that will be the case in Europe or in the US.</p>
          <p>With regard to specific SG&amp;A commitments in Europe, please understand that that is an area where I don't want to make too much of a guess right now. I mean you can assume that it's going to be a pretty competitive environment in Europe going forward. As you saw, we have been doing well with Xarelto versus Pradaxa in the VTE indication. I mean in almost all of these markets we do have a larger market share than our main competitor.</p>
          <p>And of course, we would like to have a similar situation also going forward in the other indications that are going to be approved soon. So for us, an important aspect and important area where we will make sure that all the necessary investments are being made, by the way, not only in SG&amp;A, but obviously also in Life Cycle Management and additional Phase IV studies, et cetera. Now, first question regarding Magellan, can you repeat, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So I was asking whether you have a special protocol assessment, a commitment from the FDA that should you show Xarelto to be either superior or, B, non-inferior to Lovenox that they will approve it. Obviously, it's an interesting trial design, there's less patient mix, I mean all &#x2013; the rest of stuff you know. Hence my question, what's your confidence on regulatory approval, given the design of the trial? And to what extent is it dependent on the two possible positive outcomes for the trial? Do you have an SPA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer is not specifically, it is an area where obviously approvability always depends on data. I mean this is a situation where we will have to see, with the FDA, how we best go forward once the data are published and once the data are clear, but we don't have a specific agreement with them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Andrew. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is Mr. Jo Walton. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, it's Jo Walton from Credit Suisse. Four quick questions, please. Firstly, in Pharmaceuticals, I wonder whether you could give us some sense of how successful Xarelto has been in Europe. Just give us some color as to how it's succeeding, where it is up against Pradaxa as a competitive product. And also in Pharmaceuticals, whether you could split out for us please, the Nexavar sales in China and Japan. And then moving on beyond Pharmaceuticals, in CropScience, I'm trying to get a sense of what is reasonable as a long-term operating margin. In previous years, you've managed to produce 20% to 22% operating margin, you're now down at sub-15%.</p>
          <p>Has the competitive environment and the impact of generics in herbicides, say, made a structural difference such that 20% is no longer a realistic objective for the long term? And in the same &#x2013; really with the Consumer business, again you've had 20%-odd margins, the forth quarter was particularly weak. You've told us that you have to invest more in marketing support. I haven't noticed a higher growth in sales. Is this just again a structural issue that you're having to spend more in order to get sales and we shouldn't expect a 20% long-term operating margin there either?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. So J&#xF6;rg, you can answer the first &#x2013; the two Pharma, Xarelto and Nexavar questions. And then also comment on the Consumer business, then we go to Sandy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So Jo, Xarelto, obviously it's still small number. So for the full year 2010, we had overall sales for Xarelto of &#x20AC;50 million. What I can say is that, as I mentioned before, in those markets where we compete directly with Pradaxa that actually applies to, I believe, almost all of the markets. We are doing at a low level, better than Pradaxa does, which hopefully is a good sign going forward.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, I mean, it's a very limited market. I don't think you can say much or you can &#x2013; base any decent assessment, based on these small numbers. However, it's better this way than the other way around. So from that perspective, we are reasonably confident and happy. Regarding Nexavar, of course Japan and China are the two markets where we see strongest growth. We had sales of &#x20AC;31 million in Japan in the fourth quarter, and we had &#x20AC;14 million sales in China. In Japan, this is a 32% growth, and in China it's a 16% growth.</p>
          <p>Regarding Consumer Health, yes, we had a relatively weak fourth quarter, but it has also to do with the base of 2009. Our marketing and sales spendings in 2009 were particularly low in Consumer Health, and we went back in 2010 to a more, let's call it reasonable level, as compared to 2009. We also had a weak Diabetes Care business in the US in 2010. We mentioned that. We hope that that's going to improve significantly in 2011. We also had significantly higher R&amp;D investments in Animal Health. So overall, I don't think that that level of marketing and sales spending you saw in the fourth quarter is going to be the norm. I would like us to go back to more moderate levels as we did show for the rest of the year, which means that &#x2013; and as we stated, which means that we should see a slight margin improvement there as well again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then Sandy, margin aspirations for CropSciences?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a great question, Jo. I think the simple way to answer the question is that over the mid-term, we need to get back to the 20%, which is what we were at in 2009. 2010 was a particularly challenging year, for a lot of reasons including the weather. But also there was also a lot of price pressure and generic pressure in the market. And as we are investing for the future in our BioScience business and in emerging markets, we as an organization are transitioning a little bit of where our growth will come from. But that also means that we aspire to get back to the 20% and then from there, hopefully we'll be able to get beyond that over the longer term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, Jo, I'd just like to make another general comment about the margins and the margin pressure. There is no question that in HealthCare and in CropSciences, we experienced margin pressure in 2010. That has to do with the introduction of generic competition and in HealthCare's case with health reforms. This is exactly why we have set out with this restructuring program that we've been talking about, because it is absolutely key to &#x2013; for us to be able to invest in innovation, not just R&amp;D, but also the marketing and the sales of the new products.</p>
          <p>And in order to free up resources for that, and not have that become penalizing for margins, we need to save in other areas. And that is exactly what we're doing with the restructuring program, which sort of has as a motto, more innovation and less administration. So we recognize the pressure and we are committed to continue to invest in innovation, freeing up the resources to do so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Mr. Florent Cespedes. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Florent Cespedes, Exane BNP Paribas, a few quick questions. First on the Pharma division, can you share with us what are the assumptions behind the Pharma margin improvement for 2011? Is it better resilience of <mark type="inaudible" />? Is it the cost-cutting measure, or any other item? And secondly on Xarelto, could you share with us your expectations for 2011? And lastly on Xarelto again, could you tell us your view on Xarelto potential in medically ill patients market as a cheap version of Lovenox is already available in the US? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>J&#xF6;rg?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so first of all, what we've said in the guidance is that we do expect a low-to-single &#x2013; mid-single digit growth in sales for 2011 and a slight improvement in EBITDA, which does not necessarily mean a significant margin improvement. So we will certainly strive to continue to improve margins in 2011. But I believe that if we will be able to do that, it will certainly come from productivity improvements, as Marijn mentioned, 1,800 people out of the overall restructuring volume is coming from HealthCare.</p>
          <p>That is the restructuring scope that will be done in 2011 and 2012, so almost all of that will actually affect us in 2011. But certainly this level of restructuring should have an impact and should help to bring EBITDA and margins up over time, although we will invest some part of that again in China to build our presence in emerging markets. So, I see mainly productivity improvements across the board driving it. And also, as we mentioned before, I mean, Xarelto was a very expensive program during the Phase III program over the last few years. And overall investment for Xarelto come &#x2013; and R&amp;D comes down a little bit, which should also help us in 2011.</p>
          <p>You've been asking for the expectation for Xarelto for 2011. I mentioned &#x20AC;50 million for 2010. Since we are not expecting any significant contribution from the new indications in 2011, if you don't want double the sales that we had in 2010 should be around &#x2013; in the right order of magnitude. But still going to be a relatively small product also in '11, and that's why we do see significant sales, but also profitability increase only in 2012 and beyond.</p>
          <p>You were talk &#x2013; were asking regarding the medically ill indication. Obviously we'll have to see how the market will develop there. Enoxaparin is certainly a very formidable and well-established competitor. And we'll have to see how we can establish ourselves next to them. That's something that will obviously also depend on the data that has been generated. And it's something that we may want to discuss again once the Magellan data has been made public.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thank you, J&#xF6;rg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Florent. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Thomas Gilbert. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom Gilbert, UBS. Chemicals and less tense chemicals questions, three of them. The first one is the &#x20AC;44 million licensing income in the fourth quarter, can you just clarify that was entirely booked or at the merit of the crop protection business unit? And are there any further such income streams expected for 2011-12? That is the first question. The second question is also in CropScience or crop protection, respectively. Just a clarification, the -1% for 2010 on pricing, was that meant to be a comment regarding CropScience or crop protection? And following on from that, -4.7% organic sales decline in 2010 seems way below our competitors.</p>
          <p>It looks like you've lost share, your competitors are coming up with new value propositions, bundling seeds and crop protection. Just wondering whether you think over the medium term, you've got the right value proposition for your growers. But also namely the retailers, the retail model, are you happy with what you're seeing since you've joined the crop protection business?</p>
          <p>And the third question is probably for Mr. Dekkers. Obviously, you're allowing all of the business units a nice growth path with CapEx and R&amp;D. Just wondering how you allocate money for external growth. And the balance sheet is now two times net debt plus pensions, the EBITDA looks sound. But what is the criterion you apply when business units or clusters ask you for money for external growth? And any kind of idea on an acquisition budget for 2011? That would be helpful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so Sandy. Start with the &#x20AC;44 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So Tom, I'll answer that question. The &#x20AC;44 million is &#x2013; it's income that was both due to selling off of older molecules, as well as licensing income associated with our BioScience business. And we will continue to always look at our portfolio for opportunities to sell or out license assets as we are streamlining the crop protection portfolio, as well as hopefully be able to generate incremental income from licensing some of our traits and other things at our BioScience platform over the short and mid term.</p>
          <p>So hopefully that answers your first question. As it relates to pricing and crop &#x2013; the -1% pricing that was crop protection specific &#x2013; actually in our other two businesses, we were able to sustain or actually increase pricing. And in terms of your general question about market share and our performance as a business, I'll just give you my perspective on where we are as a business and what we need to do going forward.</p>
          <p>It's quite obvious that 2010 was an extremely disappointing year for the crop protection business. Our BioScience and Environmental Sciences businesses actually saw very nice strong growth and market share gains. Both of them did in the businesses in which they operate. In our crop protection business, we clearly saw declines in most of the markets around the globe. There were a couple of places that I would describe as very positive and places where we as a business actually had done a very good job of bundling seeds and traits.</p>
          <p>That's in Canada with our Canola business, in India both with our vegetable business and crop protection business and our rice business. And in Brazil and the US with our cotton business where we've actually been able to sell in and do a quite a nice job with the growers and the dealers and all of the channel partners in those markets.</p>
          <p>So for us, I think as we move forward, it's going to be important for us to take full advantage of the innovation that we have. We have the strongest portfolio of products and the strongest pipeline in CP. And what we need to do is make sure that we are able to appropriately fund the marketing and commercialization of those products, and ensure that those value propositions are fully understood and are appreciated by the growers and the sellers in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>So we &#x2013; in 2011 and 2012, we've done a lot of things to change the focus of the organization. We've changed a number of key leaders in the organization, and I believe that will really help us improve our commercial model further, and really take advantage of the models where it has worked quite well, places like India, Brazil and Canada.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sandra. Can I just ask in on the &#x20AC;44 million, can you split the benefit to the Crop Protection and Environmental, BioScience businesses separately? Or was it by and large a Crop Protection income?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's half and &#x2013; it was about half and half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Thomas, your question with respect to an acquisitions budget, we don't have a specific acquisitions budget, because of course with acquisitions you have to be somewhat opportunistic since it's hard to know what exactly is going to be available for sale. But I think we're pleased to bring down our net debt to under a billion with terrific working capital improvement in the company in all three sub-groups. And that gives us, of course with lower debt, always more flexibility as these things are related. Areas of focus &#x2013; for our smaller acquisitions, all three sub-groups. For somewhat larger ones, I would say specifically HealthCare and CropScience. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Mr. Andreas Heine. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>From UniCredit. You have booked quite some restructuring and litigations and the restructuring program has just started. Can you remind me what you will have for the restructuring charges next year, and even more important, what the cash out will be in the year 2011 and 2012, please? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Werner Baumann will answer the question, Andreas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah &#x2013; for the overall program, we said that we're going to have expenses of roughly &#x20AC;1 billion. Most, if not all of it, most of it actually cash effective. Out of that amount, &#x20AC;62 million were booked in 2010 exclusively related to HealthCare and the next slice of it, if you want so, for 2011 is around &#x20AC;0.5 billion. And then the remainder of it mostly in 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And these &#x20AC;0.5 billion, that is cash? And what about the litigation you have booked in 2010? According to the cash flow statement and the strength of the cash flow in the last quarter, that has not been paid yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's absolutely correct. First, to your follow-up question on the &#x20AC;0.5 billion in restructuring charges. Most of it will be cash relevant in &#x2013; for 2011. And then on the litigation related charges, our cash out &#x2013; our guidance always is exclusive of litigation because that's impossible to estimate at the beginning of the year. And you're absolutely right that the charges we have taken in quarter three mostly on will arise have not become cash effective so far. And here, the timing really depends on how the discussions and negotiations proceed during the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Antonio Fernandes. Please state your name, company name followed by your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello? Clare, I guess we lost him.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. I think we have lost Mr. Fernandes' line. I will proceed to the next question. The next question is from the line of Mr. Ronald K&#xF6;hler. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, it's Ronald K&#xF6;hler from MainFirst. First question is on YAZ' franchise especially in US, you launched Beyaz, you had a nice rebound actually from &#x20AC;32 million to &#x20AC;55 million in the US. Is that the stocking effect Beyaz, or do we really now get let's say to more decent levels once again? So can you a little bit elaborate on that?</p>
          <p>Second question is on Levitra, also here you had a quite a good fourth quarter. I was wondering, is this the ODT version and what is &#x2013; is a sustainable level or is it also some stocking effect here? Third question is actually regarding tax rate. You have a new guidance, 27% to 28% previously it was 28% to 30%. Is that now a long-term guidance? Is it influenced, I guess, by more money made in emerging markets? Can you also a little bit elaborate on that, please?</p>
          <p>And the last question on HealthCare. I'm a little bit curious if you could give us, let's say, the major HealthCare product or Pharma product in emerging markets. I know Glucobay, as an example quite dominant in China. But a little bit here and the outlook meaning also the risk of getting generic pressure here on your existing portfolio. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I suggest you take the questions, J&#xF6;rg, Levitra and then HealthCare products in the major markets first, and then we go to Werner for the tax guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So regarding, yes, you're absolutely right, the way we look at that product family is from a franchise perspective. And Beyaz' launch actually so far has done well. When you look at new prescriptions, we are already at 1% in the last week, 1% market share of NRxs which is actually absolutely in line with our expectations, which leads us to the assumption that our overall YAZ business for 2011, or the franchise, is going to be flat in terms of sales.</p>
          <p>We would expect after 2011, once we have overcome the first six months of genericization, in fact that in 2012 and '13, the franchise should actually grow again by high single-digits, is what we expect, driven to a larger extent also by emerging markets where we see that oral contraceptives are going to be more and more accepted with the younger generation.</p>
          <p>As you may know there are cultural differences, obviously, in the way contraception is being done between the US, Europe and Asia. But what we see is that the younger generation in Asia is more open to hormones and oral contraception. So there it's also from a mid-term perspective, we see still growth to come. Levitra, no, it's not yet the ODT formulation in the US, which we expect to launch later this year.</p>
          <p>Overall, I believe that for the time being the Levitra, let's say, take-up is hopefully going to be sustainable. We would hope that the ODT formulation continues to add value to this overall franchise. Although we are not going to, let's say, have particularly high hopes for Levitra, but nevertheless, we do hope that the ODT formulation contributes to the stable growth of the sales there.</p>
          <p>Now regarding HealthCare in Asia, it's actually interesting when you look at main contributions that we have in China for example, when it comes from products like Glucobay, Adalat, Avalox, products that are off patents in the long period of time, at least in most parts of the world. And they are still going strong. And that has to do with the brand.</p>
          <p>I mean, we are talking about &#x2013; essentially I could ask you &#x2013; argue we are talking about branded generics where the Bayer brand is absolutely key to make this product successful.</p>
          <p>So they have been seeing generic competition since quite a while and are still growing double-digits. And that's not only the case in China, but also in quite a range of other emerging markets. So overall, I believe that that portfolio of Primary Care products, strong brands, well established, efficacious, safe and driven by the Bayer heritage is going to drive our emerging markets portfolio over the next few years, not only in Asia, but also in Latin America. In addition to that, we obviously do plan to also launch our new product. Nexavar has been launched, Xarelto has been launched. So it's going to be a mix of mature products still going strong and new products that hopefully drive growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on your question on tax rate, Ronald, you're absolutely right. We have adjusted our guidance to a new range of 27% to 28% for 2011. So it's come down and we'll see it continue at roughly that level. And that compares to an even lower current tax rate in 2010, which is driven by an unusual distribution of our regional results, yeah? On the effective tax rate, sorry, not the current tax rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Mr. Martin Fl&#xFC;ckiger. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, gentlemen. Martin Fl&#xFC;ckiger from Helvea. Just one question left, really, on BioMaterial Science. I was wondering whether you could give us some more color on the raw material price evolution that you've experienced in the fourth quarter. And if I understood Marijn correctly, could you &#x2013; that's just a clarification question. An additional one, did I hear this correctly that the EBIT hit from raw materials was &#x20AC;160 million in the fourth quarter? If &#x2013; you know, just to double check on that. And regarding your raw material prices again, looking forward, what your expectations are. Obviously, everyone is expecting rising raw material prices given the surge in oil prices of recent, but I was just wondering whether you could provide a little bit more flavor on that? Many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Yeah, thank you, Martin. Yeah, the &#x20AC;160 million, just to clarify, that was fourth quarter '10 compared to fourth quarter '09. So that was the year-on-year comparison. The sequential comparison on raw materials from quarter three to quarter four would be around about &#x20AC;60 million of increased total raw material plus energy price. Clearly as we go forward with the current volatility in oil price, we can't forecast what the average for the year will be.</p>
          <p>But just to give you a crude fix or rule of thumb, about $10 of barrel in oil equates to around about $200 million in cost for us. Clearly, we can't pass that on instantly, but typically over a period of 3 to 4 months, that is capable of being reflected in prices. And I think I highlighted those price changes earlier. So that's the dynamic at the moment. All I can say is, we're no better at forecasting oil prices than anybody else is. So I'm not going to be drawn into that game.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Coward. Okay. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Michael Leuchten. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. It's Michael Leuchten from Barclays Capital. Just a quick follow-up on Xarelto. In terms of capacity, do you have enough capacity in place to launch in most major markets immediately, or would you have to affect a staggered launch across the regions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have sufficient capacity to launch in all major markets at the same time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have a question from Mr. Ronald K&#xF6;hler. Please state your name, company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hello, it's Ronald K&#xF6;hler again from MainFirst. A follow-up question on R&amp;D. Obviously, you say that there were times you're looking for higher R&amp;D, even it seems 2011 versus 2010 a slight increase in Pharma R&amp;D. And I'm potentially, as the others, are wondering a little bit after Xarelto is running out, the pipeline is, let's say, with more specialized drugs, which I would have believed would require much less R&amp;D. Does that mean you put more money into the R or into early phases? Or what is actually your spending target here in terms of, yeah, which products or early phases? A second question is on amortization. Obviously, you had a lot of write-downs. Now does it in any way affect your amortization &#x2013; budgeted amortization or depreciation amortization for 2011 and have you a number, perhaps, on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, R&amp;D and Pharma, J&#xF6;rg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, no, there is no significant shift from one area into the other within R&amp;D. Please don't forget that beyond Xarelto, there is quite a rich Phase III pipeline that also costs money. And even with Xarelto, I mean we're talking about a Life Cycle Management program that sooner or later is going to add significant numbers of patients. As well, we have the VEGF Trap program still ongoing. There's Nexavar additional indications. We have <mark type="inaudible" />. So, there are a range of products that add to the cost. We have a number of Phase I projects that we are starting now in the oncology pipeline. So all together, I would say that our overall level of investment is absolutely adequate. And I do not foresee a significant change between research and development in the near term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And on depreciation and amortization, in rough terms, you can work with the same level of D&amp;A as you have for 2010. For 2010, prior to special items and impairments, it was about &#x20AC;1.3 billion each between depreciation and amortization, and that's where it roughly ended up. For 2011, total of depreciation and amortization is about &#x20AC;2.5 billion, also again roughly cut in half and half depreciation and amortization for the entire company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Is there another question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, Mr. Rosar, there are no further questions at this time. Please continue with any other points you wish to raise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Clare. Ladies and gentlemen, on the strong behalf of my colleagues, I'd like to say thank you for being with us on the call and thank you for your questions. Before closing the call, please allow me also to draw your attention to our upcoming Investor and Analyst Conference. Firstly, as you may already know, on March 22 and 23, we will host our Annual Mid Management Conference here in Leverkusen. Secondly, on the 17th and 18th of November, we are planning an Investor and Analyst Conference focusing on our business in China. The conference will take place at our head offices in Shanghai. We're now saying goodbye and hope to meeting you all soon again. Okey-dokey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the Full Year and Fourth Quarter 2010 Results Investor Analyst Conference Call of Bayer AG. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>