<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1508745" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>810</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Alexander Rosar</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman-Management Board &amp; CEO">Marijn E. Dekkers</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Sachin Jain</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman of the Board of Management, Bayer CropScience">Sandra E. Peterson</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Member-Management Board">Werner Baumann</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman-Management Board &amp; CEO, Bayer HealthCare AG">J&#xF6;rg Reinhardt</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Matthew J. Weston</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Kepler Capital Markets SA (Switzerland)">Fabian Wenner</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer, Bayer MaterialScience AG">Patrick W. Thomas</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Tim M. Race</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Andrew S. Baum</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Mike Leuchten</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Plc">Richard B. Vosser</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Commerzbank AG (Broker)">Lutz Gr&#xFC;ten</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd. Germany">Christian Faitz</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="MainFirst Bank AG (Broker)">Ronald K&#xF6;hler</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Commerzbank AG (Broker)">Daniel Wendorff</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Andreas Heine</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="DZ Bank AG (Securities)">Peter Spengler</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA">Florent Cespedes</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to Bayer's Investor and Analyst Conference Call on the Third Quarter 2012 Results. Throughout today's recorded presentation all participants will be in a listen-only mode. The presentation will be followed by a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Mr. Alexander Rosar, Head of Investor Relations of Bayer AG. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Cleo. Ladies and gentlemen, good afternoon. It's my pleasure this afternoon to welcome you also on behalf of my colleagues to review our third quarter results with you.</p>
          <p>Joining me on the call today are Marijn Dekkers, our CEO; and Werner Baumann, our CFO; and the representatives from our subgroups, J&#xF6;rg Reinhardt from HealthCare; Sandra Peterson from CropScience; and Patrick Thomas from MaterialScience.</p>
          <p>Marijn will start off with a brief summary of the developments in the quarter. We assume you have all received and reviewed our stockholders' newsletter, the investor and analyst briefing document and the conference call slides so that Marijn can focus his introduction on the main points.</p>
          <p>Before we get into the results for the quarter, let me remind you to carefully read through the Safe Harbor statement. Thank you. Marijn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alexander. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. During the third quarter, Bayer continued to be on track for a successful 2012. The quarter was marked, above all, by the continued expansion in our life sciences businesses. MaterialScience showed good quarterly sales and earnings power, however, there was a weakening trend as the quarter progressed.</p>
          <p>Reported earnings were impacted by high special charges. Adjusted earnings, however, improved driven by the good business momentum at HealthCare and CropScience. Our innovation pipeline continued to develop positively. We achieved important regulatory milestones and reported positive Phase III results on riociguat last week.</p>
          <p>Further, strategic progress was made with the acquisitions of Schiff Nutrition for Consumer Care, Teva's U.S. animal health business and AgraQuest for CropScience. Against this background, and based on our expectations for the last quarter of 2012, we are reiterating our guidance for the full year.</p>
          <p>Let me now elaborate on some of the key figures for the quarter. When talking about sales, I will concentrate on portfolio and currency adjusted data. Group sales rose by 5% to &#x20AC;9.7 billion. All subgroups contributed to the increase. HealthCare, and particularly Pharmaceuticals, gained further growth momentum. At CropScience, the strong business development seen in the first half of the year continued unabated and MaterialScience also registered good quarterly sales. Reported earnings in the quarter were impacted by special charges of &#x20AC;356 million. Included here were &#x20AC;205 million in further accounting measures for all cases in connection with the oral contraceptive Yasmin/YAZ of which we are currently aware and which we consider to be worthy of settlement. Other special charges were restructuring expenses of &#x20AC;134 million and impairment losses of &#x20AC;68 million on intangible assets.</p>
          <p>Special gains of &#x20AC;53 million resulted from adjustments to certain post-employment benefit entitlements in the United States. Reported EBIT thus decreased by 24% to &#x20AC;838 million. Adjusted EBITDA improved by 2% to &#x20AC;1.8 billion, driven by higher sales at HealthCare and the continued strong business momentum at CropSciences, which overcompensated for a weaker performance at MaterialScience. Margins at MaterialScience weakened, especially towards the end of the quarter. In addition, the rise in Bayer's share price in the third quarter led to a substantial additional allocation of about &#x20AC;110 million to our stock incentive programs. Currency effect of around &#x20AC;160 million, primarily at HealthCare, contributed positively to earnings growth. Core earnings per share rose by 7% to &#x20AC;1.20.</p>
          <p>From a regional perspective, the strongest growth was again generated in the U.S. where business moved ahead by 9% in the quarter, driven by the strong business expansion at HealthCare and CropSciences and solid growth at MaterialScience. In the emerging economies, we achieved a 7% sales increase. These markets accounted for 39% of group sales. The highest growth rates were in Latin America and Eastern Europe. Emerging Asia grew by 7% with China posting a 17% increase.</p>
          <p>Gross cash flow in the quarter declined by 23%, mainly because of the lower operating result. Net cash flow, however, rose by 26% due to a decrease in cash tied up in working capital. Net financial debt declined by &#x20AC;7.9 billion at the end of June to &#x20AC;6.8 billion on September 30, due to the strong operating cash flow.</p>
          <p>So let's now move on to the performance of our subgroups, beginning with HealthCare. Sales of the HealthCare subgroup increased by 5% to &#x20AC;4.6 billion, driven by the positive developments at both Pharma and Consumer Health. From a regional perspective, business developed particularly well in the U.S. and in the emerging markets. Adjusted EBITDA moved ahead 6% to &#x20AC;1.3 billion.</p>
          <p>At Pharma, sales rose by 6% driven by the growth of Xarelto and other key products. With Xarelto, we achieved sales of &#x20AC;81 million in the quarter following market launches in further countries and the expansion of indications. Given the positive development during the first nine months, we're confident of exceeding our original sales target of &#x20AC;250 million to &#x20AC;270 million for the full year of 2012.</p>
          <p>Sales of Kogenate improved 9% due to increased shipments to our distribution partner in the quarter and by higher volumes resulting from a tender business in Australia. Revenues from Mirena increased significantly by 22%, mainly as a result of higher volumes in the U.S. Glucobay sales advanced 24% on strong performance in China. Good growth momentum was also achieved with Aspirin Cardio, up 13%; Zetia, up 8%; and Fosrenol, up 36%. As we expected, revenues from our YAZ/Yasmin line of oral contraceptives and from BETASERON declined by 4% and 6% respectively.</p>
          <p>From a regional perspective, growth at Pharma was achieved mainly in North America where business was up 11%, and in the emerging markets, especially China. Business moved ahead 9% in the emerging markets as a whole and by 34% in China.</p>
          <p>Adjusted EBITDA of Pharma increased by 8% to &#x20AC;827 million. Earnings benefit &#x2013; benefited from higher volumes and from positive currency effects. This was partly offset by increased expenses for the marketing of new products and the steady expansion of our commercial activities in the emerging markets. Also important for our Pharma business, is that we achieve significant regulatory and scientific milestones in recent months.</p>
          <p>EYLEA achieved a positive opinion from the CHMP for approval in Europe in wet AMD and was approved in Japan for the same indication. Regorafenib, or Stivarga, was approved in the U.S. for metastatic colorectal cancer, was granted priority review in Japan for this indication, and was filed for GIST in the U.S. On Xarelto, we got positive CHMP opinion for the treatment of PE in Europe and were granted priority review in the U.S. for the treatment of DVT and PE. And then lastly, just last week, we reported exciting new data from two Phase III trials on riociguat. Riociguat was the first drug to demonstrate efficacy in both PAH and CTEPH, and this is a major achievement and we're looking forward to further explore the potential of this asset.</p>
          <p>Now, let's look at Consumer Health. Sales in the Consumer Health segment rose by almost 5% in the third quarter with our OTC pharmaceuticals in the Consumer Care division generating a top-line expansion of 5%, our Medical Care division of 1%, and our Animal Health division of 11%. Also, the Consumer Health segment <mark type="indiscernible" /> (10:28) especially well in the emerging markets and in North America. Adjusted EBITDA of the Consumer Health segment came in at &#x20AC;470 million, 3% above the prior year quarter.</p>
          <p>Further, strategic process (sic) [progress] (10:42) was made with two bolt-on acquisitions in our Consumer Health business. In September we announced the acquisition of the U.S. animal health business of Teva for up to &#x20AC;145 million. This acquisition will strengthen our Animal Health business in the food and the companion animal segments.</p>
          <p>And this morning, we announced our plan to acquire Schiff Nutrition International for approximately &#x20AC;1.2 billion, representing $34 per share in cash. This acquisition will strengthen Bayer's leading OTC business and complement our existing nutritional business with well-established strong brands: Move Free to promote joint health, MegaRed to support cardiovascular health, Airborne to support the immune system and Digestive Advantage, the digestive support product containing a probiotic. Schiff generates some 70% of its sales with these four products. We believe that the products to be acquired have further market potential also outside of the U.S.</p>
          <p>In addition, Schiff's products will attractively complement our existing OTC portfolio. One example is the possible interplay between Aleve, to relieve acute joint and muscle pain, and Move Free, to support joint health.</p>
          <p>On a standalone basis, Schiff is planning more than &#x20AC;370 million in sales in fiscal year 2013. The relevant market is growing at 6% per annum.</p>
          <p>Significant synergies can be realized in areas such as administration as well as in the improvement of working capital management and other efficiency measures. Sale synergies are expected from expansion of the product portfolio into additional markets. The transaction values Schiff's business at 17.8 times consensus EBITDA for the fiscal year 2013. This acquisition is immediately accretive by &#x20AC;0.03 to core EPS and dilutes Bayer's reported EPS by &#x20AC;0.02 in 2013, and is expected to be accretive thereafter.</p>
          <p>We are convinced that the planned acquisitions will further strengthen our leading OTC business and add value for Bayer's shareholders. The transaction has already been approved by Schiff's shareholders. Closing is subject to the relevant regulatory approvals and expected by year-end 2012.</p>
          <p>Now, let's move on to CropScience. Sales of the CropScience subgroup advanced by almost 13% in the quarter to &#x20AC;1.6 billion, thus continuing the strong business momentum of the first half-year. Crop Protection sales advanced 12% and developed positively in all product groups and regions. The expansion of business with our seed treatment products, renamed as SeedGrowth, was particularly strong, gaining 24%. Crop Protection sales in Europe rose by 17%. This increase was mainly driven by strong SeedGrowth sales in Germany, France, and the United Kingdom.</p>
          <p>The Herbicides business also registered significant gains, mainly due to fall applications in <mark type="ph" /> serious (14:22). We achieved strong third quarter growth in North America as well with sales up by 11%. The drought in the United States has only a marginal effect on our business so far. Sales in the Asia Pacific region rose by a moderate 3%. This was largely attributable to increases for Herbicides and SeedGrowth products.</p>
          <p>Sales in the Latin America, Africa, and Middle East region advanced by 11% year-on-year. Growth there was mainly driven by increases in Latin America, especially Brazil where the Fungicides business developed especially well in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Sales of seeds climbed by a substantial 39%. Growth there was driven by sales gains in North America, particularly for canola seed. Sales of the Environmental Science business unit developed positively overall, rising by 9%. Adjusted EBITDA of CropSciences advanced by 15% to &#x20AC;189 million, driven by higher volumes and favorable currency effects. Progress made with our efficiency improvement programs also had a positive impact on earnings. However, manufacturing and selling expenses increased.</p>
          <p>Further, strategic progress was also achieved at CropScience. The acquisition of AgraQuest will allow us to integrate innovative biological pest management solutions based on natural microorganisms into our portfolio to significantly strengthen our fruits and vegetables business. This transaction price &#x2013; the transaction price here was 340 million plus milestones &#x2013; &#x20AC;340 million. The acquisition will allow Bayer to offer farmers a truly comprehensive range of integrated crop solutions based on seeds, <mark type="ph" /> traits (16:22), and combined chemical crop protection and biological controls.</p>
          <p>Now, let's move on to the MaterialScience subgroup where sales advanced 3% in the quarter to almost &#x20AC;3 billion. This growth was the result of higher volume. Selling prices declined slightly overall. The Polyurethanes business unit increased sales by 10%. This increase was mainly driven by higher volumes in all private groups and regions. We also achieved price increases in all regions, except North America.</p>
          <p>The Polycarbonates business posted sales down 11%. This was attributable particularly to lower selling prices and somewhat lower volume. Sales in CAS, the Coatings, Adhesives, and Specialties business unit, moved forward by almost 3% driven by higher volumes. Prices as a whole were slightly lower than the prior-year level. Adjusted EBITDA of the MaterialScience subgroup declined by 4% to &#x20AC;333 million, largely as a result of higher raw material and energy costs and a slight drop in selling prices. These factors were only partly offset by volume growth, savings generated by efficiency improvement programs, and positive currency effects.</p>
          <p>So, following the good operating performance in the first nine months of 2012, we're also confident that for the remainder of the year and are thus reiterating our sales and adjusted earnings forecast for the full year that we had already raised in July. So for the Group, we continue to anticipate the currency and portfolio-adjusted sales increase of between 4% and 5%. We plan to increase EBITDA before special items by a high single-digit percentage. Core earnings per share are expected to improve by about 10%.</p>
          <p>On HealthCare, guidance is unchanged compared to the previous quarter. We expect sales to increase by between 3% and 4%, and we plan to improve adjusted EBITDA by a mid to high single-digit percentage to which high positive currency effects will contribute.</p>
          <p>On CropScience, our guidance is also unchanged. We anticipate organic sales growth of approximately 10% and adjusted EBITDA approximately 20%, up over last year. For MaterialScience, our guidance is also unchanged except a slightly more positive view on the top line development.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter of 2012, we anticipate a significant currency and portfolio adjusted sales gain and significantly higher EBITDA before special items compared to the weak prior-year quarter. For the full year 2012, we plan for small currency and portfolio adjusted sales growth and EBITDA before special items in 2012 to remain level with the prior year, 2011.</p>
          <p>So, before we open the Q&amp;A session let me just summarize the main points. First, we delivered good business momentum in our life sciences business groups, HealthCare and CropSciences. Further strategic progress was made with the acquisitions of Schiff Nutrition for Consumer Care, Teva's U.S. Animal Health business, and AgraQuest for CropScience. Our innovation pipeline continued to develop favorably. We are convinced that Bayer is on track for a successful 2012 and are reiterating our guidance for the full year.</p>
          <p>And that concludes my remarks and we would now be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, at this time, we will begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Mrs. (sic) [Mr.] (21:14) Sachin. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I assume that's me, Sachin Jain, Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Three questions, please. Firstly, some more details on the cost progression in CropScience that hampered margin progression in the quarter. How do we think about marketing and selling expenses going forward from here?</p>
          <p>Second question on YAZ litigation, any comments on what you can say regarding how near the end of this provisioning process we are? I think moving through the course of this year, each quarter we've believed we were adequately provided for and then more provisioning comes. So anything you can give us on that and what particularly surprised in the quarter there?</p>
          <p>And then thirdly on riociguat, now that you have the Phase III data, just wondered if you could give us any color on peak sales, guidance on how you're thinking about that that you usually give for products where you have data delivered? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Sandy, cost progression in crop?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So &#x2013; thanks for the question. As you know, the third quarter for CropScience as it relates to earnings is the smallest quarter of the year, so it's usually around 10% of total. So you have to think about it in that context. Overall, we're &#x2013; we continue to see positive progression in terms of cause &#x2013; COGS as a percentage of sales as well as sales and marketing as a percentage of sales both through all the initiatives we've done through the cost restructuring as well as the positive progress we're getting from some of our higher volumes and demand for our business. So the top line is helping us.</p>
          <p>What you see in the third quarter specifically is there are two very small one-time adjustments that were made to the numbers. One of them has to do with what you already have heard about, is shifting some of our trade income to earlier in the year from the third quarter. And the second one has to do with a small amount of one-time costs associated with the acquisition of AgraQuest.</p>
          <p>So in general, we continue to make positive progress both in our COGS performance as well as our sales and marketing; reinvestments but also managing them as a total of our top line growth. So we're feeling good about where we are on costs and we believe that we will continue to see the positive progress through the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Sachin, Werner Baumann will answer the YAZ question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Sachin, we had quite a significant number of additional claims in the third quarter. Overall, it's about 12,400 by now which have been served as lawsuits. In addition, we had a little more than 700 claims, which were pending and had not been filed in court. Those have been included in our calculations. We assume that they have been sitting at the plaintiffs' lawyers' desks and now were served after us having taken that provision after quarter two.</p>
          <p>We also continue to receive further claims on a weekly basis, yet we don't have enough data of, let's say, a normal weekly filing pattern which would allow us at this point in time to take an overall provision. We will need a few more months until we hope to be in that position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then riociguat?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Obviously, riociguat is a quite interesting molecule and has shown really exciting data in two indications. As you know, Sachin, in CTEPH, there is nothing on the market at the moment. And actually, the absolute numbers of patients who are eligible for treatment in that indication is not that clearly defined. But when we assume that there are between 20,000 and 30,000 patients that are eligible for treatment with riociguat in CTEPH alone, then I think one can estimate that the potential for the product should be exceeding a &#x20AC;500 million threshold.</p>
          <p>Now, in addition to that, as you know, we have shown quite exciting data also in PAH, which -data which are in my eyes comparative to what others have shown. And I believe that also in PAH there's an opportunity for the product which is difficult to quantify at the moment. So in addition to that, we will continue to explore this mechanism of action and we'll see what we can do with this compound.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sachin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Weston. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. It's Matthew Weston from Credit Suisse. Three questions, if I can. The first relating to the Schiff &#x2013; excuse me, acquisition. Just very simply looking at the share price chart, clearly, it's a stock that's done extremely well over the course of 2012. I guess my question is, why now when you didn't think it was interesting at &#x20AC;10 per share.</p>
          <p>Secondly, also continuing from Schiff; previously, you had said that you would use incremental cash flow to move pension liabilities off the balance sheet. Does the acquisition and spending mean that you're going to delay doing that? But also, we've seen a number of your competitors over the course of 3Q raise the issue of additional charges for IAS 19 being restated from next year. And I just wondered whether or not you could give us some indication of what P&amp;L impact IAS 19 will have on Bayer?</p>
          <p>And then finally, following on from Sachin's question, clearly, we've seen positive data from riociguat. Xarelto is in the process of launching, and we have three other compounds due to be commercialized next year. Can you give us some indication of how we should look at Pharma SG&amp;A going into 2013? Clearly, the Pharma margins have been impressive this year. How much would &#x2013; should we assume will need to be reinvested going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Matthew, I'll take the first question. It's a funny thing with &#x2013; when you want to buy something, it has to be for sale. And in this case with Schiff, there are two majority shareholders that have the majority of the voting rights. And we have been talking to these two shareholders for a particular point in time &#x2013; for a period of time and at &#x20AC;34, then we could convince them to sell their company to us. But given the shareholder structure, it's a little bit hard given the somewhat limited float to just look at share price alone as an indication of the value for the company. And if you look at the ratios in terms of sales and EBITDA for 2013, we think that we paid a very fair price for Schiff.</p>
          <p>Second question, Werner?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Matthew, we have of course been a little bit more acquisitive with the liquidity position we have during the year. At the same time, we have also been generating significant free cash flow. And with that, we continue to look at the possibility to fund some of our unfunded pension liabilities by the end of the year. Yet at this point in time, we have not made a final decision to do so.</p>
          <p>Secondly, you asked about IAS 19. All <mark type="ph" /> effects (28:52) together, looking both at the pension side and also at the U.S. <mark type="ph" /> opex (28:57) would result in an incremental high double-digit million expense for 2013. Last but not least, riociguat that's a question...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>J&#xF6;rg?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So, that's not a riociguat question. It's an SG&amp;A question for Pharma going into 2013, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so we have been guiding mid-term, as you know, for Pharma margin of above 30% in 2014. Now, when you look at Pharma margins at the moment, this quarter was 30.2% and when you look at nine-month it was 29.9%. So we are pretty much around that order of magnitude. Now, that also implies that there is not a significant improvement to be expected now in the next two years as compared to this year's situation.</p>
          <p>Now, we know that we will have to continue to invest significantly for the new products to come up. But you also know that two oncology products, for example &#x2013; or even EYLEA are not at the same level of investment in what you have for Xarelto &#x2013; or we did have for Xarelto.</p>
          <p>So overall, I mean we will strive to keep our Pharma margin at this level and we will &#x2013; we still believe that the opportunity to reach above 30% in 2014 exists. And we will make sure at the same time that we will not under-invest, because these products need to be adequately supported and we will do everything we need to do to keep them growing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from the line of Mr. Wenner. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good afternoon. It's Fabian Wenner from Kepler. Three quick questions, please? Just wanted to confirm that you already include potential impacts from Sandy for the fourth quarter? We know you operate out of Baytown, but you may be impacted by delays and input factors.</p>
          <p>Secondly, just to follow-up on the selling and marketing. Where do you still see major gaps in the distribution networks that you may need to close? And how much will that cost approximately?</p>
          <p>And then third, the capital costs of MaterialScience, the gross cash flow stands at &#x20AC;730 million after nine months and that's versus &#x20AC;10.5 billion of capital invested. Are you confident to cover that cost of capital this year for the division? And if not, how does the Board think about this issue going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fabian, would you mind repeating the second question? We didn't get it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. That was just a follow-up on the selling and marketing. Where do you &#x2013; where in your distribution network do you still see major gaps that you need to close and how much will that cost approximately, to infrastructure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Pharma?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think across the Group, really, because you also said that in CropScience you're building up infrastructure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. So on the impact of Sandy, you know, it's hard to say. It's very early, but I think the good news is we do not have very large manufacturing facilities on the Northeast side of the United States. We have a very important one in Berkeley on the West Coast, Cogenate. We have a very important one, of course, for MaterialScience in Texas. We have one in the Midwest, in Kansas.</p>
          <p>So &#x2013; but nothing really big and therefore from a disruption &#x2013; from a production point of view, we're really not that nervous. It's very hard to generically answer your question with respect to no commercial presence. I think in general we have very good commercial coverage, but of course, this wonderful pipeline that we are introducing in Pharma requires a very, very dedicated new sales and marketing capability that is incremental to what we already have and it's also an incremental sales opportunity. So very justified.</p>
          <p>And I would say on the CropSciences side, with the growth that the CropSciences industry is experiencing in Latin America, of course, that's an area where incremental commercial resources are very much required and we're investing there significantly. Then on the capital cost of MaterialScience, I would like to ask Patrick Thomas to answer that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Fabian, I think the way to look at this is that at the moment, we're running very close to the cost of capital. As we came out of the recession, we've been at or close to that cost of capital for the last couple of years.</p>
          <p>And looking forward, of course, we now have the investments we've already made over the last five years, particularly in China to now fill up in terms of our capacity and utilization. So it's rather like us growing into our clothes now, having made a significant level of investment in new capacity in China. For forward-looking, our CapEx over the next three years will run pretty much at depreciation level. So I think you'll see that recovery over the next 18 months to above the cost of capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Fabian. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Race. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, team. This is Tim Race here from Deutsche Bank. A few questions. First, on CropScience pricing, I know I ask this all the time, but in terms of the price element that we see, it seems to be relatively low compared to peers. Is this due to the mix effect not quite being captured in what you class as price? Or is this that you're actually going for a volume strategy these days? And maybe a comment on how you expect price to look going forward.</p>
          <p>Then a question just on the tax rate outlook. In your guidance, you've lowered the tax rate for this year. I presume this is due to the one-off items and the YAZ settlements, could &#x2013; if you could just explain on that, but also what you expect going forward. Should we expect a lower level?</p>
          <p>And then maybe just on the Pharma side, on Alpharadin, could you just give me some &#x2013; a progress report on your regulatory submission there. Are we still confident for 2012? And I'll leave it there. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Sandy, pricing in Crop.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, thanks for the question. Yes, we've tried to explain this. The &#x2013; we're actually pretty satisfied with our price impact in the third quarter and also what we're seeing in terms of our ability to take price in the fourth quarter and as we're preparing for 2013. And as you said, the impact for us, to a large degree, it is because we have so many new products that are not incorporated in the base business price effect, which has positive pricing associated with them, so there's a mix effect.</p>
          <p>We absolutely are not driving a volume strategy. The business has continued to drive a strategy that's focused on providing meaningful innovation to our customers and we're seeing very high demand for those products, because they do have meaningful innovation. So the business has not shifted to a volume strategy and there's no plan for the business to shift to a volume strategy over the next number of years. We're investing heavily in new plant and equipment because of the ability to drive products &#x2013; innovative products that are actually being desired across the globe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Sandy. So tax rate outlook, Werner?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Tim, your assumption is correct. We have lowered our tax guide &#x2013; our tax rate guidance on the back of the significant special charges, which comes with a very high tax rate in the U.S., and thus created a bigger than average deferred tax asset.</p>
          <p>For the future, I'm not in a position to give you guidance on what our ETR is going to look like in 2013 and following. Yet I will say, that as part of our tax strategy, we are working diligently and quite successfully towards lowering our overall ETR going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you and then, J&#xF6;rg, Alpharadin progress?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I am happy to confirm that we have made significant progress together with our partner in the last few weeks and months. We have completed the production runs &#x2013; the first validation runs on the production line, three of them, and the product is now in stability. So we are confident that we can make the first submissions before the end of the year as we indicated all along.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Mr. Baum. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, it's Andrew Baum from Citi. Couple of questions, please. A little while ago you outlined a number of products, which you classified as billion dollar opportunities. You held back from committing, obviously, quite ahead of the data. I would assume that you're happy to put it within that space, but if you could confirm or discuss?</p>
          <p>And then second, it was addressed, the potential downside risk from Sandy, whilst acknowledging the devastation the hurricane is causing, how do you think your demand patterns could be impacted looking at the current trajectory?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, let's talk about the billion opportunity for riociguat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Essentially, I have nothing to add to what I said earlier where I indicated that we believe that there is a &#x20AC;500 million plus opportunity, especially for CTEPH. I also left the door open a little bit for higher sales by indicating that there may be other indications to come in the mid-term, but I believe at the moment, we'll stick to the exceeding &#x20AC;500 million opportunity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just, Andrew, I'll say what I said before as well about the hurricane Sandy. From a demand point of view, I don't know. I don't really know how serious it really is because we have been preparing for this conference call all morning, so we haven't been watching TV. We'll have to see. Yeah, it's really too early to tell, but we'll see. Hard to say anything about it at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Leuchten. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Mike Leuchten from Barclays. Two questions, please. One, on the medium-term outlook in Consumer Health; you've guided here for a margin target of around 25% by 2014. Given the acquisitions that you've announced in the recent past, is that guidance still something you feel comfortable with? Or should we disregard it at this point in time?</p>
          <p>And then the second question on Xarelto, is there any color you can give us on the contribution by indication in the markets where you've launched? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Your Consumer Health margin development...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For me, given the current situation, there is no reason to make any changes to our forecast we have given earlier. I mean as you heard, we believe that Schiff is going to be accretive as of 2014. We also believe that the investment needs that we still see for significant emerging markets in consumers like China, Russia, and Brazil, we are making now &#x2013; will pay off in the mid-term. So overall, still confident and Consumer &#x2013; that Consumer Health is going to achieve those market &#x2013; margin targets.</p>
          <p>Now, regarding Xarelto, not quite sure whether the direction of the question is margin contribution in the individual regions, that's something I cannot comment on. What I'm happy to comment on is, progress that we are making in these individual regions. And overall, as Marijn pointed out, so far, we are very happy with the performance of Xarelto; assuming that we will over-achieve our target for the this year. I mean we gave guidance of &#x20AC;270 million, we hope that it's going to be more by the end of the year.</p>
          <p>And that is to a large extent driven by the excellent performance that we still see in Germany where we are now at 23.5% market share, which keeps on growing. I mean it's really marvelous how this product develops in Germany. We are not &#x2013; still not so happy with the performance in Japan where we are now at a market share of around 4%.</p>
          <p>It's getting little bit better week after week, but overall, we really need to get this two-week prescription limitation lifted early next year to see a significant difference.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, we are very happy with the performance in Latin America. In Brazil, we are at a market share of almost 22%. We are ahead of dabigatran by now, which we are certainly &#x2013; or my colleagues in Brazil are certainly very proud of. And we also beat Boehringer in Mexico where we have a market share of over 23% as well. So Latin America, we are quite happy.</p>
          <p>In Canada, we keep on increasing market share. We are now at around 7% and we also see that Canada is a little bit like the U.S. We have the highest share now of new-to-brand patients. And you'll remember, in the U.S., this was also an early indicator that we get closer to dabigatran. It's the same in Canada; we are beating them in that measure. However, we still have, warfarin and new-to-brand patients of over 50%. So it's still a tough nut to crack, likely &#x2013; like the situation in the U.S. where warfarin is even &#x2013; at more than 70% of new-to-drug patients.</p>
          <p>In the U.S. we and our partner J&amp;J, I believe, shares this level of confidence. We keep on growing market share week after week. We are now at above 9%. So that's pretty good as well.</p>
          <p>And then I come to the last two countries &#x2013; or three countries, which is the U.K., France, and Spain. As you know, U.K. uptake has been slow and still is. We are still like the dabigatran at a range of around 2% to 3%. Whereas in France, we are doing much better, but it's very early days; we are now at a market share of 6% to 7%. And when we look at Spain, difficult country, market share is a little bit below that; but it's really, really early days. So overall, we are quite happy with the performance so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Vosser. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Richard Vosser from JPMorgan. Thanks for taking my questions. A couple on CropScience to start with. Just wondering, on the visibility you have, on what protection &#x2013; crop protection products might have been left over with the farmer from the 2012 season given the drought? And whether you see any impact on this on next year's North American season?</p>
          <p>And secondly on CropScience, I think your run rate for local currency growth going out of Q3 is 13%. Just wondering how that tallies with the 10% growth for the full year? What uncertainties should we see in the Latin American season, which is potentially strong given, again, the drought in North America?</p>
          <p>Then a quick accounting question, just on the Schiff's acquisition, just what proportion of the goodwill would be intangibles and therefore going through as amortization? Would it be all of the sort of roughly &#x20AC;750 million above the net asset value or what sort of proportion would that be? If you could give us a &#x2013; some help there that would be great.</p>
          <p>And then finally on MaterialScience, just some perspectives on whether you'll be able to pass through any price rises in the fourth quarter or early into 2013 given the demand picture and the high raw material price &#x2013; the high benzene price at the moment? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sandy, start with visibility on inventories of crop protection products in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's a great question and what we &#x2013; the visibility that we have at the moment is that inventory levels for insecticides and herbicides are relatively normal, which is &#x2013; given the nature of the drought, that makes a lot of sense. The one place where we're still trying to understand and look at with customers is their truing up and giving us a better sense of it is the fungicides in the channel. For us at BCS, we actually have relatively normal channel inventories, and part of that is because of our portfolio and when the product actually got on the ground in many parts of the Midwest before the drought really hit. So the question for 2013 is really how much is in the channel of our competitors and how the customers are going to be thinking about that in 2013. But generally speaking, the rest of the channel inventories are pretty normal for this time of the year.</p>
          <p>You also had a second question having to do with looking at our run rate and looking at the Latin American season and through the end of the year. At the moment, the Latin American season is running well, and we're pleased with our performance and the uptake of our products. And so at the moment, things look like they're going quite well. The fourth quarter for us, as you know, is the Latin American-dominated season, but in addition to that, there is some question about early purchasing in some key markets in places like Japan, North America and parts of Europe. And so that will also have an impact on the fourth quarter and how we actually end the year. But we're feeling pretty good about the Latin American season at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Then on the financials for Schiff, Werner <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:00)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That's a very good question. And while we are done with signing, we are not done with purchase price allocation at this point in time yet. I will say to give you an order of magnitude, if you just look at the amortization of trademarks, it's going to be somewhere in the mid-double digits, yeah? So some will call it between &#x20AC;30 million and &#x20AC;45 million in all likelihood. But again, very early days because no such thing like purchase price allocation has been performed at this point in time. It's an educated guess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, BMS pricing Q4, Q1 with respect to benzene pricing as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Richard. I'll have to do this a little bit by sectors because the story is a little bit different by each sector. If I look in polyurethanes then on the MDI streams we have seen prices rising during quarter three. We expect that to continue and hold in quarter four for a number of reasons. There's been a number of plants that have been unreliable or under scheduled maintenance. And that continues into quarter four with Yantai Wanhua announcing a 200,000 ton unit which will be out for more than four weeks during the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>The other thing that's happening in China which is supporting prices is there's a level of tension between China and Japan which is causing some of the imports from Japan to be not successful. The other thing is with raw material prices being higher, of course, there's a strong pressure on pushing out the MDI price.</p>
          <p>On TDI, there's been a recent announcement published at Zachem, the Polish producer will close its facility in Central Europe. That is certainly pushing prices up in the European region as people are concerned about supply availability. In Asia, supply has been slightly more fluid and more matched to market and to market growth. On polyether polyols, then we're seeing pretty much feedstock prices being passed on in both directions because we've actually seen some falling propylene prices which have caused a bit of a run on polyether polyol prices. But there the margin has been pretty much protected.</p>
          <p>In polycarbonates, we see a more complex picture. Certainly in our results, you can see a pricing effect which is caused to a very large degree by mix. The main sectors in polycarbonates that are under pressure at the moment in terms of demand are the automotive and more particularly the electronic sector where demand has reduced significantly during quarter three. Normally, we would expect a pickup at the end of quarter three in polycarbonate demand for electronics as you see the pre-stocking before Christmas coming in for domestic electronic devices, flat screen TVs, laptops, and tablets. That just hasn't happened this year. There's a number of concerns there that either that the normal pre-Christmas peak is moving later or it's not happening at all.</p>
          <p>Now, those are generally higher-priced, more-sophisticated markets using compounded material. And when you reduce your sales in that segment, then the mix effect on price is quite significant, because the other large segments of optical data storage and construction tend to dominate the price mix at a much lower level. So there's a bit of a price mix going on which I suspect will roll on to the fourth quarter. We'll see whether the electronics industry picks up or not, but at the moment, we haven't really seen any pickup at all, which normally happen during August through into September. And it was just missing altogether. Automotive is surprisingly strong for us at the moment, given all the news from automotive producers. We see automotive from a carpet &#x2013; from a polyurethane position as relatively strong compared to the announcements that you've seen from the industry. And also polycarbonate, but again, that's driven by us primarily supplying the high-end cars.</p>
          <p>And for example, in China, we've seen a growth in market share of the foreign direct invested brands, where we have a disproportionately high share and a loss of share with the Chinese national brands. So it's a mixed picture, different by segment. But our ambition is to hold onto prices and of course, recover raw material price increases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, Patrick. Take the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Gr&#xFC;ten. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you. Lutz Gr&#xFC;ten, Commerzbank. Two follow-up questions. One on the CropScience and the cost progression program. You have mentioned that you feel good about the achievements out of the third quarter. Could you please quantify your feelings regarding what was achieved on cost cutting so far in 2012? And the second question regarding polycarbonates. You just stated that the pre-stocking ahead of Christmas might not happen. What's the reach of the current inventory &#x2013; inventories with your clients, with your most important customers? Are we talking about a pickup in volumes then at the beginning of Q1 next year? Or could this be also end of next &#x2013; end of the first quarter next year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Sandy, can you quantify your feelings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Quantify my feelings, it's a great question. Thank you. So I'll give you some &#x2013; just give you some sense of where we are on it. As you know, we said in end of 2010, that over a two-year period of time until the end of 2012, we would take &#x20AC;265 million of structural costs out of the business. We're ahead of that plan, so we will be close to &#x20AC;300 million by the time we're done at the end of this year. So that has helped us significantly also in terms of our ability to invest in some of the important emerging growth markets such as Brazil with more marketing and sales and commercial talent that Marijn mentioned. But if you look at our -the proportion of our cost progression, so for example, in the third quarter relative to third quarter last year, we saw one point improvement in our costs as a percentage of sales. So that gives you some sense of even though we're investing behind growth, we're doing it with better leverage on the cost line as well as on the marketing and sales line.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, the reason why the &#x2013; even though we saw improvement in our EBIT, it looks less than you might have anticipated is because there were some very small adjustments on other income and expenses around trade income shifting, as well as some costs related to the acquisitions and some of the other things that Marijn mentioned were that &#x2013; or some of which is allocated down to the CropScience business. So, hopefully that gives you some sense of some quantifications about feeling good about where we are in the cost position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, indeed. It's very helpful and to all the best. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, Patrick, polycarbonate inventories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, stock levels are relatively low with most of our direct customers, and that's been a progression over the last two years really post-crisis. People have learned to run with much lower inventory levels. The big unknown we have particularly with traders, roughly 30% of the polycarbonate market is now in China where traders are extremely active, and there are some industry estimates that there could be 100,000 or 200,000 tons of material sitting in the system, which is actually managed by traders where there's almost no visibility on their activities.</p>
          <p>I think overall, clearly there was a lot of buildup in capacity, and you'll have seen some public statements from our other major competitor that they have been very aggressive on the volume strategy. We can see that overall, because market growth numbers we're getting over the first three quarters are relatively high and support the long-term growth rate of 6% in polycarbonates. So I think that the problem is more to do with consumer demand, particularly around the electronics sector, which for us is an important sector, because it is very high value-added specialty compounds. And if that picks up towards the end of the year, it will pick up very quickly because my guess is the inventory levels are very low at the moment in that segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Faitz. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Christian Faitz from Macquarie. Thanks for taking my question. Two small questions. First of all also on the U.S. drought, you are one of the major cotton players. Can you talk about your reproduction facilities in cotton seeds? Have they been affected by U.S. drought, i.e. are you able to deliver next year in terms of seed reproduction?</p>
          <p>And then second of all, MaterialScience, Patrick, you already mentioned a couple of key trends for a few key customer industries. Can you talk about the rest of your customer industries, which are important to you? For example, furniture, shoes, et cetera. What's happening there? What do you see there, especially out of China? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So cotton production &#x2013; cotton seed production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, cotton seed production. So actually we haven't had any issues in the last 12 months as it relates to cotton seed production in the United States, because the drought was actually &#x2013; you may remember over the last couple of years, the issue of drought in cotton was two years ago in the Western part of Texas where there's a lot of cotton seed production. So last &#x2013; this past year season, our cotton seed production happens around a large swath across the bottom part of the United States, which was much less affected by drought. The issue that is more relevant than for cotton is how many acres are planted because as the soybean prices went up as much as they did, a lot of farmers started making choices to plant soybeans instead of cotton in 2012. So there were about &#x2013; we don't know the exact number, but 1.5/1 million less acres of cotton planted in 2012 to be grown for production than in the prior year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:45)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we're not impacted by the drought as it relates to our cotton production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you see that for 2013 as well that trends soy, for cotton simply because if you look at soy and cotton prices, that's &#x2013; that trend would be <mark type="ph" /> suggested (58:56)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So what's interesting is, we're seeing it a little bit in Brazil at the moment. And so there are choices being made of &#x2013; with farmers of &#x2013; planting their second season, making choices between soy and cotton. Some of them are still planting cotton because they've got significant infrastructure in place in there. If you look at the economics of it, they're making bets on cotton versus soybeans. But we have seen a slight decline in the &#x2013; in this growing season in the Southern Hemisphere in cotton. It's way too early to tell what's going to happen in the planting season next year because farmers aren't making those decisions yet. It's too early in the season for the U.S. next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then BMS, Patrick, other markets, furniture, shoes, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Christian. The storyline really is partly driven by the construction industry. So what we see at the moment is with a slight pickup in construction in the U.S. which may, following the current disaster, lead to an even greater pickup in construction activity, which always is post-bad weather, a big industry driver in the U.S. We see the principle driver as insulation and also the CARB regulations in the U.S. driving the polyurethane rigid foam insulation business. And to some extent now also in China, some of the provinces in China have now approved polyurethane for building standards, which makes an increased market opportunity there. So that's the construction industry.</p>
          <p>If we fit the furniture industry, furniture follows on from construction, and the push-down of the government on the housing bubble in China has certainly started to roll through into the furniture industry as well. We actually see the furniture industry in APAC dropping a little bit, compensated interestingly by NAFTA and Europe where we're seeing overall a world increase in furniture demand, so that drives particularly our TDI business. So it's quite an interesting picture, not quite what you would expect where the roles of the world regions have been reversed somewhat.</p>
          <p>In the footwear industry, we're seeing the industry move more than anything else. It's still continuing to grow rapidly. The move, though, is from China where labor costs are too high for the industry, even in Western China. And now you're seeing the whole footwear industry move south down into the ASEAN countries, into Cambodia, Laos, Vietnam, Indonesia, as people search for much, much lower labor costs, because labor is such a high component for the footwear industry. So hopefully that helps give a bit more color as to what's going on. Thank you, Christian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. K&#xF6;hler. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. It's Ronald K&#xF6;hler from MainFirst. I hope I will finish this. First question is actually on Consumer Health. You're targeting a high single-digit EBITDA growth for the full year. After nine months you had &#x20AC;3.2 million though there must be obviously a significant acceleration in the fourth quarter on EBITDA growth, if you just could give a little bit of flavor on what is the driver on that Consumer Health acceleration?</p>
          <p>The second point, on the Schiff acquisition, you guide for &#x20AC;0.03 earnings accretive on adjusted earnings, &#x20AC;0.02 dilutive on reported. So the &#x20AC;0.05 difference, how is the rough split? How much is the, let's say, kind of restructuring cost and how much is amortization as a &#x2013; just as a rough guidance in that &#x20AC;0.05? Marijn, you actually talked about the weakening trends during the quarter, if I rightly catch that. Can you a little bit elaborate on that, what the implication and potentially also the kind of outlook with what we recently saw on October?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let's start with Consumer Health and EBITDA growth for the year versus the first nine months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So traditionally, in Consumer Health, the fourth quarter is a very promotion and information-heavy quarter. So significant P&amp;I costs are normally spent in the fourth quarter. And that, of course, is, let's say, flexible. We also had in the first nine months of this year significant infrastructure investments, especially also in China. And in Brazil where we have added significant capacities, both of these markets have been relatively weak in Consumer Health over the last five, six years. We didn't see much growth, for example, in Brazil for three consecutive years. And we have now invested to actually accelerate growth there. The same applies to China where we have added significant capacities to go into new cities, which we haven't been active so far.</p>
          <p>Essentially, we are doing a little bit of what we have been doing with Pharma over the last few years. That has costed us some money in the last nine months and that together with, let's say, discipline in spending for the fourth quarter will drive margins up in the fourth quarter. And I hope that there is still a good chance to achieve the guidance for this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then the difference between accretion and dilution from a core EPS and a normal EPS point of view &#x20AC;0.05, Werner?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ronald, in terms of what are the drivers, your assumption is correct. It's actually restructuring, integration, and also the effects from the inventory step-up, which we would see subsequent to the acquisitions further details in terms of <mark type="ph" /> cleaning it up (65:24) are not available.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then I just want to make a clarification on the weakening trends I was talking about. This was in the context of BMS within the quarter. So from July to August to September and I'm going to ask Patrick to elaborate on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you, Ron. The whole sequence of seasonality during the third quarter is usually driven by polycarbonates, seeing their pre-Christmas demand for the electronics sector, as I mentioned earlier. And because that didn't come along, we actually saw the first couple of months of the quarter very strong. And then in the third month of the quarter, clearly a deviation from our expectation, and that's really what Marijn was referring to. As we saw that weakening trend, it was more flat line rather than weak. As we move into quarter four, we see the normal seasonality.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Wendorff. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Daniel Wendorff from Commerzbank. And thanks for taking my questions. Two are remaining, starting off with a follow-up question on riociguat. I'm not going to ask about the market potential. And again, however, one question I have and that is if you want to exploit the more than &#x20AC;500 million market opportunity, and also having in mind the competitive landscape in PAH, would you see the products being able to marketing yourself? Or would you look for kind of joint venture or marketing partnership also in light of potential and other indications to follow? And that would be my first question.</p>
          <p>And second question on Glucobay, which is developing very nicely this year year-to-date driven by China, if I understand that right during the presentation. Is that only a one-off effect we are going to see this year or would you see this trend to continue also in light of the changes in lifestyles in that country? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, J&#xF6;rg?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, regarding riociguat, I mean, when you follow the field, you of course know that it's a little bit of a complicated picture. Also with regard to potentially new competitors coming up. When you compare the clinical data, I believe that riociguat has an absolutely competitive profile even in PAH. We believe that the product, given its speciality nature, can be handled by ourselves adequately. So for the time being, we do not intend to team up with anybody. We believe that we can build enough necessary infrastructure to distribute and market this product adequately. I believe, as you know, it's an area where the clinical data and the performance &#x2013; the clinical performance of the product is extremely important. And here, I believe, we have &#x2013; with what we have been showing so far with rio, we have a very, very good basis.</p>
          <p>Regarding Glucobay, yes, we have a very good year in China. As you also know, China, you are never completely sure how pricing is developing and that obviously has a significant impact on all primary care products. So we are happy to see the good performance of Glucobay for this year. It's a little bit difficult to predict how it's going to develop next year. I would not be surprised if you see some price cuts here. On the other hand, we do still have significant expansion plans for China. So I believe that we will continue to see a good performance of Glucobay, maybe not at the same extraordinary level in this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Heine. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. This is Andreas Heine from Barclays. One question on MaterialScience and one on the seed business. In MaterialScience, if I look forward to the fourth quarter and look on the guidance, it would be fulfilled if you earn in the fourth quarter only half what you have earned in the third quarter. I do understand these trends you have described, but is the seasonality and the impact of polycarbonate that strong, that the seasonality can be that harsh looking forward in the fourth quarter. And on seed, I would like to understand what is the driver behind the 39% increase especially in canola? I guess it has nothing to do with acreage, so it has to be something else. These are my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, yeah. On MaterialScience, I don't think you're stating the fact completely in terms of what we need in the fourth quarter. But I...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'd just repeat the guidance we've given I think on quarter four. I don't think &#x2013; normally we see construction holidays. We see the construction industry slow down. We see seasonal demand slow down around some of the other sectors. So quarter four is always a weaker quarter than the other three but we expect to be significantly higher adjusted EBITDA than last time around because quarter four last year was particularly weak in terms of earnings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay. Then on seeds, 39% in canola.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the third quarter is a funny quarter. So I think if you're asking a question about canola, we should look at it for the first nine months because most of the business in canola is done in the second quarter. So for the nine-month period, the year-over-year performance was close to 40%, and that actually was a combination of market share gains as well as acreage gains. So there were more acres planted because Canada, in particular, did not have issues with flooding, which they've had in prior years. So it's a combination of both market share gains, as well as slightly higher planting, particularly in Canada but also in the northern parts of the United States. So the business performed very well on both dimensions this past year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Spengler. Please state your name, company name, followed by your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Peter Spengler, DZ Bank. Good day, ladies and gentlemen. I have a question on the Schiff acquisition. It seems to me that it was not an opportunistic acquisition. So how did Schiff qualify to make it to the top of your shortlist? And what makes those four brands you mentioned so special to Bayer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll take that question. I mean we have &#x2013; Schiff has been on our radar screen for a while, particularly because of the fact that they are active in the nutritional supplement part of the business where we would like to strengthen our portfolio. In the U.S., we have a number of vitamin products like One-A-Day and Berocca, and Flintstones for children, and Schiff is a nice opportunity to augment the nutritional supplements. So that's one part of why we are interested in terms of the complementary portfolio. It's also sort of a bite-size acquisition, if I can say it that way. It's not huge but it's not tiny either, and it has four really very good brands &#x2013; recognizable brands in the United States that we think we can build on within the U.S., but also outside of the U.S. So altogether, no. Schiff was not for sale but we developed an interest and had good conversations and that led to this announcement today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Cespedes. Please state your name, company name, followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Thank you for taking my question. Florent Cespedes, Exane BNP Paribas. A few quick ones on HealthCare. First, on EYLEA, can you tell us how you will position EYLEA against Lucentis? How do you see the ramp-up? And do you believe that this launch could also expand the use of approved drugs versus off-label use of Avastin in this space? Secondly, on BETASERON, could we have some details, some color on where you see the pressure and which countries? And any chance from the trend in Q3, any idea for next year?</p>
          <p>And the last on the M&amp;A side for the HealthCare division, which are the areas in HealthCare where you believe you have a &#x2013; you are subscale and where you still see some opportunity for acquisitions? And could you decide to divest a division which is subscale even if you don't have any opportunity immediately available? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So let's start with EYLEA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as you know the position of EYLEA hasn't changed over the last few weeks and months. It's always been that it's on a use need for injection. Given the same level of efficacy than the major competitor, Lucentis. That is a positioning that actually worked quite well in the U.S. as you can see with the &#x2013; what is it now? &#x20AC;800 million guidance for the first year after introduction of the product in the U.S. So this seems to fly. Now, when you then look at where the patients are coming from, there is actually &#x2013; obviously, a significant percentage of patients are new patients. But they also switches out of Lucentis and out of Avastin, which is a positive surprise. We might not have expected to see significant switches out of Avastin but it seems to be the case.</p>
          <p>So overall, there's no reason to believe that in the rest of the world the situation would be drastically different. Obviously, as you know, I mean country by country, there are different rules of reimbursement and different use of Avastin, and people stick to the label and they don't, that differs significantly country by country. And we'll have to see how it works out. But overall, I would expect that the positioning of less weaker dosing at the same level, at least the same level of efficacy will also apply in the rest of the world.</p>
          <p>Now, with regard to BETASERON, yes, I think we have been guiding already earlier this year that the beginning of the year, what was particularly strong mainly based on the number of one-time effects, also some accruals that we took there result this year. We also saw significant impact of the increased pricing in the U.S. But we also stated that the underlying trends with BETASERON volume-wise is continuing to be negative, and that is going to be the case now in the third quarter and the fourth quarter, which also explains the numbers in the fourth &#x2013; in the third quarter. Now, with regard to next year, it is our expectation that we will see the trends that we saw last year. And now we'll see in the second half that, that trend is continuing, which is a mid single-digit decline for the BETASERON print. And Marijn, you take the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I will just comment on the M&amp;A strategy really quickly. I mean our strategy is to drive very aggressively organic growth, particularly with new products. And I think we're very successfully doing that, augmented by bolt-on acquisitions and Schiff is an example of it. Teva is an example of it. AgraQuest is an example of that. We've done an additional three seeds acquisition, smaller seeds acquisitions in the last year and a half. And I think when you look at those acquisitions and which areas they will fall, that's a good indication of where our interest is also going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Are there any other questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, Mr. Rosar, there are no further questions at this time. Please continue with any other points you wish to raise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you, Cleo. Ladies and gentlemen, also on behalf of my colleagues, I'd like to thank you for being with us on the call and say thank you for your questions. We are now saying good-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the third quarter 2012 results investor and analyst conference call of Bayer AG. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>