<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1101232" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-02-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>810</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Dr. Alexander Rosar, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Werner Wenning, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="3">Ronald K&#xF6;hler</participant>
      <participant id="4">Werner Wenning</participant>
      <participant id="5">Arthur Higgins</participant>
      <participant id="6">Werner Winning</participant>
      <participant id="7">Patrick Thomas</participant>
      <participant id="8">Michael Leuchten</participant>
      <participant id="9">Neil Taylor</participant>
      <participant id="10">Friedrich Berschauer</participant>
      <participant id="11">Richard Vosser</participant>
      <participant id="12">Andrew Stott</participant>
      <participant id="13">Martin Brunninger</participant>
      <participant id="14">Paul Walsh</participant>
      <participant id="15">Andrew Benson</participant>
      <participant id="16">Sachin Jain</participant>
      <participant id="17">Florent Cespedes</participant>
      <participant id="18">Christian Faitz</participant>
      <participant id="19">Jean de Watteville</participant>
      <participant id="20">Paul Major</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Full Year and Fourth Quarter 2007 Results Conference Call of Bayer AG for investors and analysts on the 28th of February, 2008. Throughout today's recorded presentation, all participants will be in a listen-only mode. The presentation will be followed by a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Mr. Alexander Rosar, Head of Investor Relations of Bayer AG. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Anna. Good afternoon, everybody; happy to have you all on the call. During this call, we will review our Q4 financial results that were released earlier this morning.</p>
          <p>With us on the call today are: our CEO, Werner Wenning; our CFO, Klaus K&#xFC;hn. And the CEOs from our subgroups: Arthur Higgins from HealthCare; Friedrich Berschauer from CropScience; and Patrick Thomas from MaterialScience.</p>
          <p>Before handing over to Mr. Wenning for his presentation, I'd like to draw your attention to the forward-looking statements wordings which governs our call. Thank you. Mr. Wenning?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Ladies and gentlemen, good afternoon; we hope you are all well and thank you for joining us.</p>
          <p>The scope of today's call is to review and discuss our Q4 and full year 2007 numbers, and of course, our guidance for 2008 and beyond. I assume that you already analyze our statements and briefing documents, so I will concentrate on putting our numbers into the context of the overall strategy and to 2008 outlook.</p>
          <p>At Bayer, we are all focused on executing our proven strategy and delivering on our clearly defined objectives. So what were our most important execution priorities in 2007? Last year, we set out to further improve the profitability of our group; to successfully integrate Schering and built a world leading specialty Pharma business; to further strengthen HealthCare, keeping the integration of Schering at the top of the agenda; to develop new growth opportunities for all our businesses; and to deleverage our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>We set ourselves clear financial targets and specific objectives; namely to grow group sales by 5%, after adjusting for portfolio and currency changes, and to slightly improve the underlying EBITDA margin. The better-than-planned performance in the majority of our businesses allowed us to upgrade the EBITDA margin target twice in the course of the year. Last update we've shown in parenthesis on this slide.</p>
          <p>We also provided clear financial objectives for our subgroups. Our target for our net debt reduction was 35 at 4 to 4.5 billion, and we were able to raise this target too during the year. We were committed to a dividend proposal of between 30 and 40% of core EPS.</p>
          <p>The new Pharma strategy and combined pipeline was announced at the HealthCare Investor Conference in June. And the update on Xarelto liver safety, during our ASH Conference Call, in December.</p>
          <p>Today, we are pleased to say that we have achieved our targets in 2007, and in most cases exceeded even our upgraded targets. We expanded group sales by 6%, if adjusted for portfolio and currency changes, which is fully in line with our November guidance. Thanks to the chart rise in earnings, the underlying EBITDA margin for the group improved to 20.9%, exceeding our Q3 guidance update. All our subgroups consistently performed strongly in their markets, and achieved or exceeded our communicated targets.</p>
          <p>The underlying EBITDA margin for HealthCare came in at 25.6% above guidance. At CropScience, we generated a margin of 22.7%, a gain above guidance. Due to the uncertain business environments and highly volatile raw material prices, we decided to formulate quarterly EBITDA targets for MaterialScience, and indeed, we have not missed a single quarterly objective.</p>
          <p>We also can rightly claim that MaterialScience generated significant value during 2007. In Europe, this ratifying performance, the dividends we will propose to the annual stockholders' meeting is 1 euro and 35 cents per share. This is 35% above the previous year and corresponds to a payout ratio of 36% of core earnings per share. The significant increase in the dividend underscores the optimism and the confidence we have about the future earning power of the group.</p>
          <p>Let's also briefly look at our Q4 numbers. Overall, Q4 was a pretty solid finish to a successful year. Group sales came in at roughly 8 billion, an increase of almost 5% if adjusted for portfolio and currency changes. All subgroups contributed to the increase. At Pharma, sales advanced by 2% if adjusted for portfolio and currency against a very strong prior year quarter. Roughly 80 million of business in the quarter was lost due to the cessation of the plasma distribution, the timing of Helixate shipments to CSL, and the absence of a Cipro governmental deal which was included in the previous year quarter. Based from the overall Pharma business of 2.7 billion, that equates to 3 percentage points lost growth.</p>
          <p>The majority of our key brands performed strongly in the quarter. The Yasmin family, Avelox, Mirena, and Nexavar all showed significant double digit growth. Betaferon sales advanced 4% driven by a strong performance in Europe. In the U.S., we were able to stabilize the market share in the second half.</p>
          <p>Sales of Kogenate however were somewhat down due to, as already mentioned, lower shipments of Helixate. Nevertheless our top 15 pharma brands collectively grew by almost 7% if adjusted for currency changes and looking at our pharma business in the beginning of the year, we see that business gained momentum making us confident of growth in line with the market in 2008.</p>
          <p>During 2007, our Consumer Health segment really became a growth engine for our business. Currency and portfolio-adjusted, Q4 sales advanced 12% driven by all units and brands. CropScience grew 5% in the quarter, if adjusted for portfolio and currency changes. This gratifying growth was driven by advances in our seed treatment and BioScience businesses.</p>
          <p>In France, we observed a certain phasing of the normal season mainly as a result of a change in the French eco-tax system. We now expect to see a business shift in the range of 30 to 40 billion from the fourth quarter '07 into the first quarter of '08.</p>
          <p>Adjusted sales for MaterialScience increased by 6% mainly driven by higher volumes. Selling prices added 2 percentage points to the increase. Especially strong growth was reported in our polycarbonate, TDI, and coating raw materials units.</p>
          <p>Underlying EBITDA of the Bayer Group rose by 13%, and underlying EBIT by 24% due to higher earnings contributions from all our subgroups. Special charges of 390 million in the quarter were higher than planned, mainly due to higher provisions for our legal reserves and the suspension of Trasylol.</p>
          <p>The non-operating result of minus &#x20AC;179 million contained a one-time currency gain of approximately 50 million in connection with financing activities. Income taxes were probably somewhat higher than many of you anticipated. This was entirely due to one-time tax effects. Last year's numbers included a tax gain of 200 million whereas this year's number included a one-time tax provision of 40 million for future dividend payments to optimize our financial structures according to the new tax regulation in Germany. Cash taxes however were at last year's level.</p>
          <p>Core earnings per share advanced nicely over prior year quarter to $0.71. Overall the positive upward trend we have registered initiating our transformation process in 2002 continued in 2007; since then we have reported year-on-year improvements in underlying EBIT in 20 consecutive quarters.</p>
          <p>This chart compares the sales, underlying EBIT and EBITDA margins in 2002 and 2007. For the group as a whole, we have raised underlying EBIT by a factor of more than five and improved the EBITDA margin by 9 percentage points. But even more importantly, we have not missed out on a single objective at the group level during this time.</p>
          <p>The upward trend in our numbers was driven by the consistent strong performance in all of our businesses. Over this period, we have built HealthCare from a 9 billion to an almost 15 billion business, more than tripled underlying EBIT and improved the underlying EBITDA margin from 14 to 26%.</p>
          <p>Tremendous progress we also achieved in our CropScience business, as a margin improvement from 11 to 23% over the same period. Please allow me to compare our MaterialScience business with the entire industrial franchisee of Bayer in the year 2002. Despite 4 billion lower sales, underlying EBIT has almost doubled, and the margin has improved from 12% to 15%, which I think is quite an impressive increase.</p>
          <p>Today, we are consistently earning premiums of our cost of capital despite the significant increase in capital invested following the share and acquisition. In 2007, the cash flow return on investment came to 12.2%, slightly above the previous year. This graphic shows use of minimum returns required to cover the cost of capital and reproduction at the CFR hurdles. The current performance is displayed into the specific years with a darker part of the columns symbolizing the premium we earned over the minimum return requirement.</p>
          <p>In 2007, the cash value added amounted to 749 million euros. Ladies and gentlemen, we are convinced that we have established a firm basis for continued performance improvement and we remain committed to executing our clear strategy focusing on delivering growth and performance, and improving our portfolios. This will remain our key priorities also during 2008.</p>
          <p>So what are our specific financial targets for 2008 and beyond? In 2008, we aimed to raise group sales by about 5% after portfolio and currency changes, and are planning to further increase underlying EBITDA and the underlying EBITDA margins. The good start into 2008 confirms our expectations.</p>
          <p>Looking further ahead, we continue to expect further improvements and are targeting an underlying EBITDA margin of over 22% by 2009. Our planning is based on the exchange rate of USD $1.45 to the euro compared to an average rate of 1.37 in 2007. At HealthCare, we intend to grow with or faster than the market in all our divisions in 2008 and to improve the underlying EBITDA margin to approximately 27%. We believe that we can steadily improve on this number and confirm our 2009 target of an underlying EBITDA margin of approximately 28%.</p>
          <p>Contributing to this will be the expansion of our business and the synergies from the sharing integration. We predict a more favorable market environment for our CropScience business in 2008. We aim to grow around 5% after currency adjustments and to raise the underlying EBITDA margin above 23% this year. Going forward, we are targeting further improvements and expect to generate an underlying EBITDA Margin of 25% by 2009 in a normal market environment. MaterialScience plans further volume increases in 2008 and aims to sustain a good value creating earnings level, although probably below 2007. We predict a solid start to the New Year with first quarter EBITDA roughly on par with the fourth quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>With its excellent business portfolio and competitive production structures, we believe that Bayer MaterialScience can generate value even in a difficult market environment of earnings and attractive premium over its capital and asset replacement costs. Under favorable market conditions we plan to generate an underlying EBITDA margin in excess of 18%. We believe that this is again an ambitions yet realistic set of targets. Their achievement is of utmost priority for all of us, and we will work very hard to ensure that the trust you have shown in us and our strategy continues to be justified in the future.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much. We'll now be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, at this time we'll begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> First question comes from Mr. Ronald K&#xF6;hler from MainFirst. Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Yes, Ronald K&#xF6;hler from MainFirst. I have a question to Bayer HealthCare. Your target you've given, I just want to track how far you included any Yasmin to YAZ risk either in the March end target of 27% and/or in the top line growth meaning growing at or above market growth. How much did you include the risk so to say, seeing generics in United States. That's my first question.</p>
          <p>Second question is regarding Betaferon. Actually your competitor Merck announced in November 2007, 9% price increases for Rebif in the United States. Is it a general trend, did you announce also a significant price increase in United States, can you a little bit elaborate here?</p>
          <p>And a third question is regarding Polycarbonate. Obviously, you see very strong volume growth, above 8% in 2007, and nevertheless your pricing power seems to be rather low. You actually announced price increases in November 2007, but according to your results, it seems that that didn't stick in the market. Can you little bit elaborate here about your pricing power and going forward, are any price increases possible in this market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Mr. K&#xF6;hler. I would start with your first question, then Arthur will elaborate on Betaferon, and Patrick will come back to your Polycarbonate related question. About the Barr trial, Yasmin trial of course Mr. K&#xF6;hler, our planning for 2008 assumes that we can defend our adjustment franchise fully in the U.S., and therefore includes the full batch of sales amount for this product of course. In the rent of the negative core division, the rent and the subsequent generic competition in the U.S. of course it will require hard work to achieve this target.</p>
          <p>So in the case we would prefer that you read our HealthCare, in this case, that we are not able to win, we prefer that you read our HealthCare outlook statement more as we are planning to improve underlying EBITDA from 26% last year towards 27% instead of to approximately 27%. In any case we continue to believe that by 2009, HealthCare can achieve its target of approximately 28% underlying EBITDA margin. So now &#x2013; from 25.6 in 2007 to tough 27%, to repeat the guidance again; so Betaferon, Arthur.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ron, I hope that answered your question, and then on the second, on the Betaferon we took on July 3rd, 8% price increase of last year, and on January the 15th of this year a 12.8% price increase. So your observation in respect to price in the U.S. is correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Polycarbonate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ronald your view on Polycarbonate is of course accurate and right, the pricing power unlike the systems segment where pricing power has been very strong, in the materials segment dominated by Polycarbonate, it's been comparatively weak.  Although I would point out, if you look at it quarter-on-quarter you'll see there has been no decline in price.  The year 2007 has been pretty much stactic pricing, and in fact the volumes more than offset the pricing impact year-on-year.</p>
          <p>The big impact in the Polycarbonate world has been the phenol prices which has taken us down by more than 130 million at the EBIT level, and that has been the biggest single effect.  Whereas we've managed to compensate for raw materials in the Polyurethanes business, in Polycarbonates our capacity levels have been too low and the competitive dynamics which you've observed have changed dramatically during the year has made it very difficulty to get the pricing increases to actually follow through.  So I think the way I'd look at it is most of the price increases this year have been to hold the prices steady.  I don't believe it's going to get dramatically better next year because I think the raw material prices will stay relatively at similar levels.  What we've seen so far in the first quarter is the raw material pricing that is not as high as we were initially expecting.  So I think as we look towards 2008, I think Polycarbonates will have a similar performance level.</p>
          <p>I think the difficult thing to understand is the behavior of the new competitors in Polycarbonate, primarily the Sabic operation because certainly where we're seeing the price increases going through, or attempted to go through on our side, we are seeing matching price reductions from our major competitor.  So I think your statement to say that pricing power has been weak in Polycarbonates is perfectly valid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Mr. Michael Leuchten from Deutsche Bank.  Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you.  It's Michael Leuchten from Deutsche.  Two questions for Arthur please.  Arthur, can you help me understand the performance of Nexavar in the U.S., I look at a $43 million in Q4, and $41 million revenue in Q3.  Now I understand the approval only came in November for liver, but given that it is a market where off-label use can happen and given that the SHARP trial was quite an event at ASCO, are there any roadblocks to using Nexavar in liver cancer, and if so, how are you dealing with that going forward?</p>
          <p>And then staying on Nexavar, in the profit share with Onyx, now that non-small cell lung cancer indication has shown a negative result, Onyx was still guiding for 25% increase in the R&amp;D line.  Has your thinking changed to that?  Clearly that's driven by the Phase II trials in metastatic breast.  Are you going to tailor that to the event we've seen?  Are you going to take a more step-wise approach or are you still going to go with the five trials all-in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael thank you for those two questions.  First of all in terms of the performance of Nexavar in the U.S. in the second half of the year we clearly saw the impact of ASCO, so there was clearly some off-label use on liver.  We don't comment on that, we don't monitor it, but I think it's clear and that's probably why you didn't see such a dramatic increase prior to, or post the approval.  Though I would remind you that the approval came at Thanksgiving so effectively there was no real promotion, official promotion, behind this in 2007.  All I can tell you in line with the statement of Werner that we've seen good momentum in our business.  We've also seen good momentum in Nexavar in the first two months of the year.</p>
          <p>As far as the comment on R&amp;D for Nexavar going forward, I think both Onyx and ourselves will clearly look at what we are spending on Nexavar, there was a quite a big commitment to non-small cell lung.  We haven't given up on that, but obviously we have to reflect the negative study.  So you will see us trying to find I'm sure in 2008 a better balance of driving for profitability and not just top line growth in Nexavar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Mr. Neil Taylor from JPMorgan. Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. It's JPMorgan in London. A couple of questions please. Firstly, Patrick, going back to the MaterialScience business, just your &#x2013; Mr. Wenning's comments regarding the ability to earn a positive cost -- return on capital in &#x2013; under any sort of environment. Presumably, that is the group as a whole or the MaterialScience business as a whole and not the individual businesses, I suspect you are already below that threshold in the systems business. I just wanted you to confirm that. And also whether you can confirm what the cost of capital hurdle for the business is, whether it's the group hurdle of 10.2%.</p>
          <p>Then secondly, on the CropScience business, it strikes me that given perhaps some of the headwinds you saw in the latter part of the year, the 23% or thereabouts for 2008 doesn't look particularly optimistic and I wonder what sort of &#x2013; what's perhaps tempering your optimism, if anything. Those are the two questions for now. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let's start with first of all with MaterialScience, Patrick and then Friedrich Berschauer will address the Bayer CropScience related question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Neil, as you know, BMS we're talking about really as a group, and I think maybe you had it the other way round. The systems business is currently clearly performing well above hurdle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, beg your pardon, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And the materials business is at hurdle, if not slightly above. In fact, interestingly, the Polycarbonate business is slightly above and it's the thermoplastic urethane business that's slightly below, counter to what you might expect. The overall hurdle rate is round about 8.7% for BMS, and as you know with our cycles, they never all occur at the same time. So if you'd gone back six quarters, you would have seen Polycarbonate at greater than 20% EBITDA margins, and today you see very low EBITDA margins, and currently the Polyurethane business is well above 20% EBITDA margin. So it's a sum of the parts target, which I think is realistic given the diversity of our portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For CropScience although EBITDA target is above, one is above 23% and as Mr. Wenning pointed out, our target for 2009 is 25% in EBITDA at the moment with market conditions. In terms of iptheon, I am really optimistic because we really have an I could say &#x2013; would say an excellent start in January and February. We have a very early season in Europe and the demand clearly sales level, still ten months to go but again, the start is really very, very good and I am very optimistic in terms of 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So &#x2013; sorry just to follow-up that. It sounds like there's going to be a more smooth progression to the 25% than perhaps just a modest increase at this year, and then a bigger sort of 200 basis point leap the year after?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think after the first four months, we should have a good indication about the full year, and then we can give you a better guidance about the good that we have seen and -- excellent start in the first two months, March is of key importance to our business. So let's wait, I would say another two months and then we can give you more details. But again, it looks really good if &#x2013; when I am talking to our customers and our people the mood is very good in our industry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Mr. Richard Vosser from Bear Stearns. Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for taking my question. It's Richard Vosser from Bear Stearns here. Just returning to the Yasmin and YAZ franchise, if I could. Firstly, is it possible to give us a breakdown between YAZ and Yasmin. I think you might have done that in the third quarter, if you could that for the full year that would be very helpful. And I just wanted also to touch on the HealthCare guidance for 2009, the EBITDA guidance and whether that factors in any generics competition for YAZ. You've mentioned the Yasmin, but what are your assumptions for YAZ?</p>
          <p>And then my third question is on Kogenate, and I just wondering if you could update us on the Kogenate market share progression within the hemophilia market. It's my understanding that you've been able to gain market share for the last couple of years, I was wondering if that's still the case in 2008, and if you could also give us an update on where we are with the Phase II trials the liposomal long-acting Kogenate that would also be very useful? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Arthur?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on Yasmin franchise and the YAZ franchise I guess the number that you're most interested in is the percentage of Yasmin of the total franchise. I think the quarter is a better way to look at that. It was 26% of total global sales or 71 million euros of Yasmin in the quarter. So that's the business exposure you could modify that by four if you wanted to. But, clearly we're seeing a conversion, yes, we're seeing a conversion from Yasmin to YAZ, and this puts it in perspective with less, it's 26% of the total franchise in the fourth quarter, and the other thing to put in perspective is we have more than half of total Yasmin -- this probably alludes to your second question  -- we have more than half of our total Yasmin family outside of the U.S. and that business is growing at close to 30%. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The numbers were helpful again I think it helps you triangulate on any potential exposure. Your question on Kogenate, we believe we did gain market share again in 2007 on a volume basis and on a value basis, and on a value basis, we believe our combined share is now 40%, that's the combined share of Kogenate plus Helixate, and I think we're very pleased with the performance of Kogenate in 2007. We grew, we believe, in line or slightly ahead of market. On the liposomal, that program continues as planned, but you can't really &#x2013; and we've said that expect an update for us until at the earliest end of this year, but probably the first quarter of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is that &#x2013; I suppose two trials started. Sorry two...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it has.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it has, brilliant. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Mr. Andrew Stott from Merrill Lynch. Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. Merrill Lynch. Just two questions, one on MaterialScience. Going back to your old comment, Patrick, on raw materials and you said, I think you said you were slightly surprised to see raw materials not go up as much as you thought in the first part of this year. Is that &#x2013; sorry is that what you said before I ask my question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the expected high oil price we believed would trigger much higher aromatic prices than we're seeing at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. The only, the question I had was simple, because if I look at my data sources, I've got benzene up 20% since beginning of the year, so I wonder what, is it just the Q2 we'll see the impact of that as it comes through into your contracts or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Some of it is in the pipeline, some of it is in effect where we pre-purchased low price benzene in fourth quarter at the end of last year. And some of it is the fact that if you look at spot prices versus contract prices then you are right, you are seeing some of the spot prices rising quite quickly. But, I think third quarter contract will be lower than we expected. And therefore the original guidance we gave was a raw material impact during full year of negative 250 million. We are not seeing proportionately that in the first quarter although, I believe you are right, we'll start to see that triggering through in the second quarter. Typically from price to product is all through to the bottom line is a period of over six weeks for our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And the second question was on CropScience, if I look at just the second half data it looks to me like the sales growth that you've generated in the crop protection business within that unit is below the industry average. And a simple conclusion therefore would be that you've lost market share; what would you say to that conclusion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would agree with you in terms of top line performance, we are &#x2013; let's say on inventory it even could be a little bit below average in terms of profitability. Our development was very pleasing if you have look on our numbers and our improvement in EBITDA and EBIT, we did a very good job last year. Here in terms of top line I think it's important to realize what happened last year in the marketplace, and what we have seen as you know probably that specifically the corn rate tensions, the corn production, soybean production increased significantly, mainly corn and all those achieve open inflation increased in the United States, as well as in Latin America. And if you have a look on the product groups the herbicide, and deals in non-selective herbicide market increased significantly and this was mainly held up and touch down of our competitors, and as you know we are not in this market. In terms of insecticides, fungicides, and seed treatment, we &#x2013; our development grows at least on an average in frequent heat treatment clearly above privilege. We outperformed the market today in these indications, but in non-selective herbicides and specifically even in round up, of course we are not in this market and this will &#x2013; may change last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Mr. Martin Brunninger from Cazenove. Please state your company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Martin Brunninger from Cazenove. Thanks very much for taking my questions. The first two questions maybe on Xarelto, and the fixed state you've shown at ASH. I have noticed that you have changed your venogram reading committee which analyzes the data on from what the event. In Phase II, you've used, I think the more sensitive Goethenburg (40.21) committee like anyone else did like, Boehringer, Bristol-Myers and also Sanofi according to state-of-the-art. However, in your Phase III studies you've switched to the less sensitive Hamilton approach, which is a more older approaches used earlier &#x2013; in earlier trials. Obviously the two different committees use different criteria, how to use venograms, how these venograms are interpreted. The committee that you've chosen is looking at larger thrombi only in this regard, the smaller thrombi, they clearly must have an increase in the ratio that you have shown at ASH. So what's your view on this, and how do you think the FDA EMEA want you to show the date on the label filing?</p>
          <p>And secondly, two weeks after you've submitted your Xarelto data to the EMEA on October '07 the EMEA has changed its guidelines for these sort of studies. They now want to investigators to include bleedings located at the surgical site, and leading to re-operation to major bleeding events. You have shown the data regarding major bleeding excluding this bleeding, again what's your view regarding this regulator start towards this and, when it comes to labeling discussions, will you have to include this data to major bleeding finally, surely they will look then slightly differently?</p>
          <p>And thirdly on MRI also appreciating Gadovist was introduced to the market Magnevist lost substantially and revenues of those products together declined 1%. Could you give us any color on this please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Brunninger, you were reading too quickly from your slide, so we couldn't really get all of your comments &#x2013; the last one as made.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You read too quickly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well it's regarding the major bleeding events basically, so you have -the EMEA has submitted a basically concluded a new guidelines in November 2007 where they are, they wanted you to include the operational wounds that being to major bleedings events?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I can't give that the operational, sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The operational site bleedings, they have been excluded in your data from major bleedings, and the EMEA want you to include this. What's your view on their stand towards the label discussion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The third question was on MRI because you are appreciating Gadovist was introduced to the market but Magnevist lost substantially in revenues those for us together lost...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you are reading your information..</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I missed the last, but you've moved on to Magnevist, sorry Martin, I just, Martin you moved on to Magnevist?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the third question was about Magnevist because it looks as if you have lost substantially on revenues here, and I appreciate you have introduced Gadovist as well, but those products together lost I think 1% of revenues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you maybe explain this a bit? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you Martin for those very precise questions. Let me try and address the very technical questions, very simply. We did change committees, but the same methodology &#x2013; the same methodology was used, so nothing to be concerned about. In regards to the issues you've raised on EMEA guidance. All of our end points not only with EMEA, but FDA, were agreed upon in advance, so I think the answer to both is nothing to be concerned about. On Magnevist and Gadovist I think you have to look at the full year and on a full year basis, we showed growth &#x2013; so I don't think you can look at the fourth quarter on a full year basis I believe we grew approximately 3% currency adjusted. We are seeing another conversion, an accelerated conversion from Magnevist to Gadovist you will continue to see Magnevist decline and Gadovist grow, and net-net we expect the franchise to grow low single-digits. Thank you, Martin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And the next question comes from Mr. Paul Walsh from Morgan Stanley. Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Paul Walsh from Morgan Stanley in London. Three questions if I can, I just wanted to dig a bit deeper onto the Polyurethanes side, Patrick please, just try and understand how you are viewing that business going through this year, obviously margins in the fourth quarter pretty good, how sustainable is that? I know there are fears out there about MDI capacities coming on stream? Secondly, just from a group perspective, can you just run through where you are in the different divisions on the synergy delivery at the end of 2007 relative to your targets. And I just wanted to ask Arthur on consumer care. There was some hinting towards possibility of cutting costs in consumer care going forwards, just where you are with that, what your thoughts are, if there is any update? Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me first take the Polyurethanes part of that question. I think you are right on the story with MDI, and I was looking forward to seeing MDI growth statistics for the fourth quarter. And they're coming in somewhere between 8 and 9% which is a relatively high level. At that level the world consumes approximately 400,000 tons of MDI more every year. So if we look at the capacity investment short-term during 2008 there will definitely be some over capacity, and that will lead to some pricing erosion. We're already seeing some of that pricing erosion in MDI during the first couple of months of this year. On TDI we're seeing the opposite, TDI growing at above historical rates, and this is partly because of the developing market tending to take on comfort furnishing slightly faster than we would expected and some new applications for TDI, so we are now above the historical rate of 3.5 to 4%, and we are actually closer to 4.5% at the moment in growth driven TDI. So the market is going to remain very tight during this year, and we see plenty of pricing power in those segments.</p>
          <p>Certainly through the whole of last year we were able to more than compensate raw material costs with price and volume in Polyurethanes. I think we'll see some slight pressure on the MDI pricing levels, and also some price pressure on the polyether side of the business, the polyols business where although the market growth is strong, there is some increased capacity on the propylene oxide side. And that's putting a squeeze on polyol margins quite simply because at the moment propylene is very high and the new capacities are not yet on the stream for PO. So a bit of the mixed picture, very strong on TDI, very slight weakening on MDI, but that should be a one year to 18 month phenomenon with the growth rates we're seeing at the moment. And then polyethers we're being more selective in following a price before volume strategy in that area where we have much more degree of freedom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And coming back to your question about the fresh savings in '07 and '08. Overall we achieved fresh savings last year out of our different restructuring programs of approximately 700 million, 370 from the share integration fresh savings last year, 130 in CropScience, and around 120 million in BMS, and around 90 million in our service company, so adding up around 700 million. For 2008, we expect fresh savings of roughly 500 million for the group, 220, 240 in BHC, 60 in Bayer CropScience, 140 in BMS, and around 60 in our service company. So this is around, so we are adding up here around 500 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul on Consumer Care, first of all thanks for asking the question because it gives me the opportunity to say we were very pleased indeed, I was almost going to say thrilled by the performance of our consumer care business last year as you saw almost a 11% growth. We do believe that we will continue to show in our Consumer Care business a significant above market growth in all three businesses, and you'll be pleased to know that we also expect to see margin improvement in 2008, that's not so much a focus on cost cutting but more the benefit we have from the skill we're now delivering in some of these brands, but it's a very successful business. Werner Wenning in his comments mentioned it's become a true growth engine, and when you think our top 10 consumer products, which account for approximately 62% of our total revenue grew at over 14%, you'll understand why our focus is very much on driving the top line, but I want to give you an assurance that we will be at the same time looking at efficiency, looking at productivity so you will see an improvement also in our absolute EBITDA margin for our consumer business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Mr. Andrew Benson from Citigroup. Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Andrew Benson from Citi in London; couple of things, pricing in the CropScience, can you talk about that, how successful you've been so far, what your plans are to drive price, there's a bit of generic competition particularly in the professional products area. Is that hurting? Can you talk a little bit about your debt reduction targets, and also the acquisition environment, and if there's things on the horizon? And lastly, perhaps for Arthur, you've had a few things go wrong in the HealthCare, obviously a few things go right as well, but Trasylol, Betaferon, and Nexavar in lung cancer, Tergivec litigation, can you just say what you are trying to do to counter some of these adverse factors and keep the momentum on the division?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let's start Andrew with price increases in crop. It's my favorite topic by the way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it was also my favorite topic as someone mentioned. Overall in 2007, we had basically no price increases, also no price reduction we need to physically check <mark type="inaudible" />. First of all we had some generic competition with some price erosion. Secondly, we performed volumes by achieving two important products in our portfolio which is <mark type="inaudible" />. And we keep volumes significantly because with the new market situation we had to reduce price to some degree, but overall it was the right decision. And thirdly, in introducing our innovative new products the margins are significantly higher compared to the old portfolio.</p>
          <p>As we have seen, our performance of our new products innovation in 2007 was very, very good. We increased sales to 1.4 billion; this was an increase of almost 400 million in 2007 so this really helped. Now looking into 2008, I'm more optimistic because again first quarter there is significant demand in the marketplace; secondly, farmers are really willing to invest in agriculture, they are willing to invest into Beta products, they are willing to invest into innovation. So, I'm rather  optimistic that this year we have significant better chance to increase the prices and it's early indication from this year it's really positive, but again let's wait another two months until I can give you further guidance. But I'm much more optimistic in 2008 compared to 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you just give an idea of the scale of price increases that you've posted and where they are and how much, across which part of the portfolio that you've actually posted to your distributors and farmers now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course we have programs, we differentiate product group by product group depending on the innovation potential of the portfolio. It was a different situation now at these various regions, the market in Europe is really very good. We have a very strong position so the chance of price increases are rather good in Europe; they are also rather good in Latin America. But still I would say a challenging situation in the North America, but overall, again the chance to implement price increases this year are really better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I, put it this way, do you have posted price increases and you're waiting...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you are waiting to see if those are sticking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah; I am much more optimistic this year compared to last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can you give an idea of the scale of the price increases you've posted?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I would feel much more comfortable to wait another two months and then giving you a clear indication -- a better indication.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we are talking about price increases and debt reduction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, with regard to Andrew, debt reductions, I mean for 2008 we've plan an increase in gross cash flow, and we plan to slightly improve our performance base and the working capital, so therefore we don't want to lose any significant value in working capital. Our CapEx should also be slightly below '07 levels at 1.7 billion so that all should result in a further clear reduction of our net debt and to the extent to what will -- might be depend a little bit on the question whether we have -- how much we would spend on acquisitions or not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, your question in regard to the acquisition environment, of course there are always opportunities in the marketplace. We are continue to analyze our own position, and be sure that we stay to our overall statement that we continue to analyze how we are also able to improve our position is first priority in HealthCare due to external growth. If opportunities arise, we are -- of course we will consider to invest, to continue to invest here also in external growth in HealthCare. And you will understand that I cannot comment more specifically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Andrew on your question on the disappointments, I think Andrew and almost everybody on the telephone has heard me, and probably everybody who is involved in pharma emphasize the fact it's a volatile business and not everything goes right. I remember, I hope we get recognition for the fact that perhaps operating aside, but more importantly reflecting our discipline that we've been able to absorb all of these setbacks, disappointments, I would describe as natural volatility, and still deliver our commitments on our financials. So I think the best  answer to your question is, there will always be surprises to the up and the downs in Pharma. I think you should feel reassured that when we have downside impacts, we take the disciplined actions to ensure that we do the right thing for the short and long-term, and have a  real focus on delivering our commitments, and there's nothing at anytime with any of these impacts that we've not remained confident and committed to our goals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Mr. Sachin Jain from Merrill Lynch. Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. It's Sachin Jain from Merrill Lynch. Thanks for taking my questions. And just a few HealthCare questions -- just back to the HealthCare margin. I'm putting together the synergy comments that you just made, you are basically going to run 140 basis points increase in HealthCare margin; now it's a very quick, back of the envelope calculation, just you could pretty much get there with your incremental synergies. And obviously there is a bit of currency offsets. I'm just trying to understand what are the headwinds you're facing into '07, sorry, into '08 that are offsetting or headwinds to your underlying margin improvements? That's the first question. Second question back to Betaferon comments on the fourth quarter growth at 4%, I just wondered if, Arthur, if you could highlight how you expect to accelerate that from here in the U.S. or Europe to get back to your kind of high single-digit growth rate targets?  And then the final question was whether you had any idea on the timing of the final analysis for the BART study for Trasylol, and if that study does confirm the suspicions of excess mortality risk, what your plans thereafter would be.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Sachin.  First of all I think this is really a continuation of the previous question.  I think in our guidance we have to acknowledge that not everything works and there is volatility.  So when we give guidance we try and reflect on finding the right balance between upsides and downsides.  And I think again if I can be presumptuous, I think we've done a pretty good job of that so far.  So we will continue to do that in the future.  Regarding Betaferon, actually I wouldn't read too much into the fourth quarter, in fact as a general rule, I would hope that we don't read too much into a quarter, particularly a quarter that has December in it.  I can tell you that from a HealthCare perspective, we've got off to a strong start in 2008 and we remain committed to our guidance for Betaferon this year of between 7 to 9%.  On the timing of the BART, we are as anxious as everybody is to receive this data.  It's a little disappointing that something can happen many months ago and we're still not able to discuss it because we have not seen any data from BART.  If it is the case that this confirms excess mortality, clearly I think it will be an easy decision for us.  The issue will be much gray if the data comes out inconclusive.  So I think I've tried to answer your questions Sachin, I hope  they are answers that meet your needs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Mr. Florent Cespedes from BNP Paribas.  Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.  Florent Cespedes speaking from Exane BNP Paribas in Paris.  A few quick questions on the pharma side please.  First of all in Campath, can you provide an update on the MS programs, especially on the patient recruitment.  Secondly on Xarelto can you tell us when you will have a significant number of patients exposed to the highest dosage of the product, ideally 20 milligram.  Also a quick question on financials.  Behind which product you put higher marketing efforts in Q4?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  First of all, on the Campath MS program, I'm pleased to update it's on-track, recruiting, online with our commitments.  On Xarelto the question was --?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>To the highest dosage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think after ASH, we gave a very comprehensive review of number of patients exposed and total number of patients exposed for three to six months.  You will appreciate that we don't intend to do that in every conference call.  But during the year we will update you and because clearly behind this question is the safety of Xarelto, again I want to reassure you that so far we're very pleased.  Obviously the efficacy data remains very convincing and we've seen nothing that gives us concern on the safety and we will update you at an appropriate time this year and give you more specifics on the question you just asked, but we're not going to do that on an ad hoc basis. And...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Last one was on the marketing efforts in Q4.  It was mentioned in the press release that apparently you put more efforts during Q4.  But I would like to know which product?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, marketing, this is as we mentioned and again I think we gave very good guidance at our third quarter conference call that we would expect increase in marketing.  We have a seasonal trend in the industry, in the healthcare industry, and I guess the healthcare industry is not alone to have higher expenses, particularly in marketing in the fourth quarter.  It was across our products, but if we're looking for specific areas where we feel that there were expected increases would be in the pre-marketing for Xarelto, and obviously the launch rollout of Nexavar in liver cancer.  But the bulk of it was just the traditional seasonality we have in respect to our marketing expenses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Mr. Christian Faitz from Oppenheim.  Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you, Christian Faitz from Oppenheim.  First of all on MaterialScience, congratulations on the most honest outlook statements so far in this reporting season I have seen in the Chemical Industry.  At least you are talking about global ability which I share unlike many of your peers.  The question would be why your view differs so much from any others.  Do you simply have a better view of the markets?  And also do you have any signals of a spillover from a weak U.S. market into Asia?  That's the first question.</p>
          <p>Second of all on agrochemicals, there are some industry voices in the market who are mulling an increase in the currently record low stock to use ratios in many regions and many soft commodity areas already this year.  Would you share this view?  And which would implicity lead to a lower soft commodity prices, and maybe also lower, let's say, insecticide, pesticide prices in general.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christian, thank you for your applause on the subject to trying to forecast this very difficult market.  I think if we look at your specific point around what seems to be going on in the U.S. at the moment, we see a surprising picture.  Last year we definitely saw a decline in housing leading into the furniture market, and we saw a decline in the automotive U.S. producers.  What we're now seeing is a continuation of that effect but surprisingly some of the furniture markets have recovered slightly despite the housing market not recovering, and maybe that's because people put off purchases until they actually needed to make the purchase, and now they're making the purchases.  So in fact on TDI at the moment we're seeing quite a lot of strength in the U.S.</p>
          <p>In terms of the impact in Asia, we're really not seeing any direct connection at all.  And I think my simplistic view of that would be the first wave of Asian growth for us was indeed for export and particularly for export to the U.S.  What we're now seeing is the second wave of Asian growth which is particularly the domestic market. And if I just give you one example, the local coatings market, which is primarily for consumption within China, grew nearly 40% last year and that almost entirely with domestic consumption within China. In building programs that are going on in China, the domestic consumption, the lifestyle and quality of living advances are really generating a much more important local market now. And although there's obviously significant exports to the U.S. we're not seeing that as being such a strong driver for our business at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Commodity prices in igglich keiter you have, we all have seen the sharp price increases of most of the important commodities and we are talking here not about 5 or 10%, we are talking about 20, 30, 50, sometimes even more. So, since that has been the situation, your question is will this remain? We believe that high commodity prices will remain in 2008 and the years to come. Why do we believe this, because we have a significant increase in the food demand and feed demand, specifically in Asia. Just one example in India there is now a population of round about 300 million of people who can afford good quality of food and who can afford &#x2013; who are consuming meat which results of course in increased feed demand.</p>
          <p>So, from the demand side, the food and feed clearly on the positive side, on top of it, as you know, we have the biofuel situation and the feed plants out there producing ethanol or producing biodiesel. The big question is of course if this biofuel story will remain in the next 10 years, I don't know. But, we believe that this demand for biofuel will stay on a high level in 2008 and the following years. I would not make, let's say a clear statement how I would see the situation in terms of biofuel in 10 years' time. So overall, we believe that commodity prices will remain on a high level. Of course, there will be fluctuations, there will changes, but we do not believe that commodity prices will go back to a level as in 2005, for example.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Mr. Nathan Sedati from Highside Capital Management. Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for taking the questions. Nathan Sedati at Highside Capital. Can you guys talk about &#x2013; with Nexavar sort of &#x2013; I think, if I understood you correctly, you were saying that you're going to sort of drive towards &#x2013; more towards profitability. In your view is that sort of &#x2013; where's that coming from? Is that coming more from growing sales and sort of having a stable R&amp;D expense line going forward from kind of this new baseline or is it just more cautious increases in R&amp;D?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nathan, I think the message was we clearly have to adapt when we get information like lung cancer to look at our overall R&amp;D expenditure. Also, we're now at a stage where we're looking at a pretty substantial brand, so we should start to see marketing efficiencies which will obviously improve our overall profitability.</p>
          <p>So my comment was not about a radical shift but the natural shift you would expect after our product's been on the market for two years. And we've made very significant investments in marketing. We've been very aggressive and we'll continue to be aggressive in our R&amp;D but perhaps we'll look for more signal trials rather than pivotal studies at this stage. We still have large programs underway in melanoma and breast, but we will continue to exploit the pan-tumor potential. This is a pan-tumor drug. We just have to find which is the next target.</p>
          <p>So the message today is the outlook for Nexavar is strong but you will see us, as you would expect, to get the balance now a little bit more into marketing efficiencies, ensuring we've got the right balance of R&amp;D and all of that will be reflected in the profitability of the brand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Mr. David Luis from Bear Stearns. Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Thanks for taking my call. David Luis from Bear Stearns. I've just four quick questions on CropScience. Firstly, did you see any price increases in the fourth quarter? Secondly, why are you more optimistic this year than last year? I mean last year crop prices were also at elevated levels.</p>
          <p>Thirdly, do your own targets &#x2013; EBITDA margin targets for this business increase, include any price increases or what kind of assumptions have you made on prices in your own internal targets. And fourthly, could you tell us the impact of a 1% price increases? What impact that would have on your EBITDA margin? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, price increases, overall in last year if we do a detailed analysis. Again, we had seen significant price increases mainly specifically with glyphosate because there was a shortage of glyphosate. Now talking about 2008, first of all, the demand clearly is there. Second, and I made already this comment our customers are more willing to buy innovative products and with innovative products you really have significantly better chance to implement the price increases.</p>
          <p>So we set our year target. I get say a push from Mr. Wenning and I pass this pressure to our organization as you can imagine so we really do everything to improve feel.  And again, I really would feel more comfortable in two months' time to give you a further clear indication. Should be a &#x2013; here if you do a calculation...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we are able to increase our prices by 1%, be sure we will also increase our EBITDA by 1% margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And your own targets, they don't include any price increases in this business. You talk about a normal environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe if I may answer your question, it's part of a business model that you will &#x2013; that you are able to increase prices over a couple of months and quarters, how to compensate, for example, inflation. So this is part of our business model and has to be part of our business model of course also in CropScience, where we are spending a lot of money in R&amp;D, perhaps the highest R&amp;D budget of the industry in crop protection.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on top of it, we have to digest a lot of high raw materials and industry cost prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For example.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for your answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Mr. Jean De Watteville from Lehman Brothers. Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, hello. Good afternoon, Jean Watteville from Lehman. Two question, the first one is on Ascensia, we've seen another strong quarter. I just wondered if you can give a little more color on this product line, particularly in terms of the phasing of new product introduction? Also about, some comments about your market share and what are the pricing initiatives?</p>
          <p>Second question, again, going back on the pricing issue in crop protection, I'm afraid, can you quantify what will be the raw material cost inflation that you will see in 2008. And your comments about your optimism on prices, is it because you see that you are in a better situation to recover higher raw material prices so therefore mainly for commodity products or is it because you are very optimistic to achieve price increases for the innovative higher margin products?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A clear answer to this was we expect that in terms of our strategy to increase our &#x2013; the portfolio of our innovative products, to increase the sales. You have seen our performance in last year which was very, very pleasing. And this clearly is one of the most important keys to increase in prices. Secondly, the increase of raw material and industry cost last year was in the range of round about 20 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And there is also one logic where in CropScience, which is also true in other area that is in capacity and demand situation. And in certain products in CropScience, we are running out of --we are very-very close to our maximum capacity level.  So it is in CropScience, are not so many secrets in how to increase prices. It highly depends of the general market situation and as we've said several times this afternoon, the market is very strong and demand is very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But that applies primarily for commodity products, the supply that made argument.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No, because the pharmacy -- commodity prices are significantly up. For example take wheat, the wheat price is 50, 60% up compared to one year ago. So it's much more attractive for the farmer for example to increase the yield and therefore he is more willing invest innovative, to use innovative products and we have a lot of innovative product and this will bring us in an improved situation compared to generic companies for example.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So now, I'm switching to your Ascensia-related question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jean first of all, thanks. I have been waiting all call for somebody to ask me about my diabetes business because we were very proud to be the, in 2006 the fastest growing diabetes company in the world and we increased that lead in 2007. And as you pointed out Ascensia range is just a little shy of 1 billion and grew 24% last year.</p>
          <p>Now what are we doing and what we are doing differently? I could spend the afternoon sharing with you because we have fundamentally rebuilt our diabetes business over the last three years. It does exemplify a strength of Bayer, which is to understand that interface between the professional and the consumer, and that's what you have in diabetes. You have all this of the influence of the physician. But you now have an even greater or as great an influence of the consumer. And we have a lot of cabilities in that area and we're exploiting that and I think as the results demonstrate, we're doing it better than our competition. And in fact if you look at that number, probably means we were growing the Ascensia line at twice to 2.5 times the market rates.</p>
          <p>So this is a great success story. It's a very impressive team that we have. They are demonstrating quarter-after-quarter that they really understand how to gain share in that market. And my boss is telling me I probably said enough positive things about diabetes care. But as you can appreciate, we're very proud of this. We had a history of loosing market share and now we are rebuilding this brand and are confident again that in 2008 will be very strong performance in our diabetes franchise. Of course Ascensia will be the flagship brand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Interesting. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Mr. Paul Major from Redburn. Please state your company -- your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello it's Paul Major from Redburn Partners. Just one question, please could you update us on your expectations about how the group tax rate will develop over the medium term? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, group tax rate for 2008 is to be expected, reported tax rate in the area of 34 to 35% and so that is relatively on the same level or maybe slightly below what we have seen this year. If you ask for a current estimate for the current tax so the taxes paid, we anticipate we had in '07 a payout ratio of 27% if we adjust our profits before taxes when they're sharing amortization and debt ratio should be the same roughly next year. So basically we'll take our profit before tax as back to the sharing amortization, which is non-cash relevant and on that number roughly 27%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And beyond 2008, can you give us any indication?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's, I mean the tax schemes vary all over the world all the time, but I would not see at least currently, I don't have the single event in mind which would change these two numbers, reported and paid tax rate because it's in the, over the medium term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And the next question comes from Mr. Ronald K&#xF6;hler from MainFirst. Please state your name and company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Once again, Ronald K&#xF6;hler from MainFirst. Just coming back to the tax rate, obviously other peers saying Asian earnings are going up and Asia is usually with lower tax rate, you don't observe a better trend in your business, the first question?</p>
          <p>Second question to your other guidance -- other line in the segment, you're going obviously for cost savings for the service business of around 60 million, last year 90 million, is that something which will show up in the other line or will it then divide it so to say to the segment by giving lower charges on services. How do you go on with these cost savings here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To the latter -- latter question, the latter answer, yes, it is our philosophy that the major efficiency improvements or whatever which the service companies achieve are followed through to the -- to our customers be it external or, also to stay competitive and also to our internal customers. And the second question was with regard to tax rates in Asia, we do not observe here a significant impact on our overall tax rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, Mr. Rosar, we have now further questions, please continue with any further points you wish to address.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Anna. I'd now like to say also on behalf of my colleagues, thanks for being with us on the call. We are now saying goodbye, and hope to meeting you soon again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the full year and fourth quarter 2007 results investor conference call of Bayer AG. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>