<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1236381" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-15</date>
    <companies>
      <company>27961</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Aldo Luiz Mendes, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Marco Geovanne Tobias da Silva, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="3">Saul Martinez</participant>
      <participant id="4">Daniel Abut</participant>
      <participant id="5">Mario Pierry</participant>
      <participant id="6">Victor Galliano</participant>
      <participant id="7">Jorg Friedemann</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. We will now begin Banco do Brasil's First Quarter '09 Results Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Later, we will conduct a question-and-answer session and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded and a live broadcast with a slide presentation on the Bank's web site, at Investor Relations site from where questions may be sent through.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are based on the beliefs and assumptions of Banco do Brasil's management, and on information currently available to the company. Forward-looking statements are not guarantees of performance. They involve risks, uncertainties, and assumptions because they are related to the future events and therefore depend on circumstances that may or may not occur in the future. Investors should understand that general economic conditions, industry conditions and other operating factors could also affect the future results of Banco do Brasil and could cause results to differ materially from those expressed in such forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>With us today, Mr. Aldo Luiz Mendes, CFO; Mr. Eduardo Cesar Pasa, General Accountant; and Mr. Marco Geovanne Tobias da Silva, Head of IR. First, Mr. Aldo will comment on the company's first quarter '09 big figures. Afterwards, Mr. Geovanne will present more details of the results. After that, the executives will be available for question and answers.</p>
          <p>Mr. Aldo, you may now begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning to everyone and welcome to our conference call to discuss Banco do Brasil's first quarter results. Geovanne will present our performance in the period, but before that, I would like to highlight some of the Bank's events and conquers of BB in the quarter.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter of one year guided by the worst crisis of the global financial system, we had the net income of R$1.7 billion, which responds to an ROE of 23.8%, with earnings per share of R$0.65. The recurring net income in the quarter amounted R$1.4 billion, responding to a 19.1 ROE, in line with our 2009 guidance. That's that, I affirm to you that our feeling towards 2009 is very positive. Even a period seasonally weak like the first quarter, especially this year in the middle of a major crisis, we will see in this presentation that we were able to have a performance in line with our guidance.</p>
          <p>At the next quarter, usually have a stronger rhythm. We hope to ensure our commitments of growth and profitability. We consolidated Nossa Caixa in this quarter, which added R$64 billion to BB's assets, which reached R$592 billion at the end of the quarter. It is worth to mention that even without Nossa Caixa, the total assets of BB would increase 3.1% in the quarter and 29.8% in the year.</p>
          <p>Also regarding the assets growth, our securities portfolio had the best performance, 27.3% in the period. BB's total loan portfolio with the consolidation of 13.8 billion from Nossa Caixa ended the first quarter in R$242 billion, an increase of 40% in 12 months and 7.6% in the quarter. I also highlight that the loan growth in Banco do Brasil was higher than the recorded in the Brazilian banking industry, an increase of 40% in one year and 8.3% in the first three month of 2009, supporting the industry growth, which was 25 in 12 months and 1.1% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>The higher increase in loan assets was in the individuals portfolio, which grew 67% one year and 25.3% in the quarter, totaling more than R$61 billion. The lines that mainly drove this performance were payroll and auto-loans.</p>
          <p>The total loans to business reached R$101.1 billion, growth of 47.2% compared to the first quarter '08 and 4.7% compared to the previous quarter. This business loan portfolio ended the quarter in R$64.3 billion, a slight reduction of 0.3% in quarter and a growth of 13.7% compared to the first quarter of '08.</p>
          <p>Analyzing the quality of Banco do Brasil's loan portfolio, the portfolio of past-due loans over 90 days came from 2.4 for March and December of '08, to 2.7% in March of '09, which is significantly lower than the 3.6% recorded by the Brazilian bank industry last March. Another important information, while the average risk of the Brazilian bank industry increased 140 basis points, the average risk of BB's portfolio increased only 30 basis points compared to the fourth quarter '08.</p>
          <p>Our delinquency ratios and consequently our provision expense reflect the already expected effect of the financial crisis over the economic activity, especially to SME.</p>
          <p>Despite all the challenges ahead, we will continue to work hard to transform the threats and opportunities to Banco do Brasil. And I reinforce our trust in the strength, solidity and capacity of BB to support a good performance in different lines of business. That's why we do not see reasons at this point to revisit our 2009 guidance.</p>
          <p>Well, before Geovanne starts the presentation, I would like to inform that this results released will adopt the financial economic consolidation in our MD&amp;A, which considers our holdings in non-financial companies. Historical data since first quarter '08 will be consequently reviewed.</p>
          <p>Now I will pass to Geovanne to proceed with the presentation. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Aldo. Good morning to everybody. Let's go straight to slide number three, where we can observe the assets of Banco do Brasil with and without the consolidation of Nossa Caixa. As Aldo mentioned, with the assumption of the state control of Banco Nossa Caixa, we achieved R$592 billion in total assets, 10% higher than when we analyze Banco do Brasil separately.</p>
          <p>Regarding loans, the consolidation brought R$13.8 billion to Banco do Brasil's portfolio, which amounted R$242 billion, a 7.6% in the quarter growth and a 40% growth in 12 months. On the liabilities side, the closing of the deal added R$36.7 billion in deposits to Banco do Brasil, an amount that represent more than 13.5% of Banco do Brasil's numbers alone, and which increase the balance of deposits to R$305 billion.</p>
          <p>Another highlight was the increase of more than 5.8 million customers, which corresponds to 12% of Banco do Brasil's customer base separately, and led the base to a total of 53.9 million clients.</p>
          <p>On slide four, we see the behavior of Banco do Brasil's net income, which in the first quarter was R$1.665 billion, a drop of 29.1% when compared to the same period last year, and 43.4% when compared to the previous quarter. This results corresponded to an annualized return on equity of 23.8%, and earnings per share of R$0.65. If we do not consider the one-off, the recurring net income reached R$1.357 billion, amount 12.9% lower than the observed in the first quarter of '08, and 16.5% lower than the registered in the previous quarter. The recurring return on equity was 19.1%, close to the bottom of our 2009 guidance.</p>
          <p>On slide five, we can observe the breakdown of the one-off that impacted the results in the income statement in the period. On the one hand, we recognized tax credits in the amount of R$1.2 billion due to the fact that legal studies concluded that it's quite remote, the prospect of success in an action against the raise of the social contribution on profits rate from 9 to 15%, and also because of profit share over one-off items. On the other hand, we had extraordinary expenses regarding the use of R$1.4 billion provision to face legal claims, and R$95 million of provisions that were accounted to economic plans. Thus the net effect in the result with the one-offs was R$309 million, which brings a recurring net income to R$1.4 billion in Q1 '09.</p>
          <p>With no doubt the quarter showed clearly the impact of the crisis in the Brazilian economy and also in the Brazilian banking industry. Besides the seasonal effects usually related to the first quarter, the Banks had to deal with a reduction in the credit demand, higher aversion to risk and worsening in the quality of those operations, and also the changes in the mix of assets. The quarter also had a cut of 250 basis points in the benchmark rate by the Brazilian Central Bank. In this scenario, although we kept our credit expansion strategy, net interest income decreased 1.3% in the quarter, mainly due to the lower number of weak sales in the period to the cut in the benchmark interest rate to a seasonal drop in demand deposits, which implies an increase in the funding costs, and also a consequence of the mix effect, to a lower income with credit recoveries, and also to the increase in the participation of securities income in the built of the net interest income.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, those facts were compensated by the growth on the average earning assets, which increased 8.1% in the quarter, not considering here the effects from the consolidation of Banco Nossa Caixa. It is important to mention that in the annual comparison, net interest income grew 25.4% and this increase in 12 months analysis places Banco do Brasil in a new level of growth in its net interest income.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide seven, we can see that Banco do Brasil's overall spread behavior versus the Selic rate. While the Selic rate dropped 250 basis points between Q4 '08 and Q1 '09, Banco do Brasil's spread, a ratio between net interest income and earning assets, dropped 60 basis points, ending the quarter in 6.6%. The drop in the spread is explained mainly by the changes in the mix of assets and liabilities in the quarter. Interest bearing liabilities increased 9.2% while the average earning assets grew 8.1%. Besides that, there was a change in the composition of Banco do Brasil's average earning assets. The loan operations, the ones with better spreads, grew in a lower pace when compared to treasury assets. Thus, its share was reduced in the total earning assets volume, coming from 49.7% in Q4 '08 to 47.4% in Q1 '09.</p>
          <p>The graph below shows the spread in loan operation by specific portfolios. It is worth to highlight here that the total spread from these operations ended the quarter in 9.7%, and corresponded to a reduction of only 10 basis points when compared to the previous quarter, and also when compared to the first quarter of '08. A spread in the individual loans will once more had the higher reduction when compared to the total portfolio. This behavior is explained by the changes in the mix of the portfolio, due to the strategy of increasing the share of operations with lower risk and, then, lower spreads, as the payroll and auto loans increases. Besides the effect of portfolio acquisitions from other institutions, which have lower spreads due to the fact that the selling institutions are co-obligated with the loans; and also the adjustments of rates to customers, along with the cuts in the Selic rate.</p>
          <p>In the business book, the spread had a slight reduction in the quarter, but remained in a higher level than the ones from previous periods. Working capital lines, which usually have shorter terms and have high spreads, continued to positively affect the business operations spread. The agribusiness portfolio maintained the trend of spread recovery, started in the previous quarter, totally in line with the reduction of agri-industrial loan operation.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide eight, we have the funding of Banco do Brasil in the first quarter of '09 compared to previous quarters, besides our funding cost in the different lines in relation to Selic. While we observe the balance of total funding in this quarter helped by the consolidation of Nossa Caixa, we can see a slight increase in the total funding cost of Banco do Brasil when compared to the Selic rate. Affected this behavior, the change in the mix of funding, with the reduction in demand deposits, the increase in savings funding, which became relatively more expensive in this new scenario of decreasing rates, and the expansion in open market funding, that have higher costs.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, the increase in time deposits, that is aligned with interests most linked to the Selic, helped to reduce the increase of funding costs in relation to the benchmark rate. Even with the changes in the scenario, Banco do Brasil still have competitive funding costs, due to its capacity of growing those liabilities in a pace higher than the banking industry and due to its franchise and image towards its customers.</p>
          <p>Now in slide nine, we can see that also in loans Banco do Brasil is growing in a higher pace when compared to the banking industry, achieving an 18.3% market share. As Aldo mentioned at the beginning of his comments, we had a growth of 40% for the past 12 months and 7.6% in the quarter in our loan portfolio. The highlights here in this growth were, definitely, an individual book, with a 67% increase over Q1 '08 and 25.3% growth over the past quarter; and loans to business, which grew 47.2% in the year and 4.7% in the quarter. I remind you that in the fourth quarter of 2008, the loan portfolio of Nossa Caixa was already adjusted to consolidation, for the sake of comparison.</p>
          <p>On slide ten, we can observe that the growth in Banco do Brasil was higher than the banking industry even when we analyze the organic growth only. If we exclude, in the quarter, the acquisition of portfolios and also the portfolio from the State Bank of Santa Catarina and the loan assets from Banco Nossa Caixa, we have an increase, an organic increase, in Banco do Brasil's loan book of 1.6%, still above the growth seen in the banking industry that was only around 1%. In fact, the industry grew 25% in 12 months; while Banco do Brasil's loan portfolio expansion was almost 30% in the past 12 months.</p>
          <p>Following on to slide 11, we have a breakdown of the loan operations to individuals, considering here all credit lines that Banco do Brasil have. In the graph, we can see that we kept a strong pace of growth in payroll and auto loans. We grew the payroll portfolio by 94.5% in 12 months, and the performance in the quarter was very impressive, almost 41%. With Nossa Caixa, Banco do Brasil consolidates its leadership in the payroll segment, with a 30% market share. In auto loans, we almost doubled the portfolio in one year, but in the last quarter, the growth rhythm is smooth, becoming close to 5% as a reflect of the current economic scenario.</p>
          <p>On slide 12, we see that the loans to businesses surpassed R$100 billion. We would like to highlight here the operations with middle and large-size companies, which grew 48.2% in one year and loans to SMEs, that increased 7.2% in the quarter. It is important to mention that we took the opportunity here of a more restricted scenario to tight our relationship with business clients, in order to supply or to meet their credit needs, and this strategy guaranteeing Banco do Brasil the improvement in the profitability from those clients, and also the growth in the volume of business with these clients, as we saw in slide seven.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 13, we will analyze loans contracted, the disbursement of loans in the banking industry and also by Banco do Brasil in the past quarters. We can see in the graph that the level of disbursements in the first quarter of '09 was, on average, 3.7% lower than the volume disbursed in the same period of '08, both to the industry and to Banco do Brasil. The same happens when we compare the disbursements in the first quarter to the previous quarter that seasonally has stronger disbursements.</p>
          <p>Regarding Banco do Brasil exclusively; we see that Banco do Brasil is still responds for 15% of the contracted loan operations in the banking industry.</p>
          <p>In slide 14, we have an overview of some of the main loan operations granted by Banco do Brasil. We would like to highlight here the increasing trend of the contract of loans to individuals. While in the first quarter of '08 the disbursements to auto and payroll loans were decreasing, in the first quarter of '09, those lines reverted the trend, especially in the disbursement of pay roll operations, which grew 43% in the quarter. On the other hand, we observe here that, in business operations, credit granting decreased, but even so, Banco do Brasil's performance in this segment is still very expressive. It is important to bear in mind that, during the lack of funding &#x2013; during the crisis, the lack of funding in Q4 '08, Banco do Brasil was supplying credit to this segment and the normalization of liquidity and the seasonal aspects of the period are reflected in the behavior of disbursement to business loans.</p>
          <p>Following on to slide 15, we can see on the left graph that the expansion in the loan portfolio was in line with our estimates and also with credit quality in a more challenging scenario. Provision expenses overbooked, considering the past 12 months, achieved 3.8% in relation to the average loan portfolio, a percentile correspondent to the lower level indicated in our 2009 guidance. Past due loans for more than 90 days shown in the yellow line on the right graph, represented 2.7% of the book at the end of Q1 '09. This percentile is higher than the 2.4% observed in both Q1 '08 and Q4 '08. However, it is significantly lower than the 3.6% delinquency rate recorded by the Brazilian banking industry. We increased the required provisions over total loan book to 5.7%, well below the average risk from the industry, which was 6.7%.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 16, we can observe that during the past years, the delinquency of Banco do Brasil is below the delinquency from the Brazilian banking industry, and this trend confirms that the quarterly breakdown, especially in Q1 '09.</p>
          <p>Regarding business operations, we can see that past due loans from this portfolio are in the same trend in Banco do Brasil and in the industry. Although in Q1 '09 the level of delinquency in those operations in the industry worsened especially in those loans that are past due for more than 15 days.</p>
          <p>In loans to individuals, I would like to highlight here that Banco do Brasil has an opposite trend when compared to the industry. Our delinquency ratio is especially lower when compared to the industry. If we take into consideration for instance past due loans for more than 90 days, we can see that in the industry the delinquency rose by 30 basis points, from 8 to 8.3%, while delinquency rate in Banco do Brasil's individuals loan book remained flat at 5.9%.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 17, we brought you the vintage of our individual loan book, considering here all those credits, except overdraft accounts, credit cards and auto loans. It's quite clear in this graph the improvement seen in the delinquency of our individuals loan book, due mainly to the improvement in our credit risk assessment methodologies, along with the mix changes in the contracted operations that allowed the improvement in our delinquency ratio, mainly caused by the increase in payroll deductible lending.</p>
          <p>On slide 18, we brought our car loan vintages in Banco do Brasil for both operations; the ones contracted among our existing branch network and those contracted with dealers. It is important to highlight that this portfolio is too hard to try to estimate a trend in terms of delinquency, especially because it's a brand new portfolio for Banco do Brasil, and the delinquency ratio reflects our learning curve in this segment, in which we don't have an expertise. However, we're trying to improve even more how to deal with this new business.</p>
          <p>Following on to slide 19, I would like to highlight some information from Banco Votorantim. Banco Votorantim is our JV, we have set a JV with Banco Votorantim, and although some analysts have demonstrated some worries regarding our strategic partnership with Banco Votorantim, it is worth to mention that the quality of credit from Banco Votorantim is, without any doubts, much better than the industry. Votorantim's expertise in this segment is clear when we see its delinquency ratio of 2.2% only in a portfolio made up of more than 80% from used cars. In this way, we hope to profit from this partnership between Banco do Brasil and Banco Votorantim, and we expect it to help us to improve the quality of our own auto financing book.</p>
          <p>On slide 20, we bring some information that allows us to keep our tranquility regarding agribusiness book, in relation to 2008 and '09 crops and its performance, but also to the outlook to 2009 and '10 crop. Although production costs have increased during '08/'09 crop, prices are still attractive and guarantees a good margin to producers. We see in the graphs below that, even in an unfavorable scenario, margins of farmers in Brazil are still profitable.</p>
          <p>On slide 21, we have the agribusiness operations that are contracted with risk mitigators. The percentile of agricultural cost contracted loans with insurance came from 42% in the '06-'07 crop to 65% in the '08-'09 crop. This growth is a result from Banco do Brasil's positioning in the rural segment since 2007, addressing resources to those loans that bring risk mitigators. From the total of agri insurance contracted through our controlled company called Alian&#xE7;a do Brasil, 90% are reinsured, and the table on the right bottom part of the slide shows the reinsurance companies that reinsure these risk mitigators.</p>
          <p>Following on to slide 22, we can observe the behavior of our fee income, which amounted R$2.9 billion in the quarter, this total is completely in line with the same period of last year and represents a 3.7% decrease when compared to Q4 '08. Besides the growth of business and customer base, the increase in fee income, when compared to Q1 '08, is below our 2009 guidance that was between 5 to 8%. This behavior was strongly affected by the Central Bank's fee regulation, which effects we can observe since Q2 '08, making the comparison between these two quarters quite difficult. Regarding the quarterly comparison, it is worth to mention that the drop is mainly explained by the lower numbers of weekdays in each period. In Q4 '08 we had 64 weekdays, while in Q1 '09 we had only 61 weekdays &#x2013; working days.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 23, we can see that our administrative expenses are under control and in line with our guidance, between 9 to 12% in 12 months. In the quarter, those expenses dropped 9.5% and over the first quarter of '08, we had a growth of 11.2%.</p>
          <p>In the annual comparison, the performance is explained mainly by the behavior of personnel expenses that increased 18.2%, due to the salary raise to employees in September '09 and also because of the increase in the head count base. In the quarterly comparison, the drop in administrative expenses is explained by seasonal effects, as the concentration of the use of provisions, due to employees' vacations, and also the lower level of economic activity, usually happens during the beginning of the year.</p>
          <p>On slide 24, we see that Banco do Brasil's productivity ratios are still in good levels, cost income ratio that indicates how much of the operational income is being consumed by administrative expenses ended Q1 '09 at 43.3%. It is 240 basis points lower than the previous quarter and 140 basis points below Q1 '08. This ratio is calculated based on the income statements and we are excluding from this calculation the one-off items of the period.</p>
          <p>The improvement in the cost income ratio in the quarter is due to a stronger drop in operation revenues and in operational expenses. The personnel expenses covered ratio achieved 131.9% in Q1 '09 against 136.2% in Q4 '08 and 150.8% in Q1 '08. The decrease seen in 12 months is due to the raise in personnel expenses as I said before and that increase is being a result from the salary agreement in September '08 and also by the increase in the employee's stake due to the acquisition of banks we did last year. Besides that, the new key regulation that started from April 2008 on, okay ended up in causing this drop in income as well.</p>
          <p>And I would like now to move to slide 25 where we can observe that Banco do Brasil BIS ratio is to allowing our business a growth perspective, the BIS ratio ended the quarter in 15%, compared to 15.2% from the previous one and 14.7% at the end of March '08. Among the facts that contributed to the ratio in the quarter, we would like to highlight the consolidation of Nossa Caixa, which impact our capital allocation in R$1.7 billion; the changes in the calculation of our operational risk; the increase in loan operations; and also I would like to highlight here the increase in our outstanding subordinated debt that increased by R$2.6 billion in the period.</p>
          <p>Well, pro forma if we would try to calculate what would be the BIS ratio including the consolidation of the strategic partnership of Votorantim; we would have achieved a capital adequacy ratio of 14.1%.</p>
          <p>To wrap up this presentation, I would like to bring on slide 26, a comparison between our guidance and the performance achieved by Banco do Brasil in the first quarter of '09. We understand that some of the lines here were impact by the seasonality affect of the quarter and also by the international crisis. However, we believe that difficulties brought out by this challenging scenario presents us a very good opportunity and this challenging economic environment won't last the entire 2009.</p>
          <p>Due to this reason, we would like to reaffirm our estimates that we released during the fourth quarter '08 conference call, except to the tax rate which guidance is under review. We are reviewing our tax rate due to the recognition of tax credits that were originated from the alteration of the raise in the social contribution at tax from 9 to 15%. Well, this was mainly the information I would like to share with you in this conference call.</p>
          <p>We could now open the floor to the Q&amp;A session. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do we have any questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we will now begin question and answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question comes from the line of Saul Martinez with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, everybody. Question is on your guidance for net interest income. Obviously, you saw a little bit of a decline sequentially in terms of net interest income, but at the same time you had very, very strong growth in net interest income in the fourth quarter as your balance sheet really grew. And by my calculation, even if you kept your net interest income at the current levels, your growth in net interest income this year is somewhere in the neighborhood of 15%. So, it would be helpful to get a sense from you guys as to, not only what you expect your net interest margin to be this year, but also what you expect your net interest income growth to be. Because it seems to me like even if margins compress somewhat you can have very strong net interest income growth this year, in the neighborhood of 15 to 20%.</p>
          <p>Secondly, just on the tax rate, I know it's under review, but any preliminary views in terms of how much you expect your effective tax rate to increase by? I know you don't expect the full six percentage points but &#x2013; because of tax planning and other reasons, but if you can just give us any preliminary views in terms of what we should be expecting in terms of tax rate increases in the coming quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Saul. This is Geovanne. Well, despite the fact that we don't give official guidance in our net interest income, we definitely expect an increase in this line, something around 10 to 15% for 2009. It will depend on how fast we're able to grow our loan book mainly in the individuals portfolio, okay? And also the unfoldings of the crisis in the Brazilian economy, where we have a very good prospect in terms of the effect of the government packages to incentivate demand. So, probably we will be able to increase our net interest income for this year around 10 to 15%. Yeah, in line with the growth <mark type="inaudible" /> -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you &#x2013; I'm sorry to interrupt, Geovanne, but, I mean, is that conservative? Because that implies that you expect your net interest income to fall sequentially in the coming quarters. Because as I look at your last year, even under the re-class by numbers, you had much stronger growth in the second half than in the first half; so even if your run rate stays near current levels or increases, it seems like net interest income growth can be much &#x2013; unless you expect net interest income on a quarterly basis to be below where it's at now, it seems like 15% growth is even somewhat conservative. I mean, or am I missing something there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, you're right. It's a conservative assumption definitely, okay? We don't know exactly the impacts of the crisis and how long it's going to last, okay, for the next quarters. So, we prefer to be more conservative, okay? And with regard to the tax rate, we are still &#x2013; it's too soon to try to figure out what would be the impact from this new level of social contribution tax, but I think you &#x2013; for the sake of estimates, you should expect something around 30%, okay? So, probably &#x2013; and this we will reaffirm when we disclose Q2 numbers, okay, but probably our effective tax rate will be around 30, 31, 32%, but it's too soon to try to effectively affirm that it's going to be that, okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Daniel Abut with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Two questions. First on Nossa Caixa, if you could provide an update on where the process starts in terms of the approvals you need to obtain to finally launch and complete the takeout of the minority shareholder? And second, I was surprised to see that in this quarter you provided consolidation of all the balance sheets with new information, but you did not include the Nossa Caixa effect on your income statement. So, what I'm going to see in the second quarter when you finally include Nossa Caixa in your income statement, are we going to see an effect of the second quarter as well reflecting all at once? And I'm referring to this in particular because we noticed that Nossa Caixa reported some losses in the first quarter as they had an impact in your second quarter numbers because you will have to consolidate then what you didn't consolidate in this quarter that you have report (40.51).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Daniel, this is Geovanne, could you hold on a second, please? Well, with regard &#x2013; hold on a second.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Daniel, it's Aldo speaking. Regarding Nossa Caixa's schedule, we are waiting for the final approval of CVM, which is our SEC, as you know, and our estimate was that by the end of July, we will be able to conclude the tender offer, by the end of July.</p>
          <p>And regarding the second question, the Nossa Caixa consolidation, Daniel Abut, it's important for you to understand that the accounting practice allowed us to recognize all the numbers in the balance sheet, even the loss reported in Q1. And it's important to highlight that these losses were the consequence of the provisionings we had to account due to the due diligence we did when we were studying the acquisition, so we adjusted all Nossa Caixa's provisions in order to face or to bring it in line with the practice of Banco do Brasil.</p>
          <p>So in terms of income statement, the first quarter of '09 brought no impact in Banco do Brasil's income statement. From now on, all revenues and expenses from Nossa Caixa will now be accounted in the income statement of Banco do Brasil during the consolidation. However, the numbers from the first quarter will not impact our income statement because we made all the adjustments in the goodwill paid for Nossa Caixa. So the numbers for the first quarter was a balance sheet impact, and the numbers from the second, third and fourth quarter on, will now pass through our income statement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Geovanne. I'm hearing that we weren't declaring the process with the CVM, Geovanne , and I always understood that the key approval was with the Central Bank, which was obtained, and that the CVM was more a rubber stamping at the end of the particular <mark type="inaudible" />? What is taking so long that you are now predicting end of July for the takeout to be completed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hold on a second, please. Well, Daniel, there were some setbacks during the approval from the Brazilian SEC, the CVM, and it was mainly due to operational issues. For instance, we have &#x2013; we offered the minority shareholders the possibility of receiving the price of the tender offer on a monthly basis installment, and it was necessary to adjust all the investment bank contracts to face this tender, this maturity. So, basically, bureaucratic issues, red tape issues that ended up in delaying the timeframe we had, okay? And it will be delayed by 30 days.</p>
          <p>We were expecting to end this tender offer, at the beginning when we started this process, by the end of June, however, with the setbacks we will &#x2013; we're expecting to end it by the end of July. If everything runs smoothly, CVM will approve it by the end of May, and at the beginning of June we will be able to publish the tender offer notice, okay? But we got to wait for the final approval from the CVM to start the tender offer, otherwise even though we have the approve from the Central Bank, the party, the government party that is responsible for setting the rules for tender offers and IPOs et cetera is the CVM, so we got to wait for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And assuming that you get the approval from them end of May, it then takes up to two months to complete the process, that will put you into the end of July?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the legal framework that we must comply with. So, usually it's two months, because you've got to publish the notice, the tender offer must be opened for 30 days minimum and then you have all the closing of the deal and the final payments, okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Geovanne.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Mario Pierry with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, everybody. I have two questions. The first one is on Nossa Caixa, if by now if you're able to quantify any of the synergies that you expect to achieve from this merger, either on the fees or on the cost base. And then second question is related to the &#x2013; I would assume you will be starting your negotiations for the equalization revenues for the next agriculture cycle, if you have had any indications already if the government is willing to maintain the ROE for the business or if you seeing any indication that the equalization revenues would imply a lower ROE for the business in the next 12 months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Mario, it's Aldo speaking. Regarding the equalization process under discussion and negotiation, we didn't started yet the negotiation. And the ROE that will be in place (47.47) in our negotiation with the government is the same level that we had last year, which was 18% ROE. So, as soon as we start this we will let you know that we had already started the negotiation with the National Treasurer (48.06), but, in fact, we didn't do it yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Aldo, if you can just remind me then, when do you normally start this negotiation, and also if this minimum ROE that you can negotiate, if this is based on the levels of the Selic or if it based on the profitability of the private sector bank, or how is this 18% ROE determined?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Usually we start this negotiation by the end of May. So, pretty soon we will be starting this negotiation. And the figure, this 18%, is something that is discussed in the Board of Directors of Banco do Brasil, is in line with our main shareholder expect of our earnings. So this number is settled by the Board of Directors of the Bank.</p>
          <p>Regarding your other question, Mario Pierry, the synergies, the only number that we have disclosed was the synergy study carried out by Accenture, that was the company we hired to evaluate what would be the positive and negative synergies we would see during this consolidation period. I don't &#x2013; I'm not aware if they have revised it downward because of this tighter economic scenario, but, meanwhile, we are working pretty hard trying to speed up all the consolidation period. Could you hold on a second, please?</p>
          <p>Okay. Well, I am here with the general manager responsible for the consolidation of Nossa Caixa and he's telling me that the synergies are being under review because of this tighter scenario, however, for now, unfortunately, I don't have any numbers that I could share with you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Victor Galliano with HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Yeah, firstly, on asset quality and looking in particular at Banco Votorantim, it looks to me from the slide that you've given us, the coverage ratio is about 105% in Banco Votorantim and this is based on 90 days. Can you give us some sort of data here in terms of what the past-due loan ratio is on 60-days basis for Votorantim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, hold on a second, Victor, you want to know the past-due loans ratio for 60 days -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Marcelo, are you on line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, unfortunately, we don't have this figure right now. We have been working with the figure of past due till 90 days and we would have to inform later this for your department, Geovanne, would be that okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. No problem. We can follow-up on that specific question, Victor, later, because I was talking to Marcelo, the CFO of Votorantim, he's participating in this call as well and he got to work on that data to disclose it to you, okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The other thing I was going to ask was according to our calculations it looks like there was a very sharp increase in the NPL formation in the quarter in agribusiness. Can you comment on that? Was there any particular segment of agribusiness where you saw such in NPL formation in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Give me just one sec, okay. Victor, I don't know which table you are using to take out this conclusions, but if you look at table 73, you will see that in terms of risk concentration there was just a slight increase from D to H risk in the agri book. As of December '08 we had 14% and it ran up to 14.6%, okay. And basically, if you look here in terms of provisions due to risk migration, from December to March, in December was R$889 million of provisions reinforcement due to risk deterioration and in March it was R$873 million. It was even lower. The difference was because of the improvements in the risk because we had better improvements &#x2013; higher improvements in Q4 than we had in Q1, so the net impact gives us the idea that there was an increase in NPL formation due to risk migration. But if you look separately, the problem was that we didn't have the improvements in the risk, but in terms of risk deterioration there was a reduction in the formation of provisions. But it's important to mention, if you look on table 76, that was an increase in past due loans for more than 90 days in those old loans that were renegotiated, that were restructured, okay. Provisions, the volume of loans that were past due in December was R$259 million, it went up to R$377 million, because of that, past due loans for more than 90 days over the restructured loan portfolio increased from 1.8 to 2.6%. And that's why provisions here went up as well, to cover these loans. Let me ask our Agribusiness Director if he has any comments on what happened here in this restructured loans. Wait a minute, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>According to my Agribusiness Director, he was explaining to me, Victor, that these restructured loans, many of them would have their installments becoming due, okay, and they could negotiate how to pay these installments and there was a kind of lock period, okay. And this due date was December. So for those customers that had restructured loans that could join this negotiation, they had up to December to formally join this negotiation. The ones that did not join the negotiation by December, Banco do Brasil called off the lock-up period and downgraded increasing provisions for these loans that did not, how can I say,  joined this payment negotiation. And this downgrade was retroactive, so we got all the <mark type="inaudible" /> since the last payments until now, that's why there was this increase from 259 million to R$377 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay, thank you. And just one final question on Votorantim, when do you expect that to be consolidated, end of the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That's it. Of course, Victor, we need the final approval of Central Bank. We are expecting this by the end of this semester, so probably we will be able to consolidate Votorantim figures in Banco do Brasil numbers by the end of this semester.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Jorg Friedemann with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I have just one question, it's regarding treasury results. I can see in the MD&amp;A that other revenues included in your gross margin calculation remained virtually stable whereas other private banks grew those treasury revenues pretty strongly during the same period. I also realize that exposure to fixed rate instrument declined in first quarter versus the past quarter, and that exposure to public bonds I much higher in the case of Banco do Brasil compared to other private banks. So, I expect that lower contribution from treasury revenues to the formation of Banco do Brasil's gross margin, and would like to know if you agree with this statement whether you could see an improvement of those lines by a higher risk take? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in part, we do agree with you, Jorg, but it's important to understand what happened in our treasury and what happened in our peers' treasury. They made lots of money this first quarter because of the mark-to-market especially in private bonds. Banco do Brasil does not have an impressive exposure to private bonds. So that's why our treasury was mainly affected by &#x2013; our treasury results were mainly affected by changes in the Selic rate. So since we did not have this mark-to-market affect to price up the bonds, the private bonds, we didn't post a very strong treasury result this quarter, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And to this point, do you think that Banco do Brasil could make some improvement in these lines in the future by taking more risk or do you think that's going to be difficult?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Jorg, we have here a sort of program to improve private risk in terms of our portfolio of bonds and securities but we are going very slow in this movement because many of the issuers in Brazil, they are also companies that demand credit from Banco do Brasil and we have only one credit limit, or limit of credit for this company. So we have to accommodate both credit and bonds in the same amount of limit, so we are going very slow because we're not increasing the limits of our credits for the companies, at least right now. But in the future, yes, definitely we need to increase this portfolio of private bonds and securities in our portfolio. There's a program to do that and I expect to be able to increase this by the second half of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Understood. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's question-and-answer session. Mr. Aldo, at this time you may proceed with your closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you all. We appreciated very much everyone's attention, and if you need further information about Banco do Brasil, please, contact our IR Team or visit our website. Have a good day and a nice weekend and until another opportunity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That concludes our Banco do Brasil conference call for today. As a reminder, the material used in this conference call is available on the Bank investor relations website. Thank you very much for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>