<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1434496" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-11-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>27961</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Investor Relations Person">Gilberto Louren&#xE7;o da Aparecida</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="BTG Pactual CTVM SA">Marcelo Henriques</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="VP-Finance, Capital Market &amp; Investor Relations">Ivan de Souza Monteiro</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Jorge Kuri</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Daniel Adrian Abut</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs Brasil Banco M&#xFA;ltiplo SA">Carlos Macedo</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Saul Martinez</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities USA, Inc.">Victor Galliano</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Ita&#xFA; Corretora de Valores SA">Regina Longo Sanchez</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (Brasil) SA CTVM">Marcelo Telles</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you for standing by. We will now begin Banco do Brasil's Third Quarter 2011 Results Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question-and-answer session, and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded in a live broadcast with a slide presentation on the Bank's website, at Investor Relations site, where questions may be sent through.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that this presentation may include references and statements, planned synergies, increasing estimates, projections of results and future strategy for Banco do Brasil, its associated and affiliated companies and subsidiaries. These expectations are highly dependent on the market conditions, on Brazil's economic and banking system of performances, as well as an international market one. Banco do Brasil is not responsible for bringing up to date any estimated information in this presentation.</p>
          <p>First, we're going to have some details of the results. At the end of the presentation, the executives will answer the questions from the participants. With us today, Mr. Ivan Monteiro, CFO, and Mr. Gilberto Louren&#xE7;o, Head of IR.</p>
          <p>Mr. Gilberto, you may begin the conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I thank everybody to have the time to take to be in our conference call today about the third quarter results. Good morning. I'll start our presentation on slide number three. We have the main highlights from the third quarter 2011. There was the credit portfolio still growing; the level of delinquency, absolutely, under control; our control on expense is tight; and the business diversification.</p>
          <p>From slide four on, we will see more details from the results. In the first nine months of 2011, we reached the recurring net income of R$8.7 billion, a growth up to 25% in 12 months.</p>
          <p>On the following slide, number five, we show how we were able to deliver these operational results. In the revenue side highlights to the results from the insurance operation, which in 12 months came from 3.3% to 3.9% in revenue generation.</p>
          <p>One year ago, the operating expenses were responsible for almost 51% of the total revenues of Banco do Brasil. In the first nine months of 2011, this share dropped to less than 49%. It is also worth to highlight that the loan loss provision, which share in the total expenses reduced &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; share in the total revenues reduced from 21% to 20%.</p>
          <p>On slide number six, we can observe that along with the assets we kept our leadership in the main segments of the Brazilian Banking Industry. We are leading in everything that matters in the Banking Industry: in assets, loan portfolio, deposits, in assets under management.</p>
          <p>Moving to next slide, slide number 7, we observe that we're still the largest bank in Latin America with assets amounting more than almost R$950 billion.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, number eight, we have new information which allows us to understand the funding movements and the use of those sources. In one year, we can see an increase in the funding through letter of credit, commercial letter, commercial papers, agribusiness letter of credit and debentures of 271%. We can also observe that the share of compulsory deposits increased 90 basis points in one year due to change in the rule of the Brazilian Central Bank. The reduction of 80 bps in the loan-to-deposits ratio is due to the higher increase in the net funding.</p>
          <p>To complement the previous information on deposits, here on slide number nine we have the fund expansion, which grew more than 20% in one year. Banco do Brasil's distribution network, once again, allowed the maintenance of our leadership in deposits. Actually, Banco do Brazil has one-fourth of the total deposits in the banking industry.</p>
          <p>Facing the economic scenario and adopting a more conservative approach, Banco do Brasil's prioritized the growth on time deposits. The share of time deposits in the total deposits came from 55% in September 2010 to 60% in Q3, while demand deposits came from 16.9% to 13.7%. As observed on slide number eight and with more details here on slide number 10, it is clear that despite the additional funding, Banco do Brasil is diversifying its base, mainly through agricultural and financial letters, which together grew 415% over the September 2010.</p>
          <p>Banco do Brasil also had an increased access to funding sources abroad. On the slide 11, we show that the amounts raised grew substantially, 35% in one year. Highlight to Interbank Fund, which only in September had a renovation or revolving ratio of 120%.</p>
          <p>On slide number 12, we released new information regarding the formation of our net interest income in the period to investigate the margin or have better idea of the margin formation. On one hand, we have loan operation margin considering the cost of opportunity in loan operation and we have also &#x2013; and we had the information related to the funding and we have the opportunity of revenues that are in this kind of business. As you can see in this slide, the loan operation margin increased in the quarter 6.2% while, in the other hand, the funding margin decreased 1.3%. We have at the end of the day our net interest income increasing 0.9%, amounting R$10.7 billion.</p>
          <p>On slide 13, you have the information about the spreads. Slide 13, observe that the global spread decreased 20 bps quarter-over-quarter. This movement essentially motivated by the increasing funding cost in comparison with SELIC rate as well when compared to the same effect in the net interest margin adjusted by risk.</p>
          <p>Here on slide 14, we have the spread by segment and the total portfolio. On the total portfolio observe an increase of 20 bps in the quarter due to good growth in the business and in agribusiness portfolio spreads. Individual portfolio, the 40 bps decrease is explained by the strong growth in margin operation as opposed to the drop in the share of operation with high yield such as overdraft account and consumer loan and other consumer loans.</p>
          <p>On slide 15, we have the historical series of our FX exposure which is, in the reduced level, bringing no relevant impact to Banco do Brasil net interest income. Extracting the information about the loan portfolio on slide 16, we have absorbed that Banco do Brasil kept it's leadership in a great market, about 20%; the portfolio reached at R$441 billion including private securities and bank guarantees. We got a 21% growth in one year. If you take a look in the portfolio, Banco do Brasil has maintained our strategy to increase the portfolio and credit to individuals that amounts to R$125.8 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide 17 brings us the individual &#x2013; the business portfolio, where once again we can see the increase in operation with lower risk profile, such as those linked to payrolls, auto loans and mortgage. Those operation represents more than 80% of this portfolio; that's good because in those operations we have a better shape in terms of credit risk.</p>
          <p>Talking a little about our fast growing portfolio mortgage, on slide 18, we have disbursement and contracts to individuals business third quarter 2010. Q3 disbursements were 2.4 times higher than those accounted in the third quarter 2010.</p>
          <p>Also regarding mortgage, slide 19 brings us the same information as the previous one, but to the corporate segment. As you can see, the number of contracts increase three times in one year while disbursements grew almost five times in the same period.</p>
          <p>Now on slide 20, we have the evolution of the business portfolio which grew 21.6% in 12 months, highlights the investment in secured operations that already represent almost 30% of the total portfolio to companies.</p>
          <p>Moving now to slide 21, we have the breakdown of the corporate portfolio. We can see relevant growth in operation with medium and large companies and also in SME segments. On SME segment, we are focusing on operations collateral, as we can see on slide 22. As an example, FGO the guarantee fund for that segment. In September 2011, there were more than R$451,000 operation of this collateral, which reached the balance of R$8.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Regarding our foreign trading portfolio, we see on slide 23 that Banco do Brasil presence abroad is fundamental to support this market. The B remains leader in import and export market and also in trading financing.</p>
          <p>The slide 24 brings us disbursement of investment loans, which reached R$8.6 billion in Q3 and R$21.5 billion in the first nine months of 2011. We would like to highlight once again that the investment finance will bring great opportunities to Brazilian banks in the next years as an important cross-selling driver.</p>
          <p>And on slide 25, we present the quarterly disbursement of BNDES card, quiet leading product of Banco do Brasil, leading in wide range in terms of amounts disbursed, number of cards and transactions. And now in this quarter we launched our brand new card, BNDES card, using MasterCard brand.</p>
          <p>On slide 26 &#x2013; and the next slide brings us some information on the agribusiness portfolio. Banco do Brasil has a market share close to 62%, being the major partner of the Brazilian agribusiness. The portfolio is increasing in a consistent way with highlights of corporate loans.</p>
          <p>On slide 27, we have the use of insurance and agricultural loans, 60% of the working capital lines. From 2011, 2012 crop were contracts with some kind of risk mitigator. In the bottom of this slide, we have the map with distribution of this type of insurance.</p>
          <p>Moving on with the Agribusiness, slide 28 shows us that the investment in Agribusiness guaranteeing more efficiency to the production; better seeds, fertilizers, machinery have made possible the increase in productivity. Slide 29 shows us that the main cultures bring good profitability to the producers, as soybeans with 51% margin, corn with 44%, both project through to 2011-2012 crop.</p>
          <p>Finally, ending our information on Agribusiness, slide 30 shows us that the share of renegotiated loans in Agribusiness portfolio is decreasing quarter-over-quarter. In 2008, those operations represented 22.7% of the total portfolio. In September 2011 this share dropped to 6.9%.</p>
          <p>Now talking about quality of our portfolio, slide 31 brings the credit risk. The operations with better risk of AA to C came from 92.8% in September 2010 to 93.9% this year as a consequence of the quality of our loans origination.</p>
          <p>Slide 32 brings us the delinquency ratios and confirms the strategy of concentrating the book on lower risk operation. The NPL ratio of Banco do Brasil quite better than the market. While the market are accounting 3.5% as of September, 2011, Banco do Brasil accounted 2.1%.</p>
          <p>Slide 33 pictures the delinquency by portfolio. Here in the quarterly corporation a slight worsening, 20 bps, in the business portfolio and a slight improvement, 10 bps, in the business portfolio and Agribusiness present a quite good partner at 0.9% in terms of 90 days NPL.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 34, we can see some brand new information related to the breakdown of our provision, the outstanding provision of Banco do Brasil. As presented this slide, as you can see, those provisions related to regular operation has increased and those provision related to past due operations has decreased when compared to September 2010. Those provision are above the potential bank regulation has maintained at R$1.9 billion.</p>
          <p>Moving to the slide 35, we see that a covered ratio of Banco do Brasil over the NPL 90 days quite above the system. Banco do Brasil account is 220% while the market, 160%.</p>
          <p>Slide 36, we have some information about renegotiate portfolio &#x2013; the restructured portfolio. And I would like to thank everybody that granted us feedback in that regard. Because of it we are introducing this information in our company. As you can see, the total amount of restructured loans is R$7.7 billion, the outstanding provision related to that R$1.8 billion, NPL 90 days is R$600 million and the coverage ratio that is about 261%, so quite a good numbers related to our restructured loans.</p>
          <p>Now on slide 37, we have some information on our branch network in Brazil such as market share and distribution region. As you see, Banco do Brasil extends 25% of the total branch network in Brazil. I'd like to call your attention for North East position of Banco do Brasil with amounted 37% market share in that division, the fastest growing region in Brazil. And quite good provision other region to enjoy the dynamic of our economy.</p>
          <p>Slide 38, we have the commercial revenues that comprise net interest income, fee income and insurance income per customer. That increased more than 6% in one year as a consequence of our investment and enhanced the retail segment of the bank.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 39, we can see that the business expansion is being followed by a strict control of expenses. The ratio of expenses to assets have decreased every quarter. As you can see on the slide 40, as a consequence from the increase in fees and the expense control, Banco do Brasil cost/income ratio has got better. The efficiency ratio in 12 months reached 41.1%; last year this number was 44%.</p>
          <p>Here in slide 41, we have some information about our revenue diversification. The Brazilian market is moving to a fee-based model and the market segments shown have high growth rates; highlight to insurance operational revenues, which were responsible for 4.5% from last year and 5.2% this year considering these revenues related to insurance those in the financial revenue side.</p>
          <p>Regarding new business on slide 42, you notice that the recent restructuring of our insurance department or insurance area, including the reorganization in our affiliated companies, is already bringing good results. The insurance results in the Banco do Brasil has increased more than 28% in one year.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 43, also regarding those new business, we observed that the cards billing or the cards volume has increased more than 25% in one year. In the first nine months of 2011, the market share reached 21.3% from 20.6% last year.</p>
          <p>On slide 44, observe the consolidation of our capital market business. Banco do Brasil in that segment has presented a quite outstanding leadership in the fixed income business.</p>
          <p>Slide 45 has more to tell us on Banco do Brasil operational result and I'd like to call your attention for the reduction that we have in the revenues related to actual gains and the increase that we accounted in legal risk, mostly related to labor claims.</p>
          <p>On slide 46, we have BIS ratio of Banco do Brasil which, at the end of September, reached 4.05%. That's the pro forma number that includes some commercial paper that we are applying Central Bank to be considered as Tier 2 capital.</p>
          <p>Moving to the next slide, wrapping up our presentation, we have the guidance granted by Banco do Brasil. I'd like to call your attention by the revision we deployed this quarter reduced our net interest income expectation from 16% to 20% to 11% to 13%. If you take a look overall, our guidance is quite matching the expectation that we had at beginning of the year in terms of return on assets. We accounted 22.4%, quite in the mid of the guidance. Total deposits are slightly above the guidance, as I mentioned previously in the presentation, 20.4%.</p>
          <p>Our credit portfolio increasing &#x2013; would be in the guidance 15.6%; as planned by Banco do Brasil more concentrated in credit individuals that has grown 17.1%. At provision expenses credit costs, below the guidance we accounted 3% nine months 2011. Fee income growing pretty much close to the guidance at 11.4%, admin expenses quite outstanding performance at 7.8% below the guidance, and tax rate at 31%.</p>
          <p>So those were the words that we would like to share with you and now we are open for the Q&amp;A session. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Excuse me, Mr. Marcelo Henriques with BTG Pactual would like to ask a question. Mr. Henriques, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. I have a couple of questions. The first one is on the interest income. I'm having difficulty in understanding. If you look at the slide 12, just to ask you guide more directly, what &#x2013; can you give us more color on what is this other line use and why has this decreased quite substantially quarter-on-quarter? And then, I'll ask the follow-up questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The idea of slide 12, Marcelo, is only to give a better color and information of our net interest income, okay. So we are using here some methodology as explained in the bottom part of this slide. We have in the loan operation opportunity cost, so there is established price as opportunity cost. The same applied also in the funding side so we have opportunities revenues.</p>
          <p>So in the end, what explained better the behavior of the margin is the fact that we have this performance in the funding side decreasing 1.3% over the second quarter. So the rest, we have a quite good quarter in terms of credit portfolio increasing 6.2%. And there's movement in others. It is because in this cost &#x2013; opportunity costs and opportunity revenues methodology, we cannot capture everything related to the interest rate so on so forth. So there is no other major effect in the margin unless those related to the funding cost side. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But when you see the increasing fund cost &#x2013; but when I look at your balance sheet on the liability side, I mean if you compare to the other banks in terms of growth in terms of profits and <mark type="ph" /> letters of credit (26:15), so on so forth, it seems pretty similar to the system and also looking at the CD number, the one they have the registration of CDs this quarter.</p>
          <p>So I'm trying to understand how structural this change is? It's just &#x2013; I mean, is your funding cost actually increased this quarter and this will maintain in the following quarters? Because also when you compare the loan operations nine month to nine month, it actually increase just 6%. So I'm trying to understand how structural this change is and how do you see that on a going forward basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Ivan. It is not a structural thing as I mentioned before. We believe that we can benefit in the Q4. We just increased the liquidity of the bank because what we are &#x2013; we have seen; we have seen the best about the prices, but you are pretty comfortable that we don't need to do this, then you can say that it's not a trend and I believe that we could benefit in the Q4 because of this behavior in Q3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I think you have the outstanding amount enough and just for support operations in Q4 and increase your loans and this will &#x2013; your margins will kick up in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the strategy. That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On Banco Votorantim specifically, I saw the same behavior in terms of net interest margin, and actually I mean also looking at the balance sheet for overall Banco Votorantim, we have available here, term deposits and then deposits remain quite stable in the quarter. So again, it's like a huge spike in the interest expenses; it went from 10.3% to 11.3%. In this sense from Banco Votorantim, is this more structural than when it's compared to Banco do Brasil? Is this like this new cost of funding because of lengthening the tenor of the &#x2013; on the liability side? Is this for stay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Banco Votorantim is different because they don't have deposits there. They rely on Interbank lines and new issue CDs or CPs or things like that. It's completely different from Banco do Brasil. What we are trying to do &#x2013; and since we joined the bank, we can see that the size of the fund increased. The verification of the fund increased. But the costs didn't decrease, didn't reduce in the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (28:47).</p>
          <p>What we are trying to do is to reduce the special, to increase the maturity of the fund because it is good to upgrade to more stability in this funding. Remember that if you don't have the branch network as we have, we have less alternative to diversify our source of funding.</p>
          <p>I believe that they made a very good job. Remember that they issue of lot bonds and get this benefit from funding in a lower price. But in my opinion we are more focused now to create more stability and to do this without <mark type="ph" /> deploying (29:19) the cost of this fund. This is completely different from Banco do Brasil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But if you look at the numbers and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:24) because I wasn't able to translate the Portuguese for some of the reason, but if you look at from third quarter 2010, it was 9.7% and then increased to 10.3% in the second quarter and now it's 11.3% in the third quarter. So you think that this will move upwards or you think that the lengthening of the tariffs, it's already happened and this will be the new, let's say, new funding cost of Banco Votorantim or do you think there is more to come?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't. I believe that we are in the very good level &#x2013; talking about the liquidity in Banco Votorantim, we are in a very good level. And the same behavior, we imagine that this crisis &#x2013; now I believe that the European crisis is coming to an end. I don't know what kind of end, but in my opinion we don't expect to increase this. As I mentioned, changing of &#x2013; talking about Banco do Brasil, we could benefit in the fourth quarter because of this behavior in Q3. But again, Banco Votorantim, if you analyze its cost of the funding it's completely different from Banco do Brasil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just on &#x2013; just one last question on BIS, very strong both Banco do Brasil and Votorantim. What is the strategy? Now the Tier 1 is at 10.6 at Banco do Brasil. Tier 1 of Banco Votorantim in the second quarter was 9.7. So if I assume that there was higher basis point decline, we're choosing a line of the BIS reduction of Banco Votorantim as a whole. It will bring your Tier 1 of Banco Votorantim to below 9%. On both banks, I mean, is there are any minimum level that raise like a yellow flag and this would make you think about a potential capitalization going forward than you have imagined?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, for Banco do Brasil, the minimum, the regulatory level is the level and we worked always with 13. And we try to apply the same for Banco Votorantim. Remember that in Banco Votorantim you have the opportunity to sell part of our portfolio. That is different from Banco do Brasil. That's why you can use more tools there. But again, we are waiting for the public hearing about Basel III, then we can establish a correct strategy. Basically on the measures that the regulators in Brazil put in place to be sure that Brazil will achieve the levels that Basel III will require in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one last question, sorry; I promise. On the &#x2013; if you look at Banco Votorantim itself, the profit sharing line has a percentage of your total net profit before this distribution as roughly 40%. I mean it's actually been accrued the past three quarters despite the, let's say, at least disappointing results of Banco Votorantim. Is this something that you accrue quarter-on-quarter and then at the end of the year you'll see that if it reached the results or not? And then you take it back or is this something that is already established, <mark type="ph" /> it's meant to be (32:51) because even this quarter that was a net loss; you accumulated like R$80 million in profit sharing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gilberto could you explain this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The fact &#x2013; the remuneration of Banco Votorantim increased quite a bit of remunerations are variable remuneration, so we account part of this expenses in profit sharing, so even have a loss, these two have protection so that explain why we have this level of R$81 million. But it's reduced because part of these remuneration is also related to the total performance of the bank in terms of net income. So this R$81 million, pretty much related to protection of Banco Votorantim increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll take that offline and then I'm just concluding. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Mr. Jorge Kuri of Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, everyone. I have a question also on your financial margins, not looking specifically a bit quarter-on-quarter change but taking a step back and looking at the last year. If I look at your reported net interest income and subtract the FX position hedge item, your trading gains and the <mark type="ph" /> qualitation (34:30) revenues so that I can isolate only what's really the intermediation business.</p>
          <p>I get to a growth for the first nine months of the year of 7.5% versus the previous &#x2013; versus 2010, also nine months of the year. So your financial revenues are growing at 7.5%, yet your earning assets grew 18%, including loans also around 18%, 19%; SELIC rates first nine months of this year are higher versus the first nine months of last year. Can you help us understand what's happening at the bank that your financial revenues are growing much slower than your assets even though you're seeing credit spreads go up in the system? So just help me understand why is it that you're growing at half the rate of overall asset growth? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Ivan; Jorge, the point is, first of all, there is not only one answer for this question first. The surge of the bank, when it comes to credit portfolio, has been increasing in those more collateralized. It has been for a while; if you take a look in everything that we have presented to the market for instance, the breaking now of correct portfolio to individuals has increasing those more collateralized. I mean payroll loans, car financing, more recently mortgage. The consequence of this that we can have a better shape in terms of correct portfolio. On the other hand we can &#x2013; we have pressure in our margin, okay.</p>
          <p>Talking about specifically this quarter, we have another effect that was first the increase in SELIC rate for all kind of floating funding that we have in our liability and the increase of the cost of this funding also as presented on the slide where we show the cost of our deposits increasing from 64% to 67%, okay. In another point it is the fact the deposits, especially time deposit, gained participation the total funding of the bank.</p>
          <p>So talking about specifically this quarter, the pressure that we have in margin, it's quite manageable to be better shaped in the following quarter because next quarter we have reduction in interest rate and we have increasing non-interest bearing liabilities like demand deposits because of liquidity in economy. So basically it's that; so this structure side could be the strategy of the bank in growing those lower-yield operation, as I mentioned, and in more conjunction side this increasing cost that we have in the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And so going forward should we assume this next level of evolution between earning asset growth and financial income growth? Are you still going to see significantly lower growth in your net interest income relative to the asset base?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Going forward, we have to assume the guidance that we grant to the market. The NII growth guidance is to be 11 to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am thinking about 2012; I mean, obviously, 2011 is done, so I am thinking...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah; more falling in the region of earning assets, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fall in the region of the earning assets growth. You can assume it's that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Less than earning asset growth or inline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, falling; the same pace, in the same pace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So then, does that mean that you are going change the strategy? So you just told me that over the last 12 months you've been focusing on more secured type of credit, therefore the mix have deteriorated towards lower NIMs; does that mean that if you're going forward that's not going to be the case that your volumes are going to grow in line with your financial income?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but we have &#x2013; sorry to interrupt, but we have to bear in mind that within the earnings assets, credit portfolio if you expect to have a better growth or credit portfolio being ahead of other assets we can recover little bit the return of the assets by this measure; increasing the credit portfolio in the total earnings assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. So then my second question is, so if I take down safe values, you're going towards more secured products. If I then adjust that number by the provisions, I end up with a post-provision financial income growth of 9% year-on-year, so those are not &#x2013; I mean it doesn't seem to be having to &#x2013; adding much to the financial income growth. Is there a time lag? I mean are we supposed to see that paying off for you guys in terms of growing your risk adjusted margins faster at some point or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Jorge, we have &#x2013; we can follow up with your question; you can give me a call in that regard because you are using our methodology to assets but what we can tell you that, our guidance related to provision is quite under control because we have accounted 3% of the total credit portfolio and the reduction that we have in risk adjust margin mostly explain of this phenomenon third quarter related to the cost of funding, okay.</p>
          <p>So what I am trying to tell you, that in the fourth quarter we tend to recover the net interest income of Banco do Brasil, so we tend to have a better net interest margin the fourth quarter and as a consequence of this, recovering the adjust net interest margin because we are not seeing any deterioration in the credit risk side. So that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you, thanks. My last question is regarding Banco Postal; can you give us some color on what level of expenditures are you anticipating in order to ramp up that business? How does your &#x2013; I know you're not providing guidance for 2012, but just give me a sense &#x2013; because I'm assuming a lot of those expenses are going to be over the next 12 months, how the expenses will look 2012 versus 2011 given that you have to ramp up that quite large business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you are right. We didn't give yet any guidance related to 2012. But the business model for Banco Postal is pretty much linked to variable costs than fixed costs because we're going to use our structure of Banco Postal to originate the business so their personnel, their structure, their marketing, so on and so forth, okay.</p>
          <p>The only expense that you're going to have because of the increasing that business will be those related to the variable cost, the expense related to the transaction, so give an example. If they collect the deposits we can have &#x2013; we have to pay a percentage of the deposits. So as long as we have business, we're going to have expense; but of course with margin, with gain of margin. That's the rationale behind the Banco Postal model. So the major expense that we're going to have related to Banco Postal would be those &#x2013; the amortization of intangible that we paid to Banco Postal, this R$2.8 billion; that's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you, Gilberto.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Daniel Abut of Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Gilberto. A couple of one-off questions and then one more specific question about <mark type="indiscernible" /> (43:28). Follow-up on the prior questions, you said that you got to value you would expect next year to have manage this income growth more in line with asset growth. Although you're not giving guidance here, what are you thinking in terms of loan growth for next year, at least as a soft indication? You started this year thinking that it was going to be 15% to 18% of your domestic portfolio. It seems you're going to end the year closer to the low end of that range, closer to the 15% level. What is your current thinking in terms of volume growth for next year, at least as a soft indication?</p>
          <p>And then in expenses, it's actually quite remarkable that you are the bank that are performing the best with these expenses we see here, even though you don't have any significant merger synergies, anything like that to obtain. What has been allowing you to grow expenses in only single-digits? Is it a cost saving coming from the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (44:22) acquisition that have come in later, even though that was not the reason why you did the transaction?</p>
          <p>What has caused it? In a year where inflation has been running close to that level that you've been growing expenses only vary with inflation and what does this mean for next year? Do you think you can repeat that performance of growing expenses vary with inflation or there was something one-off this year and looks difficult to repeat next year? After you answer these two follow-up questions I'll come back with one more specific on Votorantim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Daniel. So talking about spread, growth expectations and so of course, we, as I mentioned, we didn't give any guidance for 2012. But following, the main driver problem is going to be having growth, to repeat in that we have 2011, something close to 15%; that's our expectation. Of course, we have to wait to see what's going to be the guidance granted by the bank at the beginning of next year. But potentially 15% tends to be a reasonable number.</p>
          <p>Expenses; the behavior that we have in expenses really is pretty much close to our discipline &#x2013; cost discipline of Banco do Brasil. There is no way out, Daniel. Margin, we have pressure in margin that over time trend for banking. So we have to be very disciplined when it comes to cost and we have succeed to do it so. So part of this performance is explained by the synergy gains come from Banco <mark type="indiscernible" /> (46:02), but also by a very, very strict cost control that we have in Banco do Brasil and we tend to have the same approach for next year. We do not expect anything more than to be as strict in cost control through next year, okay. So we tend to follow the driver related to expense that are inflation, something like that or so some organic growth by the year end. We tend to seek single-digit growth, maximum 10% growth for next year in expenses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you repeat the end? I kind of lost the number. We wait for your guidance early in the year, which you normally do. But your current thinking is that another year of high single-digit expense growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>High single digit; maximum 10% growth. That's all I can say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good, Gilberto. But quickly on Votorantim, although you have mentioned in prior questions that most of the issue is related to funding there, and then in the words of the European effect start to a very rapid improve, but I also noted that a very significant increase in BNP ratio of Votorantim in this quarter. Although it was not significant &#x2013; not material for the overall NPL ratio of Banco do Brasil, it may be an issue for the business of Votorantim going forward. So what's going on there? Is this related to the Banco do Brasil loans that affected the auto lending business and when do you think that situation is going to normalize and therefore allow Votorantim to be more &#x2013; to be stronger on the regulation side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's mixed with the market prediction measures, but we believe &#x2013; we are trying to stabilize this and to the end of 2011 and we are pretty sure that we are going to do this. If you share the business in Banco Votorantim you have the &#x2013; like quarter-to-quarter wealth and asset management business doing very, very well. The broker/dealer is the same and indeed this <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:18) you have only car finance and payroll; payroll is dong very well. The problem is only related to car finance. We took a lot of measures just to be sure that we can establish our target for to start decreasing the NPL ratio due to &#x2013; overdue 90 days and we are pretty sure that we can do this and through the end of 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ivan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Daniel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Carlos Macedo of Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, Gilberto; good morning, Ivan. I have a couple of questions. Going back to Banco Votorantim, I understand that the NPL ratios, that you're looking for ways to improve them. But at the same time you &#x2013; the loan growth and the auto line still remains fairly robust. If you include the loans that get sold in auto, probably to Banco do Brasil itself, we would see even stronger growth coming from that line. And the bank reported I think &#x2013; well, reported an R$80 loss and really hasn't had stellar performance on the ROE side since the acquisition.</p>
          <p>What have you been doing &#x2013; I mean it is the auto book responsible for everything there, for the 13% of ROE that we're seeing &#x2013; that we've been seeing is being the most recurring ROE there? What do you expect out of Banco Votorantim? What should we expect when we look at it and analyze it as being part of Banco do Brasil?</p>
          <p>The second question is little bit more specific. Fee income growth for you guys expanded significantly in the second quarter vis-&#xE0;-vis &#x2013; or third quarter vis-&#xE0;-vis the second. A lot of it seemed to be driven by an increase in other fees. I was just wondering what exactly ends up being that line that pushed your fee income higher and should we expect that to remain at a high level in the fourth quarter and next year? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Carlos, talking about the Banco Votorantim, the target there is to be close up to the ROE of Banco do Brasil. That's what we are working to do this.</p>
          <p>The problem that we are facing on the <mark type="ph" /> Banco Votorantim (50:28), as I mentioned before, we are trying to fix immediately as soon as possible. But again, if you share the bank and you get all the wholesale, the wholesale is doing very well. But we acquired this bank focused on car finance. We didn't have the technologies to originate the assets inside the dealers that we do inside the banks of Banco do Brasil; that's why we decided to acquire. And we're trying to improve, just focus on next week &#x2013; I'm sorry, on next year.</p>
          <p>You're going to see a new regulatory environment and you can &#x2013; and in this new regulatory environment, we want to be sure that the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (51:06) is profitable business to run. That's why we are doing now and not waiting for the impact of this regulatory environment in 2012.</p>
          <p>That's why &#x2013; and we &#x2013; in Banco do Brasil, we have &#x2013; we are &#x2013; we have a very conservative approach talking about the provisions. We are trying to do the same in Banco Votorantim. That's why we are now trying to reduce the production in September, October, November and December just to be sure that we are getting the best cars, the best originations, the best assets. Just to be sure that we can reduce the delinquencies there not only now, but for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so, Ivan, if you allow me a follow-on to this, so we should expect the profitability to resume or to go back to the levels that we saw on previous quarter around between 10% and 15%. But to get around 20%, which is where Banco do Brasil typically has been, probably something for the end of 2012 or should we expect that earlier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe at the end of 2012. Why? Because that the cost of funding there is different from Banco do Brasil. We have a very good cost of funding. That's why &#x2013; it's difficult. If you put the cost of funding for Votorantim and if you get the new environment regulatory environment for 2012, in car finance you see that there is a dramatic reduction on the ROE of this business. That's why we have took the measures &#x2013; we take the measures now. Just to be sure that we can preserve, we can keep profitability even with the costs, the actual costs of funding but in an environment that's &#x2013; for example, you are not able to get up front the benefit if you decided to sell part of our portfolio. We are doing now and not waiting for what we expect to be the profitability of this business in 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Just on fees, then, the additional &#x2013; the fees that are outside the &#x2013; is this something that we should expect to see going forward at this level or what is something specific to this quarter that happened?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we identified was fees related to affiliated companies that accounted R$180 &#x2013; R$118 million in the third quarter. So probably those were related to the insurance companies, okay. So I would expect the same level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The same level and &#x2013; okay. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Up to now. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from the line of Saul Martinez of JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks taking my call. I have two follow-up questions. Quickly, first, I didn't understand the response to the first question on what exactly is in &#x2013; on slide 12, in the other line. The explanation for why sequentially net interest income evolution was poor was related to funding costs, but I would think that the higher funding costs related to growth in time deposits and higher costs on time deposit would have been in the line called funding. Yet the decline &#x2013; the poor NII evolution sequentially had more to do mathematically from a &#x2013; from a 44% quarter-on-quarter decline in the Other line. So I just want to understand what is in there. The &#x2013; your release says it has more to do with treasury items. I'm not sure how it's captured &#x2013; the higher funding costs are captured in that line. Can you just explain a little bit more in detail what's in there and why it was so poor this quarter?</p>
          <p>Secondly, on the capital issue, you mentioned the uncertainty around Basel III, the public hearing. Can you just talk a little bit about what your expectations are related to the implementation of Basel III in Brazil and whether that should be a concern in terms of capital adequacy and potentially the need to raise capital sooner than maybe the market is expecting? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So talking about the funding, as explained before, we have seen a decrease in the DDA deposits and increase in time deposits. And in time deposit don't increase in the price of this. As I mentioned before, it's a not a trend for us and we believe that we could benefit in Q4 because of this behavior. Related &#x2013; the majority related off the &#x2013; developed off the European price.</p>
          <p>Talking about the Basel III, we are waiting for the public hearing just to be sure what kind of measures that we need to put in place in the bank. But it's impossible to anticipate this without the final rules from Basel III. In Basel II, Brazil was not invited to participate in the discussion; completely different now in Basel III. The regulators in Brazil, they are following closely this issue and I believe that they will establish the same rules and in the same sets as the international rules will be disclosed by the Basel committee.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me just ask &#x2013; I understand conceptually about why the net interest income was sluggish. My question is why did the Other line on page 12 go from R$817 million to R$455 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you like to call me later?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To talk about it. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Victor Galliano of HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks. Most of my questions have been answered. But if I can just focus on, again, the outlook for 2012 and focusing here on cost and particular organic growth build out. Now you've got Banco Postal. What expectations do you have in terms of 2012 build out, if there is any, of main branches or other branches? And what sort of cost pressures could that put on? Would that threaten your, shall we say, soft early guidance of less than 10% OpEx growth? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the plan that we have related to opening a new branch, we tend to change a little bit. When it comes to the small branch, because we're going to fulfill our needs to serve our customers especially those customers that are underserved in our customer base through Banco Postal, okay. But other kind of branches for high incomes segment, we maintain the same plan.</p>
          <p>So when talking about the costs that we have planned to have next year, something close to 10% or below 10%, we are considered everything together. We are considered the development of Banco Postal, the investment that we have to make to fulfill other needs that we have in other segments, because the idea is the same. The idea is to maintain on track our strategy to enhance the retail segment because out there we're going to be &#x2013; we're going to have the increase in cross selling and more diversification revenue as I'm talking about; increasing the insurance segment business, credit card business and other businesses that tend to be very important to compensate any other impression that it can have in margin.</p>
          <p>So the plan, when it comes to investment and expense is the same. So everything together, we're going to stick at lower than 10%, something close to 10% expense in growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And do you have a number of branches or an idea of a number of branches you'd like to add anything in 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just one quick follow up if I may. On the renegotiated credits, and thank you for including that in the presentation, very helpful; and in your disclosure. But if we look at slide 30, which has the renegotiations for the Agribusiness book, are those included in the global numbers for renegotiated credits that you have for about R$8 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It is included.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So that 5.9 or whatever it is, 5.8...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is part of that R$7.7 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. You're right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Thiago Batista of Ita&#xFA;. Mr. Batista?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Yes, hello everybody, this is Regina Sanchez from Ita&#xFA; BBA. So my question is that we noted that you have classified premiums paid over acquired portfolios added to the net interest income. And this was one of the reasons to change the guidance of net interest growth. Actually, I would like to know, if you could let us know how much of this revision of guidance was related to this reclassification and how much was related to the higher funding costs as well as maybe lower trading results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Result of reclassification the net interest income of the bank would increase 11.5% instead of increasing 10%; so 150 basis point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was reclassification. The rest, Regina &#x2013; sorry, the rest is more related to the shape of the liability size so deposit growth, funding costs, so on so forth. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks you. Then my other question is regarding administrative expenses. I mean in order to achieve this guidance of growth between 9% and 12%, I think Banco do Brasil will need to post a more significant increase, maybe above 10%, in our calculation in the fourth quarter. If this is correct, what can have a more positive dynamics in the fourth quarter to maybe compensate partially these higher expenses? Do you think fees or maybe fee income, or do you think this administrative expenses could be even slightly below the guidance range?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. To be in the low &#x2013; sorry, Regina. To be in the low range of net interest income, we have to increase in the fourth quarter 4.5%, 5% over the third quarter net interest income. Fee income tends to follow the same written, growing above 5%; that's our expectation. Fourth quarter tends to be quite good for credit cards, for asset under management, so on and so forth.</p>
          <p>And we have a lot of expectation insurance business to compensate the seasonal behavior in expense side. Bear in mind that we have signed with the union the agreement, the salary agreement, and in average we tend to have 9% to 10% in personnel expenses growth over the third quarter. And we have more activity in the fourth that put more pressure in other expenses. So having 9% to 10% growth over the third quarter in expense is quite normal, quite seasonal effect. So quite compensated by other revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Marcelo Telles of Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everyone. I have two questions. The first one, I'm sorry to insist so much on this NII question, but I think it's important to get some more clarification on that. When I look in terms of Banco Votorantim, as pointed out earlier, I mean, there was a big drop in the NII quarter-over-quarter; about 8.5%. And I was wondering if there was &#x2013; given that this also had a big impact in the overall result of Banco do Brasil, we're talking about a net decline of R$120 million.</p>
          <p>So I was wondering if there is anything that related to a treasury loss at Votorantim and I ask that because when I look in terms of in the press release for the second quarter, I &#x2013; we can see that actually 200 basis points decline in the yield curve would actually lead Votorantim to post a loss of close to R$300 million in the quarter, right? And then when I look in the 3Q release, we see that they would still post a loss of R$107 million, so that means that they really haven't changed the exposure in terms of interest rate cuts. I mean, they'd lose money if interest rates go down and I'm talking about here &#x2013; hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and I'm talking about the trading portfolio. I'm talking about just the portfolio that is actually mark-to-market. So given that the yield curve actually shifted downwards by 200 bps, I would expect that Votorantim posted quite a big loss in the quarter and I was wondering if that has something to do with the very poor performance in NII at Votorantim given that the changed yield curve happened end of August and September.</p>
          <p>And the other question I have, on a different subject, is regarding the asset quality. I mean, if you look at your asset quality numbers, I mean, clearly, you are doing very well. But if we look at the NPL ratio on agricultural loans, it's pretty much at the historical lows. So going in 2012, do you expect those &#x2013; that NPL ratio to remain at such low levels, I believe like 0.9%? Because my concern is that if that NPL ratio goes up, or normalizes at least throughout 2012, you could actually have, let's say, a bigger impact in terms of the overall NPL ratio for Banco do Brasil and that could lead you to have much higher &#x2013; like provision expenses next year probably growing above your loan growth. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ivan, could you take that Votorantim question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Votorantim is not related with treasury. It's only related with the NPL ratio and the problems that we described before in car finance. That's the only reason. We don't believe and we are &#x2013; as the partnership with development, we are trying to get the conservative approach that we have here in Banco do Brasil and trying to do the same in Votorantim. Why? Because we feel comfortable with it.</p>
          <p>That's why &#x2013; don't expect any kind of difference related to things like treasury or to make money. Try to get the best knowledge about the trend for interest rates, for the exchange rate and things like that. Gilberto, could you help, talking about the second part of the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The historical level, we're not in the burn-off in terms of historical level because prior to 2005, the NPL ratio of the Agribusiness used to be 0.5%, 0.6%. So part of this 0.9% is still being affected by the fact that we do have size of portfolio with structured loans in Agribusiness. So it decreased, but it has demand more provision that reg life, I can say that operation.</p>
          <p>So we still have some room to maintain this improvement in Agribusiness because of this &#x2013; the reduction that we tend to have in the structured loans, okay. And compared to historical level, this portfolio &#x2013; it is &#x2013; has been originated in a better shape because now we are more &#x2013; we have the use of risk mitigators. We have direct loans only for those risk-free debtor. So they originate &#x2013; the quality of origination of Agribusiness is quite better than used to be in the past when it used to have this 0.5% NPL ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So your expectation for asset quality for next year, I mean looking at the bank as a whole, do you think &#x2013; do you expect the stability in NPL ratio to compare December '11 to December '12 or think it could deteriorate a little bit? And also, do you think your provision expenses can grow in line with the loan portfolio or they would tend to grow at a faster pace then your loan portfolio next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For time being the expectation is to follow the credit portfolio, okay. According to the guidance that we grant to the market, we still expect some slight deterioration because as you &#x2013; as we saw in our guidance, the provision expense that's published in the guidance is 3.3% to 3.7% and we still account at 3% yet.</p>
          <p>So if some deterioration can have, the maximum should be at the lower end of the guidance in terms of provision expenses. And this 2.1% increase, more 20 bps maximum, until the end of this year. That's the expectation that we have. Consider everything together including the behavior in Banco Votorantim book; I'm talking about Banco do Brasil as a whole. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. But my question is more like towards 2012. I mean you think that &#x2013; I mean you don't see any...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...maintaining the number that you're going to see at the end of December. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Basically flat NPL ratio for 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's our expectations for the time being.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For the time being. I mean are you getting more negative on the economy like for on the outlook for next year or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...the risk is more on the upside or the downside?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No I believe it's neutral. Until now it's neutral, because there's no further expectations to see major deterioration in the consumer finance side. I'm talking about unemployment rate. The expectation in terms of GDP, it should be at 3 something percent growth, so it's quite at reasonable level. So for the time being, according to the where we are in the economy, that's our expectation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This concludes today's question-and-answer session. Mr. Ivan, at this time, you may proceed with any closing statements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for the participation. And if you have an additional question, please call the Gilberto team or you can go on the IR department through internet. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude our Banco do Brasil's conference for today. As a reminder, the materials used in this conference call is available on the Bank Investor Relations website. Thank you very much for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>