<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1187605" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-10-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9041</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jean Philippe Leroy, Department Director</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Milton Almicar Silva Vargas, Executive Vice President</participant>
      <participant id="3">Jean Philippe Leroy</participant>
      <participant id="4">Saul Martinez</participant>
      <participant id="5">Mario Pierry</participant>
      <participant id="6">Samuel Monteiro dos Santos, Jr.</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. We would like to welcome everyone to Banco Bradesco's Third Quarter 2008 Earnings Results Conference Call. This call will be conducted by Mr. M&#xE1;rcio Artur Laurelli Cypriano, Chief Executive Officer; Mr. Milton Vargas, Executive Vice President, Investor Relations Officer; Mr. Samuel Monteiro dos Santos J&#xFA;nior, Chief Financial Officer of Bradesco Seguros Insurance; and Mr. Jean Philippe Leroy, Department Director.</p>
          <p>This call is being broadcasted simultaneously through the Internet, in the website, www.bradesco.com.br/ir. In that address, you can also find a banner through which the presentation will be available for download. We inform that all participants will only be able to listen to the conference call during the company's presentation. After the presentation, there will a question-and-answer session. At that time, further instructions will be given. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Forward-looking statements are based on the beliefs and assumptions of Banco Bradesco's management and on information currently available to the company. Forward-looking statements are not guarantee of performance. They involve risks, uncertainties and assumptions because they relate to future events and therefore depend on circumstances that may or may not occur in the future. Investors should understand that general economic conditions, industry conditions and other operating factors could also affect the future results of Banco Bradesco and could cause results to differ materially from those expressed in such forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll turn the conference over to Mr. Jean Leroy, Department Director. Mr. Leroy, you may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, everyone, and welcome to our conference call. Let me now move the floor to Mr. Milton Vargas, Bradesco's CFO for his opening remarks, and after that I will be conducting the PowerPoint presentation. Milton?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Bradesco recorded a net income of more than R$6 billion in the first nine months of 2008, and R$1.91 billion in the third quarter. Although the world's economic scenario is adverse, I would particularly like to highlight the efforts of the Brazilian authorities to mitigate the potential contagion in our country.</p>
          <p>Thanks to the measure conducted by the Brazilian Central Bank, Banco now has, one, extra resource for foreign trade; two, <mark type="inaudible" /> requirements were reduced, providing the economy a significant increase in liquidities; and three, the purchase of the loan portfolio is now motivated.</p>
          <p>In Bradesco's case, the effects of these measures will be felt over the coming period. We participate in the auction of credit lines for foreign trade, ensuring sufficient volume to meet the short-term demand. We have more than R$6 billion in reserve requirements released for operation. And finally, we have opportunities to acquire R$6 billion of loan portfolios from small and middle-size banks.</p>
          <p>In terms of GDP, the perspective for 2008 remains at around 5% and close to 3% for next year. The decline in the outlook of GDP for 2008 was expected, but Brazil's growth should still be well above the estimated figure for the developed economy.</p>
          <p>Before turning the floor over to Jean, I would just like to highlight some important numbers and drivers. We reached the mark of 20 million account holders, a result of both dedication of our staff and the usage of CRM tools we deliver to our Branch Managers. In the balance sheet, assets grew by more than 33% over the last 12 months with loans growing by 41%. On the liability side, the deposits increased by 60% in the period, and by 13% just in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Regarding revenues, over the last 12 months we were able to expand our net interest income by growing the loan portfolio and increasing fees, mainly in cards, consortium, and asset management. As for insurance and private pension plans and savings bond, we have increased premiums by 10.7% since September 2007, mainly in the life pension plan, also in health insurance segment.</p>
          <p>Personal expenses rose because of the increment of more than 3,600 employees due to our distribution network expansion and wage increase. The growth in administrative expenses was due to the expansion of activities, higher business volume, and solid investments in information technology, particularly in the IT improvement program.</p>
          <p>Overall, we emphasized our permanent concern on cost control and the struggle for higher efficiency. Over the last 12 months, we have expanded our distribution network, adding more than 7,500 owned and third-party customer service points. We opened 168th new branch in the period, reaching a total of 3,235 branch, allowing us to increasing further our market share from 16.8% in September 2007 to 17.4% in September 2008.</p>
          <p>The efficiency ratio calculated over the last 12 months improved from 41.8% at September 2007 to 41.6% last September. In addition, in the same period our insurance group also improved its combination ratio from 85.5 to 84.4. Grupo Bradesco de Seguros e Previd&#xEA;ncia records a net income of R$2.98 billion upto to September 2008, representing 36% of Bradesco's net income.</p>
          <p>And last, but not least, I would like to emphasize that Bradesco does not operate with target for derivatives or any other leveraged derivatives. Finally, I would like to emphasize that despite the dimension of the global crisis, we remain optimistic about the future. We intent to invest in the expansion of our distribution network in IT then in training of our staff.</p>
          <p>The Brazilian bank sector is robust and prepared to meet the demand and challenges of the market. On the top of that, banks are well capitalized in about the strict accounting standard and the best corporate governance practices. Brazil is enjoying is the best every economic fundamental. The unemployment rate is at its lowest level over the last 16 years, with more than 2 million registered jobs generated over the last 12 months. Moreover, the amount of salary has increased and the inflation is pointed out to the target set by the Brazilian Central Bank.</p>
          <p>I will now give the floor to Jean, and I will be at your disposal during the Q&amp;A session. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's move to Slide number two please. On slide two, you can see Bradesco's main performance indicators, as previously highlighted by Milton. Slide number three, Bradesco's net income in the first nine months of 2008 surpassed the mark of R$6 billion. Net of non-recurring events, accumulated net income stood at R$5.8 billion, an increase of around 9% in the period.</p>
          <p>Report net income of R$1.91 billion in the third quarter, a slight reduction on a quarter-over-quarter basis, impacted mainly by lower gains in financial margin of non-interest income, R$340 million net of taxes impacting this performance. This was partially offset by the reversal of provision, R$123 million net of taxes. Thanks to successful outcomes in tax lawsuits.</p>
          <p>Please note that all the comparative analysis and ratios in this presentation, in the press release and in the report on economic and financial analysis consider net income adjusted by non-recurring events.</p>
          <p>Slide number four. In this slide, we show that Bradesco's adjusted net income over the past quarters, which has presented consistent performance. Despite substantial investments in IT and the expansion of our distribution network, the efficiency ratio improved from 41.8 in September '07 to 41.6 in September '08, due to Bradesco's persistence in cost control. In the third quarter alone, Bradesco added around 500 customer service outlets, of which 318 advanced service branches. A marginal drop shown in the net income in the quarter is due to mark-to-market effect of own positions and a collective bargaining agreement with our employees.</p>
          <p>Slide number five. Bradesco's total assets reached R$423 billion in this quarter, increasing by 4.8% in the quarter and by 33% over the last 12 months. The quarterly growth was mainly due to the increase in the loan portfolio. And for the adjusted net income, the annualized return on average equity stood at 25.4% and the annualized return on average assets at 2%. The Capital Adequacy Ratio calculated inline with the new Basel Rules also called Basel II in the standard model reached 15.6%. This ratio gives us a capital margin of R$13.2 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide number six. Unrealized gain by Bradesco and its subsidiaries totaled R$2.012 billion in September '08. We should point out that the reduction in this quarter was mainly due to the mark-to-market effect of securities experienced in a period of very high volatility. Anyway, this does not mean lower expectation for future profits, since most of these assets are sovereign Brazilian bonds that guarantee technical provisions whose liabilities we are using a 4.3% per annum assumption. As a market capitalization falls and the spread the actual interest of these securities increases at the same ratio.</p>
          <p>And taking into account that we will carry these assets, there is no effect on future results. It is also worth remembering that such figures do not include the market capitalization of stakes in companies that are not listed on the stock exchange than Bradesco owns such as Serasa and Visanet.</p>
          <p>Slide number seven, shows the breakdown of Bradesco's net income, which is inline with previous periods. The quarterly reduction in the share of the insurance segment was basically due to lower non-interest bearing results, the sale &#x2013; lower sales of shares of equities and the effect of the mark-to market. I would also like to emphasize the fact that we maintained the relative participation of fees even after the realignment of individual fees in view of the increase in the client base and volumes. Slide eight gives a summary of our income statement showing the main variations.</p>
          <p>Slide nine, adjusted financial margin grew by 16% in the period as you can see. The increase of interest-bearing operations, basically the loans, was the main driver of this growth, offsetting the margin impact caused by reduced spreads in the quarter and also in the nine-month period. The significant drop in non-interest operations, 475 million, occurred in the third quarter and is due to mark-to-market effect in loan derivatives basically credited for swaps of sovereign Brazilian bonds issued abroad of R$150 million, lower gains in the sale of equities and mark-to-market effect held in the insurance group, R$185 million, and least &#x2013; and last but not least mark-to-market of all the derivatives used as market risk, hedges of loan operations in the country, basically R$140 million.</p>
          <p>It is worth to highlight that our risk is on Brazilian sovereign securities issued abroad with 95% of the maturity, I am talking about the CDS, and with 95% of the maturity over the next two years. We do not feel comfortable with the effect of the mark-to-market effect but we are sure that the process of mark-to-market should reverse over time. And this is the reason why we should keep those securities up to their maturity, up to the end. We have no doubts of the capacity of payment of the Brazilian government as those securities that are maturing are irrelevant vis-&#xE0;-vis the Brazilian reserves just as a matter of example.</p>
          <p>On slide 10, we show the nominal growth of 20% of the adjusted net interest income when compared to the nine months period of 2007. The increase in loans and funding operations was fundamental in raising the margin by R$260 million in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Slide 11 gives the breakdown of the adjusted net interest income where you can see that the share of loan operations is increasing and reached 69% of the total vis-&#xE0;-vis 66% in September '07.</p>
          <p>Slide 12, on this slide you can see our interest-bearing and non-interest-bearing results since 2005. The highlight was a lower share from non-interest operations even in nominal terms when compared to the previous quarters, as we already mentioned in the explanation of slide number nine.</p>
          <p>Moving on now to slide 13, which gives a summary of loan operations. In the first line blue, we can show that the gross margin composed by the loan interest income, net of the cost of opportunity basically the Selic or the CDI, in the red line the provisions for delinquencies adding the discount and taking out the recoveries of the period, and in the black line and just in the middle of both previous lines, we call it the net margin for loans, which recorded a 20% growth when compared to 2007, proving the good performance of our loan operation strategy.</p>
          <p>Slide 14, Bradesco's total loan portfolio reached R$197 billion, a consistent growth of 8.6% in the quarter and an increase of 40.8% over the last 12 months, outpacing the market which grew by 34% over the same period. It is worth mentioning the largest growth of loans in the corporate segment both in terms of working capital operations and also investments, which consider maybe to those large corporations, Bradesco as the ideal partner for their growth prospect.</p>
          <p>Slide 15 and 16, we basically have a breakdown of the loan portfolio, credit lines for corporates and individuals. On slide 17, we show the consumer finance operation, which reached R$56.2 billion in the quarter, an increase of 28.3% over the last 12 months and a growth of 5.5% just on a quarter-over-quarter basis. Please note that a segment of vehicle financing 72% of this total and payroll deductible loans. The 12% represent 84% of the total consumer finance operation and conceiving their guarantees and characteristics, they offer a very adequate level of credit risk.</p>
          <p>Slide 18, just moving on to vehicles, you can see basically the breakdown of the portfolio for cars and the vehicles in general. As the solid growth of leasing operations is due to the IOF, which is basically a financial operation tax that we have exemption. We &#x2013; I say the client have exemptions on the IOF when to use the leasing portfolios, this is the reason why most of them are moving on to those credit lines, its less expensive, if you want.</p>
          <p>On slide number 19, we can verify the coverage ratio over the expected losses. R$1.2 billion would be the additional provisions to that required by the Brazilian Central Bank's criteria. So basically the difference between the two first lines 5.7% minus 4.9% would be the R$1.2 billion. The R$2.8 billion we consider as effectively the additional level of provision that we have because we are comparing the level of provisions vis-&#xE0;-vis the expectations of losses going forward, that we see a very strong correlation between the two flat lines. So basically the expectation is to continue to move down closely to 4% and compared to as 5.7, the excess of 2.8 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide 20, total delinquency ratio, loans overdue by more than 90 days remained stable in the quarter, attesting solid &#x2013; granting scores and loan monitoring procedures. Also deserves a very important highlight in the drop of the delinquency in the individual segment, showing the reversal trend to what we saw between June and March. Our expectation is for these indexes to remain stable over the next quarters, taking into consideration that income and employment are key for this to be <mark type="inaudible" /> (20.30) in the individual segment.</p>
          <p>Slide 21, looking at mortgages, Bradesco's mortgage origination, which R$4.8 billion over the first nine months of this year, a 74% increase vis-&#xE0;-vis September of 2007. We do have a 24% market share in origination in mortgage. Bradesco financed 38,000, almost 39,000 properties, around 20% of the total number of homes financed in the country. We believe the market will remain strong even with the expected slowdown of the economy for the coming year, and there will be no shortage of funds since there is the savings liability to be completed with.</p>
          <p>Slide 22, fee income moved up by 6.2% on a year-over-year basis and 1.6% on a quarter-over-quarter analysis. Higher income from credit cards, asset management, consortium and custody basically due to the growth in volumes, were keys to offset the declining fees we noticed and experienced in non-operations and checking accounts, arising from the regulatory changes.</p>
          <p>Slide 23, in relation to personnel expenses, 6.8% increase in structural expenses in the quarter was mainly due to the collective bargaining agreement effect, which had an impact of R$62 million. If we exclude this effect, the structural expenses moved up just by 2.5% in the quarter and by 8.9% in the 12 months analysis. Mainly due to the expansion of our distribution network, we opened 168 new full-size branches over these last 12 months. We also opened 772 advanced service branches, which implied in the additional hiring of 3,634 employees over the last 12 months.</p>
          <p>The network expansion as well as the investments in technology, mainly the <mark type="inaudible" />  improvement program and the business expansion are also reflected in the rise of the administrative expense. This expansion is in line with our projections, but actions are still being implemented to improve our operating efficiency by means of reviewing internal processes along with the final phase of the IT improvement project which should be ending over the next couple of years.</p>
          <p>On Slide 24, we are showing the coverage ratio basically comparing fees and operational expenses adding personnel and administrative expenses and we see a slight decline recently in this coverage ratio, mainly is due to the impact of the expansion of our distribution, on one hand and on the other hand the effect of the regulatory measures which impacted fees this year. We account onto the increase in both volumes and client base to reverse these declining trends for the coverage ratio. We expect going forward to increase to coverage back again.</p>
          <p>Slide 25 presents, our funding gross highlighting demand and savings deposit and CD's. The strong expansion in time deposits was due to a stronger loan demand. In this quarter, the growth in assets under management was affected by the decline in the &#x2013; in equities given the performance of the Bovespa which declined by 23.8% in the very same period.</p>
          <p>On Slide 26, we opened for the first time a slide talking about comparison between loans and their funding. We have been &#x2013; having a lot of demand about that loan to deposit ratio, but we believe that this way is much better for you to understand in a more appropriate way what we consider as the real loan to deposits ratio.</p>
          <p>Pay attention to the fact that for loans housing the country our need for foreign capital is of only 6% over the total portfolio or 12.7%, if loans held abroad were also to be included. We are overcoming in a smooth manner the transitory difficulties in raising foreign funds from the markets and from all the banks which includes the participation in the external lines and the auctions, but we also are participating that basically will be helping to increase the external funding.</p>
          <p>On Slide 27, we are making a summary of the different changes promoted by the Central Bank of Brazil taking into account funds released and other items that will be better beneficial to improve liquidity in the market. We have higher liquidity due to the release of R$6.3 billion in reserved funds as you can see. We have also R$6 billion limit for the acquisition of loan portfolios from other financial institutions using reserve requirement funds up to date, up to now, Bradesco already applied R$1.5 billion and intend, of portfolio, and intend to use this limit, if we see good opportunities of business. And also higher requirement for agricultural loans R$1 billion which will be easily complied over the next 30 days.</p>
          <p>On Slide 28, as already mentioned, but this would does not carry-out leverage, derivative transactions known as target forward operation. Operations with traditional derivatives are held just with clients seeking protection from foreign exchange variations.</p>
          <p>On October 23 of this year if Bradesco have to show what these would be impacting, Bradesco had receivables of R$973 million of basically 206 times, the largest volume of which totals with a R$142 million with one single company and payables of R$655 million to 110 client, the largest of which would be a 109.</p>
          <p>Receivables are within limits previously attributed to which borrower, therefore this does not mean additional credit risk. So this is already included in the risk profile in the risk of each and every company using this operation, usually they are basically exporters who are basically the prepaid or the advanced payment in other currencies &#x2013; in foreign currencies and have a longer settlement, commitment without any foreign exchange exposure.</p>
          <p>So Bradesco referring its position that carries out derivatives only to hedge ourselves against foreign exchange variations in which of our investments in branches and subsidiaries that we have abroad, basically we have hedges to our own positions of $5 billion of equity and investments that we have abroad.</p>
          <p>On Slide 29, in order to provide a better understanding of our insurance operations, insurance private pension plan and savings bonds, we are presenting a summary of our insurance group income statement, and despite the improvement in its main performance indicator such as the claims ratio which fell from 73.1 to 72.4 and the sales ratio dropping from 10.7 to 10.3, the third quarter net income recorded a slight decline due to the reduction in the income from equity funds and mark-to-market caused by obviously very high market volatility we are experiencing.</p>
          <p>In the first nine months, the net income of Group of Bradesco Seguro de Presidente increased by 18.3% reaching 2 billion, almost R$2.1 billion with an annualized return on average equity of 31% and represented 37.1% of the net income of Brazil's entire insurance market. This is as of July 2008. The increase was due to higher sales, the 22.5% increase in the client base, the reduction in the claims ratio. And as a result include combine ratio, as well as the adjustment of technical provisions in the individual health, insurance segment which was concluded by the end of 2007.</p>
          <p>Slide 30, written premiums and revenues of private pension plans and savings bonds reached R$16.9 billion in the nine months period, a 10.7% increase vis-&#xE0;-vis the same period of last year. It represents 23.7% of the entire insurance markets as of July. As a result, Bradesco maintains its leadership in the property and life insurance segments, as well as in private pension plan.</p>
          <p>Slides 31 and 32, own financing assets and technical provisions guaranteed reached R$71 billion equivalents to 35.3% of the market as of again July 2008. It is worth mentioning that 80% of these assets correspond to pension plans and PGBL investment portfolios. Total assets grew by 10.4% on a year-over-year comparison. Technical provisions reached 53 billion or 34.9% of the insurance market again as of July '08.</p>
          <p>Slide 33 represents two efficiency ratios of the insurance segment, obviously the lower the ratio the better. The combined ratio has been improving consistently indicating better operational efficiency of the insurance group regarding claims and on rising policy.</p>
          <p>Slide 34, we decided to include in this slide some highlights that attest the strength of our balance sheet. Funds raised under managements surpassed R$570 billion as funding exceeded loan operations which allowed also to lower the cost.</p>
          <p>Delinquency ratio as already mentioned remained at a very comfortable level, Bradesco's leverage is extremely low mainly is compared to international banks just for having an idea. Loans under the Brazilian Central Bank calculation methodology a R$160 billion would be lower than first times our shareholders equity of R$34 billion.</p>
          <p>On Page 35, we basically are maintaining our 2008 guidance. As soon as we include our budgets, we conclude our budget plan for 2009, which is still in progress, which is still underway, we will disclose our guidance for that year 2009.</p>
          <p>On Slide 36 basically we are summarizing the forecast for '08 and '09 of GDP interest rates inflation and the FX rate.</p>
          <p>We have on slide 37 and 38. On slide 37, the three next events that we are doing with investors in Brazil, so each and everyone is obviously invited. And on page 38, we are disclosing the save the date of Bradesco's Investor Day which will be held on the New York Stock Exchange, Euronext in New York City on November 25, it's a lunch. So please each and everyone wanting to participate feel free to part to be in this event.</p>
          <p>Concluding, many difficulties had been faced in the course, of the first nine months of this year, uncertainties caused by international financial markets turmoil affecting assets value. Increased inflation and higher interest rates impacted on administrative and funding cost. In <mark type="inaudible" /> fee adjustments including the elimination of the loan processing fee and advanced loan settlement fee.</p>
          <p>Increase in the financial operation tax, the IOF on loans for individuals, change in several deductible loan rules. Increase in the social contribution on net income from 9 to 15%. So bottomline given all of this and considering that we are involved in several ongoing structural and expansion project and we mentioned in this presentation, we understand and believe that our results were extremely strong. So now, I would like to open the floor to your questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Ladies and gentleman, we will now begin the question and answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question comes from Mr. Jason Mullin with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Jason Mullin. My question is related to the risk in the portfolio. Thank you for your disclosure on your clients and Bradesco's exposure to these derivatives products. Can you help us size the problem in the system; is Bradesco concerned about corporate, that have experienced losses that perhaps Bradesco didn't write and what that would mean from a credit risk perspective?</p>
          <p>And secondly on the consumer side of the book, if you could talk a little bit about where you think unemployment is going to go next year, and your asset quality numbers today was very good but with an economic slow down, I mean, you did suggest that you are going to try to maintain these figures, but if unemployment kicks up what do you think that that means for asset quality in Bradesco's loan book individuals?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jason. Obviously we have been reading in the newspaper a lot of articles and a lot of numbers talking about maybe hundreds of companies that could be involved in the process of using derivatives, to leverage derivatives as we read in the newspaper. Obviously taking to that consideration, but Bradesco always analyses what could be the implication on its portfolio. And we have been drawing a lot loans to companies over the last periods.</p>
          <p>So obviously the concern is even higher. Based on that we have a structure called Bradesco corporate focused on the large corporations, basically 1,500 companies and also Bradesco Empresas is focusing on the middle sized companies had conducted a survey asking their clients if they were using this type of derivatives and using that to measure on a consolidated basis what could be the implication for Bradesco in terms of needs of future provision.</p>
          <p>And we were quite optimistic that we &#x2013; the impact &#x2013; the number &#x2013; first, the number of companies was extremely low, and second, that the impact would not be relevant on Bradesco's amount. So at the end of the day obviously risk is a concern every day. But we believe that the service that we conducted made us go through future periods with not so much volatility in provisioning or impacting our profitability levels.</p>
          <p>In terms of the unemployment, we have a very good number; we have the lowest unemployment rate over the last 16 years. And just over the last 12 months as I mentioned before two million jobs, registered jobs were created. The minister of work, of labor in Brazil is expecting a job creation in 2009 of additionally another 1 million people. And obviously it's not only a question of quality, of number of employees, but also the quality of the employment.</p>
          <p>We have been seeing more and more companies hiring people officially, which mean that those employees, they have the ability as which is the fun that they have. And even if in the case of some people being fired, laid off, you have a penalty on the 40% FTTS account, which makes basically the expectation for our asset quality for individuals also to be positive over the coming year. Obviously we are going to continue to monitor what is going to happen.</p>
          <p>We have the 3% GDP growth expectation for Brazil. We are in the process of concluding our budget planning for 2009. But up to now we feel comfortable that Brazil should be passing through this crisis on a much better shape than a lot of other economies. And also our strategy has been extremely positive and correct in terms of our expansion in loans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And are you seeing, I mean, just in the month of October, are you seeing some deterioration in asset quality? Did companies opt or individuals opt not to pay given the volatility in the market? And have you seen some of those clients come back or are people actually holding their cash at this point, companies and individuals?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you, Jason if you look on slide number 20, you'll see the performance of our delinquency ratio that has been quite stable. In individuals it even improved. We didn't see anything changing dramatically in October. And this is the reason why we are in this call trying to tell to the investment analysts that our expectations for asset quality will be relatively stable over the coming period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jean.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question come from Mr. Saul Martinez with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning everybody. Actually I want to follow-up on Jason's question on, specifically on corporate credit quality, regardless of what happens with, you know, obviously if there is direct and indirect exposure to corporates who've used these &#x2013; the derivative products, but more broadly speaking, when I look at page 20, delinquency rates were at 0.3% for large corporates, they've been that way for over a year, I guess my question to you Jean, we've had a very good economic environment in Brazil, these delinquency rates look awfully low.</p>
          <p>The question is, if this is good as it's going to get, if, you know, obviously if the economy slows further than it kind of what's embedded in your forecast of 3% GDP growth. The funding conditions are certainly tightened, the cost of funding has increased for corporates, do you see a risk that delinquency rates could increase meaningfully for large corporates and meaningfully mean &#x2013; could even mean going to 1 to 2% over the next 12 months? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Saul, sorry &#x2013; I was just...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On my view here, we are pretty comfortable about the sustainability of the companies in the perspective of the continuity of investment. And the one is stopping there the operation. You have obviously some adjustments, some companies have more inventories or maybe they give vacation to some employees. But overall, the picture continues to be quite positive. If you also analyze Bradesco's exposure, we try to be as diversified as we can.</p>
          <p>So the number &#x2013; the 50 largest borrowers, they have 20% of the loan book, the largest have 0.9. We also try not to be so concentrated in any particular segment. And we &#x2013; even using a stress model, obviously when we conducted this survey with our clients we are always keen to understand that how many of the companies could be having impact and how much this could be impacting Bradesco.</p>
          <p>But we feel quite comfortable, the level of delinquencies has been very good because of the quality of our scorage process in terms of individuals, in terms of companies. We are always following the operation. We have a group of people looking at loans. Our credit director, I believe has more than 30 years working in credit, so he knows very well all the companies. And we don't believe that with more stress that the level of percentage of delinquency ratio for large companies should change so much.</p>
          <p>Maybe some changes you can see in SMEs, you saw a slight increase because a lot of that is statistical. So if you grow more in large companies or less, or if you grow more in SMEs or less, is in fact a little bit of the ratio. But if we take out this process of statistical effect, we believe that the fundamentals of most of the companies are extremely good. The fundamentals of the Brazilian economy are extremely healthy. And we believe that the trends for asset quality should not deteriorate so much going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks, Jean. That's helpful. And just one quick follow-up on your other operating income and other operating expenses. In other operating expenses, you've highlighted in the previous calls. It really has increased pretty meaningfully this year versus last year. Other operating income I think benefited this quarter from a reversal of provisions.</p>
          <p>If I net those two numbers, the 544 and the 1445, I guess something close to 900 million in net other operating expenses. It's lower than what it was in the first half, but still pretty high. What &#x2013; how should we think about that number in those going forward? Because it obviously does have a pretty meaningful impact on our &#x2013; in terms of our forecast and in the earnings power we &#x2013; we think you can generate going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Saul, basically we had the reverse of this provisions that we disclosed in our different information, press release and others. So if you &#x2013; even though it is closer to the recurring number. But if you adjust that other operating expenses and revenues, you'll have roughly a maintenance of the level &#x2013; of the net level of other operating revenues and other operating expenses.</p>
          <p>So I believe that this line should be roughly even over time. Just to explain a little bit more, what is this reversal about. We have a positive decision from lawsuit we had because there was a CPMF charge from the leasing company, from Bradesco Leasing. And we were questioning CPMF on this type of operation and we won. So there is no chance of having that being reversed anytime. So we decided to basically to reverse what we were building in terms of provisions. So we still have a huge amount of &#x2013; R$7.1 billion of fiscal provisions in our liabilities.</p>
          <p>We had done these provisions. We had expensed these provisions in leasing and we were questioning. So when we want, we reverse them. So it's totally recurring. But if you add these 185 you come back to numbers that are roughly close to the previous quarter. We had 1.1 billion in the second quarter. R$900 million negative in the third quarter, adding back to 185, we are roughly in the same level as the previous quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So we should think that this is somewhere kind of in the neighborhood of 1 billion to 1.1 billion or so it would be a best guess?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. You told the correct word, best guess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. No, I know it's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Best guidance, but the best guess...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Best a guess that, would be that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Got it. Thanks a lot, Jean.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Mario Pierry with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everybody. I have two questions, the first one is on Page nine. You showed that your margin on just the &#x2013; on the interest income and excluding interest expenses that your margins fell about 110 basis points quarter-over-quarter. I would imagine some of this drop is related to the change in your loan mix. But could you comment about what impact did funding costs have on leading to a lower margin quarter-on-quarter. And how &#x2013; what kind of rates are you paying on your time deposits now and how they compare to the beginning of the year?</p>
          <p>And then my second question is related to the acquired portfolios you mentioned, that you have bought about R$1 billion worth of &#x2013; worth of loans from other banks that you could buy as much as 6 billion in total. Just trying to get a sense, what type of loans are you targeting? Are you targeting SME loans, payroll loans and what kind of prices are you paying for these loans? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Mario. So responding your first question. Obviously, we had a decline in the net interest margin on the quarter-over-quarter basis. But this is basically because of the non-interest parts. And because of the effect of the mark-to-market we basically explained. And in the interest part we are able to continue to expand the volumes and counter balancing the reduction in the spread. The cost of the funding is relatively the same, it didn't change.</p>
          <p>We are paying close to 103 &#x2013; 103.5% of the Selic for institutional funding. You saw a very important increase in the term deposits, so definitively Bradesco I believe is benefiting from this volatility because we are getting more funding from the market. Perspectives going forward, I would say in general terms for the interest part is a continuity of expansion in the loan book, making able us to counter balance the spread reduction.</p>
          <p>It's a little bit tricky to understand this part because you remember when interest rate, when the Selic was moving down you had an impact on the spread because we are reducing the rates for the customers and now we basically have spread the same and &#x2013; sorry the Selic is the same, but we are moving more into corporate, where the spread is lower.</p>
          <p>So this is a different type of impact, but we are able to continue to expand the volume. So over time, I believe the trend will be maybe to expand the net interest margin if you look on page 10, maybe you &#x2013; we would be able to grow more the margin. In terms of the portfolios that we acquired just to give you an idea, we were analyzing almost R$11 billion of loan books with basically 20 different banks. We analyze already R$3.4 billion. We are right now analyzing R$7.3 billion from all this credit lines that we were analyzing R$2.8 billion, we didn't want.</p>
          <p>We basically are analyzing operations that should be adding some R$3.4 billion or 3 billion, close to R$3 billion of operations to Bradesco. We already gave 1.5 billion and we should be with the different institutions, different banks adding another 1.4 billion. So we just see &#x2013; analyzing R$11 billion of portfolios and doing R$3 billion of operations. We are very selective in analyzing the operations. We really want to bring good operations. And the portfolios that we are analyzing, they are most &#x2013; they are in all the different types of loans, but we are focusing more in payroll deductible loans and in autos, where the risk is also much lower.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just let me follow-up then with the question on the margin. What are your expectations for loan growth then for next year, I think you've talked about in the past about 20% loan growth next year, and should we assume that you will continue to grow much faster in your corporate portfolio rather than your consumer and thus the margin might stay stable even though your net interest income could increase because your loan portfolio is growing, but would your margins stay stable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mario, again we are right now in the process of concluding our budget planning for 2009. So we are not giving a guidance for 2009 that we should be expanding by 20%. We are giving like the best case, best guess if you want. And in this guess probably if Brazil grows close to 3% GDP, which is what you see in our presentation, there is an expectation from the economic team that the loans to banks should be granting 16, 17% more loans.</p>
          <p>And as usually Bradesco grows more than the market, we should be growing little bit more than that. But again, we are in the process of revising this, so we cannot even dig more inside and tell you know from this 20%, X% should be to corporate, Y% should be to individuals. We don't feel comfortable enough to be giving a guidance for 2009, although we know that we are almost in November and people are just extremely interested to know what is going to happen for next year. But we are at the end of the process as soon as we have this disclosed definitely we should be disclosing that.</p>
          <p>We are also going to give a guidance for the net interest income. We don't give a guidance for the margin, but we always give for the net interest income. So all in all, company up to now what we are seeing should be growing 15 to 16%, based on the 3% GDP growth, and Bradesco should be growing a little bit more than that maybe closer to 20%. But as we conclude the budget planning based also on the revisions of the GDP and other items that the Chief Economist of Bradesco is doing and providing to our Planning Department, we will be extremely happy to give to the guidance to everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then finally Jean just to go back on what you said on the acquired portfolio, so you are looking at, if you can just give us a sense of what price are you paying, I would assume you are not paying face value for this loan. So just to give us an idea, what kind of pricing are you seeing on the loans that you are buying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mario, we are not disclosing this information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" /> of Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, hi. My question is regarding the insurance business, given that the loan growth is expected to decelerate in 2009, I would like to know if you would expect insurance business to increase its relevance, its share into earnings of the group in next year. And what would be the main segment inside insurance company to highlight for 2009? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. I'm Samuel Monteiro. To response your question, I would say to you, I can project nothing or to next year until now. But I assume that the insurance business for this group could be very strong, business is very important I think would be to maintain our share in the market and though we will be maintaining our share in terms of a representation in the profit of the bank <mark type="inaudible" /> reveals everything to project for next years and now it will be working our budget for the 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Rafael?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, sorry. I didn't understand the question, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&gt;: You didn't understand the answer. Basically what Samuel was saying that he is also working on the budget planning for 2009. So based on that he's not able to give you a precise guidance not in terms of the premium growth and not even in terms of &#x2013; and much less in terms of which factors that we should be growing more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. All right, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So basically we are going to be available for any additional questions you might have. And please don't forget about the Bradesco Day event on November 25 where you will have access to the Senior Management of Bradesco, Mr. M&#xE1;rcio Cypriano and other top executives will be there, totally open to disclose information and to clear any doubts that you might have. Thank you very much and talk to you anytime soon. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude the Banco Bradesco audio conference for today. Thank you very much for your participation. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>