<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1448180" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-02-01</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9041</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Vice President">Domingos Figueiredo de Abreu</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Daniel Adrian Abut</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs Brasil Banco M&#xFA;ltiplo SA">Carlos Macedo</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Saul Martinez</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities USA, Inc.">Victor Galliano</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Corretora de Valores SA">Mario Pierry</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (Brasil) SA CTVM">Marcelo Telles</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Ita&#xFA; Corretora de Valores SA">Regina Longo Sanchez</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Raymond James Argentina Sociedad de Bolsa SA">Federico Rey Marino</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. We would like to welcome everyone to Banco Bradesco's Fourth Quarter 2011 Earnings Results Conference Call. This call will be conducted by Mr. Luiz Carlos Trabuco Cappi, Chief Executive Officer; Mr. Domingos Figueiredo de Abreu, Executive Vice President; Mr. Julio Siqueira Carvalho de Araujo, Executive Vice President; Mr. Marco Antonio Rossi, Chief Executive Officer of Bradesco Seguros Group Insurance and Bradesco Executive Vice President; Mr. Carlos Angelotti, Executive Managing Officer and Investor Relations Officer; Mr. Moacir Nachbar Junior, Deputy Officer; Mr. Paulo Faustino da Costa, Market Relations Department Director.</p>
          <p>This call is being broadcasted simultaneously through the Internet in the Website, www.bradesco.com.br/ir. In that address you can also find a banner through which the presentation will be available for download. We inform all participants will be only listening to the conference call during the company's presentation. After the presentation, there will be a question-and-answer session. At that time, further instructions will be given. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Forward-looking statements are based on the beliefs and assumptions of Banco Bradesco's management and on information currently available to the company. Forward-looking statements are not guarantees of performance. They involve risks, uncertainties and assumptions, because they relate to future events and therefore depend on circumstances that may or may not occur in the future.</p>
          <p>Investors should understand that general economic conditions, industry conditions and other operating factors could also affect the future results of Banco Bradesco and could cause results to differ materially from those expressed in such forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Now, I will turn the conference over to Mr. Domingos Figueiredo de Abreu, Executive Vice President. Please, sir, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good morning, everyone, and welcome to our conference call. 2011 was a historic year for Bradesco, and we had the opportunity to overcome challenges. We reaffirmed our focus, priority and commitment to Brazilian market. It was a challenge to adapt our strategies along the year to better fit changes in the current conjuncture and business opportunities while guaranteeing the development of our organic growth projects.</p>
          <p>We consider the results to be very good given the massive investment and infrastructure and technology carry out in 2011. During this period, Bradesco opened more than 1,000 new branches and hired more than 90,000 new employees. Unexpected event brought out excellent business opportunities. The strategic acquisition of Banco do Estado do Rio de Janeiro, BERJ, brought to us over 400,000 public employees with whom we can now build lasting relationships.</p>
          <p>The state of Rio de Janeiro has the second largest GDP in Brazil. Besides being a state with enormous economic potential and that has been the target of substantial investments, especially those related to the pre-salt exploration, the 2014 World Cup and the Rio 2016 Olympic Games. The discontinuation of the Banco Postal agreement was a second factor which challenged us to invest in our sales network and afford us to strengthen our capillarity. We now understand this was the right decision given that the amount invested in locations where we were only present via Banco Postal was lower than the final price in the auction. In addition, with branches installed in these areas, we can expand the range of products and services offered and make sure that the customer serves through our branches' managers.</p>
          <p>In addition to expanding the sales network, we continue to invest in our IT improvements project which should be concluded in 2012. These investments are absolutely necessary if you are to ensure even better services for our more than 65 million clients, holders of 25 million checking accounts, 43 million saving accounts and more than 40 million insurance products.</p>
          <p>Now moving on to our presentation, we can see some of our period highlights on slides two and three. I would particularly like to emphasize our 2011 adjusted net income with total close to R$11.2 billion, 14.2% up on 2010. I would like to emphasize also our total assets which increased by 19.5% reaching R$762 billion. The expanded loan portfolio that with R$346 billion, 17.1% up on the previous year and delinquency over 90 days which account for 3.9% of the total portfolio, 30 basis points above the ratio at the end of 2010 but below the average in the market.</p>
          <p>Slide four, the main non-recurring event in the fourth quarter was the provision for certain contingencies in regard to economic plans which totaled R$79 million. Adjusted for dues and other events, our book net income increased from R$2.726 billion in the quarter to R$2.771 billion and from around R$11 billion in the year to around R$11.2 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide five, fourth quarter net income was impacted by higher personnel and administrative expense due to a strong organic growth in the second half, as well as lower gains from our trading position given the volatility that we had in the last December. On the positive side, we recorded higher fee income, mainly thanks to credit card and checking account transactions and the lower provisions for loan losses.</p>
          <p>Our annual net income increased by around R$1.4 billion or 14.2% fostered by the upturn in the net interest income, higher fee income and increased revenues from our Insurance Group together with the healthy results from <mark type="ph" /> debt earned (07:40) in the business world led by the net addition, for example, of 10.5 million new credit and debit card holders and around 2 million checking account holders. Earnings per share in the last 12 months moved up by around 12% in the year from R$2.61 to R$2.93.</p>
          <p>Slide six, this slide shows our efficiency ratio which following a period of stability increased slightly in the fourth quarter, primarily due to expenses from the expansion of our sales network which had a direct impact on personnel and administrative expense as well as higher advertising and marketing expenses. We expect the ratio to stabilize at its current level in the short term before improving as the recent investments mature.</p>
          <p>Slide seven, as we mentioned before, our total assets came to R$762 billion, a growth of R$124 billion or 20% over December 2010. Return on average assets came to 1.6% while adjusted return on average equity stood at 21.3%. The Basel ratio closed the period at 15.1%, up 40 basis points improvement in the quarter and the year ago. The quarterly improvement was due to the recent Central Bank measures that reduced capital requirements for certain loan operations and investments.</p>
          <p>Slide eight, this slide shows the relative share of our main operations in the net income. In the annual comparison, this share remains stable. In the quarterly comparison, the highlight was increase in the relative share of our Insurance Group to 31% not only due to the good performance of the segment itself, but also to increased pressure on financial activities due to, as we mentioned before, the higher expense and the lower trading gains.</p>
          <p>Slide nine, unrealized gains totaled a robust R$10.6 billion in the quarter, an increase of R$1.6 billion over September 2011, basically due to depreciation of some of our investments, especially Cielo's shares, and fixed income securities. Once again, I'd like to remind you that these figures do not include the potential goodwill from our own properties in the total month of around R$3 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide 10, on this slide we show the evolution of our net interest income from both non-interest and interest earnings operations. The highlight was interest earning portion which increased by 19.5% in 2011, largely due to the upturn in the average business volume, led by lower and funding operations. In the quarter, the non-interest portion reported lower trading gains reflect, as we mentioned before, increased volatility in last, mainly last December. Please note that the fourth quarter results include a gain of R$179 million from the partial sale of our investment in Cetip.</p>
          <p>Next slide 11, net interest income increased by 3.2% in the quarter, basically due to the higher gains from loans and securities. Most of this growth came from the higher volume of business which maintained the NII's net interest margin at 7.6%. We believe net interest income will continue to record growth in 2012 given the addition of the new businesses, although the net interest margin should suffer a slight reduction, mainly due to the change in the loan portfolio mix and expect reduction in Selic.</p>
          <p>Slide 12, the slide gives a breakdown of our net interest income. Security recorded most growth in the quarter, including gains from derivative financial instruments in the management of our fixed commercial portfolio which offset their adoption in funding and insurance portions which were impacted by the decline in Selic in the period. In the annual comparison, the highlight was a 50.6% increase in income from funding fostered by the higher business volume and higher average spreads, mainly due to the improved funding mix and increase in average Selic rates.</p>
          <p>Slide 13, this quarter gross interest income from loans, the grey area, increased by 3.4% to R$7.162 billion, sustained by the high volume &#x2013; business volumes again. The red area shows the provision for loan losses which recorded decline this quarter due to the adequation we made in provisioning levels according to expected losses from certain operations with corporate customers which offset the period of turn in delinquency. In the annual comparison, the 13% increase in net interest income from loans was mostly due to the higher business volume given increase in the average loan portfolio.</p>
          <p>Slide 14, this slide shows total expanded loan portfolio which closed December 2011 at R$346 billion, 4% up in the quarter and 17.1% up on December 2010. This improvement was mainly due to the increase in loans to micro businesses and SMEs, which moved up by more than 6% in the quarter and 22.7% in the year. In the annual comparison, the corporate portfolio highlights were mortgage loans, working capital loans, export finance and capital market related operations, which had risk-based delinquent pricing, debentures and <mark type="ph" /> other securities (14:28).</p>
          <p>Slide 15, this quarter our total delinquency ratio for loans overdue by more than 90 days went up by 10 basis points over September 2011 to 3.90% mainly due to the increase in loans to micro business and SMEs. Delinquency in the large corporate segment remained stable in the last 12 months. In 2012, primarily due to the first quarter seasonality, we expect the ratio to move up slightly into the second quarter. However, given the expected increase in the pace of economic growth in the second half, we expect certain stability and a reduction in the latter period.</p>
          <p>Slide 16, this slide shows delinquency ratio for loans overdue by between 61 and 90 days, which as you can see has remained relatively stable.</p>
          <p>Slide 17, this slide represents the stiffness of the renegotiated portfolio in relation to the total loan portfolio, which remains flat over September 2011 at 3.2% in line with the performing portfolio trends.</p>
          <p>Slide 18, this slide shows that provisioning levels have remained high and stable in relation to delinquency of more than 90 days for the renegotiated portfolio. In December 2011, our allowance for loan losses was equivalent to 63.8% of the portfolio for delinquency of 27.6%, ratio which we have maintained for the last three years.</p>
          <p>Slide 19, this slide highlights our high provisioning levels. Despite the slightly upturned delinquency in the last three quarters, provisioning levels have remained comfortable. As such, we had a surplus of R$4 billion in relation to the amount required by the Central Bank or R$9.3 billion in relation to expected gross losses in the next 12 months, the dotted part of the blue line in the graph, or even R$12.6 billion in relation to losses net of recoveries, I'm referring to the dotted part of the purple line, also for the next 12 months.</p>
          <p>Slide 20, reinforcing what we mentioned in regard to the previous slides. Here you can see the coverage ratio of the allowance for loan losses in relation to credits overdue by more than 90 and 60 days, which despite the fourth quarter reduction remained highly comfortable and among the highest for Brazilian banks.</p>
          <p>Slide 21, fourth quarter fee income totaled more than R$4 billion, 5.4% up on the previous three months, mainly due to high revenue from cards with 8.2%, checking accounts with 5.6% and underwriting operations with 53.4% reflecting the high volume operation and the expansion of the client base.</p>
          <p>In the annual comparison, fee income moved up by around 14%. The highlights were revenues again from cards which increased 21.3%, consort with 21.7% and checking accounts with 18%, again basically due to the increase in the customer service portfolio and the net addition of around 2 million new account holders and increase in our credit card space, for example, R$4.8 million as I mentioned previously.</p>
          <p>Slide 22, operating expenses increased by 8.5% in the fourth quarter, mainly due to expenses related to organic growth, higher salaries and expansion of the workforce. The 12 months increase in personnel expenses was primarily due to the 2010 and 2011 collective bargaining agreement together with expansion of the workforce. It's always worth mentioning that the expansion of our workforce is concentrated in our sales force related to both organic growth and improved segmentation.</p>
          <p>Slide 23, administrative expenses moved up by 8.1% in the quarter and 16.3% in the year as a whole, driven by higher expenses from advertising, especially in the fourth quarter, and expenses related to the acceleration of organic growth, for example, transportation, security and surveillance, maintenance and conservation of assets, as well as variable expenses relates to the increase in revenues and business volume, for example, Call Center and banking correspondent. These increases are compatible. We now understand that with the growth of our service network which increased again by around 11 owned and 35 service points in the last 12 months, including more than 1,000 branches.</p>
          <p>Slide 24 will give you a bad idea of the behavior of our operating expenses. On this slide we present some of our organic growth figures. We have broken down the effects of this organic growth as you can see. If these impacts were excluded, our administrative and personnel expenses would have increased by 14% year-on-year, which we consider compatible with the growth of our business in the same period. It's also worth noting the expansion of our service network and our workforce. The latter recorded a net increase of more than 9,400 employees in the last 12 months, mostly as I mentioned before concentrating our sales force, in line with our strategy of strengthening our basic business structures in a way that is consistent with the projected growth of our operation.</p>
          <p>Slide 25, this slide shows revenues from our insurance activities, which increased by 23% in the fourth quarter, mainly due to the strong growth in the Pension Plans segment. In the annual comparison, overall growth came to 21.3% led by the Life Insurance, Pension Plans, Health, Insurance and Savings Bonds segments. Fourth quarter net income totaled R$860 million, 10.3% up on the previous three months and 10.2% in the last 12 months, essentially due to the upturn and the various reduction in the claims ratios and the improved financial position.</p>
          <p>Slide 26, the combined ratio recorded 83.6% in the fourth quarter, 260 basis points down on the previous three months basically due to decreased revenues from the Life Insurance and the Pension Plans products and the reduction in the claims ratio. Financial assets totaled R$113 billion, a growth of 17% in the year while technical provisions stood at R$103.7 billion, R$91 billion of which are related to the Life and Pension Plans products.</p>
          <p>Slide 27, this slide shows our economic departments, GDP, interest rate, inflation and exchange rate estimates for 2012 and 2013. Despite expected slowdown in the global economy, we expect domestic growth to accelerate in 2012 in response to the various stimulatory measures. Consequently, we believe this scenario is favorable for the development of our business in regard to the both financial and insurance activities. In an event, it's worth noting that the expected dynamics in 2012 will be the opposite that had happened in 2011 with lower growth in the first half followed by a more accelerated pace in the second half.</p>
          <p>Slide 28, as usual at this time of the year this slide compares our 2011 guidance with our actual performance. We achieved virtually all of our guidance figures except in the case of the auto portfolio where we made the strategic choice to prioritize the portfolio's quality and the margin instead of gains on market share thereby affecting the total operations with the individuals.</p>
          <p>Mortgage loans did exceptionally well as we originate around R$15 billion in 2011, 63% up on 2010. We also recorded a large increase in regard to the interest earning portion of the net interest income, fee income and insurance premium. Although operating expenses remained within their expected limit, it's worth noting that the guidance for this item was revised in the last quarter due to the acceleration of our organic growth. And just to remind you, our initial guidance for these expenses was an increase of between 11% and 15%.</p>
          <p>Slide 29, we believe our loan portfolio, we'll talk about our guidance, we believe our loan portfolio will continue to expand in 2012 growing by between 18% and 22% pushed by corporate loans especially through micro business and SMEs and certain new business lines such as credit cards and payroll deductible loans. As for mortgage, we believe we will originate around R$11.4 billion in the new operations in 2012, slightly less than in 2011, but still a very healthy figure.</p>
          <p>As for operating expenses, we believe the greatest impact has already occurred given we have invested in 2011. So, we have good expectation for expense to grow from 8% to 12%, but we are confident that we will be able to meet this target. As of this year, our expectations include a growth in revenues generated by the increase in business volumes arising from the strong organic growth in 2011.</p>
          <p>Well, in conclusion, our 2011 results were highly satisfactory despite slightly more pressures in the last quarters from the lower trading performance and increase in expenses. Despite the signs of slowdown in the global economic scenario and the uncertainties regarding the pace and sustainability of growth in the developed countries in the coming months, we can take some reassurance from Brazil's social and economic performance in 2011 and 2012 further reinforcing Bradesco with positive long-term outlook for the country.</p>
          <p>The last few years and most recently in the last six months, we had experienced ways to up investments in the infrastructure, technology, new products and services, service points and our workforce in line with organic growth strategy. Despite the slight upturn in the delinquency ratio this quarter, we have maintained high provisioning levels. We have also kept a constant eye on the quality of our loan portfolio whose growth is in line with the sustainability of our results.</p>
          <p>We believe our expansion strategy will allow us to pursue all the new business opportunities that arise, not only in the consumption and financial markets, but also in all segments in the Insurance business.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention so far. And now we will open the floor for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Mr. Daniel Abut from Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Domingos and team. A couple of questions on your guidance. A key one for me is the guidance of operating expenses that you're giving 8% to 12% significantly below the performance that we saw last year, and I would say significantly below the performance of expenses over the last quite a few years. In last quarter, you explained, Domingos, because you've been investing in infrastructure, you've been investing in IT and revamping your systems and IT platform, what measures are you taking to give us more comfort that you will be able to keep that aggressive guidance?</p>
          <p>I think you said that the IT project will not be complete until the end of this year suggesting that there are still expenses related to that to come? Are you slowing down significantly your opening of new branches and that's part of the equation? What concrete plans can you share with us that will give us more comfort that this time you can hit that guidance?</p>
          <p>And second on the fee income one, it seems to me that that's the opposite after a very good performance in 2011 where you grew fee income above 14%. You are toning down your guidance there to 8% to 12%, suggesting that perhaps you're being too conservative there. What makes you feel that this year should be tougher in terms of fee income growth than last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Daniel, let's try. Look, you're right. Remember, we mentioned in our speech that we have the last three or four year we have been having an impressive movement of organic growth and investment in IT. For 2012, certainly we have slowed down these investments. You mentioned about branches. We expect to open few branches in 2012, but something close around 70 new branches, but only the branches that we are in the process to build during this year.</p>
          <p>We understand 2012 will be a year to consolidate this movement that we make, right. That's why we understand that even in IT we have some investments to do, but when you make a comparison with the previous years, it's much, much lower. So that's why we are confident to meet this guidance for expenses this quarter.</p>
          <p>The last year we certainly met the guidance for expenses. If you don't need to change to our investment to accelerate our process as we mentioned, we already talk about. But we are confident certainly in this part and don't forget that we don't have the weight to pay the fees of Postal Bank <mark type="indiscernible" /> (31:10) compensate the growth that we have in our branches and something like this.</p>
          <p>In other words, we change a part of variable costs for Banco Postal to fix costs for new branches auditing. So that's why and you're now starting from a higher baseline, so, okay, we can assume that. The fee income is different. We understand that we have a positive trend, but it's different. In terms of cost we start with our base of cost during the year. We have the natural increase in the costs during the year, but it will be lower than the increase this year. It will start with the lower base once you have the maturation of this investment in the new branches and all the investments. You have a growth in the fees.</p>
          <p>We said that we finished the year in a better way in comparison in terms of fees that we started the year. In terms of the dynamic of the comfort &#x2013; the behavior of the cost, for example, you'll see along the quarters the reduction in the growth when you compare year-over-year, while the fees you see a movement of growth. So, we expect to reach both in this sense. In other words, I think at the end of the year certainly we will be in a better position than we will be in the beginning of this year. I don't know if I was clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just to clarify...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I expect the efficiency &#x2013; Luiz remind me, that's why I mentioned that the efficiency ratio it tends to be in the level that is normal to have some expectations to have some improvement by the second half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The efficiency ratio should improve in the second half but stays around the current levels in the first half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah. I don't have them at &#x2013; we start to have...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Despite what you say about &#x2013; on branches you said only 70 new branches planned in 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, only the branches, we know that we will have some space to continue to expand, but this year, in particular in this sense is a moment to consolidate all these investments so that we made all the effort that we made so far. But we need to finish what we had in the pipeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And no more branches are needed for the Banco Postal replacement project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, regular branch. We are in the process that we were in the process. The Banco Postal project, to replace Banco Postal, we already finished all the investments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Domingos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Carlos Macedo from Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Domingos. Good afternoon, gentlemen. I have a couple of questions. One, I want to talk about the guidance again, go back to the loan growth guidance versus the net interest income expansion guidance and what we see is that different from last year where you were guiding stronger net interest income growth than loan growth. This year you're guiding stronger loan growth than interest income growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you talk a little bit about what is going to factor into this slower growth in net interest income, is it the base rate, is it trading gains, is it insurance? And that's in one side. The second question is with respect, just in general, with the guidance, it does seem like even though you still have an acceleration of economic growth in 2012, that your guidance for 2012 with the exception of loan growth is weaker than what you actually did in 2011 and with the expect to fee income, net interest income, certain portfolios of growth, particularly individuals and things like that. I was wondering if you can give us some color with respect to that, what exactly will drive, will lead these lines to be weaker despite a stronger year growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. In terms of margin, Carlos, if you please take a look in slide 12, it's better to understand. You see that we grew in 2011 19.5% and it does include, it is important, the slide does include trading gains here, right. We had 19.5% of growth, but credit portfolio represent, the growth was around 15%.</p>
          <p>What we have here, we have consumption of the funding, we grew more based on remember that we have a movement of increase in Selic during the year. At the end of the year we're in a movement to reduce Selic, but on the average we have Selic higher, then we make a comparison with 2010.</p>
          <p>What we expect the next year, we have Selic to reach something close to 9.5% and kept with 9.5%. So, it would be &#x2013; we have more operation in this line, in this funding. It's certainly a part of the equity of insurance, we see the same movement that have operational on this side. That will be this line, we'll be, as we have just talked before, we'll be compensated the reduction with the gain that we have in our fixed portfolio that will be you see this materialize in the securities, right.</p>
          <p>But if this gain that we have here will compensate the reduction in the other line, but it will not be enough to present a growth when we make a comparison. That's why the dynamic of this year will give us the growth in the margin, in other words the growth in the margin for this year will be only depending on the credit portfolio in this sense. That's why --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One question is in the past you used to say that 100 basis points of decline in the Selic would have &#x2013; if I remember correctly R$500 million or R$600 million of an impact on your net interest income, does that still apply or it hasn't changed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a minute. Yeah, something around R$500 million. But remember we have compensation to other lines, as I mentioned, that we don't have a growth of the volumes that &#x2013; our expectation for funding, for example, that will be more or less the same, the same level that we have during the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. To have an idea even with this reduction in Selic, but they compare, but you don't have a growth in these lines right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of fees, we have some, some math &#x2013; remember that our guidance we made last year we revised by the end of the year. Right normally in terms of fees we are conservative and that we expect to beat this, but we need to have remind that we are starting a year with a baseline higher. So it's very difficult and you have a maturation of this investment during the year, right as we talked in the previous question with Daniel. We see a different movement, we start these new branches and new investment that we made we start a lower level of activities and we again represent <mark type="indiscernible" /> (39:09) during the year. So in the average we don't have the same growth that we expect. In other words --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about mortgage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you get the last quarter, for example, growth certainly you analyze this during the one year certainly will be higher than to make during this other years let's say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What about mortgages and auto loans because mortgages it is a quite a sensitive large deceleration and origination and auto loans is a pretty low amount of growth for a portfolio that is a pretty big part of your total loan book?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mortgage certainly, we grow it a lot during the year, but we understand that's a movement of even the companies now are revising their plans to slow down a little bit the movement of growth because they have the people to deliver in the time that they promised something so just adjustment that's it. But it's a market that we understand, we are confident, we continue to have space to grow, but if we make a comparison with a strong growth that we have in 2011 really it's difficult.</p>
          <p>In terms of auto loans is a market that is far the most competitive market. So we have a competition factor here to see and we are and we have a strategic decision here is not to grow market share in this market unless we have condition to do this in a safe way. In other words we have to go with spreads and with lower risk. So that's why once we have sometimes this market is very, very competitive that we don't have good expectation to grow too much of this one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, Domingos. Good luck in your new functions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Saul Martinez from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning or good afternoon to you in Brazil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of questions as well. First on asset quality, I want to understand the dynamics a little bit better. Obviously, during the course of the year for the system your performance on credit card was much better than the system, NPLs for the system gone up meaningfully, for your major peers they have gone up much more than for you guys.</p>
          <p>But it seems like perhaps you're a little bit more cautious in terms of the first quarter and the first half of the year and if I am correct, I think you indicated on the Portuguese call another 30 basis points of NPL pressure in the first half at a time when the system NPL seemed to be maybe peaking. Can you just talk about what, how your portfolio differs or how your NPL evolution is differed from the system? What's driven the better performance thus far and is there anything that would suggest that your NPL performance will be worse in the first part of 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then secondly, I wanted to ask just a follow-up on the expenses. It seems aggressive to me in light of the fact that even if you made these investments, your average head count is going to be much higher, is going to be higher in 2012 than 2011. You had the wage hike in September which puts some pressure on your personnel costs as well.</p>
          <p>And not only that, in the fourth quarter the base of your cost is much higher than it was in the beginning of last year, so you'd have to have a reduction in the first part of the year. Can you just give us a little bit more detail on specific things you're doing that make you comfortable that you'll be within that 8% to 12% growth guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's start with NPLs. Our NPL became to get the duration by the second half of the last year if you remember. It was different and that's what's happened with the market as a whole. That market will start, it is moving earlier. What we see that our NPL follows more or less the dynamic of our economy. When we saw in the second half of the year we have a slowdown in our economy. That's why we have this assumption that our economy will continue this movement not to slowdown but to start to recover, but still in a lower pace that's why this dynamic we can have some effect in our NPL in the first half of the year. When I say that 30 basis points is not a certain, we don't have this in mind in fact but something that seamlessly is moving us to have 10 basis points one quarter and in other and then maybe we will start. We will see that our portfolio really very linked to what the dynamic of our economy, so that's why we expect first and second half of the year we'll start moving to grow.</p>
          <p>In the second half we will be in the highest point of the growth that's why we'll have more good expectation for delinquency in the second half than the first half. In terms of expenses what we have &#x2013; you are right we have expectation on our guidance to have a new agreement in September with the employees. In the insurance business we have expectation to have agreement now beginning in January we have that. It includes some assumptions on this.</p>
          <p>It is more that we have certainly we have more pressure to meet the guidance, but we are confident we are able to do so. But it's certainly we don't get only the last quarter and as it compares to all the year, because the last quarter is higher than the first quarter. Certainly the first quarter in terms of expenses will be lower, but we won't see our expenses and moving that start. When you make a comparison 12 months to 12 months in the first half of 2012, you won't see something there inside the guidance that we gave. Certainly we'll see this as reduction. Now we finish with 17.4% maybe you'll see something close to 14% the next quarter in the movement of reduction and to reach the guidance that we have there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's helpful, Domingos. So, I guess the even considering those dynamics and tougher comps in the first half and easier in the second half, for the full year you're guiding for 8% to 12% incorporating the whole year. So, I am just struggling with how you get there and is your head count going to be flat, do you think that it will even decline next year, is it, are there less investments in certain types of &#x2013; I think you mentioned lower IT. I'm just looking for a little bit more specificity in how you get that type of efficiency improvement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, if you got all the expense in 2012 in last quarter, you multiply for four, you'll have something close to 12% to have an idea. But as I mentioned the last quarter is not the same though, the first quarter normally is lower, will have low pressure in expense that we have in the last quarter in terms of...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...advertising, we have more activities in the last quarter than we have in the first. So we have this move. But we are making only this you're right and we have more pressure in terms of inflation, in other causes we have pressure in terms of new, you have new agreement with employees and so on. But it's all inside our budget we have there. But we don't have in a positive side, yes we don't have the, you remember that we already have in our base of cost the fixed cost of the new branches to replacement Postal for example.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You already have in this base. But you don't have the fees that you need to pay for Banco Postal anymore in the next year. So we have this in the positive side that you have. Second, it's decided to resume at this point is we have in our budget. We know that we need to &#x2013; we'll be very carefully looking for this distinct desire of consolidation of this investment that we've made. And we are focused very, very, very close to these things that the best message that I can tell that we are very, very confident that we will meet this guidance, yes we have that. Unless you are talking about different things like the last year what we had two big investments that requires to change our view at the beginning of this year. But if everything go the way that we have seen there is no way to in order to reach this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Victor Galliano from HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Domingos. Yeah, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up really on credit quality. Can you give us some guidance? I see the coverage has come down a bit in Q4. Can you give us some sort of guidance as to what you would expect in terms of credit charge for 2012? Would you expect that to be kind of in line with loan growth, coming down a little bit, a little bit higher? How do you see that or is it kind of a game of two halves as you describe in credit quality? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Vic, you talk about charge-offs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm talking about our provisions, provisions against earnings, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Expense and provisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We understand that we can have some improvement, but to be conservative, we understand that will be something around that we had. If you look in the slide 13, that will be something around in an average around 38% to 39% of the gross margin. But if we have this positive environment, the second half of the year, we can even have some good surprise by the end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Just a quick follow-up, if I may, on OpEx. So, you said that really the IT program will be done this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Banco Postal is done. So, on that basis, clearly following up from Saul's question, you seem to be pretty confident that you're going to hit this guidance this year in terms of cost. And really, just kind of thinking on that, where do you expect or how far do you expect you might be able to improve on the efficiency ratio by the year-end?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we have expectation of to keep the expense relatively in a good mood. We expect to gain revenues along the year, that's why expectation is to keep the efficiency ratio around this 43% at least in one or two quarters and then to have some improvement. We don't have an exercise for that, but we'd be satisfied at the end of the year with something close to go back for &#x2013; in an annualized basis to something close to 42.7%, which would be very good. And then for the following years, certainly, have more space to improve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sir. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:04).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, <mark type="ph" /> bada bings (52:06) on your new appointment and all the best.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Mario Pierry from Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everybody. Most of my questions have been answered, but let me follow up then on this question about expenses and efficiency ratios. Clearly, as you mentioned, Abreu, that the bank has been making significant investments over the past three years, IT, opening new branches.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you're still showing a good efficiency ratio of 43%. Most of these investments should be completed by 2012. So, on a long term, if we look beyond 2013, let's say 2014, could we eventually see this efficiency ratio below 40%? Would you feel comfortable with such a ratio? Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, Mario, we have a chance to talk before about this matter. We don't have a guidance for efficiency ratio, but we have our internal challenge, we have our efficiency commit and we are confident that we can reach to something close. But I don't say that is our guidance or our target, because there is a lot of things to happen until then, but we understand it's possible to be around 39% by the end of 2014. That's what you're looking for, right. It will depend on the condition of the economy and everything, but we understand that's possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, second question is to go back to asset quality, also a similar question, we're seeing your coverage ratio now at 184%...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...of reserves over non-performing loans over 90 days. This is the lowest level, I think, since '09. Are you comfortable in reducing this coverage ratio, especially as you're going to be growing more into, I'll say, more secure type of loans, more into corporate loans rather than consumer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, Mario, this ratio impact is a result of the policy of provisioning and everything, right. We are confident with this level. I think this is the highest that we have here in Brazil and we don't have a target for this, right. If we have condition to keep a good level of cover, I think we'll try to keep, but it definitely is not something that we are &#x2013; have this like I want to have these <mark type="ph" /> liabilities (54:58).</p>
          <p>I want to be better when you make a comparison with our competitors, but not necessarily we have a target for this level, right. If you are comfortable with our portfolio, the cover that we have in each different portfolios, each different segments, it's okay, but we expect to keep this R$4 billion in excess that we had. So we don't have plans to increase or not to reduce it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This will be dependent on &#x2013; the way if you have improved in delinquency, certainly this would increase more. You have more pressure in delinquencies that we don't expect too much. We can have some deterioration in this coverage ratio, but not necessarily.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then final question, like you mentioned, you expect delinquencies to probably pick up in the first and second quarter. Central Bank data is showing that corporate delinquencies already started to improve in December. Can you then just give us guidance, when you say you expect a further deterioration in first half of the year, which segments are you more concerned about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we understand that we can have some more pressure in the business at the beginning of the year, as usually we have in that the seasonality we have some effect, but not something significant, a big impact. In the corporate, we will see last quarter is very, very stable and SMEs have a part of this is the deterioration, but we have to put the biggest part of this as a matter of mix. If you're growing in more or less the business, so that the mix has changed due to inside <mark type="indiscernible" /> (57:03), right. So you see a part of business mix. We don't see &#x2013; in general, I think, we'll be more in the business and that will continue to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, Abreu, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mario.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Marcelo Telles from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, gentlemen. Thanks for the opportunity once again. My question is regarding your loan growth expectation for the year, the 18% to 22% growth. One of your peers, yesterday, guided much lower loan growth expectation, around 15% to 17%. Are you expecting to grow above the market or you think that your guidance is pretty much where I also expect the market to grow?</p>
          <p>And the second question is you seem to be pretty bullish on retail lending growth with expected growth of 16% to 20%. Given that we are, let's say, at very high levels in terms of consumer leverage at least by looking at the Central Bank data, are you concerned at all that this growth in individuals might actually lead to a potential continuation of the upward trend and delinquency towards the second half of the year, I mean despite, of course, a better economic environment for the second part of the year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we understand that we have space to gain so much share, yes. In some line of business, certainly, we can lose much share. As we talk about auto loans, for example, we are not looking for much share in this business. We are looking for profitability. So, we can depend on how our competitors will be in the market during 2012. We even can lose so much share in this, but in the other portfolio, we expect to gain much share, given all these investments that we made and so, certainly, have space to conquer part of this much. The assumption that we have is this one.</p>
          <p>In terms of &#x2013; in the consumer side, your question, right, we have some movement in 2012, like for example, the new minimum wage for example and we have other signs that will give more revenues for the families during this year. So, certainly, have space to continue to grow in this market and certainly we can have this space not to compromise too much the revenues they have.</p>
          <p>The data that we have inside the bank for the Central Bank data with the reduction there, we certainly reduced the commitment of the families in terms of what they need to pay. So, it certainly can create space to develop the business in this side. So that's why we have, but certainly we'll be very &#x2013; continue to be very, very conservative in terms of policy of &#x2013; to approve new <mark type="ph" /> spreads (01:00:35) like we always do, so we'll try to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Domingos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Marcelo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Ms. Regina Sanchez from Ita&#xFA; BBA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Hello, everybody. My question is really a follow-up on the other questions. It's related to the NPL ratio. During the year, you said that maybe because of seasonality we'll have an increase in the first half of the year, basically more in first quarter of the year. But then, do you expect, I mean, overall for the year to be flat, I mean to go up, up to 30 basis point in the first quarter &#x2013; first half of the year and then decline? Because I want to reconcile this statement with your expectation that maybe provision for loan losses could be &#x2013; could grow even less than the loan portfolio growth. And then, I'll follow up after your answers. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, Regina, we understand that the delinquency will follow more or less what the dynamics of the economy, as we talked before with your previous question- or the colleague who made a question. We understand that we'll fall in the first half of the year. Second, we have some individuals' portfolio more <mark type="ph" /> in assets seasonality (01:02:05), yes, but in an average, I don't think it would be significant impact, but we continue <mark type="ph" /> this movement (01:02:12) that our economy is leaving a movement of decelerating, we start accelerating and so. But we still see this impact in delinquency until we recover the base that we have we expect to be in the second half of the year. That's why we can see some slight deterioration, yes, but we're not really concerned about this deterioration.</p>
          <p>I think if you have this duration, it's not something that would be whereabouts, but we have good expectation for the second half, yes, it means that the first half of the year, certainly we'll require more expense, yes, could be, if you are right in our assumption that in terms of economic growth, economy in Brazil, certainly, the second half will have lower pressure in terms of expense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then we also noted that in this fourth quarter, one of the reasons you have seen a decline quarter-over-quarter in provision expenses was that you have lower level of discounts granted for clients, which in the case of Bradesco, you classify in the provision for loan losses line instead of the net interest income. And also we saw a decline on generic provisions, because of upgrade of some ratings from corporate clients. We note that loans classified as letter C declined from 23% to 18% and also the loan that classified as letter B went up from 9% to 16%. There is more room I mean for this type of re-classifications of ratings, especially considering that Bradesco has the highest level of coverage of NPL ratios. And this could be a possibility, maybe, to help in this expectation that, maybe, overall provisions for loan losses could grow less than the loan portfolio growth in 2012? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regina, look, it's important to understand what happened, in fact. What happened in a specific portfolio that our risk, we have a specific area in a bank the risk department that they analyze all the line of business and all of the provisions that we have if you have a <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:04:54) or not for some specific line of business or specific segment or orders.</p>
          <p>In this case, in particular, was a specific portfolio that we identified that we have more than 20 times provisions or we have the losses in the last, for example, three years. So the decision was to make an upgrade on this that even with this upgrade this portfolio keeps 10 times provisions than the expected losses, so that's why. If we identified something like this, maybe we can do.</p>
          <p>In other words, if you have other portfolio that's identified to have a lack of provision, maybe you need to make some adjustment. But it's something that is a natural movement that you do during the year, they analyze, they present these where we have a committed risk that they're making a decision when it is necessary, right. But you can say that if you understand that it seems like this, like this very, very, let's say, over, over excess provision, in this sense, maybe you can do that, certainly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just as a final follow-up, I know that you don't provide guidance, I mean, in terms of profitability or earnings per share growth. But what was the long-term view considering the, not the guidance but the plan to reach the 39% efficiency ratio by 2014. Do you think maybe a level of returns above 20% are sustainable, if sustainable for Bradesco, maybe in the case of this year, I mean double-digit earnings per share growth? It also makes sense considering the guidance that you're providing for the March.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, Regina, we're not ready to talk about that, but we understand that I think it will be something around 20% of return on equity based on what we know so far, what we don't in terms of regulation, in terms of everything. This is something, in terms of spread, so I think is normal. But to &#x2013; you know that every year is different year and we have different movement and economy, we'll have different situation, so but we need to analyze. But we understand that we have been able to keep this in different movement, in different situation, that's why we can say it's very difficult for me to say about that because I won't be here in the next year to deliver this, to deliver with my friends with Carlos Angelotti. But I think it's something around 20%, I think something that we can work in a good 15%. Some year we could be a little bit higher, some year a little bit below, but something in an average 20% is good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you so much. Good luck in your new responsibilities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Federico Rey from Raymond James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, everybody. I have a follow-up question on the margin side. According to your guidance, you're forecasting a decline in the margins in 2012. In a previous question you mentioned that this could be related to the expected reduction in the Selic rate, but you also mentioned something about changes in the portfolio mix. My question is how your guidance in term of loan growth and how this will change the participation of SMEs and large corporate relative to, for example, individual lending could affect the margins considering the portfolio mix? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, it's important <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:08:57) not only by segment, we also have this mix. We are growing more in SMEs than expectation than the large corps. If you look at loan for the, on the company segments, certainly we can expect to have improvement in the mix, all right, because SMEs has more than &#x2013; but it doesn't make the total segment of corporate growing more than the individuals. Then you have the reduction in the mix in this sense. But inside the segments we have some changes in the mix for example, individual segment. We are going more in mortgage with lower spread. We are going more in sale deductible loans with the lower spreads <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:09:41) relatively basis you gain more represented dividend in this portfolio certainly in the average, we have this change in the mix. Even inside the SMEs if you are growing SMEs in portfolios, for example, discount receivables for example we have a reduction in the spread, right. And then we'll have the mix inside the segment we'll have this movement so it's a natural movement, but certainly we need to expect a reduction in delinquencies. We know that it doesn't happen at the same moment, this moment, but once you are growing more secured portfolio the improvement in delinquency come later right, but it's actually more or less the dynamic that we understand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Ladies and gentlemen, since there are no further questions, I would like to invite Mr. Domingos Figueiredo de Abreu to proceed with his closing statements. Please, sir, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I would like to thank all of you for your attention so far. If you remind any other questions, please feel free to contact our Investor Relations area. They will be more than happy to attend or demands that you can have. I would like to take this opportunity to thank you all of you for these years of working together where we built we understand we built a healthy relationship. I am confident that Luiz Carlos Angelotti along with the Market Relations Department will do an excellent job in Investor Relations continuing our tradition of transparency and dedication, right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude the Banco Bradesco's audio conference for today. Thank you very much for your participation, and have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>