<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1344057" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-05-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3180</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">&#xC1;ngel Cano Fern&#xE1;ndez, President, Chief Operating Officer and Director</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Manuel Gonz&#xE1;lez Cid, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">&#xC1;ngel Cano, President and Chief Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">&#xC1;ngel Cano Fern&#xE1;ndez</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Manuel Gonz&#xE1;lez Cid</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone and welcome to this webcast with the presentation of the BBVA Group Results for the First Quarter of 2011. The presentation and explanation of the results will be given regarding the Group by our COO, &#xC1;ngel Cano and after that talking about the relative performance of the different business areas by our CFO, Manuel Gonz&#xE1;lez Cid.</p>
          <p>As we always do, at the end of their presentation, we'll answer all the questions that we've received over the webcast. Any questions that can't be answered because there is not enough time will be dealt with by the people from our Investor Relations department today.</p>
          <p>So, &#xC1;ngel, I'd give floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone and welcome to this presentation of our results for the first quarter of 2011 for the BBVA Group. Before we start to talk about the results of the quarter as such, I wanted to briefly go over the environment that we have had during the quarter.</p>
          <p>We started the year better than we ended last year. We are still seeing uneven growth in different geographical areas. The emerging markets are definitely becoming the driving force of world growth in GDP and 2011 have seen growth of over 7% in these emerging economies where we are operating. And for 2011, we're expecting 6% growth by the end of the year there.</p>
          <p>If we then look at the developed economies, there we're seeing some recovery again rather uneven depending on where we're talking about. But we can confirm that progress is being made in terms of governance in Europe and then also in terms of the loan to plans to consolidate economic recovery in various different countries. So, what we yet have to see is how will these plans actually going to rollout in reality.</p>
          <p>Now let's move on to the result of the Group as such. I think there are five key highlights for this first quarter that I want to talk about. First of all, this quarter, I've seen record results over last two quarters. Thanks to the competition of the Group, the diversification we have of our revenue sources between emerging economies and developed economies.</p>
          <p>As we'll see later on in the presentation, we are seeing dynamic growth in revenues and business volumes in the emerging economy and very resilient results as well in the developed economies.</p>
          <p>If we look at the risk indicators after the exercise at the end of 2009 of anticipating or bringing forward provisions for the worst case scenario we had for the NPA ratio, now for the fifth quarter running, we see that we are &#x2013; I would like it to go up &#x2013; flat or better risk indicators.</p>
          <p>The third highlight is just how strong our balance sheet is. At the end of the quarter, we've got 8.9% core capital ratio after having reduced the impact of the investment in Garanti that's at 5%. Yes, the 5% that we have in that Turkish bank incorporates up to March. So, we're seeing continuous improvement in the financial structure of the balance sheet and therefore the key capital adequacy ratios.</p>
          <p>The fourth highlight is due to the dynamic economies in the developing economies is we've got the highest growth income we've ever seen in both Mexico and South America and incorporation of countries such as Turkey and the confirmation of the strong growth of revenues coming from Asia.</p>
          <p>Finally, in the resistance or the resilience that we're seeing in the main geographies of the developed world in 2011 and we've seen this in this first quarter, Spain, the United States are growing in a very focused way with resilient earnings for the key products in the business. So, what's that meant? It means we can present an attributable profit of &#x20AC;1.15 billion which is 22.5% on &#x2013; up from the final quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>We've seen prices going up on retail customer funds in Spain and the growth of the earnings in the first quarter of the year is due to the very dynamic revenues from the emerging markets. The incorporation to revenues of our growth projects, which we've been working on over the last few quarters. And the very positive performance that we're seeing in the key geographic areas like Mexico, South America and Asia. And then the consolidation of the risk premium in this first quarter, the lowest levels that we've seen last year.</p>
          <p>Talking about this resilient net interest income, we can see the performance here in this chart. And you can see that it's higher than it was at the end of last year. So, we think that we probably hit bottom last year. And so from now on, we can expect to see this net interest income creeping up, because of the buoyant performance of the emerging economies, which offset what's been happening in the developed economies, where &#x2013; however we've seen a slower decline in the drop in net interest incomes anyway. And the net trading income gives us then gross income of &#x20AC;5.26 billion which is up 6.4% on the last quarter of last year, pretty well flat through the first quarter of the year.</p>
          <p>We've had some portfolio sales in the United States and in Mexico, and we've taken advantage of the higher revenues that I was talking about to endow more generic provisions for &#x20AC;175 million. This allocation has meant that our generic funds at the end of March, is higher than what we had at the end of 2010.</p>
          <p>Costs are also in line with the forecasts and in line with the growth plans that we have for the whole year. The growth plans and the investment plans focusing on the emerging economies that are growing fastest. And so in this quarter, over the last 12 months, we've grown.</p>
          <p>Staff, we are adding more than 3,700 people, opening another 67 branches quarter-on-quarter and we are still investing in ATMs. And apart from that, another important key to the growth in our expenses is the investment we've made in technology which is growing 16% over this quarter, which has made it possible to continue to confirm as I said before risk premiums at the lowest levels that we saw last year.</p>
          <p>They are slightly above &#x20AC;1 billion and very much in line with the fourth quarter and the first quarter of last year. The total is 1.2% and we can definitely see that its more stable, which means that our income statement is very, very resilient because of the excellent revenues coming in and the net attributable profit is &#x20AC;1.15 billion that's down 7.3% and in all the key lines it's better than it was at the end of 2010.</p>
          <p>Return on assets is 0.95% and return on equity 12.8% and taking into account that this quarter, we've already incorporated the total figure of capital issued last year. And nonetheless, we have not really consolidated hardly anything of the investment we've made in Turkey. So, this is the new snapshot that we get at the end of the first quarter, showing the composition of our income and our profit by different geographical areas.</p>
          <p>Growth income, we can see Mexico and South America give us nearly 50% of our business. The emerging economies account for 57%, which is up from what we saw at the end of last year. Spain is still 32%. And the new region, which our CFO will talk about later is the rest of Europe and Asia already accounts for 13.5% of our net attributable profit.</p>
          <p>The second I wanted talk about is that after the exercise in which we set aside provisions to deal with a worst case scenario for the NPA ratio above all for promoter risk in 2009.</p>
          <p>We can now confirm for the fifth quarter running that we're keeping a very strict control on our key risk indicators. Net additions in this period have gone down 11%. But what's most relevant is not that, it's the fact that they've gone down 11% after already having fallen over 61% last year, and we can expect that to go on. And we really are one of the few players in the financial market that can report these kinds of stabilized indicators, in fact, indicators going down.</p>
          <p>NPA is still stable, 4.1% very similar to the previous quarters. And the specific risk premium and that's very important in order to go on consolidating this concept that we</p>
          <p>won't need to release generic provisions is now just at 1% at the end of the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Earlier on, I was talking about our core capital 8.9% is the ratio after having subtracting the 1.1% of the investment in Garanti, after having added on the impact on our capital of the scrip dividend from the end of the year. That's nearly 20 basis points.</p>
          <p>And the contribution of organic capital that's another 20 basis points, very much in line with what we had forecast for the different quarters. So, our Tier 1 is 9.8% and the total ratio &#x2013; the BIS ratio 13%. And we got confirmation from Moody's of current rating.</p>
          <p>If you look at the financial structure of our balance sheet, you can see that we've been taken advantage of all the windows opening up in the market for issues. 70% of our euro maturities are already covered.</p>
          <p>In Mexico, we've had a successful issuance of &#x20AC;2 billion, and we still have collateral available, &#x20AC;62 billion collateral at European level, and we still haven't needed to tap those markets in any serious way.</p>
          <p>Emerging markets, very clearly, we were expecting buoyant growth for 2011 onwards. And we can see that the dynamic business volumes in both lending and customer funds has been very good. In Mexico, lending was 14%, customer funds 8.6. In South America 28.6% for lending, 15.9% for customer funds, and that shows or that knocks on to the highest gross income figures that we've ever seen in these franchises. If we look at the performance of all the emerging economies, not just Mexico and South America but also Asia, and only for 10 days, but Turkey as well. You can see that revenues coming from the emerging economies are very sound and growing.</p>
          <p>And in the rest of the geographical areas in the developed economies, we've also seen growth. And here the growth has been very focused. We're gaining market share in the products and in the markets that we want to gain market share in, in residential mortgages for example, and we're trying to shore up the balance sheet in such a way that we've been able to generate 160 basis points in market share in Spain over this period.</p>
          <p>In the United States, we are improving things. We are strengthening the mix on the balance sheet. And in particular, we are going from a combination in which 81% or 80% of the loan portfolio was for individuals and companies and 20% was for developers, and now, we've got 89% for non-construction and only 11% for developers or construction, let's say &#x2013; call it there.</p>
          <p>That means there has been a drop of more than 43% in this specific part of the balance sheet in the United States. We've also seen over the quarter improvements in our spreads &#x2013; our customer spread in Spain, it has improved 14 basis points which means we've seen a slowdown in the decline in net interest income that we've reported over the last two quarters. And in the United States it's improvement in the mix on the balance sheet, not just in lending, but also in deposits. This meant that year-on-year, we've generated 17 basis points more or better customer spread.</p>
          <p>And then the consolidation at very low levels of our specific risk premium in Spain at 0.7% and in the United States, that's 1.1%.</p>
          <p>So, all in all, very sound earnings, very resilient earnings. A big contribution coming from the emerging economies and the net attributable profit was &#x20AC;1.15 billion that's higher than the third and fourth quarter of last year. And this focus on net interest income at the end of 2010 was really important and this meant that we have been able to improve it as of the beginning of this year. And we're seeing that in all the different geographical areas in the Group, we're improving our risk indicators. And we have a very strong balance sheet as we take advantage of windows for issuance and all the liquidity ratios are improving.</p>
          <p>In emerging economies, the ones, which are most resilient, are Mexico, South America and Asia and they're showing record figures for revenues in the Group. And in the developing countries, we are seeing how resilient they are to problems elsewhere. And in the developed world as well, we are managing to focus on the products that we want to focus on that are most profitable and in the United States, as well we are improving the fundamentals.</p>
          <p>I'll now pass the floor to our CFO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, &#xC1;ngel. Good morning everybody. After the COO has gone over the highlights of the quarter for the Group, what I'm going to do is to focus on the highlights of each of the geographical areas or business areas.</p>
          <p>May be I'd like to start with a comment about our reporting structure, which as you know this quarter, we're changing the reporting structure that we've been using, and where this will have a greater impact in some areas than in others.</p>
          <p>We've sent all the quarterly data for 2010 and 2009 for this. The reason we've changed our reporting structure is to get a more geographic view of the different businesses the Group operates in. There are many reasons for this.</p>
          <p>First of all, because of Garanti coming into the Group, although this doesn't have a major impact on our earnings on the balance sheet in this quarter as it was only consolidated on the 22nd. But obviously it means that we have to rethink our reporting structure.</p>
          <p>Then on the other hand, to-date we've been focusing on assets on the accounts on wholesale banking and asset management only in Europe and Asia, whereas at the moment, we have a global area that has been defined that also has to be made more transparent in order so that you can see our entire wholesale banking and asset management business throughout the world at the moment.</p>
          <p>So, we thought that the change in the reporting structure will improve the geographic consistency between areas and it means &#x2013; it makes prospective analysis easier with regard to the performance of the different business areas. And it's also another important point, it makes it more easier to compare with our peers in each of our geographic growth and also on a global level.</p>
          <p>As you know, the geographic view of this new reporting structure will affect Spain, and basically we're going to be in Spain &#x2013; we're reporting all our businesses in Spain. But we have a new area which we called Eurasia which is part Europe and part Asia and this includes all our business in the rest of Europe including Portugal, private banking in Switzerland, the branches we have &#x2013; the wholesale branches that we have in different countries in Europe and also in the branches we have, retail branches in other European countries.</p>
          <p>And then on the other hand we also have Garanti. In the case of Asia what we're reporting here these would be the results that come from Citic plus all our wholesale banking business in Asia, whereas in Mexico, the South America and the United States, there is no important change in the reporting structure.</p>
          <p>As you know in the United States, just to remind you, we introduced a change last year where we're bringing the New York branch into the America. It's part of wholesale banking in the US and obviously Puerto Rico and Bancomer Transfer Services. This is important when it comes to interpreting the results and the balance sheet in the United States properly.</p>
          <p>We understand that any change in reporting is difficult, but I'm sure you will agree with us that it was necessary to do this, and of course we are available to you to help you to &#x2013; change of your analysis models. And obviously, we'll be delighted to have any of your feedback what you think on these changes.</p>
          <p>So, having said that, let's have a look at the highlights of the quarter for each of these geographic areas. I would say, there are three important issues in Spain that I would like to highlight.</p>
          <p>First of all, the net interest income decline is slowing down, and I think this is important. Secondly, we're continuing to gain organic market share systematically, slowly, but systematically. And thirdly, as we heard from &#xC1;ngel the situation or the risks that we face is totally different from all our peer groups as was made obvious in the fourth quarter. And this is still true in the first quarter and even more so.</p>
          <p>With regard to Eurasia, may be the most important thing here is the growing contribution from our holdings in China and Turkey, despite the fact that they don't contribute a lot to results this quarter from Turkey but also the wholesale business in Europe.</p>
          <p>Mexico now, I think there are three critical issues here. First of all, the strength of business volumes, the second that revenues are at record levels in this quarter, despite the fact that traditionally the first quarter in Mexico is usually a lot slower than the fourth quarter because of the seasonality of the business in the area. And finally, another important point is that the risk indicators continue to stabilize and they are still showing signs of approval.</p>
          <p>South America, I think we could say the same thing here, but more so, highly dynamic business volumes. The main margins &#x2013; record levels and the risk indicators despite the strong growth that we're showing are very positive.</p>
          <p>United States, this is a very interesting area. First of all, there are clear signs of how business volumes are improving and we have an increasing presence in the market in the segments where we want to be which is the individuals and companies and how the risk premium is improving and therefore generating greater dynamism in the net attributable profit. And this is far truer of Compass than it is for the United States as a whole.</p>
          <p>And finally, wholesale banking and asset management continues to show its resilience and its strength and this is taking advantage of the geographic diversification of the bank. Our wholesale area is picking up more and more traction.</p>
          <p>So, let's start with Spain. The first issue that I mentioned is the trends that we're seeing in the net interest income where the decline is slowing down.</p>
          <p>On the right of the slide, we can see the net interest income where we have taken the markets out, given the volatility that this adds to the net interest income because of the transfers in this operations between the net trading income, the net interest income. And this gives us an idea of the recurring margin of our business in Spain and how it's performing. And we can see how this fall in the net interest income which was quite sharp in the second and third quarter, because of the liabilities, but this is slowing down.</p>
          <p>And great news here, for the first time we've got a 14 basis points improvement this quarter as a consequence, first of all, because we have contained the liability cost and secondly, because of the improvement in the profitability of our assets.</p>
          <p>And on the left of this slide, there are two key factors in this. First of all, how the costs of gathering time deposits are slowing down since 2010. We're talking about almost 90 basis points less than the cost of the time deposits. And then in 12 months it's gone up 71 basis points. And this is associated to a significant improvement in our liability margins where that's still deficient, but has been substantial improvements, if we compare it with the second half of 2010.</p>
          <p>But on the asset side, on the left at the bottom, we can see how we're generating severe reprising all over in all business lines, which we're starting to see the results from in the improvements in the assets, which of course is contributing to the short-term increase in interest rates.</p>
          <p>But as time goes by, we can see the substantial improvements in this. Then the second major issue in Spain is gaining market share. There is no growth in the investment in this market, this is clear. This is part of the cure that the Spanish economy needs.</p>
          <p>And we're growing 26.3% in customer funds and the balance sheet, which is a major improvement as our COO said in the structure of our balance sheet in Spain. And we've gained market shares in the segments where we want to gain market share such as mortgages, which is a way of injecting new customers into the Group's residential mortgages and this is generating new business far quicker than we have seen before. And all of this is improving and of course there is improvement in customer funds.</p>
          <p>And then the third issue that's important in our opinion here in Spain, is the improvement in the risk indicators or the differential that sets us apart from our rivals our NPA is stabilized, it's even showing signs of dropping year-on-year, whereas our peer groups are showing significant increase in the NPA ratio still.</p>
          <p>And maybe the most important thing is not just this, but also the specific risk premium is starting to show signs of dropping as we have pointed out, in a quarter where we've also allotted generic provisions of &#x20AC;175 million here in Spain, which shows that we have very conservative closed end balance.</p>
          <p>Here we have the performance with 478 million in earnings in Spain. And if we compare this year-on-year, this is the worst time to make this comparison, because we're comparing totally different scenarios, but if we look at the fourth quarter, we can see how this has improved &#x2013; that first quarter, with the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>In Eurasia, we can see the highly dynamic revenues and then Turkey adds 24 million in revenues in this quarter, because of the fact it was only consolidated for nine days during the quarters.</p>
          <p>So, in Europe and in Asia, we can see that the revenues are performing very well. And we're talking about an area that is now generating &#x20AC;128 million. And we can also see the performance and the growth in both the quarter as a whole and year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Then Mexico, we said the dynamics of business volumes there. We can see how investment has grown 14% up, our customer funds have also grown quickly 8.6%, despite the seasonality of the business that I mentioned of the first quarter compared with the fourth quarter. And if we looked at this product-by-product and business-by-business, we can see where the growth comes.</p>
          <p>And we can see that we have strong growth in the activities that give us the greatest profitability margins on the balances such as residential mortgages, credit cards are up by practically 15%, we're talking about average balances &#x2013; investments in companies, 9.6%, transaction deposits 5.6%, investment funds16.8%. So, we're accelerating the growth which gives us the greatest margin.</p>
          <p>At the same time, risk indicators are very, very positive. We can see how the loss loans &#x2013; 12.8% and we're normalizing our risk premiums in Mexico.</p>
          <p>So, in short, strong results, record revenues and the net interest income is starting to show clear signs of growth we're now talking about a growth of 5.1%, but we'll see this pick up throughout the rest of the year, as the growth moves &#x2013; filters down into the income statement where you can talk we've seen very flat net interest incomes. We are showing growth and the net attributable profit is up 17.3%, and which is 443 million in net attributable profit. And we can see the year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter comparison here.</p>
          <p>Moving on to South America now, we said &#x2013; what we said about Mexico is also true of South America. Investment is increasing by 28.6%, customer funds are up by 15.9% and we continue to grow market share, both in lending and in customer funds, deposits but despite this growth the stability in the NPA with a coverage ratio which is very sound, very strong with loan losses of 8.5%, and all of this shows that the dynamics of the earnings are very positive.</p>
          <p>The net interest income has increased by 23.5%. The net attributable income 17.5% giving us records in all the main margins. And if we look at the income statement, we can see that South America is generating &#x20AC;280 million in net attributable profit. This is very similar to Mexico year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter the results are excellent too. So, great results from South America.</p>
          <p>United States now, our CEO in his presentation of the Group mentioned some of the issues as I am going to focus on &#x2013; I'm not going to spend too much time on them but we can see how the structure of our balance is changing. Now 89% of our lending is associated with individuals and companies, and here we're growing 9%.</p>
          <p>With new business originations that are doubling in the case of individuals, and if we compare this with last year we are talking about 44.3% growth in the case of businesses. And I think this is very important. We're not just growing in the stock. If you look at the flow, there is enormous growth there which shows that the franchise is starting to bear fruits.</p>
          <p>And if we look on the lending side non-remunerated liabilities have grown by 13% which is excellent and if we look at the remunerator part which has fallen 4% so we are still substituting expensive liabilities &#x2013; liabilities at no cost. And this is the change in our customers where we have a very resilient customer base which has grown by 4%.</p>
          <p>What is just as important &#x2013; the trends we're seeing in loss loan provisions in the first quarter, the provisions are far lower than the average result than the year before. The provision in 2009 of course with the risk premium far closer now to the normal risk premium so although we are a long way from the pre-crisis levels with established NPA ratio, the doubtful ones have fallen by 12.8% and the spreads continue to improve quarter-on-quarter.</p>
          <p>If we look at the income statements, we can see that the situation that I mentioned is translated in to significant growth both year-on-year under the net attributable profit which is &#x20AC;81.9 million and also in those quarter-on-quarter comparison where we are also absorbing certain regulatory impacts that are having an effect on our revenues in comparative terms with last year. So, in the quarter we're talking about an impact of some $25 million.</p>
          <p>Finally, wholesale banking. In wholesale banking and here we are not including the results from the consolidation &#x2013; by the equity method of Citic. This is part of Eurasia rather than wholesale banking. So, we can see how the gross margin quarter-on-quarter has improved significantly. Although this has fallen if we compare with the last year, but it is also important how the result in the emerging markets is now 34% of the wholesale banking franchise, and we can see the trading income has increased and there's also an improvement in revenues which are concentrated on the customer side which has grown by 2%. And we can see the aggregated account for wholesale banking in all geographies which generates an attributed net profit of &#x20AC;364 million, which is a fall if we compare this to last year because the first quarter of last year is one of the strongest we have seen. But if we look at the trends quarter-on-quarter, you can see that it has grown.</p>
          <p>So, in short, sound trends, very resilient in the different areas and businesses with different driving forces driving this growth operating at the same time and an improvement process in areas that are showing &#x2013; that have shown improvement in the past. All this improvement is accelerated.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Manuel and just to round off; we've seen how &#x2013; in this quarter we have generated &#x20AC;1.150 billion, thanks to the dynamic performance of the emerging economies and the revenues. We have also seen a consolidation in the resilience of the developed economies in this case Spain and US with focalized growth depending on the segments and the products.</p>
          <p>With regard to the risk indicators for the fifth quarter, we have excellent news. We are keeping these risk indicators at decent levels and we've even improved some basis points of some of these indicators. The third highlight or key is the clear strengthening of the financial structure of the balance sheet. Core capital is 8.9% having deduced the Garanti investment and we have improved most of the liquidity indicators.</p>
          <p>The fourth improvement, the record revenues from the emerging economies, especially from Mexico and South America, and the fifth point is the consolidation and the strengthening of the franchise in the developed country both in Spain and in the US which is enabling us to gain market share head and shoulders above our rivals in the main products. What about the rest of the year? From the emerging markets, I would say a clear progression quarter-on-quarter both in business volumes and also its gradual translation in to the &#x2013; filtering down to the different margins and therefore the products for this region.</p>
          <p>And from the developed economies here in Spain, we are still seeing how the net interest income can continue to creep down slightly maybe up until the third quarter of this year and especially once we see an increase in interest rates in the Eurozone. But we're still going to focus on gaining market share in the products, as I said in the presentation that gives a great &#x2013; contribute the greatest value to the franchise.</p>
          <p>From the United States the picture is similar. We're consolidating the franchise, we're investing in technology still and changing and consolidating the business model in the United States. We will continue to see successive improvements in our customer spreads and we're going to gain in market share in the most profitable products for the franchise such as individuals, residential mortgages especially and also companies. So, we're going to see an excellent combination of revenues from the emerging markets and also from the developed countries.</p>
          <p>So, now both Manuel and I are here to take any questions you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker>
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, we'll start the Q&amp;A session as we usually do. What I'm trying to do is to Group the questions together into different blocks, in order to save time and give us more time to answer all the questions as we &#x2013; are put to us. The first question with regard to the global results of the Group Britta Schmidt from Autonomous asks about how sustainable the results that we see in our net trading income are &#x2013; how sustainable are these? What are the one-off gains from Mexico and Venezuela?</p>
          <p>Along the same lines, Daragh Quinn from Nomura asks about our views for trading revenues for 2011 whether we're going to exceed the net interest income. Can we exceed the 2010 figure. And then Group wide, when do we expect the provisions charge to drop below 100 basis points for their risk premium? Andrea Filtri from Mediobanca asks the same question concerning the trading income and Carlo Di Grandi from HSBC talks about Group costs, he said that increased by 11% year-on-year this quarter. So, do we think there are &#x2013; investment plan will continue along these lines in 2012? Are we going to be reporting growth of around 11% throughout 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then. I'll start with first the question, when we looked the net trading income figures, we saw that it was divided into various components over the first quarter. We've had no further portfolios that we had in the first quarter of last year. We have had a very good month in euro markets, but quite weak in America. And we are bringing forward the sale of portfolios in the United States and Mexico that was &#x20AC;50 million, and now we're following a similar policy taking advantage of the rates curve in Spain as to what, we did in Spain last year, taking advantage of unrealized capital gains on our portfolios in the United States and above all in Mexico.</p>
          <p>Venezuela contributed because of the valuation of the assets in dollars from $115 million in revenues and the impact on the gross operating income is because of the hyperinflation was another &#x20AC;88 million. So, the gross operating income we're talking about &#x20AC;25 million impact from these two factors. You asked about the sustainability from now on but we could see more capital gains on sales of portfolios in Mexico. It's unlikely that we'll see more quarters as negative or as weak as what we've had in the markets in the Americas, New York, South America and Mexico all the Americas.</p>
          <p>And that means we should see our net trading income seeing less revenues coming in from that because in Venezuela we won't have more revenues of this kind. Revenues that &#x2013; we didn't say this before, but we took advantage in order to offset the hyperinflationary effect in order to satisfy provisions the &#x20AC;35 million in Venezuela. And so, in terms of profit, it's not really relevant. But in terms of the line where these revenues are booked we'll see from now on probably lower levels. However, we should remember that this quarter we haven't had any Telef&#xF3;nica dividend because of the way they scheduled their dividends and they will be in later quarters. And in Turkey as, Manuel have said we've incorporated the investment in Turkey.</p>
          <p>But we've only generated &#x20AC;10 million because we've only brought in that amount of profit. But as of the 1st of April we'll be incorporating the revenues at cruising speed, so that will be more normalized. So, there are some items that aren't yet incorporated, but which will be in the next few quarters. We're expecting the improvement in markets and in trading income from markets; no more one-offs from what we had in &#x2013; or like what we had in Venezuela which means net trading income will go down and this will be offset by other revenues which haven't been incorporated yet. And do you want to talk about the net interest income, Manuel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay, net interest income. There we've got the impact of the exchange rate which could subtract from the income figure in current euros. But our net interest income for 2011 we think should grow against 2010 definitely. Taking into account, the warning about what might happen to interest rates because last year in the second quarter the dollar levels were below 120 or so points, but now we are 148 and more. But even with what might happen to the rates we expect to see growth in net interest income.</p>
          <p>And the risk premium you asked about as well. There as you saw, we got 1.2 at the end of the year, taking into account, we've incorporated in a non-recurrent basis the &#x20AC;175 million of generic provisions taking advantage of the strong growth that we were talking about before in the revenues coming from net trading income. So, if we don't have more NTI and if the risk &#x2013; the specific risk premium makes it possible for us not to draw against our generic provisions in any relevant manner, what we would expect would to have to premiums of about 1% this year and we can expect to see premiums below 1% next year.</p>
          <p>Expenses in 2012 &#x2013; well, here clearly, as we've said in the presentation or we tried to say in the presentation, expenses are growing in a very focused way, focusing on the developing economies, where we see a lot of upside for organic growth. And taking advantage of our leadership positions there, we want to open new branches in Mexico, South America. We've got a plan to go on expanding our ATM network in these regions, in order to improve the productivity and efficiency of these regions in the future.</p>
          <p>And what we are doing now is to invest at least at a similar level to the revenues that we're bringing in. And, as of 2012, the cost income ratio will probably reflect that. So, we're investing in high growth regions and we're keeping a tight control on costs in the developed countries, Spain.</p>
          <p>Retail business is seeing flat growth in costs over the quarter. And we expect the costs even to go down from now to the end of the year.</p>
          <p>We've got several questions from Mario Lodos from Sabadell, asking about the impact of Basel III on our capital ratios.</p>
          <p>And the current Tier 1 that we have is very high 9%. And if it were higher than 9% would we think of increasing our payout over and above the current level?</p>
          <p>And regarding capital, Britta Schmidt from Autonomous asks about the risk for the banking industry in Spain of the results, of the latest stress tests. And will that have a big impact on the financial industry here for June? And, Britta asks about, she says, considering the &#x20AC;2 billion convertibles are going to be included in capital. Would we expect that when you're doing the economic value-added stress tests that's going to have an impact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do what we can. With regard to the impact of Basel III, the first question that was asked. What we're considering is an impact of around 60 and 70 basis points of core capital.</p>
          <p>Because of the &#x2013; all the adaptations we have to make to Basel III regulations. What we're observing this year from Basel 2.5 and market risks we think that given the organic generation of capital within the Group, which is highly significant. And also the measures taken to reinforce this, we think that we can absorb these regulatory impacts with organic generation without any problem and having a very strong capital ratio.</p>
          <p>Apart from being highly strong, if we compare with any of our peers, this rests on APR rate &#x2013; WRA rate was at nearly 60%, which is almost the highest in Europe. So, a core capital of nine with the density of weight risk &#x2013; weight risked assets of 60% if we do compare this &#x2013; if you have a 30% WRA which is the average of our peer group in Europe.</p>
          <p>With regard to whether we're going to incorporate convertibles in the initial ratio and in the stress tests for EVA, I think we will know this because I've seen articles in the press, the EVA capital is highly conservative which is not going to be included in the initial balance of any convertibles, not even for us although we can convert it at any time we want in any quarter, we have the option to do this. But this does not have a fixed conversion price. It's converted at &#x2013; this all depends on when we convert the convertibles. But we are quite comfortable with our position with regard to the EVA stress tests. I don't think we're going to face any kind of problems to meet the stress requisite. And I'm sure with highly restrictive hypothesis and very restrictive definitions of capitals, I'm sure we will be able to generate capital organically. We're highly optimistic here.</p>
          <p>From the point of view of the EVA stress test with regard to the Spanish financial sector, we can't see any general problems here for the Spanish financial sector because the Bank of Spain has defined a main capital ratio, although there are differences &#x2013; this is going to be 8%. So, all banks are going to have to adapt to this new capital requirement.</p>
          <p>And as you know, the minimum core capital required in this stress test of EVA is 5%. So, we are not anticipating any kind of problems for the Spanish financial sector here. And just around of the &#x2013; there's a question on the payouts, it's true that we're around 9% and in the coming quarters more capital will be generated organically. But on the other hand, there are regulatory points that are still pending and we're seeing new trends that we have seen in the past in Switzerland and recently we're seeing this in England.</p>
          <p>There have been recommendations of maintaining high ratios. Until we clarify these uncertainties, I don't think we should do anything to the payout. But the payout is not really our specific reference, but this figure of dividend per share of $0.42, this continues to be our floor for payout dividends and we can confirm this in the quarters to come. So, let's start on the block concerning Spain. I have quite a few questions here, and I'm going to divide this into sub blocks. So, that I don't do them all at once.</p>
          <p>First of all, what is going to be the trend in margins, if there is an increase in interest rates? The question from Antonio Martinez and Raoul Leonard from the Royal Bank of Scotland, how sensitive would our margins be to increases in interest rate in 50, 60 basis points in the interest the rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The sensitivity of our net interest income on the euro balance sheet which is how we manage it not just in Spain, while most of it is Spain, there was a 100 basis points rise would be 12 months, we'd a reduction of 2%, so it's a negative sensitivity to a rise in interest rates in the first year. This is distributed in different way over the year. So, initially there are two quarters where the revaluation of the customer funds is higher than that of the loan portfolios where the penalization is greater and after the second quarter than the reprising of the loan book takes over and then moves on into the next year when we'll get a positive impact of about 5%.</p>
          <p>Obviously, this parallel movement on the curve leads to an increase in the sharpness of the curve in the three to 12 months, and we'd see a reduction of that initial negative sensitivity and that would be good for the net interest margin, net interest income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what evolution would you expect in net interest income in Spain over 2011 and 2012? That's the question from Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric Teschner, Natixis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Basically the COO said in his presentation if you remember that the net interest income if we're talking about trends here in Spain then it's going to continue to drop, but increasingly slower in absolute terms, up until about the third quarter of the year, second-third quarter. The increase in interest rates and what we've just mentioned on the impact they can have in the initial quarter means that the flow and the size of net interest income is around that level. But from there it's going to flatten off those increase slightly in the fourth quarter and then be to a progressive improvement through 2012. That's the trend that we're seeing at the moment, for the net interest income that we're going to see here in Spain.</p>
          <p>So, if we compare year-on-year, the first part of the year, will still be a very complex situation because we're talking about two very different periods. Then in the second half of the year, the year-on-year comparison will improve significantly, and then in 2012, I think the comparative is going to be much better than 2011. Maybe this comment is &#x2013; Manuel, as you say, we need to bear in mind the forecast levels of interest rates and now current volumes with the business volumes we're seeing in Spain.</p>
          <p>Raoul Leonard from the Royal Bank of Scotland points out that we've done an excellent job with regard to reducing loan-to-deposit ratio. His question is the 193% or 163%, do we have a mid-term goal set here, a mid-term goal and how much we want for loan-to-deposit in 2011, 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Published internally &#x2013; in fact, in the Board, we've established ratios and we were talking about improving the capital adequacy ratios, and we established limits for that which were very demanding. To make it possible, to cope with volatility on financial markets and feel completely comfortable. So, we did that as of last year, and in the first part of the year, we've continued to consolidate these limits and improve in a sustainable manner. Gradually that is to say, we're not expecting to see any enormous leaps in the indicators, but we will very gradually improve the ratios.</p>
          <p>How are we working? In two ways we're continuing to generate stable customer funds and we're also diversifying the sources from which we obtain our funding either from retail or from wholesale customers.</p>
          <p>From Nmas 1 the analyst thinks that we've brought down the cost of deposits about 5 basis points quarter-against-quarter and he asks if we could give more color about the competitive environment for deposits? And what you're expecting to happen there in this so called deposit war over 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the first quarter this year, Manuel mentioned this in his presentation, we're talking about 89 basis points lower than the peak in the loan costs last year &#x2013; low costs on lending, customer funds last year. In the second quarter of the year was &#x2013; there is a need to renew deposits or most of our rivals have to renew deposits. So, what we're seeing in the market is greater pressure on prices than we've seen in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>We think that what we're going to see between now and the end of the year would be a slightly higher price than we've seen in the first quarter. But Manuel also mentioned that this will be clearly below the prices we are paying last year not just ourselves, but also our rivals the prices that they were paying.</p>
          <p>And the second important issue is that in the past banks have paid high prices for customer funds has been difficult for them to finance this. So, we think the pressure &#x2013; the all included pressure should be less throughout the rest of the year although that could be still the some kind of pressure especially in the next quarter.</p>
          <p>Concerning generic provisions in Spain in the first quarter of 2011 Tania Gold from UniCredit and Britta Schmidt from Autonomous and Antonio Ramirez from Keefe ask about what will be the levels of generic provisions that we're &#x2013; we think we will have in 2011? How are we going to generate this throughout 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I have said in the presentation, at the moment in our case generic provisions aren't as important as they use to be because we've gradually been reducing our specific provisions here in Spain. And that's very important and definitely this is apart from what other entities are doing. And as long as that continues to be the case, we could even as to endow the generic provisions rather than charge against them. But at the moment, we feel quite comfortable about the levels we have and think that they'll probably stay around there for the rest of the year. And I must say our situation is rather different from that of our peers, because we are improving our provisions for specific &#x2013; sorry our forecast for specific provisions. And along similar lines, talking about generic provisions, Carlos Carulla from Barclays Capital talks about the recurrent levels of specific provisioning throughout the year, because it's the charge that we put to the 2010 accounts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first quarter of the year, it's highly representative of what we're going to see throughout the year. And then in the presentation we saw the premium of 0.7% which really consolidates the lower level at the end of last year, the beginning of this year. And this means that we will not &#x2013; or effectively won't have to use any generic provisions, and as Manuel said, this is not going to be so important throughout the year. Generic provisions, we certainly have enough. And the levels for specific provisions we do not see any change in the trends that we're seeing in the first months of the year now.</p>
          <p>Raoul Leonard from the Royal Bank of Scotland comments or asks how we've perceived the loans, the NPA's falling in the financial sector in Spain as a whole. Have we gone beyond the peak? Or are there going to be several quarters where we'll see the NPO continue to increase and what is our position here and Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric Teschner from Natixis asked practically the same question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Here I think I'm just going to focus on two things. In our activity in recoveries and also when we add new NPAs in the presentation, we give you the figures for the Group and for Spain. And you would have seen that we're consolidating the low level of net additions and something that I didn't say is that the growth addition to this quarter for the Group are the lowest that we've reported over the last 10 quarters.</p>
          <p>And in general, we're not seeing any changes in tendency. In the sector &#x2013; I'm just saying what I'm reading or what I've heard in the results presentation of our peers that the peak in the NPA ratio isn't expected to arrive until the third quarter of this year on basis of the information that we perceive. But in our case we prefer not to be too optimistic yet about these indicators. We just want to monitor the indicators keeping them stable and under control and then see what happens to the economy in general in Spain. And then finally talking about Spain.</p>
          <p>And Andrea Filtri from Mediobanca asks for an explanation about how we see the close of BBVA here in Spain; could you give any guidance about the growth of the loan book and revenues as well in 2011? If the growth of unemployment could have an impact on the balance of NBAs in the system. So, what are we expecting the performance is precisely going to be in 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regardless of the consensus of those we had talking about what's going to happen this year, where the growth our 1% or 0.9% or 1.1% depending on the analyst. With economic growth of this kind this is not enough to generate jobs, so we're going to have to wait for 2012 to see if the economy can grow faster.</p>
          <p>With regard to business volumes, I think there are two kinds of effects here, first of all, the bank balance in Spain needs to delever more, this is something we're seeing quarter after quarter and that's why our lending activity and both Manuel and I have said in our presentations that's why we focus on certain high growth products, but we're still seeing low growth rates especially in products that were strong last year, such as residential mortgages.</p>
          <p>So, if we talk about the financial sector are a whole, we think that lending activity will continue to fold throughout the year by around 5% and for us, we're looking about flat or maybe 1% growth in lending over last year. But obviously the growth rate will be very low. If we translate this into revenues, the main effect on revenues has just been explained by Manuel, with regard to the interest rates we're going to see growth in interest rates and what this will do will lead to greater growth in the margins in the future. But it will take two or three months lag to get this once after an interest rate hike.</p>
          <p>So, I think, revenues are going to be stable throughout the year along the lines that we have seen in this quarter there will be an increase in revenues for 2012, where in turn, we should see greater lending because of greater economic growth as a whole in the country.</p>
          <p>And there was one question or two questions just to finish up this block on Spain. These are economic type questions Andrea Filtri, Mediobanca asks about our forecast for real estate prices, can we expect further falls in prices throughout 2011 and [Didier Monde] asks about the deposit war getting more fierce in Spain. What &#x2013; how do we see this for 2011 and how it going to affect real estate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Real estate prices, in general terms on average, we could talk about a drop of &#x2013; average drop this is of about 20%, 19% maybe, 20% against the current prices of real estate assets. But this will be very unevenly spread depending on the areas we're talking about. We have talked about this in other presentations there are regions in Spain, where they dropped about 5%, 10% but other areas, where the drop has been closer to 15% above all on the coast. What do we expect from now on? We can expect further drops, but more on the coastal areas than in the big cities and that will probably be gradual &#x2013; a gradual drop off over the next quarters. We can't expect to see any sudden drop, although the regions with lot of tourism and a lot of second homes are going to be worst hit.</p>
          <p>Then we have to look at the percentage of housing on our portfolio, it's about 75% and 25%, 26% is land, but 98% of the land is either already got buildings on it or has got town planning for building, and so it's quite easy to get it off of our balance sheet. So, pricing nothing that relevant really in terms of big drops. And then you were talking about deposits.</p>
          <p>As I've said at the end of last year, and in the second quarter where we'll see the renovation of all the campaigns for deposits, we're seeing some more pressure, but from what we've heard for April the prices should be lower on deposits than the prices that were set last year. I'd say probably 1% less than last year on average and we can expect to see these prices gradually creep down further on the basis of the evaluations that we had the last year. What's most important here is that the income statements of the banks aren't strong enough to fund that kind of deposit war.</p>
          <p>Antonio Ramirez from Keefe now has a question about how much risk weighted assets has to do with Garanti? And are going to optimize the management of our risk weighted assets over the next few months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The increase in risk weighted assets regard to Garanti has been &#x20AC;15 billion. So, the effect in RWAs for the quarter is about &#x20AC;15 billion of these come from Garanti. This is just above what we are expected because of the greater growth in Garanti especially in lending.</p>
          <p>And also as a consequence of the exchange rate effects since the transaction was announced. With regard to its capacity to generate cost income in risk weighted assets, we think there is still a lot of upside there that we will see. But the RWAs are closely tied to the dynamics of the business volumes that we're seeing in many of our geographic areas where we're growing significantly in Mexico, South America, in Asia.</p>
          <p>So, we think this is going to continue and we think they will continue to generate certain growth on the basis of risk weighted assets. Moving on to Mexico now there were a lot of questions on the margins and how they are performing Axel Kinzelberg (sic) [Finsterbusch] from JPMorgan asks about the trends in loans in Mexico, bearing in mind the business volumes in the first quarter in comparison with the previous quarter is fairly flat. So, how are we looking forward in Mexico, what do we think is going to happen there with regard to loans?</p>
          <p>Daragh Quinn from Nomura would like more information with regard to outlook on margins and net interest income and the growth in net interest income in general in Mexico. Has there been &#x2013; is there a possibility of any deterioration in the cost of risk in Mexico in 2011?</p>
          <p>Carlos Berastain from Deutsche Bank with regard to whether the growth that we have seen in the presentation in consumer and cards is significant, could this generate problems for future NPAs? And the provisions in Mexico, also by Carlos Berastain, has changed the falling trend for recent quarters. Do we think this is going to be a more or less permanent trend? So, we'll take those questions first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. First of all, lending. We've seen growth on average of about 14% in the first quarter for our loan book in Mexico. If we separate this out between corporate and retail, retail has been growing slightly more than 9%, and this is the rate of growth that we are expecting for the year as a whole between 9% and 10%.</p>
          <p>The income items because of the delay in the knock on effect of the increase in business volumes means that every months and over the last three quarters we've seen gradual growth in net interest income quarter-against-quarter, and that's the kind of trend we're expecting to see throughout the year as a whole.</p>
          <p>Because of the growth, double-digit growth in our loan book which will gradually trickle down into the income items risk premium for the quarter, well that's based on the kind of portfolio we have in Mexico where we have greatest growth as we saw in consumer lending and cards. We've got internal modules to calculate expected loss. And so incorporating the forecast of &#x2013; for expected loss in the future, we don't expect to see any significant change in the risk premium over the next few quarters or the level of provisioning either, the levels we have. We ended the year or the quarter at 3.4%. Last year it was 3.6%. And so now, really, we expect to see risk premiums to remain flat or perhaps even drop off slightly. That's one of the most positive factors that we have been able to report in Mexico for this quarter, in fact. And then what was the other question?</p>
          <p>The change in the tendency in the risk premium, we haven't really seen a change of tendency, first of all, because the lending volume seem to be following the trends which I said at the end of my presentation, from now on in Mexico and in South America we should expect to see further confirmation of very buoyant growth in the different income items, and therefore that particular is down to net profit. We're not expecting much changes in revenues or in the risk premium. So, we already expect to see things changing very gradually over the next two quarters.</p>
          <p>You've answered the question about the impact of the increase in the loan book on income items. But we've got other questions from Britta Schmidt from Autonomous, who has a question about the performance of the coverage ratio, because of the application of the program, end point program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is just the effect of an accounting entry a book entry. This end point program comes because of the crisis that in the 90s &#x2013; in the late 90s where on the balance we had the back book of &#x20AC;400 million outstanding though it's fully covered by provisions because we had a state guarantee. So, in the end we have a debt with the Mexican state that was fully covered by provision. So, what we did in January/February was to close this end point plan with the government where we wrote off 450 million in outstanding and we booked 450 million to provisions. There was no NPA effect except for a tiny effect on the denominator which means that lending force. This has not generated any reduction in the NPA balance, but the coverage has fallen because the provisions have been taken off the books.</p>
          <p>Just to finish off the Mexican books, we have a question from Banco Santander, what are our impressions with regard to the news that has just appeared in the Mexican media talking about forced placement of our division in Mexico. Would BBVA be interested in movements of this kind in the mid or long term and what would this depend on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First question. Quite honestly, we don't like talking about rumors. We haven't been able to analyze anything like this. So, anything that can generate value for our shareholders in BBVA is worth analyzing in the future, but at the moment, it's definitely not something we've analyzed, it is the matter of whether something can generate value or not.</p>
          <p>And then Latin America as a whole. There are two questions, one from Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric Teschner from Natixis which is a macro question. The impact of inflation in emerging markets, what do we expect to happen to inflation in 2011, 2012? And then second question about Latin America from Mario Lodos from Banco Sabadell is what do we think will happen with Banco Provincial, does it make sense to go on to expect this bank to be sold off, is it possible that this Venezuelan bank can be sold off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First point, inflation in emerging countries, you talked about two countries, Argentina and Venezuela, where inflation is clearly above any kind of standard that we want. All the countries in South America have done their home work in a highly orthodox fashion with regard to macroeconomics. We have the levers to be able to control the inflation in these countries. And we are very comfortable with it. The central banks of all the other countries are highly focused on this concept. And they are working on the levers that they have to in order to maintain inflation under control to ensure that it is not a drag on their economic growth. So, you have to be highly orthodox in this region with the exception of Venezuela and Argentina.</p>
          <p>Banco Provincial, first of all we are not considering any sales. We have no intention of selling our bank in Venezuela. This is, far in a way the best bank in the country that is generating recurring revenues. It's highly solvent. Quarter-after-quarter, it's gaining market share. Its position is magnificent both with regard to lending and customer deposits in Venezuela. So, apart from the one-offs that we've seen because of the effects of the devaluation of the exchange rate, it continues to generate revenues in a sustained fashion and we are not considering any kind of analysis. We're not analyzing any kind of sale of any bank in Venezuela.</p>
          <p>Moving on now to the United States, Carlo Digrandi at HSBC asks about our expectations for revenues in the United States for 2011 and 2012, what are going to be the drivers of the expected revenues for 2011 and 2012? Bearing in mind that in his opinion the earnings are a bit flat in the United States for the first quarter, and then along the same lines, David Vaamonde of Fidentiis asks whether the cost of risk in the United States is sustainable and Irma Garrido from Ahorro Corporaci&#xF3;n asks whether the expected profit in the United States, do we expect greater profits in the coming quarters? And what sense would it make to have another impairment later on because of the goodwill we still have on the accounts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Carlo, you ask about revenues in 2011 and 2012 in the United States and basically the main trends we are seeing there, let's talk first of all about Compass, that's the biggest chunk of our business unit in the United States. What we're seeing there is underlying &#x2013; if you look at those static balance sheet, we're seeing underlying growth in customer funds, but lending is pretty well flat at the moment.</p>
          <p>But we're seeing changes in the composition of the mix, so, the income items are improving there. So, quarter-by-quarter, we can reasonably expect that unless there are substantial changes in the competitive environment, there will be improvements. And once we get through the restructuring on the lending side, we will see moderate growth in lending, and similar to what we're seeing in customer funds at the moment.</p>
          <p>And then with respect to some of the one-offs because of the incorporation of Garanti those have to do with the accounting, but they could have a lesser impact than they did last year, which was positive obviously last year, which could be negative in the comparatives for 2011 against 2010. But by 2012, these impacts will be much lower. And then in terms of the other lines of revenues, at the moment what we're absorbing in 2010 and 2011 are various impacts of the regulatory changes in the United States, which have been very significant.</p>
          <p>You know what they are. The increase of the contributions to the guarantees of deposit changes in the regulations on the fees and changes with respect to credit and debit cards. And these have dragged down the generation of revenues in 2010.</p>
          <p>And will continue to do so, perhaps even more in 2011 when the impact would be about $150 million. But once again, once we've got beyond that, by 2012, these revenues will tend to recover significantly.</p>
          <p>And then in the US at the moment, we are also making significant investments in upgrading the technology of the franchise with a new platform which means we are significantly laying out CapEx in 2010 and in 2011 and in the beginning of 2012 to improve the platform.</p>
          <p>But as 2012 moves ahead, things will normalize as the investment will not be so important. So, the impact of these two factors, the regulatory changes above all will be seen in 2011.</p>
          <p>But once we get beyond that, the positive outlook for 2012 is significantly improved. From what, Manuel said, I think there are certain trends. And after 2012, we can expect double-digit growth in the net interest income between 9% and11% year-on-year just about double-digit.</p>
          <p>If we look at the risk premiums, that's another question you asked. There we expect to see slight drops over the next few years, against figures we are currently reporting. So, we're not expecting on the basis of current information that the risk premium will increase in any way. So, we're expecting relevant growth in distributable earnings as of 2012, with the time lag that we talked about in other presentations, because of the crisis we've had in the United States.</p>
          <p>2011 would be the final year of transition. As we absorb the regulatory impacts that Manuel has talked about at the same time. We can expect to reach the highest CapEx in technology in this year, as we roll out the platform in the US. And after we've done that, we can expect good news for the net interest income and risk premium, which means that as of 2012, we can expect to have significant growth throughout the US.</p>
          <p>And then the impairment charge you talked about in that last question. First of all, we are not planning anything like that. But anyway, as you know, this impact doesn't have an impact on our net worth because we've already booked the goodwill.</p>
          <p>And so really, it would just be a matter of where you book the interest. It doesn't have an impact on the capital. It doesn't have an impact on expected earnings. And above all, anyway, we're not planning or expecting or even analyzing anything like that from now till the end of the year.</p>
          <p>In the corporate center, there are two questions from Antonio Ramirez from Keefe, Francisco Riquel from Nmas 1, whether we could give a little bit more color about the composition, volume and contribution to the net interest income from the ALCO portfolio in Spain and for the Group as a whole. They also want to know more about the yield from that portfolio, the kind of terms that you've got, and may we should have a whole new webcast just to talk about that. But anyway a little bit of color of the main issues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a press conference after this as well. We have an &#x2013; a portfolio available for sale of about &#x20AC;20 billion. This is the interest rate risk management portfolio that we have for the euro balance and especially for operations in Spain. This portfolio has a duration of 3.5 i.e. some loss of this portfolio is considered at maturities of between two and four years.</p>
          <p>The contribution of this portfolio in the first quarter has been approximately &#x2013; not approximately it was &#x20AC;198 million. So, that's the data from the ALCO portfolio. I'm not sure whether it's just giving a bit of color or whether I'm giving the whole portfolio.</p>
          <p>Just to finish the final block on strategy, I have three questions here Antonio Ramirez asks about what's our view of our restructuring of the savings banks or non-listed banks in Spain. Tania Gold from UniCredito asks about whether we would be interested in acquiring the Llyods branches in the UK which are going to be put up for sale very soon. And from Citi we have another question, which is almost the same question asking about the UK and would be interested in entering this restructuring process both in the UK and in Spain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, our priority &#x2013; our top priority is to focus on what's fundamental. We want to have ambitious organic growth within the Group in all the different geographical areas where we operate. So, the analysis of any non-organic operation is not a top priority for us, that's point number one.</p>
          <p>Having said that, we're obliged to analyze any transaction in Spain where we're a big player with respect to the savings banks. But as I've said on other occasions, our analysis will always try to generate value. So, anyway that the sale might be instrumental will be looked at, but we would always put generation of value first and foremost.</p>
          <p>Interest for the &#x2013; in the Llyods' branches, we don't have an operation in the UK. I don't know what level of priority we'd assign to this six, seven, I don't know. Strategically, speaking it's not something that's going to worry us too much over the next few months. Obviously, we analyze information as it comes in, but there is no specific interest of any kind right now in analyzing this possible sale when it takes place of branches in England &#x2013; in the UK.</p>
          <p>We've got a lot of business to work on in USA, Mexico, South America, Asia, Turkey and Spain. So, we've got more than enough to eat well. In fact, we probably got too much food on our plate to eat for the next few years. And so we are focusing on our internal growth plans which are very, very ambitious.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>