<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1344055" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-10-26</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3180</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Operating Officer &amp; Director">&#xC1;ngel Cano Fern&#xE1;ndez</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Head of Investor Relations">Tom&#xE1;s Blasco</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Manuel Gonz&#xE1;lez Cid</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and welcome to this webcast for the presentation of the BBVA Results of the Third Quarter of 2011. This presentation regarding the results will be given by &#xC1;ngel Cano, who is the group COO. And during the Q&amp;A which would take place immediately after the presentation, we will also have Manuel Gonz&#xE1;lez Cid with us, the CFO for the group.</p>
          <p>Any questions that can't be answered over the webcast will be dealt with by the investor relations team during today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Welcome to this presentation of the third quarter results for the BBVA Group this 2011. Let's start by pretty quickly looking at the environment. I'm not going to repeat yet again words about the situation we are in in the first two quarters of the year. But in this third quarter, maybe we've seen even greater stress because of the uncertainty hovering over all of Europe. We can see it clearly when we look at the figures for the performance of the markets which aren't in the bank stock market. And we can see the difference here in the performance of the Euro STOXX 50 and the Euro STOXX 50 Banks. And all of this has meant that this quarter we've had a complicated time on the market and also with respect to the environment.</p>
          <p>Maybe this is where once again we've managed to show that our strength is even greater than that of our peers in the three main stays of business at these kinds of times &#x2013; that's capital adequacy, funding and the capacity to generate resilient earnings over time.</p>
          <p>What do I mean when I talk about capital adequacy? Well, that has to do with the capital itself, but also with risks. It's vital to see &#x2013; the capacity to generate capital organically and it's also important to have quality capital. And we must never forget the track record we have in prudent management as we anticipate how to use the right levers to keep the capital at the right level. And we also have to look at the risks. And once again, there there's a lot of stability in our risk management. And the risk profile compared to our peers, I think, demonstrates our asset quality.</p>
          <p>I was talking about the importance of generating capital organically. Definitely that's been a sprint over the last four years, more than 320 basis points of generation of organic capital over this period of time. Moreover, during this period, we've asked our investors for more than 2.3 percentage points of capital, which we've invested in turn in growth operations. Maybe the most important one is the investment we made in Turkey, which meant that we had 1.6 percentage points knocked off our total capital and on others by 0.6, which means we have from a core capital of 5.8% at the end of December 2007 to 9.1%, which is the figure we're presenting now at the end of this third quarter.</p>
          <p>Once again, in this quarter, we've been generating core capital organically, 15 basis points. What we've been seeing over all these quarters since 2007 has been constant generation of organic capital. Apart from that growth in organic, we've had inorganic growth in Turkey and some operations in South America and as we improve our RWA profile over the crisis.</p>
          <p>Perhaps what's most relevant in order to be able to generate capital organically is to be able to generate net operating income that's really resilient with the right kinds of levels of provisioning, which is exactly what we've done over the last few years.</p>
          <p>Talking about the quality of our assets, there's nothing important to say. We've got a 9.1% ratio, as I said before, but we have to look at the quality of the capital behind that ratio. What we present is probably the best density &#x2013; that's RWAs to total assets &#x2013; of all of our peers within the industry.</p>
          <p>But if we look at other ratios such as the EBA capital and its leverage over total tangible assets, maybe there we're amongst the top in our peer group. We're just trying here to understand the quality of our capital despite applying or simulating the same leverage ratio to the rest of our peers. To the right, you can see, what needs for capital exist amongst each of our peers, if this EBA level is applied. So once again, we are in a very sound position.</p>
          <p>And, again, talking about the track record, I don't think I need to remind you of everything we've done from 2007 to date. But the main aim has always been to keep ahead of the wave.</p>
          <p>The second point that I talked about was risk. This is the seventh quarter running since the end of 2009 that we've been able to present stable ratios in terms of additions and recoveries and the total NPA balances that we are presenting for this quarter. As a consequence of this, we've also got stability in our key risk indicators, not just the NPA, but also in the coverage ratio and then bit-by-bit and very stably, we are showing cost of risk which is going down.</p>
          <p>The second vital aspect is funding. We said this in other quarters when we compare ourselves against the last 15 months, just to look at when we last had such tight liquidity on the market, we've improved our gap &#x2013; our liquidity gap and also the wholesale redemption timeline compared to our peer group.</p>
          <p>What do I mean when I talk about our sound funding position? Well, if we look at any of the ratios &#x2013; credit to deposits, customer deposits to assets &#x2013; there we present the best ratios in our peer group.</p>
          <p>And then looking at trends, if we look at the euro denominated balance which is where liquidity is being tighted (sic) [tightened] (0:07:10), there we can see that we are well ahead of our peers. For several months now, we've been anticipating our funding requirements for 2011. So with that, we've already covered them now for the whole year.</p>
          <p>We've been reducing the liquidity gap constantly in all our main business areas. And as a consequence of this, we've got a significant increase in our customer funds on the euro balance sheet.</p>
          <p>The redemptions also look good at the end here, but that is positive in this case. If you look at the schedule for redemptions in 2011, and we're just talking about &#x20AC;11 billion. The third but equally important mainstay is our ability to generate earnings.</p>
          <p>In this quarter, we've seen that we are able to generate net interest margin which is recurrent. And in the quarter, we've seen a situation in which net trading income has been pretty well zero, but slightly negative. Possibly, this is the worst quarter on markets that we can even remember for a long time. And once again, provisioning is pretty stable. And that means that the main risk indicators are also stable.</p>
          <p>Now, we can look at the performance of our gross income over these nine months, 5.7% down. But what's most important here is what happened quarter-on-quarter over the last five quarters. There, if we take out the impact of the volatility of our net trading income and the impact of the dividend as well, because, as you know, in two quarters, in the second and the fourth, that's booked, so it has a seasonal impact because <mark type="indiscernible" /> (0:09:04) Telef&#xF3;nica dividend. We can get a better idea of the more underlying trend of the gross income. And you can see that there is a slight upward trend quarter-on-quarter. This is based basically on the resilience of our net interest income as we'll see very soon.</p>
          <p>Net trading income is a one-off issue. It's difficult to predict what will happen to the trading markets. But this quarter, we know what the markets are like and that was why it was about &#x2013; net trading income was about zero. And now, if we look at the net interest income, we can see that we are very much in line with the gross income, 2.2% growth quarter-on-quarter. And this quarter, the year-on-year comparison against the same quarter of the previous year, it gives us a 1.3% growth. This is due to the diversification of our businesses.</p>
          <p>The more emerging areas are showing growth on average about 17% whilst in the developed markets it's down 11.3%. Perhaps what's vital here is to look at what's happening to net trading income. It obviously hasn't brought in revenues this quarter. In fact, there was a slight negative contribution.</p>
          <p>The trading is very leveraged on our customer business. So the advantage here is that it's not possible to see significant losses in this activity. Maybe we've hit rock bottom here within our business model. And apart from that, the way that we manage market risk is based on marking on to market and having significant stop-loss on all our leveraged positions. And in this line, there were no extraordinary contributions like you've seen in other quarters or any other kind of extraordinary contribution of realizing capital gains which has been the case in other quarters.</p>
          <p>In general, the impact has been all over the world in all the different geographical areas as prices dropped in all the different markets. Costs are evolving in line with previous quarters, really pretty well flat. We shouldn't forget the impact of guarantee on these costs. Without the investment in guarantee, we are growing 5.1% that we can already see that there is a slight flattening out or even a slight downward trend in these costs.</p>
          <p>The growth in costs, as I've said in other quarters, is fundamentally located in those geographical areas where we have emerging economies with growth plans in terms of new branches, putting in ATMs and trying to bring in new customers into the banking system.</p>
          <p>Provisioning &#x2013; well, in provisioning, once again, this quarter we see a slight downward trend. Maybe what's so important here is more the confirmation of the dropping-off of provisioning levels in the US for some quarters now. This is definitely being confirmed and there is very little uncertainty here because it &#x2013; it's because of the kind of MBA portfolio we have there, which means that we don't have to have so much provisioning for the bad book, for the non-performing assets.</p>
          <p>So income statement shows a net attributable profit of &#x20AC;3 billion &#x2013; &#x20AC;3.14 billion for the nine months to date. That's a drop of 14.3%. If we don't include the NTI here, then the drop would have been 4.8% instead of 14.3%. It's also true that the &#x20AC;8 billion figure for the quarter, nearly all of the drop against the previous quarter, could be considered to be due to what's happened to trading income.</p>
          <p>Anyway, the ratios concerning our different returns look very good; they're lower than previous quarters. But if you take into account the environment we are operating in, the comparison against our main peers shows that we are doing well compared to them.</p>
          <p>Okay. Let's go to geographic areas now. And if I go over these highlights as I move from one geography to another, and we can see the main highlights for each of the geographies here.</p>
          <p>So let's start in Spain. One of the two or three main issues in Spain is the stabilization of the net interest income after the sharp fall that we saw in the third quarter of 2010 and a slightly lower fall in the last quarter of 2010. And from then on, we've started to recover the spreads based on re-pricing management for our assets and managing a lower cost of our funding both for retail and for wholesale banking.</p>
          <p>Because of this, we can clearly show the way on &#x2013; we've reached the floor in our performance in the net trading income and we are starting to see it flattening out and becoming more stable, so that we can now &#x2013; I can forecast a slight recovery in the net trading income in the coming quarters.</p>
          <p>Risk indicators now. As I said before, we have stability in all these indicators starting with NPAs. The NPA ratio is up slightly this quarter, but this is because of the denominator rather than numerator. And as we can see in the graph here, and I think the coverage rate is in line with previous quarter's risk premium, now this has stabled off as well. And 0.7 after &#x2013; for the third consecutive quarter and maybe the big difference here is if we look at these risk indicators and compare them with the industry, after several consecutive quarters, we can see significant deterioration in these.</p>
          <p>Looking at the income statement for Spain now, we've got &#x20AC;1.172 billion &#x2013; &#x20AC;1.162 billion, but the environment has been a very difficult one, especially on the net trading income in the market area &#x2013; net interest income, sorry.</p>
          <p>This is the first &#x2013; this year 2011 is the first year we've started reporting Eurasia with a highly dynamic generation of revenues. We can talk about the rest of Europe. We're also including a new investment we've made in Turkey, plus Asia, which includes the Chinese investment. So as we can see, we're growing at a very fast rate and, in fact, over &#x20AC;1.3 billion in gross income which comes from this region.</p>
          <p>If we look at the income statement now, the contribution from this income statement in the first three quarters of the month is over &#x20AC;700 million. So it's a clear net contributor to the income statement for the group and I think this is something that will continue in the coming quarters.</p>
          <p>The next region we're going to look at is Mexico. Mexico is growing in its main headings. Slightly under 10% both in lending and in customer funds. And it's also growing in the budget items that are the most profitable ones from the point of view of the net interest income. And from the point of view of customer funds, it's grow &#x2013; we're seeing double-digit growth almost with regard to transactions and time deposits. This leads us to 6% increase in the net trading &#x2013; net interest income in the first nine months of the year and then year-to-date. But if we zoom in on this performance, we can see that the performance is even better than that.</p>
          <p>If we look at the retail net interest income, which is growing by almost 13%, and this net interest incomes for global retail banking, especially from the market area, is showing clearly lower growth and this is what gives us the average of 6% growth. But in any event, if we compare ourselves with our peers in Mexico, we can see that the net interest income is clearly above that of our peers.</p>
          <p>In lending, once again, the improvement in provisioning, this is stable enough. This is down to 3.4%. But we can show a fall of over 3% in our provisioning. At the end of the bottom line, the net attributable profit is &#x20AC;1.275 billion, which is approximately a 3% growth on the year-to-date. And especially, this is driven by two lines, the net interest income and provisioning.</p>
          <p>South America now. We're seeing activities both in business and in assets. In South America, it's growing much faster than anywhere else. We're going at nearly 30%, both in lending and in customer deposits, which means that the net interest income is growing by over 28%.</p>
          <p>Despite the fact the markets have had an impact, the gross income continues to grow at 19%. And obviously, any of these margins this quarter is setting records for the region. And apart from this highly dynamic growth in revenues, the risk indicators are also behaving very well. We've got the best figures here for the group. The NPA &#x2013; it has the lowest NPA ratio, the highest coverage ratio for the whole group. Despite the fact that loan loss provision has increased by 10%. But this is offset by the enormous increase in the business we're seeing. And the best way to understand that is to look at the risk premium and we can see that this is 1.3% which is fantastic.</p>
          <p>So if we look at the income statement now, we are talking over &#x20AC;750 million results, over 11%. And both in Mexico and in South America, this is enabling us to invest in opening new branch offices and to generate new business. We're continue to modernize and to invest in technology in these franchises in order to improve the servicing for our customers, but above all to bring new customers into the bank.</p>
          <p>United States now. United States continues to perform as it has in recent quarters. It's selective growth both in lending and customers funds, especially in individuals &#x2013; individuals and companies. But we're still seeing significant falls in commercial real estate as we can see here, nearly 40% fall here.</p>
          <p>We're gaining market share in &#x2013; market share of lending without the commercial real estate business increases. Customer deposits, unremunerated versus remunerated, are growing because of the liquidity we have in the United States and BBVA Compass franchise which means that we've reduced the balances on the remunerated balances.</p>
          <p>And this combination means that the cost of customer deposits has fallen once again for the fifth consecutive quarter, so that we've managed to improve our customer spreads to 3.94 that we reached at the end of the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Once again, in the United States, as we've seen in other franchises, the net interest income for the more retail bank, so the local markets, we're talking about an increase of nearly 3% whereas the wholesale banking have fallen by nearly 24% in this quarter.</p>
          <p>Loss loan provisioning is a highly positive news from this quarter on the income statement. There are falls of nearly 40% in the year-to-date and the risk premium is down around 1%. This means that once again this quarter we have an NPA ratio of below 4% and with a coverage ratio that continues to grow for the fifth consecutive quarter and we're nearly 70% coverage. Basically, this is due to a significant reduction in the gross entries, which have fallen by over 40%, and we're recovering almost 100% of the entries or additions in each. This means that we have net attributable profits that are still smaller at &#x20AC;218 million, which is a growth of 1.5%, although the impact here is depended on the way the markets have behaved in the United States, the wholesale market especially.</p>
          <p>If we take out the wholesale factor, BBVA Compass, and the local business would be growing by almost 40% in net &#x2013; attributable net profit.</p>
          <p>And finally, just a quick overview of wholesale banking. First of all, we need to talk about the recurrence of our wholesale banking even in a complex environment such as this quarter. Thanks to the diversification by geographic areas, we can see this clearly on the slide. Almost half of it comes from Europe and the rest is well divided between the different geographies. But it also comes from the different products that make up the gross income.</p>
          <p>Maybe we can quickly go over the main units of this business area. We have corporate and investment banking. They are growing their net interest income by 3.4% and net fee income by nearly 6%. So the recurrence of the revenues is great despite the fact that lending is practically flat.</p>
          <p>If we look at global markets, we've continually been reporting the difference in behavior between the revenues that come from the customer franchise and the revenues that come from trading. These have fallen in the year-to-date by 36%. However, the revenues coming in from the customer franchise were increased by 17%.</p>
          <p>Let me put these two components together. So the gross margin here has fallen by 5.3%, but the resilience of revenues can be seen to come from the weight of the customer franchise. And finally, this gives us an income statement for wholesale banking in all geographies that's over &#x20AC;860 million. This is an 11.8% fall because of the market performance in this quarter, but I think it still shows significant resilience in the revenues.</p>
          <p>And just to round off, I'd like to go over the three highlights for managing situations such as the one we're seeing in the current environment and to maintain our position apart from our peers. Capital adequacy, the impacts that we've seen of managing capital from the point of organic generation of capital and to continue working on the quality of the capital that we generate with prudent and anticipatory management as always.</p>
          <p>From the risk point of view, this is the seventh consecutive quarter with stability in the risk indictors when the industry is deteriorating. In funding, we are improving quarter-on-quarter in our funding structure both in redemptions and managing our spreads and finally in generating earnings.</p>
          <p>This is critical. It's very, very similar. It's resilient throughout the income statement. And the quality of our net interest income and in this market and especially the revenues that come from trading income that have really marked this quarter because of the resilience of our revenues. And once again, I would repeat we are showing this sustained stability of provisioning in this quarter.</p>
          <p>So I'll now hand the floor over to Tom&#xE1;s Blasco. And Manuel Gonz&#xE1;lez Cid and myself will be only too happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we've done in previous quarters, what I'll try to do is to put questions together in different blocks, so we can answer as many questions as possible.</p>
          <p>So let's start with the net trading income. Marzello [Marzello Zanardo] from Bernstein, Antonio Ramirez [Antonio Ramirez] from Keefe, Benjie Creelan [Benjie Creelan-Sandford] from Macquarie and Daragh Quinn from Nomura are asking about whether we can &#x2013; you can give us a bit more color with why or what explains the fall in the net trading income for this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Above all &#x2013; and, of course, you can add to what I say, Manuel. But I think what we should be looking at is what's happened over this quarter where we've seen an across-the-board drop of prices in nearly all the markets &#x2013; well, in all the markets, even the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>Normally, as I said in the presentation, the way we manage market risk means that we are consistently using the levers to avoid losses with a stop-loss function which comes in &#x2013; kicks in automatically. And that means that you have this floor, which means in turn that we don't have to see such high losses as some of our peers at times like this because other banks have had very significant losses compared to us.</p>
          <p>If we compare ourselves, if we look at the &#x20AC;300 million, &#x20AC;330 million more recurrent in more normal conditions, that's the main difference that sets us apart from the rest in this quarter. But fundamentally, I'd say the fact that there has been a drop in prices in all the markets has been important. And that's had an impact on our pension managers as well because they have fixed income securities on their asset books and they have to be marked to market because they have to obey the regulations regarding this marking to market and so there is a pure price impact here. There is no extraordinary impact which might offset this generalized drop in prices.</p>
          <p>Previously, in other quarters, we've been reporting the realization of unrealized capital gains on the liability side. And here we've just got exactly what we got from the trading without anything else, however. We can see that the customer franchise gives us room to growth in &#x2013; to grow in investment banking and in global banking for the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In line with what the COO just said, I just wanted to add that if you look at the corporate activities, there, the NTI is negative. And basically, what we've got there are the mark-to-market of the positions deriving from hedging. And they've classified this hedging on the accounts, but they are really hedging interest rate risk and forex risk and the equity books. And given the current state of the market, that's negative. But that's like an underlying hedging which actually would have performed better than it seems to when you look at the figures.</p>
          <p>And then we're asked about the tax rate. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (0:30:24) and from Bernstein and from Preventis, we have questions about the possibility of you explaining this low tax rate for this quarter. And can you give us some outlook for this rate which seems to be significantly lower than other quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The tax rate this quarter once again, as we saw last quarter, is very similar. And there &#x2013; I think there are two important factors here. First of all, the fact that we're seeing more and more profit as we can see from the earnings, they are coming from more geographies where the tax rate are lower than here in Spain, which reduces the tax burden that we have here, not just now, but also in the future. And also the losses in this quarter related to trading are based in Spain where we have the higher tax burden and the combination of this brings down the overall tax burden. But maybe the most important thing here in this question is not just the current situation, but rather going forward for the group in general.</p>
          <p>What we're forecasting for the coming quarters would be a tax burden that will be reasonably sustainable below 20%. Maybe one step down from what we've been seeing in the previous quarters. And this is because of the different contributions coming from the different geographies within the group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the net interest income, <mark type="ph" /> Antonio Petosky from ENG Bank (0:32:12) asks &#x2013; is asking about what our forecasts are for net interest income in Spain for the fourth quarter of 2012 and what are the forecasts for 2012, what should we expect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The net interest income in Spain, as far as we can see, is showing signs of flattening out after significant deterioration as of the third quarter of 2010 in the environment in which the cost of funding was going up significantly. This cost of funding, above all, with customer funds, it's improving. The lending book is improving. And this improvement hasn't yet been reflected sufficiently in the net interest income because the funding costs on the wholesale markets are dragging down that improvement in our customer spreads.</p>
          <p>However, what we are expecting is to see this net interest income to remain at similar levels to what we've reported in the third quarter once we get to the fourth quarter. And we are expecting to see further stabilization throughout 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Talking about capital now, we've got a question from <mark type="indiscernible" /> (0:33:32) from Daiwa Asset Management. He asks for information regarding the core Tier 1 ratio under Basel III. What would it be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Manuel, would you like to take this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Basically, I don't think it makes very much sense talking about this ratio at this moment in time because, as you know, Basel III comes online in 2013 and is going to be phased out in 2019. So talking about a ratio in September 2011 of Basel III with all the impacts of Basel III, something that's going to come in in a long time in the future, I don't think it really makes a lot of sense.</p>
          <p>You have all the information about our core ratio, the way we published it. And basically, our core ratio in capital is very, very similar to other ratios that are currently under consideration. And from the point of view of deductions, as you know the deductions that we have, so I think you can work out your own figures. But if we took into account all the impacts of Basel III seriously, I think it will be &#x2013; it would be over 7%, which is the minimum ratio established by Basel III for 2019.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Funding and liquidity, Britta Schmidt from Autonomous and Raoul Leonard from the Royal Bank of Scotland are asking about what have you been done is repo activities throughout this quarter, if you can give us a bit of color right from the beginning of the year from 2011. They're asking about the price that we think should be &#x2013; that cover bonds should reach in the market and then uninsured or unsecured debt.</p>
          <p>Raoul Leonard is asking about the absolute repo funding level that we have, for instance, in the London clearinghouse and some other euro clearinghouses. What's going to happen in this? Can you forecast what's going to happen throughout the year? And he ends up with a question about whether we are building any kind of extra liquid assets or do we have any certain extra liquidity in some assets because we think there is going to be a credit squeeze in the market with regard to lending. So do we think there could be a credit crunch in 2012, so we're offsetting this now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To answer all the questions on this, I would say, first of all, as was made clear in the presentation that BBVA has a well contained balance sheet with significant base of deposits. So its dependence on the capital markets is limited. That's the first message to take home from here.</p>
          <p>In an environment like what we have now when the liquidity risk is a top line concern in this quarter for many of the financial institutions in Europe, it's really important to take that into account. You know what's happened on the market and this situation has entailed impairment of unsecured funding and people have fled to the secured markets which have continued to work pretty well and some markets &#x2013; even some unsecured markets in the short-term have worked reasonably well, especially for credit institutions with the quality and the level of capital adequacy that the BBVA shows.</p>
          <p>Looking at the increased repos this quarter, the figure is associated to trading operations and customer transactions. In our ALCO portfolio where we are working on the basis of a multifactor analysis and the balance isn't that different from what we had in December, for example. It has gone down in June and now it's gone up this quarter, but it's not especially significant. I think it's &#x20AC;8 billion in the quarter and that kind of figure is not significant in itself.</p>
          <p>And if we look at BBVA's dependence on funding from clearinghouses, this is very limited and there haven't been significant changes in our need to turn to the clearinghouses during this quarter at all.</p>
          <p>Our liquidity management in this environment, as you know, is something that we've been actively managing for some time with an idea of anticipating what might happen in the future, looking at our available collateral at all times, which is very important and it's far higher than our short-term funding from the unsecured markets, okay, and your asset quality.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David Vaamonde from Fidentiis asks about the NPA ratio in Spain. It seems to have worsened for the first time since the fourth quarter of 2009. How do we think it's going to perform in the short-term, that is over the next few quarters? And which of the segments where we see the worst impairment?</p>
          <p>And Rohith Chandra from Barclays asks about the explanation for the quarter-on-quarter increase in our NPA ratio, 20 basis points this quarter. He suggests that the developers have pretty stable balances. So what part of the loan book is showing greater impairment?</p>
          <p>From La Caixa, David Fern&#xE1;ndez asks about outlook regarding provisions and NPAs in 2012, what we think 2012 will shape out like.</p>
          <p>And Francisco Riquel from N+1 says that in the fourth quarter of 2009 we said that the peak in NPA in this cycle could be at about 5%. What kind of visibility have we got regarding that 5%, taking into account the macro impairment could be expected over 2012? Are we thinking of pushing up that possible peak in 2012?</p>
          <p>And we've just this very minute got another question from Luis Pe&#xF1;a from JB regarding asset quality. And he asks, is BBVA thinking of increasing its real estate coverage in Spain for all the stressed and distressed assets? What's the BBVA strategy regarding setting up a pool of illiquid assets? So there is a five or six questions that they all have to do with the same underlying theme.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, there are three slides from my presentation, numbers 9, 10 and 23. Slides 9 and 10 talk about the NPA ratio for the group and number 23 talks about the NPA ratio for Spain. But if we look at either of these we can see the stability in the NPA ratio, but in particularly in Spain, in slide 23, we can see how the NPAs, i.e. the numerator in this equation, remain stable. And there's no particular segment or product that stands out especially because, as you said, not even developed, have shown any growth in NPAs in this quarter.</p>
          <p>But here we're talking about the denominator, i.e. the fall in lending, and that is what has caused this 20 basis points increase &#x2013; a 4.9% increase. So in this quarter, I don't think there is any change in trend that will force us to change our discourse to date in practice. I think things are stable especially if we look at the NPA ratio.</p>
          <p>Looking forward now, from what we can see in the pre-entries, if you like, we're not seeing anything that would make us change our forecast. What is more complex is to decide when the industry is increasing their provisions for NPA ratios with the forecast that we're seeing coming out to date.</p>
          <p>We haven't considered any exercise that will consist of an accelerated increase in coverage. We're still in line with the regulations the way they are. Maybe we're being slightly more prudent in our assessment of our assets. So we are devoting &#x2013; putting some million euros aside extra to cover real estate assets, so that we can have the best possible cover. We're talking about 33% coverage ratio. But maybe going forward, if we had to look over the next two years, maybe over the next 18 to 24 months, there could be a slight impairment of assets. This could be between an additional 8% and 10%. So I don't think it's highly significant, nothing that can't be covered in the next coming years with the capacity we have for generating net interest &#x2013; sorry, operating income in this group.</p>
          <p>With regard to managing illiquid assets, we don't have or had any plans to create any unit for illiquid assets. All of this is covered especially here in Spain where this activity of mobilizing assets off the balance sheet is more important. The question here is to have professional teams we've increased in recent years, so that we can accelerate the recovery, not just of the entries in NPAs, but also the sale of real estate assets, but there's no plans to create any new units.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Coming back to capital. Britta Schmidt from Autonomous. Her question is whether we're considering to maintain the scrip dividend for 2012 in order to conserve our capital figures. Along the same lines, Ignacio Cerezo [Credit Suisse], his question is practically the same. He talks about the distribution in absolute terms both in cash and in scrip. And Ignacio Cerezo from Credit Suisse asks us about where the increase in risk-weighted assets have come from in this quarter and how the risk-weighted assets &#x2013; what's going to happen to them throughout 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Starting with the dividend, we shouldn't forget that these decisions have to be taken by the Board of Directors; and secondly, they have to be approved by the general meeting. So here, at this stage of the year, all we can say is what we've said previous quarters firstly.</p>
          <p>We are thinking of changing the dividend policy with respect to the payout level that we have at the moment. Secondly, the idea of having a scrip dividend is subject to the proposals put by the Board to the general meeting will probably be at a similar level to that that we had in 2011. As to our risk-weighted assets, you know where they come from. We told you in the presentation, basically from the most dynamic geographical areas with the highest growth in business volumes, which are the main contributors of RWA this quarter. So those are geographical areas that bring in the highest returns and the highest profits to the group at the moment.</p>
          <p>However, as we look forward to the next few quarters, our intention is to continue to work with the internal plans we have to keep a strict control on our capital consumption using internal models, so that we can control RWAs and perhaps not even having them growing over the next few months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And with respect to sovereign debt, Juan Pablo L&#xF3;pez from Espirito Santo Investment asks us to explain in greater detail what exposure there is to the public sector. Customer funds from the public sector seem to have increased, but that's true of lending which is going up about 8% year-on-year. What kind of NPA ratio would you see in the public sector? Is there a refinancing going on?</p>
          <p>And then F&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric Teschner from Natixis wants more color on our exposure to sovereign risk in Greece, Ireland, Italy, Portugal and Spain in terms of available for sale and hold to maturity and the trading book. Can you please give us this kind of information?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you know, we have a long track record of relations on managing customers in the public sector and with the Spanish public sector, both with the central government, the regional governments and the municipal governments. Credits to this segment, lending to this segment has been totally flat this quarter. We do, of course, have a higher market share because of where our group comes from, especially Argentaria where we have a bank that specializes in funding the public sector. But I can assure you that at the moment we are financing under 10% of the regional governments, which I think is a major indictor if we bear in mind that our natural market share in the Spanish market would be approximately 12%.</p>
          <p>From a risk point of view, we consider this a sector that performs well. The NPA is almost inexistent and at the moment we're talking about one of the most profitable segments with regard to spread and also the sovereign debt crisis that we are seeing.</p>
          <p>We have large deposits from the public sector and a significant amount of the funding flows that come from tax gathered by <mark type="ph" /> the states (0:49:17). So we have a good assessment of the cash flows from all these regional and local governments. So it is of no concern to us at the moment within our business strategy here in Spain.</p>
          <p>At the same time, you also know a constitutional ceiling has been placed on the indebtedness of the public sector, which also includes the regional government, apart from the budget control measures that have been taken within the fiscal correction program taken by the Spanish government, which includes all the public administrations. So I would think that the lending issue will continue to improve.</p>
          <p>If we look now at exposure, the exposure that you had mentioned, currently, our exposure to Greek debt is &#x20AC;86 million. It's nothing. It's also absolutely irrelevant in Portugal. We're talking about &#x20AC;14 million. We're talking about the sovereign debt of EU states. And we have no exposure to Irish sovereign debt. And the only exposure we have at the moment or the most important exposure we have would be to Spanish sovereign debt followed by Italy. Greece, practically all our exposure is fully covered, our exposure to Greek sovereign debt. So our exposure to European sovereign risk is concentrated basically in Spain and, to a much lesser extent, in Italy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Costs. <mark type="ph" /> Carlos Gonzalez (0:51:27) from the Santander Group is asking us about the growth in costs. Although the COO mentioned that they should slow down, the truth is how long will this take and what are the mid-term sustainable levels both for Spain and in the other geographies where we operate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cost performance, as we saw in the presentation, has flattened out in this third quarter. Within our forecast, costs are growing in those areas where there is highest growth. I repeat, that's basically in Mexico and in South America and partially in the US linked to the new IT platform that we've been building over the last two years.</p>
          <p>Our forecast is that once the main track of investments have been made, we can expect to see new branches being opened in Mexico and South America. In Mexico, we want to have 2,000 branches by the end of next year. And this will mean some increase in the cost profile for Mexico and South America, but always linked to the generation of revenues in that region.</p>
          <p>The cost performance over the next few quarters will be very much in line with what we've been seeing this quarter and next quarter with costs being kept under strict control at all times as we're seeing in Spain with even &#x2013; where there is even a slight drop in costs. And it's only in those places where we have organic growth plans should we expect to see costs increase at all.</p>
          <p>In the presentation we showed that without incorporating the guarantee costs on to this quarter or in the year-to-date, the costs would have gone up 0.1% and this one decimal point up or down reflects the average inflation we have for the group as a whole. So most of the growth in costs is linked to growth in the developing economies which are growing fastest, which means that we have to put in new ATMs, we have to open new branches in order to service our customers in those areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then Leonard from Royal Bank of Scotland, but also we have questions from Barclays, we have questions about what's happening to the loan book in Spain. All three analysts think that the rate of growth of the loan book in Spain is slowing down quarter-on-quarter. What pace do we think the deleverage <mark type="ph" /> will deleveraging (0:54:21) growth, as we show, over the next 18 months? Will the deleveraging continue as fast as it has in this third quarter of 2011? What do we expect for 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we've seen this quarter is a general situation of lack of lending, which means that this is what has led to the 2% fall in lending that we saw in the presentation. And the feeling that we get, there is lack of lending growth. We think this is something that will be ongoing, certainly throughout 2012, so we're seeing deleverage. Industry-wide, there is going to be greater than we've seen in our group &#x2013; that's about 6% -- and where it could be down to about 5%. In our case, I think it's going to be similar to what we are seeing at the moment. But I think that this lack of lending business would cover most of the products that we are talking and most of the products that we sell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Moving on now to profitability or the return on the group, Carlo Di Grandi from HSBC, he says that if we take the environment into consideration, the changing environment, and the regulator will continue to have an impact with the measures that they take on the rotation line of the banks, what can we expect with regard to return on equity over the next two years? Where do you think BBVA is going to be in line with our forecasts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's all related to guidance, assumed guidance for the next two quarter, but you know that we don't give guidance. Our target is, first of all, to continue to present the best return ratios in our peer group, which is what we are doing now, and even in quarters when they're lower compared against our track record, but not against our peers. So our target for the next two, three years is once again to reach the levels of about 14, 15%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mexico. Britta Schmidt from Autonomous asks about the results from Mexico, which seem to have somewhat weakened in constant exchange terms compared to the forecast at the beginning of the year. And there seemed to have been some problems related to the net interest income &#x2013; net interest income performance. Then what do you think this performance will be next year compared to this year? Is it impacted by the currency?</p>
          <p>Carlo Di Grandi from HSBC asks about the growth of operating income and net attributable profit which he says hasn't been as high as expected despite the increase in volume. What forecasts do we have for 2012?</p>
          <p>Matteo Ramenghi from UBS asks if there is a change in the Mexico strategy. He says, are we giving more credit card and consumer finance and less residential mortgages? Is there a change of mix in Mexico? Is it intentional? So those are the questions about Mexico.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, our view of the earnings from Mexico. We don't think that they're weaker at all. It's a fact that the retail or local results can show an increase in net interest income of nearly 13%, which is above the approximately 9% growth in lending. So if we look at the underlying of the earnings, I think it clearly shows there's a positive growth. And this is &#x2013; I think is setting the trend for the next few quarters.</p>
          <p>The component that offsets this is the net interest income in the wholesale business, which brings it down in this quarter. But I would repeat that once again this is one of the most complex quarters from the markets point of view, so the underlying &#x2013; the lending activity in the retail business, I think it's continued to perform very, very well. Maybe what we have seen in very recent months is a lower increase in company and business credits, SMEs lending, because both consumers and mortgages are growing well. So maybe in mortgages, there is only one issue that makes it difficult to compare with last year and that is a reduction of some old mortgages that related to the <mark type="ph" /> stand (0:59:46), which were cancelled &#x2013; the bad book were cancelled at the beginning of the year. And the first thing that we did, this led to a one-off drop in our bad book.</p>
          <p>But the underlining is very much the same. We look &#x2013; we want to grow in the individual banking and in credit cards, in consumer finance, in mortgages, and in SMEs and business banking. We hope that business will pick up again, especially with regard to the governments and big business. The forecast for 2012, without giving you any numbers, but basically each quarter, we're going to see how the net &#x2013; the underlying net interest income will continue to grow at a rapid pace.</p>
          <p>The other important item, once the trading income for the quarter is high &#x2013; has been highly volatile as it has in other geography. If we factor this in, this is something that we cannot predict for the coming quarters, then the other line that we will continue to conserve will be the risk premium. Quite honestly, this is stable now, maybe slightly higher than other areas, but this is linked to the growth in lending in Mexico in the consumer markets and that's the answer to that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. EBA, the European Banking Authority, which is the next block. There are lots of question here concerning the same issues. Britta Schmidt from Autonomous, Antonio Ramirez from Keefe and Tania Gold from UniCredit, Daragh Quinn from Nomura, Rohith Chandra from Barclays, Carlos Peixoto from BPI, Juan Tuesta from Banesto, and they are all practically answering &#x2013; asking the same thing. If the ratio that's finally established for core Tier 1 is 9%, how can we expect to reach this ratio for 2012? What measures could you use to offset this potential capital deficit or shortfall? Are we thinking about increasing capital taking into consideration that the share price is below book value? Are we in negotiations with the Bank of Spain to correct our risk-weighted assets? Do we expect the convertibles to be included as capital to be counted as eligible? What do you think are capital requisites going to be estimated by the European Banking Authority for the BBVA Group? Are we thinking &#x2013; would there be any scenario where we would sell our Telef&#xF3;nica share or any other kind of portfolio management, what options do we have? And this is a summary of the six or seven people who've asked that information about our position on this issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right then. First of all, as you can imagine, we don't have any specific information right now. And we don't know when we will get that information from the EBA. So there is a lot of uncertainty &#x2013; the same uncertainty you've all got.</p>
          <p>So with this whole battery of questions, there are some important issues, however, that come up that we should be talking about. I wanted to remind you that when we did <mark type="ph" /> process (1:03:46) this in July using the data to December, we showed, if you remember, that we had a EBA capital ratio, I'll call it that, I don't know if it was &#x2013; Basel II would be 2.5%, but it was 8% this EBA ratio. And at that time, when we did the exercise, we said that it was because of our capacity to organically generate capital and we could expect a core capital of 9.2% by the end of 2012.</p>
          <p>You remember that we were ahead of the league table with our main peer group with respect to that ratio.</p>
          <p>In this quarter &#x2013; well, the whole year so far, we are talking about June 2011 based on data to December 2010. What's happened to that 8% figure? If I go back to what's happened during the year, it didn't take into account the investment in guarantee, as I explained at the time, or the conversions of our convertible bonds which we brought forward to July. And, obviously, it didn't take into account the capacity we have to organically generate capital over the nine months of the year.</p>
          <p>So if we take out the guarantee investment and we bring in the organic generation of capital and the conversion of bonds, once again, we're back at 8% core capital under the EBA requirements.</p>
          <p>From now on, what might happen? Well, probably this growth to 9%, which hasn't been confirmed, working with sovereign portfolios, we don't know what will happen there. That's the situation then. At the moment, there is not that much visibility on those matters. But what could happen? In all the scenarios, we've got measures that we can take which will be sufficient to give us some peace of mind on this matter. Obviously, we're going to be managing it very actively there because it's important.</p>
          <p>There are some other questions I wanted to deal with here. We're talking about generating capital over the next six, nine months to meet these requirements, which might come out &#x2013; might come out in June 2012, but we haven't got any definite information on that. So before we start divesting, we have our own capacity to organically generate capacity &#x2013; to generate capital. Without divesting, we still can generate capital in the final quarter of the year as well.</p>
          <p>Earlier on, I said that in the first quarters, we've been working to establish internal models. And there was a question about Bank of Spain and internal models and the negotiation. There is not so much negotiation. It's really just exchanging views, showing the papers about the models before we implement them. We've been working on this for several quarters now and said something that within the next nine months &#x2013; earlier probably, sooner rather than later, we can expect these internal models to come into operation.</p>
          <p>What expectations do we have regarding the use of internal models on the basis of normal organic capital generation over the next quarters? We can expect to see about &#x20AC;4.7 billion being generated in this way. So with all of these different factors coming into play, we would have a significant amount added in order to be able to meet any additional capital requirements without having to do anything else on the balance sheet because we are keeping our balance sheet pretty well intact. And here, optimizing the balance sheet will be one possibility, further deleverage of certain items which we consider to be less productive. Obviously, it depends on the final requirement level.</p>
          <p>We could think of off-loading some of the less profitable business lines or portfolios in order to deleverage, but mainly on the basis of the information we currently have, we think that this nearly &#x20AC;4.7 billion that we'll be generating, which is very much within our control because it only depends on us, will be sufficient to meet any possible increases in capital requirements which means that we won't probably have to turn to other measures, although the measures are there and they are available.</p>
          <p>The convertible bonds. In our case, we don't have convertible bonds because we already did early conversion <mark type="ph" /> last July (1:09:07). So this discussion which we've seen come out in press headlines over the last few days doesn't have anything to do with us specifically.</p>
          <p>I don't know Manuel if there is anything you wanted to add to all of this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, perhaps I could say that what we do know is that the exercise doesn't contemplate any kind of standardization of the risk-weighted asset metrics.</p>
          <p>So the requirement of this 9% core capital will have to do with the risk-weighted assets to total assets ratio in each entity and there we think it's important that the regulators recognize that the risk-weighted asset should be treated in the same way in different countries because otherwise they are not comparable and the differences in the density will be different. But they won't be shown in the stress testing and that undermines credibility simply because of different metrics used to measure risk-weighted assets in different European countries. And that is unfortunate.</p>
          <p>When we look at the recapitalization plan, it would be very positive if this issue was tackled now because I think it's a source of concern that we share with many supervisors and regulators throughout the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the US, Carlo Di Grandi from HSBC asks whether it &#x2013; well, he says our net attributable profit is pretty well flat in the US. Are we happy with that performance? What do we expect to see happening over the next few quarters after having got the change of mix on our loan book? When do we expect the US to reach cruising speed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said before, this flat growth in the United States is not caused by the BBVA Compass, the local operation, it comes from the market performance, the New York office where we &#x2013; which is the base for our wholesale business. And that's why I said that the growth in profits in the local franchise grew by almost 40% or around 40%. And there's one basic component here which was provisioning which have gradually declined, in line with increasing the quality of our assets.</p>
          <p>The other component that we're seeing in recent work is the stabling off of recurring revenues in the franchise. So what we're looking forward to in the coming quarters is to start to see slightly higher contributions than we've seen to date, so growth of around 40% in the underlying business, the purely local business. And this is what will enable us in the coming quarters to see substantial growth in 2012. This will certainly not be the kind of growth that we expect to see in the United States in a longer-term.</p>
          <p>This is just one of the milestones on the way, so what we expect to be saying in 2013, '14 and '15 with regard to the increasing weight that the US will have in their contribution to earnings. But what has been done is to recompose the quality of our assets on the balance sheet. And as I said in the presentation, also on the liability side, so that we can maybe present one of the best net interest income over average total assets you'll find anywhere in the United States. And I think this is the way that the underlying business is going to continue to go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to M&amp;A, we have three questions concerning Spain and our position in Turkey. Andrea Filtri from Mediobanca, her question is, when do we consider to complete our takeover or acquisition in Turkey? Or have we changed our plans there? Maybe you could give us an update of the situation in Turkey.</p>
          <p>David Vaamonde from Fidentiis asks for information about our assessment of the contribution of guarantee to the group. Is there any change in our consideration of the results coming in from Turkey?</p>
          <p>Daiwa Asset Management has a question about whether we have any plans here in Spain for taking over any banks here in Spain.</p>
          <p>And Luis Pe&#xF1;a from JB, his question is whether the BBVA has any interest in closing M&amp;A operations either here in Spain or beyond the borders of Spain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Starting with Turkey, first of all, there is no change in our strategy for Turkey. Maybe what's most relevant here is how the relationship stands with this new investment in Turkey, with this new bank in Turkey. And for us, it's a point of satisfaction that the group &#x2013; the Turkish group, the management team in guarantee has come on board with 140% integration there on the networks. We are working intensively with them in corporate transactions, working with SMEs and investment bank here as well. And we are pulling all our expertise. So it's a two-way flow, Spain-Turkey, Turkey-Mexico. There is an exchange of best practices across the board.</p>
          <p>I'd say it's even greater than what we could have expected. The cultural integration has gone really smoothly. This was one of the things that last year when we started with this transaction, it was something that, as you can imagine, we thought about. But actually, the cultural integration, I would say, has been the fastest such integration we've seen to date. It's been magnificent.</p>
          <p>So in terms of the way things are evolving, we will see important increase in the underlying business. And as to the results, if we take out the volatility of the net interest income from the bonds which are inflation-linked, but they're basically for hedging, the evolution of the net interest income, <mark type="ph" /> given we've got the (1:16:06) higher requirements as well to try to slowdown the heated growth of the economy in Turkey means that we have to have active management of these indicators.</p>
          <p>So if we compare as in terms of returns, cost/income ratio, we are seeing the guarantee is head and shoulders above its peers in Turkey in terms of its performance and we're expecting it to make a bigger and bigger contribution to the group earnings in general year-by-year .</p>
          <p>When we made the investment, we said that we'd be open to future opportunities. At present, we don't want to speed things up in the short-term. We are moving in gradually and we will have to see what happens to the markets there. And we consider at all times what will happen.</p>
          <p>What about the Spain? Well, here there is a market share, an important market share that will be consolidated over the next few years. I wouldn't say the next few months. I don't know if it will be 20%, 25%, but it will be a significant amount. I think this consolidation will probably occur over the next two, three years.</p>
          <p>With the consolidation taking place in a staggered basis that I think one of the biggest players in the Spanish market is the BBVA and therefore it would be natural to expect that we would take home a big market share. But what we're not going to do is to increase our exposure to Spain in the short-term. There is no reason to do so nor do we wish to have higher exposure to the liquidity situation here.</p>
          <p>So we think what's most important is to be able to organically generate greater market share, which is what we've been working on in the past and we'll continue to do so in the future. Obviously, we are a big player here and we're analyzing the opportunities that may arise, but always on the basis of a strict control over our capital consumption and our exposure to risk and the possibility of having tighter liquidity, if we get involved in any non-organic transactions.</p>
          <p>We think this is a matter of years. It will probably take two, three years anyway and we just have to see how things unfold. Our appetite to increase our market share in Spain continues, but we want to get organic growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then finally, four questions about different blocks that have &#x2013; some others have come in, but they've been answered. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:18:59) from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale asks about our plan for funding the group, given that since the summer our capacity to issue debt on the market has been limited.</p>
          <p>Then Neil Smith [WestLB] asks about our exposure to sovereign debt and he wants information about the exposure to September '11 to Spanish sovereign debt and to Italian sovereign debt.</p>
          <p>Santiago Lopez from Exane asks about the tax rate and asks if we are concerned because with this low rate, is it possible that taxes could be pushed up by the regulators.</p>
          <p>And then regarding asset quality, Antonio Ramirez from Keefe asks if we could explain the bank's strategy regarding its asset management for the bad book, will we be taking these off the balance sheet and would it be possible to set up a bad bank within the group?</p>
          <p>Before answering these questions, there are others that have come in, which will be answered by the investor relations team later today, but some of them have already been answered. For example, regarding the performance of GDP in Spain that was asked by Javier Bernat from <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:20:30) asks about the guidance for dividends over the next few years but that's also been answered. And what are &#x2013; the estimate is of the core capital using Basel 2.5 requirements and that's already been answered too.</p>
          <p>F&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric Teschner from Natixis asks about the core capital of BBVA under Basel 2.5. That's been discussed too. And regarding Mexico, there are questions about the potential difference between the customer spread in Mexico and South America and that's been answered by the COO and by the CFO.</p>
          <p>Anyway, all the questions that require further detail will be answered through the Investor Relations Department during the rest of today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe, Manuel, you would like to take the first two questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question was how we consider our funding plan for 2012? As we saw in the presentation, our wholesale redemptions are &#x20AC;11 billion and these are well distributed throughout the year without any special concentration and there are no important redemptions until the second quarter of 2012. So I think we're fairly comfortable if we bear in mind that just in the last year, from June last year to date, we've grown by &#x20AC;20 billion in customer funds in our Spanish business.</p>
          <p>At the same time, as &#xC1;ngel explained in the presentation, lending in this environment and what we're expecting for 2012, I don't think it's going to grow very much. There is not very high demand for lending. There is only &#x2013; there is very slight increase maybe. But the underlying balance in the euro balance, which is where we do have exposure, although it's a limited exposure to the capital market, but I think our capital requirements for wholesale funding are going to be less for 2012.</p>
          <p>Our business plan includes generating growth in the improvement of the balanced structure on this balance. This will be done on the balance sheet by the different areas which will exceed all the medium and long-term redemptions of capital for 2012. But in the worst possible scenario, if the markets are totally closed, which is something we're seeing since May 2011, we wouldn't face any kind of problem in operating normally. That's the plan that we are drawing up and this is the hypothesis that we're contemplating with all the budget revisions that we're doing with all the different business units.</p>
          <p>As you know, the credit conditions and funding conditions for all our franchises are excellent and <mark type="ph" /> liquidity (1:18:15) balance in Mexico, the United States and all our other Latin American franchises is very, very comfortable, and in some situations we are generating more credit than we need.</p>
          <p>With regard to our exposure to sovereign debt at September 2011 to the European economic area, which is what I imagine you'll be interested in, we have &#x20AC;16.3 billion and hold-to-maturity &#x20AC;9.9 billion. So we have &#x20AC;26.2 billion. Most &#x2013; our greatest exposure is to Spain because in Italy, available for sale and held-to-maturity is &#x20AC;2.5 billion at the moment.</p>
          <p>As for the variation in our portfolio over the quarter, basically it's remained stable throughout the quarter without any kind of change. But what I would like to highlight is that our exposure for available-to-sale and hold-to-maturity as far as terms go is excellent. The average duration of the portfolio is 2.8. And a large part of the portfolio, about two-thirds of the portfolio matures in less than three years. So irrespective of the size of the portfolio, the underlying risk to the market is relatively limited. So we don't &#x2013; we're not really exposed over in the long-term and I think this answers your question.</p>
          <p>And the final two questions, one was about the tax rate, whether we think there is going to be any increase in tax rates, quite honestly, I don't think there will be. I can't see any trend of moving in that direction at the moment here in Spain. So irrespective of the fall in the tax rate, there the tax burden is exactly the same, but we've seen a drop in profits here in Spain as we saw in the presentation. But in answer to your question from Santi Lopez, I think the answer is no.</p>
          <p>The other question with regard to bad asset management or creating a bad bank, we have no plans for creating a bad bank. The management of our less profitable assets here in Spain, which is where we find most of our less profitable assets, we have a department that manages this within the Spanish retail business, which monitors the real estate, the developer risk and they manage the real estate assets that are on the balance sheet. And as I said before, we're hiring new people to reinforce and accelerate that process of mobilizing and divesting these non-profitable assets. But we are not setting up any kind of special unit. But we think that we have the people to do this. And what we have to do is to do everything we can to accelerate the process of mobilizing these less profitable assets on the bank's balance sheet as we've been doing in the last few quarters.</p>
          <p>And with regard to the GDP here in Spain, our forecasts were between here to the end of the year in Spain will be a growth of somewhat under 1% and for 2012 we are talking about just over 1% growth, 1.2% maybe of GDP. But we need to bear in mind the current environment in all of this because if there is any change in the environment, this could obviously have either a negative or a positive effect on the growth in GDP as a consequence of the measures that we hope will be taken in Europe, maybe the economy could start picking up again in the next few quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, having answered the final question, it just remains to thank you all for attending over the webcast. And as I would say, any questions that have not been answered will be answered by the investor relations department. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>