<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1203064" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-10-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3180</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">&#xC1;ngel Cano, President and Chief Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Manuel Gonz&#xE1;lez, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Daragh Quinn</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Arturo de Frias</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Jerners Omahen</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Matteo Ramenghi</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone.  We are delighted to present the Third Quarter Earnings for the BBVA.  So, first of all &#xC1;ngel Cano, our President and COO will give you a general overview of the results for the Group.  And after that Manuel Gonz&#xE1;lez Cid, our CFO will go into more details about the main highlights of each business area. And then &#xC1;ngel Cano will wrap-up the presentation with some conclusions.</p>
          <p>And as of then we'll open the floor to a Q&amp;A session, like we always do.  First of all, as I say letting you ask your questions here in the room and after that we will take questions over the conference call.  Then finally, we will give a summary of the questions that come through our webcast.</p>
          <p>For those of you who come here today to sit in the room to hear our results, you can come and have coffee with us in the next door room afterwards. And I think without further ado I will give the floor to &#xC1;ngel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone.  Welcome to this presentation of the BBVA results for the third quarter. And as usual &#x2013; here we are; now we have done it.  I have found out how this works.  As you can see on the screen, we are going to start talking about the most significant highlights of the period. And the operating income has gone up 13.5% whilst attributable profit for the quarter was 1.380 billion and we'll see later how that compares against the same quarter of the previous year.</p>
          <p>And then in terms of our performance relative to our peers, our competitors, against which we benchmark for TSR, we've gained 250 basis points. And when I'm talking about the period, I'm talking about the first six months of the year during which we can compare ourselves with the published results of all our peers.  And then looking towards the future, what I want to highlight is a couple of concepts.  First of all, you know that in this period, we've sold-off various branches and some properties belonging to the Group and we've obtained some capital gains of &#x20AC;830 million.</p>
          <p>These capital gains have been fully put into higher generic provisioning and then looking at our core capital over the quarter, we've got an 8% core capital ratio.  And then finally in the same period, in the United States, we've added another entity to our franchise, because we bought Guaranty Bank in September in the end.</p>
          <p>So, now let's have a look at the income statement and the main ratios in the format that you can see on the screen.  First of all, we'll look at our earnings, then we'll look at the main data related to risk concepts and then we'll look at our capital strength and returns, and then as Carmen said at the end Manuel will be going over the main franchises within the Group.</p>
          <p>So we have reached an attributable profit of &#x20AC;4.3 billion (sic) &#x20AC;4.18 billion, which is a drop of 3.3% although in constant terms, would be going up 1.3%.  Consequently what you are seeing is 4 points of difference between the constant and the current rates.  In terms of the quarterly profit as we said before, we hit &#x20AC;1.33 billion, sorry, 1.38. And that compares very well against the previous quarter, although if you recognized that we have to include the dividend Telef&#xF3;nica, you can see that we'll be talking really about 1.2 in that quarter.  The earnings per share although the profits had gone down we see a drop of 3.3% there, but we could talk about the &#x20AC;1.12 per share.</p>
          <p>And now let's go down the different concepts in the income statement starting with net interest income.  As you can see, we had a figure of over 10 billion, going up nearly 20% year-on-year, once we are in constant terms, we can see these 4 points of difference which is impacted by the exchange rate.  And I'd like to say in general that although there has been a slowdown in business volume growth in most of the franchises over this period, but we're at the same in general is an increase or an improvement in the net interest income over average total assets in all the areas, in all the different lines.</p>
          <p>In terms of our gross income, there you can see, we are growing 6.6% in current terms, more or less 10% in constant euros and here what we should highlight is a couple of issues.  First of all last year, we got capital gains coming from the VISA IPO, which was more or less &#x20AC;235 million. And within this margin last year, we had Gamesa booked at 2.2 million and then there were some other items that added into 50 million and that's why we see that drop going down to 6.6% from the previous 20 something figure.</p>
          <p>If we compare ourselves against our peer group, starting in the first half of 2007 to have a three year series, we can see that our performance has been year-on-year growth and we can see what happened to our peer group and you can see who they are the 19 banks that we're comparing ourselves against in all the different countries; England, France, Germany, et cetera.</p>
          <p>And then operating costs; that's definitely a strong point for us.  Quarter-by-quarter, we have managed to bring down the total operating costs in the group and this quarter, we've had a drop of 2.4%.  As you can imagine, the cost/income ratio consequently you can &#x2013; remains below 40% because of the improvement in our operating costs, it's now at 39.7% or more important still that's nearly four percentage points improvement.</p>
          <p>As you can imagine, if we go over the operating costs in all the different areas, Spain and Portugal has managed really get &#x2013; good performance this year, 5.7% down. And if we're comparing against the quarter in the previous year when we are already beginning to see operating costs going down, but nonetheless, we are talking about these nine months where there's been significant drop.  Mexico has inflation of about 4.8, is flat in operating costs.</p>
          <p>Wholesale Banking &amp; Asset Management has gone down to below 5%.  The United States with the integration of all the different businesses nonetheless is seeing a drop of over 10% and South America with inflation of about 16% is still seeing its operating costs going up less than 10%.  So it's really a six percentage drop in real terms and actual terms.</p>
          <p>And looking at the operating income, you can see it has grown 13.5%, influenced by certain deals that we haven't had this year above all in net trading income and that would be 18% in constant terms consequently.</p>
          <p>And on the right, you can see the jaws in the period and how they've opened up both for this year and our reference point here is September 2007. As you can see here we've opened up 15 percentage points, the difference between the growth in income and the growth in costs.</p>
          <p>And this performance of 13.5% in operating income can be seen in all the different areas; Spain and Portugal growing 3.4%, Wholesale Banking &amp; Asset Management 12.6%, Mexico over 7%, the United States despite everything that's happening there 14% up and South America more than 31% up, once again beating quarterly records.</p>
          <p>Before in the first screen, I was talking about our performance taking into account the data to June and then comparing ourselves against the 19 banks that we use as our peers.  We had a 5.1% market share of operating income in June 2007 and now that's 7.6, that's up 250 basis points.</p>
          <p>On the right, you can see something very interesting, that 15.1 percentage point growth in the difference, but looking at the data of our peers, you have to include all the write-offs and such like.  So it's not that easy to compare, but what we do think is more indicative of what we are really doing is the share of operating income that we've gained over the year.  And that's shown in this screen and here we are still leaders in both efficiency and our cost/income ratio at 39.4%, two points better than the next bank and seven nearly for the other.  And so on average, there are improvements up to 15 or more percentage points over our peers.  So we're definitely at the head of this table and the same with respect to operating income over total assets.  We are also ranked number one.</p>
          <p>When we talk about risks, five points that I wanted to highlight.  First of all, what's happened with additions to NPA and what's happened to our coverage, taking into account the collateral we have as well.  Thirdly, what's happened to the cost of risk. And then what's happened with respect to property purchases; and then if we take into account the returns and the cost of risk, what time &#x2013; type of ratios do we get?</p>
          <p>I don't want to talk about a big drop in the new additions to NPAs, but they are definitely slowing down in net terms and stabilizing out in recoveries after a peak in the second quarter.  We've managed to maintain the level of recoveries that we are achieving with new additions to NPAs and more than 45% of the new additions to NPA are recovered within the same period.</p>
          <p>In terms of provision and coverage, earlier on I was saying at the beginning of the presentation that we've attained 830 million in capital gains because of selling off properties and we've put that fully into endowing our generic provisions.  If we add up all the generic provisions that we've got in the group plus the substandard provisions that are for more specific things, we've got over 4.65 billion euros in total provisioning.</p>
          <p>And then let's see what our provisions look like, taking into account collateral as well.  First of all, on the left, you can see the comparison between those doubtful loans that are secured with tangible assets, that's more than 12.6 billion which gives us a coverage of 190%.</p>
          <p>Then on the right, you can see the loans that aren't secured.  And that will be 5.8 billion for which we have more or less 8.45 billion in total provisions, adding together we get that figure that you can see in the protocols of 12.6 billion &#x2013; million and we were talking about additions into NPAs and saying that they were stable and on the way down, on the cost of risk meanwhile is stable, and what is happening to the NPA ratio in the group as you can see is going down and has been over the last three quarters.</p>
          <p>In the last quarter of last year and the first quarter of this year, we were growing about 55 basis points, but now that's gone down to 25 basis points getting to an NPA ratio for the group of 3.4%.  The cost of risk is stable then slightly above 1%.</p>
          <p>What about our property purchases then?  In principle you'd say that our performance is better than we were expecting at the beginning of the year.  So far this year, we've incorporated on to our portfolio an extra 772 million and above all in land and residential housing &#x2013; finished housing.</p>
          <p>And then in the quarter, we can see that we've only incorporated just over 100 million euros on to our property portfolio.  If we look at the total stock of properties, which would give us a coverage of 23%, that means we've got over a billion euros accumulated this year in stock.</p>
          <p>And to finish with risk-related matters, I wanted to show you what kind of adjusted risk/return ratio we've got discounting the credit risk.  If we compare ourselves against the first half data of our peer group; in the first nine months, we've reached 1.8% and once again we are far away from the average and far away from the median.  We've really outperformed our peers here.</p>
          <p>And then before I give the floor to Manuel to talk about the different business areas, what does our complete income statement look like from top to bottom?  Our net interest income is growing nearly 20% as I said at the beginning of the presentation. Our gross income because of certain transactions that weren't repeated this year, Gamesa, the VISA IPO et cetera is being growing 6.6% operating income after the drop of 2.4% in costs has grown 13.5%.</p>
          <p>If we take out the provisioning for the period, we'd be growing in attributable profit, actually it will go down 3.3% taking into account the last year when we are talking about one-offs, we were talking about 180 million net taking into account the Bradesco transaction in the early retirement provisioning that we had to do.</p>
          <p>In terms of our core capital, I said at the beginning that we had reached 8%.  It will be 8.04% if we are going to be very precise.  This 8% has been maintained, 1.1% of it came from organic generation of core capital of which just in the third quarter we've got a further billion added to our core capital in absolute terms.  And apart from that we've got the convertible bonds operation we did which is 70 basis points added to that.  The Tier 1 is down 9.4% and our total capital ratio stands at 13.4%.</p>
          <p>In terms of returns then in June, once again we are at the top of the ranking tables whether we are looking at return on equity or tangible assets we compare very well against our peers even though we are looking at the average or at the median.  And to September, we would have an ROE which is very similar to what we had in June 21.2% or an ROTE close to 30%.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share that drop of 3.3%, we saw earlier on in attributable profit.  If we look to the series and compared ourselves against what our peers are doing once again base 100 is in 2006 and we're growing 9% over this period of time whilst the others, our peers have 31% less than they had in 2006 as what the median would have and on average that would be 20.  And so definitely our earnings per share has been growing constantly, we could say over this time.  And I think Manuel I can give you the floor and you can talk about the different business areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Buenos &#x2013; good morning everybody.  I will go over as &#xC1;ngel said the performance of the different business areas in the Group and I will start up by saying that in this quarter we've strengthened the different franchises that the Group has and we'll start with Spain and Portugal as usual.</p>
          <p>In Spain and Portugal, there are several keys to our success this quarter that's important to bear in our mind.  First of all, the performance of the net trading income which in a weak environment, this has grown by 13.1% and basically this is due to two factors. One of them is the improvement in the spreads.  You can see this on the right at the top, that you have some of the data there with &#x2013; from the different divisions within Spain and Portugal and we can see how there is an improvement in the spreads which is a marked improvement and this is happening in new operations which is what we can see on the slide, but it's also happening in our balance stock.  And on the other hand, on the recently on the balance sheet, resources, we have a clear strategy consisting first of all of not migrating from funds to deposits and we're being extremely cautious with the cost of liabilities, especially term liabilities and finally we are focusing on growing our liquid resources and the ones with lower cost.</p>
          <p>And in fact this year have increased by five percentage points in the division of Spain and Portugal. So we've adjusted our prices and we are ahead of our rivals.  At the same time as &#xC1;ngel said before, we are also controlling our cost as &#xC1;ngel said. This has been going on for some time now and at the moment even if we compare ourselves with a period when we started to cut costs, we are seeing falls, in cost in Spain, in cost of around 6%.  And quite honestly, you will be hard pressed to find this with any of our peers here in Spain and this has generated growth in our operating income of 3.4% with one additional element which I think is extremely important and that is the stabilization of the net interest into NPA.  There has been a fall in 2% in the gross entries in NPA.  There is a slight fall as you can see, but from &#x2013; but the rate, the levels are still higher than for the first quarter of this and &#x2013; last year, but bear in mind the third quarter, because of the seasonality of August in Spain, is always a poor quarter in terms of recoveries and entries in NPA.  So, these results are very satisfactory if we bear in mind what happens, what &#x2013; and what is traditionally a bad quarter for us.</p>
          <p>So NPAs are stabling off as we have announced, everything is performing more or less as we said and recoveries are improving from what &#x2013; the figures we've seen in previous quarters and this means that at the moment if we measure our NPA ratio with our peer groups and look at the policies of buying properties and <mark type="inaudible" /> enough.  I think it's important to have a broad definition of the NPA ratio.</p>
          <p>So if we use the broad term so, if we have NPA plus the property purchases with the information that we have at the moment, the bank has the best risk quality that you'll find anywhere in Spain at the moment.  And we're ahead of our nearest competitor in &#x2013; by 80 basis points of where in June, which is the latest figures that we have, that is if we use this broader definition of the NPA, which I really think gives you a better idea of the quality of the risk in the sector.  And as a consequence of all of this, and I don't think this is a minor issue at all, the bank at the moment, on the six main rivals here in Spain &#x2013; I'm not talking about the entire industry, I am just talking about the six Spanish leading financial institutes; we have a market share in recurring operating income after provisioning, which is a good measure of looking at our results of 43.5%.</p>
          <p>This is very important with regard to how the trend, because if you look at a year ago we were 20 percentage points lower and in &#x2013; but over the last year we have generated this 20 point advantage and this means that things are going as expected, i.e. that the bank in comparison with its peers, the bank has a fantastic opportunity and we've seized this opportunity.</p>
          <p>Moving on now, you have all the accounts here.  So moving on to Wholesale Banking &amp; Asset Management, the first thing I would like to mention here and here I'm going to focus my presentation only on the banking side of this business in Corporate &amp; Investment Banking.  I think the results are quite enlightening.  You can see the two or three striking issues which is the management effort that's been made in this area.  First of all, the improvement in the margins over gross income which have increased substantially throughout 2009 and this is true also for the third quarter we're at the same level of the gross income of 243 over the average portfolio, which is a very high percentage if we bear in mind that at the end of the year it was 174 and this shows you the re-pricing effort and cross-selling effort that we're doing on our customer base and the area of Corporate &amp; Investment Banking and the management effort that was being made to improve our business margins.</p>
          <p>By the same token, if we look at the income side, this means we are growing 24% in income, in commissions by 53% which shows how the business is changing in this area, where the fees or other income now represent 41% of all revenues, i.e. 6 percentage points more than it was a year ago.  And this is given our tight cost structure wherein another effort is being made and this means that the operating profit for Corporate &amp; Investment Banking is growing by &#x2013; their operating income is growing by over 29%.</p>
          <p>Moving on now to Global Markets, we've got an operating income that's growing by 13.9% and over last year, and last year was a good year.  So we are growing &#x2013; we got double-digit growth in comparison with a good year and the reason for this is a growth in our revenues in geographic areas where traditionally the bank had a very little presence or didn't generate any revenues.  And at the moment, if we look at the growth in revenues from Global Markets outside of Spain, in Europe and Asia, we are talking about growth of 70% which accounts for 30% of the total revenues in Europe and Asia including Spain and approximately 15% of the total revenue for this area including America.  So we can see how Wholesale Banking is penetrating in other territories.  It's moving out of its traditional core interest.</p>
          <p>And finally on the Asset Management side as we can see here, we are maintaining the leadership in the sector here in Spain with a market share of practically 20 percentage points which has improved continuously since the crisis began due to our strategies and management policy that hasn't changed because there is no policy of migration to deposits from funds, and we have maintained recurrent management of our customer bases.  So it's been an excellent result and excellent results from the Wholesale Banking and Asset Management.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Mexico now, I think this slide clearly shows what the year has been and the last quarter in Mexico, i.e., in a scenario of maximum stress with a lot of complications, with falls in GDP year-to-date of around 7%, and with a profound change in our portfolio mix that has been going on for some time, but just this year, has led to a fall in consumers four percentage points and also in credit cards within the full lending side in Mexico.  So these are the results with an operating income without bearing in mind the one-offs of their Visa IPO of last year which is of 11% and costs which shows we can further reduce costs, as you can see, costs are flat and we're around zero and at the same time there is an improvement in our market share recurrent operating income by almost six percentage points just last year in comparison with our main peers in Mexico.</p>
          <p>And another piece of good news that's important for us, especially looking forward and that is the stabilizing of provisioning, quarterly provisioning in Mexico, which is a sign that we are coming out of the worst part of the crisis in Mexico and this highlights that the franchise that we have in Mexico that has capacity for generating recurrent incomes even in very complex situations as you have seen in Mexico recently, and the reasons for this performance can be seen on this slide with a portfolio that has suffered a 14% drop in consumer finance and credit cards but has grown 11% in mortgages or 5% in SMEs and corporate banking et cetera, they've all grown, and also a major effort has been made to improve the spreads with strong growth in customer deposits.</p>
          <p>And even on the site &#x2013; and savings accounts there were reduced costs by 18% and term deposits as in Group by 9.4 despite the low market share that we have in mix.  And this means that the operating income has grown by 7.1% if we exclude the one-offs of the Visa IPO then this growth would be up to 11%.</p>
          <p>As I said at the beginning with regard to Mexico, the NPO provisionings, there's &#x2013; I've some good news for you as well.  The bank is not just maintaining a far lower cost of risk than our peers because of the different provisioning strategies and the sustained growth that we have shown, but also at the time the provisioning has been stabling off, and we're talking about an average of 360 million and there is &#x2013; we've got 364 this year in comparison with 373 euros in the last quarter.  So and this is a clear sign that we are over the worst in provisioning.  So, we can now look forward to a scenario significant change in the way the economy performs.</p>
          <p>As a consequence of all of this, we can see &#x2013; as we can see in the throughout the Group, but especially in risk, the growth in NPA ratios are slowing down.  It slid 11 basis points just this quarter and I think what is more important than this and that we have two quarters, we didn't say anything in the second quarter; we're announcing this now, but for two quarters there's been a reduction in the fall of NPA ratio in consumer finance and credit cards and this has been the main driver of the basic explanation of this improvement or stabilization of the NPA ratio.  So I think the results are excellent in Mexico in the context and very positive signs looking forward.</p>
          <p>And as we said here in Spain this means that we &#x2013; 50% of our recurring income in the five leading banks in the country and this has been systematically increased throughout the crisis.  So this also shows the strength of Bancomer in the Mexican market and this is translating into the fact that we are harnessing this opportunity and generating income for us.</p>
          <p>Move on now to the United States where it's been a very good quarter with some landmarks, basically the main one is taking over Guaranty that we haven't had the chance to talk to you about in detail, although you do have all the information.  What I would like to highlight here is that our purchase of Guaranty is another sign of our progressive and focused strategy of penetrating a series of markets that we consider to be critical and strategic for our future in the U.S.  And now we have a franchise with a critical mass in an area of the United States that is even greater than the economy of France for instance, just to give you an idea, and with a critical mass, which means that we can generate synergies and we are more competitive in the local market in an area where from the point of your population growth and the prospects of future economic development is going to be highly strategic for us.</p>
          <p>I just remind you that just talking about Texas alone, this is the leading export state in the U.S. through which 50% of all the U.S. exports come out of Texas.  So as I was saying one of the landmarks of this quarter has been our purchase of Guaranty.  As you know the major figures you can see here on the screen, we're talking about a bank with 10 billion in loans, 1,700 employees, 164 branches, and maybe I could just highlight the fact that this is one of the largest purchases that we've done first assisted by the FDIC and the first one that's been assisted by the FDIC in collaboration with a foreign bank which shows that BBVA is gradually building its franchise to compete with the American banks and we can compete with them and we've shown ourselves that we are at the top end of the management table.</p>
          <p>From the point of view of results in the current environment in the U.S., one important point here and that is the possibility of generating cost synergies and cost saving synergies and a chance to reduce the cost of risk in the future, in the current market context, I think these results clearly show that Compass is very, as our COO said, they are rapidly integrating with all the banks that we have in the region and looking forward, we have the Guaranty project which we hope to bring on board very quickly.  And this will reduce costs by 10% and basically this will drive results far better than our peers can. And this will enable us to add to the growth of revenues and the management of the margins which will show as a growth in our operating income of nearly 14%, which puts us at the top of the table.  Guaranty is contributing &#x20AC;7 million to the operating income.</p>
          <p>We only have &#x2013; we've only been working with them for one month, so they're still being integrated.  So these figures haven't really been affected by Guaranty yet.  We will see that later on in the future, but this will grow &#x2013; so all of this growth in the net operating income comes without Guaranty. Also the United States, in the case of Compass, we're seeing a stabilization of entries into NPA and with recovery levels that are around 50% which is very high.  This has also been pushed up.  We have seen this throughout the Group. It's also shown here in this area of the United States, the efforts they are making within the economic context.  So if we're efficient in recoveries in this context this is vital to us.</p>
          <p>And basically our recovery rates are very, very high and the net entries to NPAs in comparison are very stable.  And superior performance, we're outperforming our peers. The net interest income that Compass is earning is 3.68% if we compare that with the peer group which we can see this at the bottom of the slide of 3.21 on average and this efficiency is improving, it is now 58.9% is the long way from the cost efficiency ratio that we have for the whole group.  But if we compare them with other U.S. banks, then it is good and with the net operating income that are generally uniform and in line with the industry. But if we just talk about Compass, we are talking about a growth of 21% when the average for the Group is either flat or there is a slight fall of about 1%.  So the management over there is starting to show how we are outperforming our peers as we see in other geographic areas.</p>
          <p>And finally on this, I will close with this, before &#xC1;ngel concludes the presentation, I would just like to mention South America.  And I think that this is an area that deserves growing attention.  These are the results of the growth we are seeing in South America for the year as a whole.  We are growing, the gross income of 23% and the net operating income 32%, and the attributable profit of 27% growth.</p>
          <p>So these growth rates are really remarkable.  This is real growth in the context of a crisis.  But we are not just getting these growth rates, but if we look at the trends where these growth rates are taking off, they are accelerating.  We are showing almost 10 points more of growth in operating income in comparison with 2007.  So we are talking about historic growth rates which shows the capacity of our growth and the value of our Latin American franchise. And with significant advances in the area of efficiency, we are below 40% which is something we've never managed before in South America and efficiency levels are very close in line with the Group as a whole and the cost of risk we can see on the right which is very stable with no major increase in NPAs to really point out.</p>
          <p>All of this is happening with these excellent results and excellent growth.  All of this is happening not just in the area of our banks in the region, but also as in pension and insurance. If we look on the right here, we'll see how pensions and insurance in South America is doubling the results in comparison with last year to this date, which is another sign of growth.  And obviously this area is generating excellent results.</p>
          <p>So in short, we like to talk about South America as a second Bancomer, if you like, because the market considers us with a presence &#x2013; a very strong presence in Spain and in Mexico, but they don't pay too much attention to the wholesale franchise that I've just shown you with such impressive results and they pay very little results to a franchise in Latin America.  But in terms of size is almost the same size as Mexico. You can see the figures here which speak for themselves in terms of assets and customer loans, deposits and also in terms of profit before minorities.  And obviously South America is very similar and uniform and very similar in size and in terms of generating revenues as Mexico's.</p>
          <p>I think we've gone over the main business areas and I can show you the results for this quarter are very good, very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Manuel.  So to wrap up, it's lovely to be able to present these kinds of numbers in these presentations because in all the lines on the income statement, on all the lines returns on capital, everything else, we compare very favorably against our peers with this group of 19 banks worldwide.  If we look at the numbers, 4.5 in attributable earnings or minus 3.3% compared against last year, which in constant terms should be 1.3% positive growth.</p>
          <p>For the quarter, we've got a result of 1.3 billion comparing very well against last year in the same quarter.  If we take out the Telef&#xF3;nica dividends as I said before, we'd be going up about 10% earnings per share of more or less at the same levels as in 2008 operating income growing 13.5% across the board throughout all the business areas in the Group.  The cost of risk is stable as well.  NPA ratio is doing very well and not growing as fast as it has been over the last few quarters.</p>
          <p>And then if we look at each of the business areas as you saw, in all cases we are beating our own records in operating income everywhere. And in terms of our fundamentals, our returns, our capital ratios, we've hit 8% in this period in core capital, generating 110 basis points of this capital through organic growth over the last nine months.  It's very clear.  Any capital gains that come in are put into increasing our generic provisions for the group and with these kinds of numbers as you could imagine we are in the leadership position in terms of our cost/income ratio and our returns and profitability.</p>
          <p>So, thank you. Now Manuel and I will be delighted to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] . [Operator Instructions].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm Daragh Quinn from Nomura. I have got several questions. The first has to do with your strategy or potential strategy for M&amp;As. I think you are talking about more ambitious stage now, that's what you talked about at the press conference when you changed your senior management. So what kind of changes can we expect in your strategy? Should we expect changes with respect to your size or with respect to your geographical focus? And then about your core capital, I can understand that you are comfortable with the core capital ratio of 8%, should we expect that this year there will be an increase in your pay-out of dividends or will that happen next year? And the third question has to do with costs. I think there is a reduction of 2.5% over the first nine months, is there any further potential for more improvement there? And then I would like more color on recoveries. Is there a level of breaking down the restructuring of loans which have come out of NPAs or what percentage of your recoveries are restructured NPAs? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will answer the first three questions, and then Manuel will take the fourth question. With regard to strategy, we are not going to change the strategy that we've been using to-date. Our focus is clearly what we've just said on the United States. As you know, we are paying close attention to the transactions or the operations that can come out of the FDIC. We are integrating Guaranty which should take us through to February when it should be fully integrated and from there on we should be generating the synergies that we think that we will be able to generate. And I would say that we are not going to make any change in strategy from the point of view of growth. Maybe our ambition now would to speed up the organic and internal management for the strategy that we're currently using, but in each business area, we want the group to support this as much as possible, so that the area will be &#x2013; each business area has more independence obviously with a greater supervision from the head office. So as you can see there is basically no special change or there shouldn't be any special change in strategy.</p>
          <p>You talked about 8% core capital; obviously with this capital ratio we do feel very comfortable. People would love to have 8% core capital. But from the point of view of dividends, we did announce a 30% pay-out, but just in cash, and not many banks can make a pay-out that way on the international market. And then still about next spring and we start talking about the 2010 dividend, we're not going to make any change in our dividend policy.</p>
          <p>Costs you said with a drop in 2.4% in this period, whether this is going to be &#x2013; go even further, I'd say we've got to go as further as we can. We do think we can cut costs further. But as we have to-date, we need to separate the everyday operation of the bank where we think there is still more room for cutting costs. We need to separate that from the transformation of the bank where we need to invest in projects of growth and technology and things, but we need to prioritize what we spend our money on. We've focused on reducing costs in the business as usual on the operating side, but we do think there is room for maneuver, but by &#x2013; above all by continuing to invest in new projects. And questions related to the transformation of the group as a whole, Manuel would like to take the fourth question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In answer to your final question as I said the group does not have a policy of using refinancings or restructuring as a mechanism for reducing NPAs. So there is no kind of recovery that is associated with restructuring or refinancing NPAs. I think that's the first important point. The second point that I would like to make, 76% of all our recoveries in Spain are associated with cash, they are cash recoveries, and I think this is another important point, because obviously if you're going to restructure recoveries, this is totally irrelevant. So the 20 &#x2013; the other 23% are either we buy &#x2013; we purchase assets or the adjudication of &#x2013; or legal adjudication of assets, but 77% of these recoveries are cash recoveries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Further questions from the floor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I'd be delighted with the standardized cost of risks, i.e., excluding the one-off provisions of 1.14% that we saw in the third quarter. Can we extrapolate this, what can we expect from 2010, and also could you tell us something about the trends of generics and when do you expect this to run out and what kind of cost of risks are we facing for next year? On the other hand the different &#x2013; the spread of customers in euros has increased, the residential sector, there is a strong fall compared with the last quarter. So maybe you could tell us a little bit about your forecasts for the years to come? With regard to the Compass' NPA ratio, if we take Guaranty out of the equation, what would it be at the 30th of September? Those are all my questions. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'll answer the first question. And then Manuel can deal with the other two. The stable cost of risk which we've seen over the last few quarters is related to what's been happening with gross additions to NPAs in the group. So for the last two quarters we've been stable at about 1.4. And our forecast is that they should remain pretty well flat. We haven't got any more information right now, nothing that would lead us to think either that who go up or go down very much, but we prefer to look at things quarter-by-quarter and we're glad to see this ongoing stability.</p>
          <p>And then in terms of generic provisioning, you ask when we think this will come to an end. Well, once again we don't have any different information that would lead us to think that we won't get to 11. Our latest estimate is that at the end of 2010 we should continue with these kinds of improvements going on to 2011 which means that our generic provisioning will definitely not be used up in 2010. And so that's what we can see at the moment. And then the difference in euros...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, microphone? In terms of customer spread in euros as is explained on page nine in your document, you can see there's a reduction in our return on investment of 73 basis points and a reduction in the cost of liabilities of 37 basis points. So what's going on there is basically the re-pricing of our mortgage book at lower rates which has an impact of the returns on our assets which goes down and it can go down faster than what we could generate at the current customer funds rates that we have. But as you know, the margins that we get on our lending books in different parts of the group in Spain and elsewhere, there we are getting a lot of re-pricing which means that this effect of the reduction of our customer spreads is closely linked to the re-pricing of our mortgage book without narrowing customer spreads at all, quietly opposite in fact. What's happening is that over average total assets, it's been maintained stable in all the domestic units and in the wholesale part of our business it's even going up in terms of what it is over the average total assets.</p>
          <p>And in the NPA ratio in Compass without Guaranty I can't bring the figure to mind, but I know that it's slightly higher than last quarter. It's going down in the U.S. because of Guaranty coming in with its loan books and with no kinds of bad loans, but without it, it would be slightly higher than it was last quarter for the group as a whole. I think it's 3.9 in Compass for the period. And as Manuel said it's slightly higher than the previous quarter, if that's the right figure. But we can give you the exact figure later if you want.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more questions here in the room? <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We have a question from Arturo de Frias from Evolution. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wanted to ask you various question. Two of them had to do with Spain. Irma has just asked something similar. But I want to come back to the whole issue looking forward to 2010. Looking at the total financial margin over average total assets, I'm doing a calculation which is very approximate, but it's gone down slightly over the quarter, two basis points I think it is.</p>
          <p>And this is pretty similar to what's happening in other Spanish banks. And many of them are saying that 2010 is going to be a difficult year, more difficult even than this year because this year you've got the advantage of the re-pricing on your mortgage book and such like. And how do you see what's going to happen to net interest income in the Spain? Do you think that it could flatten out and stabilize given the cost of deposits or do you think it would drop off as it's happening with other banks?</p>
          <p>And then my second question, which has to do with the market share in Spain, I think it's pretty obvious that a lot of your peers are going to disappear very soon or at least there won't be as many in number. And that could open up some important opportunities for you. I don't think that at any time you're thinking of buying up networks of savings banks in Spain. But I do wonder whether it'd be possible for you to increase your competitive edge or gain market share taking advantage of the weakness of your peers. Is that the case? Are you thinking of growing substantially above the sector average in terms of lending during 2010? So that's my second question.</p>
          <p>And then the third question I have is related to China. I'm quite surprised that you haven't mentioned China at all throughout your presentation. And there you've invested a quite respectable sum already. So I'd like to know what your vision of the area is. How does China fit in with your strategy? Personally, I've never seen a very clear cut fit of China within your business mix. But I'd like you to talk a little bit about that and give me some color on the situation at present and how it does fit into your strategy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Arturo. Manuel, maybe you could start?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'll start. Good morning, Arturo. From regard to the trading income, net interest income in 2010, we are just finishing off our budget. And as you know we do this every three years. So we're looking at 2010, 2011, 2012, and our forecast for that.</p>
          <p>With regard to 2010 and we haven't finished this. In a few weeks, we should have a better idea about this. But the impression we get at the moment is quite a positive one. We think that we can protect our net interest income in 2010 in Spain for several different reasons.</p>
          <p>We believe that there will be a progressive improvement or less impairment in business as we move forward with regard to the loan side of the business. We think that we'll be able to attract more customer business from the market without using any specially aggressive pricing strategies. And I'm sure that there is going to be a price war with our peers.</p>
          <p>And we've seen that the re-pricing in the mortgage book has stabilized through the first and second quarter and then the third quarter of 2012, which is very important to us, the short part of the curve, which maintains major spreads. And at the moment, we have coverage to guarantee these spreads with a view to 2010.</p>
          <p>And also if there is any spike in the interest rates, the strain &#x2013; the growth in site deposits should give us the chance to improve our net interest income. So for all these reasons, we believe that we can stabilize the domestic part of our net interest income in 2010.</p>
          <p>Okay, Arturo, the second question you asked about what we are going to do in the future bearing in mind the market in Spain and the situation of the banks and savings banks. As always, we are going to try and grow organically as much as possible to attract new customers. And we are going to do this here in Spain the way we always have.</p>
          <p>Maybe we might focus even more, but as you said we are not really focused on buying networks of branches. And certainly at the seven territories that we have in Spain we certainly keep a close eye on the way they generate new customers. It's as simple as that. Our hopes are pinned on that. And we think that we can clearly gain market share in 2010 and moving forward.</p>
          <p>You also mentioned China. I was asked whether I was going to change the strategy or the size of our investments in China. China for us from a strategic point of view and in the long-term &#x2013; and this is something we've always said. We've always stressed the long-term aspect. We think that this is where there are going to be fantastic opportunities for growth in the coming years.</p>
          <p>This is in the long-term, but in the way &#x2013; along the way, we have forged two allies with CITIC, our Chinese ally and now we are working on a plan to continue actively growing on the wholesale side. We've got good markets from global markets and our objective here and that is to drive greater growth in the wholesale side.</p>
          <p>Just to give you an understanding of our group's strategy, don't forget that one of the reasons that South America is so healthy is because of its close ties with Asia. So we are getting the indirect impact of it. So we got two focuses, the indirect one through South America and then the direct one because of plans we have for more organic than inorganic growth in China and to forge new alliances that will be of interest to all the parties concerned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One question, coming back on what you just said, and another one that I forget about. When do you think that China will become a material part of your results? Are we talking about 2012, 2015? When do you think China is going to make an impact on your bottom line? And the question that I forgot. Do you have any facts and figures, any statistics that you could share with us on how the credits in Spain with developers, retail or mortgage that have been refinanced in recent quarters? Are you seeing a growth in NPA ratio? Do you have any figures to give us an idea that refinancing is successful? Could you answer &#x2013; come back to us on this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't refer to a crystal ball, but maybe I won't, Arturo, Asia, well China. When we're expecting &#x2013; that we say long-term, what is long-term? But it's longer than three years, we have to go step by step, though. I'd say that incorporating results as of this year more than next year and more than &#x2013; still the following year. But as for when it's going to be a relevant chunk of our earnings, I think it's too early to say right now.</p>
          <p>And then the question about restructuring, you should take into account that we're talking about all the restructuring which is done which has been very recent, it's very new. So obviously right now, we can only say that normal. When we talk about refinancing or restructuring, we have to look at what underlies all of this, the fundamentals behind the company that we are refinancing.</p>
          <p>So if we were to think that we're talking about companies that have a tricky financial situation, then maybe with them we'd have a different kind of agreement. But under this item there are no negative data. And I think that what really matters is to re-negotiate with companies that have sound fundamentals in the long term at least.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much, Arturo. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's go on with more questions and across the conference call. There are no more questions from the conference call in the Spanish. Our first question comes from Mr. Jerners Omahen [Goldman Sachs]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi there. It's Jerners here from Goldman Sachs. Can you hear me? I hope you can. Anyway, so I have four questions. The first one is on page 25 of your presentation where I think you very nicely show that there was 110 basis points of organic capital generation during the first nine months of the year. I was just wondering, given the convertible &#x2013; the 2 billion of converts increased the core Tier 1 ratio by 70 basis points. Why did BBVA feel the necessity to actually issue these converts? Why not wait for two or three quarters and actually get there organically? So I would just like to understand that better? That's question one. The question number two is on page 20 of the presentation when you very clearly show the volume of property purchases. And I would just like to understand what proportion of the property purchases and as well of the stock is in land and what proportion is in completed buildings? And I think the last question I have is on the gross additions to non-performing loans. They stood at roughly 3.6 billion in the third quarter, and I think that's more or less unchanged on the first and the second quarter. And I wonder whether you would agree that this number should be looked at as a fair forward-looking indicator as to where credit quality is currently going or whether you think that is not the case? That's all. And maybe the fourth question, if you have a chance I was just looking at the net interest income from Corporate Activities and I think it's down from &#x20AC;190 million in Q2 to 110 in Q3. I'm assuming that's the impact of the deposit hedge. And if you were able to highlight if that indeed is the case and secondly where you think the progression of this line is going to be over the next quarters? That's all from my side. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Manuel is going to answer you the first and the fourth question and I will do the second and the third.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to your first question, looking at the convertibles we issued, why? Well obviously, we decided to make this issue of convertibles, given the flexibility that we can get from that. First of all, we've got a convertible bond that for our customers who have taken up this product is a very positive product, because it minimizes the price risks associated to the distribution of a product of this kind throughout our retail customer base. So we think that it's a very attractive product for our customers. And in fact the placement has been a tremendous success.</p>
          <p>We could have placed substantially more bonds than we finally did. In fact, we went to the maximum that we had expected to manage to place. And in terms of the way the banks use it, well it gives us enormous flexibility in the way we manage our capital. Because what we are doing is to generate capital very fast, so that we boost our capital ratio to fantastic levels, whoever you compare us against internationally, without generating any dilution for our shareholders. And we also have the option up to a year in all the following four years to convert the capital into ordinary stock at any time at the discretion of the Bank itself.</p>
          <p>So right now, BBVA has &#x20AC;2 billion out there available if it's necessary to use them to boost our core capital at any time. And so from now, there is already capital for us, but we're not generating any dilution for our shareholders. So that's the logic behind this issue of convertible bonds in a context in which the whole issue of capital, I think you'd all agree is probably the thing that people are talking about most when they talk about banks. And at the moment, we're going through a process of seeing how regulations are being developed. We don't know what the regulations are going to look like in the end. All we know is that there will be higher capital requirement and we know that with our retail basis, we're going to be much more impacted than others with the tougher standards that we will have.</p>
          <p>So what we are doing is anticipating what the standards might be when we know that the capital requirements will be really tough. And then at the same time, as &#xC1;ngel said before, we are paying out cash dividends. Which means that the return to our shareholders is pretty reasonable compared to any comparative metrics you might wish to use. We are shoring up our capital ratios, and alongside that, we're still paying out an attractive dividend to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>So we're very proud of our capital management throughout this crisis. We're the only bank worldwide that hasn't had to increase its capital or accept any aid from the public sector during this time. And I think that really shows just how strong the Group's balance sheet is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then the second question I think was about the type of properties that we are bringing on to our books in Spain. I don't know if I'm right, but I think about 80% is land, did I say that in the presentation? 80% is land. And then of the rest, about 15% is finished housing. So there's just 5% outstanding that isn't finished.</p>
          <p>So we are talking about properties that can be managed for sale, either land or buildings. And I think you are asking as well about the NPA ratio, what we're expecting to happen to it over the next few quarters. And there I'd say well there was a screen showing the reduction of the growth in the NPA ratio over the last few quarters. We were reducing the rate with growth of only 25 basis points, whereas before it was 55 at the end of last year or beginning of this year.</p>
          <p>So we're seeing growth is flattening out and stabilization is really what we're seeing, in fact going down sometimes. And there was another transparency showing Spain and Portugal. And Manuel was talking about this, where we saw the difference compared to the next competitor, more than 80 basis points, if we looked at the incorporation of the properties we bought.</p>
          <p>From here over the next few quarters we can expect to maintain that kind of advantage that we have over our competitors in general.  And I can try to give you a number but it will depend on the macroeconomic scenario in all the different countries.  But I think we could be talking about cost of risk being stable, new additions pretty well stable, and NPA continuing to outperform our peers.</p>
          <p>Coming back to your list of questions, I want to deal with your last one about the net interest income, the difference between the third and the second quarter.  As you can see in the third quarter, quarter-on-quarter at Group level there is a reduction of 150 million. 73 million is just because of the exchange rate.  So the reduction in real terms, in actual terms will be 79 million and that reduction is totally associated to the updating of the type of assets we have on our mortgage books in Spain, the process of re-pricing of our mortgage book which is generating this reduction in the net interest income. So it's focused on Corporate Activities which is where we have the interest risk rate on our euro balance sheet booked and so that stabilization is there with figure which is dropping off at very similar levels to the exchange rate.</p>
          <p>Sir, shall we go on with the next question or was there was another question in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Matteo Ramenghi from UBS.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Good morning to everyone.  I have three quick questions left.  First, if I understand well, from the third quarter the &#x20AC;2 billion mandatory convertible is included in quarter one.  However, the result in increase in share account is not factored in yet and it will be only upon conversion?</p>
          <p>The second, going back to the sale and leaseback of real estate, I was wondering if you disclose that the yield and the impact on costs from the transaction, apologies if you gave this information already and I missed it?</p>
          <p>Third, on asset quality, we welcome the fact that the NPL coverage was kept flat in the quarter at 68% group level. Clearly there was &#x2013; you took advantage from using the capital gains.  However, I was wondering if you could comment on the level of coverage and this is a coverage that you feel comfortable with and therefore you may want to maintain more or less at this level going forward?  Many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matteo buon giorno. Getting on to your quick questions concerning the convertible, basically the convertible bonds this is included in core capital because it is capital, so it is capital, is deployed, it's available but it's not generating any increase in shares certainly for a year.  And they will only do so depending on how the Group coverts them, these bonds into shares if it needs to, and it will last for five years. So this has no impact on earning per shares and it does no immediate dilution of the share for shareholders.  Obviously, it's a mandatory instrument and the conversion will take place when it matures.</p>
          <p>With regard to the sales and leaseback, we're talking about approximately &#x20AC;100 million a year as the cost of rents that we didn't have and we've now will, but it's not very significant at all.</p>
          <p>And finally with regard to the coverage 70, 68% of the NPAs without the Group, and this is a very favorable comparison if we look at what we know about our international peers and certainly in the domestic market this coverage we're talking about 4.6 billion in generic nonstandard and substandard provisions that will be available for covering any possible increase in the specific regulatory provisions that we are required to hold, and we think that is a very strong coverage rate given the collateral situation that we have at the moment and also the structure of the quality of the NPA that we have that I mentioned before, whatever kind of reduction in the prices, the collaterals that you want to use.</p>
          <p>Coverage has improved in Spain because of the leaseback going into generic provisions, but here I would like to say something about coverage because in the end coverage is a very instrumental issue. We have standards and rules with regard to making entries into NPA, so this is done very quickly and at a time the cycle of this is done very objectively. There is no subjectivity or little very subjectivity with regard to booking NPAs and the provisions requirements are also established very objectively.  And depending on the kind of NPA we are talking about, we have one calendar or another one.</p>
          <p>So if we are not talking about the mortgage book, the top quality mortgage book, we have to have 100% coverage in the case of Spain within 24 months of the NPA, if it hasn't been recovered.  So, at a time of the cycle like this, well, obviously the NPAs are going to increase and the provisions that will grow with it but at a slower rate.  And obviously this means we will need further provisioning requirement, but this is an instrumental issue under the current rules, but if you look at other portfolios such as credit cards in Mexico, we have to have 100% provisioning in 12 months.  So the calendaring provisioning is very much quicker.  And this is really what we are looking at.</p>
          <p>I would just like to add page 18 of the presentation where we were going over the &#x20AC;12.5 billion that broke down into those, they were secured loans and those that were unsecured loans.  And if you remember, we had some 6.6 billion in doubtful unsecured loans which was 190% coverage with the guarantees that we have. So we are talking about another 5.8 billion in doubtfuls but with unsecured loans, but they were covered with 144% coverage. Another figure that I didn't mention when we are talking about NPA ratio whether they were secured or unsecured, what is true is the 770 million that we have spent in the first nine months of the year compare very favorably with the purchases that have been made in the industry, whether we are talking about two or 3 billion from each of our major rivals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, as there are no more conference call questions. We'll get the webcast. We'll move on to the webcast questions many of which have already been answered. So let's start may be with the issue of capital. We are asked by Citigroup and also Caja Madrid, what are our targets in terms of capital ratio, core capital in Tier 1, Tier 2?  We are also asked how much organic capital do we intend to generate in the next 12 to 18 months? And then with regard to capital ratios, but with regard to the denominator, we are asked if we are still seeing falls in the weight risked &#x2013; risk-weighted assets moving forward? And we are also asked how many NPAs <mark type="inaudible" /> have we incorporated with the Guaranty in the first quarter?</p>
          <p>[Foreign language] (1:18:43 to 1:18:59)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What Manuel was talking about before was that in 2010, the regulations would change and we think that there will be more strict capital requirements who have to have more capital required of us. But we don't think that will have a significant impact on us. Thinking about getting a lot more or a lot less, well it's better to be prudent and wait until the regulations are published and then we will see. And as Manuel has said that way it won't have an impact on the dividend policy or our capital ratios. What we're seeing well, the figures I think show it. It's difficult to foresee the future but we are seeing organic growth in capital &#x2013; in core capital coming from organic growth about 20 basis points in &#x2013; under normal conditions and we are doing even better than that at the moment. So I don't think I can give you any better information than that. And you're going to talk about risk weighted assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we saw in the quarter-on-quarter growth, risk weighted assets are pretty well stable. They are dropping off at 1.1% absorbing the Guaranty operation which has an impact on our risk weighted assets of $2.4 billion. And I think with that I've answered your third question.</p>
          <p>What is making our WA's go down, well, that lesser growth of our lending books and the change in mix towards lower risk assets which is impacting our whole loan book, do we think that will continue in the future? We think that growth throughout the rest of the year will be pretty low in risk weighted assets and for 2010, we're expecting to see a progressive recovery of levels of our business volumes there which will mean progressive speeding up of the growth of our risk weighted assets.</p>
          <p>What level of organic capital generation we're expecting over the next 18 months shall we say, maintaining the current policy with respect to our pay-out as &#xC1;ngel just said, we're expecting to get organic growth of about 20 basis points per quarter which we think is a reasonable estimate if the risk weighted assets grow less, that figure might be higher. But we are sort of envisaging this upward increase of RWAs over the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've got a couple of questions here, some &#x2013; one has been partially answered, whether, we're going to generate more capital gains in 2010 to put into generic provisioning and whether our coverage &#x2013; well, if we have to increase our coverage would we be considering any partial IPOs of any of our franchises in this case. That was one of the questions. The second is if we could get more color on the write-offs this quarter and where we've seen the growth, because the figures have gone up from 819 to 1,089 what's the reason for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> we've answered the question on the capital gains. As we said, our idea is to for any capital gains that are generated and not due to IPOs, because we haven't got any plan for the next, god knows how many quarters. They're all going to go to additional provisions as we have this quarter. And with regard to the write-offs, the markdowns that was 200 million for this quarter which is a modest growth and this has to do &#x2013; associated with Spain and the United States. In the case of Spain this is the policy that we have established, marking down any NPAs that are covered by &#x2013; 100% by provisions in this period where we don't have to mark them down according to the regulations. So we are talking about approximately 100 million in Spain and in the U.S. we have another 100 million and this is because of the policy we have &#x2013; the provisioning policy that we follow in the United States which we call partial markdowns.</p>
          <p>These are loans of 100 with provisions of 20, so we have marked down 20 and we have a loan on the balance sheet of 80, but at all times the loan is on the balance sheet and at the best estimate of the underlying asset that the loan is covering. So that's what we are seeing in the United States. And this is our policy of partial charge-offs.</p>
          <p>In the other regions that don't use the same policy, and &#x2013; but this is the general rule in the United States and this also means that coverage in the United States is obviously lower because you lower the provisions and you lower the point of the loan, that Manuel just said, so the result in coverage is also going to be lower. But this is a procedure that is generally accepted in the United States that affects everybody, our rivals over there as well, it's established by the Fed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have three questions dealing with the performance of refinancing or restructuring, I think they have already been answered, but maybe you could give us more information on this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But basically there are no further questions &#x2013; or nothing further to add for this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we will move on to another question from Santiago L&#xF3;pez [CSFB], who's talking about trends in the margin on a group level rather than just Spain.  He asked that how can we explain the growth, and the margin &#x2013; 19% growth in the margin with a loan book where falling margins &#x2013; and how do we expect the net interest income to perform in 2010, and what impact will the ALCO portfolio have on it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The ALCO portfolio basically is used to hedge deposits at cost level which with the resident sector in Spain will be &#x20AC;24 billion approximately with the portfolio which right now would be about 35. And that's generating 5.86% in net interest &#x2013; of the net interest income of the Group and that will explain the very strong growth that we are seeing in the net interest income which is associated to some margins that are growing.</p>
          <p>You should remember what we saw in the presentation about the process of re-pricing and how it works. One thing is the spread which can narrow because of the re-pricing of the assets in the domestic business in Spain, but then the margins we're getting on transactions -- new transactions and the new conditions that we are getting on the existing stock are all going up.</p>
          <p>And that's really what's behind this growth in our net interest income along with the structure of growth that we have on the liability side of the account with customer funds to hear about the reasons that we've already discussed. Some of them are extrapolable to the rest of the geographical areas and we think that the net interest income in 2010 could grow. At the moment what we are seeing, as we review things for the budget, is better expectations of growth in business volumes in some geographical areas as 2010 unfolds. There are some areas we think where we could have growth at the end of the year in double digits compared to rather flat levels, even negative levels that we are reporting at the moment. We should think about Mexico, for example, we are talking about a drop there of GDP of 6.8% in the first half and we are talking about forecast for growth in 2010 of more than 3% growth in the GDP. So that will be reflected, as you could imagine, in better business volumes and the same will be happening in other areas of our business.</p>
          <p>For example, corporations and businesses there, we are seeing de-leveraging and restructuring of debt and the companies that can go out on to the capital markets are doing so now. But that process will begin to generate new investment with more demand for credit for the combination of margins &#x2013; higher margins. The recovery of business levels &#x2013; business volumes on our loan book and customer funds moving towards lower cost customer funds which should improve our net interest income and mean that we get positive growth in 2010.</p>
          <p>We've got various questions about Mexico from various different analysts. And basically they're wondering what kind of recovery we are expecting in Mexico in this context. What we think will happen in terms of business volumes, NPA and returns, and the cost of risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Manuel has just said what we all like to hear is that we are over the worst in Mexico and the fall we are going to see in 2009, most of this has already happened or a large percentage of this happened in the first quarter, the 6.8%, Manuel said. And if we look at the whole year, the year as a whole, I think they will continue to fall a little bit no more, but the forecast for improvements at the end of the year and in our opinion over the next 10 or 12 days we will present the results for Mexico. But what we're seeing is growth of around 3% for Mexico which consolidates the sort of growth that we are seeing in business and mortgages. Unlike other countries, in Mexico the stock of unsold houses is almost zero. At the beginning of 2010 new housing will have to be build, so the mortgage sector, we're going to see a growth in our business in 2010 and I would also say that also in business and governments customers, we're going to continue to change our mix moving away from credit cards into 2010 and basically this will lead us to increase our net interest income during this period.</p>
          <p>Well, I can't tell you exactly how much at the moment because we are reviewing budget at the moment and we are asking for guidance for this region, for 2010, but I would say that in Mexico we're going to see good news in 2010 for business volumes in the mix of the activities especially and we're going to get to see good numbers in attracting customer funds in liquid funds with regard to term funds. So I think in Mexico the news should be good in 2010. Oh yes, and NPAs and the cost of risk. The level of provisions, yes, you saw from the presentation is around &#x20AC;316 million and is stable with a reduction in the NPA ratio. And Manuel said that, explained how we provisioned for credit cards in 12 months you have to have 100% provisions and we have seen an increase of two percentage points in the NPA, so we are talking about cost of risk and provisions level that is really stable for Mexico for us, and obviously what we are expecting are reductions in the volume of provisions and in the cost of risk in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have three questions about division of the Wholesale Banking. The first of which concerns the positive performance we are seeing in revenues and Firenzes asked whether we see any signs of slowdown in the short-term or do you think this is going to be sound growth that will be maintained. The second question, can we explain the losses in net trading income? Are we going to see this in the future? And the third question is can you tell us a little bit more about the generic release provision, the buyback of generic provisions in this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to your first question, the wholesale business is a business that our Group has based above all on our customers which means the revenues don't come through commercial credit spreads, the difference between lending and borrowing, it's more a matter of our global business with our customers. So the mix of revenues between net interest income and the rest has changed towards fee income because of all the operations we're generating with our customers worldwide, you already saw when I showed you the presentation what's been happening on the credit side.  We're increasing revenues by more than 24% over the period.  You mentioned, well I'd say continuing with this strategy which is very customer-oriented would mean we have more recurrent revenues and we'll generate revenues over the next few quarters and we're expecting growth with respect to losses.</p>
          <p>Well, if we look at the line in the NTI, there could be losses there, but we should see how they fit into the net interest income, what that means and how it compares to the NTI because basically the way that markets works has to &#x2013; means you have to take into account both figures.  So it's more relevant to look at the revenues line for both the net trading income and the net interest income.  Right now, the net trading income on its own doesn't give you relevant information in this case.</p>
          <p>And then the third question?  Yes, you can talk about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the release of generic provisions, Davide that's associated to the reduction in business volumes against the last quarter, so it's closely linked to the reduction of business volumes and less growth in lending and that's why we're releasing generic provisions in Wholesale Banking.  And also the exchange rate because the dollar is weakening and that means that 85 million less is needed, but that's just because of the exchange rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we're also asked about what's happening to the asset quality in the U.S. with respect to the provisions.  And Alfonso G&#xF3;mez of Citigroup has a question.  He asked to what degree Guaranty will contribute to the provisions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we said in the case of Guaranty, this has practically no impact because it's only been with us for a month during this quarter.  From the point of view of asset quality, we've seen that the additions to NPAs, in Compass these are fairly stable in net terms and with regard to provisions, this is the more aggressive policy that we've implemented with regard to partial charge-offs.  And at the moment, the net charge-off ratio that we have in Compass excluding a tiny contribution from Guaranty is 1.98% and if we &#x2013; and this is in comparison with the peer group where the average is 2.59%.  In the case of Compass, I'm talking about 1.98%.</p>
          <p>In the case of BB&amp;T, we are talking about 70%.  So it's lower than Compass.  And in the case of Regions, we are talking 2.14 which is slightly above Compass and Bank of America, we are talking about 1.81%, in the case of Frost, a major bank in Texas we are talking about 0.46%.  And that's why we have higher provisions at the moment.</p>
          <p>To give you more intuitive figures about three quarters of Compass's operating income is &#x2013; goes to provisions, our peers mentioned by Manuel just now or the average provisioning over 100% of the operating income or the net interest income to provisions.  I'm sure you've seen some recent articles where the state is putting &#x2013; the government is putting pressure on accounts and credit portfolios in all the banks in the states.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can finish with a final question from Ignacio Cerezo [JPMorgan] concerning the release of generic provisions in Spain.  How much generic provisions have we released in Spain and how much have we got at the end of September?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we've answered this, at least partially.  2.2 billion is the balance in Spain.  Of that 4.6 that we had in the presentation, 2.2 are purely generic.  We freed up 400 in the third quarter a little bit more.  Well, it's gone down a little bit more than in our third quarters, but as Manuel said that's linked to business volumes and exchange rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay then, I think you've pretty well answered all the questions.  If there are any more questions you know that you just have to get in contact with us in Investor Relations.  So, now thank you very much for having listened to us and anyone who is here can have a cup of coffee with us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>