<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1344058" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-02</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3180</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">&#xC1;ngel Cano, President and Chief Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Manuel Gonz&#xE1;lez, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Welcome to this webcast in which we are presenting the earnings of the BBVA Group for the 2010. The presentation of the results obtained will be done by our Chief Operating Officer, &#xC1;ngel Cano was talking about the group within the entire economy and then our CFO, Manuel Gonz&#xE1;lez Cid will be talking about the different business areas in the group.</p>
          <p>And then we'll have Q&amp;A session in which we'll take on all the questions that come over the webcast to us. If we then have enough time to answer all of the questions during the webcast the Investor Relations' team will be getting back to you with there answers during today.</p>
          <p>So &#xC1;ngel, whenever you wish, you have the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to this presentation of the BBVA Group's earnings for the final quarter and the entire year of 2010. One thing is pretty clear, this year has been the fourth year &#x2013; not the fourth full year, but the fourth year since the crisis began.</p>
          <p>Once again we've been working in an environment of very high stress. It's been very complex, but of course, it was different depending on whether we're talking about the developed economies or the emerging economies.</p>
          <p>I'm not going to get back into all of the different factors that have already had a big impact on the crisis or even on 2010 in the developed world. But it's very clear that we can draw a certain conclusion from it and many people are, which is that growth is going to be lower, when we compare against the kind of growth rates that we had before the crisis. And there is going to be an uneven impact depending on where you live. If you're in an emerging economy or a more developed one. And when we talk about 2010, we can see that growth has clearly been lower in the developed countries, especially in the G7 countries as you can see on the screen, then it has been in the emerging economies.</p>
          <p>It's also clear that although this is the fourth year of the crisis, we are still seeing a lot of uncertainty, especially in the developed world, and the growth potential of the emerging economies is standing out more and more. Of course all this uncertainty doesn't mean to say that opportunities for growth are not coming up, either for organic growth or non-organic growth. But, I think for us organic growth is of main interest in the developed economies that we're operating in. So in this very complex high stress environment, BBVA once again has been a road to end the year 2010 with very good earnings, over &#x20AC;4.6 billion. That means growth of 9.4%, as we increase against the previous year.</p>
          <p>And that means that both our operating income and the net attributable profit looks very good, and we've been able to go on financing the provisions we have. I'm sorry, I think that this interference might be due to my telephone, let me see, I'll turn it off, if you'll excuse me. At least I've turned mine off, so I put a clear conscious. But anyway with this volume of earnings, we've been able to maintain the good level of risk indicators and other ratios. And at the end of the year, we've improved our NPA ratio and the net interest into NPAs during the year.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we've showed up the solvency ratios we have. The capital ratio has given us a core capital of 9.6% at year-end. And we've made that compatible with an improvement in the financing structure on the balance sheet for the group, as well as managing to do this without having to tap any finance coming from the European Central Bank. And more important still, we've been able to improve and leverage the future growth of the group with a non-organic acquisition in 2010 and the dynamic management of the different franchises that we already have in the group.</p>
          <p>Let's look at these very strong recurrent earnings, which are based on two key pillars. The first one is diversification. We've been managing this for sometime in the group and the other thing has to do with anticipation, so that we can forecast what's going to happen. We've been doing that, we did it at the end of last year and we're still doing it now.</p>
          <p>What does diversification mean? It means that our business portfolio is very well balanced. One-third of the revenues come from Spain and Portugal and then if we take into account the Asia business, which is included under global business, about 50% of the revenues come from emerging markets.</p>
          <p>As I was saying at the beginning of the presentation, these markets are outgrowing the more developed markets. So, we're getting more than 11% growth in the emerging economies, whilst we're seeing a drop of over 3% in the more developed economies, which means that in the emerging economies, as we grow, we are generating more and more revenues and in the developed world our outlook is to boost revenues as we increase our market share in the different economies where we operate, which means that we've been able to put up growth earnings by 1.2%.</p>
          <p>And we are also streamlining our accounts. At the end of last year, we've set aside lot of provisions as you know, because we are anticipating what's going to happen, which is meant that this year we've managed to bring down our loan-loss provisions by over 12%, although 38% of the new entries last year were booked as possible NPAs, but are in fact performing and not in arrears.</p>
          <p>If we look at total costs, we see the same kind of behavior as we grow more in the emerging than in the developed economies. In the emerging economies we are investing in staff, in hardware, software, new offices and infrastructure and in the developed countries, we are really only investing in technology.</p>
          <p>Our head count in the emerging countries is growing, in the developed countries it's pretty well flat. But what's really important is that technology is boosting our efficiency all the time. 42% of the investment in technology that we've made over the year has been put into transformation projects and the rest has been the kind of investment that we make to maintain the IT we already have. So this is very important, especially if we compare ourselves against our peers that are below 30%, or if we compare our self against ourselves in 2006.</p>
          <p>This growth in revenues is very sound growth, and if we look at the cost performance, it depends where we are of course. But it means that we can still hedge the ranking table for efficiency in the world. If you look at the cost income ratio that have already been published. There are some data on this table from banks that haven't yet published their year-end results. So we put the data to September. But here, we are the leaders in terms of efficiency.</p>
          <p>So we can say that this dynamic management in the different franchises has given us recurrent, sustainable, very resilient earnings. We've got two key figures, gross income over &#x20AC;20 billion and net attributable profit of &#x20AC;4.6 billion. And that means that we are able to improve our risk profile at the same time. As we grow year-on-year and as the returns go down elsewhere, our returns are looking very good, our return on equity is close to 16%.</p>
          <p>These kinds of earnings, as I said, mean that we can propose the following motion to the next AGM for dividends. We want to remunerate shareholders four times a year on the same dates as we always have. We are bringing in the special optional payment for investors to have a cash or share payment in the April and October payments. And this is based on minimum remuneration if &#x20AC;0.42 per share, which is what we've been announcing in previous presentations. And of the &#x20AC;12 billion, which we have in net attributable profit &#x2013; no, I'm sorry, in operating income, means that we are able to improve our NPA ratios and bring down the cost of risk year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Net interest have gone down 50%, if we take out the impact of what happened last year, if we look at the main effects, the drop in gross additions by 11% or 23%, if we take into account the special reserves that we set aside for anticipation, and then the recoveries, which have grown close to 40%, which gives us then the net interest, which are dropping 50% from &#x20AC;8.3 billion last year to &#x20AC;4 billion in 2010. And with this kind of performance in net interest, we can actually say that the figure of NPAs in the group is leveling out, and all risk indicators are improving, as we see a 5% increase in our coverage ratio.</p>
          <p>At the same time, the NPA ratios, I said, goes down from 4.3% to 4.1%, and the overall cost of risk goes down from 1.5% to 1.3%. So these strong earning means that we can report today a core capital of about 9.6% coming up from 8%. There are three factors, which are very simple to explain behind this, the organic generation of capital, which is something that we've been increasing quarter-on-quarter, 70 basis points for the year as a whole. The impact of the capital increase, 1.5%, and then another factor, which is linked to the increased stake that we have in China of 5%. The impact of inflation in Venezuela and other impacts, which aren't quite important, that takes out another 60 basis points. So we end up with that 9.6% figure that I gave you for our core capital ratio.</p>
          <p>The fourth very relevant point is that we have been able to and still are able to improve our financing structure on the balance sheet without having to go to the European Central Bank at any time. So that's because we have a higher ratio of customer funds, the total assets reaching 49.9% at the year-end as we improve our financing structure, which has been made compatible of with time schedule for maturities during 2011 and the next few years, which is obviously better than most of our peers.</p>
          <p>Without the fact that we have collaterals of about &#x20AC;70 billion, which are also there to add an additional cushion. And we shouldn't forget how important it is to go on ensuring that we will have future growth in the bank, both organic and inorganic growth.</p>
          <p>In organic growth, it was really important that we moved into Turkey, which is one of the most attractive markets in the emerging economies. We're talking about a bank which is well known by investors. And I think that it's been recognized to have a fantastic management team and it's got a very innovative focus on businesses, which is very similar to the BBVA one.</p>
          <p>And the way we see it is that we are going to be able to share best practices between the two entities because I think they'll learn from us, but we can learn from them as well in our global areas. The transaction was structured, as you know, in a very clear way.</p>
          <p>Obviously, we are moving towards the possibility of taking over more control over the next few years and incorporating such a big franchise into the group has reinforced the joint ventures that we have in Asia where we are seeing the process of business generation speeding up as we have also bought Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole in Uruguay and so we'll have a big market share in the Uruguayan market as well.</p>
          <p>And apart from that we're also improving the dynamics in all the different franchises in different ways. We're seeing growth &#x2013; you'll see this more later in the presentation, but very high growth in our banking business in Mexico and in South America. And another thing we are seeing is that systematically we are gaining market share in both lending and in customer funds in Spain.</p>
          <p>So to sum up, if we combine things like the cost income ratio, the coverage ratio and the returns on equity, we are standing apart from our peers. We are in a class of our own. And if you look at the geographic diversification of revenues, it looks very healthy and is improving over time as well. This snapshot of the diversification of our revenues is one of the keys to ensure the sustainability of our growing revenues in the future.</p>
          <p>So to sum up I can say that our income statement is very strong with sustainable revenues because we are improving the diversification of the sources of our revenues and we're consistently anticipating the market in terms of what we're doing with our cost profiles and we're getting growth at the same time as we are working on the cost side and we're standing out from our peers as we improve our risk profile. And that's something we're not seeing any of our peers doing.</p>
          <p>We're also improving our capital adequacy with very good ratios compared to our peers and we're shoring up the balance sheet consistently with a very good financing structure that's vital for the group. But I think also, it's also vital to go on managing dynamically so that we can guarantee future revenues and continue to standout against our peers with a focus on emerging economies as we increase our market share in developed economies as well and investing in technology which gives us a clear competitive edge.</p>
          <p>So from now on, I'm going to hand the floor over to our CFO, who will look at what's happened in the different group businesses over the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Let's take a quick look at the performance of the different areas of business in 2010, with some references to the quarterly performance of the final quarter of the year. Maybe the basic conclusion of this analysis can be seen on this slide; here we have the key aspects. This is what we would like to highlight from each of our business areas.</p>
          <p>Let's start with Spain and Portugal. Taking advantage of the restructuring of the sectors making it possible to generate growth in our market share and at the same time we are showing superior performance, an increasingly superior performance every time we put out the earnings in comparison with our peers here in Spain, both with regards to the financial income and also in credit &#x2013; asset quality and also provisionings for the income statement. And then of course the net attributable profit also continues to grow in our franchise in Spain. We'll go in to more detail.</p>
          <p>Mexico now; here the leading aspect is an upward trend quarter-after-quarter we're seeing in earnings in the context of a highly dynamic economy. Business is growing and there is a substantial improvement in the risk indicators. There is a very similar situation in the South American franchise, where this growth in business activities, that's a very sharp growth, which is generating growth in all the lines of the income statement in an environment of improvements and stability in risk quality.</p>
          <p>Turning to the United States now; the U.S. has shown how we are starting to see the fruit of rolling out the business model in our franchise in the U.S and this is something you can clearly see if we look at that presentation, the enormous change in the mix that we're seeing both in the assets and the liability side of the balance sheet with a generalized improvement in all indicators, but particularly with regard to the asset quality indicators.</p>
          <p>And finally, last but not least, Wholesale Banking and Asset Management continues to show growth in a complex environment, but the quality of the incomes and recurring earnings with a clear strengthening of our customer franchise, which levered on the increasingly international dimension of the group. And I think what is also important, how Asia is starting to show high profitability and a growing contribution to our revenues. I think these are the key aspects of the business areas. So now we can look at this one-by-one.</p>
          <p>Spain and Portugal; we said we're gaining market share. With the latest available information, the group has gained 30 basis points in lending and 1% in deposits. So with the gain in lending, if we look at the public sector, this gain in share is even greater. But if we look at the dynamics of the income statement &#x2013; and this is what stands us apart from the rest of the sector if we looked at the net trading income on one hand and the provisions on the other side. So if we look at the net interest income, which is about &#x20AC;1.1 billion with a fall of 2.7% quarter-on-quarter, we're continuing to suffer from the margins with the narrowing of spreads, but also this is a situation that is starting to level off, because of the measurement measures taken.</p>
          <p>In fact, there is fall in the &#x2013; in net interest income. It's one of the lowest we've seen in the industry. And in fact if we looked at 2010 as a whole, our net interest income is falling by 4.8% when the average for our main competitors here in Spain, who've published their earnings to-date, they're talking about falls at 15.2% and some of our most sounded peers are reporting falls of around 20%. And this comes with performance on the cost side of minus 1.4%, which absorbs all the increase in the cost of leases, because of the sale in leaseback operations and also shows an exhausted control on all our cost, despite the fact that we've been showing systematic falls in operating expenses for some years here in Spain, anticipating the current scenario.</p>
          <p>And if you look at the other component that sets us apart from our rivals and there is other risk indicators, we can see how as our loss &#x2013; loan loss provisions have fallen by 30%, NPA figures have increased by &#x2013; improved by 1.1% and this figure is a substantial improvement with the underlying quality of our assets, where we see a substantial fall in the net entries in NPAs, which is &#x20AC;1.6 billion. Last year, we had &#x20AC;6.2 billion.</p>
          <p>With sound growth in recoveries, but also &#x2013; what is also important a substantial fall in the gross entries in NPAs. So the net entries have improved not only because of the fall in the gross entries, but also because of the improvements in recoveries. And all of this gives us an NPA ratio that's dropped by 0.1% in an industry where we're seeing major growth in NPA ratios in the industry as a whole over 2010.</p>
          <p>With regard to our exposure to developers, as we have heard on many occasions from the market, we have chosen for maximum transparency policy here and the transparent &#x2013; I've got two slides on this and in the leaflet, there is a detailed analysis of the whole issue together with the group's policies, regardless of the tables that we have presented in the annual management report. But just to give you an idea, we have an exposure to developers of &#x20AC;6.6 (sic) [&#x20AC;16.6] billion, with &#x20AC;3.5 billion of NPAs, i.e. 21.3% of NPAs.</p>
          <p>And what's important is one-third of this is associated with subjective NPAs, i.e. they are up-to-date in their payments, but the group has decided subjectively to classify them as &#x2013; put them on the watch list. Moreover, we have another &#x20AC;2.38 billion over &#x2013; just classified as substantial and with regard to our position in collateral, i.e. what we're financing in &#x2013; for these developers, we only have 26% in land and 68% of this land is already built on and developed and 66% of our exposure to developers is guaranteed by buildings or finished housing.</p>
          <p>There are three issues I'd like to touch upon with regard to this. First of all, our exposure to the developers is 8% of our lending book in Spain, which is an important issue, when as the industry as a whole it accounts for 18%. So BBVA has an exposure to the developers in Spain that's far lower then the figures that are coming out of other banks.</p>
          <p>The second important issue in my opinion is the level of the NPA is higher with regards to developer risk than you'll see in the industry as a whole, which is another important factor in my opinion. Moreover in the ones we've put down, one-third of the NPA is associated to subjective NPA or they're on the watch list.</p>
          <p>And the third important issue, if we look at the coverage of our doubtful risk and our substandards associated to developers and we look at the collateral that's supporting the NPAs. And if we look at the updated values of these transactions of the guarantees as per the Bank of Spain's circular, then I think that the NPAs are well covered in this portfolio.</p>
          <p>So, with regard to developer risk, once again, we are much better positioned than our rivals in the industry. And if we look at individual mortgages now, we can see how the quality of our individual mortgage book is quite high. We have an NPA ratio of 2.9% and an average loan-to-value of 51%, 96% of this portfolio is associated with financing first residencies. So we have very little financing of second homes and we have very few loans with a loan-to-value of over 100%. So, high quality of our mortgage &#x2013; retail mortgage book. And just to close the circle, if we look at the foreclosures and asset purchases, the volume of the foreclosures and asset purchases including stakes in companies is 4.693% (sic) [4.793%] with an average coverage of 33.4%, which indicates two major issues.</p>
          <p>First of all the weight of foreclosures and assets purchased in the bank as a whole is below the national &#x2013; the industry average and the valuation of these properties is net of provisions and this is very, very close to the current market values, if we bear in mind that these assets are put on our balance sheet with a reduction of between 20% and 25% plus the sales costs over the original price of the guaranties when the loans were granted.</p>
          <p>So, the developer risk and the real estate risk again is far better than the position of our peers and the combination of the lower impact on the net trading income that we are suffering together &#x2013; sorry the net interest income is enabling us to stabilize the quality of our earnings. So we only have 9%, which in the current context looking around us makes us feel very comfortable, and of course, a positive result in the final quarter.</p>
          <p>If we move onto Mexico now, we have a totally different picture. Business is growing. Lending is up by 40% with deposits growing by 8.7% and quarter-after-quarter, this growth is taking off and the growth in assets is not just because of the macroeconomic improvements we're seeing in the Mexico with significant growth in real terms, it's also associated with a substantial gain in market share both in companies and also in public administration and in consumer loans and credit cards.</p>
          <p>So Mexico is in a far better position from a macro point of view, but also the bank is gaining substantial market share in the context. And this leads to a dynamics of growing earnings quarter-after-quarter, which we can see the fourth quarter here of &#x20AC;454 million in the quarter, which gives us a clear improvement, which can also be seen in all the income statement with improvement in the net interest income up 3% quarter-on-quarter and this is generating a market share gain, not just in business, but also in net recurrent earnings where at the moment, Bancomer represents 33.3% of the recurring net interest income of the &#x2013; all of the Mexican banking industry.</p>
          <p>If we add to this, what's going on with regard to lending quality, we can see that the NPA has reduced by 3.2% with a systematic reduction since last year with a reduction in provisions of 30%, which improves the coverage ratios with generous provisions, even with the 28% reduction, which gives us a cost of risk of 3.6%, which gives us room for future drops here.</p>
          <p>And all of this gives us earnings in Mexico for 2010 of &#x20AC;1.7 billion &#x2013; &#x20AC;1.71 billion to be exact, constant growth without taking into account the exchange rates of 11%. And if we do this in euros, we're talking about growth of 25.7%. And if we bear in mind, the coverage ratios have been relatively low during the year, expecting an appreciation in the euro, Mexican peso exchange rate. So, our shareholders are going to benefit from a growth in the earnings that is over 25%.</p>
          <p>South America; if we saw improvement in business volumes in Mexico quarter-after-quarter, if we go to South America, we can see that there's even better is happening far quicker. The growth in lending is 23.3%, i.e. it's over 20% with growth in deposits of over 19%. And here once again the macroeconomic situation in South America is very positive, but on top of this, we're gaining market share both in lending and customer deposits in all the countries as a whole. And at the same time, the net attributable profit therefore, that is also growing 19.5% without factoring in the exchange rate effect.</p>
          <p>If we also look at the composition of the earnings in South America, we can see how 20.7% of the earnings come from our pensions and insurance business. This is a business that is showing major growth and on the other hand, we have 79% of the earnings, which comes from our banks.</p>
          <p>And if we look at the distribution of the earnings by geography, you'll see there's enormous diversity there. For instance, the greatest contribution in the growing earnings at the moment come from Colombia, Chile, and Peru, which if we put them together are about the same as Mexico with regard to volume of population and also from the point of view of the critical mass of the countries.</p>
          <p>So with those three countries on their own, account for almost the same as Mexico and with major growth in earnings. And we can see that despite the growth in the business volumes, NPAs is quite stable, it's even dropped year-on-year, and the coverage ratio is still very broad. We're maintaining stable or slightly dropping in provisions with a cost of risk that is very stable, at around 1.5%. And this enables us to have a net attributable profit in South America, which is growing 16.5% income before tax &#x2013; sorry, net interest income of 11.1%; gross income of nearly 10%, and the prospective revenues for the future are &#x2013; have enormous potential for next year as they did in Mexico.</p>
          <p>United States; at the beginning, I said that the headline here is how the rollout of the BBVA business model is starting to generate results. And we're seeing this clearly in many different areas. We highlighted two areas that we consider to be important, how growth in new production in lending is growing in major segments. New business written, we have year-on-year of new business in individual mortgages, consumer finance, and also in SMEs or commercial as it's called here. And we can see how the growth in new business written in this quarter if we compare it with the same quarter of last year are very significant. So the dynamics in lending are highly positive. And moreover, this is substantially changing the mix of the assets on the balance sheet of Compass.</p>
          <p>At the moment, loans to commercial account for 51% of total lending that have grown by 5% and loans to individual account for 37%. These have grown by 6% over the year. And you can see how we're making a major effort to reduce our exposure to real estate, both in residential construction and in commercial construction, where this portfolio now only accounts for 13% of the total and its fallen by 43%. This will give you an idea of the effort that we've made in the United States and how we're gradually generating results quarter-after-quarter in the income statement.</p>
          <p>If we just looked at on the liability side, it's a very similar situation, the high cost liabilities, the term deposits are reducing and how site deposits and current accounts are growing.</p>
          <p>Another issue that we'd like to highlight is the improvement of the general risk indicators. In provisions, there's a fall by 52% compared with last year and we've even seen a substantial fall if we factored in the one-off provisioning that we did last year. So our cost of risk is still very, very high at 1.7%, but it is starting to converge to what we would expect to see in the future after the crisis and we are starting to see how the NPA balance and the NPA ratio has fallen slightly, but it's starting to show signs of leveling off and the coverage ratio thus improved to 76%. And this is given us earnings of &#x20AC;237 million in the United States despite the effort we've made to restructure the balance sheet and despite the rollout of the new technological platform and despite the number of issues that are emerging in the United States to adapt our franchise to the BBVA business model.</p>
          <p>And, finally, Wholesale Banking and Asset Management; maybe the leading aspects here, as I said at the beginning, there are three of them. First of all, stability and growth in Corporate and Investment Banking. Despite a complex growth in lending, we are seeing growth of around 12% and commissions &#x2013; fees and commissions of about 17% and the major dynamics in a very difficult environment. And at the same time, if we look at our market model and how they distribute their revenues, we are seeing the revenues coming from the customer finance have an increasing rate. We are now talking about 79% of total revenues and only 21% come from trading, which means that even in difficult markets such as the market in Asia last year and &#x2013; we have continued to generate earnings and recurrent earnings.</p>
          <p>And if we look at the third issue that we'd like to highlight and that is how Asia is starting to generate a volume of &#x2013; a significant volume of revenues and earnings, in 2010, we have &#x20AC;424 million in Asia. We now have more revenues in Asia than in Continental Europe.</p>
          <p>And currently in Asia, we have this distribution of income 75% is in CITIC, but 25% of these earnings is organic growth that come from our franchises, our offices in Asia. And quarter-after-quarter, they're starting to generate earnings that are significant in the areas as a whole and also in the group as a whole, which means that in a complex environment for wholesalers, which we can see from the reporting of some other banks, we are growing our earnings by 11.4% in a very complex environment.</p>
          <p>And &#x20AC;950 million in earnings in Wholesale Banking and Asset Management. So all the franchises are positive in the different businesses and in very different in economic environments, depending on where we're talking about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>And so to wrap-up this presentation before we open the Q&amp;A session. I just wanted to give you a quick trailer as to what kind of priorities we can have in management in 2011. And after as you've seen we've been generating a certain dynamic in the presentation as we separated out two different levers of growth in the developed and in the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>And the consequences of what we do, however, have to be the similar in both, we have to get better revenues, we have to gain market share in both, we have to continue to be leaders in the countries, where we are operating. And that for us will be a vital part of our management. It always has been and it will be in the future.</p>
          <p>Obviously in developed markets, as I said before, quite apart from all this uncertainty that we hope will dissipate a bit in 2011, we think that there still will be opportunities for new growth. Earlier on, I was saying that for us, we've got a very clear priority to focus on organic growth, but at the same time, we are always looking at possible windows for &#x2013; in organic growth in the countries where we are operating.</p>
          <p>But we want to gain market share, we want to get more customers and that means, more business volumes. We want customers with whom we can continue to grow overtime as we boost our share of wallet with them, which is the best way to boost returns for our shareholders. We want to continue to focus very clearly on managing margins.</p>
          <p>As Manuel said before, because of the increase in costs, especially on the liabilities side, we again have to manage costs very carefully and we'll continue to do so as we improve our risk indicators. And as you saw in 2010, we did that very well at a time when there was very high stress, very complex market, but we did it.</p>
          <p>In the emerging markets, we have to take advantage of the very buoyant markets that we're seeing in most of the countries we're operating in. We will look to boost the dynamic growth in business volumes that we've already got as we gain market share in the biggest markets, and we have very specific plans, which are clearly focused on ambitious growth in all of these different areas.</p>
          <p>And we have to measure this very carefully to see that in the transversal areas we can add value to the countries that we're working in. In the more mature global area, which is in wholesale banking, where we have to take advantage of growth in all of the places that we work. Recently, we've also got another global area, which is now the global retail area, where we want to take advantage of best practices, so that wherever we're doing business, well we learn how to do it even better elsewhere, as we bring in more customers, get more share of wallet. And the group as a whole adds value to all the different geographical areas in the group. And for us technology will continue to be a key part of our development in all the geographical areas, so that in the future we'll be able to roll out our ambitious growth plans.</p>
          <p>If we look at then at the different geographical areas, Manuel has already made it quite clear about how last year ended and how this year is beginning. But there is a couple of things I wanted to highlight for each of the geographical areas in Spain, we're going to see more and more pressure on margins and especially in deposit accounts.</p>
          <p>And we think and I believe this is true that the tightening of the margins on deposits isn't going to be as high as it has been at some points in 2010. But it will be critical to make sure that our spreads are better than those of our peers. And we also manage to stand apart in the way that we report our main risk factors.</p>
          <p>Gain in market share will be a central part of our policy, both on the lending side of the account and with respect to deposits as we take advantage as we have done over the last few quarters of the restructuring which has led to a consolidation of the market here in Spain.</p>
          <p>In Mexico, we have to consolidate the leadership we've already got. We've seen in 2010, quarter-on-quarter we've been improving. And at the end of the year, we're beginning to see in the bottom line what the impact of the growth in business volumes has been.</p>
          <p>And Manuel has been reporting on the figures for the last few quarters, but I think in 2011 you'll see over the next few quarters that this upward tendency to grow faster and faster as the quarters go by will continue in Mexico. And this will be compatible with continuous improvement in risk profile and our cost of risk.</p>
          <p>In South America, we've seen that we've had buoyant business and earnings in 2010, especially as of the third quarter, but getting better and better quarter-on-quarter throughout the year. And this is something that we expect to continue. We look forward to reporting the results there in the next few quarters because we think that performance is going to very positive.</p>
          <p>In the United States we'll go on working very hard focusing on consolidating our group business model there. We are still seeing the roll out is slightly slower than we would have liked in the net attributable profit line. But the level of operating income we think in 2011, we can see a significant upside. And as Manuel said, for the group it's really important that we are still investing in technology and we completely change the platform in the USA, which is obviously going to have impact on earnings.</p>
          <p>In wholesale banking and asset management, obviously there has been a lot of volatility in all of the markets last year. Although in our case, because of our business model, which is very customer oriented, we've been able to grow in all our franchises with respect to customer business. And in 2011, we are going to continue to reinforce this business &#x2013; sorry, this customer oriented model and boost revenue volumes because of our relationship model.</p>
          <p>So we want to work in all of the franchises in different ways with different focuses. But with positive expectations from all the businesses, improving and consolidating the positive dynamics, we've already got an increasing market shares in all the economies where we're operating.</p>
          <p>And I think that's about it, isn't it Manuel? So, I think we can probably now take questions. Well, as I've tried to do in other presentations, I'll try to group the questions together on the basis of their subject matter, so that we can deal with enormous number of questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So first of all the dividends, right from the time we opened the line, people have been asking about the dividend. I don't know if that's people didn't understand or maybe there was &#x2013; we said something in a confusing way. And so the three questions we have here about dividends come from Antonio Ramirez from Keefe, from Rohith Chandra-Rajan from Barclays and Andrew Lim from Matrix Group.</p>
          <p>The questions on the dividend are as follows. Are you changing your dividend policy? Will it mean there is going to be less cash payout? And secondly, are you going to increase the payout over the next few years to reach 50%, because that was the average that you've been reporting over the last few years. And why are you proposing this scrip dividend with this option of being paid in either cash or shares? And why are we doing this, that's what Andrew Lim asks. When we've got very good capital ratios and market cap would make it possible to pay out in cash it would seem, so can you talk about the dividend a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regardless of the fact that Manuel will add to this, he can add whatever you have like. The dividend policy, basically hasn't changed. We continue, as we said, we continue to pay four dividends a year, as we've done so far, four payments. The payments at the end of the payout at the end of the year will be 38%, which is a 30% increase over last years.</p>
          <p>And as I said during the presentation, on the basis of maintaining &#x20AC;0.42 per share in the current situation. We have no plans at the moment to increase the &#x20AC;0.42 on the share &#x2013; per share. But I can't rule it out in the future, depending on how things happen in the economic and financial environment. I certainly can't rule out an increase.</p>
          <p>Two issues I'd like to clarify. First of all, with regard to demands from share actions, we've had a lot of requests from shareholders to take advantage of the tax effect of handing out shares. And what's even more important, we're not talking about a scrip dividend, we're talking about an option, a total option for shareholders, so the shareholder can decide whether they want to be paid in cash or in shares.</p>
          <p>So this benefits all shareholders who want to take advantage of this and those who prefer to get cash payout, they can have it. Our policy is a 38% payout or rather our calculation of the payout is a 38% payout. And we have no plans to increase this or change our policy, but we do want to maintain a payout of at least &#x20AC;0.42 a share, but this will depend on the performance that we will see in the uncertain economic situation.</p>
          <p>I don't know if you'd like to add anything to this Manuel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I could add that the bank's dividend policy what we've all tried to do is to cover three requisites, stability, predictability and recurrence. Basically the only change that we see here is we continue to pay three interim dividends. But what we're are doing is to introduce the possibility of taking the dividend either in cash or in shares.</p>
          <p>In 2010 in the interim ones and the interim ones in 2011, our idea is to make this the second interim dividend. But this will be determined by the proposal that's going to be put to the AGM. So shareholders for these dividends will be able to choose whether they want to be remunerated in shares or in cash.</p>
          <p>And the legal base for this is to release capital as a mechanism for remunerating shareholders who prefer to get paid in shares rather in cash. But the dates of the interim dividends are the same, the policy is the same, and our commitment to maintain the flow of returns on share of &#x20AC;0.42 per share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Within the net interest income, Britta Schmidt from Autonomous, her question concerns the reasons for the fall in the net interest income in the corporate center and what would be our forecast for 2011? She also talks about the elasticity of domestic deposits in the face of a raise in interest rates, do we have any calculations dealing with this?</p>
          <p>Rohith Chandra-Rajan, once again from Barclays, has a question concerning the fall in the net interest income, are we comfortable with this? Can we overcome this in the course of 2011?</p>
          <p>Raoul Leonard from the Royal Bank of Scotland, mentions that the fall in the last few quarters in the net interest income has led to a situation. What measures is the bank going to take or are they taking in order to reduce falls of this kind in 2011.</p>
          <p>Arturo de frias from Evolution asks, so given the spreads of &#x2013; of the latest issues of around 225 basis points for the corporate bonds, maybe you could tell us something about our best guess &#x2013; or best estimate for 2011 for the net interest income for the &#x2013; in the corporate center.</p>
          <p>Francisco Riquel from N+1, asks whether we could &#x2013; you could give us an update on the Assets and Liability Committee, the ALCO portfolio. The sovereign debts, the maturity dates. This is something that's been &#x2013; he has also asked about the outlook for the net interest income for Spain in the coming quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then Manuel, maybe we can take it in turns or give some clarifying. The drop in the corporate center in net interest income has to do with the higher costs of funding, above all after the second half of 2010. Anyway trying to answer everything that people are referring to about net interest income in Spain and in the corporate center, because this is one of the questions that's come up again and again.</p>
          <p>Maybe what's most relevant is to look at the fourth quarter after a third quarter in which we were &#x2013; got the full hit from the higher cost of retail deposits and the higher costs of wholesale issues. In the fourth quarter, we saw that we've kept the levels at a very similar level to what they've reached in the third quarter. So what's the outlook, what kind of trends are we expecting to see over the next few quarters?</p>
          <p>Well two quarters ahead, I'd say in principle, given the current situation the first and second quarter of 2011 should be pretty similar to what we've seen in the end of last year. So we have two quarters during which &#x2013; and there won't be significant drops in net interest income, it will stay more or less at the same levels as the third and fourth quarter of last year. And we will continue to see spreads &#x2013; and I think it was Arturo de frias who was asking about that. Spreads that we have, I'd say are at the moment in the same kind of pricing as we've got on deposits in the market here in Spain. So, I'd say that we've seen asset repricing as Europe all went up over the last few months.</p>
          <p>But now we think that probably net interest income as of the end of the second quarter, so as we look towards the third quarter of 2011, there should be a recovery in net interest income. So quarter-on-quarter, we can expect the levels to go from lower to higher or may be stable over the first two quarters and then growth in the third and fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>And then &#x2013; yes, the measures that we are taking, it's not so much for 2011 really. It's something we've been doing for sometime. The main things we have to talk about here are &#x2013; well, earlier on in the presentation, we looked at one item, which came up a couple of times, which was how hard we worked to improve our financial structuring, so that we're not so dependent on the markets and that means that, we can have more domestic policies for managing the prices of our customer funds or the cost of our customer funds.</p>
          <p>If we approximately calculate the price of our deposits in Spain and how they perform compared to our peers, we could talk about 50, 60 basis points on average, less cost for us on deposits and this is something I've been reporting on for several quarters now because of our individualized pricing policy, so that we can get customized pricing because of the technology we have here in Spain. At the moment, we are one percentage point below the cost of the deposits that we were observing at the beginning of the third quarter in 2010.</p>
          <p>Consequently, we're going to be monitoring the pricing very closely, so that we can make sure that the cost of our customer funds continues to be efficient as we improve our policy such that we will not have to go out to tap any wholesale markets and we won't have any dependency or we have lessened our dependency on the European Central Bank.</p>
          <p>So for 2011, we hope to see some improvement in some of these parameters maybe and any improvement such as a bigger reduction in the cost of borrowing which is something we've been seeing over the last few weeks. We'll definitely improve the outlook further. So any reduction in the spreads that we're seeing at the moment would also just improve our outlook that we've already given for the next few quarters.</p>
          <p>Earlier on, I was saying that sincerely I think it's unlikely in the view of the current situation and the kind of consolidation that we're seeing in the market for there to be any surges in the cost of dividends and customer funds. And I say that very sincerely because I really don't think it will be possible because of the weakness that we've seen in our competitors' accounts here in Spain, there have been some drops in net interest income.</p>
          <p>In our accounts, we're still outperforming our peers definitely and is precisely because of the very high cost of customer funds that our competitors have done so badly, so it's unlikely they are going to be able to put up the prices that they are offering customers to make the process any more. So we think there will be less pressure on the cost of deposits in 2011 and especially in the first two quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then I'll answer the other question. Shall I? To give you a little bit more color on the net interest income in the corporate center. I think it's pretty interesting to look at the reasons for the year-on-year drop from 2009 to 2010. And the drop in the last quarter &#x2013; third quarter and fourth quarter, I think that's what you're talking about in your questions. So let's start with the drop, 2009, 2010 in the net interest income of the corporate center. The biggest impact here of about &#x20AC;700 million came from the repricing of retail mortgages because of the new interest rates that we've got. So that's the biggest impact.</p>
          <p>Spain and Portugal unit gets its remunerations, which has to do with the origination level and so there is a certain risk spread which then goes to the corporate center when interest rates change. And then there is another impact, which has to do with wholesale borrowing becoming more expensive. That's about a &#x20AC;140 million year-on-year. And these effects are offset partially by the return on our ALCO account, which you can see, which is also booked to the corporate center. So that offsets some of the more negative hits that we get from the returns on our books.</p>
          <p>If we look quarter-on-quarter what's been happening in the corporate center, so third quarter against fourth quarter, there is a drop of &#x20AC;81 billion &#x2013; sorry &#x20AC;1.81 billion &#x2013; &#x20AC;1.081 billon, which is due to higher wholesale borrowing costs, &#x20AC;71 million in both long and short-term borrowing. And there is also the impact, &#x20AC;10 million because of the reduction in the returns on the ALCO account and that's behind that figure &#x20AC;10 million.</p>
          <p>So there's been a reduction because of the divestment we made as we realized capital gains at the beginning of the year as we anticipated the high volatility on the debt market, which we did indeed see.</p>
          <p>And as for higher interest rates, if we look at the euro balance sheet, we have a negative sensitivity only about 3%. That's not very high, that's the one-year rates. And the sensitivity is changing bit by bit. So that we can protect our self against possible rises in short-term rates, so a drop of 100 basis points in interest rates.</p>
          <p>Well, if you look on the curve as a whole that would generate a 3% increase in our euro balance sheet figure. And as &#xC1;ngel said before, the way that margins are behaving in Spain and outside Spain are rather different, very positive margin growth in all the franchises in Mexico and in South America and also with upside because of the structural kind of spreads we have even in the United States. And you can't all together see them because of the change in mix that we're seeing in our books. But as the second part of 2011 opens up, we'll actually see that having a real impact on our accounts. So that's quite different from what's happening here in Spain.</p>
          <p>In Spain, however, things are definitely going to improve for everyone and they've been much better for us than any of our peers in Spain. Anyway, if you look at the net interest income in the corporate center, we can say that in an environment of progressively higher short-term rates, although we're not expecting them to go a lot higher, we can expect that the contribution of our financial management portfolios, that is the ALCO portfolios, will be reduced over time and wholesale funding is becoming more important. But that's very, very relevant, because we're not very dependent on the wholesale markets.</p>
          <p>I mean, if I have to estimate this, let's say, we've got maturities on medium to long-term books of about &#x20AC;11.9 billion and there could be an increase, of course, if we completely renew these issues, we'd be talking about the 150 basis points on the average costs we have at the moment. So we'd be talking about &#x20AC;180 million, &#x20AC;190 million, which could come in through this channel, if the rates stay at about the levels they are which isn't something that we're expecting to happen.</p>
          <p>As to the ALCO portfolio, at the moment if we look at the euro balance, the portfolio is &#x20AC;27 billion with a maturity of three years. In Mexico, the portfolio is &#x20AC;8.5 billion with the maturity of 2.6 and we've got a portfolio in the United States of &#x20AC;6.2 billion. So all of these account value is in euros with the maturity of about 2.6. So we can see that the total volumes of the ALCO portfolios are going down almost everywhere.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two more questions, which I think have been answered, but just in case you want to clarify them in this block from Carlo Di Grandi, HSBC. So I think you've answered this, but he is asking about, why we are seeing a lower fall off than our peers. Do we have better funding costs, or is our capacity to reprice higher or is there another reason?</p>
          <p>Hector Martinez also asks about what quarter we would expect net interest income to hit rock bottom in Spain and Portugal. I think you've answered those questions. But if want to say anything about it you can?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When we were talking about the performance in the deposit side, we compared 4.8% in the drop in net interest income in Spain with our rivals, sort of, falling about 15%. But I also said that between 50 and 60 basis points was the lower cost in our liability side in the second half of our year since our rivals from the beginning of the year, when they started to pay. So the main effect can be explained by this. It's true, there's also a positive effect that we will see to a greater extent in 2011, which is the repricing of assets as they mature.</p>
          <p>And with regard to bottoming out, I think we covered this. Apart from small nuances, I think the fourth quarter was slightly below the third quarter, but only just, and I think this is the way we're going looking forward. I think the fourth quarter could be the value or the bottoming out or may be the first or second quarter of 2011. We're talking about very similar performance over the next two quarters, and then from the third quarter onwards, our forecasts based on current information with regard to cost of deposits and spreads. This would indicate that the third quarter of 2011 is when we're going to see them picking up. If costs dropped below the levels that we see today then maybe the net interest income could start picking up a little bit soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to provisions and assets qualities. There are several questions concerning the cost of risk in Spain and provisions. Patrick Lee from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale, his question is whether the booking you've done of 350 million in the fourth quarter, which is very high in comparison with the underlying &#x2013; and of the last &#x2013; average of the last three quarters is this the new run rate for this year or would we get back to the normal of between the first and third quarter of 2010 that's sort of rate.</p>
          <p>Then Benjie Creelan from Macquarie asks about the new entries in NPAs are higher since the end of 2009. And what is the driver of this situation and what can we expect for 2011, it's very similar to the previous question.</p>
          <p>Claire Kane, from MF Global asks which do we think &#x2013; what do we think the cost of risk is going to be in Spain, is it going to drop in 2011?</p>
          <p>And Britta Schmidt from Autonomous asks what the forecast is for provisioning for 2011? We're seeing major increases in write-offs and if this is so, will this have an impact in reducing NPAs by writing them off?</p>
          <p>Chandra-Rajan from Barclays with regard to asset quality and provisions with regard to the new entries that have grown &#x2013; new entries to NPAs have shown a significant rise. Is this due to a specific sector or segment of customers?</p>
          <p>And Raoul Leonard from the Royal Bank of Scotland asks about the new entries to NPAs in the fourth quarter. There seems to be a pronounced increase, when is this going to peak, when are we going to see the peak in NPAs in the group and in Spain? What are expectations for 2011 for provisioning and loss loan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. There was a slight increase in the last quarter &#x2013; in the run rate, but it's not something that we can automatically forecast for the future, because at the end of the year that tends to be a blip anyway.</p>
          <p>What's important is the provisioning. We've done a lot of provisioning in the final quarter for real estate assets, above all in the last quarter, we could talk of provisioning of about more than &#x20AC;300 million, just in the final quarter for that one item. And that's just for credit provisioning. And there is nothing special there apart from that slight increase in the real estate assets, which would not compare against all the other quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I could add something to that Manuel. At year end, we always review the different portfolios, especially the key ones, which are things like the developer loan books where for one-off reasons there is some 400 millions of one-off entries. And I really mean one-off.</p>
          <p>And in no way do they establish any tendency or trend for 2011. And anyway the figures are very much lower than what we had at the end of the previous year. We're talking about one-off cases with very specific names attached to them and the general impact has been an impact to the whole system, but the advantage we have over others is that because we did the analysis at the end of the previous year anyway, it didn't really significantly increase our exposure. We were talking about 21%, 21.3% as the ratio on our developers' book and we came from about 17% a year before and you may remember that a year ago, we were talking about an average in the system of about 9%.</p>
          <p>We were all expecting to see these problems as the real underlying problems of this sector came to light. And in the presentations, we've been talking about that and it's just continued to happen as we're expecting. So we've just had two updates, very specific accounts with specific customers and that shouldn't have an impact at all on the 2011 figures.</p>
          <p>We think that the NPAs should stabilize. In fact, there might be a reduction in the total balance for the group as a whole. And our forecast for 2011 is that we will continue to see increasing the positive news on this ratio.</p>
          <p>You asked about our charge-offs. It's true that because we haven't done any non-natural charge-offs, we have slightly below 2 billion of our NPAs, which have 100% coverage ratio.</p>
          <p>Nonetheless, we do have to charge-off things in certain accounts quarter-by-quarter, and we prefer that the improvement of the NPA &#x2013; balances in NPA ratios should follow the natural tendency.</p>
          <p>The cost of risk in 2011, earlier on we gave you a very relevant fact about the behavior of our provisions in 2011 and we've said that the cost of risk specifically to Spain, and you saw that it went down to 1.1 for the year as a whole. What does that mean? Well, it means that probably, we have bottomed out in specific and generic provisions that we have to set aside in Spain.</p>
          <p>So at the moment, allocations to provisions could be necessary because of the overall drop that we're seeing in the level of our specific provisions. So in 2011, we can say we will have stable provisioning, a slight drop-off as we see the impact of the lower levels of NPA ratios. At 11, we were meant to finish our webcast, but really there are so many questions, that perhaps we should add on another 15, 20 minutes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Next set of matters is liquidity capital, Carlo Di Grandi from HSBC. The ratio of loans to deposits in the group was 130 going to 123 in the final quarter. Do you have any target for 2011 for the ratio? What would be the optimum ratio that you think we should have, given the current market conditions at the moment?</p>
          <p> Pablo L&#xF3;pez Cobo from Investment, asks about what we are doing in the clearing table and those like the London Clearing House what are we doing there? And do we think that issues of covered bonds with spreads of about 220 basis points are reasonably -or are reasonable and are they sustainable in the medium term.</p>
          <p>Antonio Ramirez from Keefe, asks about maturities of debt in 2011 and 2012, are you going to bring forward any of them into the next two years?</p>
          <p>And Raoul Leonard from Royal Bank of Scotland says that in the domestic market that is in Spain there is a tendency for growth in public sector loans. How sustainable is that in the medium term? Why have we had this increase in the loans that we're giving to the public administrations? And he also asks about the terms on wholesale funding. If wholesale borrowing is still expensive how much margin do we have to go out to other markets to avoid the very expensive long-term markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, Carlo Di Grandi's question. I'm not quite sure where he gets his loan-to-deposit ratio from I imagine he is talking about those group in Spain. Loan-to-deposits in the group as &#xC1;ngel has said before &#x2013; sorry, deposits to total assets at the moment we're talking about 49.9%. And if we talk to about loan-to-deposits the bank currently has an excess of deposits over loans or a surplus, I understand he is talking about Spain and in Spain we have our commercial business where we have no kind of liquidity and the group has the deposit balance which covers our lending.</p>
          <p>And the wholesale midterm and long-term financing covers all our mid to long-term lending, basically this comes from individual mortgages. So the balance in the structure of our liquidity is very consistent and totally sustainable over time.</p>
          <p>So this gives us no &#x2013; this is no source of concern at the moment. The cost of wholesale financing for the bank at the moment, we're talking about part of the balance, the small part of the balance, if we look at the total balance or our dependency on wholesale bankings if we compare them with the main European banks.</p>
          <p>The situation with record to spreads in corporate bonds, for issuers at the moment such as first top quality Spaniards such as ourself if they're reasonable and sustainable here what we're looking at is sovereign risk. We're issuing spreads of treasury bonds at minimum spreads, but obviously we get a knock-on effect from the sovereign debts and the market seems to consider the government's measures to be reasonable, so is improving the situation of the sovereign risk.</p>
          <p>The bank irrespective of the performance of the spreads and how they offer, the bank is a traditional issuer in mid and long-term placement and maturities in answer to your question of &#x20AC;11.9 billion and &#x20AC;8 billion for rest of 2011 and &#x20AC;8 billion for 2012. So we've got a very low need to renew these, unlike the situation in the industry as a whole. And basically we can totally renew our wholesale funding. And the maximum impact this would have on the net interest income is well within our capacity with regards to the growth in customer deposit or from the point of view of the wait of short-term financing, which at the moment is a very small proportion of our financing, and this has also been reduced in recent months.</p>
          <p>So, if we look at 2010 here in Spain, we've grown &#x2013; the average deposit balance has grown by &#x20AC;20 billion. And the maturities for mid to long-term, we have &#x20AC;11.9 billion. So even if we didn't make any further issues, we can finance these maturities with the growth in customer deposits without any problem.</p>
          <p>So the figures are totally sustainable and to give you &#x2013; to prove &#x2013; to show you this, I give you two figures exposure to the ECB or dependency on ECB, which is zero, December 2010. Not just zero, but we also have &#x2013; we have our deposits with ECB at &#x20AC;2.7 billion at the end of the year with &#x20AC;70 billion in available collateral, which shows the strength of our position. We're not using sources of finances, they are available to us, though not to other issuers then talking about short term with lower cost. And we have quite a large margin to handle all of this.</p>
          <p>I think that answers the questions. With regard to the clearing houses, the clearing house is just a normal activity. And what's happening is a business opportunity for our markets unit to intermediate or to mediate by temporary acquisitions and temporary sessions to entities that have no access to the clearing house. But this is just a business deal, a one-off deal. So it's not a specific change in policy with regard to clearing activities.</p>
          <p>Capital adequacy, practically all these questions concern the bank's situation in terms of Basel layer III.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>F&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric from Natixis asks for our forecast about on core capital in basis points that we can generate over the next two years. And maybe we can give some detail about the growth over the last quarter in risk weighted assets.</p>
          <p>Andrea Filtri from Mediobanca asked the same thing and Samuel Lopez from Vanguard also asks about the core capital that we presented of 9.6%. Is this under Basel layer II, what would the number be under the criteria Basel III?</p>
          <p>Neil Smith asks about the impact of our financial investments in institutions in accordance with Basel III in comparison with Basel II? And whether this is included in our guidance on the impact of Basel III, we're talking about less than 100 basis points that has been mentioned?</p>
          <p>Rohith Chandra-Rajan from Barclays asks what our core capital or the level of core capital that BBVA will be comfortable with?</p>
          <p>And Francisco Riquel from N+1 asks for an additional explanation about the performance in the movements of core capital in the course of 2010 and the organic generation in coming quarters? This has also been asked by other analyst and the impact on Basel III, with regard to capital ratios that has also been asked before?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay then, let's take the questions one by one, there were so many, I've hardly been able to write them all down, but you can jog my memory, if I miss any. So first question, the impact of Basel III on the figures that we're reporting for core capital. Well, as we said, we are thinking of impacts of about 60 basis points at the moment because of rolling out Basel III for our core capital that is. And we think these impacts, of course, it would depend on the growth of P/E ratios. It could be 55, they could be 70, but probably not much more variation and anyway the impacts could be absorbed by our organic generation of capital from now to 2019.</p>
          <p>We think that these impacts will probably be felt as of 2013, 2014 with a gradual phase out depending on what happens. It's probably about 10% to 15% a year, and so we're not thinking that these impacts are going to hit us all of a sudden on day one.</p>
          <p>So really we don't perceive any problem of applying Basel III to the bank, quite the opposite. We think that the bank will come out better under Basel III because of our business model, which is quite different from our peers. It's based on relational banking with our customers. Even in the wholesale markets we've got an international focus, so we're diversified. And balance has limited leverage with contained costs anyway, we will look better than others with the new regulations.</p>
          <p>As to our capacity to generate capital organically, well for some time we've been talking about some 20 basis points in an environment of low growth quarter-by-quarter, which will mean organic growth of 80 basis points with our current payout forecast in the environment of slightly more growth than we've been seeing last year. Especially in our franchisees outside Spain, where we'd be talking about organic generation of capital going down about 60 basis points with a more active dynamic as the APRs grow &#x2013; sorry, the risk weighted assets grow.</p>
          <p>In these scenarios, we'll include the impact of our financial investments which would be about 38 basis points and that would be probably the most important for us. In terms of risk weighted assets, in the quarter, we've got figures, let's have a look. Yes, risk weighted assets, we've got a growth, I think, quarter-on-quarter in the fourth quarter against the third quarter of 2.3%. 0.6% of this 2.3%, that is 0.6 of 2.3 is associated to foreign currency and our Forex rate and the rest is associated to real growth of our lending business, which as you saw is growing in general in all the franchises and even growing slightly in Spain.</p>
          <p>So that's really explanation behind what's happening to risk weighted assets at the end of the year. In the year as a whole, they've gone up 7.6%, &#x20AC;22 billion, so as a whole then that's &#x20AC;8 billion are associated to the Forex exchange rates and then the rest is associated to an improvement in our business volumes.</p>
          <p>Finally, I think the only question I haven't answered is from, the one from N+1. Riquel talked about this, as he talked about the impact of the capital increase with &#x2013; on the &#x2013; on the risk weighted assets at the end of the year, the organic growth has generated 70 basis points, net of &#x2013; well through retained earnings against the organic growth in risk weighted assets and there are various impacts that we have to take into account.</p>
          <p>They had different kinds of impacts, but that's another 60 basis points of core capital absorbed, some have to do with the acquisition of 5% more in CITIC, and the devaluation in Venezuela. And the increase of our structural position for Forex risk with the hedging we've got in order to be able to cover the dollar payment for our acquisition in Turkey and then other things which are related to regulatory issues. But they are not so important. So that really is what's behind the 0.60 figures. We've got 10 questions now in the next 10 minutes. So one minute for each question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Antonio Ramirez from Keefe asks about how we are positioned, if the Spanish system is restructured and the sayings banks out there, are they going to be bought up? Obviously there is the recapitulation from the fund. Will there be any kind of sharing agreement, would the market share change here in Spain?</p>
          <p>And Andrea Filtri from Mediobanca asks about &#x2013; well it's more or less the same. What our position would be as that we see changes in the system of savings banks and listed banks here in Spain.</p>
          <p>Claire Kane from Global, yes, pretty well asks the same. After the statement made by the Minister of Finance, what's our position with respect to the knock-on effect of the draft world decree which should be enacted quite soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Restructuring, what we're witnessing is the implementation of the restructuring that we've been talking about for the last year and a half basically. And since the end of last year we're started to see that some of the initiatives that has been rolled out by the financial systems are being rolled out. And basically I'm talking about the close of branches, the closure of branches and the reduction of manpower, or manning levels and what we're going to see over the next few months is how the new financial system takes place based on new banks rather than on old savings banks.</p>
          <p>But in any kind of situation, I think to a greater or lesser extent, all of these are going to have to reduce the number of branches and reduce their manning levels to conform to a new standard.</p>
          <p>With regards to our position, we've been telling you this. It's very clear to us we want to benefit from any opportunity that emerges or appears in the market from this restructuring position and for now, it means that we're gaining market share both in loans and deposits.</p>
          <p>So apart from gaining market share, we're also attracting new customers to add to the ones we've already got. And we're considering major gains in our market share over the next three years. And I'm talking about a major market share, so I'm talking about a minimum of 50% more than what we have at the moment. We think that we can do that in the current situation.</p>
          <p>If on top of this management policy that we have in an area where we know exactly what's going on where in-store capacity is being reduced if an additional opportunity appears to analyze one of these banks, obviously we have to analyze this from the point of view of generating value, obviously.</p>
          <p>And this means that the conditions would have to be that it would not mean reducing the capital adequacy of our group at all. So if there is an opportunity that does generate value, we will analyze it in detail of course but we won't feel any commitment of any kind to go into a deal because we have no commitments of any kind to form part of this process beyond coming out of the situation stronger.</p>
          <p>So that is our mid to long-term position. We are willing to analyze any possible opportunity, but I repeat, we will be very demanding it has &#x2013; it would have to generate value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>M&amp;A strategies, we have several questions some of which have been answered by the COE. Marzello from Bernstein, he assumes that the management will reinforce their capital ratios before entering into any inorganic operation in 2011?</p>
          <p>Second question from Benjie Creelan from Macquarie. After purchasing guarantee, are we thinking of any acquisitions for 2011, but focus more on the EAGLE countries? And also concerning is, Alejandro Ruyra from Kepler who asks whether we're thinking about any inorganic acquisition in Spain as a way of increasing our market share which is what &#xC1;ngel has just replied to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as we have to shore up capital &#x2013; shoring up capital ratios for our inorganic operations in 2011. And I said when I ended the presentation that we have certain management priorities, which are pretty clear.</p>
          <p>First of all, to reinforce the franchises, where we're already operating with this new focus that we've got now in Turkey and we want to be able to go on getting more value out of these markets, so that we can add to the group revenues as a whole.</p>
          <p>So we'll grow in Turkey, consolidate our model in the USA, that's a clear priority. Before I said that in 2011, we're going to see significant growth in earnings there, still below what we're expecting in the long term, but nonetheless significant growth.</p>
          <p>And in Spain we think that there are going to be a lot of opportunities because everything is very open now. And we're very well positioned and we have a very good knowledge about what is going on in Spain and which savings banks are doing what, we have enough money, we have a lot of in-store capacity in our branch office network to be able to take up these bigger opportunities that will come up with all our local knowledge.</p>
          <p>So we're going to analyze any opportunities that might come up, but if we do so we are always &#x2013; be after value and there are no pre-established ideas about what we might do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then there are four or five questions left now, so I'm going to group them together. They have to with guidance for 2011. Marzello Zanardo from Bernstein, asks about our outlook, prognosis for lending margins in Spain and Portugal for 2011 and for the rest of the group.</p>
          <p>Neil Smith from West Capital asks about our main concern for 2011, what would worry us most and what might be the biggest impact on our bottom line?</p>
          <p>Arturo de frias from Evolution, Arturo asks for comments about the group's profit, what kind of levels are we expecting to see in 2011? He says that the consensus is about &#x20AC;5 billion. Do we feel comfortable with that consensus? How much growth do we expect to see in 2011?</p>
          <p>Francisco Riquel from N+1 says that last year targets were given for the U.S. and Asia that would be about 15% to 18% of the group profits for 2011. Do you want to update that outlook that you gave a year ago, are we still aiming at the same kind of percentages?</p>
          <p>And then another question is the only one that we've got, which is why I want to end on it on real estate. It comes from the Daiwa Group asking about coverage ratio for developers in Spain. Where would we expect our coverage ratio to stand for the property business in developer loans in Spain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So those were pretty well all of the questions. If there any more detailed ones they will be covered by our investor relations team during the day. There are a few questions that have come in about the different business areas, but time is just too tight. So really we can only cover these four or five questions taking us up to quarter past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all our guidance, as you know, we don't usually give guidance and I'm not going to change that policy now. But having said that I will offer our best opinion of what we think is going to happen in 2011. Business volumes, this I'm mentioning, because I think it was Arturo de frias who asked for our opinion about the &#x20AC;5 billion in profits at the end of 2011, which is what I've just answered.</p>
          <p>With regard to business volumes and net interest income, first of all, I'll give you an overview of what we expect to see in the group. I think about 6%, 7% is an average for the group as a whole. Obviously, this will vary according to the geography. A reasonably flat in the U.S. and Spain on the basis that our expectations for the system as a whole, both in Spain and the U.S., where we have forecasts of a fall of around 4% or 5% in either of these geographies or both of them. But we'll probably see growth of around 15% or above in Mexico and South America, which will confirm the trend that we're seeing at the end of last year.</p>
          <p>This means that once again we will have a net interest income that as Manuel explained, that has varied in its performance. If we look at Spain, we heard that in 2010 the net interest income has dropped off, especially after the second quarter where the cost of deposits started to fall and in 2011, we think the reverse is true. It's going to start picking up. The first two quarters will be similar to the last quarter and then in the third, fourth quarter it's going to pick up. That's the Spain.</p>
          <p>But for the &#x2013; in America, Mexico and South America, I think we're going to see growth quarter after quarter in each of these areas. So, I think the positive effects from America are going to offset the negative or the initially negative and later on neutral effects that we'll see in Spain and the U.S.</p>
          <p>Objectives for 2011 for USA and the Asia, initially we talked about three years for USA and Asia not 2011 and Asia will start with the figures that we're starting to see confirmation of. That we saw in the presentation, we talked about &#x20AC;425 million from Asia in profits. Three quarters of this profit came from major growth and sustained growth in &#x2013; from our investment in China. But Asia, that's the way Asia is going from the point of view of our investment in CITIC, but also organic growth through the different business areas, and the products that we're rolling out in Asia through branches in Singapore, Sydney, Taiwan et cetera.</p>
          <p>USA, I said before that we're consolidating and the figures are improving. We're starting to see clear improvements in the U.S. franchise. We saw growth percentages in new production, especially business consumer, especially domestic mortgages. And thanks to having done our homework, we clearly improved the mix of the business that we have on the asset side of Compass. And I think this has been completed by the close of 2010, which means we're starting to consolidate significant growth in earnings in 2011 in order to reach the percentage mentioned by Thomas. We're not going to reach that, but from 2012 or maybe even 2013, but I doubt, it's not going to be 2011, where we will see major growth, but not the sort of growth we were forecasting. But the forecast, I think will be attained in 2012 or maybe the first part of 2013 we'll be consolidating high digits from the U.S.</p>
          <p>The coverage ratio for real estates, there are two coverage ratios that have appeared in the presentation, one was for properties the &#x20AC;4.8 billion in properties bought in Spain with a coverage ratio of over 33% of the assets acquired. The coverage for 2011 is going to be around there, maybe slightly higher depending on what the prospects for sales of these assets will be.</p>
          <p>One thing we didn't mention was that in 2010 we sold some &#x20AC;550 million worth of these assets and the net result, it's true that we factor in the provisions, I think it's around &#x20AC;60 million. So there's no reason, why we should think that we're going to need significantly higher provisions than what we already have and neither do we think that we're going to generate any great capital gains from these assets. But we're going to &#x2013; the capital gain should offset, but with a coverage ratio of 33%, I think this reflects the market valuation of these assets.</p>
          <p>Developers now, the presentation showed there is 25% coverage ratio. And these days certainly covers the value of the guarantees that underlie them. Manuel mentioned how about a quarter of the assets underlying these loans are land and most of the land are &#x2013; is land that can be developed.</p>
          <p>I think there is just under 5% of land that cannot be developed is greenbelt. But the rest are either developed or can be developed. And if we &#x2013; and this of course &#x2013; with this 25% this covers our needs for coverage for the developers' portfolio assuming that what we've presented to-date is the lowest wait of developers of any bank in Spain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's the end of the webcast. So, I'd just like to thank you for coming along. And I would like to remind you that our Investor Relations team will answer any questions that haven't &#x2013; we haven't been able to answer here due to lack of time.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>