<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1525172" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-02-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1556</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Thane Fotopoulos</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Vice-President and Chief Financial Officer">Siim A. Vanaselja</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President and Chief Executive Officer">George Alexander Cope</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. I'm Thane Fotopoulos, the Vice President of Investor Relations at BCE. And on behalf of the entire Bell executive leadership team here today, I want to welcome you to our 2013 Investor Day Conference.</p>
          <p>It's been a few years since we met in this kind of forum, four years to be exact. And a lot of progress has been made in those four years in growing the business and delivering value to BCE shareholders. And we're here to tell you about that and, more importantly, how we intend to keep that up going forward.</p>
          <p>We're happy to have this opportunity here this morning to give you an in-depth update on our strategies and plans for 2013. However, before we get started, I'd like to remind you that today's event will be webcast. Links to the webcast along with all supporting materials are on BCE's Investor Relations webpage. And of course, I also need to cover the Safe Harbor notice which is up behind me on the screen.</p>
          <p>Today's presentation and comments will contain forward-looking statements that represent our expectations as of today and accordingly are subject to change. We do not undertake any obligation to update any forward-looking statement except as may be required by Canadian Securities laws. A number of assumptions were made by us in preparing these forward-looking statements, which are subject to risks. Results may differ materially. Details on these risks and assumptions are in our filings with the Canadian Securities Commission and with the SEC which are all found on our website.</p>
          <p>We have a great agenda for you today as you can see here. So let me quickly cover that with you before we begin. We'll start off with an overview from our CFO, Siim Vanaselja, on our Q4 results that were just released this morning as well as our 2013 financial guidance targets. Siim will be followed by our President and CEO, George Cope, who will give you a strategic overview and update of our key business initiatives including a Wireline &#x2013; comprehensive Wireline overview. Then Mary Ann Turcke and John Watson, our respective EVPs of Field Services and Customer Operations, will cover our service agenda and the strides we've made in that space in making, in positioning Bell rather, the leader in customer service.</p>
          <p>We'll then take a short 15-minute break and after the break, Wade Oosterman, our President of Bell Mobility and Bell Residential Services, will come on and discuss the growth opportunities that are available to Bell in the Wireless sector. Next, our Chief Technology Officer, Stephen Howe, will talk to you about our Wireline and Wireless platforms and how we're leveraging those networks to support the overall growth of the business.</p>
          <p>And last but not least, Kevin W. Crull, our President of Bell Media, will provide an overview of the Media segment, our newest segment in the company and he'll tell you the value that that asset has brought to us since we acquired CTV back in 2011. We'll then wrap it up with all the presenters in a Q&amp;A session at the end of the morning. So as you can see, quite a busy agenda and I hope you'll find the day very informative and useful. And on that note, I'll invite Siim to come up on stage and start off the presentations for us. So, thanks again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Thane. Good morning, everyone. We are really happy to have this opportunity today to share our strategic plans and our financial outlook with you this morning. What I'm going to do is start with our fourth quarter financial highlights, which we released this morning. I'd say our operations delivered on a steady course with quite a strong contribution from both Wireless and Media. Total service revenue growth in the quarter of 0.3% represents a healthy revenue growth across our growth businesses, across Wireless TV, Internet and Media and that was offset by lower business data product sales and ongoing Voice decline.</p>
          <p>Sales EBITDA grew nicely, 2.2% in the fourth quarter and that increase was driven by our Wireless segment which posted great EBITDA performance. Wireline's EBITDA decline was pretty much in line with what we saw in the third quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated margin at Bell expanded 80 basis points. That was on improved service margins both in Wireless and in Media. At the EPS level, BCE's statutory EPS in the fourth quarter was $0.91 per share. That's up from $0.62 per share a year ago and that increase reflects an addition to higher EBITDA, lower year-over-year severance costs and as well we had in the quarter a one-time non-cash gain that we realized on the transfer of Spectrum from Inukshuk out to its respective shareholders.</p>
          <p>When we look at adjusted EPS in the quarter, increased 4.8% to $0.65 per share. And I'll highlight that our effective tax rate this quarter was just below the statutory rate and that's because the Inukshuk Spectrum gain that we realized was non-taxable. I'll also say that there were no tax provision adjustments this quarter.</p>
          <p>On free cash flow, our operations generated over $600 million in the quarter representing growth of 7.3%. I think that supports the high level of capital investment we had in our businesses and at the same time, it further strengthens our balance sheet and our financial position as we move into 2013.</p>
          <p>Let me turn to our operating results, beginning with Wireless. Postpaid subscriber growth was certainly again one of the highlights in the quarter. Postpaid net adds of 144,000 up 9% year-over-year. We believe Bell Mobility again captured an attractive market share of net postpaids in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>Higher year-over-year postpaid gross adds were led by strong sales of Apple's iPhone 5 as well as the wide lineup of Android devices that the Bell stores carry. Smartphone subscribers now account for about 64% of our postpaid base. That's up significantly since the end of 2011 where we stood at about 48%. And as you know, these are premium customers with higher ARPU and lower churn.</p>
          <p>Wireless ARPU increased 4.1% in the quarter. And with that we've now had three consecutive years of ARPU growth. In this intensely competitive fourth quarter of sales, we're also pleased to report that we saw a 20 basis point improvement in postpaid churn to 1.3%. And Wireless retention spending in the quarter increased to 12% of service revenues as we matched some of the richer acquisition offers that were in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>On the financial side, Wireless service revenue growth accelerated to 7.4%. That was driven by data revenues, which were up 28% in the quarter and data revenues now account for close to 40% of our Wireless ARPU. Wireless EBITDA was another highlight in the quarter growing 13.8% year-over-year and that's our best fourth quarter Wireless growth in six years. A good result, I think, having given that we spent an incremental $26 million or so on acquisition and retention in the quarter.</p>
          <p>The quarter's performance brought Bell's Wireless EBITDA growth for 2012 to 15.7% and our Wireless service margin for the year expanded 3.3 points to 41.5%. Wireless EBITDA less CapEx also provided a strong contribution free cash flow both in the quarter and for the full year.</p>
          <p>So overall our Wireless position is very well positioned as we head into 2013 and you'll hear more about that from Wade and George.</p>
          <p>Let's move now to our Wireline operations. On the residential side, the quarter was really about Fibe TV I'd say and the strong attach rates that we're seeing with other Bell services. Fibe TV posted a record 48,000 net customer additions in the quarter and we closed 2012 with 248,000 total Fibe TV customers. That gives us an 8% penetration rate of IPTV homes passed and I think we're really pleased with that performance, the steady gain in penetration we're seeing, recognizing that this is all still at a very early stage.</p>
          <p>Satellite TV net adds continue to be impacted by the expansion of competitors' IPTV networks in Western Canada and in Atlantic Canada and as well we're seeing Bell customer migrations from satellite TV to Fibe TV that are running at about 15% of Fibe TV gross adds. We're also seeing great three-product household penetration with about 84% of Bell's Fibe TV customer base also taking Internet and home phone. Internet net adds overall, I'd say, were soft throughout 2012. I do want to say, however, that we expect that to pick up particularly as our fibre footprint and our IPTV penetration increase.</p>
          <p>In the quarter, residential NAS erosion show improvement and we're definitely seeing a significant reduction in NAS losses in our IPTV footprint compared to areas outside of that footprint and therefore our strategy remains very squarely focused on continuing to grow that footprint and drive higher levels of penetration.</p>
          <p>On the business side of Wireline, I want to highlight that about half of the NAS losses that we've seen overall for 2012 were due to wholesale customer deactivations with one particular reseller. So if we look at Bell branded NAS losses, in fact those have remained relatively stable throughout the year.</p>
          <p>Looking at the financials for Wireline, the pace of revenue decline in the quarter improved. It was driven by TV revenue growth of 5.2% and a slowing Voice erosion. Data revenue performance in the quarter was really similar to what we've seen throughout the year with TV growth being offset by lower data product sales and repricing pressures that we've seen in the business market.</p>
          <p>So Wireline's EBITDA decline in the quarter was 6.6%. However, we did incur a $9 million charge relating to the CRTC's decision to reduce rates on local loops and they introduced that decision to lower rates on a retroactive basis back to December of 2009, so that whole $9 million charge came through this quarter. Excluding that charge, Bell's year-over-year Wireline EBITDA decline, in fact, improved by about 50 basis points over the third quarter.</p>
          <p>For 2012 overall Bell's Wireline EBITDA margin was relatively stable at 38.4%. We saw good operating expense reductions and good productivity performance particularly in our call centers and in our field center operations. In 2013, we expect growth services to become a larger component of our Wireline mix with a stronger contribution from TV and Internet and a gradual improvement in business markets.</p>
          <p>Bell Media has become such an integral part of Bell's overall operations and financial performance. For the quarter, subscriber revenue growth at Bell Media was up 7% year-over-year led by higher specialty programming rates and I'll add that we do expect to see some more modest rate increases on specialty rate programming throughout the course of 2013, consistent with the new broadcast rate agreements that we've entered into.</p>
          <p>Advertising revenue in the quarter, however, decreased by about 1%. That was expected and it was due to the NHL hockey lock out which impacted advertising revenues both at TSN and RDS. That pressure, however, was offset pretty much by quite a good shift in advertising demand both to our conventional networks and to our non-sports specialty networks. With the flow through of higher subscriber revenues and revenues in lower programming cost because of the hockey lock out, Bell Media's EBITDA grew quite significantly by 32%. And EBITDA on free cash flow, if we exclude the non-cash purchase price adjustment amortization, we saw Bell's EBITDA of $199 million in the quarter and EBITDA of $610 million for the full year. Remarkably, that's about 75% higher than the EBITDA of CTV at the time of our acquisition back in April of 2011. So that's it on the quarter.</p>
          <p>2012 as a full year altogether, I would say, was very successful for Bell. We achieved on our full year revenue guidance and surpassed our EBITDA guidance with 4.4% growth. We saw an increase in contribution from our growth services. We were successful in reducing costs and with that we expanded Bell's consolidated EBITDA margin to 37.4%. We increased our EPS guidance during the course of the year and we achieved that increased guidance. And we finished the year with a strong 7% overall growth in free cash flow which totaled more than $2.4 billion.</p>
          <p>All of that gives Bell's strong operating cash flow and it enables us to move up our capital intensity during the year to 16.6%, increasing our spending on strategic priorities. So all in all, 2012 had good performance and I think puts us into a really good starting position for 2013.</p>
          <p>With that, let me move to our capital markets model. And I have to say it really is pretty simple. We are looking to deliver sustainable shareholder returns through reliable dividend growth and that objective is underpinned all the while by maintaining healthy levels of growth and investment in our capital investment programs and maintaining a strong balance sheet with solid investment grade credit metrics.</p>
          <p>Importantly as well, we have strong alignment of interests now between our shareholders and our management long-term incentive plan. That plan has vesting criteria which is tied to the company's ability to execute on its dividend growth model. So simply put, as we grow our free cash flow, we're able to grow our dividend, our common dividend, and therefore we create value for shareholders and management alike.</p>
          <p>Now we've had a successful track record as a dividend growth company. This morning we announced a further $0.06 common share dividend increase, which is our ninth consecutive dividend increase since the fourth quarter of 2008. In total, we've grown our common dividend 60% over that period and we have one of the best yields on the TSX today. Together with a $0.10 dividend increase that we announced this past August, BCE's common dividend for 2013 is up 7.5% or $0.16 per share. And I think that's a strong reflection of the confidence that we have in our business performance and our free cash flow generation.</p>
          <p>With this dividend, we expect to maintain BCE's payout ratio just below the midpoint of our target range of 65% to 75% of free cash flow. And you'll know that we have been presenting BCE's dividend payout ratio on the basis of both free cash flow and EPS and those payouts have always been very comparable. So I want to draw to your attention today that beginning in 2013, we will start expressing our dividend payouts solely on the basis of a free cash flow payout. And this change is necessary because of the noncash impact that results from the new IFRS pension accounting standard, which comes into effect in 2013, and I'll talk about that standard in a moment.</p>
          <p>On a free cash flow basis, our common dividend payout policy will continue to be maintained at the range of 65% to 75%. And I say that because our pension accounting change is entirely a noncash change, we think that a free cash flow dividend payout policy is a much better economic measure to use.</p>
          <p>Importantly, our dividend payout preserves a very high level of cash generation for the company to deploy giving us excellent overall financial flexibility. Surplus cash amounts to about $800 million a year for us, and I think we've always been pretty balanced in how we've directed that surplus cash and how we've deployed it. Over the last four years, we've made $2.75 billion in voluntary contributions to our pension plan. That ensures that our pension plans have maintained a very high funded status, and it really minimizes the ongoing volatility of our pension funding requirement.</p>
          <p>We've also returned $1.7 billion in value to our shareholders through share buyback programs, and we've enjoyed a remarkable payback on that investment. And we've made strategic acquisitions that you know of, particularly CTV, The Source, Virgin, MLSE, The Montr&#xE9;al Canadiens and Q9. And we've executed all of those actions while maintaining an overall credit profile that's consistent with our credit objectives.</p>
          <p>For 2013, talking about excess cash, our plans will be to deploy that cash towards the purchase of wireless spectrum in the upcoming 700 MHz spectrum auctions that are slated for the fourth quarter of this year. Our capital structure, I think provides us with quite a solid foundation and a very high level of overall financial flexibility.</p>
          <p>Our credit ratings all have stable outlooks and we expect our credit ratios to improve over time as we grow our EBITDA and as we grow our free cash flow. I also want to say that I think Bell is very well positioned with an attractive long-term debt maturity schedule. As you see on the slide, our average term of debt is approximately 10 years. Over the past four years, we've taken advantage of low interest rates to reduce our cost of debt by about 200 basis points with our average after-tax cost of debt today being about 3.9%. And I think you should expect us to continue being opportunistic in pursuing those type of refinancing actions as we see opportunities for them. We also maintain committed lines of credit giving us access to over $3 billion of liquidity should we need it.</p>
          <p>And finally, you'll know that our history of financial management has always been a prudent one and that's not going to change.</p>
          <p>So let me turn to our financial guidance for 2013. First, I'd say that with the transformation of our operating mix more and more towards growth services and away from Wireline voice, we expect Bell revenue growth of up to 2% in 2013. Our consolidated operating margin should be stable resulting in Bell EBITDA growth of 1.3% and that should then translate to growth in free cash flow of 5% to 9%.</p>
          <p>We're looking to manage Bell's capital intensity in 2013 at around 16% to 17% of revenues and that will allow increased spending to expand our IPTV footprint, to begin implementing pair bonding, to extend our urban LTE build out and to meet growth in demand. At the BCE consolidated level, our guidance is for adjusted EPS of $2.97 to $3.03 per share and that reflects the new accounting for pensions.</p>
          <p>Lastly, I want to be clear that our financial targets that we're presenting today do not include the pending acquisition of Astral. What we'll do is come back and refresh our 2013 once Astral is closed, which we expect to happen around the end of the second quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>So a couple of comments on revenue. First, our plan continues to be built around strong growth at Wireless. Bell Wireless revenue in 2013 will benefit from the flow through of strong postpaid subscriber acquisitions in 2012, growth in Smartphone penetration and an increasing share of high value customers in the west and in business markets. Wireless voice ARPU is expected to continue declining, but will be more than offset by data ARPU growth as higher Smartphone penetration, LTE devices and emerging revenue opportunities like mobile commerce, all contribute to growth in overall ARPU.</p>
          <p>In Wireline, we expect improvement in residential NAS erosion as we leverage our growing Fibe TV footprint to drive both three-product households as well as driving greater levels of growth in the MDU market. Stronger TV and Internet revenue growth should support total Wireline revenues in 2013 being essentially stable on a year-over-year basis.</p>
          <p>Wireline revenues will also benefit from the residential customers who are coming off significant promotional discounts of last year and as well from price increases on residential services that we introduced in January of this year.</p>
          <p>In the business market, I have to say we don't have any great crystal balls on the economic front. But we are very positive about the new product and service bundles that we're rolling out for the SMB market and as well the commercial relationship that we now have with Q9 and with those we anticipate overall improving business market trends for 2013.</p>
          <p>Finally in the Bell Media segment, revenue should remain stable year-over-year given the significant sales lift we got from the London Olympics last year. On EBITDA, the main driver for 2013 will also be Wireless. In addition, we expect Wireline to gradually improve over the course of the year benefiting from improving revenue performance and additional cost savings. Media EBITDA will be impacted by the retroactive specialty rate increases that we benefited from in 2012. And with all of that, we expect Bell's consolidated EBITDA margin for 2013 to be stable at about 37% to 38%.</p>
          <p>So I'd like now to specifically address our pension accounting for 2013. As I mentioned our reporting will be impacted by the new IFRS standard, which requires that the expected rate of return on pension assets has to be reduced to the accounting discount rate. Under the new standard, we will be restating our 2012 pension expense and EPS. That will result in a non-cash reduction of adjusted EPS in the amount of $0.22 for 2012 on a restated basis. Then as we look at 2013, the new standard together with a lower accounting discount rate that we'll be applying and that new rate will be 4.4%. All of that will result in about a further $0.06 year-over-year non-cash impact on adjusted EPS.</p>
          <p>At the EBITDA level, about a $50 million year-over-year increase in pension current service cost. That comes from applying that new lower discount rate and also from the fact that in 2012, we had a one-time $24 million curtailment gain related to some of our post-employment benefit plans. Less pension expense on the funding side, Bell's normal cash funding for 2013 and for future years for that matter will be maintained at a stable annual level of about $350 million.</p>
          <p>I want to be very clear that there's no letters of credit that we're using or that we would be planning to use towards the funding of our pension plan. The funding of our plan is at a very high status level right now. In fact, Bell's pension solvency deficit could be eliminated if the discount rate should decline by about 1%. And should that happen, it will reduce Bell's ongoing level of cash funding in future years. And I say, in fact, we've already seen about a 25 basis point increase in the discount rate that would be applied to Bell just in the first month of 2013, so we're off to the right start.</p>
          <p>Our history in managing the pension plan, I think, has always been a very prudent one. I think we've stayed well ahead of it and I think that's going to benefit us for years to come.</p>
          <p>So moving on to taxes, statutory rate is the same in 2013, 26.6%. Our accounting effective tax rate should be just slightly lower than that at 26%. We had a high level of tax adjustments in 2012 of about $0.18 per share. For 2013, we anticipate a lower level of tax recoveries of about $0.07 per share.</p>
          <p>Lastly, we expect overall cash taxes to be maintained at about the same level, about $300 million in 2013, equal to what we paid in 2012. And our taxes are going to benefit from the tax deductibility of that special pension contribution that we made at the end of last year. And we'll also enjoy higher depreciation, tax depreciation claims and investment tax credit claims from the increased level of capital spending that we've made over the past few years, so overall a stable outlook.</p>
          <p>Turning to EPS, with the new pension accounting standard, our 2012 EPS on a restated basis will be $2.96 and with the higher expected pension expense and lower tax adjustments that I spoke of, we're projecting 2013 adjusted EPS to grow modestly to $2.97 to $3.03 per share. Before tax adjustments, that represents growth of about 4% to 6%.</p>
          <p>And lastly on our free cash flow generation for 2013, I think that's going to be quite strong. We expect it to grow to a range of $2.55 billion to $2.65 billion before common dividends. That's a growth target of 5% to 9%. Cash interest payments will be slightly higher in 2013 given the slightly higher level of overall debt that we have from the acquisitions of MLSE and Q9.</p>
          <p>Our 2013 cash generation, I think, provides solid support both for the higher level of capital investment we're making into the business and for the $0.06 dividend increase that we announced this morning.</p>
          <p>So on this side, this is really &#x2013; slide, it's for your reference. It's a breakdown of main reconciling items between EBITDA and free cash flow and all of that is in line with our guidance.</p>
          <p>So to conclude, I think I'd like to say that our 2013 plan is a very solid one and a very achievable one in the eyes of our management. We expect good growth in consolidated revenue in EBITDA, EPS and free cash flow. Wireless will lead the way with continued double-digit EBITDA growth and some margin expansion. And Wireline will reach an important point of progress in its business transformation where it will show improved performance with a more reliable broadband growth mix and improving business market.</p>
          <p>All of this will ensure a stable consolidated margin at Bell. So Bell's fundamentals are strong. I think we're well positioned to sustain continued growth for the longer term and continued healthy dividend growth for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>So, thank you. And before I hand it over to George, we'd like to share a short video with you, which we think captures nicely some of the milestones that Bell has delivered over the past four years. So let's show that and then George will be up. Thank you.</p>
          <p>[Video Presentation] (32:14 to 36:58)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good morning. And, Siim, thank you for taking the time this morning to give us an opportunity to give you a much deeper understanding of what we're planning to do in 2013 and what we have been doing. As the video hopefully reminds everyone, we have accomplished a significant amount over the past four years as a company and for the investment community. But as the video says, I actually truly believe we are now just getting started.</p>
          <p>The focus of today's agenda is really about 2013 operationally and strategically, or probably more importantly, I felt it was really an opportunity to give the investors a unique time with some of our senior executives. The executive team that we have built in this company over the last five years, I'm convinced, would stand up to any telco or cable leadership team on the globe and we want to give you that opportunity to hear from those leaders today as investors in Bell.</p>
          <p>And as Siim talked about, we accomplished a lot into 2012 and I'll just quickly add a few comments to the year.</p>
          <p>If you go back to 2008 and you look of where we are today, operationally in 2012 leading, and we believe we will lead the industry this year in postpaid net adds, wireless ARPU growth and EBITDA when all the numbers are in for the year increasing our consolidated Bell EBITDA margin year over year in that declining voice challenge we have on the local access side.</p>
          <p>Again reducing our OpEx cost, this time $166 million, bringing our cost reduction since 2008 to well over $1 billion. And that excludes the working capital improvements of well over $500 million, a quarter million, 250,000 Fibe TVs, under Kevin's leadership not easy because sometimes we compete with these people and sometimes they're customers in terms of the distributors, but we settled agreements with all of the BDUs in Canada and, most importantly, significant improvement in our service, which drives lower churn.</p>
          <p>We're going to spend a lot of time on the strategic stuff this morning, but strategically expanding our, what we call FTTx, which would be Fibre-to-the-Node or Fibre-to-the-Home, ending the year at five million homes passed and 3.3 million, as we said we would achieve in terms of Fibe TV, launching the largest city in Canada with fibre with Quebec City, 100% fibre, and absolutely thrilled with those results.</p>
          <p>Wireless as we mentioned, LTE at 67% of the population. Acquiring the ownership in MLSE, securing us access and price going forward onto the most important content in the media business in Canada, and that being sports, and also something we're seeing on a global basis. Acquiring ownership of Q9, positioning ourselves in the fastest area of growth in the enterprise space and that's the data hosting and cloud computing market. And we were hoping to have a check mark there, as everyone knows, but still pending the Astral acquisition, which as Siim said, we're very confident we'll close the middle of this year.</p>
          <p>This slide to me is very important for the investors. We have had a dramatic change in our revenue mix in the last five years. And I'm going to share a few numbers we wouldn't normally share just to make sure the investment communities can see what's really happening underneath our revenue.</p>
          <p>Over 80% of our revenue in 2013 will be driven from our growth portfolio, and 20% will be from voice. Importantly, of course, Business Voice is much more stable than Consumer Voice because consumer substitution we're continuing to see on the wireless side.</p>
          <p>So we will actually exit 2013, pro forma the Astral transaction, with Consumer Voice revenue representing less than 7% of our revenue, okay? And that is significant, as of course the analysts know, if you look at what our mix was a few years ago because a 10% decline on a 7% of your base is a heck of a lot different from where we were four or five years ago.</p>
          <p>So an absolutely critical transition in our revenue stream is going, if you will, through time through our revenue and also our mix with all of the growth in our growth portfolios.</p>
          <p>You saw on the video, we're a little boring; six strategic imperatives, same story, same story going forward. We execute successfully in the marketplace on these six strategic imperatives. We continue to generate the free cash flow that we're building the company on the basis with the capital markets on, which is an improving free cash flow that allows us to continue to do what this asset should best do which is generate dividend growth, steady dividend growth over time, for shareholders.</p>
          <p>So we take a look at our broadband network strategy for next year, you'll notice, we've creeped up our capital intensity from that 16% to a 16% to 17% range next year. We did not want to cut our capital back because the Astral transaction did not close. So we creeped it up a little bit, right investment, and also you can see with our free cash flow guidance we have lots of room to do that.</p>
          <p>From a Wireless perspective, we will end 2013 with 75% of the population covered, getting to 98% ultimately. After the 700 auction is completed, we will cover rural Canada with LTE and we'd expect that rural coverage to happen, obviously, in 2014 as we now expect the auction to take place late in 2013.</p>
          <p>And it is worth mentioning, also, over the last four or five years, Canada has become the global leader of wireless technology, but there is no other country in the world that has three LTE networks like we have in Canada. It's incredible how the industry has changed in Canada and we lead. Go to Europe, your handset will go back three levels of technology. The concept that other places in the world are ahead of Canada in wireless technology are quickly, are quite frankly, wrong. We are ahead of the world in wireless technology.</p>
          <p>Turning to our Wireline acceleration, it's all about broadband and fibre, getting fibre as close to business and as close to the home as we possibly can and extending our IPTV footprint. And we'll extend our IPTV footprint this year, and Stephen Howe will share a little better detail than I can. But we'll do part of that through the introduction of pair bonding, which will increase the distance that will allow us to actually extend our IPTV footprint and, over time, speed and Stephen will talk about that.</p>
          <p>We do Fibre-to-the-Home now in every Greenfield. Any new neighborhood that's built, we build fibre right to the house. All condominiums, we build Fibre-to-the-Building and it's been going back to all the condominiums in Toronto and across all of our footprint. And also from a business perspective, we're building fibre to many more buildings this year, and anywhere we have aerial <mark type="ph" /> plant (44:24) that does not have Fibre-to-the-Node, we are putting it in using fibre because aerial <mark type="ph" /> plant (44:27) with fibre is, quite frankly at this point, is economical for us or very close versus doing Fiber-to-the-Node. Thirdly, continual capital program and customer service <mark type="audio gap" /> (44:41 &#x2013; 45:30) now and importantly for you drives our costs down going forward.</p>
          <p>At the end of the year 2012, we launched a number of services. John will talk about this as well, but a real focus on self-service functionality. On the Wireless side, we've launched a new app. Customers can track their wireless usage, check their balances, make payments, all of this online, and we've seen millions of users already and we just launched that in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>And on the online side from our TV business where customers can go in and upgrade or lower the package they want, select the programs they want and track their Internet usage real time from a billing perspective; all these areas what the customer wants to see and, from our perspective, again, drive significant cost opportunities for us going forward.</p>
          <p>And I think one of the issues always for investors with our story is how much cost? What can you continue to achieve? Let me just sit back and remind investors, we have a $10 billion cost structure. So 1% productivity and cost for us, remember, is $100 million.</p>
          <p>We expect in 2013 to further reduce costs another $170 million, and that will come through the call center efficiencies and field service productivity tools I just talked about, workforce reduction through normal attrition and retirement. As our employee base ages and we've put in place the productivity tools, we don't need to necessarily replace employees who decide to leave the company or actually meet retirement and that drives our cost structure down.</p>
          <p>Over 50% of our Wireless customers today do not get a paper bill. They choose to get their bill online. And so that is obviously dropping costs and, quite frankly, is why we've been recognized globally as the most green company in Canada.</p>
          <p>Further reductions have been negotiated with all of our major suppliers for 2013 on both billing, software licenses, set-top box and logistics. There is no Olympics in 2013; not great if you're a sports fan. But if you're in Bell, that's a good thing this year <mark type="indiscernible" /> (47:40) looking at our cost side because our costs will be less to execute this year. And this does not include any of the significant synergies we expect. Kevin will be able to sort through when we integrate Astral with Bell Media. And most importantly, a satisfied customer from our end cost us less to support and that's been key to what we've done.</p>
          <p>I think the mix slide is really important. I think this is probably &#x2013; Siim and I have seen in talking to our major shareholders a really important slide because there is a perception that our Wireline margin is somehow going to our other Wireline margins are in North America and that's not going to happen.</p>
          <p>People forget that we already have a $2 billion TV business in our revenue stream. Yes, our Wireline is challenged. But we think 2013 starts to be a bit of a turn in that. So we, in a rare not really guidance, but to give you a sense, we expect our Wireline EBITDA growth, which was negative 5% to 6% this year will be in the 2% to 4% range as we go into 2013. Why will that happen? Well, we're coming out of the J-curve on Fibe TV.</p>
          <p>We've already seen that we've bottomed on the negative EBITDA of Fibe TV. We're going through some of those promotions that we do to launch the initial service and the customers are now those rates come off those discounts. The market has absorbed some price increases both from the cable operators and from ourselves. Our business performance, B2B, has improved and we expect to improve this year as the Ontario and Quebec economy shows some signs of job growth, and I mentioned already the further cost savings.</p>
          <p>We expect our EBITDA margin to come in around 37%, interestingly enough, higher than our EBITDA margin was in Wireline in 2008 and 2009 when over 30% of our revenue was from Voice. And if you take the noncash charge in our pension, it actually is relatively flat year over year and so that, I think, is a real stake in the ground for us, and one that so many of you have brought to our attention. And we wanted to make sure you had some clarity around that as investors and what we're planning to do in 2013.</p>
          <p>Also on the Wireline side, of course, Siim talked about, for us it's about Fibe TV. Fibe TV is growing; 250,000 subs at the end of 2012. 85% of our TV subs are coming from cable operators or new growth. 15% is migrating from our satellite business. We expect that to continue to happen, the migration from part of our satellite portfolio. Obviously, our satellite portfolio lends itself perfect in some markets, and that's where we have to focus and move our market share; 3.3 million homes covered. 84% of the customers with Fibe TV take all three services. Importantly, 100% of customers who have Fibe TV take Internet, and that's fundamental to what we need to do going forward to grow our Internet market share.</p>
          <p>This slide probably best shows what's happening where we have IPTV and where we do not. We are actually positive RGU growth in the footprint where we have IPTV. So our Internet and IPTV growth is more than our NAS loses. So strategy: add more IPTV footprint. And so you can see in 2013, we think we will be right on the cusp of as many clients left, if you will, and the other footprint added, if you will, where we expand IPTV footprint. So very close to break even, and that's obviously very important to the revenue stream of our consumer wireline business and the lower revenue from voice as we go forward into 2014, 2015 and 2016.</p>
          <p>So we're going to expand footprint, and there are significant markets we are not in today, Ottawa being the largest. So we will go into the Ottawa market with Fibe TV with the same type of marketing that we did in Quebec City, and we expect to move the needle for market share for us and away from our competitors in the TV business.</p>
          <p>And so we will end the year with $4.3 million. You can see we'll launch Markham, Laval, North Shore, South Shore Montreal, all these markets, and what's really important for our marketing team, that gives us the ability to market this product in a much broader way through many more distribution channels because when it's available, if you will, in a footprint that large, the marketing is much more effective. So we're really excited about it.</p>
          <p>Four-point-three million homes covered of our seven million homes at the end of 2013. Bonding will expand our IPTV footprint in current footprint. It takes a distance where right now you need to be 900 meters from the home where the fibre starts to 1,400 meters when we go to bonding. And we will introduce bonding the middle of this year. And in later this year and in the mid part, we will actually roll out a wireless set-top box, which means you'll have multiple boxes in the home that are wireless for IPTV. That will take installation time down dramatically for Mary Ann; make us much more competitive than we already are where Fibe already has an advantage.</p>
          <p>Customers can mute the box. You can actually sit outside, whatever you want to do in terms of the box being wireless; takes installed times down, cost times and quite frankly we think it's going to be a game changer for us with Fibe TV.</p>
          <p>On the business market side, it seems sad. I mean clearly that is so economically driven for us. Yes. There's substitution and there's competition, but clearly job growth is what drives our business growth, and because we're so focused on Ontario/Quebec, we have a $4 billion business unit, and that's wireline. That excludes our wireless B2B. You add $1 billion for wholesale. We have a $5 billion business there, and quite frankly job growth will have that asset growing better than we have historically. And we're cautiously, as all of us are, optimistic the job growth in the U.S. will drive some job growth in Ontario and Quebec.</p>
          <p>Our investment in Q9 and our own data centers gives us 19 data hosting centers; sets us up perfectly for our customer base. We see about a 30% connectivity attach rate to data hosting.  So we now have the number one data hosting partnership and our own locations in Canada; absolutely in the sweet spot of our customer base. Ninety-six of the top 100 companies in Canada use Bell today, and we obviously want to manage their hosting and data services going forward.</p>
          <p>Turning to wireless. I would say probably the item that the management team of Bell is most proud of, and that is the turnaround of our wireless business to go from where we were to back into a leadership position. Yes, head-to-head with two really good competitors, but we're in the game, and we're competing aggressively.</p>
          <p>And a number of things have taken place to do that. So many investors ask, so what exactly, what's the one thing you did? It's not one thing. It's all these items that have been important under Wade's leadership, launching the new network, making the strategic acquisitions, leading the industry in distribution. And I have to give Wade Oosterman credit here. Wade said three years ago retail was going small screen, and he said buy The Source. And he was absolutely dead on, and having small retails turned into a competitive advantage because the products have got smaller. Eighty million Canadians go through The Source a year, and we have a store within 5 kilometers of every Canadian, so I mean it's a powerful distribution.</p>
          <p>Refresh the brand, improving customer service, and Wade Oosterman, John Watson and Stephen Howe have more experience than any executive team in Canada in wireless. So we have a great team leading that base with a proven track record.</p>
          <p>And this slide probably tells the story the best. The real internal goal of Bell is not 33% of postpaid market share. It's 33% postpaid market share, but more than that of incremental revenue and EBITDA share. So you want to punch above your way, you want to be reasonable in market share, but execute on revenue and EBITDA and you can see in the previous 12 months, yes, 39% of the net adds, but 43% of the revenue and 54% of the incremental value. So 54% of the industry's growth and EBITDA we captured of the incumbents over the last 12 months. And you can see the same the year before and the year before. Well, that was the acceleration of the market share move to be back in the game against our two competitors.</p>
          <p>The media acquisitions, really they have met our objective, probably exceeded our expectations and I think fair to say investors' expectations. As you know, we had no great strategy here we followed. We followed our cable competitors, who had vertically integrated. Ironically, the name vertical integration didn't come up until Bell vertically integrated, but all of our competitors had vertically integrated. So as you step back and say has it been a growth opportunity? Yes. Has it accelerated our positioning from a four-screen perspective? Absolutely. The market is moving to TV Everywhere, and Kevin's going to talk about that.</p>
          <p>We've had some differentiation in the market with mobile TV leadership, and in an industry that's so competitive, having differentiation is really valuable. It's been a great hedge against our programming costs, which are now &#x2013; we spend more than $600 million a year on content, and now we're going to end up buying roughly a third of that from ourselves. And we leveled the playing field against the cable operators. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (57:28) it's important for investors to remember, Rogers was vertically integrated, Quebecor was vertically integrated and Shaw was vertically integrated. And all of a sudden people weren't giving us access to the content, so we bought content to make sure that no one would ever deny us access to content, and that's working very well. And most important for you, it's been very shareholder value accretive, as Siim talked about.</p>
          <p>Kevin will touch on this, but clearly 2012, an important year because for us the first full year of ownership of the asset, great financial results, great new contracts with the BDUs, global leadership from an Olympic perspective and tremendous therefore for the brand. And 2013 is all about maintaining that viewership, leadership, containing our programming costs, both in Canada and the U.S., leveraging our investment in MLSE and the Montreal Canadiens because we have access to that content. And obviously, many new product introductions, and most importantly from a corporate development perspective, getting that Astral transaction closed.</p>
          <p>Turning to our regulatory agenda for 2013 for the investors. I think there's really three key files, excuse me, the first one being the Astral transaction. We expect the hearing to be in the spring. We anticipate that we know already we will need CRTC and Competition Bureau approval, and we'll make sure we have those in that timeframe. And we would expect closing to be in the summer time period, subject to the hearing happening in spring and then getting the approval.</p>
          <p>There will be &#x2013; our application will meet the requirements that the CRTC wants to see. There's no doubt the rules changed from the first proposal to what the CRTC now wants to see, and so the assets that we will put forward to meet those requirements will become clear to the investment community at the time the file comes out. But even so, we believe we can meet all of our strategic objectives with that acquisition. It will still be accretive, and Kevin will make a few comments in a moment.</p>
          <p>Turn to the spectrum auction. 700 megahertz is strategic for Bell. We will participate in that auction. And we will secure spectrum to make sure we can execute our strategy in the marketplace going forward for Canadians in rural markets because 700 megahertz is tremendous for rural Canada. And allows us to continue the leadership that Canada has globally by getting LTE into all those rural markets as quickly as we can. The policy does encourage investment nationally. We think it's the right policy in terms of what's been put forward.</p>
          <p>I think the auction we expect it now in the fourth quarter. I think that the rules continue to come out a little slower than we anticipated. And one of the issues for us, we want to make sure is that there is some set-aside spectrum, which we're fine with, but we want to make sure there are actual companies who are going to bid for that spectrum. And if they're not, we're really pushing hard that if they're not able to bid or someone decides not to, that spectrum shouldn't just be handed to someone, and someway should be re-entered into another auction.</p>
          <p>So if people are not prepared to step up and acquire that spectrum, we want to see that put back in. And so you hear us voicing that. Having said that, if everyone's prepared to participate, we're comfortable where the rules are today. We just don't want to have spectrum not going anywhere and not deployed, and we've just seen that happen already. Spectrum that was auctioned four years ago is now &#x2013; has now been sold through a process with an option on it and there was deployment of that spectrum; a complete waste of spectrum in this country. We need to deploy it in the country for the wireless industry.</p>
          <p>And then the wireless code of conduct, this is an important hearing. It's one that the three wireless carriers, the major carriers, have asked the CRTC to do because what we were running into was each of the provinces wanted to see certain different codes in each province. And we thought to be consistent with the country's productivity agenda and for our companies and for the shareholders, one code would be much better than having code by province, especially from an IT perspective, which takes productivity out of the Canadian economy if we all have different programs for every store and every province.</p>
          <p>So we'd like to see one national code. We're encouraged by what we've seen the CRTC announce. We think a number of those things are the right steps. A number of those are being done, some we're all looking to do. So I think it's going to be &#x2013; it should be a very positive outcome. The only caution I would have, and we're going to push very hard on this, we can't have a code and then say but each province will then have a code as well. Otherwise, we've totally defeated the purpose of having a national code.</p>
          <p>And so that's paramount for us, and it's paramount, I think, for investors and for Canada to have one national wireless code that we all follow and go through. And I said already, Canada leads the world in wireless technology, and we want to continue to do that after this, of course.</p>
          <p>So 2013, keep the wireless momentum; improve the wireline trajectory that I've showed you how we plan to do that; accelerate IPTV footprint; execute the cost reductions; that transformation <mark type="ph" /> risk (1:02:53) of revenue mix; and growing our free cash flow 5% to 9%, and that excludes the Astral transaction, which as you know, is also cash flow accretive as we go forward.</p>
          <p>Siim showed you this slide. I just want to give you a sense of how I think about it as well and in one sense how the board of directors thinks about this. We want to continue to see that excess cash flow, which you see of about $800 million a year where we can deploy it on strategic agendas, be it pension or acquisition or spectrum. And the reason we increased the dividend today, if you look at our guidance, we're right in the midpoint at 69% free cash flow with the dividend that we announced, and so that's why we're able to raise the dividend based on our confidence in our free cash flow going forward next year.</p>
          <p>So that's a quick overview of where we are. We're going into a little more detail now than normal. I'd like to call up Mary Ann Turcke, who's our Executive Vice President, Field Services. She's going to give you a sense of how we're able to improve service, while at the same time drive costs out of the business.</p>
          <p>So, Mary Ann, over to you. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>