<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1287715" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-11-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1556</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Thane Fotopoulos, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">George Cope, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Siim A. Vanaselja, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Simon Flannery</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Maher Yaghi</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Ric Prentiss</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Greg MacDonald</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Jeffrey Fan</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Dvai Ghose</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Phillip Huang</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Vince Valentini</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Glen Campbell</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Jonathan Allen</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Robert Bek</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to BCE's Third Quarter Results Conference Call. I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. Thane Fotopoulos. Please go ahead, Mr. Fotopoulos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Colleen. Good morning everybody. As usual I am here today with our CEO, George Cope and CFO, Siim Vanaselja. Earlier this morning, we did issue a news release and third quarter financial statements, MD&amp;A, and supplementary information package, which are all posted on our website as well as on SEDAR. Also posted on the Investor section of our website is a slide presentation that Siim and George will take you through this morning. George will start off with a brief overview of our operational performance before Siim takes us through the financials as well as a synopsis of the transitional impacts from the changeover to IFRS accounting practices. So, once all that's done, we'll move to Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>However, before we begin, as usual I'd like to remind you that today's remarks will contain certain forward-looking statements with respect to items such as revenue, EBITDA, adjusted EPS, free cash flow, and capital intensity. Several assumptions were made by us in preparing these forward-looking statements, and there are risks that our actual results will differ materially from those contemplated by our forward-looking statements. For additional information on such assumptions and risks, please consult our 2009 Annual MD&amp;A as updated in BCE's Q1, Q2 and Q3 2010 MD&amp;As, and BCE's press release dated November 4, 2010, announcing our financial results for the third quarter. All of these are filed with the Canadian Securities Commission and with the SEC and are also available on our website.</p>
          <p>These forward-looking statements represent our expectations as of today, and accordingly are subject to change after such date. Except as may be required by Canadian securities laws, we do not undertake any obligation to update any forward-looking statements, whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise, and I am making this cautionary statement on behalf of both George and Siim today.</p>
          <p>With that, I will hand it over to George.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Thane. Good morning everyone. Thank you for joining us this morning. I am on page four of the presentation and I will take you through a quick overview of the quarter as Thane had mentioned. Bell's strategic agenda clearly advanced in Q3. The company's strong wireless performance continues and can be seen in the results that we'll talk about this morning. We launched IPTV in late September. We secured a long-term exclusive mobile NFL content deal for our wireless business. We announced, as everyone knows, the acquisition of CTV Canada's leading media assets, which we anticipate closing in Q2 of next year. We also enhanced our business ICT leadership with acquisitions of Hypertec early in this quarter, the largest hosting facility in the Province of Qu&#xE9;bec and the acquisition of xwave. Our ICT business is now over $1.5 billion business unit within our enterprise group. And most importantly we achieved a wireline EBITDA growth of 5.4% through our continued focus on cost control.</p>
          <p>So, let's take a look at page five of our wireless results. Postpaid net adds were up 31% year-over-year driving, we believe, what will be one of the leading postpaid market shares in the quarter. And in fact our net adds as of the end of Q3 of 343,000 year-to-date is more than we did in all of 2009 and are up 55% at this point in the year.</p>
          <p>Just as important as our growth in postpaid is our continual growth now in ARPU. This is the third quarter that we've seen a year-over-year increase and for the first time in two years, our postpaid ARPU exceeded $65. And this has been principally driven through our data growth, which was up 39% year-over-year in the quarter. Materially important for the company and our shareholders as we're starting to attract the mix of customers that we anticipated with our new network launch. In fact, it's a year ago today that we launched our HSPA+ network. We now have over 1 million subscribers on our HSPA network and they are generating a postpaid ARPU of over $80 at this point. So, driving the momentum of wireless is really beginning to pay off for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>If you go to page six, there is no doubt that our device leadership is helping us drive industry-leading data growth now. Having exclusive access to the Samsung Galaxy S in the quarter, you can see here the photo and the lineup of customers for the Samsung Galaxy. If we had had access to more Galaxy S's and more iPhones we believe we would have done anywhere from 10 to 15,000 more net adds on postpaid. We also a little later this quarter will launch the new Samsung Galaxy Tab, which we think brings a brand new revenue stream to the wireless industry and if you will, we think absolutely clarifies the penetration well over 100% in the wireless industry in Canada over the coming years because of multiple devices that will be used by subscribers.</p>
          <p>Turning to page seven, our wireline business, our traditional voice business had its best revenue performance in over five years, with a decline in local access revenue of only 3.1%. This was driven by the 12th consecutive quarter of reduced year-over-year retail residential NAS losses as well as improvements in residential NAS ARPU. On the business side, we saw a slight decline year-over-year in NAS loss, so, some improvement. In essence, the economy is stabilizing. We still have not seen an increase in what we call orders-in as business expands we are also seeing a stabilizing environment on the business side.</p>
          <p>Turning to page eight, our TV business had another excellent financial quarter. Our revenue growth of 9.3% combined with our ARPU growth of 5.8% created some strong financials for us in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Net adds were up 19,000 in Q3, down year-over-year, really not a result of much of a reduction in gross adds, but an increase in churn as we had seen in the previous quarter and we've seen that really driven by some pretty aggressive competition with our cable competitor in Ontario. Also from a strategic standpoint, we launched Bell Fibe TV in a few neighborhoods in Toronto to Montr&#xE9;al in late September. We believe Bell Fibe TV will be a meaningful business for us in the second half of 2011 and we would anticipate exiting 2011 with between 1.8 and 2 million homes passed for IPTV.</p>
          <p>Today it's an industry milestone. I think I mentioned it last quarter, but we are now generating more TV revenue than we are local access revenue in the home, and that's before we build out IPTV and begin to generate revenue from that portfolio.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide nine, our residential services had an excellent revenue quarter on &#x2013; from a data perspective as well with data revenue growth of 5% driven principally by the bandwidth usage revenue being up 83% year-over-year. We're also pleased with our net adds of 22,000 which were unchanged year-over-year. Although the mix changed a little bit, we continue to see very positive results in Quebec and we've seen some churn rate declines with the move to our new Fibe product with our customers.</p>
          <p>On the business side, we continue to see solid IP revenue growth offset by legacy data declines and pricing pressures and the general slow economy as I talked about earlier on. So, data revenues were flat for our business division overall from a year-over-year perspective.</p>
          <p>So in summary, excellent quarter for Bell. We truly did execute well in our focus on our five strategic imperatives and moved our agenda forward with some of the strategic developments I mentioned. Wireless had a strong quarter. The reduced NAS line losses and the slower revenue erosion clearly are important in our landline business. And also, the growth in TV Internet and home ARPU &#x2013; home phone ARPU helped us on a service revenue side year-over-year.</p>
          <p>But most importantly is our continued focus on cost discipline in the wireline business which enabled us to produce, as I mentioned earlier, the 5% wireline EBITDA growth, which I think will stand well against any of our North American peers. I believe the results Bell, BCE has produced this quarter puts us in an excellent position for an EBITDA growth rate in 2011 that should enable the company to continue to execute our dividend growth strategy going forward.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it over to Thane. I guess, it won't go to Thane, we'll actually go to Siim to take you through the quarter's financials. Siim, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks, George. Good morning everyone. As Thane said, in addition to my usual review of Bell's financial performance, this morning I'll also spend some time reviewing our preliminary analysis of the reporting impacts that'll take place with the upcoming changeover from Canadian GAAP to IFRS and that takes place on January 1 next year.</p>
          <p>But first, let me start with the quarter and the summary financial results on slide 12. Overall, our execution was high. Wireless enjoyed another standout quarter of subscriber acquisitions, data growth and ARPU improvement. In wireline, Bell TV and Internet delivered healthy subscriber and ARPU results. And NAS losses continued to ease. In fact this was our best quarter, quarterly line loss performance in the past five years, a good result. All this contributed to solid revenue and EBITDA growth, year-over-year EBITDA margin improvement, which was supported by reductions in direct operating costs. Our net earnings were strong and we saw a significant 25% increase in free cash flow.</p>
          <p>Total revenue growth at Bell this quarter was 1.8%. Again, this was driven by strong wireless and TV revenue growth. Higher IP broadband revenues also contributed to the improvement. Two factors however, I'd say moderated total revenue growth this quarter. First, the slower pace of economic recovery on our business market unit. And second as I think you all know, the year-over-year impact of The Source and Virgin, which as of the beginning of the third quarter are fully reflected in our year-over-year results comparison. EBITDA grew 3.1% and EBITDA margin improved by 0.5 percentage year-over-year. I think that's a great result when taking into account that $83 million of incremental year-over-year spending that was incurred to increase subscriber activations and on customer retention upgrades.</p>
          <p>And EBITDA also continued to benefit from lower pension expense as it passed through the first three quarters of this year. CapEx spending accelerated this quarter on fibre deployment and network grooming in support of our broadband footprint expansion and IPTV. And as expected wireless CapEx was lower with our HSPA+ network build completed. I think we are still on track with our outlook to achieve a capital intensity level of close to 16% for the full year and of course that means we expect higher capital spending in the fourth quarter. BCE statutory EPS for the third quarter was $0.70 compared to $0.72 per share last year. Our restructuring charges were lower year-over-year, but EPS decreased slightly due to lower income tax expense in the third quarter of 2009, which was the result of the favorable resolution of uncertain tax positions.</p>
          <p>Similarly, adjusted EPS at $0.82 per share before restructuring costs also decreased $0.02 per share versus last year due to the tax factor that I mentioned as well as due to higher income tax &#x2013; sorry, higher income tax expense, but we benefited from higher year-over-year EBITDA, lower interest expense and a lower share count outstanding.</p>
          <p>And finally we generated free cash flow of 812 million for the quarter, which was 25% higher year-over-year. That's a strong result and adds to our already healthy liquidity position given our substantial $1.2 billion cash balance at the end of the quarter.</p>
          <p>So with that high-level perspective, let me turn to each of our segments. Bell Wireless performance continued on an upward trajectory. Wireless service revenues increased approximately 10% reflecting the strength of postpaid subscriber growth. We saw 39% increase in data revenues as George mentioned and accelerated smartphone adoption. Wireless APRU grew 2.7% representing a third quarter of the year-over-year improvement. The increase was driven by higher data ARPU as mobile broadband adoption and data usage continues to accelerate. Data ARPU now represents about one-quarter of total ARPU.</p>
          <p>During this back-to-school quarter, in response to competitive acquisition offers, we also lowered our average handset prices, and as a result wireless product revenues were down year-over-year. Wireless EBITDA this quarter reflected the 83 million higher spending year-over-year, I mentioned, to gain 66,000 more postpaid activations and to convert about 133,000 more customers to high-end handsets. That investment in improving our postpaid and smartphone mix should yield improved ARPU and churn performance going forward. Our wireless EBITDA margin was nevertheless maintained above 40%. So, I'd say really a strong quarter for wireless, highlighted by exceptional postpaid subscriber results, ARPU improvement and strong data growth.</p>
          <p>In the wireline segment, residential services maintained good momentum in TV and Internet subscriber acquisitions and overall revenue growth. We saw a good pace of customer upgrades to higher-priced TV programming packages. We saw a growth in five Internet customers, and we saw increased usage-based revenues.</p>
          <p>The pace of local voice revenue erosion improved to its best level in over five years. Residential NAS line losses improved for a 12th consecutive quarter year-over-year. Win-backs increased. And our home phone service bundle penetration increased. As a consequence, Bell's local and access revenues declined only 3.1% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Bell business markets continued to be dampened by secular pressures from the slow economic recovery and competitive pricing pressures. However, IP broadband growth was solid and we experienced fewer business NAS losses this quarter. Cost efficiency initiatives and lower pension expense contributed to the good overall EBITDA growth in wireline at a healthy 5.4%.</p>
          <p>If we turn to slide 15, adjusted EPS was $0.82 in the third quarter. This is a strong result driven by higher year-over-year EBITDA and accretion from our share repurchases under the NCIB program. And just on that, currently our NCIB program as you recall targets the repurchase of 500 million in BCE common shares and that program is 75% completed and we have as an objective to complete the remaining 25% in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Lower net interest expense due to less debt outstanding and lower interest rates year-over-year also provided some earnings upside. However, tax recoveries amounted to $0.16 per share this quarter being $0.13 per share lower than the third quarter of 2009. The year-to-date tax recoveries in 2010 have contributed $0.27 of EPS and that's in line with the guidance that we provided at the end of the Q2 call and it corresponds to an effective tax rate of about 17% year-to-date. Our full year 2010 guidance is for an effective tax rate of about 20% and consistent with that we are forecasting an effective tax rate for the fourth quarter that is more in line with our statutory tax rate. So, adjusted for the non-taxable earnings of Bell Aliant that we consolidate that rate should equal about $0.27 &#x2013; 27% for the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Our year-to-date adjusted EPS is $2.24 per share. And I believe we're well-positioned, comfortably positioned to achieve our full-year 2010 EPS guidance of 2.75 to $2.80 per share.</p>
          <p>Very briefly on free cash flow, as I said at the outset, really good performance in the quarter with a 25% year-over-year increase. Cash generation improved in a number of areas, EBITDA growth, net interest payments decreasing, restructuring payments related to our workforce reduction and real estate, rationalization programs being lower year-over-year. And our working capital increased due to the timing of supplier payables and higher inventory levels in wireless and we'll see that moderate a bit in the fourth quarter. So, on a year-to-date basis we've now generated free cash flow of over $1.9 billion.</p>
          <p>Turning to the outlook to sum up on slide 17, we delivered strong financial performance and attractive wireless TV and Internet subscriber growth, I'd say in an increasingly competitive marketplace. We continued to invest significantly at the same time in broadband networks and service programs and that will support future growth. We continued to reduce costs, which contributed to growth in EBITDA and margins. And we increased our investment in wireless subscriber acquisition and retention. So, looking forward we continued to see a positive outlook for the business. Into the fourth quarter, we expect to sustain strong execution and maintain a solid competitive position across all our product lines. So, with all key financial indicators tracking comfortably to plan, I can reconfirm all of our 2010 guidance components.</p>
          <p>So, before we move to the Q&amp;A, I want to take a few minutes to review the major changes that the transition to IFRS will have on our reported results. In preparation for that changeover we have been working on for the past year, we've prepared on a preliminary basis our 2010 opening balance sheet and year-to-date income statement using IFRS. And these are included in our MD&amp;A for your reference. I'd say at a high level that the key message is that there is no significant impact on our operating results or our key financial indicators. Revenues, EBITDA, adjusted EPS and free cash flow are largely unchanged. Our definitions of EBITDA and free cash flow will remain consistent with what they are today. Subscriber and related metrics will also continue to be reported as they are today under Canadian GAAP.</p>
          <p>So, as a result, we don't foresee any material changes to our MD&amp;A reporting. The significant impact for BCE is the balance sheet impact of the transition adjustments, which are required as a result of adopting international accounting standards. These balance sheet adjustments have no impact, I should say, on our credit policies, our dividend policy or our capital structure, capital market strategy. Over the past year we did a thorough assessment of all the mandatory and elective IFRS policy changes on our business. And we determined that the two principal areas of impact relate to capital assets and pensions.</p>
          <p>And I'll start with capital assets on slide 20. As part of the transition we re-valued certain capital assets as of January 1, the beginning of this year taking a fair value writedown to reduce the cost of those assets, which had a fair value below amortized cost. Secondly, we also changed the method of depreciation we were using to straight line. The fair value writedown which is a transition election under IFRS was determined by an independent third-party appraiser. And the change in depreciation method is a mandatory requirement as IFRS does not permit the group method, which we were using under Canadian GAAP for most of our wireline assets and that depreciation method really dates back to regulatory requirements.</p>
          <p>As a result of the fair value asset writedown and the change to straight line depreciation, which was applied retrospectively, we're reducing capital assets on the balance sheet by approximately $1.9 billion. And of this total 1.6 billion is attributable to Bell Canada and 300 million to Bell Aliant.</p>
          <p>On the P&amp;L, the fair value writedown results in a positive adjusted EPS impact of about $0.08 per share and that consists of $0.10 in the form of reduced depreciation expense, which is offset by a $0.02 loss to recognize asset retirements in other income and expense. So, that's capital assets.</p>
          <p>I'll move on to pensions. Here there are three main differences in the calculation and presentation of pension plan assets and obligations under IFRS. First, unlike Canadian GAAP where all of the components of pension expense are included in operating income, under IFRS, only the current service cost can be charged to operating income. The interest cost and asset return components of pensions under IFRS are included in the P&amp;L as interest expense and interest income respectively. This new presentation reduces year-over-year EBITDA volatility from changes in pension expense and that's good.</p>
          <p>Secondly, under IFRS, net actuarial gains and losses are effectively charged to shareholders' equity. And this is different from Canadian GAAP that amortizes those gains and losses to the P&amp;L over time. So, again the second change will help minimize future P&amp;L impacts from market fluctuations. And the third difference has to do with the return on pension plan assets, which under IFRS must be based on a current market value approach rather than on the four-year market related value or smooth value of pension assets as we use under Canadian GAAP. And so as you see on the slide, BCE's 2010 pension expense under IFRS is approximately $80 million or $0.07 per share higher.</p>
          <p>And the difference there is the net result of three items. The most significant is the $51 million one-time pension valuation reversal, which you may remember we recognized under Canadian GAAP in the first quarter of this year. That gain under IFRS is not recognized on the P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>The second item is the higher net pension financing costs and that's due to the revaluation of pension plan assets at market under IFRS. And the third under IFRS is that we will capitalize a portion of pension costs related to work performed by employees on capital projects. That's pension. One final important observation I'd make on pensions is that the changeover does not in any way affect our cash pension funding requirements.</p>
          <p>On slide 22, you will see how the various balance sheet line items are impacted under IFRS. The adoption of IFRS is expected to result in an overall reduction of approximately $3.5 billion in BCE shareholders' equity. This amount relates mainly to the writedown of capital assets and the recognition of the unfunded pension liability. The writedown of BCE's capital assets totals $2 billion, which is the 1.9 billion I mentioned earlier, but also an additional 100 million relating to the deconsolidation of our Inukshuk joint venture. And under IFRS joint ventures have to be accounted for using the equity method.</p>
          <p>On pensions under IFRS we will reflect the full plan deficit on the balance sheet as well as the full amount of unfunded post employment liabilities. And you can see that under IFRS, BCE's pension obligations total just under $3 billion. Now that amount reflects about 1.6 billion in unfunded pension liabilities at both Bell and Bell Aliant and about 1.4 billion of unfunded post employment liabilities at Bell and Bell Aliant. So as a result, the capital assets and pension liability adjustments, our future income taxes are reduced by about 1.5 billion.</p>
          <p>And finally the last change, our 1.3 billion accounts receivable securitization program is recognized both as a current asset and current liability under IFRS. So, that comes on to the balance sheet and the two line items are in the same amount. As I stated earlier while there is still a substantial charge to shareholders' equity as a result of the conversion to IFRS there is no impact on our strong credit profile, our liquidity position or our credit profile.</p>
          <p>On the next slide we have provided you with an earnings walk-down from Canadian GAAP to IFRS for both the first nine months of 2010 and also our full-year 2010 guidance. On the table you see there is no net impact on adjusted EPS from the adoption of IFRS. The impact on revenue is minimal with some minor decreases from the deconsolidation of the Inukshuk joint venture and some minor changes to deferred revenue recognition on some longer-term enterprise contracts. There is also no material difference to EBITDA either, just a slight decrease that arises from the flowthrough of the revenue adjustments and the higher pension expense.</p>
          <p>Now given that the higher pension expense in 2010 is mainly due to that one-time $51 million valuation credit not flowing through earnings, we would expect that the impact in 2011 and beyond should be minimal. And as I described, because we use current market values under IFRS rather than market-related values to determine pension asset returns, this results in $90 million of additional pension financing expense. And that happens below EBITDA representing about $0.07 per adjusted EPS. And finally, as a result of the write-down in capital assets and the change in depreciation method, depreciation expense decreases under IFRS providing $0.10 of incremental EPS, again partly offset by the P&amp;L recognition of losses on asset disposals of about $0.02 per share in other income. So, all in all an immaterial impact on our overall adjusted EPS, but certainly requiring an extensive amount of work on the part of our controllers group.</p>
          <p>To summarize then, no real impacts on how we manage our business. Revenue and EBITDA remain essentially unchanged. Higher pension expense under IFRS is offset by lower depreciation expense and consequently adjusted EPS is unaffected. Free cash flow is impacted slightly positively and that's due to the deconsolidation of joint ventures and that necessitated the reclassification of spectrum purchases to investment activities.</p>
          <p>And finally, while we see a material reduction in shareholders' equity on the balance sheet, no changes to our dividend policy or credit policies. In fact, we'll continue to maintain a very focused capital market strategy directed at increasing cash distributions to shareholders on a consistent and sustainable basis going forward.</p>
          <p>So, that's a lot to digest. We can take questions and I'll turn it back to Thane and the operator to begin the question period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thanks, Siim. So given the time that we have left, I please ask that you keep your questions short and to the point in respect <mark type="inaudible" /> many people on the line as possible. So, with that, Colleen, can you please explain the polling instructions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Fotopoulos. We will now take questions from the telephone lines. <mark type="Operator instructions" /> Our first question is from Simon Flannery of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Good morning. Could you talk a little bit about what was going on in the prepaid segment, you had some losses there, I assume the &#x2013; you've got some competitive impact which <mark type="inaudible" /> on the postpaid side you've done some things around Solo, perhaps give us a commentary on how things are proceeding and what to expect there? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, prepaid, it's pretty straightforward. We've moved Virgin's focus almost dramatically away from prepaid to postpaid. So you can see that in our postpaid numbers and where everyone knows the money is in the business. And on the prepaid side, if we've seen any impact on the new entrant competitors, it's the prepaid customer base going to some of those plans where they say they don't do any credit checks and etcetera. So, that's probably where we've seen the impact. And as far as the Solo Unlimited as we thought it would be a competitive offer in the marketplace, but as we also said to people, unlimited voice isn't really where the market is today, it's all about the data opportunities. So, it's there but frankly it's there as a competitive item not that is particularly material. So, we would anticipate quite frankly strength and focus by us on the postpaid side and prepaid that we may continue to see trends like this, we'll just have to see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Maher Yaghi of Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. I wanted to ask you a question regarding the use of cash. I mean, you had mentioned on the call earlier that cash generation continues to be solid. Is there an opportunity to use some of that cash before the end of the year to make a special contribution to your pension in order to get some lower taxation effect next year like you did last year and so just maybe your thoughts about how access could look for 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start and then turn it over to Siim. I think, first of all, to remind all of our investors, of course we have the acquisition of CTV, which will close in the second quarter of next year. And so clearly part of our strong balance sheet and cash position will be used for that. Secondly, we will at the same time as we get to the end of the year look at our cash position and at that point we have our guidance call in February to talk about where we are on uses of cash. And one of the considerations will be exactly the question that you've raised which is do we look at our pension planning gain given the return that we see on that type of investment for our shareholders in the sense of the tax cash returns we see and dealing with our pensions. So that will be on our list of considerations. As it was last year we have not made a final decision at this point in time. Siim, is there anything you want to add to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just to say that while we have 1.2 billion of cash on the balance sheet today we expect to end the year in fact with 500 to $600 million of cash. In the fourth quarter, we have a dividend payment in October that's about $350 million. At that level we also have a Series EC debenture that's coming due in the amount of about $270 million. We've got completion of our NCIB in the amount of $125 million. And then we've got the purchases of Hypertec and xwave as well. So, with all of that, we would expect to end the year with 500 to $600 million. As George said, we are giving consideration to how to apply that remaining cash balance recognizing there is the acquisition of CTV, the opportunity to potentially put more money into the pension plan and other alternatives to consider. So, we'll be in a position when we provide our guidance for 2011 to review all of that with you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And none of that, no one should be concerned, none of that takes away our focus on our dividend growth model. That will continue to be the focus of the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes and I think the other question you asked was our tax outlook for 2011. What we have consistently said is that we expect a manageable gradual increase in cash taxes over the next 3 to 5 years. With the acquisition of CTV, there was about $100 million of tax value that that brings us so that improves our tax position. But again we will be able to provide more detailed guidance on what type of tax expense and cash tax position you should expect for 2011. But there should be no surprises there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Ric Prentiss of Raymond James. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning. I appreciate all the color, particularly interested in the HSPA point that you made, that $80 ARPUs. Can you update us a little bit about how many devices you have and how it seems like for next year as far as additional devices and what percent of your base is on smartphones now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will give you some of the answers, some we &#x2013; we &#x2013; I think we've shared a lot this morning on the HSPA. We really want the shareholders to get a sense that we are getting the right mix of clients. So, just, I thought I had said it but maybe I didn't. We have over 1 million clients on HSPA+ and generating about $80 &#x2013; a little over $80 on the postpaid side. And so that comes from two places. It comes from a migration of clients from CDMA as their contracts come due to HSPA+ and it comes from our growth in gross adds on smartphones.</p>
          <p>But I don't think we've been sharing our percent of base on smartphone. And it's not where we're going to go from a competitive perspective, but we are obviously trying to be very transparent on the data revenue growth to give people a comfort we're getting the right mix of clients now, which was one of our challenges a few years back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hopefully that's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It is. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is Greg MacDonald from National Bank Financial. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, guys. It's another kind of variation of the cash usage question and really it's focused on the bond market, very strong bond market. QE2 means that things are getting better for bonds if that's possible, a little low debt costs out there. You guys are in a pretty good position with respect to debt maturities, I note that you do have I think a $500 million 2012 note...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's plus 6% coupon on that. Siim, what's the potential for you for Bell to pre-finance or mature those types of credits, I know there is not much left that you can do, what's the opportunity there to give yourself a little bit more flexibility on cash, because I'm looking at things like the CTV acquisition and the possibility of making a special pension contribution. And I'm wondering, with that dictating your flexibility, where does the buyback for 2011 stand relative to things like increasing CapEx on fiber-to-the-home, I'm trying to know &#x2013; I'm trying to figure out where in order of magnitude where the buyback is going to be standing as time goes on and if flexibility on pre-financing some debt out there gives you more flexibility than what I think you do?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I'll let Siim talk about the bond market in that I mean, our capital market strategy continues as we said, number one priority will be the dividend growth model then usage of cash we will clarify. In February we do have the CTV acquisition. We do have to consider buybacks and we have to also consider the use of the money for the pension and which one we think is optimal for our shareholders is what will drive that ultimate decision. But, maybe then I'll turn it over to Siim now, you're right about the attractiveness of the bond market for sure and so Siim, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Well, we're very fortunate to be in the healthy liquidity position that we're in. And Greg you're certainly right in drawing attention to the attractive bond markets that are out there. And I think notwithstanding that we have sufficiently three-year term facilities in place or bridge facilities in place for the CTV acquisition. It makes it very attractive for us to want to go to the market as soon as that acquisition is completed and lock in as favorable rates as we can. In terms of looking at the debt maturity schedule and opportunities for early refinancing bad debt, we look at that on a daily basis.</p>
          <p>And last year we refinanced $1 billion of debt calling that debt early and that saved us considerable amount of cash in the form of reduced interest expense. The opportunities are a little bit more challenging today. It depends on your outlook as to what interest rates are going to be over the medium-term. But I wouldn't rule out that we'll act over the next quarter. As I say it's the question of assessing where we think interest rates are going to go over the next three to four years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful. And just as a very quick follow-on on the pension side of things, rates down 50 bps means liability is likely up. How have your assets performed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Asset performance has been strong through the year-to-date. They are over 9%. You're right, discount rates have gone down. And just at the end of October, the Institute of Actuaries announced what companies will be required to use as the discount rate both for the &#x2013; there is a commuted value rate and annuity purchase rate. And you use a blend of those rates depending on the mix of your pension plan. So, we expect that when we file our pension valuation at the end of 2010, we will have to use a slightly lower discount rate that could be as much as 50 basis points lower.</p>
          <p>So I suspect that's going to have an impact on the solvency deficit at the end of this year, it's going to be partly offset by the solid returns that the pension fund has earned. But we'll again be in a position to talk about that and what our funding obligations are for 2011 when we announced our guidance. I would say though that all in all, I don't think the discount rates or &#x2013; and the returns that we've generated are going to materially change the level of annual funding as we go into 2011. The question is more the appropriateness of doing some further pre-funding of the overall pension liability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the tax benefit, great. Thanks very much, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Thanks for the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Jeff Fan of Scotia Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and good morning. I want to ask a question regarding the broadband Internet, ARPU up 4.5%. I was wondering if you can help break down a little bit, the drivers between, as you mentioned, broadband usage but what about the upgrades to the higher tiers to Fibe Internet and price. I'm just wondering how, George, how you see this changing over time with in terms of the overall ARPU trends for Internet and also each of these drivers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's a good question. On our slides we know that our FTTN on our five customers are up 28% year-over-year. So, there really are two things happening, it was really three things I guess on the revenue side, on the Internet that are happening. One is just the consumer is moving to the Fibe network that we have because of the access to the quality of the service and the speed of the service. And when they do that of course they upgrade to a different rate plan because they are using a product that's superior to where they were before. So, that's one piece of driving ARPU.</p>
          <p>The second piece of driving ARPU is obviously as we see a growth in video usage on the Internet making sure we're monetizing that for our shareholders through the bandwidth usage charges is a second contributor to that growth. So those two things. And then I think earlier in the year there was a small price increase on the base, but that's been flowing through over the entire year. Those are really the three keys and obviously to a lesser extent 22,000 net adds as overall revenue, but your real question is about, I think, ARPU.</p>
          <p>So, those are the mixes. We would anticipate going forward, each of those elements to move in our favor, because we anticipate over time all of our clients will move to our Fibe network. And we would expect obviously their FTTN footprint grows, that adds to that and we obviously do not expect less usage on the Internet going forward. We would anticipate people using the Internet more and more over the years. And so we think the revenue per customer opportunity through our significant investments, we think this could be quite positive for our shareholders over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Dvai Ghose of Canaccord Genuity. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Thanks very much. My question is on your Fibe IPTV strategy, George, you mentioned that the video ads were a little light in the quarter, it wasn't a gross issue, it was a churn issue because of increased competition in Ontario from Rogers. But arguably your IPTV product is superior to their cable product, but they will catch up with their interactive guides, better two-way connectivity and so on; one set-top box remote control use of PVR and so on. So, shouldn't you really be making hay when the sun shines and perhaps driving your IPTV strategy more aggressively while you have this lead time advantage over cable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, as the &#x2013; it's a great question, Dvai, and obviously we got to consider all those points on the competitive dynamics. The only ILEC in North America that has 2 million subscribers on TV already, we think that's one of the key parts to that strategy, because obviously satellite competes pretty well. There is no doubt in Toronto Montr&#xE9;al core, Ottowa core IPTV rollout will add to that competitive footprint for us. So, we would agree with you on that and so frankly 2011 we do want it to be an important year for us in Fibe TV. We're not as concerned about people catching up to us competitively in the product portfolio as we see Microsoft roll out. So, yes, the faster we can do it, the quicker we will. Obviously with the focus also recognizing we have a pretty powerful TV franchise already. So, I think it's additive, I think it puts us in a great spot because &#x2013; and we think given the proven technology and the execution we're seeing by both AT&amp;T and Telus on the products, it only encourages us more to move as quickly as we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Phillip Huang of UBS Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much for taking my question. First just a quick follow-up on taxes, I know your effective tax rate in recent quarters have benefited from favorable rulings. Just based on your current visibility, should we expect the effective tax rate to be sort of closer to the statutory rate in the year ahead? And my question is on wireless retention spending, just given the heightened competition this quarter and your postpaid churn up slightly, wanted to get your thoughts on whether you expect to sort of further increase your pension focus going forward? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I'll start with the question on the statutory tax rate. As I said for the fourth quarter we expect our effective tax rate to be at about 27%, which is our corporate tax rate adjusted for the non-taxable earnings of Bell Aliant that are in our results. I'd prefer to defer your question on effective tax rate for 2011 until we provide all of our guidance. It's always an exercise for us to look at the status of our tax audits, status of R&amp;D claims. And that's an exercise that is underway right now and I prefer to comment on it in conjunction with all of our guidance because there is elements on how much pension we fund can impact that kind of tax rate as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will come back to you on that if you let us a little later on this year when we do our guidance in the New Year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the retention spend, yes, great point, I think we would anticipate our expenditures on retention to continue to grow and also probably we have been a lower expenditure there because of what our network was historically and our competitors have been higher, we certainly took that number up in Q3. We would anticipate that to continue to grow. One of the keys for us obviously there to provide the EBITDA growth we want next year is to continue to see the right mix of ARPU if you will, stable to hopefully growing as a function of the data growth that we see to offset some of those upgrades because I think it &#x2013; it is part of the structure of the industry now that we have got &#x2013; we got to expense through the P&amp;L and we have a real focus on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And should we correspondingly expect churn to tickle back down or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I would say that's a &#x2013; it's also a real focus of our organization now, because one of the things we clearly see is our mix has changed and the clients we're attracting and there obviously are some that haven't stayed with us, it may have been a different mix than we had in the past. And then I think the tougher one on that, the call for us and I gather probably our other competitors will be the impact of the new entrants <mark type="inaudible" /> we see an increased stay or do we get it back down to the retention. The company's goal will be to get it back down. We have to execute that, I think, to show that to the Street.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Vince Valentini of TD Newcrest. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks very much. I am wondering within your NAS declines in residential if you're tracking how much of that is going to competitors versus going to substitution and if you've seen any change in the rate of substitution with all these new wireless unlimited offers in Toronto?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we do. I mean we &#x2013; what we do is probably what you're probably doing at the end of the quarter, which is we take a look at the NAS moving to the cable companies and their adds and then obviously what we lost. And generally, I think it's probably safe to assume the gap would be wireless substitution and I think a couple of people started to pick that up and make a note on it and we're obviously following it the same way. So, there is no doubt this year, we've seen some acceleration in wireless substitution, because we've seen obviously some pretty weak growth from our cable competitors in terms of NAS additions. And so that's what we would see. I don't think we've seen Vince, an acceleration that I could link to the new entrants to be completely transparent on it.</p>
          <p>We just know that the number is bigger and but it hasn't all of a sudden rapidly accelerated. But the good news is, everybody can calculate it I think. If you take our NAS declines and the other telco NAS declines, the cable adds and the gap generally you would think would be wireless substitution. It's hard to think what else it would be, especially when you have home growth right going the other way. It sounds like we're having a decline in population in Canada.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Glen Campbell of Bank of America/Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks very much. You made a very interesting comment about your home phone ARPU, the voice side rising 3.4% year-over-year. That's a remarkable result considering some of the retention and acquisition offers you've got out there. Presumably its rate increase is offset by more retention acquisition discounting. Could you comment on the balance there and what else might be contributing to that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Glen, part of the contribution we see when ARPU mix goes up is also making sure we're losing &#x2013; if there is such a thing, as losing the right clients. So, you tend to keep &#x2013; if you keep the user of the heavier packages, as your base declines, if you're keeping the right clients you also see an ARPU increase, so that's part of the contribution because we've done a lot of bundling pieces that have advantage for our wireline clients, who have had many services with us.</p>
          <p>So, that's helped us stay a little stickier with that base and secondly as there were some price changes during this year that have also clearly been able to hold in the marketplace. And we have seen, as you know in Ontario, one of our competitors had implemented a pricing change as well. And so I think that's what's really boded well for us on the ARPU side there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And any increase in the long distance attach rate there that might explain it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, if it is totaled, that would be &#x2013; we've done a number of bundling on the LD side that has these unlimited packages, but frankly you see LD rates, the decline you're seeing in our percentage, it's not contributing a lot, it's more helping us maintain that improving NAS retention rate, in terms of the number of clients we're losing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great quarter. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Jonathan Allen of RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Just a quick question about the deferral account and how we should be modelling that, Siim, should we be &#x2013; has it already been accounted or should we look at the &#x2013; sorry, the home phone revenue dip down in the next quarter or two as you hand out some of those rebates and promotions, and similarly on the CapEx side, should we be modelling on higher CapEx in the next couple of quarters or will it fit into the existing budget?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so first thing, I didn't mention this on the call, but in the quarter we took an additional $95 million restructuring charge to reflect the final CRTC decision, which included an interest factor in the deferral account. So, in terms of the P&amp;L impacts, the deferral account has been reflected 100% at this point. We will be spending $306 million for rural broadband deployment.</p>
          <p>Our plans are not entirely finalized and it'll be a number of years that we incur those expenditures and then there is $250 million of the total deferral account balance of 583 million that has to be returned to residential local service customers by the end of March next year. So, over the next four years, the aggregate free cash flow impact is going to be about $580 million.</p>
          <p>We see that in terms of the build-out side being absorbed within the existing 16% capital intensity that we're kind of operating at now and the rebates, we're just working through the form of rebates that we're going to provide. We've built some of that into our plans and our free cash flow guidance for 2010, I suspect that the larger portion of it will be rebated in the first quarter of 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And would those rebates show up as lower revenue or is it fully reflected as you said in the P&amp;L?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's fully reflected in the P&amp;L, there would be no further impact on our statements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Siim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the interest of time Colleen, this will be our last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our last question is from Rob Bek of CIBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just &#x2013; my question is on wireless ARPU, George, obviously a very strong quarter for data, which is key to the story, by our take your blended voice ARPU declined only by about 3 or 4%, which is really quite good relative to your peers in the industry, can you talk at all about what's driving that improved voice ARPU performance as obviously a lower anchor to the data growth is key to the story?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's mix, it's mix. It's &#x2013; the story for Bell and the move in growth in ARPU isn't about premium pricing strategies to our competitors, because that's a competitor market. It's having the network, the distribution the brand and the product platforms to compete now head-to-head against our major competitor, who had an advantage over a number of years in that area, so that we are attracting now the categories of the &#x2013; all categories that frankly have higher ARPU, whereas before we had some competitive challenges there. So, it's really mix-driven and we would see therefore the same mix on voice. And then of course we have the benefits overall of now global roaming with our handsets that we didn't have before and all those things are probably helping us a little different than our competitor who would add some of those advantages to themselves a few years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Colleen. Thanks for your participation this morning. As always I'm available for follow-ups and further questions throughout the day. On that, have a great day. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The conference has now ended. Please disconnect your lines. Thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>