<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1405245" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-11-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1556</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Thane Fotopoulos</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">George Alexander Cope</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Siim A. Vanaselja</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Desjardins Securities">Maher Yaghi</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities Canada">Phillip Huang</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Simon Flannery</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital Markets Canada Ltd.">Greg MacDonald</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="GMP Securities LP">Peter MacDonald</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Canaccord Genuity Corp.">Dvai Ghose</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Scotia Capital Markets">Jeff Fan</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="BMO Capital Markets (Canada)">Peter L. Rhamey</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="CIBC World Markets, Inc.">Bob Bek</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch Canada, Inc.">Glen D. Campbell</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="TD Securities">Vince Valentini</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the BCE's Third Quarter 2011 Results Conference Call. I would now like to turn your meeting over to Mr. Thane Fotopoulos. Please go ahead, Mr. Fotopoulos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jason, and good morning to everyone who has taken the time to join us today. As usual, I'm joined here by George Cope, Bell's President and CEO and Siim Vanaselja, our CFO. Earlier this morning, we did issue our third quarter 2011 financial and operating results. This release along with our supplementary information package can be found on our corporate website.</p>
          <p>George and Siim will begin the day by reviewing a brief slide presentation with you and then we'll move to Q&amp;A as time permits. However, as usual, before I begin or we begin, I'd like to remind you that today's remarks will contain certain forward-looking statements with respect to items such as revenue, EBITDA, adjusted EPS, free cash flow and capital intensity. Several assumptions were made by us in preparing these forward-looking statements and there are risks that our actual results will differ materially from those contemplated by our forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>For additional information on such risks and assumptions, please consult BCE's 2010 Annual MD&amp;A, as updated in BCE's Q1, Q2, Q3 2011 MD&amp;As and BCE's press release dated November 3, 2011, announcing our financial results for the third quarter of 2011. All these documents are filed with the Canadian Securities Commission as well as with the SEC and are available on our corporate website.</p>
          <p>Any forward-looking statements made represents BCE's expectations as of today and accordingly are subject to change after such day. Except as may be required by Canadian Securities Laws, we do not undertake any obligation to update any forward-looking statement, whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise, and I'm making this cautionary statement on behalf of both George and Siim, whose remarks today may contain forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>So with that, over and done with, George over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you, Thane. Good morning everyone. Again, thank you for joining us. I'm on slide four titled, solid wireless operating metrics to begin. In terms of the quarter, we again are pleased with our net adds in postpaid of 127,000. We believe based on the reporting of one of our competitors already, we should have achieved our goal of more than one-third of the postpaid net adds among the three incumbents.</p>
          <p>Importantly, blended ARPU increased for the seventh consecutive quarter of 2.7% and postpaid ARPU was essentially flat. The ARPU growth on a blended basis, continue to be driven through our growth in data revenue and as you can see in the quarter up year-over-year 34%. Importantly, we now have 43% of our base on smartphones and more importantly the opportunity is the other 57% to continue to drive ARPU growth going forward. And also worth noting that our voice revenue ARPU was down 1.8%, so really a healthy quarter, I think given the competitive intensity in terms of our ARPU and subscriber growth.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide five, we as everyone knows launched LTE. Importantly this month we've launched LTE handset and we'll launch another one this month. And it works on a national basis, because it's a dual mode product that's LTE/HSPA plus compatible and therefore national coverage is available from day one with those who purchased these LTE handsets in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide six, in terms of our NAS performance, we did see a tick-up in the consumer side and we believe that is driven from competitive intensity and more importantly we continue to see a growth in some wireless substitution.</p>
          <p>On the positive side, the business NAS losses were down 35% year-over-year. And I guess most importantly is our revenue decline on a total voice basis was down 5.1% versus 5.8%, as we've been able to hold ARPUs on the home phone business, despite the obvious pressure on NAS erosion.</p>
          <p>We go to slide seven, we're very pleased that we are starting to see traction on our Fibe TV product as we had expected in the second half of the year. Net adds up 26,000 in the quarter, up 41% year-over-year, but importantly 25,000 on net adds in Ontario and Qu&#xE9;bec, and wholesale net adds essentially flat. So clearly with 26 in the total, there were some decline on the satellite side and areas outside of our Ontario/Qu&#xE9;bec footprint, excluding the wholesale.</p>
          <p>Fibe TV continues to ramp up. As we've said, the branding has now picked up in both Toronto and Montreal. We anticipate ending the year as we had said with approximately 2 million homes past for IPTV.</p>
          <p>Interesting milestone for the company. We now generate more revenue from TV than we do from residential voice revenues, and that's $454 million, obviously we expect that to continue to grow. And so we must be &#x2013; I am sure we are close to one of the only telcos in North America now generating more revenue from TV than from their voice portfolio. And we have been able to absorb this net add growth for Fibe TV in our wireline EBITDA, and as Siim will comment, you saw an increase in our EBITDA margin this quarter.</p>
          <p>Turn to wireline data, really mixed results there. Overall, our data service revenue was essentially flat. And it's important to remind people that we moved our portal data revenue over to Bell Media. So if you account for, that's roughly up 1% year-over-year on the service side. We definitely saw soft hardware sales, really low-margin product sales, but it did drive our revenue down in data, as we saw. You can see here on the slide, a significant reduction in our hardware sales in the business market.</p>
          <p>On the consumer side, Internet ARPU continues to be strong. But it was a very aggressive quarter from some of our cable operators in terms of Internet marketing and we saw that was really flat Internet &#x2013; with the Internet subscriber base not growing in the quarter. And we particularly sought in the DSL footprint, not the FTTN footprint.</p>
          <p>And on the business side, that continues to be a soft area for us, and so from a data perspective consumer revenue is strong, business revenue is not as strong as we'd like to see.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide nine, we continue to focus on our strategic imperative of executing cost reductions in the quarters, year-over-year savings of about $80 million, bringing our year-to-date savings to $240 million. I also like to confirm that through the month of October, we reduced our management resources by about 1,200 people in late September, early October. None of those areas will affect our frontline service organization where we continued to improve our service to our customers. Overall, we expect annualized savings of about $100 million in labor cost as a result of that program that we put in place through late September and early October.</p>
          <p>Overall, you can see that the cost reductions continued to enable us to provide best-in-class wireline margins and at the same time, as I said absorb our growth we're beginning to see on the TV side.</p>
          <p>Turning to Bell Media, continues to perform well. Number of initiatives, CTV Two continues to accelerate very well, the launching of TSN Radio in Montreal and Winnipeg with some rebranding there, the announcement of pursuing the Olympics in partnership with CBC to manage our cost investments there and securing the rights for FIFA World Cup going forward.</p>
          <p>We continue to progress nicely on the TSN/RDS rate renegotiations some of that benefiting us this year, most of it benefiting us next year, all in all a strong quarter. We, as our other competitors, have mentioned are cautious about the fourth quarter in terms of advertising revenue. Our guidance remains the same for the company, but clearly that's one area that we're watching carefully given some of the events on a global basis.</p>
          <p>In summary, from our perspective, a strong quarter from a wireless perspective; really pleased with our postpaid subscriber growth, our data growth and our ARPU growth on a blended basis. The launch of the dual mode LTE handsets, Fibe TV gaining traction, business results soft and continue to be challenging and has been that way as I think our shareholders know for the last two years or so. And our cost reductions continue to give us the headroom we need to drive the TV growth in the wireline margins that you're seeing.</p>
          <p>Overall, our broadband investments in the fourth quarter we continue to focus and into next year on IPTV, fiber rollouts and LTE. And quite frankly, I don't think we've ever been better positioned in all segments going into 2012 and believe we have a clear path towards our dividend growth model into 2012.</p>
          <p>With that over to Siim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, George, and good morning to everyone on the call. Our financial highlights for the quarter are summarized on slide 13. Overall, we turned in another quarter of solid earnings and free cash flow generation and that was supported by good operating momentum across all our segments.</p>
          <p>Total revenue growth at Bell was 10.1% and that reflects the substantial revenue contribution of CTV, which is reported in the Bell Media segment as you know from the beginning of the second quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>Excluding Bell Media, Bell Service revenues were up 1.2% year-over-year, that's consistent with our year-to-date trend. This reflected the solid performance of our consumer businesses in the quarter with wireless TV and Internet, residential Internet service revenue growth of 6.1%, 3.9%, and 8% respectively.</p>
          <p>Consistent with recent past quarters top line growth continues to be impacted by data product sales, which decreased 11% year-over-year as businesses continued to defer spending on legacy data products.</p>
          <p>EBITDA increased 7.5% year-over-year, again reflecting the inclusion of CTV results. Excluding Bell Media, EBITDA grew 2.1% driven by ongoing wireline cost savings and stronger wireless financial performance.</p>
          <p>Capital spending in the quarter was focused mainly on continued investment in our wireline and wireless broadband platforms including the deployment of broadband fiber, IPTV service network expansion, and a construction of our 4G LTE wireless network.</p>
          <p>Adjusted EPS before severance and acquisition costs and net investment gains increased $0.12 per share over last year to $0.93. In addition to the contribution from higher year-over-year EBITDA, adjusted EPS improved on lower net pension financing costs, gains from derivative contracts that we've entered into and higher tax provision adjustments year-over-year from the resolution of tax matters with the tax authorities. These tax adjustments contributed EPS growth of $0.21 per share in the third quarter, which is $0.05 per share higher than last year.</p>
          <p>BCE statutory EPS in the third quarter was $0.83 per share that's up from $0.60 last year. And in addition to the higher tax adjustments, the increase in statutory EPS also reflects the fair value loss of approximately $0.08 per share in the third quarter of 2010 and that was on the publicly held units of Bell Aliant income fund which were treated as debt under IFRS prior to the conversation of Bell Aliant back to a corporation.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow was just over $1 billion for the quarter, up $199 million year-over-year and that's really stellar performance. We fully caught up on cash collections following the end of the postal strike and Bell Media had a very strong quarter of receivables collections in the third quarter consistent with its business cycle.</p>
          <p>Now let's look at our wireless third quarter results in more detail on slide 14. Total service revenues in wireless increased 6.1% on 8.9% postpaid revenue growth. These are higher growth rates compared to the previous quarter. Subscriber gains throughout the year have been weighted to an increase mix of higher value postpaid customers and we continued to see accelerating smartphone and data plan adoption which helped fuel data revenue growth of 34% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Smartphone subscribers now represent 43% of our postpaid basis George said just up from 26% the year ago. Improving our smartphone mix provides us with the good opportunity to continue growing blended ARPU and as well those customers tend to have a churn rate that is below average.</p>
          <p>This back-to-school quarter saw lower average handset prices in the marketplace and consequently wireless product revenues decreased 1%. Our wireless EBITDA performance improved this quarter with growth of 3% while we absorbed $15 million of incremental acquisition costs and $10 million in higher retention spending year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding the more intense competition in the quarter given the back-to-school plans and pricing, which traditionally has pressured margins in the third quarter, we maintained a relatively stable EBITDA margin of 39.2% sequentially compared to the second quarter. So that covers wireless which was a solid quarter both operationally and financially.</p>
          <p>Let's move to the Wireline segment. Our residential services unit maintained good operating trends with solid growth in TV and residential Internet which are becoming a larger portion of our Wireline revenue mix. Additionally, the pace of long distance erosion improved to its best level in more than seven, years driving Bell's year-over-year voice revenue decline to 5.1% down from 5.8% last year.</p>
          <p>In Business Markets, we're still experiencing pressure from the sluggish economy, slow employment and the transformation to IP-based network services, as has been the case &#x2013; much the case over the past two years. And that was most evident this quarter in the form of lower data product sales in many key sectors as well as continued decline in business connectivity revenue.</p>
          <p>Despite the macroeconomic challenges though that we're seeing, we are seeing some improved traction in IP-broadband business solutions and professional services, which saw good growth after a number of quarters of decline. Business access line losses also showed improvement. So while that segment continues to work through the economic cycle, it does remain well positioned and continues to invest in both growth and productivity measures.</p>
          <p>In the quarter, Wireline EBITDA increased 1.7%, reflecting about $180 million reduction in operating expenses year-over-year, bringing our year-to-date decrease in Wireline operating expenses to $240 million. Those efficiency savings offset the costs related to our IPTV service rollout and the lower year-over-year contribution from business markets, resulting in an overall strong 1.9 percentage point improvement in Wireline margin, which was 40% this quarter.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 16 and Bell Media, overall a very good set of results in what is seasonally a low quarter for advertising spending in the media sector. Subscriber revenues grew by a healthy 4% year-over-year driven in part by rate increases that were implemented on contract renewals with broadcast distributors for our sports channels TSN and RDS. To date, we've now concluded agreements with more than a 140 BDUs, including many of the major players and we hope to have other contracts finalize by year end, and that will position us to begin realizing the full benefit of those rate increases beginning in 2012.</p>
          <p>Advertising revenues were also up around 1% year-over-year, reflecting steady demand across most industry sectors and supported by continued industry leading ratings across Bell Media's conventional and specialty TV channels. Advertising revenues in the third quarter also benefited from the launch of TSN Radio.</p>
          <p>EBITDA growth for Bell Media was impressive, increasing 27% year-over-year. As I highlighted on our last call, as part of the purchase price accounting for the CTV acquisition EBITDA for media includes a non-cash charge to amortize the fair value of their programming inventory, and that charge was $9 million in the quarter. So excluding that charge, Bell Media's EBITDA was up 40% over last year. So we're really pleased with Bell Media's performance in its contribution to Bell's overall financials this quarter.</p>
          <p>And we clearly are beginning to realize the strategic value of owning media assets and the benefits that the CTV acquisition brings to Bell. CTV is substantially integrated into Bell now and that should also generate some cost saving synergies as we go forward.</p>
          <p>On slide 17, adjusted EPS was $0.93 per share this quarter, 14.8% higher than last year. This very strong result was ahead of plan for the quarter, reflecting a higher than forecasted level of tax adjustments, and we touched upon that.</p>
          <p>Tax recoveries amounted to $0.21 per share this quarter versus $0.16 in the third quarter last year, and that resulted in the low effective tax rate 9.8%. We had expected these tax settlements to be resolved later, most likely later this year or early in 2012; so with $0.28 per share of tax adjustments year-to-date, we now expect an effective tax rate of approximately 21% for the full year 2011, down from our previous expectation of a 25% tax rate. If we exclude the tax adjustments, adjusted EPS growth in the third quarter was still exceptional at a double digit increase of 10.8% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Higher EBITDA accounted for $0.09 of that EPS growth, lower year-over-year net pension financing costs, and a 2.4% reduction in the statutory tax rate for 2011 also contributed to the improvement in adjusted EPS this quarter. Higher year-over-year interest and depreciation expense was mainly due to the acquisition of CTV, which on an overall basis is accretive to our earnings.</p>
          <p>Our cash flow summary is on the next slide, slide 18. As I commented earlier, our cash generation was exceptional in the quarter with over $1 billion of free cash flow for a 24.7% year-over-year increase. Cash generation improved on higher EBITDA and improved working capital position. And year-to-date, we've generated a healthy free cash flow of $1.7 billion, as you see. And I'd say our balance sheet is strong with $1.1 billion in cash and cash equivalents on hand at the end of the quarter. Our credit metrics remains sound, all of that giving us substantial financial flexibility.</p>
          <p>So I'll wrap up with a few quick comments on our guidance in the outlook. First, our performance through the first three quarters has demonstrated solid execution of our strategic imperative and our momentum for ongoing success is positive to cross our business lines as we enter the fourth quarter. As a result of the higher than expected level of tax adjustments that I mentioned, we are updating our adjusted EPS guidance to reflect the revised projected effective tax rate for the 2011 year of about 21%. So consequently we are now expecting adjusted EPS to be in the range of $3.10 to $3.15 per share that represents year-over-year growth of 11% to 13%.</p>
          <p>In terms of free cash flow, there's no change to our guidance of $2.2 billion to $2.3 billion for 2011. However, I would mention our free cash flow outlook now takes into account some acceleration in capital spending versus our plan about to take place in the fourth quarter and offsetting the increase in that capital spending is an improved cash tax outlook which resulted from the favorable resolution of tax issues in the quarter. So cash taxes are now expected to total $175 million approximately and that's down from our previous tax expectation of cash taxes of $225 million.</p>
          <p>Finally, we expect to incur about $90 million in cash severance payments related to the recent downsizing of management positions but the significant portion of those cash severance payments will only be incurred in the first quarter of 2012 with some impact but not significant in the fourth quarter this year.</p>
          <p>Taking all of that into account, we now expect our year-end cash balance to be closer to $800 million which is the high end of our previous outlook. And I say that consistent with our past practice, we will make our determinations on the use of that surplus cash at year end once we framed our plans for 2012 and once we also have more clarity on the valuation position of our pension plan. There's no other changes to our 2011 financial guidance and assumptions.</p>
          <p>So with that thanks everyone for joining the call and I'll turn things back over to Siim and the operator to begin the Q&amp;A period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Thane. So before we start the Q&amp;A period, I just want to remind you to keep your questions short to the point, so we can get to as many callers as possible and just one brief follow-up if you may.</p>
          <p>So Jason with that, please explain the polling instructions, we're ready to begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Fotopoulos. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from Maher Yaghi from Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, thanks for taking my questions. Maybe this question is directed to Siim more. I'm trying to understand a bit the tax adjustments here and what is &#x2013; of the favorable tax adjustments, how many will be helping or could be thought of as contributing &#x2013; continuing to contribute for 2012 in terms of your base taxes? How much of the changes in the taxes that you have gained in the third quarter could be seen as continuing to help you in 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thanks for the question Maher. So if we look at our year-to-date adjustments for &#x2013; through the three quarters of 2011, they contributed $0.21 in EPS through the first three quarters of 2010 &#x2013; sorry I gave you the wrong numbers, its $0.28 through the first three quarters of 2011 and for the full 2010 year, they were $0.27. So we're about at the same level in 2010 as we are in 2011.</p>
          <p>Over those two years, 2010 and 2011, we have managed to make some significant progress with the tax authorities on a range of outstanding issues both federally and provincially. We do have some significant remaining large ticket items to settle with the tax authorities. It's always uncertain as to the timing of if and when we'll be able to reach agreement. We are hopeful that there will be incremental tax adjustments into 2012, and recognizing that we'll be providing full 2012 guidance. At the beginning of the year, we'll comment &#x2013; we'll comment on it at that time on a more a holistic basis with all our guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, just to make things clear, of the $0.28, if other tax adjustments &#x2013; let's assume we don't know the results of those yet, but if we just take what already occurred, the $0.28 that you benefited from year-to-date, of those, can we use them as a base assumption that will be recurring into 2012 or these are &#x2013; or how many of those are one-time items that helped 2011 that will not recur in 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. You have to appreciate that these are all one-time items. So, in that given year we have $2 billion of taxable income. We file our tax returns and there is a number of items that the tax authorities choose to challenge and it's a long lengthy process for settling those. In fact, some of the items that we settled in the third quarter date back a number of years, so they are one time. As I said there is &#x2013; there are still significant one-time items that we're looking to hopefully resolve in 2012 that we'll comment on when we issue our guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have to come back to that in the guidance call for 2012. We had an effective tax rate this year planned for 25%, Siim has said it will be 21% this year now and so we'll come back with 2012 with an effective tax rate expected at the point of guidance and we'll have to do it that at that point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just a follow up question on the NAS decline, they picked up this quarter could you explain on the residential side what drove that pickup in NAS declines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there is couple of things. I think actually three different things all contributing, one a little less on the wholesale side that we've seen last year that's for sure. Secondly, we think wireless substitution accelerated in the back of the University crowd, which probably wouldn't be surprising one on the call, but we could see that. And thirdly it was certainly an aggressive competitive quarter when we started the CTV growth, of course, we're seeing a competitive response there but generally I believe it was the wholesale and wireless substitution. And in the end, the analysts I think will be able to calculate that once everyone's reported their NAS in the cable side just try to get a sense of what that total industry reduction on our growth was in the substitute would obviously go to wireless.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Phillip Huang of UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good morning. Thanks for taking my question. Good to see your TV growth gain momentum. I was wondering if you could maybe provide this color of &#x2013; on where are those subscribers came from, Roger's reported growth and their TV subscriber base in the quarter? And my sense is that I think you've been more active of Fibe TV marketing in Montreal than in Toronto so I was wondering if Qu&#xE9;bec was a bigger driver of that growth than Ontario?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think proportionally, Montreal's footprint was a little ahead of Toronto's and so proportionally a little more than the population you would think of came out of the Montreal market and we've now begun to ramp up in Ontario aggressively, and we should &#x2013; hopefully we'll see some results on that in 2012. So there definitely was a little more shift in the Montreal market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then also on the TV ARPU, there was a bit of slowdown to its growth, I was wondering to what extent does that reflect promotions on Fibe TV, and should we assume sort of slower ARPU growth as you expand your IPTV footprint?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think that's a fair point. When we're acquiring new subscribers and we're doing typically in a triple is what our real focus is, there is early-on acquisition discounts, and so I think it is fair to assume that the ARPU growth that we would have seen in a more mature satellite business will be impacted somewhat by the growth next year in Fibe TV.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And you're right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then if I could &#x2013; let me do a final one. On the back of the sort of accelerated residential line loss, as you sort of explained in terms of more aggressive competition as you expand your TV marketing, to what extent do you see the need to step up your retention program in response to the aggressive competition?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we will. It's a quarter-to-quarter, ever-ending marketing battle between the companies. And so we'll be &#x2013; we'll obviously adjust our strategies based on where results come in on all three of the products. I mean, our true execution focus is on the three-product household now with Fibe TV and satellite we now have the ability to operate everywhere and the other of course is as we expand &#x2013; continue to expand our IPTV footprint, we also continue to expand our FTTN footprint and that helps us on the DSL side because we're not in the mark with FTTN and certainly that's where the churn rate is higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Simon Flannery of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Good morning. On wireless you had some solid postpaid net adds, I was wondering if you could just comment on the impact of the iPhone 4, as we saw in the U.S. I think particularly in September, the pause in activity as customers waited for the new device and then I think the carriers have been guiding to strong sales in Q4 and commensurate margin dilution sequentially. And I was wondering if that &#x2013; if you were sort of seeing any trends along those lines and any other comments on the device would be great? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we didn't &#x2013; from our perspective we don't think we saw an impact in the late sales in the third quarter on postpaid in anticipation of the new iPhone. Clearly in the fourth quarter, we'll see an increase in upgrades, but that's in all of our guidance, so everyone should be comfortable with that. It's in our guidance that we would expect to an increase in upgrades because of that product which of course we're converting people from voice products to data products that continues to show to be accretive on our ARPU perspective. And then in terms of fourth quarter outlook, I'm just going to not address that on this call for various reasons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I know. The supply is okay for device.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How are they &#x2013; supplies for the 4S?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Supply is excellent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have all of the product we need access to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Greg MacDonald of Macquarie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>George, you made a comment on sustainability of dividend growth is being important to the company, obviously that's still the case. Tax affects EPS and so what I'm wondering, can I just make the assumption that high 20%, maybe 30% tax rates &#x2013; effective tax rates, so what we should use for normalizing EPS when you &#x2013; to think about how you and the board think about the dividend payout ratio? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>Second quickly related to that, 2012 maybe a year of excess free cash flow that you're not going to see repeated in '13 as a result of the spectrum auction, $800 million in cash at the end of the year, you certainly have enough if you want to make a special contribution to the pension plan, what about share buybacks? Can you comment on that yet or is that something that has to wait until guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think &#x2013; and the tax issues we worked, we've been as transparent this quarter on what are the one-time items so that everyone can see through those as best they can and we will get obviously clarified in 2012. But in terms of our uses of cash, it continues to be four key things that we've talked about. Number one priority for the board, for our shareholders is the dividend growth model and that's something that we see a clear path based on where we are today for 2012 and obviously we have continue to execute there. And then the other three uses have been the tuck-in acquisitions that are strategically executed on the imperative side making sure we're managing our pension prudently and then looking of incremental cash beyond that, if there's &#x2013; if it's <mark type="ph" /> their own (37:00) buybacks and those have been the four uses of cash and that will continue to be the strategy into 2012, and we need to see where we end up at year-end on all these items and I think we're in a strong position going into 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll come back and clarify all that as Siim said a little later on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And I just to get back to this question on the dividend growth model, is it safe for me to assume high 20% range is an effective tax rate that you think about when you're thinking of the dividend payout because you do have that dividend payout ratio and a lot of us out here think about where you are in respect to that, are you in the middle, are you in the high and a lot of that might depend on what you assume for an effective tax rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Greg, Greg what I say is that even if you look at our new guidance and you normalize for the amount of tax adjustments, our dividend payout is still just a little bit below the midpoint of our payout policy. So certainly even without any tax adjustments there is still room within that payout policy to increase the dividend without any growth in EPS and I'm not at all suggesting there isn't going to be growth in EPS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That is helpful. Thanks, Siim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Peter McDonald of GMP Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I just have a couple of questions on the pension. So Bell Aliant gave us some information on the interest rate change and the asset change they said their's is flat and about a 50 to 90 basis point change in the interest rates for the liability. Is that the same for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Again, we will take you through the valuation position of our pension plan at the end of the year when we give our guidance. Certainly at the beginning of the year with the prefunding special voluntary contributions that we've made over the last two years, we were in a very healthy position with a solvency ratio in excess of 90%. Our discount rates have certainly come down through the year. Return on assets in our pension plan, year-to-date, have been about 3.5%. So we've taken a more conservative mix in investing the assets of our plan and that has benefited us this year and we'll see what the balance of the year goes.</p>
          <p>The important point that I would make is, I think irrespective of where our solvency position ends at the end of the year, we're not expecting that there is any significant impact that will happen for purposes of cash funding of the pension plan, given the flexibility that we have with the special contributions that have been made. And also wonder, IFRS, when we look at our P&amp;L pension expense is not particularly materially impacted either by changes in the discount rate and return on assets. In fact, much of the difference in returns on assets doesn't go through P&amp;L, but it goes through out of comprehensive income now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just as a follow-up, you said that your contributions previously will may &#x2013; regardless of what happens to your solvency deficit will mean that you have very little cash impact from it. Is that because of the averaging of previous years that it won't have an impact or maybe you can expand on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. What it means is that over the past two years, we have voluntarily paid $1.25 billion into the pension plan over and above the mandatory deficit funding contributions that have been required. Going forward, if we choose, we always have the flexibility to use any portion of that special funding towards future year deficit funding requirements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That's helpful. Just can you tell me what 25 basis point change in interest rate means to your liability?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's a little over $400 million, about $425 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. That's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Dvai Ghose of Canaccord Genuity. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks very much. Good morning. In light of the CRTC's vertical integration decision in September, which essentially rules out exclusivity on any platform in any genre, I am wondering if you could just quickly revisit the strategic rationale and whether in retrospect you perhaps should have spent more capital on connectivity, IPTV in particular, and perhaps less on media? And just on a related point, while it's great to see the video additions accelerate, to what extent was that for the whole industry because of a shutdown of over-the-air analog and is that really sustainable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Dvai, the second part of the question, not a lot of ours was from the over-the-air analog conversion. Most of it was, as we mentioned, in the IPTV footprint, which would be more urban, so that tended to be what's happened there. So we're nothing is real till we execute, but our goal with our investment on IPTV is to continue to grow that asset.</p>
          <p>In terms of Bell Media, we couldn't be happier with the acquisition. Financial results are excellent. The integration of that asset into our strategy I think would be clear to anyone who's watching what we're doing in the marketplace and helping us. And in terms of the regulatory decision, people may recall when we acquired the asset, we talked about the fact that there were rules in place that allowed for content to be exclusive, but it was our strategy that we would commercially sell this content anyway, and our strategy continues to be that.</p>
          <p>The rules we think are more cumbersome and complicated by the CRTC than quite frankly they need to be in a commercial marketplace. But having said that, our obligation to sell our content is on commercial terms, and we anticipate doing that to &#x2013; in all of the genres, be it on the online side or in the mobile side, we look to sell our content to both that compete with us on the subscriber side, but not as a customer of ours on the content side. So, no, I don't think it's reduced our capital intensity one bit in terms of our focus. Our 16% <mark type="ph" /> C-to-I (44:15) was the same before we bought the business, it's the same now that we bought the business and if anything, Bell Media is going to give us a little more capital next year to invest because our consolidated <mark type="ph" /> C-to-I (44:22) we think will continue to be around the 16% number and the media business only takes about 4% to 5% <mark type="ph" /> C-to-I (44:32) to run it, so it's given us some incremental cash for our shareholders and some incremental cash to continue our capital base model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're really quite pleased with it. We wish the rules weren't quite as complicated as they are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Jeff Fan of Scotia Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks very much and good morning. My question is on the broadband Internet subs. When I look at your TV trends and TV subscriber adds, those are really strong, but there is a divergent trend here with Internet being flat in Q3. So the bigger picture question is, is Fibe TV or is IPTV enough to keep Internet subs growing over the long-term? And a follow on to that is, can you give us an update on the rollout of FTTN, where you guys are at now and what your plans are in terms of covering your overall footprint over the next couple of years? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, question and I think we believe that the rollout of our IPTV will continue to help us from a competitive perspective on all three products into the household. It was a very aggressive quarter from a competitive standpoint. On the Internet, some very aggressive pricing in acquisition offers. And as you can see, given the moderation of growth in that sector, a small amount of swing can have an impact obviously on whether or not you do plus 15 or don't do plus 15 on the Internet side. So I think that's what happened there.</p>
          <p>On the FTTN, we continued to invest in our footprint and next year we'll come back in '12 and maybe talk about where we are in terms of footprint coverage on FTTN and IPTV plans, but our goal here is to ultimately match our IPTV footprint over time with our FTTN footprint. And so, next year there will be more investment and why don't I on the call in '12 come back and update everybody on those footprints.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question is from Peter Rhamey of BMO Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. Good morning, George and Siim. ARPU is trending better over the prior quarter. I think you mentioned a number on voice declines in the low single digit. Is that reflective of a conscious effort on your part, change in strategy or tactics in the marketplace? We did see something from Rogers directionally similar to yours or is that more a reflection of just easier comps?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean from our perspective, it's on the postpaid side and really the blended benefit is because of our focus on the high value sector which has been postpaid now for three, four years when we embarked on this new strategy. We are being much more successful in the business market. We're being more successful as we expand the opportunity in Western Canada where the ARPUs are obviously stronger and those are things that are driving our mix and therefore driving our blended ARPU higher.</p>
          <p>We obviously were pleased in the third quarter to see a bit of a reversal on that slight tick down on postpaid in Q2. And really what has to offset that is the migration to the data handsets, accretive enough to offset the voice pressure and as you can see in the quarter, we're able to in essence, achieve that on a blended side. We would anticipate our blended ARPU given our mix favorability to continue to help us going forward and that's what we hope happens, but obviously can't make a forecast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And just as a follow-up. On the retention side, are you changing your policy on retention spend at this point in time, getting a little less aggressive on that given that your churn performance has been pretty solid?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we would like to see churn come down. We're still not in line with our competitors on the postpaid side. We're getting closer, but unfortunately that's &#x2013; they are coming up not because we're going down. And at the same time, our percent of revenue on retention, we continue to tweak it up, we're trying to get it into the levels that would be closer to our peers and we're trying to manage that really closely relative to the obvious from years ago the revenue ARPU differentiation between us and our competitors that's continued to narrow and so it's giving us the headroom that we need to address &#x2013; invest in retention and you'll see us do that again as we go in to next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's fair to say that you tweak your retention up a little bit to the extent you get some latitude on your EBITDA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely we do. As we've said many times, we run the business on a consolidated EBITDA basis not on the three different business units. We report them separately for investor to see how they're doing, but clearly, the EBITDA growth that we've seen in wireline, which is as people would know one of the few in North America is being invested back into our wireless business to manage these competitive pressures around retention and migration to data handsets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, George.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Bob Bek of CIBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. I just have one television question left. George, can you comment at all on the CRTC's other regulatory ruling on the a-la-carte, skinny basic options, given that TV is now playing in a more important role for your business, what your thoughts are on the structure for video going forward? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well. Yeah, I think, we're going to have to see &#x2013; we're waiting for the regulations now to be written to understand it. As I mentioned to Dvai's question, I think they are more complicated than they need to be as a supplier side. Obviously, at the distributor side, if the market moves in a certain direction, we're going to have to move that way. And quite frankly, some of the markets have done that a little bit. But we need to really understand now when the CRTC comes back with the written regulations whether or not this is a direction or a guidance and the way it was written, quite frankly, that's not a 100% clear yet. And so, we are actually right now still trying to figure out what those implications will be and we're awaiting the regulations that the CRTC has said they're going to put them out. In the meantime, we're operating under the old rules for now as people know and we're waiting for them to get clarify.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. As a follow up to that, I mean, underlying all of this is, I guess, <mark type="ph" /> they didn't move to digital and/or achieving core (50:47) cutting. I mean, would this speak to your intent on the FTTN investments, basically get the broadband also as well as whatever video growth you can catch up on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, we continue to see a nice growth in our portal business at Bell Media combining it with Sympatico and CTV's assets, we're generating some nice &#x2013; very nice revenue growth on that side of the business from advertising revenue and that's contributing to our Bell Media growth. And we think over time as we've said all four screens we would like to be able to generate content revenue from and if we can do it creatively subscription revenue through our Bell assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Glen Campbell of Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks very much. My question is on retention discounting. You continue to put up really very good ARPU despite very competitive conditions across the business. So, I was just wondering if you could talk about the trends in the incidents of retention discounting in each of your businesses in wireless, in triple-play and then standalone satellite? Are you seeing it rise, fall, I was wondering if you could comment product by product? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's a good question, Glen. It's really into the operations of what we're trying to manage here. What we're typically trying to do on retention is upgrade people to handsets while having minimal impact on rates if we can. If you do both, of course, it's where you get hit on the ARPU side, particularly on the wireless side. So we're trying to invest the money in upgrading the customer and not having quite an aggressive offer on the rate side. And the same in the household, what we're really trying to do now that we have the three product portfolio in a lot of our footprint when we add satellite in and with as we've said with Fibe TV growing, now we can say, okay, the pricing comes that way for the customer on a retention basis provided they add the third product. And that creates as you will know the accretive opportunity there for household ARPU. And we are actually managing that very carefully. We think in some ways may be a little stronger than one of our competitors and frankly we think that's what we're seeing in our ARPU blended growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you comment at all about the percentage of customers that are on these kinds of discounts that these are turning to be stable or rise or fall?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, look, I don't think, I can't give you those numbers. All I would say is that competitive intensity in the wireless side, as everyone would know <mark type="indiscernible" /> (53:13), probably never been as high as it is, because particularly because of the market share shifts we've seen even amongst the incumbents, our issue as you know historically was we didn't have the right handset lineup, our distribution wasn't right, and frankly the footprint opportunity and market share for us that we've been able to grow in Ontario and are doing in the West is what helps us offset the lowest ARPU market in the country, which is in Quebec where we had previously had &#x2013; where a lot of our market share had come from in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a mix of business clients and geography and a focus on postpaid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Given that we're running out of time, this will be our last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The conference has now ended.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's okay. We'll take one more question, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly. The next question is from Vince Valentini of TD Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for sneaking me in there Thane. Question on the elasticity related to the substitution effect. You mentioned you have seen a bit of increase in George. Is there any way you can parse it down between what you're seeing on substitution in Toronto versus Montreal, given this quite a bit different nature of the wireless competition and sort of video drawn in Montreal, and sort of bundled offers in slightly disciplined pricing, and then the sort of craziness in Toronto with the three new entrants in their ultra low pricing? Does that have an impact on how much substitution you see, or do you think it's basically just a structural trend that's kind of agnostic to the pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it's a structural change, Vince. I can't give you that. I don't have it here. Your insight may be absolutely correct, but it's not one that I've personally specifically asked the question. My intuitive sense would be yours that probably more of it would be in Toronto given what's happening, but I think it's more about a structural move that we've all seen, which is over time people continue migration of our NAS and some of that will go to wireless. I tend to believe those that are using our wireline product have proven quite frankly that price isn't necessarily what's driving some of that behavior. It's just actual lifestyle change of a certain demographic that drives that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks everyone for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I'm available for follow-ups and clarifications throughout the day. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The conference is now ended. Please disconnect your lines at this time and we thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>