<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1176315" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-08-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2056</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Marius Kloppers, Chief Executive Officer and Executive Director</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Alex Vanselow, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">Andrew Keen</participant>
      <participant id="3">Marius Kloppers</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jason Fairclough</participant>
      <participant id="5">Robert Clifford</participant>
      <participant id="6">Alex Vanselow</participant>
      <participant id="7">Vicky Binns</participant>
      <participant id="8">Craig Campbell</participant>
      <participant id="9">Brendan Harris</participant>
      <participant id="10">Sylvain Brunet</participant>
      <participant id="11">Sophia Hart</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="13">Peter O'Connor</participant>
      <participant id="14">Warren Edney</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, my name is Marius Kloppers, Chief Executive Officer of BHP Billiton. Welcome today to the presentation of our full year results for our fiscal year 2008. I am speaking to you today from London. We've got in Sydney, Alex Vanselow, CFO of the company who will be presenting from Sydney.</p>
          <p>Before we begin today's presentation, unfortunately, as is now customary I've got to point you to the three pages of disclaimers. They are important. As usual, we tried hard to get them down to two pages and didn't succeed. But they are important in relation to today's presentation. Please read them carefully in the materials that you've received.</p>
          <p>Before handing over to Alex Vanselow to give you a full overview of the financial results, I would like to start by giving you a brief overview of the results. I'll then cover, after Alex has spoken, our performance, BHP Billiton's perspectives on the macroenvironment, supply/demand for our product, and then finally I will talk about a few aspects of our business and how we're positioned. Then Alex and I will take some questions.</p>
          <p>So let me talk about the most difficult part of today's presentation, and simultaneously also the most important: safety. Over the past year, as we did last year, we had a 20% improvement in our total recordable injury frequency rate, which is the measure that we most commonly use to measure our performance; 20% improvement. Last year we had roughly the same improvement.</p>
          <p>And over the past year, we've taken down our rate to 5.9, which is a very, very good achievement by industry standards.</p>
          <p>However, despite this positive result, despite our severity rates, despite our injury rates going down, we still suffered 11 fatalities this year, five of which in a helicopter crash in Angola.</p>
          <p>This is a very difficult thing for a company to handle that is dedicated to zero harm. These events touch not only the families, but also colleagues and operations of those teams that our workers are involved in. And it just shows you that despite our best efforts, despite having made great progress on safety, we've got more to do.</p>
          <p>And you should understand that that this management team, every person in the company is committed to taking this further, to continue to strive to zero harm and continue to drive towards that goal. We believe that zero harm is an achievable objective.</p>
          <p>Now let me talk about our financial performance. In the past year, we've continued to see strong demand for our products. Strong demand with supply side constraints, which we'll talk about a little bit later on, has resulted in a strong pricing environment for us.</p>
          <p>And it's against this backdrop of strong supply/demand &#x2013;  good supply/demand conditions, that I am very pleased with the strong operating result that the company has put in, which has allowed us to present another set of record results today. The seventh set of record results in succession.</p>
          <p>The result in this performance demonstrates our focus on the core business. We achieved this result through production records across the breadths of our portfolio. And we posted earnings record numbers and production record numbers for a number of key commodities.</p>
          <p>I'm extremely pleased about our cost performance, which has been achieved in a market that has been very, very tight for inputs and where certainly some of our raw materials have escalated in cost fairly dramatically over the period.</p>
          <p>So in summary, our EBITDA was up 22% to $28 billion. Our EBIT up 21% to $24.3 billion, and then the measure that's perhaps of most interest to our shareholders: attributable profit. Our attributable profit was up 12% to $15.4 billion before exceptional items. And the exceptional items in our results really was immaterial over this past year.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share was up 18% per share to $2.75 per share. The latter figure, which is obviously higher than the 12% on the attributable line, showed the benefit of our buyback program, which unfortunately had to be suspended in December 2007 when our mandates expired, because of regulatory constraints surrounding our bid for Rio Tinto.</p>
          <p>Despite cost pressures, and Alex will talk about that a little bit more, we continued to capture a very substantial portion of price movement to the bottom line. Our underlying EBIT margin was 48%, our return on capital was 38% &#x2013; and I just want to point out that that return on capital figure was achieved in an environment where we've been ramping up our capital expenditure, and there is a considerable amount of capital that is not yet productive on the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>These results are spectacular. They are built on very, very solid operating performance. And looking towards the future we continued our track record of successful project execution and achieved first production in 10 major new projects. And these were spread across five commodities and during the past 12 months, we also sanctioned another seven new projects.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the dividend, we've always said that our base dividend is a function of our future expectations for the sustainable earnings on the business, and cash generation of the business. And I'm very pleased that for the second year in row we've rebased our dividend, this time to a final dividend of $0.41 per share. This is 50% higher than the equivalent period last year and importantly over the last three years, we have seen 150% dividend increase.</p>
          <p>Because we look at our dividend as an annuity on which we progressively build, this dividend rebasing reflects Management and the Board's confidence in the outlook for our business in the years ahead. Taken together, the operating and financial results, the dividend growth and the capital management program illustrate how we continue to lead our industry.</p>
          <p>Now, let me hand over to Alex to take you through the details of the financial results. Alex?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Marius and welcome to everyone. Today I am delighted to present as Marius has highlighted, a seventh consecutive record profit result. We delivered an absolute record attributable profit of $15.4 billion, which is an exceptional achievement. Realized with the diligence of our people, the hard work of our people, excellent operating performance and cost control.</p>
          <p>Importantly, we also delivered higher volumes in to a strong market condition. This result demonstrates that we are focused on the right strategy of owning and operating a portfolio of upstream, large, low cost, long life, expandable assets, diversified by commodities and geographies.</p>
          <p>This strategy provides us with greater stability of cash flow and a solid platform of growth, enabling us to reinvest in our business for the individual commodity cycles, and also to continue to create and return significant value to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Marius mentioned a number of financial highlights in his introduction. But it is worth repeating that it is the strength of our strategy and the quality of our delivery that has produced record performance for each one of these key measures.</p>
          <p>This year's performance is not just about the 2008 financial year. These results build on the strength of previous years achieved through the disciplined execution of our strategy. Most of you will recall the Jackson Pollock slide that's on the screen now, which showed the margins by commodities over half-year intervals.</p>
          <p>This is a very relevant slide because our EBIT margin progression over time shows that underlying commodities are indeed volatile. But it also shows how a highly diversified portfolio of exceptional quality and scale embedded with superior growth optionality can and will continue to create outstanding shareholder value. Our portfolio diversification, quality and scale is without parallel in our industry.</p>
          <p>Let's have a look at the second half of 2008 financial year on the slide. Our performance was impacted by power disruptions, by floods, by industrial action and by accelerated cost inflation. However, EBIT margin for the second half expanded to an all time record 50%. And for the full year as Marius mentioned, we &#x2013; the EBIT margin was 48%.</p>
          <p>Now we'll turn to the performance for each customer sector group in detail. And as usual we'll start with Petroleum. This business is a core component of our uniquely diversified portfolio with 13% volume growth, strong oil prices and low and stable operating cash costs, Petroleum achieved an EBIT of $5.5 billion, which was an impressive 82% increase from the prior year.</p>
          <p>Importantly, this result was not just about high oil prices. Volumes from new operations were a significant contributor adding $1.1 billion to EBIT. Atlantis, Genghis Khan, Stybarrow were all commissioned during the year, increasing the mix of higher margin liquids in our production to 44%. This strength is likely to continue in future years, starting with the production of Neptune, which was commissioned on 6 July.</p>
          <p>As we said before, we want to focus on operating assets. And we are the operator of three of these four projects. We've been particularly pleased with the startup of these operations. Stybarrow has continued to produce at full capacity of 80,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day and Neptune reached full capacity in just 15 days. These are remarkable achievements.</p>
          <p>We have also continued to progress our growth pipeline with the approval of both Bass Strait Kipper and Turrum projects and in addition, the capture of significant acreage in the Gulf of Mexico through lease sales and our discovery of the large Thebe gas field in North Western Australia have added further to our growth pipeline.</p>
          <p>Outside the Gulf of Mexico and outside Australia we also continue to build a solid portfolio of opportunities within Colombia, Malaysia and the Falklands. Our focus on long-term sustainable development is also evident. For the second consecutive year we achieved greater than 100% reserve replacement.</p>
          <p>Aluminium delivered record Alumina and metals sales. However, industry wide cost increases for energy, fuel and other raw materials drove EBIT down by 21%. Despite a mandate of 10% reduction in power consumption in South Africa, we have been able to limit the loss of local Southern African metal production to just 8%. We are managing the situation as best as we can, but the impact in Southern African metal production will continue.</p>
          <p>Base Metals is the largest EBIT contributor in the group, with a record EBIT of $8 billion. As well as higher prices we achieved record copper production for the third consecutive year, despite two earthquakes in Chile and unplanned SAG mill outages at Antamina in Peru. We delivered a 10% increase in copper production at a time of very high prices. We also announced the discovery of Pampa Escondida, drilling to date suggests that Pampa Escondida contains at least 1 billion metric tonnes of porphyry style mineralization.</p>
          <p>Diamonds and Specialty Products EBIT was in line with last year. The Koala Underground project was delivered ahead of schedule and under budget and production is ramping up strongly.</p>
          <p>In early July, we acquired Anglo Potash, which gives us the full ownership of more than 7,000 square kilometers of highly prospective exploration permits near some of the major potash mines in Saskatchewan, Canada and Potash will further diversify our portfolio.</p>
          <p>For Stainless Steel, EBIT was down 65%, mainly due to lower nickel price and volume and also the start up of Ravensthorpe and the Yabulu expansion. The nickel price has eased from its record high in May 2007, but has remained above long-term average historical rates. During the year, we commissioned three major projects, Ravensthorpe, the Yabulu expansion and Cliffs, production ramp up is continuing.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to the Steelmaking Materials customer sector groups; in iron ore, we deliver yet another record result driven by strong volume growth and also cost control to capture the full benefits of the higher prices.</p>
          <p>Excluding the impact of foreign exchange, increase in operating costs &#x2013; cash costs in Western Australia was contained to only 3%, this at a time when the whole industry is facing substantial inflationary pressures.</p>
          <p>We have consistently delivered against our aggressive growth plan, which will take production capacity to more than 300 million tonnes per annum by 2015 and even more beyond. This is our eighth consecutive iron ore production record reflecting an exceptional history of successful project execution and operation efficiency.</p>
          <p>During the financial year, we commissioned and ramped up the Western Australian Iron Ore Rapid Growth Project 3, we call it RGP 3, and delivered the first production from the Samarco expansion.</p>
          <p>We expect strong volume to continue next year, fiscal year 2009 and this via the continued improvement of our Western Australian production system which we'll see production hit an expected 137 million tonnes on a 100% basis in the 2009 financial year. This is 8 million tonnes or 6% higher than RGP 3 installed capacity.</p>
          <p>Our growth plan is underpinned by an extensive exploration and development program. During the year, we delivered 46% increase in mineral resources and over the next five years, we will spend about $500 million on exploration to delineate new resources that will support bigger mining hubs.</p>
          <p>Higher sales, all-time record ore and alloy production and higher prices for the year have driven manganese EBIT up 550% to a record $1.6 billion. This is an exceptional result when you consider that production records we achieved despite the impact of the South African power crisis.</p>
          <p>The Groote Eylandt expansion, which will deliver an additional 1 million tonnes of concentrate per annum, was approved during the period. While two other expansions projects in South Africa, will add on a 100% basis, 1.7 million tonnes of concentrate capacity per annum for our capital expenditure of less than $50 million our share. This expansion plans are underpinned by large long-life high quality resources.</p>
          <p>Metallurgical Coal, EBIT was impacted by heavy flooding in Queensland in the second half of the financial year. And costs attributed to the flood recovery activities were approximately $40 million in this period with an additional $80 million of cost inefficiencies associated with the lower volume year-on-year. A further $70 million of costs are expected to be incurred to complete the flood recovery in 2009 financial year.</p>
          <p>Operations are now almost back to full capacity. Margins were still healthy at 24% despite the loss of production and these additional costs. The outlook for met coals continued to be very positive and we look forward to the benefit of the more than 200% price increase which is largely not reflected in these numbers.</p>
          <p>Market conditions are anticipated to remain tight with robust longer-term demand being driven by Brazil, India and China. We are accelerating our deep inventory of growth opportunities to meet these demands.</p>
          <p>Record EBIT for energy coal was driven by higher prices and continued strong demand. Record production was achieved at Hunter Valley coal in Australia and Cerrejon in Colombia. The Klipspruit and Douglas-Middelburg projects in South Africa and the new export terminal in Newcastle were all approved during the period.</p>
          <p>So wrapping up this CSG [Customer Sector Group] highlights, I think it's fair to say that this has been another stellar year across the business. We have achieved record underlying EBIT in petroleum, base metals, iron ore, manganese and energy coal CSGs at a time when market conditions remained favorable.</p>
          <p>Before I hand you over to Marius, I would like to cover a few key focus areas, starting with the cost pressures. Cost pressures have been an issue across the industry for some time and they have accelerated into the second half of the financial year as many of our industry peers have noted. Managing cost is a key focus for everyone at BHP Billiton. In total cost pressures on a pre-tax basis adjusted for price linked cost, exchange rates and inflation impacted EBIT by $1.2 billion. Excluding non-cash cost impact of $260 million, this is an increase of 4.3% over last year's total cost base.</p>
          <p>Looking at this cost increase in detail, the &#x2013; by far the largest component representing 67% of the net cost increase relates to cost, largely recouped in our revenue line. We paid $371 million more for fuel and energy cost during the period. However, we are uniquely positioned in our industry to capture a revenue benefit from higher energy prices. Our unrivalled suite of energy projects captured an additional 2.8 billion of revenue, which is 7.5 times higher than the increase in costs.</p>
          <p>We are also incurring higher freight charges, $70 million, where we deliver product to our customers. But this is a pass through cost. We have and are continuing to pay more, $204 million, for commodity related input materials. The prices of coke, sulfuric acid, caustic soda, all increased by more than 50% since December 2007.</p>
          <p>In addition, approximately 20% of the net cost increase relates to &#x2013; largely to non-recurring or one-off incidents and I have referred to some of those before. Our continuous and intensive focus on cost containment through our various business excellence initiatives have again delivered, this time to $225 million of cost reduction.</p>
          <p>So the net impact of higher prices added 6.6 billion to EBIT. This is not just good fortune. It is a reflection of having a superior mix of high margin commodities in our portfolio and consistently achieving strong production and quality growth.</p>
          <p>Our operational excellence meant that an estimated 64% of this increased revenue flowed through to EBIT. This is an outstanding achievement in the current environment and even more remarkable when we consider the significant disruptions to production during the financial year. And of course, the other key focus area is always on the delivery of value to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>So our priorities for cash flow remained unchanged. Our first priority has always been to reinvest in growth opportunities that deliver greater value to shareholders. We have done that both organically and through acquisitions. Capital investment and spending on exploration activities increased to a record level in the 2008 financial year. The majority of this is still non-productive capital expenditure and there will always be a time lag between cash spend and production. Despite this our return on capital employed has increase from 11% in 2002 financial year to 38% in the 2008 financial year.</p>
          <p>Our second priority for cash flow is to maintain a solid A credit rating and as of 30 of June our net gearing stood at 18%, reflecting the strength of our balance sheet at a time of extreme credit tightness. And finally our third priority is to return excess funds to shareholders, as Marius said we are not in the condition to do buybacks at this time. But we have re-based our final dividend to $0.41 per share.</p>
          <p>And for a second consecutive year, we have increased the base level from which we will pay dividends in the future. This is a strong signal of our Board's confidence in the long-term outlook. This represents a significant as Marius said 150% increase in annual dividend in only three years. And during the same period, annual earnings per share have increased by 163%, reflecting our strong results and value accretive share buyback program. Once again, we continue to lead our industry in a disciplined approach to capital management.</p>
          <p>Finally, I would like to again make the point that today we have delivered another outstanding result. But great financial outcomes have their foundation in strong operating performance. And in 2001 (sic) [2008] financial year, we demonstrated just that. We operated our assets well. We delivered strong production growth and managed costs in a very challenging environment. We commissioned 10 new projects and continue to invest in the business at record levels. We continue to reward shareholders for a significantly increased and rebased dividend.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll hand you back to Marius.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alex. Now that Alex has taken you through the results, I would like to highlight a few points. As Alex has said, BHP Billiton had another fantastic, outstanding year. These results flow out of a strategy that has been unchanged, since we put the company together in its present form going on for a decade now. It pulls on our proven track record of delivering great financial results underpinned by solid operational delivery.</p>
          <p>Growth in high margin volumes to grow value is particularly important during periods of supply/demand that give high prices, such as we experienced during the past year. So we're particularly pleased with the volume growth that we've &#x2013; again for the seventh consecutive year we've grown the company in terms of volume. This time we brought online 10 projects, these projects and the further seven that we sanctioned during the year will continue to grow our volumes in fiscal year 2009 and beyond.</p>
          <p>Again, I want to emphasize the unbroken record of increases in production. We will continue this trend in fiscal year '09 and we estimate circa 10% growth for the next year across our portfolio.</p>
          <p>As we've said, growth is particularly valuable when it's added in the highest margin products. And for us over the past year virtually all of our growth were in the highest margin products of iron ore, petroleum, manganese and base metals.</p>
          <p>The unrivaled diversification of our portfolio is not an accident. It is the product of an unchanged strategy. And this has meant that despite earthquakes, rain, power shortages and other operating challenges, we've once again been able to maintain the group margin at 48%. This means that as in the past products with superior performance in our diversified portfolio more than offset challenges that we had in other projects &#x2013; in other products.</p>
          <p>Alex showed us again today the Jackson Pollock chart that shows the benefits of diversification and graphically illustrates the point. I want to just reflect for a minute on the magnitude of that number. EBIT margin of 48% means that for every $2 of revenue $1 goes to the EBIT line. That is an exceptional achievement. But let me say a few words about the macro-economic outlook and today I will deal because they are different issues that work separately with demand and separately with supply.</p>
          <p>Starting with the demand side, I don't need to remind you what all of you have lived for the last year. That in the developed economies the rates of growth are slowing down, driven by credit and liquidity issues in the financial system, the impact of high food, energy and raw material price inflation and the knock-on impact on businesses and consumers.</p>
          <p>For example, the US business confidence is at a 16-year low &#x2013; sorry, consumer confidence is at a 16-year low. Japan has just posted the lowest growth rate that it's had in the past six years. And we are seeing some flow through, to the developing economies. The developing economies are not completely isolated. In China, we slowed perhaps a couple of percentage points, but it is really on this topic that I want to say a few words just to tell where that slowdown is occurring and what the impact on us is.</p>
          <p>We see the slowdown really occurring mostly in the light manufacturing sector. Those sectors that are predominantly export-oriented. For the domestically driven, investment driven sectors, such as the steel business, which are driven by domestic demand conditions and the maritime nature of the Chinese economy, we see these businesses performed well despite increases in the energy and raw materials costs.</p>
          <p>Now having just spent some time in Beijing and apologies to those Britons in the audience today, I didn't see most of the gold medals, but in interaction with our customers over the past week, they absolutely support this outlook that I have just stated.</p>
          <p>Shorter term outlook in the more middle-class, more finished good oriented metals such as nickel and particularly in aluminium appears somewhat weaker. The bulks and steel and so on remains more resilient. But the long-term fundamentals for these economies remain intact. Just take a look.</p>
          <p>China has averaged at about 10% growth for an extended period of time. And what I want to emphasis is the cumulative nature of growth. From about 2001 that 10% growth became important not only as a percentage, but really as an absolute value in the world economy. At the same time, in about 2002, 2003, we've also started seeing an acceleration of growth in the other developing economies, such as India, but also South East Asia and other economies.</p>
          <p>Now while the IMF data shows that from 2001 to 2007, the developed economies halved their growth rate, I've already spoken about the effect in China, because it is so largely a domestic economy that feed-through has been much more muted. And I also want to point out in particular that each unit of GDP in a developing economy is about four to five times as material intensive as a unit of GDP in the developed economies. So, ironically this is a company that is very much leveraged to the developing economies, and those are the economies that have shown more resilience here.</p>
          <p>Only the long-term will tell us to what degree China is only loosely coupled to the developed economies. But we can certainly say that given the maritime nature, given the domestic nature of its &#x2013; of its growth base. There clearly is some divergence between China, the main driver of materials demand and the rest of the world.</p>
          <p>As we've said China is mainly a domestic demand story, and the bulk of demand in raw materials is driven by investment and private consumption. Trade is an important element of the activity and we've spoken about some of those light manufacturing sectors are facing some pressure at the moment. And obviously trade reflects the integration of China into the world economy. But growth continues to be driven in a domestic fashion. Why? The demand is all about industrialization and urbanization. And let's just take a few figures to just step back, look at the effect of cumulation and trying to create a picture in your mind to what is going to happen.</p>
          <p>China is forecast to add 40 billion square meters of floor space in the next 20 years at about 75 kilograms of steel per square meter there would be over the next 20 years, 3 billion tonnes of steel, just going into the construction sector.</p>
          <p>Now, let's put that in perspective. From '63 to 2007 half a century, Australia supplied just about 3 billion tonnes of contained iron ore units. That means that in construction alone and there is obviously many, many other sectors that consume steel. But just in construction, we would have to supply from the pallbearer the equivalent amount that was supplied in the last &#x2013; almost a century. But we've got to do that in a much shorter timeframe.</p>
          <p>So let's take another look. The industrialization of China means that as we can see here the accumulated steel stock in China, is already as much as the US did in the last &#x2013; most of the last century, from 1900 to 1970.</p>
          <p>At growth rate similar to this year, by 2015, China will have accumulated more steel in inventory than the US achieved in its entire history. And that means that there will be a very large call on iron ore, manganese and eventually coking coal. This call really has got no historical parallel.</p>
          <p>But as nations industrialize, they also become heavy users of energy, while China's energy consumption is about 20% of world primary energy use and contrast that against metals and cement and so on where it's between 30 and 50% world demand.</p>
          <p>Take note that as we show on this slide, China has accounted for half of the world's incremental energy growth. The supply system is struggling to meet this demand and has had a very noticeable impact on the world energy feedstock prices. But, more importantly, the world's energy needs and China's energy needs have also revealed a strong reliance on coal. And this is a particular challenge for China, which is trying to rebalance its energy mix for many reasons, environmental not being the least of it.</p>
          <p>As the world becomes increasingly concerned about climate change and the contribution from gas, nuclear power looks safe to grow most strongly, placing a premium on long-term secure and reliable sources of supply for these products, products which we happen to supply.</p>
          <p>So, the demand side is clearly important. China is clearly important. However, it is only one half of the equation. The other half is the supply side. Our industry is faced as an industry and will continue to face serious challenges on the supply side, as operations are pushed harder in order to produce this incremental demand.</p>
          <p>There are a number of well documented factors that people have spoken about that limit the ability for miners to expand production. And they include on the left-hand side here, things like equipment stress, industrial action and wage disputes, labor and equipment shortages, inflationary pressures and then infrastructural problems and things like power, which we've seen in China, South Africa, Chile, Brazil heading that way and so on and also in the existing operations a deterioration of ore grades being mined, particularly in the base metal businesses. And we are starting to see export tariffs and quotas being imposed. All of these things make it more difficult to expand production as an industry.</p>
          <p>However, those factors on the right-hand side, which impact future demand &#x2013; supply growth, have a greater impact on the future supply growth dynamics. Firstly, it doesn't matter how much we dig out of the ground, if we can't get it our customers it just doesn't count. They can't use it. Continued infrastructural constraints will be of interest.</p>
          <p>We are also seeing that as an industry we are not developing very large new territory, new ore bodies. We've got no new Escondida, we've got no new Bingham Canyon, we've got no new El Teniente, we've got no new Grasberg and so on. None of those are being developed. Instead developments are increasingly likely to be smaller, lower risk and &#x2013; sorry lower grade and higher risk.</p>
          <p>On top of this, we've got equipment shortages and rising capital costs, causing longer lead times. And we've got higher nationalism which increases the risk and knocks out some of those speculative capital, project finance, smaller players and so on that mooted entering into these new environments. All of these things are going to constrain supply and it's compounded by the fact, that the absolute size of the markets are now much larger.</p>
          <p>So let's just continue on this theme for a second. The issue of truck and tires are well known and people have written about that a lot. But we are also seeing long lead-times in shovels, draglines long-walls. In some cases people express concerns about the future availability of explosives. And not only do we face that from our suppliers as an industry and I want to continue to talk about the industry, but those suppliers face constraints from their suppliers. For example, the growth in the wind farms has meant that there is shortage of large bearings. There is a chronic shortage of capacity to manufacture the large castings and forgings which we require for mills and super class trucks.</p>
          <p>And we have got an aging work force producing many of these things in the industry. So it's not just an issue of adding new capacity and equipment. The combination of equipment lead-time delays, tightness in the labor market and all of those things that we've just spoken about is flowing through to project schedules for the industry.</p>
          <p>In the copper industry, for example, if we take a look at what it forecast in 2006, or what the analyst forecast in 2006, some 18 months ago &#x2013; perhaps two years ago, now project schedules of those same projects are two to three years late. So we've lost three years in about 18 months of schedule as an industry.</p>
          <p>Analysts continue to be too optimistic. And year-after-year, they have to revise their production growth forecast down.</p>
          <p>Now I've spoken about the industry, what about BHP Billiton? Despite these challenges BHP Billiton is exceptionally well positioned to grow and I point at that unbroken track record of delivering volume growth year-after-year.</p>
          <p>We got particularly &#x2013; we got a strong balance sheet, we have got a large scope. For example, in February we approved a billion dollars of pre-expenditure on RGP 5. Smaller business, single project business just can't do that sort of a thing. And early funding you know helps us to procure long lead-time items in order to make sure that we as a company remain on track with our volume expansions. Not all industry participants can do this.</p>
          <p>I have taken some time to talk about the macro-economic outlook in the supply side. Let me summarize, while the short term outlook is certainly uncertain in the developed economies, the longer term fundamentals remains absolutely intact, those fundamentals on which we base our investment plans.</p>
          <p>And we also believe, in particular, that the industry is taking insufficient notice. The analysts are insufficiently taking notice of supply side issues and they haven't received enough attention and they will continue to be a key determinant in commodity prices going forward. This was my message in February; this is my message today.</p>
          <p>Now, while we are not immune to cost pressures, our scale, scope and diversification does provide significant competitive advantages. We've spoken about the balance sheet strength, long lead-time items, pre-commitments and so on. But let's also consider for a moment, our relationship with our key vendors. Once we've secured build slots, we can redeploy them around the company as various project lead-times change without losing those both slots. If you've got one or two projects, you just can't do that.</p>
          <p>These benefits come from a disciplined execution of a consistent strategy. A strategy that remains unchanged for most of the last decade. And from an operational perspective, we continue to drive towards simplicity, accountability and effectiveness in our operations.</p>
          <p>Simplicity helps us to deliver a profit per employee that is two to five times as much as our closest competitors; two to five times as much profit per employee as our closest competitor. This comes with simplicity, simplicity comes with many managing fewer, larger assets; being up-stream focused, which makes for an overall company that is simpler to manage and easier to expand.</p>
          <p>Our track record of project delivery and our high quality portfolio of growth projects will allow us to continue to deliver growth into a strong demand environment and delivering the types of financial results that we also saw today.</p>
          <p>Growing production year-after-year, across the portfolio is based on a carefully constructed capability. Growing production at essentially the same rate in the future, as we've delivered over much of the last decade year-after-year.</p>
          <p>Production growth that we've repeatedly demonstrated we are capable of since the formulation of the company in this present form. And it's not about volume growth at any price; capital, risk and margins do matter. We've got a significant proportion of our near-term growth, which is essentially in our backyard. We've spoken about that many times.</p>
          <p>Owning large low cost Tier-1 assets allow us to conduct lower risk brownfield developments. We know the resource, we understand the environment and we've got existing infrastructure in place. The growth is hence lower risk. It's also been generated in political regimes that we are familiar with and countries with fewer risks for financial risk for our investment. And importantly, for us growth is being generated from high margin commodities.</p>
          <p>In fact, we expect that nearly 63% of our growth in production over the next five years will be generated in those CSGs that have had more than 50% EBIT margins over the last three years ensuring that this volume growth will also be the bedrock of value growth for our shareholders. And our longer-term options really have the same characteristics.</p>
          <p>As you know, we usually talk about our growth in terms of our five-year planning period and in the longer-term. For the longer-term, we normally show that double chart, but today we've split out the $90 billion or so on that double chart that we normally show you and we've shown them in terms of brownfield, greenfield and we've shown them in terms of new geography and existing geography.</p>
          <p>I want to highlight the point that even as we look beyond the five-year horizon, our growth is about aggressively expanding in our backyard, aggressively expanding in those environments that we know, well belong &#x2013; well beyond our five-year planning period.</p>
          <p>So as I have shown you BHP Billiton has an absolutely fantastic future as a standalone company. But in the context of the supply and demand challenges for the longer-term that I just outlined, the combination of Rio Tinto and BHP will be value-accretive for both sets of shareholders. Let me summarize again how we propose to unlock value from this combination in three main ways.</p>
          <p>Firstly, by optimizing mineral basin positions and the infrastructure in a supply constrained world, allowing us lower cost of production for the combined group and allowing us to unlock additional volumes by matching resources to infrastructure.</p>
          <p>Secondly, by creating an enhanced platform for future growth. By deploying scarce resources to those highest value, most NPV accretive opportunities and becoming as a larger company, an even more global company, better positioned as the partner for choice in new developments and through being able to manage exploration and other types of development more efficiently.</p>
          <p>We said that this will be value-creative for both sets of shareholders and the synergies and combination benefits and might I add synergies and combinations benefits that are absolutely unique to this set of overlapping assets will be derived mainly from economies of scale for example in procurement, avoiding duplication and therefore reducing corporate and divisional non-operating costs and most importantly, delivering more product more quickly to our customers, more quickly than otherwise would have been the case. A situation of two plus one equals five.</p>
          <p>So in summary, our diversified portfolios delivered excellent results. Our long-term demand outlook remains strong. The constraints of the supply side will play an important role in pricing dynamics for our commodities. And we are well set for the future with a fantastic diversified portfolio of assets and commodities predominately in stable geographies, large-scale control infrastructure and a very low risk growth portfolio.</p>
          <p>The BHP Billiton FY '08 results show that we can contend with all sorts of headwinds and tailwinds and still turn-in great results. It's not just a mixture of good luck and bad luck, but a mixture of the right strategies, the right people and superior assets. They have come together to produce this striking result. We face our fiscal year '09 and beyond confident our strategies, people and assets will allow us to successfully manage the road ahead.</p>
          <p>And on that note I'd like to finish and take questions. We will rotate around the various locations starting in London and then after, we will go to Sydney and then finally to the phones. If you could address the questions to me in the first instance, I will pass them to Alex as is required.</p>
          <p>If I may have the first question from London please, please take a microphone from one of our representatives here and if you could kindly state your name and organization clearly, before stating the question that would help a lot. So may I have the first question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Marius, its Andrew Keen from Sanford Bernstein. Just two questions, firstly, on the commodity markets. Can you confirm whether you are seeing any particular weakness at the moment from your own product in various markets?</p>
          <p>And secondly, on the Rio bids, can you give any update on the regulatory process, whether you are still confident about not needing any divestments and what the timing might look like? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Andrew, thank you. On the &#x2013; I think as you've seen on our set of the results here today, perhaps nickel and aluminium stand out in terms of cost pressures in the industry. Perhaps, firstly a word about nickel; we do have some operations, not in our portfolio, but in the industry at large which is probably not making a lot of cash at the moment and it wouldn't surprise me if we saw some capacity shutdowns.</p>
          <p>I think aluminium is perhaps the one that stands out a little bit more starkly. Because not only have we had cost pressures in the industry at large, and if you go and analyze our supplementary information, and the other results that are out in the market, you will see that our general view that aluminium is less capable of passing EBIT to bottom line is industry reinforced.</p>
          <p>And that is coupled with the fact that the smelter build program in China has been very aggressive. And so we are actually looking at a supply/demand situation there that is slightly more loose than in most of our products. So we've got to take a look at nickel going forward, but in particular, aluminium is probably the product that is showing weakest at the moment in terms of profit potential.</p>
          <p>And in terms of the regulatory update, very difficult for me to talk about the discussions and so on. Our original timetable unchanged. Our basic analysis of the situation unchanged, but you will have to forgive me for today not giving you a detailed look. We continue to believe that we are on very solid ground economically, particularly, in those products where we will have the most scrutiny. But, Andrew, just can't comment more than that.</p>
          <p>Sorry, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah it's Jason Fairclough from Merrill Lynch. Hi, just a question on marketing and price discovery. Really you've been leading the way in terms of changing the way a lot of these products are priced. Could you talk a little bit about the iron ore spot market, how that's going and maybe the potential you see in some of your other products that still aren't spot priced to move to that sort of pricing mechanism?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason, we regard ourselves as a volume supplier in the price stake. We've spoken about that a lot and we've demonstrated that over the last &#x2013; since the company was formed. We believe we compete in terms of cost efficiencies and the nature of the ore bodies that we have got and geographic proximity and so on. And hence our drive for our market is really a dual mission statement: one, get today's price today. Secondly, if you don't know what today's price is, please try and create something which will tell you what today's price is. And we've been unflinching in that in diamonds, in energy coal, manganese and so on.</p>
          <p>In iron ore, there is great interest for a traded product. I do think that one of the next developments that will happen is that there will be a physical market develop, in the same way that in the coal liberalization we had the screen API market, and then we have global coal which was a physical market, and those two really drove the developments. I think that over the next couple of periods, we will see a greater transparency and physical market develop to augment the traded market. And I think that those two things need to come together to really give us accurate price discovery going forward.</p>
          <p>So we're still very interested in that. We continue to drive that. And as we've said before we would not like to sign any new term iron ore contracts that are based on traditional benchmark systems. I do think the fact that there is now a plethora of so-called benchmark prices basically tells you that our prediction over the last couple of years that the benchmark system is coming apart at the seams, has really &#x2013; we've sort of lost a pant-leg now and I think the situation is largely irreversible from here going forward.</p>
          <p>With respect to other products, one always has to take a look at the size of the market and the liquidity in the market. And one of the things that's attractive for iron ore, why we think we can get a liquid market there, is that it's now an enormous market, like copper, like aluminium and so on. And size and number of participants in a market is really very important. So I wouldn't like to look far beyond that. People sometimes think that some of the smaller markets, you can do the same thing with. But that's really a little bit more difficult to get the same. For now, we really focused on continuing to drive liquidity in those products that we've already done: diamonds, energy coal and obviously all of the other traded products and then adding iron ore to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Marius. Rob Clifford; Deutsche Bank. Just a question on the return to shareholders, you mentioned some regretful disappointment having to stop the buyback, which suggests that you would like to continue that. Do the regulatory issues prevent you from buybacks for the remainder of the takeover period? And do they, or do that preclude special dividends as an alternative means to beef up your return to shareholders to previous levels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Perhaps the best person to give you some detail around that Rob is Alex. Alex did you &#x2013; did you get those two parts of the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I did Marius. Yes, we, since December '07, when our mandate expired, we are in possession of what's consider to be confidential, or internally privileged information from the UK takeover panel perspective. So, that puts an imposition that we cannot</p>
          <p>order new buyback activities.</p>
          <p>In terms of the special dividend, that's something that we haven't really favored anytime in our recent history. And if you look at the priorities for cash utilization in the company, and we went for that both myself and Marius, being first of all the investment in future growth. And second, the balance sheet. You understand that probably an 18% gearing is a bit strong, and is stronger than the solid A credit rating that we are targeting. But that has to do with our commitment in the offer that once the merger is completed, we would execute a $30 billion buyback. So that's building that capacity in the balance sheet, so we can execute to that commitment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Alex. I wonder while we are in Sydney, we've taken a couple of questions here in London. Could we take a couple of questions in Sydney? Alex, if you could just moderate there and direct the questions to me in the first instance please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Vicky Binns from Merrill Lynch. I'm very impressed by the CapEx outlook, you're looking for next year of 13.5 billion, of which 12 billion is growth projects. And you've even clarified that only 700 million of that is petroleum. Could you give us a little granularity as to what makes up that mammoth CapEx commitment, including any update you might have on Olympic Dam Expansion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Vicky, let me &#x2013; let me try and take a stab. Now obviously, I especially memorized all of those figures for you, but I can give you &#x2013; I can give you some broad pieces. There is a significant piece that comes out of the RGP 5 program, the iron ore program. There is a continued ramp-up of projects that are already in execution. For example the Worsley project, which is fairly material. Some of the projects that we've got on Petroleum is sanctioned, will come through there. There is a Guinea Alumina project, which comes through there. So really if you take a look at the appendix slides that we've got, which shows the quantum and the sanctioning date for those projects. I think you should be able to reconstruct that from that, but there is also some money for Olympic Dam in there.</p>
          <p>But if I could quickly make a &#x2013; just a quick note of how that will flow. We really are for Olympic Dam in EIS [Environmental Impact Study] preparation period. That will become public early in calendar year '09, 12 months display period roughly and then the sequential development starts after that. So there is not a material portion of this that is going toward Olympic Dam in the next year. It really is a combination of the Alumina projects, the Iron Ore projects and then a number of other projects that have already been sanctioned and are ramping up. Alex, I don't know &#x2013; if you &#x2013; you can add a few words to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are spot on, Marius. On page 52 you have some of the pre-feasibility projects there. Quite of a few Met Coal projects coming in and some Energy Coal projects as well. But there is a portion that are projects that are currently under execution that continue to &#x2013; that process in next year and some of the pre-feasibility projects getting their sanction, expecting to get their sanction next fiscal year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alex, can I have the next question from Sydney?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Hi Marius, it's Craig Campbell at Morgan Stanley. Marius in Australia, the government's released a discussion paper on carbon, just wondering if BHP has had a chance to assess how that's going to impact going forward, and how is it looking to impact maybe your capital allocation decisions in Australia? Basically, do you think there is potential negative impact coming through here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Craig we've obviously spent a huge amount of time looking at greenhouse not only in the Australian context, but also on a worldwide basis. Our basics stance and this is reflected in our greenhouse policy is that carbon in the atmosphere is a problem and that the world has to stabilize that. That's the starting point for us.</p>
          <p>Second one is that &#x2013; aligned with that, what we would like to see are implementations that actually reduce the carbon in the atmosphere. And some of the other trading schemes that we've seen in Europe, for example, didn't achieve that in the first go, because of design issues. Perhaps the most important thing for us as we think about carbon trading schemes and we think about how the carbon actually is reduced is through investment by business. So any scheme, well-designed scheme that gives investment, the right investment signals with limited volatility and so on will allow us to take those investment decisions to reduce our carbon footprint.</p>
          <p>So perhaps, just to put that in simple terms, low volatility implementations are very important to us, based on our deep experience in Europe and other places. If we look at our overall analysis of carbon taxes, it really does depend on where the marginal producer is located from a geographical perspective. We are in commodity markets and the supply and demand curve sets prices. If that marginal producer is subject to carbon taxes you are likely to get price passthrough of the carbon tax or whatever &#x2013; let's just call it a carbon tax for now.</p>
          <p>In those industries where the marginal producer is unlikely to get a carbon tax imposed, the carbon tax will be more of a deadweight economic cost. So that's the way we look at it. Let me just recap quickly. We think carbon is a problem; we favor schemes that give investment stability so that businesses can reduce the carbon emissions. And then thirdly, the way we look at the different products is where the marginal producer sits, and whether that marginal producer is likely to pay a carbon tax anywhere in the near future.</p>
          <p>If we just take for example China, without making the answer too lengthy, a lot of marginal producers for lot of our products sit in China. Our assessment would be that it's unlikely that China gets carbon taxes anywhere soon. So at least for an intermediate period, you are likely to see carbon taxes on a worldwide basis as being a net economic cost to this industry.</p>
          <p>So, Craig, I don't know if that answered your question.</p>
          <p>Okay. Could we have the next question in Sydney please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning over there Marius. Brendan Harris from Macquarie.</p>
          <p>I just wanted to go through the logic for the investment &#x2013; the significant investment that you're putting into the alumina business. You discussed earlier that you saw the aluminium market's supply/demand possibly not being as exciting as elsewhere. Yet, you are putting significant capital into &#x2013; in certain areas as well where there is a great degree of inflationary pressure such as Worsley in Western Australia and the capital intensity there, certainly isn't the lowest we've seen for the last sort of five years. So I'm just trying to get sense for what that means &#x2013; can you maybe just elaborate on how you see alumina pricing developing? Do you see a movement away from a linkage or how do you see the linkage progressing and how does that tie into your view on the aluminium price.</p>
          <p>And just secondly, if I can, just on Ravensthorpe, can I just get a sense, possibly the amount of costs that are actually being expensed that would otherwise if you weren't say through the commissioning phase, that would otherwise have been capitalized; i.e. the need to possibly bring in contractors for immediate work, or to replace valves, pumps and things like that, as you work through, I guess, the typical problems that one faces with the laterite? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the alumina side, I think the best guidance can be found in our results. If I recall the figure &#x2013; and they've carefully positioned me at the lectern without my crib notes in front of me. But if I recall, our alumina prices moved by about 1% of LME over the last year to about $365 a tonne from about 345 last year. Roughly speaking at about to same average aluminium price over the year as the last year, which shows that that linkage to alumina price is indeed coming though.</p>
          <p>Both Alex and myself, which have spent a lot of time in the alumina industry are probably of a belief that we will continue to see a movement in that direction. And under the scenarios that we postulate, Brendan, very simply put we are investing in these two brownfield expansions that we currently have under construction, because we think that they will be value accretive. And particularly, because despite the inflationary conditions in WA [Western Australia], Worsley is right down there amongst the cheapest producers in the world.</p>
          <p>So we do base those decisions purely on whether we see those investments will be value accretive. We clearly believe that there is more room for alumina to re-price relative to metal. We continue to see metal smelting capacity in some cases where it's based on grid power and so on, just being a conversion business. And that view is really unchanged with what we discussed over the long period of time.</p>
          <p>With respect to Ravensthorpe and the particular accounting treatment, perhaps a few words upfront. Normal commission is taking place here. I wouldn't say it's more easy or more difficult than any other complex plant. And perhaps Alex can just take us through exactly how that $320 million of expensed items is calculated. Alex?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can give you the full details of that as &#x2013; including the results. But basically what you have is all your fixed costs are in place, all your startup costs are in place. And as you gradually commission and ramp up each component of your plant that weight is separated from the normal results, like we would do if any other plant of any other component, all the startups are separated into other results.</p>
          <p>So in this case what you see is the depreciation of all the other costs of this ramp up that does not reflect economics of that plant separated until such time that it reaches a reasonable constant, consistent production level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Brendan, perhaps I will move at this stage just back to London, take a couple more questions here and then I will go to the phones. So if I can have the first question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Sylvain Brunet with Exane BNP Paribas. First question on coal, just to confirm what volume on &#x2013; in both Met Coal and Energy Coal, you expect to be priced at market prices in the coming financial year?</p>
          <p>My second question is on the rate of cost increase. What guidance you could give us going into the next financial year?</p>
          <p>And last question is on the volume growth in the petroleum division, if you could give us also a bit of range there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Can you just repeat the last part of that question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Last one is growth in the petroleum division, volume growth guidance, please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Firstly, on the coal, what percentage &#x2013; what coal we've got priced? We have no update to what we put out in our production report. There are two particular things on our website that you can consult, which should give you a very precise view of what is priced and unpriced, which is our last production report; and the press release that we put out when we lifted force majeure. Both of these in conjunction will give you the precise amount of carryover tonnes into the FY '09 financial year. And we have no update to that today.</p>
          <p>In terms of cost increase, perhaps the best guidance can be taken from, where Alex showed us that for the above inflationary cost increase or the super inflationary cost increase, the vast majority of that really, as Alex said, two-thirds of that are in those inputs which we buy. So it's oil and energy proxies, freight, and other raw materials such as caustic soda, sulfuric acid, sulfur and so on.</p>
          <p>Rather than me try and forecast that which will be an instantaneous forecast today as well, I think the base guidance that you can have to model that through is to take that we try and achieve floating price inputs for those prices as well. So if the fuel &#x2013; if petroleum prices go up, our inflation on that proportion goes up. If petroleum prices go down, it goes down again. And so really the inflation that we can expect is a function of where those input prices settle, which are very transparent and so on.</p>
          <p>In terms of our growth in petroleum business, our overall guidance for our five-year plan period is unchanged, that we'd like to grow that business by about 10% per year. Alex, I don't if you've got a little bit more precise volume guidance for exactly what that means in the year, in the coming financial year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Marius, we haven't given guidance to exact point at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So another 10% production increase over this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, next &#x2013; sorry, just here in front.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Sophia Hart from UBS. There seems to be a bit of a race in growing LNG capacity in the Pacific Basin, everyone wants to be in Australia to grow LNG production. Obviously, you're already well-placed for long-term contracts. We are seeing some amendments to the advantage of producers. There is also a lot of interest in coal bed methane in Australia. Is this an area that you'd be likely to look at or to get involved with, and otherwise do you have any other plans to participate in that race in LNG, especially in spot prices as &#x2013; or spot contracts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we've stated in our Petroleum briefing that we are very optimistic that as over the next four years the majority of our LNG contracts roll off, that LNG particularly in the North Asian Basin will trade much closer to liquids parity. And we've seen that that is starting to happen with the ore mining gas into North Asia being re-priced completely. Some of our contracts are currently under negotiation and we have no update in guidance, but to say, we believe that you'll get full price linkage to oil without caps and floors for most of these volumes as we go forward.</p>
          <p>In terms of LNG, our most immediate objectives are monetization of those gas statics that we've got in Western Australia. They're material, we've got excellent partners there and that clearly the Scarborough and Thebe field which are proximate, that's one set of developments that we'd like to push forward as quickly as we can. Our partner there obviously in Scarborough is ExxonMobil.</p>
          <p>In terms of coal bed methane, there was considerable debate about that a couple of years ago. You will recall that we had a small coal bed methane business, which ultimately in Queensland got rolled up into &#x2013; I think the Arrow consortium. We concluded a couple of years ago and we have no update to that conclusion that drilling lots of holes laying lots of pipe and being on a treadmill is really not in line with businesses that we'd like to be in. That guidance is really unchanged and we've subsequently sold out of our coal bed methane positions not only in Australia but also in China. It's probably not a business that you'll see us pursue to any great extent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mauritsio Caroli from AXA Investment Managers. I've two questions if I may. The first one probably for Alex is on the cash flow. I've noted on the cash flow statement that trade at end of the receivables have increased very, very substantially from about 1 billon in the past couple of years to almost to 5 billion. I just wanted to have a bit more of detail on the causes of that, please?</p>
          <p>And the second question for Marius, I guess I assume you can answer to that. I would like to have a bit of a feedback for the meetings that you've been having in recent months with shareholders, regarding the combination between Rio and BHP what sorts of feedback do you get from the people you have met?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Difficult to summarize the second one succinctly, but let me try and answer the first one on trade and receivables. Its largely just price, if I look at our days of receivables across the commodities, overdues, and so on, I don't see any changes there. So the five-fold increase in receivables that you've got sort of more or less mirrors the five-fold increase in prices that we've had across our portfolio. There is nothing structural. There in fact, it's a number that we watch very closely and because we've got a centralized marketing organization, we actually have very, very good control over that. No change there.</p>
          <p>There is obviously some capital impact as you spend capital, which also impacts there. So we've just got a separate a little bit the capital investment portfolio from the pure trade receivables on our commodities.</p>
          <p>In terms of feedback from shareholders, I joked earlier this morning that we said we would be patient and people didn't believe us. We're clearly set in for the long haul here, and what is it? Well, it is a complex transaction. Best way that I would describe it is that, in the beginning people were a little bit shocked, that this proposal could be made. I think that people have now generally worked through and understand all of these volume and synergy benefits that can be had if these two sets of assets can be put together. I think I would be honest in and fair to say that there is to a certain extent a little bit of wait and see attitude, particularly, here in Europe, where it is the holiday season. And people really are waiting to see how we tick those boxes on the various regulatory fronts.</p>
          <p>So, but I think that from understanding how the assets will fit together, from understanding what the standalone capabilities of the two companies are like, there has been a great growth in understanding. We really now need to progress this through those various hurdles that we've got ahead of us.</p>
          <p>Let me just take a few questions on the telephone. I'm mindful that time is running out &#x2013; ticking quite quickly, if I could have the first question on the telephone please? And then I'll see if there any &#x2013; there is any chance to return to Sidney perhaps.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question we have it's from the line of Peter O'Connor of Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead Mr. O'Connor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Marius. In your recent trips to China, have your discussions with your new shareholder been constructive?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I actually, I have been &#x2013; I did spend almost week and a half in the Beijing Olympic Games. But we actually didn't have any formal investor discussions or indeed customer discussions at that time. We obviously had, oh gosh, I would say 95% of our main Chinese customers represented as invitees of our company both at the opening and then later on, but there has been &#x2013; that really has been the focus: to have fun in Beijing over the last couple of days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Prior to that Marius and the intervening period between the purchase and the Olympics?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry; just say that again, Peter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any discussions between their purchase of stock back in February and the Olympics?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, the line is terrible. So you'll have to speak, very slowly, my apologies...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Since their acquisition of that line or their position in the company, has there been constructive discussions with them, any time during the course of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter as you know, we can't comment on individual shareholder discussions. But you also will understand that there are some strict limitations under the UK takeovers code that limits what discussions can be had with Chinalco, but certainly for the avoidance of doubt. I mean Chinalco was one of the guests that we took to the opening ceremony of the Olympics along with a whole slew of other people.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's fine. Marius, could you just clarify, you mentioned the Olympic Dam before and the study that you're going to move into in the start of 2009? Did you suggest that once that study was concluded and the review period of 12 months was completed, you would then move to the next phase? By that do you mean development or do you mean further feasibility work?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, Peter we would certainly hope that upon completion of the EIS, we would have ticked most of the development sequence that we would have &#x2013; have in place for sanctioning. So with that timeframe that I sort of loosely indicated and by no means do I want to cement that in stone because EISs are unpredictable in their nature. But certainly at the end of that we would hope that we can move towards starting the development sequence of this asset.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That would be early mid 2010 &#x2013; best case?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's what I said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Marius.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Peter. The next question on the phones, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from line of Mr. David Flemings of Macquarie. Please go ahead Mr. Flemings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, gents. Just a very quick question on the slide of the rate of cost increase of the 4.3%. I wonder if you could give some color on that with respects to the various customer service groups i.e. sort of coal and iron ore and et cetera, how varied it was that across the various divisions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, let me take a quick stab at that. I think Alex is probably the better person to answer around that. We have seen a couple of CSGs that are not that energy intensive, not that raw materials input sensitive achieve great cost control, I think, if I take iron ore for example we had local currency, the Australian dollar so loose of FX effects, we had almost flat costs, like a couple of percent up. In Petroleum, the on field cash costs actually in nominal terms was unchanged on a year-on-year basis.</p>
          <p>In contrast to that are those CSGs, which have large input costs. And in particular I take a look at copper, where I think power cost in Escondida must have gone up &#x2013; and Chile must have gone up by over $100 million over the year and is set to go further in future. We also ramped-up leaching operations in the sulfide leach and in the Spence project, there in again it's no secret that sulfuric acid delivered Chile is probably $500 plus a ton so sulfuric acid consumption has been there.</p>
          <p>So the general distinction that I would make is those businesses, which have input costs versus those businesses that don't have that many input costs, so the processing related businesses. So copper I've already spoken about Nickel, obviously, sulfuric acid in Ravensthorpe. Olympic Dam &#x2013; sulfur in the Olympic Dam operations. And then I think people forget how much dirt we move in our metallurgical coal business. I mean that is by far the largest mover of dirt, substantial portion of that is moved by diesel. And obviously at the sort of 130, $140 oil price that we saw over the last quarter that impacts cost. So I hope that gives you a little bit of guidance.</p>
          <p>Alex, I don't know if you want to comment on that just for a few seconds more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm very impressed Marius. At BHP we all pay attention to costs and you certainly showing by example that you know every cost movement in the company, so you didn't leave me much to talk about, but I think one area that I'd like to reemphasize is the 225 million cost savings. Because that shows how each operation, each division there is no division that's not really contributing to that and that number has climbed over the years, if you go back and look how we've been delivering that, so just to close your comment, Marius.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alex. Let me take one more question from the phones, if we have any.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from the line of Warren Edney of ABN AMRO. Please go ahead, Mr. Edney.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Warren, good evening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Marius. I just wondered if you give us a bit an update on the coal business in South Africa and how that's faring with the shortage of power and what the outlook is and whether that's changed and is it possible to change the pricing mechanism going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Warren, our coal business has performed well in South Africa. The team has done very well. Obviously, the numbers that we see there are ex- the divestment of the two assets that we've got. But we like that business and that's why we've got the two coal projects that we're doing there at the moment Klipspruit and the DMO [Douglas-Middleburg Optimization] project.</p>
          <p>All of our coal from South Africa is essentially sold on index, either directly as a floating price or indirectly as a fixed price and the combination of a derivative and indeed in the derivative mark-to-market line, you will see that there is some of that economic position that flows through the P&amp;L there. But from an economic basis we essentially achieved the floating market price for 100% of the volumes out of South Africa, which incidentally is the same that we achieve out of Australia now as well, which is why this business has performed well from a profit perspective. So, it's not a business in South Africa that we are going to grow dramatically in terms of output. But the two projects that we are doing there, is going to cement a stable volume and make that into a long-term asset. And we like that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>In think we have come to the end of today. I am going to have the opportunity to see many of you over the next days and weeks. So I want to thank you for your attendance today, especially those in Sydney. I know that it is getting on. For those of you in coming earlier this morning in London, thank you very much for the effort made to be here and once again thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>