<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1285940" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call - Q&amp;A Teleconference</title>
    <date>2010-02-10</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2056</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Marius Kloppers, Chief Executive Officer, Executive Director and Chairman of the Group Management Committee</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Kieran Daly</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Jason Fairclough</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Robert Clifford</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Olivia Ker</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">David Pleming</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Peter Davey</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Sam Catalano</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to those of you calling in for our U.K., and South Africa Question-and-Answer Conference Call. Thank you for joining us. In order to give us the maximum time for questions, I'll make a few brief opening remarks.</p>
          <p>As always, I'd like to start off with safety. And I'm saddened to report that we've had four fatalities in the current financial year. Each one of these accidents is a tragic testament that we still have risks in our business, and importantly, is a reminder that we must never let up on our aim of zero harm. However, we are making continued progress, and the number of injuries at our operations reduced by 30% on a year-on-year basis, continuing a long-term improvement trend.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to results. During the half year, we saw a strong recovery in demand and prices for most of our commodities, as compared to the first half of the year. The rally in prices was driven by strong early recoveries in China and India, and the beginning of restocking across the developed economies later in the period.</p>
          <p>However, I do want to point out that although commodity prices have generally recovered, as compared to the first half of the 2009 calendar year, we obviously always report on a period-on-period basis, and in the reporting period, prices were still lower than the corresponding period in 2008.</p>
          <p>These low prices, together with stronger producer currencies, negatively impacted our earnings results for this half year, again compared to the corresponding period. However, through good operating performance and rigorous cost control, we were somewhat able to offset these factors.</p>
          <p>And despite the price and currency effects, our underlying EBIT margin remained at a healthy 38%, and underlying return on capital at 24%, the latter, in spite of substantial new investment spending that is not yet productive.</p>
          <p>The investment program continued to deliver volume growth. Particularly pleasing was that we had half year production records in two of our biggest businesses, namely iron ore and petroleum. Balance sheet remains strong. Net gearing is at a modest 15%, and continues to give us significant flexibility to invest in our business and increase returns to shareholders.</p>
          <p>Going forward, we remain cautious about the speed and strength of the global economic recovery in the &#x2013; across the developed world, in spite of the positive momentum in developing countries.</p>
          <p>Our longer term outlook is unchanged and robust driven by the factors that we've commented on before, continuing urbanization and industrialization of China and other developing economies. And in particular, I want to note again the materials-intensive nature of these countries' development.</p>
          <p>Our strategy has been unchanged for almost a decade, and has proved itself throughout the cycle. I want to reiterate again our focus on large, long-life Tier 1 resources with multiple expansion options, assets that are upstream and export-oriented, and also, diversified by commodity, geography and customer.</p>
          <p>And I want to emphasize that we have been able to, with this strategy, grow investment, maintain the balance sheet at a strong level, and increase our dividend at the same time.</p>
          <p>So on that note, I'd like to pause and, operator, if I may, have the first question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The first question is from Kieran Daly from Investec Securities. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Kieran.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Marius. Afternoon, Marius. I've got two questions on coal and they are both related to Tier 1 assets kind of definition that you have. First one is on Maruwai in Indonesia, the coking coal project, which you said I think last year that it didn't fit your definition of Tier 1. You were looking at options on that and stuff I heard recently suggest that you might be actually &#x2013; change your mind in that, retaining majority shareholding. And given your view on where you're positioned in coking coal, I just wonder what your plan is for that project at this stage?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, on thermal coal in South Africa, you've been paring back your coal portfolio quite a bit. But you've still got about 60% of your coal production in NSA, which is &#x2013; which goes to Eskom. And some of that is tied in with mines, which are also producer export. But a large chunk of it is the Khutala mine, which is just for Eskom. And I just wondered, it didn't seem to fit in your definition of Tier 1, and it's certainly not export-oriented, I just wondered what your plan is for that Khutala mine going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Kieran, perhaps the second question I can answer first. In our suite we would call the entire South African coal business is one asset as we define it. In the same way Queensland coal would be another one, Hunter Valley coal, and so on. So, if I classify what we call BECSA the South African coal business as a Tier 1 asset, it is the entirety of that coal business and I think that's the business that we've just &#x2013; in the process of investing $1.5 billion in; no particular comments about Khutala as one of the operations within that asset per se.</p>
          <p>On Maruwai, you are correct, in that, you say that we took this asset upon review. We had been waiting for an upturn in the coking coal market &#x2013; sorry, a growth in the coking coal market via growth in the Chinese opportunities for our business for some time. And our development plans, I would say, in Maruwai were relatively modest. We were going to build a relatively small mine, which we looked at and asked ourselves the question during the &#x2013; basically the depth of the financial crisis whether that was something that we wanted to do.</p>
          <p>I think what you should anticipate there is that we will continue ownership of that business. And that doesn't mean that we won't perhaps get a partner in as a result of the current process that we're running there. But I think you should also look towards, perhaps, a little bit more aggressive development of that resource. I am probably not at liberty to give you much more information on that, Kieran.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Jason Fairclough from Bank of America-Merrill Lynch. Go ahead. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jason. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead. Thank you, Mr. Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Marius. Yep, sorry. I had myself on mute. Good afternoon. And just one quick question I guess. Wonder if you could give us a little bit more color on the ramp up in your capital expenditure. To me, the new numbers look pretty huge and really I just want to understand the degree to which the step up reflects new projects and new scope that means increased production versus inflation in CapEx expectations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gosh, Jason, it's a little difficult to obviously make a long-term comparison of what you get for the dollar. But I would comment on the fact that everything that we've sanctioned on is currently in execution, is pretty much tracking within budget and on time as we commented also in our Production Report a couple of weeks ago. So, I think that with respect to costs in projects that are in execution, you can cross that off as a cause.</p>
          <p>So by your definition, this is &#x2013; the additional spend that you're seeing there is a combination of perhaps things that fall under the threshold of 250, which is the level at which we disclose individual projects and then, projects that are currently in feasibility that are not yet approved, but on which we're spending money, and in projects which we still hope to approve, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, if I read between the lines, it sounds like we should expect a raft of new project approvals this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you've seen a number of announcements on our side. I'm certain that our investor relations team would be more than willing to work with you on the details on what we've disclosed in our CapEx program but &#x2013; and it's not really a tremendous ramp-up. I mean, it's just a continuation of that progressive growth in spend that we've detailed before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Rob Clifford from Deutsche Bank. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Marius. Two questions; one is you mentioned overnight that the debt &#x2013; the iron ore spot market, I think, hundreds of millions of tons. I wonder if you just comment &#x2013; if you thought that was growing from here or if you thought that that was due to some near term anomaly.</p>
          <p>And the second question I guess just following-on a bit from Jason, the increase in CapEx, we've seen other miners do it as well, we got caught out a couple of years ago with the CapEx spike, including sort of poor quality and overpaying. How are you managing going into this next CapEx ramp up on quality of work and spend control?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Rob, the first thing is that again, the emphasis today was obviously where our CapEx is trending. But I think the bigger message was on the progressive nature of the CapEx, which is, I think what you should take away from the data that we discussed today is that we're probably not a company that is going to slash stuff when downturns come and you've seen that last year, nor are we going to announce some day that we're doubling something. There has been a progressive growth over many years of the capability to deploy CapEx, which I think partly answers your question.</p>
          <p>Second point on CapEx is that obviously, there is a spend trajectory of projects that are currently in execution where we are spending money at the moment. So, we're not starting afresh. And if I look at the, let's call it, while we haven't made a final investment decision on the iron ore, RGP6, let's, call it, about a $10 billion program in total in the Pilbara that is currently being executed. So, in many of these cases, the teams are on the ground, things are being built and it's not like we've got to commission them from scratch.</p>
          <p>I also just want to point out that in the CapEx for 2011, which is the full cost of I think just over 20 billion that we've given, the Rio &#x2013; the JV spend, the equalization spend with Rio is in there and I just want to make sure that you remove that when you considered the underlying spend.</p>
          <p>Will the iron ore spot market grow? I think that the trend is towards the incremental iron ore volumes going &#x2013; certainly from a number of players going into the market, clearing markets. So, the way I look at it is that it's the domestic Chinese production any growth in that &#x2013; the Indian production. Clearly, we stated that we want to sell all of our incremental production on the market, clearing market.</p>
          <p>There is obviously the other Australian, major Australian producer, but I can't really comment on what their plans are. I think the combination of what I've just outlined does tell you that that market is going to over time take a bigger portion of the total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Olivia Ker from UBS. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Marius.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Olivia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I got &#x2013; I have some questions on copper growth. The copper market from a longer term point of view looks structurally very attractive. But really Escondida, <mark type="inaudible" /> and maybe some other brownfield opportunities along with Olympic Dam are really your major options which are rather longer dated. Does it make sense to you guys to look at Tier 2 assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would it be higher margin in the nickel and alloy business, and then for you to sort of try not to margin and bring them down the cost curve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And for Olympic Dam, how long do you envisage it will be until there is sufficient sort of reactor build out in China to actually support and manage uranium that you would need to put into the market from Olympic Dam phase one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Olivia, the way I look at the Olympic Dam project is that the sort of the determining rate limiting step here is sort of the pace at which we can get through the EIS. We obviously want to make sure that as we contemplate building that mine that we're not going to run into anything anticipated in what will be a multiple project sequence as we've outlined before. So, we want to make sure that we exhaust all of the opportunities there &#x2013; sorry, all of the questions there. I think that obviously gives us I don't know, 18 months or so before that is complete and as we've seen the reactor build programs continue to be revised upwards, Olivia.</p>
          <p>Perhaps just back to your first question on the Tier 2 assets, and I kept the answer very short, because we are absolutely focused on only having in each of our industries Tier 1 assets. And we probably don't make the comparison between margin in one business versus margin in another business, just always wanting to earn the best assets in each one of our chosen industries, Olivia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from David Pleming from Macquarie. Go ahead. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Marius. Wonder if you could just give us a little bit more color on cash costs. I see that the cash costs performance is actually pretty good in this period. Can you just tell us where the pressure points are, and if you are seeing in fact, cash costs continue to go down in those businesses or going up? I'm talking about the level of increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, David what we always emphasize is that one shouldn't look for, what I would call, cash reduction programs in our business. We believe that we try and run the business lean every day. We take obviously decisions on a daily basis in order to try and optimize these assets. So, we've shied away from announcing a cost reduction exercise, because we don't think that that's the way we run our business.</p>
          <p>But that doesn't mean, as I emphasized again today, in the last part of the presentation that I made, that we are not extremely focused on making sure that we don't put any cost in our businesses that needn't be there. However, we do know that the &#x2013; one of the major drivers on a period-on-period basis for our asset cost performance is the input cost of raw materials. And therefore, we've always emphasized that if prices go up, to talk of costs structurally going down is probably not going to happen, and we've never done that.</p>
          <p>We've also emphasized over time that input costs tend to lag prices. So, what we've seen during this six-month period is the raw materials that we purchased six months or a year ago, when the market was down, those cost manifesting through our cost line. If the product prices for our products hold up, we consume many of those products as inputs. In due course, those costs will again work through our cost structures, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Could I just ask another question in terms of the aluminium business? I mean, obviously, the business is under pressure because of the weak aluminium price, and I think we all know the reasons why.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you still have faith in this business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do want to &#x2013; we do consider this business as a essential part of our portfolio and the diversification offering. It's not a business where there's currently a very large share of the capital for the &#x2013; of &#x2013; out of the total capital program targeted. So, it's probably not a business that you should look towards dramatically growing in size. It's obviously dependent on where energy prices in China go, and where the Chinese currency goes. But at this stage, we are happy to hold effectively the size of the business that we've got, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Peter Davey from Ambrian. Go ahead. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening, Marius. Just looking at the flattening of the cash dividends and lack of any message about any resumption of a buyback program is having some investors sort of speculating you're building a war chest again. But going to be a little bit more simple than that by perhaps overlooking that you all need to perhaps keep money back to pay Rio for that equalization payment, if the WAIO is successfully commissioned?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, I think part of that question I talked about when I talked to Robert about his question, in that, the $20 billion that we've got earmarked to spend next year, that the Rio equalization is in there. And I think what I also tried to indicate today is that we are going to spend a substantial amount of CapEx going forward. And then the third point that I always emphasize is that we review this every six months.</p>
          <p>So, in light of the capital program that we're seeing, the equalization payment that we have to make to Rio, other opportunities that we're looking at, and still a reasonably sanguine outlook on the world economy, we elected today to only progress our dividend in the way that we normally do, without rebasing it, or without launching a buyback at this stage, Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But the quantum you've put into that 20 billion, is it the original figures -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's probably on the order of 5.8 or the number that we originally announced in that number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Kieran Daly from Investec Securities. Go ahead. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Marius, you spent a bit of time at the end of the presentation area today just talking about &#x2013; you always talk about being a simple organization et cetera and the business model, and so on. The way you were talking about, you almost sounded like you're not quite sure you've got the right business model organizational structure just yet. Am I misinterpreting that or do you think there are things you still need to do with the old structure and the model to be more efficient?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kieran, the fact that we've had an unchanged strategy and effectively an unchanged &#x2013; what I would call &#x2013; base organization, which divides us into a product-based business units plus a shared marketing and a shared mini organization means that we've got an extremely high degree of stability in how we are organized. What I do think is that, perhaps not seen every day, the management team and every employee, there are a number of initiatives going on to continually try to reduce drag in the organization, simplify further, stop unnecessary activities, and so on. It's not something that you talk about typically on a day-to-day basis with investors, but I can assure you that there's a lot going on there.</p>
          <p>And my comment was merely to punctuate again what we've said over the last couple of years. We try and run a simple portfolio of large assets, get rid of the smaller assets out of the portfolio, but beyond that, we work very hard every day to have a scalable organization. And that is work that is ongoing, but I think I would describe our position in this respect certainly as right up there in the best, not only in our industry, but also against comparable industries, Kieran.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Sam Catalano from Macquarie. Go ahead. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, Marius. Two questions. First of all, is just with reference to the CapEx guidance, and then if I'm looking at your bubble chart actually, there's quite a lot of very big sized bubbles in the Future Options section. And I wonder, do you think conceptually that the mining industry is heading towards, I guess, a scenario where it's really the large scale, very big investment projects that's going to be necessary to generate effective returns? Is that sort of the dynamic that you look at?</p>
          <p>And secondly, just to touch on the Tier 1, Tier 2 asset question from earlier, is it not unreasonable to think that BHP Billiton, with its expertise and access to capital, and also, to the other types of things, could take assets that are currently perceived as Tier 2, and transform them into Tier 1 or do you think that really the nature of the asset is inherent in what's in the ground more so than anything else?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sam, a little bit different. There's a variety of ways that you assess what a Tier 1 asset is and I'm always fond of quoting another CEO in our industry, who once said to me that the Tier 1 asset is like the Messiah; you can't define it, but you know it when you see it. And I think that what that means is that there are many dimensions which ultimately make up an assessment of whether something can be Tier 1.</p>
          <p>But I would say that a Tier 1 asset is never small, and so largeness is an integral part of Tier 1, as obviously the other parts to it as well. And that perhaps gives you some guidance as to how we think about it.</p>
          <p>Sam, I just lost my train of thought &#x2013; what was the first part of your question again? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Sam has just &#x2013; has left the queue. I'll just try and transfer him back through for you. One moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I now recall, larger scale projects. Yes, I think the industry is heading towards larger scale projects in general. I think our focus has been on creating what I would call Tier 1 assets, where you have multiple mines in one basin, multiple investment opportunities in one basin. And if you look at what we project onwards, we see multiple iron ore expansions, multiple coking coal expansions in the Bowen Basin, multiple expansions of Olympic Dam, multiple additional projects in Escondida, multiple potash projects, and so on, and that sort of gives you the idea of how we think about this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There are no further questions in the queue at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Unless there are any last-minute questions, I realize that for many of you this call-in comes 4 some hours after we release our results. We appreciate you dialing in. We stand ready with our Investor Relations teams and others to continue to build on your questions, answer any additional questions that may arise out of this session.</p>
          <p>I want to close in emphasizing that we do think that this is a good result. The strength of the company, the quality of the assets, and the opportunities that the market will give us over the long term in supplying additional product, we believe puts this company in an unparalleled position to continue to create value for shareholders. So, on that note, I'd like to thank you, again and close.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>