<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1326854" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-07-21</date>
    <companies>
      <company>44197</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Victor Tseng, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Robin Li, Co-Founder, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Jennifer Li, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Alan Hellawell</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Haoyu Shen</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">James Mitchell</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Richard Ji</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Alicia Yap</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Dick Wei</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Yu Jin</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Andrey Glukhov</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Eddie Leung</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Stephen Ju</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Aaron Kessler</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Wallace Cheung</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Mayuresh Masurekar</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Jake Li</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Wendy Huang</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Welin Li</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello and thank you for standing by for Baidu's Second Quarter 2010 Earnings Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in listen-only mode. After management's prepared remarks, there will be a question-and-answer session. Today's conference is being recorded. If you have any objections, you may disconnect at this time.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to turn the meeting over to your host for today's conference, Victor Tseng, Baidu's Investor Relations Director. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to Baidu's second quarter 2010 earnings conference call. We issued Baidu's second quarter 2010 earnings release earlier today. You can find a copy of the earnings release on the company's website as well as on Newswire services.</p>
          <p>Today, you will hear from Robin Li, Baidu's Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, and Jennifer Li, Baidu's Chief Financial Officer. After their prepared remarks, Robin and Jennifer will be joined by Haoyu Shen, Senior Vice President of Business Operations, to answer your questions.</p>
          <p>Before we carry on, please note that the discussion today will contain forward-looking statements made under the Safe Harbor provisions of the U.S. Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Baidu does not undertake any obligation to update any forward-looking statements except as required under applicable law. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded. In addition, a webcast of this conference call will be available on Baidu's corporate website at ir.baidu.com.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Baidu's Chairman and CEO, Robin Li.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everyone, and thank you for joining us today. I am pleased to report another quarter of strong performance. Successful customer acquisition was the main driver for our top line growth. We saw a record number of customer additions, a total of 33,000 during the quarter. This was driven largely by our successful nationwide marketing campaign and the favorable macro environment.</p>
          <p>As part of the marketing campaign, our teams visited over 100 cities across China and attracted a significant number of new customers by educating the market about Baidu and the power of search engine marketing. Also, the rollout of our CRM system helped increase sales productivity. Today, our current base of 254,000 customers is still just a tiny fraction of the total addressable market of millions of SMEs in China. As the market leader, we will continue to educate companies about Baidu's cost effective marketing platform.</p>
          <p>During the second quarter, we continued to implement enhancements to our online marketing platform. We were able to monetize more effectively and large companies and SMEs are spending more with us. This trend should continue as customers become more familiar with the platform functions and see potentially higher ROI.</p>
          <p>Phoenix Nest implementation is largely complete, but consider it as Version 1.0. There is still much more room for further improvements on an ongoing basis.</p>
          <p>Q2 also marked a big step forward for our vision of box computing. We continue to add more applications in our search engine result page. In other words, our box can do more, especially for time sensitive query. The World Cup event is a great testimonial of this technology. During that time, we entered more than 100 million related queries with eight different apps on games schedule, match scores, live broadcasting and recorded videos, et cetera. And the social games we developed during the World Cup on post bar attracted millions of people to participate. As a result, we have seen great traffic patterns since the game started.</p>
          <p>Typically, our website traffic is negatively impacted during large and newsworthy events. This time it was an exception. And in part because of the better than expected search traffic during the World Cup, we were able to deliver Q2 revenue higher than previously guided.</p>
          <p>Our close connection to our users has been a central factor in establishing Baidu's leadership. But new technologies are emerging all the time. The market remains a very competitive place. Over time, success depends on investing in long term to anticipate industry trends and keep up with technological developments. That's why recruiting top talent, especially in R&amp;D, remains a focus for us. As you may have heard, we were in Silicon Valley this month looking for top software engineers to expand our R&amp;D team. We are excited about the talented people we met and look forward to making some great hires.</p>
          <p>In our Union business, we benefited from our new policy which reward high quality, incremental traffic. This is in an initiative we began in the third quarter last year. By focusing on improving Union traffic quality and nurturing organic traffic growth, we saw a significant decline in traffic acquisition costs as a percentage of revenue. We're also working on improving our contextual <mark type="inaudible" />, although it is still relatively small.</p>
          <p>As we approach the fifth anniversary of our IPO, it is worth looking back on how far we've come. Since our NASDAQ listing on August 5, 2005, China's internet population has grown from 1 million in 2005 to 420 million today. Baidu's revenue grow from RMB70 million in Q2 of '05 to 1.9 billion this past quarter. And we've gone from having 41,000 active online marketing customers to 254,000. Keep in mind that while China already has the largest online population in the world, almost 70% of the country is still offline.</p>
          <p>While we are proud of the exceptional shareholder value Baidu has created as a public company, we are just getting started. By keeping our focus on providing the best way for people to find what they're looking for, in the years ahead, I'm confident Baidu will become ever more central to China's Internet ecosystem.</p>
          <p>Thank you again for joining us today and if you plan to be in Beijing on September 2, we'd love to see you at our Annual Baidu World event, where you will get a chance to witness the progress we are making.</p>
          <p>And I will now turn the call over to Jennifer for financial highlights.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Robin. Hello, everyone. We had another great quarter; both top and bottom line results were very strong. Robin explained that top-line growth was driven by effective customer acquisition, continued improvement in monetization and better than expected traffic. At the same time, we also effectively managed our expenses, and as a result, margins scaled to all-time high.</p>
          <p>As we said last quarter, 2010 is a year of investment. To ensure we continue to develop and serve our customers and users effectively and provide the best the search experience, we'll keep recruitment for sales and R&amp;D teams as a priority. You will also see aggressive investment in our network infrastructure which is entering a new investment cycle.</p>
          <p>Now let's look at the financial highlights for the quarter. All amounts mentioned are in RMB unless otherwise noted. Online marketing revenues for the second quarter of 2010 were 1.913 billion, a 74.5% increase year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Baidu had around 254,000 active online marketing customers in the second quarter of 2010, a 25% increase from the corresponding period in 2009 and a 15% increase from the previous quarter. The sequential increase was attributable to our successful marketing campaign and a favorable macro environment. Since we first introduced our new online marketing platform, we have seen strong customer acceptance.</p>
          <p>This has led to increased customer spending. Revenue per online marketing customer in the second quarter reached approximately 7,500 a 39% increase from the corresponding period in 2009 and a 27% increase from the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Traffic acquisition cost as a component of cost of revenue, was 186 million, a 9.7% of total revenues as compared to 16% in the corresponding period in 2009 and 13.2% in the first quarter of 2010. The substantial decrease in TAC as a percent of total revenue is attributable to improvement of Union traffic quality. We expect TAC to remain at approximately this level with moderate fluctuations.</p>
          <p>Bandwidth cost as a component of cost of revenue was 68 million, representing 4% of total revenues, compared to 5% in the corresponding period in '09. Depreciation cost as a component of cost of revenue were 84 million, representing 4% of total revenues, compared to 5% in the corresponding period in '09. The decreases in bandwidth and depreciation costs as percentages of total revenues reflect scalability of the business model. As we <mark type="inaudible" /> infrastructure, depreciation cost will go up.</p>
          <p>Selling, general and administrative expenses in Q2 were 265 million, a increase of 47% year-on-year, primarily due to increased sales head count and marketing spend. R&amp;D expenses were 159 million, a 66% increase from the year ago period, primarily due to increased costs associated with R&amp;D head count.</p>
          <p>Share-based compensation, which were allocated to related operating cost and expense line items, decreased in aggregate to 22 million in the second quarter of 2010 from 23 million in the corresponding period in '09.</p>
          <p>Operating profit was 972 million, a 130% increase year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Total head count as of June 30, 2010 was about 9,000, roughly 1,100 more than the previous quarter. The increase in head count comes mainly from sales and R&amp;D. In 2010, we'll remain focused on investing heavily in sales and R&amp;D to drive growth in our business.</p>
          <p>Income tax expense was 141 million for the second quarter. The effective tax rate for the second quarter was 14.4%, compared to 11.8% for the corresponding period in '09. The increase in effective tax rate was due to a new tax circular issued in the second quarter resulting in changes to the applicable tax for one of our subsidiaries in China.</p>
          <p>Before going into net income and EPS figures, I'd like to remind you that due to the 10 to 1 ADS to ordinary share ratio change in May, earnings per ADS figures now represent 1/10 of the ADS value announced in previous quarters.</p>
          <p>Net income was 837 million, a 118% increase from the corresponding period in '09. Basic and diluted earnings per ADS for the second quarter of 2010 amounted to 2.41 and 2.40, respectively.</p>
          <p>Net income excluding share-based compensation, a non-GAAP measure, was 859 million, a 111% increase from the corresponding period in 2009. Basic and diluted earnings per ADS excluding share-based compensation expenses, both non-GAAP measures, were 2.47and 2.46, respectively.</p>
          <p>As of June 30, 2010, the company had cash, cash equivalents and short-term investments of 5.9 billion. Net operating cash inflow and capital expenditures for the second quarter of 2010 were 1.24 billion and 182 million, respectively.</p>
          <p>As we mentioned earlier, we will aggressively invest in infrastructure and equipment in 2010 to drive innovation, enhanced monetization and support growth.</p>
          <p>Now let me provide you with our top line guidance for the third quarter of 2010. We currently expect total revenue for the third quarter of 2010 to be between 2.2 billion and 2.26 billion, which would represent 72 to 77% year-on-year growth. This forecast reflects Baidu's current and preliminary view, which is subject to change.</p>
          <p>I will now open the call to questions. Operator, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. The question-and-answer session of this conference call will start in a moment. In order to be fair to all callers who wish to ask questions, we will take one question at a time from each caller. If you have more than one question, please request to join the question queue again after your first question has been addressed.</p>
          <p>Your first question comes from the line of Alan Hellawell with Deutsche Bank; please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and congrats on your another fantastic quarter. The one thing I wanted to focus on is something that we've been badgering you guys about and still seem to be overly conservative on, and that's traffic acquisition costs. They just seem to be falling incredibly dramatically.</p>
          <p>And I'd like to know now that you're a couple of quarters into reviewing your Baidu Union terms, what are the dynamics of this coming down? Can you give us a sense as to how you're changing your revenue share or what the broad restructuring of these agreements is? And going forward, how much do you think we can now expect in terms of further TAC savings? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Alan, it's Haoyu. Yeah, we're seeing a significant decline of TAC as a percent of total revenue this quarter. As Robin mentioned in his prepared remarks and also Jennifer, this is really a result of our continued initiative to improve the quality of our CDA traffic, which these initiatives started in the second half of last year. What we are doing &#x2013; or what we did is really we once reward the traffic brought by our CDA partners that are more of a incremental nature rather than a cannibalization nature. So we choose to &#x2013; we become more selective in partnering with different kind of players. And in some cases, we reduce the payout rate if we believe that the traffic is less of an incremental nature to us. In some cases, we choose to not work with some type of partners because it's too much &#x2013; we deem the traffic to be too much of a cannibalization nature.</p>
          <p>So the impact will be not only &#x2013; I think in an overall level the payout ratio is probably coming down. And also some of the affiliate traffic we had before is now reverting to organic traffic, so both of these factors are working to cause a decline of TAC percentage.</p>
          <p>Going forward, we expect this TAC ratio to stay at a relatively low level but I don't think it will go further down much more. And I do want to caution you that affiliate search or search in general is still a very competitive business in China so we need to stay competitive. We need to stay flexible, so going forward I'm sure we will continue to see some fluctuation of TAC ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And broadly speaking &#x2013; sorry, just a quick follow-up on the same topic. We are obviously seeing the formation of some other unions; and to the best of your knowledge and very generically speaking, are they trying to gain traction by offering more generous revenue share or do you feel like everyone is clustered around the same revenue share terms as you guys are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, we don't know any details of how they're structuring their deals, but as I mentioned this is still very competitive. There are other search engines out there who are probably willing to come out and get some traffic. So we will still need to stay flexible and stay competitive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Dick Wei with J.P. Morgan. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can't hear. Dick, are you there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>His line is open. This line maybe muted. Sir, is your line muted? Your next question comes from the line of James Mitchell with Goldman Sachs. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you for taking the question. When I look at the very strong customer adds in the second quarter, do you think there was any pent up demand from prior quarters when the sales force were busy with Phoenix Nest stuff? And also, did you see any trends in terms of which industries or provinces have contributed the most to the customer growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, first of all I think every year during the second quarter we have a nationwide marketing campaign to educate the market and do a lot of customer sign up. And I guess also the Phoenix Nest transition was kind of a distraction for the past few quarters until Q2 of this year.</p>
          <p>In terms of customer trends, we have seen strong customer demand from all kinds of sectors, so we think this is a very healthy trend and it will go on for the next few quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Richard Ji with Morgan Stanley. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Robin and Jennifer, Haoyu, good morning, and congrats on a very strong quarter. Just ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>... let me start with &#x2013; yeah, sure. I've got a first question is regarding the revenue contribution from your big corporate clients. Obviously, we are seeing significant pick up in terms of <mark type="inaudible" /> and spending from those folks and if you elaborate a little more on their relative growth ratio &#x2013; growth rate versus the small player. And what is the, roughly speaking, the ballpark revenue contribution. And do you also plan to have a dedicated sales force to service these big corporate clients given their deep pockets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Haoyu?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Richard, this is Haoyu. As we commented a few times in the past, the large advertisers are spending more with us and their spend with us has been growing faster than the spend by &#x2013; total spend by SMEs. And I think that continues to be the case, although a lot of &#x2013; when you look at SMEs you can keep adding many more new customers every quarter but as far as large advertisers you only have a couple hundred &#x2013; a few hundred, less than a thousand to work with.</p>
          <p>But we're seeing very healthy growth on their ARPU with us. They are buying search for brand building purposes, they're buying search for transaction purposes; a lot of companies are setting up their online stores, so all the key metrics are going in the right direction. And we always had a dedicated sales force serving &#x2013; acquiring and serving these large customers and they are based in Beijing and the Shanghai and in Shenzhen and <mark type="inaudible" />. So that team is continuing to deliver good results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, okay; also highlight your top listing category and especially after the Phoenix Nest roll out, have you seen a pick up in any of these area in terms of growth rate and versus your previous stage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you mean the key factors among large customers or overall?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Overall, overall, yeah. Especially I'm curious about which sector has shown particularly more robust growth after the roll out of Phoenix Nest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I might also get the orders, Jennifer you have the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think particularly the customers, large customers we said are more mature and they already are adopters of Phoenix Nest. We have seen sectors such as financial services, real estate really outpace the sector growth in other areas. All sectors are growing very strong, but these sectors that I just named, they were particularly strongly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Alicia Yap with Citi. Please proceed, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, congratulation on a strong quarter. My question is on your new customer add, how much of that increase would you attribute to the new sales team hire versus the improved productivity of the existing sales team? And were most of the increase come from the second and third tier city as a result of your nationwide campaign or is that increase is more diversified among all the cities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The new customer, very diversified among all kind of cities including the tier 1 major cities and the smaller cities. I would say the new customer adds are mainly attributable to the increase of our sales force, because our productivity improvement just got started; although we have seen great results, but it's not fully in function yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Dick Wei [J.P. Morgan]. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Congratulations on good quarter. Is it possible to update for the mobile search initiative? I wonder, any new plans for that and mobile search, approximately how much of the total search volume that accounts for? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>During the past couple of years, we have seen faster growth in mobile search traffic versus PC-based search, but it remains to be a small percentage of our total traffic. The mobile landscape is still not settled yet because majority of the internet users who access the internet through mobile are still using 2G phones. They are expensive and they are slow.</p>
          <p>There are a small fraction of users who use 3G network, but they obviously use the mobile for search on a more frequent basis. But going forward, we think smartphone will take over and that the traffic will grow even faster. We have designed a number of mobile-related products and functions to adapt to this kind of user behavior. But I wouldn't see the direction for mobile search is settled yet so there are maybe a lot of changes going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you, and congrats on a good quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Yu Jin with CICC. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, Robin and Jennifer; how are you? And congratulations on such a strong quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I had a question &#x2013; one question is for Jennifer. So Baidu has already launched at GE and the company is already in operation and it will launch Baidu Rakuten soon. So I think the management showed a more accurate understanding over the investment amount. So can Jennifer elaborate a little bit how the 2 billion hit will affect our second half and the next year's financials?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And &#x2013; yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the GE investment, we have clarified last quarter because of the shareholding structure and the management control agreed upon between the parties, the investment is accounted for on an equity method basis. And I did mention last quarter that on a going forward basis, we do not expect material impact from GE, from the joint venture there, unless there is a shareholder structure change. So if there is a shareholder structure change, we'll update the investment community clearly, so do not expect significant material impact from GE.</p>
          <p>On the Rakuten JV, the JV will officially launch in Q4 and will start to consolidate or we'll start to include their results starting in Q4. Because we own less than 50% of the venture, we will likely account the Rakuten joint venture on an equity accounting method as well. We do not anticipate within a year's time the Rakuten joint venture will have material impact to the bottom line. We will give you more updates we move in Q4 and you will get to see the picture.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jennifer. And the second one is an open question for Robin. I just follow the wireless in and out question, so my question is, so based on our practice can you tell us some difference like between wireless and wired in and out? <mark type="inaudible" />. And from the company's perspective, what area where we will focus in the near term beyond the search? That's all from me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. For wireless, because the mobile phones generally have a much smaller screen, users tend to flip pages more than the PC based users and we try to design the mobile user experience so that each page is simpler and lighter than the PC based ones. Because people carry their mobile phones all the time, the location-based information and it's more personal, so local is more useful in general to the wireless internet users than the PC users. Like I mentioned, I think it's pretty much still an open area for wireless search going forward exactly what's going to happen to the user behavior.</p>
          <p>I mean the search behavior on the mobile side is, it's still an open question and devices that have access to internet are also getting diversified. You have Tablet PC, you have mobile phones, smartphones, <mark type="inaudible" /> phones and laptop computers. These kind of terminals all have different kind of user behaviors and we are still studying these kind of trends and try to come up with necessary products and functions to satisfy our users.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Andrey Glukhov with Brean Murray. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks for taking the question. Two things if I may. First, if I look at the customer trends, can you guys comment in addition to the strong just new customer acquisition, are you seeing any improvement or any changes in the, essentially, advertiser churn levels? And then separately, Jennifer, if you can just comment what was the &#x2013; why was the other income substantially negative amount? That would help as well. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first part of question about customer churn, it's stable, the churn rate. We never disclose that number, but the churn rate has been stable. Although as part of the effort in <mark type="inaudible" /> processes and putting good CRM in place, we are working hard to improve the attrition front of customer retention. So hopefully going forward we'll see some improvements, but up to now it's stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on your other question, Andrey, the other income is substantially negative this quarter. We did disclose last &#x2013; in our last earnings call because of the Yushu earthquake, we donated mostly &#x2013; most of the number is because of the donation we made. We donated RMB10 million to the tragic &#x2013; to the suffered areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks. Congrats on the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Eddie Leung with Bank of America [Merrill Lynch]. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning, everyone. The first question I have is, Robin, you mentioned that the existing customers are spending more throughout the quarter. So in general, was this coming more from expansion of keywords or driven by raising prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. I didn't quite get your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm asking about the increase in spending of the old customers. In general was this coming more from increase in keywords or driven by raising prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Haoyu, you want to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Eddie, if you look at the good growth of ARPU, it's really driven by many things, first of all traffic, right. When traffic goes up, click will go up, definitely you will see customers spending a lot then. And we are seeing customers appreciation of the new system, so their budget is going up. So a lot of the times budget is a binding factor for how much they will spend as there are a lot of customers increasing the budget; that's a prerequisite for ARPU growth. And of course, the other monetization metrics such as click through rate and CPC; so all of these are contributing to the good growth of ARPU this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, Phoenix Nest allows our customers to pick a lot more keywords, the bids, the cost per clicks is also going up but slowly. I would say at a slower rate than before. So we're happy about this trend because our customers are getting better ROI because of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful. And then one housekeeping question. Jennifer, could you give us the top advertiser industries for the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Certainly, the top five sectors are these; they account for about 50% of the total revenue. They are medical, healthcare, machinery equipment, education and travel and franchising for this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Stephen Ju with RBC. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everybody, I wanted to take <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Stephen, you're breaking out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about that &#x2013; I just wanted to see if you have a mobile operating system in the plans for you at some point. And also the JV with Rakuten, I'm just wondering what is going to be the incremental value add or differentiating factor that is going to set the platform apart from <mark type="inaudible" /> or <mark type="inaudible" />. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. We have a number of very exciting projects going on internally. Obviously, we are optimistic about mobile Internet in the future. But typically we do not preannounce the products so I cannot give you a yes or no answer on the mobile OS thing.</p>
          <p>For Rakuten, like I mentioned in the past two quarters, we think search engine is the biggest beneficiary of e-commerce so we try all kinds of things to nurture that the e-commerce market and the Rakuten JV is just one of the endeavors. So as science we can help companies like Rakuten to set up the platforms to allow more businesses to sell their product and services online. We think we will eventually benefit Rakuten on more than 50% of this joint venture, so they will take the lead and do whatever to make it successful.</p>
          <p>The value we add is two-fold. One is we can drive traffic to them; the other is that the Baidu brand is much bigger than Rakuten here in China so carrying the Baidu brand will help them to sign up more businesses especially the larger businesses. I think more choices to the Chinese businesses is better and we have seen a lot of interest especially from the larger corporations who want to sell online on our Rakuten platform.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are ready for the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Aaron Kessler with ThinkEquity. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, guys; a couple of questions. First, given the strength of the advertiser growth in the quarter, do you feel comfortable with kind of a higher level of advertiser growth going forward given some of your recent initiatives in terms of the marketing campaign and added sales count? And also just in terms of the sales and marketing expense, it looks like it was pretty flat sequentially; I would think that will be up a little more given the increase in head count. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the customer acquisition will follow the typical seasonality of the past few years. Q2 generally we have quite strong customer acquisition momentum but Q3 and Q4 we are continuing to add new customers and Q1 is typically the slowest one. Regarding the sales and marketing costs, maybe Jennifer can...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly, yeah I think you are right, Aaron. The &#x2013; you did notice that we added about 1,100 head counts in the quarter and they come from sales and R&amp;D. Not everybody joins the company on the first day of the quarter, so you only see part of the expense impact of these head count additions. The full impact will be felt in the next quarter. And on top of that, of course, we continue to aggressively hire sales force and R&amp;D, so that's why we wanted you guys to fully be aware of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And do you just have a sense on the Phoenix Nest on how much of the monetization improvements you've seen to this point, like how &#x2013; what inning are you in, in terms of improvements for Phoenix Nest monetization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Aaron, this is Haoyu. I think that the <mark type="inaudible" /> part of the trajectory is largely behind us, although going forward there's still a lot of room for us to put in over in the improvements into Phoenix Nest. But I think the monetization improvement will be more gradual than what you saw in the past two quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Wallace Cheung with Credit Suisse. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello; morning. Wanted to ask about your SMS strategies as Google also wanted to develop some kind of SMS called Me. Is it important for the search engine to get into the SMS? And also wanted to hear your thought about any initiative on the real time search as well? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We already have an SMS type of service called Baidu Space. It is a good complementary to our search business but I would say it's not very closely related to search. The business model for SMS is quite different from search, especially in China. The SMS companies typically charge end users, they run online games and that sort of thing, but for search, we basically satisfy people's information needs. Users come with something in mind, with an agenda when they come to our search services, but the users <mark type="inaudible" /> to SMS services to kill time and stay connected so I think these are very different type of user needs.</p>
          <p>Regarding to real-time search, it's actually not a new phenomenon. More than 10 years ago, search engines started to try to tackle the real-time search problem, but it's not an easy problem to solve because when it's real time, it's very easy to be spammed. So we have been cautious on this.</p>
          <p>Having said that, we have a lot of ways to integrate real-time information in our search result page. The example I mentioned in the prepared remark is the World Cup event. We have real time information updated through our box computing technology or the Aladdin platform. We can integrate the real-time information from trusted sources, so that's our take on real-time search.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Congratulations on a good quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mayuresh Masurekar with Kaufman Bros. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Baidu revenue growth has been accelerating significantly over the last three quarters from 40% to 60% and now 74%. Could you give us a rough estimate of how much of this growth is from the marketing campaign, how much from Phoenix Nest, how much from easy comps because of the economy and how much from share gains from your leading competitor and could you rank those factors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think there are a few factors that contributed to this phenomena. In 2009, it was a year of transition for the company. We launched Phoenix Nest in April of 2009, but the system actually runs parallel with the classical version of our pay-search system. That have got a lot of distraction for the overall operation of the company and also caused some confusion on the market. We were able to successfully switch over December 1 of last year; therefore we were able to resume the normal growth trajectory we developed for market with great potential.</p>
          <p>Along the way, based on third-party research report, we have been gaining traffic share gradually but because we already have traffic share north of 70%, so the share gain is kind of a smaller contributor to the overall picture.</p>
          <p>Another factor I would say that internet &#x2013; the businesses, small and large businesses in China increasingly start to appreciate the marketing power a search engine can bring to them. China's Internet is kind of different from the developed market in the sense that majority of the internet users are very young; they started to use the internet for entertainment purposes. Even today I think the majority of internet related revenues are entertainment or end users consumers pay to play games and to communicate and back up things. But gradually we have seen a pick up on the business activities on the internet and I am sure going forward more and more business activities will be conducted through the internet and therefore we will continue to benefit from this kind of trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jake Li with Guotai Junan. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. Thank you for taking the question. Regarding the tax, in the second quarter, is there any one-time item affecting the decrease of the ratio? I know the ratio &#x2013; the pay out ratio <mark type="inaudible" />. So excluding the conceptual &#x2013; what the expansion will be? This is the first, then the second, regarding the contextual ads, I know that revenue contribution is relatively small currently, so what the trend is going forward and I know you will increase the PR ratio by 10 to 15%, so I think the contribution will be higher going forward, so could you give me more color? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi this is Haoyu. There is no major one time event related to TAC in Q2. So as I mentioned they will &#x2013; TAC will probably continue to stay at this relatively low level as far as we can see. Contextual is where, we mentioned few times before, we were very excited about contextual, the opportunity in contextual ads going forward. So we are putting a lot of product management people and a lot of R&amp;D people behind this effort, although we're not seeing &#x2013; up to now, you're not seeing major impact on revenue yet. It's still a relatively small percentage of our total revenue.</p>
          <p>But as I said, we are very excited; we are very much looking forward to having more revenue contribution from this product maybe towards the end of this year and next year as well.</p>
          <p>It &#x2013; when contextual becomes a bigger part of our revenue it will impact TAC because typically the TAC payout is higher on contextual than on CD aided search just because the depression, the inventory belongs to somebody else that we need to pay a higher rate. When that happens it will probably have an impact on total TAC as a percent of total revenue but that's a good thing to have, but that's not going to happen in the very short term yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Wendy Huang with RBS. Please proceed, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. Two quick questions. First, Google recently announced to acquire ITA, so I wonder if Baidu will consider acquiring any virtual search engines such as the Turbo search engine?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We already have a number of so-called verticals. We have image search, we have Baidu Post Bar, we have Baidu notes, we have Baidu encyclopedia and we have technologies to integrate this kind of information in our web search result page and we also have a open platform that allows third-party information to be integrated in this related search with our pages.</p>
          <p>So at the end of day, we think about satisfying users' information needs. If any type of actions can help satisfy our information, our users information is better, we will do that. We have our internally user-generated content and we integrate third-party information sites. And if a certain type of information is owned by someone who have unique content, we may consider that too.</p>
          <p>So going forward, we will look for more type of content &#x2013; information content or valuable content. We could generate it by ourselves. We could integrate third-party and we could buy them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. My second question is regarding your investment. You mentioned in the prepared remarks that you would invest aggressively in infrastructure and equipment, so can you give me some idea for your budget for this type of investment in the next one to three years? And also apart from this investment in your core search business, what's your budget for the non-core business, such as the mobile search and the mobile OS possibly in next three years? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you can see from the Q2, our CapEx number is a step-up from the Q1 level, and going out in the out quarters, we have plans to get into the new investment cycle, and therefore significantly step up the spending, so pretty material going forward.</p>
          <p>The infrastructure investment will be on enhancing the core search capability, to enlarge our index size, to ensure we expand our computing power, and also to build flexibility and competency and capability on the infrastructure side.</p>
          <p>So there's plenty of things that we do surrounding the core search capability; that's where the main investment comes from. Robin, do you want to comment on ...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, in terms of resource allocation, we consider that's a media platform and anything that can either enhance our platform or take advantage of our platform we would invest in that. Of course, central to the platform is our web search. So roughly 70% of our resources will be devoted to web search and pay search, this type of business. And 20% of our resources will invested &#x2013; will be invested in projects that could help drive traffic to our web search. And the rest, 10%, will be invested in well, kind of also truly in the <mark type="inaudible" /> project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful. Jennifer, can you actually update your CapEx guidance for 2010/11?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't give out CapEx forecast that long. Just to give you a sense, Q1 was &#x2013; the spending was about 100 million and Q2 is about 180 million. So you can see the massive Q2 step up and continue to expect that kind of a momentum.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. That's all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Welin Li with UBS. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, congratulations for the strong results. Just one question, can you share with us last revenue breakdown among the Tier 1 cities and Tier 2 and Tier 3? And also which segment is growing faster and also how much revenue comes from direct sales versus the agency sales? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We typically do not breakout among the Tier 1, Tier 2, Tier 3 cities, but what I can tell you is that the growth among this type of cities are roughly at the same pace. We have seen very, very good growth rates among almost all major cities.</p>
          <p>And like I mentioned before probably, you know, one year or two years ago. Direct sales still represent more than 50% of our total revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of James Mitchell with Goldman Sachs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for taking another question. You mentioned in the beginning that the World Cup Soccer event.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Helped your traffic. Did it also help your monetization, you revenue? I think in the past events like the World Cup tended to be high traffic but low paid lead generation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Haoyu? You want to talk about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Typically these keywords are not very monetizable, although we monetized some of these keywords through different methods but, you know, I think what Robin really meant was during the World Cup lot of people came to search engine and they searched for stuff related to World Cup and that overall increased people's appreciation of how much search engine can help them.</p>
          <p>So just like every Chinese New Year, after every Chinese New Year, you're going to see a major step-up of overall search volume. So a big event like World Cup this time also had that kind of impact on overall search volume; not so much on the revenue, growth is not so much due to the monetization of these specific World Cup related keywords, really.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then you benefit with -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The benefit we get from the World Cup related project is that we really made our users more dependent upon Baidu services.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. And the new tax <mark type="inaudible" /> in the second quarter that resided in a 14% effective tax rate for the company, did you expect the tax rates to remain around those levels or this is a one quarter phenomenon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We did provide, James, we did provide earlier in the year guidance for tax. We said it's going to be mid to low teens and we will remain that guidance and probably more towards the mid teens than low teens.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your last question comes from the line of Wallace Cheung with Credit Suisse. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, just one quick question, regarding the latest PPOC rules on the third party payment services, because we know Baidu also has a Baidu pay service, so are you going to apply for the payment license as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Wallace we are going to apply for that license.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We are now approaching to the end of the conference call. I would now like to turn the call over to the Baidu's Chief Executive Officer, Robin Li for closing remarks. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, once again thank you for joining us today and please do not hesitate to contact us if you have any further questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may now disconnect. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>