<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1150479" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-04-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>44197</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Helen Zhang, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Robin Li, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Jennifer Li, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Dick Wei</participant>
      <participant id="5">Robin Li</participant>
      <participant id="6">Haoyu Shen</participant>
      <participant id="7">Eddie Leung</participant>
      <participant id="8">C. Ming Zhao</participant>
      <participant id="9">Jason Brueschke</participant>
      <participant id="10">Jennifer Li</participant>
      <participant id="11">James Mitchell</participant>
      <participant id="12">Richard Ji</participant>
      <participant id="13">Gene Munster</participant>
      <participant id="14">James Lee</participant>
      <participant id="15">Steve Weinstein</participant>
      <participant id="16">Stephen Ju</participant>
      <participant id="17">Wallace Cheung</participant>
      <participant id="18">Collin Gillis</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening and thank you for standing by for Baidu's First Quarter 2008 Earnings Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> After management's prepared remarks, there will be a question and answer session.  Today's conference is being recorded. If you have any objections, you may disconnect at this time.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to your host for today's conference, Helen Zhang, the Senior Manager of Investor Relations at Baidu.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello everyone and welcome to Baidu's First Quarter 2008 Earnings Conference Call. We distributed Baidu's First Quarter 2008 Earnings earlier today. You may find a copy of the press release on the company's website as well as on news wire services. Today you will hear from Robin Li, Baidu's Chief Executive Officer; and Jennifer Li, Baidu's Chief Financial Officer. After their prepared remarks, Robin and Jennifer will be joined by Haoyu Shen, Baidu's Vice President of Business Operations, to answer your questions.</p>
          <p>Before we continue, please note that the discussion today, will contain forward-looking statements, and made under the Safe Harbor provisions of the US Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Baidu does not undertake any obligation to update any forward-looking statements, except as required under applicable law. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded. In addition, a webcast of this conference call will be available on Baidu's company website at www.ir.Baidu.com.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over Baidu's CEO, Robin Li.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everyone, and thank you for joining us today.  We are pleased to report that in the first quarter of 2008, we exceeded the top end of our revenue guidance, with 108 year-over-year growth. This result is in large part due to the continuous efforts of our sales force and our strong customer teams.  It also reflects an increase in understanding of and appreciation for the benefits of research by both our existing online advertisers, and more traditional advertisers turning to this platform.</p>
          <p>Despite a long Chinese New Year holiday and severe snowstorms at the start of the quarter, we exceeded our goal.  Revenue growth was driven both organically and through our continued expansion of Baidu Union.  Our revenue growth is a clear indication of our continued ability to retain and attract new users and customers to the premiere Chinese online search platform.</p>
          <p>Our focus on knowing our customers' needs, as well as our transition to a direct sales model, have paid off.  Active online marketing customers have reached 161,000, up from 155,000 last quarter.  Revenue per online marketing customer for the first quarter remained stable at approximately RMB3300, an increase of 44% from the corresponding period in 2007.  Our web search services are well complimented by a full suite of other popular products.  In particular, image search has done very well and has become the largest non-web search service in terms of page bill.  Community based products are growing fast.  internet users usually find that the most relevant results from their web sites &#x2013; from their web search queries come from Baidu Knows, no matter which community they use.</p>
          <p>This past quarter we also began the public testing phase of Baidu Hi, our instant messenger platform.  The IM market in China is different from that of other countries.   In China, it is common practice to use instant messenger as the primary means of communication in professional as well as social networks.  We believe Baidu Hi will bring more convenience to Baidu users and attract new internet users to our site.</p>
          <p>We have also made progress this quarter in our ongoing strategy to become an entertainment hotspot on the internet.  In addition to our ongoing cooperative agreement with the leading record companies, we have also recently signed agreements with 15 radio stations and we are at the forefront of music and information streaming from radio stations online.  We are continuing to explore new and innovative partnerships with record labels and content providers, paving the way for Baidu to function as an online media platform for music and information.</p>
          <p>We also continue to expand Baidu Union. Our recently announced partnership with China Netcom is an exciting development.  China Netcom is an Olympic sponsor and has an extensive user base.  According to the agreement, China Netcom subscribers will automatically be redirected to a Baidu search page if they attempt to visit an incorrect or non-existent URL; a practice enabling more user-friendly and efficient online information searches.  This agreement is an excellent method to increase traffic to Baidu.</p>
          <p>Another development I'd like to mention is a recently initiated revenue sharing partnership with four online gaming operators including Shanda, the NASDAQ listed internet gaming company.  According to the agreement, online gamers will be able to access their game from Baidu's online game platform,  yoshi.baidu.com [game.baidu.com], which will then redirect the traffic to the gaming operators.  This allows game users convenient access and drive gaming traffic to Baidu's gaming partners.  We are pleased to have formed this partnership.</p>
          <p>Our Japanese initiatives are also progressing very well.  In 2008 we will maintain our focus on product development.  In that regard, we recently announced as a partnership with Waseda University in Tokyo, a pioneer local internet search engine developer to jointly conduct web search related research.  Our goal in Japan is to develop a product that suits the needs of Japanese users and establish the Baidu brand as a highly quality alternative and meaningful player in the dynamic Japanese market in the coming years.</p>
          <p>I would also like to update everyone on our C2C platform.  In the past quarter we continued to develop and design the platform and hired staff who helped managed this operation.  We remain on track with this project and plan to launch in 2008.  We will keep updated on progress in the coming quarters.</p>
          <p>While we continue to grow the business and invest in long-term opportunities we are constantly focused on improving operating efficiency and leveraging our online platform to extend scalability.</p>
          <p>Now turning to our management team.  We have two very important new members of the Baidu staff.  First it is my great pleasure to introduce you all to Jennifer Li, our new Chief Financial Officer who is here with me today.  Jennifer joined Baidu as our Chief Financial Officer in March.  She is an experienced finance leader who brings over 13 years of experience in financial management, treasury, corporate finance and financial analysis.  Jennifer joins Baidu from GMAC where she served as controller of GMAC's North American operations.  Prior to that, Jennifer was Chief Financial Officer of General Motors China where she was responsible GM's wholly-owned and joint venture businesses. We are excited by Jennifer's vast financial and international experience, and are confident that she will bring a new perspective to our finance function and continue to strengthen Baidu's international standard of confidence.  We are extremely pleased to have Jennifer with us at Baidu.</p>
          <p>Also, today is actually the first day on the job for our new Chief Operating Officer, Peng Ye.  Peng joins the team with a wide range of experience in sales, marketing and business operations management, as well as software development in the IT and Telecom industries.  Most recently, Peng served as country general manager for Apple China.  In that role, he oversaw all business operations for Apple China.  Prior to that, he worked for SatCom AG as managing director and for Motorola Mobile in North Asia as Vice President of Asia-Pacific and General Manager of New Wireless Carrier Operations.  Peng also served with Nortel China and Nortel Europe for 7 years in several senior management and product development positions.  Peng is a strategic addition to the management team, and we are confident that he will make significant contributions to Baidu's future.  So I'm very pleased that after a year of vacancy, we were able to fill the Chief Operating Officer position with such a high-quality member.</p>
          <p>With that, I will now turn the call over to Jennifer to go through the quarter's financial highlights with you.  Jennifer, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and good evening everyone.  I want to thank Robin for the kind introduction, and I would like to add a few words.  First of all, I'm thrilled to be here today.  People ask me why I joined Baidu.  Returning to my home country and working for such a vanguard company is a great opportunity and a challenge I welcome.  Having come from the relatively mature automotive industry, I'm keen to be part of the promising Chinese internet industry as it emerges from its infancy.</p>
          <p>Baidu is one of the strongest brand names in China and a source of national pride.  In its started as a Chinese internet company, Baidu is now recognized globally, and is a true international player.  The company's impressive growth to date reflects the promise of the industry and the entrepreneurial spirit of Baidu.  Robin is a great leader with an excellent reputation.  Working with Robin and the Baidu team is a pleasure, and I am excited that my position will allow me to apply my experiences in international finance to a new international company operating in an exciting market.  I'm very happy to be home, proud to be at Baidu and excited to contribute to the company's future. I will now turn to our first quarter results and provide you with financial highlights.</p>
          <p>As many of you know, our first quarter results tend to reflect the seasonal impact of the long Chinese New Year holiday break.  This year, severe snowstorms furthered the negative impact.  Despite this, we posted healthy growth in the quarter, generating total revenues of RMB574 million, nearly 5% above our guidance and up 108% year-over-year.   Both the number of active online customers, as well as per customer spending increased by approximately 44% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Solid revenue growth was achieved through the continuous efforts of our sales force, strong customer service teams and an increased awareness and use of P4P online marketing and signup.  Online marketing revenue grew to RMB572 million, a 109% increase year-over-year. Traffic acquisition costs as a component of cost of revenue was RMB77 million with 13% of total revenue compared to 10% a year ago.  The increase reflects continued growth of revenue contributions from Baidu Union.</p>
          <p>Share-based compensation expenses increased to RMB16 million from RMB12 million in the year-ago period.  SG&amp;A expenses were RMB147 million, a 96% increase from a year ago.  This was due to the expansion of our direct-sales force.  Excluding share-based compensation expenses, SG&amp;A rose 109% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Research and development expenses were RMB51 million, 106% increase from a year ago, mainly due to the expansion of head count.  Excluding share-based compensation expenses, R&amp;D expenses rose 107% year-over-year.  As Robin mentioned earlier, our Japan initiative is both progressing well.  Baidu Japan incurred operating costs and expenses in the first quarter of RMB30 million in aggregate.</p>
          <p>Adjusted EBITDA, a non-GAAP measure, was RMB228 million for the first quarter, representing a 93% increase from the year ago period.  Operating profit was RMB147 million, double the level of the first selling period in 2007.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter of 2008 our income tax expenses was approximately RMB11 million.  The increase in tax over previous quarters reflects expected increase in tax rate applied to two of our PRC-based subsidiaries.  Next holiday either expired or partially elapsed.  Regarding taxes, as some of you may know, a new enterprise income tax law with some detailed guidelines came into effect on January 1, 2008.  This new law continues to offer preferential tax rates to qualified entities.  At this stage, we're still awaiting final detailed guidelines to confirm our current preferential tax rate treatment for some of our entities.  We'll keep you updated as we have information.</p>
          <p>Net income for the quarter was RMB147 million, a 71% increase year-over-year.  You will notice the year-over-year net income grew less than the year-over-year operating profit this quarter.  This is mainly due to the flat year-over-year other income levels, particularly interest income. Net income excluding share-based compensation expenses, a non-GAAP measure, was RMB163 million, a 67% increase from a year ago.  Basic and diluted EPS, excluding share-based compensation expenses, were 4.77 and RMB4.68, translating roughly to $0.68 and $0.67, respectively.</p>
          <p>Now moving on to the balance sheet.  We ended the first quarter of 2008 with cash, cash equivalents and short-term investments of RMB1.7 billion, or $238 million. Operating cash flow for the quarter was RMB248 million, representing a year-over-year increase of 120%.  Capital expenditures for the first quarter was around RMB158 million, up from RMB164 million a year ago.  A portion of capital expenditures were allocated to the construction of Baidu's new campus facilities.</p>
          <p>Now let me provide you our top line guidelines for the second quarter of 2008.  We currently expect total revenues to between 780 and RMB800 million, which would represent year-over-year growth of 94% to 99%, and a quarter-over-quarter growth of 36 to 39%. I do wish to emphasize that this forecast reflects Baidu's current and preliminary view, which is subject to change.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call back to Robin for his closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you again, and for joining us today.  As always, we believe that the best is ahead of us.  We look forward to continuing to provide the best online search experience for our users and to continuing to execute our strong growth strategy in the coming quarters and years. We will now open the call to questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The question-and-answer session of this conference will start in a moment. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  Your first question comes from the line of Dick Wei with JPMorgan.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, Robin, Jennifer, and Haoyu. Congrats on a very good quarter.  My question is that -- I'm very, like, excited about the new initiatives for online games, <mark type="inaudible" /> et cetera.  But for your core search business, what are some of the key plans you try to drive monetization for 2008?  For example, if could you comment on the trend for revenue per search, any room for improvement on that front, any potential changes could there be in your sponsored search effort and actually, do you have any sense of revenue per search compared to your competitors? That would be great.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  As many of you know, we started to improve the monetization actually since 2006.  We implemented our Dynamic Bidding and Dynamic Starting Bid Price, and incorporated quality factors in ordering the sponsor's links.  Those have set a very good foundation for further improvement in the revenue per search opportunities for us.  So this year, we continued to fine-tune those offerings, and have been making constant progress in including the relevancy of the sponsored links, and revenue per search has been growing steadily.  Having said that, I have to point out that the best is yet ahead of us.  We have identified lots of areas in the monetization that we can do a better job, not only this year, but next year.  We still have a lot to do.  We don't have the numbers for RPS for our competitors, but our internal assessment is that we are not doing a better job in this area.  Hayou, do you want anything to add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I agree with what Robin just said.  I think we knew everything was going to production every day, in terms of the research, and definitely there's a lot of things I see ahead of us for the rest of year and going into next year as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thanks a lot and congratulations on the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Eddie Leung with Merrill Lynch.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Haoyu, Robin, Jennifer, how are you?.  I have one question.  About the Olympics, could you tell us, help us to understand what could be the impact on your advertiser per click and the search traffic in the third quarter?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ad budget for the third quarter.  I think at this time there are still some uncertainties.  Larger companies generally have extra budget for the Olympics starting from the first quarter of this year and ramping up to the second quarter and third quarter.  I think we will be a beneficiary of that but a large portion of our revenue come from small and medium enterprises and they are generally not that sensitive to the game. Also, during the game, the traffic patterns may change significantly so we are not sure what kind of impact we will have during the game time, but longer term we think the Olympics will be a driving force for better improved internet usage in China.  People will have a better sense of how to leverage the internet to do marketing.  We think longer term it's going to be a positive impact for Baidu, but during the third quarter if traffic pattern changes significantly our revenue, which is based on cost per click, could be impacted negatively.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey Robin, a follow-up on that front regarding the traffic, could you also share with us some of your experiences during the World Cup soccer in 2006?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the traffic did not change that much during the World Cup in 2006.  We were not a beneficiary of that because at that time not that many sports related advertisers came to Baidu. So I would say that the impact was minimal at that time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ming Zhao with SIG.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Why thank you.  Good morning, everyone.  Just a question on the Baidu Union, it seems like the TAC ratio is going up gradually every quarter, so my question is after we look at this Baidu Union's contribution to your top line, if you can tell us a rough idea how much revenue is from the Baidu Union?  And also just the behavior on this Baidu Union's websites is the revenue mainly coming from the search or the direct product?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Let me start this with a few words then I'll have Haoyu to elaborate.  When we look at the revenue from Baidu Union, we really look at the net revenue, meaning revenue net of traffic acquisition cost.  If the net revenue is positive to us, we will do a deal, but based on that philosophy for the past few quarters, we have been able to sign up more revenue -- or content partners, and revenue for the Baidu Union have been growing very well.  And I think even if you back out the traffic acquisition costs, our Q1 revenue year-on-year grow more than 100%.  That's the big picture.  Haoyu, would you want to add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  As far as the TAC going up as we always said that TAC as a percentage of total revenue going up, the main reason is that revenue from Union members has been growing faster, although we don't break out numbers, but it's safe to say that Baidu Union does contribute a big portion of our revenue.  As far as the revenue based on search versus the revenue based on contextual ads, what we can say is the majority of the revenue, or the revenue from search is larger than the revenue from contextual ads.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jason Brueschke with Citigroup.  Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I want to extend my welcome to Jennifer, to the firm and my best wishes, and second a quick congratulations on the quarter.  I have two questions.  First, more of a housekeeping question, could you update us on what the P&amp;L impact in the quarter was from both the Japan initiative and the C2C initiative?  Maybe give us an update as to what you think the P&amp;L impact will be for the balance of the year.  And can you tell us whether the spending in Japan has peaked and when you will start to get revenues from Japan?  So that's kind of the first set.</p>
          <p>And then secondly I have a question about mobile search.  There have been some comments from I think a competitor of yours, that mobile search in China will be larger than PC-based search within three years.  I was wondering if we could get your views on that.  An also, Google, your competitor, has partnered with China Mobile, who is the dominant wireless carrier, and I was wondering if I could get your comments on whether that gives them some particular competitive advantage, if in fact you believe mobile search becomes important to this market?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'll let Jennifer to answer the P&amp;L question first, and I'll cover the mobile search part.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jason.  Our first quarter Japan P&amp;L impact, the Japan operations P&amp;L impact, was RMB30 million.  We have mentioned in the past that we expect our 2008 total operating expenses related to our Japan operations will be between 20 to $25 million.  So when you think about Q1, that's a little over 4 million, so we expect our expenses to continue to occur in Japan, and they will slightly ramp up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And for the revenue opportunities in Japan, we have stated that we do not expect any revenue for this year.  And we will update you our outlook for next year as time pass by when we have a better idea.  As I mentioned before, C2C it's a relatively lower-cost initiative, and we currently do not break that down in our P&amp;L.  For mobile search, we have been constantly monitoring the Mobile internet market in China.  There has been a lot of talk about mobile search, a lot of talk about 3G networks, but so far, I think everything is pretty much pure talk, not reality.  We are anxiously waiting for the 3G network systems to become widely available and affordable to the average Chinese consumers.  And when that happens I think we will be able to have a better idea of how important mobile search is and how should we play in that battleground.  Having said that, I have to say that I'm optimistic about mobile search going forward.  But the form of mobile search may not be the same as you see today, and today a lot of users that mobile search to the form of WAP and just to clarify that wapbaidu.com is the most popular wireless search in China today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Robin, maybe a comment on the relative importance of the carriers in this market going forward, China Mobile, China Unicom?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the carriers are very, very important in this market.  But going forward we do expect more competition among the carriers, which should be a good impact for players like us who offer application services on top of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks again, and congratulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from James Mitchell with Goldman Sachs.  Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks for taking the question.  When I look at your operating expenses increasing quarter on quarter, on the SG&amp;A and on the R&amp;D, is that increase mostly due to new head count additions, a bigger head count?  Or is it mostly due to salary increases for existing head count?  And what kind of wage inflation are you experiencing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jennifer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, our SG&amp;A and R&amp;D expense increases are predominantly driven by head count increases.  For the quarter, we ended the quarter with a total head count of about 6,700 and that's up from about 6,200 at the end of Q4.  We do, as you know, continue to ramp up our direct sales force through the transition of this engine distribution channel.  And at the same time, primarily our head count increases are in the R&amp;D function as we build up the capabilities of the function and try to expand the product offerings.  We do also see salary increases over time.  Generally, in the Q1 timeframe is when we give yearly increases and year-end bonuses.  So Q1 you do continue to see operating expenses, SG&amp;A go up a little bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What sort of wage inflation are you experiencing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our compensation is a total package.  It's a combination of a cash bonus and a stock-based compensation, so we look at everything as a total package.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what kind of total package inflation are you experiencing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Slightly better than the CPI increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Richard Ji, with Morgan Stanley. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Robin, Jennifer, Haoyu, good quarter. I have one question -- two questions actually, starting with the average spending per customer, and which you say rather flattish, quarter-on-quarter.  Is that mainly due to a seasonality issue, or some other factors, and should we expect acceleration in the ARPU figure for your customer?  And a related question is, again, <mark type="inaudible" /> prices in China are facing a lot of challenges this year and they're due to a tighter credit environment, and higher depreciation, as well as rising labor factors.  And so far, have you seen a material impact on your customer base, and especially for their advertising budget?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. For the ARPU, I think it's a function of seasonality, because of the Chinese New Year, as well as the severe snowstorm.  In many of the areas in China traffic actually dropped significantly during that period and our sales force were not able to go out and approach retail customers during that period.  So average spending actually was flattish quarter-on-quarter, but if you look at the year-over-year number, it's still looking very good.  So don't worry about ARPU.  I think for Q2, it will have significant increase on that front.  Regarding to the ad spend customers -- so far, we haven't seen any slowdown, in their spending or in their interest to use our platform.  We continue to believe that paid search is the best promotional platform for any company of any size to promote their product and services.  If there's any challenge in their operations, the first cut of their promotional budget should not come from the Baidu budget, it should come from other areas.  And if the goal is to save costs, they can just move all the other budget to the Baidu platform.  I haven't seen any negative impact from the tax credit or an RMB appreciation to our customer spending.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Robin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Gene Munster with Piper Jaffray.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You have my congratulations.  And if you look at this &#x2013; the revenue growth and the guidance, this looks more like a breakout period versus a -- or a breakout quarter versus kind of a longer inflection time.  It seems like something's actually going on.  I know you mentioned earlier in the call a number of different factors.  Is there one factor that -- one or two factors that have really caused this revenue acceleration?  My first question.  Second is can you repeat what the paid click growth was year-over-year please?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, when you look at the revenue guidance, you really need to look at the year-over-year number.  I think to us it just looks normal.  We have been growing like this year after year, so this year is no exception.  Now I know that's kind of impressive because that number gets larger and larger, but also the paid search marketing in China has become more mature, and quarter after quarter we see more companies come to us as they realize that the power of our capital and they realize the benefit of paid search.  So far, all over the world, I haven't seen any other promotional platform that's better than paid search, and of course Baidu dominates the paid search market in China.  So I think that's the main reason.  In addition to that, I think that execution is very important.  We have been very careful.  We have been doing a good job in executing our strategies and our vision.</p>
          <p>In terms of number of paid clicks, we never disclosed this kind of metric, because the paid search offering is still being revamped constantly, and sometimes we may tune down the number of clicks a bit.  Sometimes we may turn tune it up.  And it's a tricky balance between the average clicking price and number of clicks, the relevancy of the ad, the user experience -- that the bidding structure.  There are lots of factors we are playing with.  So before the monetization algorithm is stable, I don't think we want to discuss the trends in the number of paid clicks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  How about revenue per click?  Revenue per click growth?  Is that something you can --.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In a broader sense I have to tell you that the number of clicks and the revenue per click have been going up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Great.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe just add more color to your first question about Q2 versus Q1, if you look at historical Q2 versus Q1, we always have the best sequential growth.  So we don't' really look at it quarter, this coming Q2 as a breakout.  It's really a normal, and if you look at year-over-year, we are still targeting over 9% growth, that's really demonstrates our confidence in the business model and our execution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of James Lee with Sterne Agee Capital Markets.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Robin.  Can you talk about the, elaborate about the banner program a little bit?  Can we get a sixth sense of the scale of the business, like how many advertisers you currently have, and if you could talk about pricing a little bit maybe compared to last year?  How much of a pricing leverage you were able to get, and maybe compare that versus the major portals?  That would be very helpful.  Maybe talk about some of the top verticals in there as well?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Haoyu, you want to take on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we have, as you know, we have banner ads on our non-web search pop-ups such as Baidu Knows and Baidu Post Bar, and we interpret the number of advertisers to be in the hundreds.  Probably less than 1,000, but it's definitely in the hundreds, and these advertisers, they typically buy both banner ads and paid search, either in the same campaign or in a different campaigns. And they pick up display ads, sometimes it's similar to <mark type="inaudible" /> and we do have rate increase there.  So as far as the ads for the advertisers, we identify them in terms of price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Haoyu, you were going in and out.  Sorry if I missed it.  When's the last time you increased the price, and how much?  Can we get a sense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We typically increase rate by in January and in third quarter.  So we did again this January, but I don't want to get into the details of exact numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Lastly, can you talk about the ASP of the major advertisers on your banner program versus maybe consider ASP versus small to medium size, how much more are they spending versus the SMEs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't dictate how they pay us when someone posts their ads.  I think it's you don't like at whether it's SME or advertisers since they're put in the same system.  When you think about ASP, you probably would think about the certain sectors.  Different sectors, typically have &#x2013; are in different levels of profitability and vary a lot in different sectors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was referring to your banner program.  Like how much, what's ARPU per advertiser, I just want to get a sense, compared to your SMEs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The ARPU for &#x2013; we only have hundred of big advertisers.  Their ARPU is higher, much higher than small advertisers, than SMEs.  Although within the SME universe there are more and more advertisers who are spending a lot of resources every quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Steve Weinstein with Pacific Crest.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. Just a follow-up question on the operating expenses.  In particular the sales and marketing expenses as a percent of revenue hit a level that we haven't seen in quite a while. Can you go over what were some of the investments that came in that quarter particularly on that line?  And how should we think about that in terms of an ability to get leverage to kind of work through the year and the sequential growth of the business?  So are those going to be like ongoing investments and we should think about that as a higher base or are they kind of front end loaded people costs that we'll see leverage on going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look at the Q1 '08 versus Q1 '07 you will notice our revenue went by up 108%; our SG&amp;A expenses went up basically at the same percentage.  It's &#x2013; bear in mind like over the years when we have time.  Basically we invested in the direct sales force and so hired the sales force and as well hired customer support functions.  So the SG&amp;A in general, if you think about the population of customers out there that we support, that's constantly going up so we will have to hire customer support teams to support to provide the best service to the customer.</p>
          <p>At the same time I think the major investment is made in the direct sales force.  Transitioning in all the channels to the direct sales force in the main market areas will help us focus on developing the vast customer base and get more operational efficiency over time.  We have mentioned in the past, the transition to direct sales force, we do not see the impact immediately.  It takes a few quarters for us to actually see this, the operating efficiency.  So in this particular timeframe over the past year as we see the SG&amp;A expenses go up,  it's primarily a reflection of the investment in the kind of reorganizing the distribution channel so that we have the sales force that we can sustain and utilize them and build greater revenue generation going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We did -- just one thing, we did have a Baidu entertainment ceremony, a reward ceremony in this past quarter so I think that added RMB3 million to SG&amp;A expense in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Did you say 3 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually yes.  It's a bit higher than 3 million.  So we did have, just quarter-over-quarter trend, there are a couple of things that happen in Q1.  We did have a local entertainment kind of a promotional event.  That event itself drives so many expenses.  In addition we had our official launch in Japan so that event itself also pulled some promotional expense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks a lot. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Stephen Ju with RBC Capital Markets.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Good morning, everybody.  So sorry to keep harping on regarding the TAC rate again but just to clarify on the growth rates for Baidu Union base revenue versus your owned and operated revenue.  Is it fair to assume that revenue from Baidu Union is growing faster than your owned and operated?  And is your Union based revenue growing faster than your owned and operated on an organic basis?  And also how should we think about this TAC rate going forward?  Will it stabilize?  Because this seems to be the primary source of your gross margin. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes revenue from Union members has been growing faster than Baidu's own property.  Organically I don't have the detailed numbers in front of me but I would say a lot of Union revenues growth is due to the addition of new Union members.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.  But if you strip out the new Union members and just look at it on kind of a same store basis if you will and compare that versus your owned and operated?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said I don't have the exact numbers in front of me but I would think the growth is contributed by those two factors, but I don't have the exact numbers in front of me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Also I would add that we have the flexibility to turn around to shift the revenue from organic to Union and vice versa.  We can choose to show more ads on the Union site, and we can choose less ads on the Union site.  It really depends on our assessment of the ROI for our customers or advertisers and our assessment of the return for our profitability and revenue growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to add a few comments here.  You do look at TAC as an important component of our costs.  It does demonstrate that Union traffic and Union revenue is an important contributor to our total revenue.  Our organic source of revenue as well as Union revenues are both going up, but to Robin's point, we can definitely leverage the partnership and we can turn on or off of the Union traffic any partnerships that we build.  To the extent we believe the Union partnership brings positive contributions to Baidu, if you think about the way we support our customers, we have a growing population of customers, and these customers will either use Baidu's old platform to promote themselves, or kind of reach out through the Union platform to reach out to a broader space of customers.  I think the infrastructure for us to support the core customer base is the same, but the Union platform offers us an extended kind of reach to the end users.  So it benefits Baidu, it benefits our Union customers, and it actually benefits the end users who get to see more products, more services.  So it's a win-win situation for all, and I think my point is, and I think you mentioned about gross margin compression, through the Union network is definitely the faster way to grow the business, but if we have the infrastructure already, this offers an additional platform bringing additional revenue -- actually it's a better way to produce a better operating profit margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think if you are really interested in the TAC issue, you can just back out the TAC and look at the main revenue growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Wallace Cheung with Credit Suisse.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.  Two questions, first of all, can you just give us a bit more highlight on the strategies on Hi?  So is this close to like <mark type="inaudible" /> and can add more business models to your company?  Or is it more like PUD say Adivan Wang, is more like a supportive platform for your C2C going forward.  And the second question will be regarding to the interest income, surprisingly your cash is going up, but your interest income going down on a sequential basis, is it because you're keeping more cash on the US dollars?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, for our IM Baidu Hi, the strategy is to really provide a better user experience for our existing users.  As you know, we have a number of community oriented products like Post Bar, Baidu Knows, Baidu Encyclopedia and our users do have the need to communicate instantly and this also relates to the culture for Chinese internet users.  We believe that Baidu Hi fulfills this kind of demand from our users.  Currently, we do not expect any revenue from Baidu Hi and it is just a tool for the existing Baidu users for other kind of applications, be it C2C or Post Bar or Baidu Space.  It's really an integrated user experience.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jennifer, you want to pick up on the interest question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry Wallace, can you please repeat your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, Jennifer.  So the interest income on a sequential basis, based on my records is actually coming down a little bit, but the cash level is going up.  So I am just figuring out what the reason behind it is because maybe you are holding more US dollars cash, then the interest rate coming down, the US dollar is depreciating and so your cash is getting higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's predominantly market driven.  Our cash and cash equivalents, primarily earns money market rates, as the overall rate environment comes down, that's basically the interest income comes down.  But the cash level, as you noted, is actually going up, of course it's due to positive cash flow generated by operations, less the primary spenders, which is primarily on the capital expenditure side.  So our cash levels are going up, but lower interest income is predominantly due to lower market rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You mean, when you talk about market rate, do you mean US market rate or the RMB market rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Both, okay thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Kwan (sic) [Mark May] with Needham &amp; Company. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys, good morning, thanks for taking my question.  I was just wondering, how many of the customers that you guys had this year were -- had never previously marketed with Baidu before?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't provide that statistic, but if you look at quarter-over-quarter number of customer growth, I think a meaningful number is from customers who never stand with us before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Collin Gillis, with Canaccord. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the Union, can you discuss how many of the different brackets there are right now, and maybe how many members there are in the top bracket?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Generally, we have five categories of Union members.  We have third party websites.  We have softwares.  We have internet cafes and we have carriers.  The last category, I think, is the other ad networks.  We have, in total, we have over, I believe we have over 160 or 170,000 Union members.  And I can't provide breakdown of numbers in each category.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could we get a sense maybe in a rough term, what percent strive to make that top category?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, they -- by and large all the Union members can be categorized into these top five.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then turning to Japan, what was the head count at the end of the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do not provide the exact number of head count in Japan, but it has been growing steadily.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So could we just get a sense in terms of that 20 to 25 million expense?  Any color to the ramp of when that comes?  Should we see it growing linearly, or is there a spike in any particular quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's pretty much going to be linear growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  I guess just, finally, looking out five years, do you see any major shifts in Baidu's market share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are confident that we will continue to be the dominant player for the foreseeable future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Hey, thank you for taking my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes as a follow-up from the line of Dick Wei with JPMorgan.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, folks, just a quick question. First, did you mention anything about the launch base of C2C -- is that first half of '08, or is that just 2008?  And secondly, if we can get some guidance on the tax rate, how should we look at for next couple of quarters, if you are qualified for special tax treatment, and if you do not get that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry can you repeat the first question about C2C?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes just the launch date for the C2C service.  Is that first half '08? That's what I believe was mentioned before, in 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We never mentioned the exact date of the C2C launch.  We only said it's this year, sometime this year.  The exact date has not been decided yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the tax rate question the -- you probably know, and I mentioned in my remarks that at the beginning of the year we do have a new law coming into place.  We have now more detailed information on the actual guidelines in terms of the preferential treatment for certain qualified entities and what that looks like.  It's still not finalized yet, but what I wanted to point out is if you look at our Q1 tax expenditure we have mentioned that our -- a certain of our tax of our entities are migrating through their tax holidays and one entity actually has the tax off holidays expired and another one is moving on to the next stage.  Still enjoying low tax, preferred tax rates, but it's higher than what they had enjoyed in the past two years. But in terms of the new law, whether we qualify or not, it only will impact part of Baidu's legal entities.  It does not, even if we don't qualify, it does not have a material impact on our total effective tax rate.  You look at Q1, our tax rate is close to 7% and we think that for the remainder of the year it's still in the single digit range but more reflective of what you have seen in Q1.  It's in higher end of the single digit range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes as a follow-up from the line of James Mitchell with Goldman Sachs.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking the follow-up and I apologize, it's slightly detailed.  If I just look at the cash flow your CapEx is 158 million, your depreciation is 65 million and your PP&amp;E is flat?  What happens to the balance of the CapEx on the balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We capitalize it, but what it basically says is what we show on our balance sheet is a net balance so through the quarter the depreciation was -- the depreciation itself was 62 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes as a follow-up from the James --.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me follow -- let me take a note of that and follow up with you offline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question does come as a follow-up from the line of James Lee with Sterne Agee Capital Markets.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just some quick housekeeping questions here.  Can you guys just reconfirm what the CapEx spending planning for this year, and also last quarter you guys don't disclose the traffic of non-search on your Baidu.com, that was like 60% as of last quarter?  I wonder if anything has changed to that traffic pattern?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding to the non-search traffic, I think the percentage has been quite stable, with the non-search traffic growing slightly faster than the web-search traffic.  On the CapEx spending for the next year, for the rest of year, Jennifer do you want to say a few words?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, absolutely. For the remainder of the year we mentioned one portion of our capital expenditures related to the impact of Baidu Campus. So we'll continue to incur that expenditure.  We will have, continue to have CapEx related to equipment and capacity expansion, so we continue to invest in future opportunities.  I just wanted to get back on the question earlier related to the reconciliation of the cash flow stated CapEx versus what you're seeing on the balance sheet. It's cash flow related, the 158 million, but what we have capitalized, the 158 is cash related.  Part of this activity is already capitalized in prior periods, and so it's not directly reconciled, you can know that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Jennifer, can I ask you a quick follow-up question?  Can you just update on the CapEx for Baidu Campus and how much have you spent so far?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have mentioned in the past three quarters that a big portion of our capital expenditure was Baidu Campus related.  So a few months of late, as you look at it, we spent about 150, 160 million a quarter, which that cumulatively will be close to 150 million in terms of construction related expenses.  For the Baidu Campus itself, we do anticipate to ramp up, and you know the construction and everything, in '09, between '08 and '09.  The Campus-related capital expenditures total between 50 to $60 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We are now approaching the end of the conference call.  I will now turn the call over to Baidu's Chief Executive Officer, Robin Li, for his closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Once again, thank you for joining us today, and please do not hesitate to contact us if you have any further questions.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation in today's conference.  This concludes the presentation.  You may now disconnect.  Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>