<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1446264" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-01-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>77</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Andy Clark</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman, President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Gerald L. Hassell</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice Chairman &amp; Chief Financial Officer">Thomas P. Gibbons</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Securities International, Inc.">Glenn Schorr</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice Chairman &amp; CEO-Investment Management">Curtis Y. Arledge</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice Chairman">Timothy Keaney</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (United States)">Howard H. Chen</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Alexander Blostein</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">Ken M. Usdin</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice Chairman &amp; CEO-Financial Markets &amp; Treasury">Karen B. Peetz</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Agricole Securities (USA), Inc.">Rob C. Rutschow</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Guggenheim Securities LLC">Marty Lacey Mosby</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Brian B. Bedell</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Executive VP &amp; CEO-Global Markets">Arthur Certosimo</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="SunTrust Robinson Humphrey">John Wolfe Stilmar</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Executive Vice President">Brian Thomas Shea</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Betsy L. Graseck</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Gerard Cassidy</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the fourth quarter 2011 earnings conference call hosted by BNY Mellon. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Mr. Andy Clark. Mr. Clark, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lindy. And welcome, everyone. With us today are Gerald Hassell, our Chairman, President, and CEO; Todd Gibbons, our CFO; as well as several members of our executive management team.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, let me remind you that our remarks today may include forward-looking statements. Actual results may differ materially from those indicated or implied by the forward-looking statements as a result of various factors. These factors include those identified in the cautionary statement on Page 13 of the press release, those identified in our documents filed with the SEC that are available on our website, BNYmellon.com. Forward-looking statements in this call speak only as of today, January 18, 2012, and we will not update forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>This morning's press release provides the highlights of our results, and we also have the quarterly earnings review document available on our website, which provides a quarterly review of the total company and the individual businesses. We will be using the quarterly earnings review document to discuss our results.</p>
          <p>Now, I'd like to turn the call over to Gerald. Gerald?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Andy. And good morning, everyone. And thanks for joining us on what I know is a very busy day for you all.</p>
          <p>For the quarter, we generated net income of $505 million and earnings per share of $0.42, which compares to $0.54 in the fourth quarter of last year. I should note that the fourth quarter of 2011 included a restructuring charge related to our efficiency initiatives and some other items that Todd will cover in just a minute.</p>
          <p>Obviously, it was a tough revenue quarter, as our results reflected the ongoing macro environment challenges. The general uncertainty in the financial markets resulted in lower-than-normal levels of client activity. Now, a good indicator of that is the combined share volume on the New York Stock Exchange and NASDAQ, which was down 6% year over year and 18% sequentially. That clearly has an impact on areas like our investment services fee revenues.</p>
          <p>Investors have been very risk-averse. We saw a lack of organic growth as our clients reallocated their assets in a more defensive posture, significantly to cash, in response to uncertainty in the markets.</p>
          <p>Money market fund managers, including our own, have been particularly conservative. They've shortened durations and reduced European exposure, which resulted in lower yields and even higher money market fee fund waivers.</p>
          <p>Now, despite those challenges, we were pleased with what we were able to accomplish in terms of winning new business, strengthening our balance sheet, controlling expenses, and positioning our company for 2012.</p>
          <p>We are continuing to win new business. In asset management, we had positive long-term flows in every quarter in 2011. And in the fourth quarter, we had another strong quarter in terms of new assets under custody wins.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet continues to strengthen in terms of liquidity, asset quality, and capital. On the liquidity front, deposit levels grew significantly. For example, non-interest-bearing deposits were up 93% year over year. Asset quality improved as our sub-investment-grade securities declined 11% due to paydowns and some opportunistic selling.</p>
          <p>And on the capital front, we generated almost $570 million of Tier 1 common and are ahead of where we expected to be in terms of Basel III Tier 1 common ratio. And excluding the restructuring charge, we delivered a very strong 20% return on that increased level of equity capital.</p>
          <p>Now, we did slow down our buyback program a bit in the fourth quarter to make sure we met our capital targets. But we are looking to resume our program this quarter.</p>
          <p>Now, most of our core investment services metrics continued to look good, especially in clearing, but they were severely impacted by volumes. And in investment management, we're encouraged by our continued strong long-term investment performance and positive flow.</p>
          <p>On the expense front, we made meaningful progress in containing expense growth and bringing down our run rate as we have begun to realize the benefits of the efficiency initiatives we discussed at our Investor Day. Excluding the restructuring charge, total expenses were down 3% sequentially and down 2% year over year. And that's ahead of where we expected to be at this particular point.</p>
          <p>Now, those efficiency initiatives are still in their early days, so we have substantial benefits to come, but we're off to a strong start in terms of adjusting our cost base to manage through the current environment.</p>
          <p>Now, I should also note that we closed a deal to sell our Shareowner Services business. We were able to get a good price for the business, and it takes goodwill intangibles off our balance sheet and positions us to improve our profit margin going forward.</p>
          <p>So lots of meaningful progress during the quarter. And while the revenue environment was tough, we believe the lower level of client activity to be a short-term issue. Our fee revenue should recover quickly as we return to normal levels of activity. In the meantime, we're controlling our expense base to offset market weakness. We're investing in areas that will generate organic revenue growth, we're putting our deposits to work, and we remain very focused on returning capital to shareholders.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it over to Todd to go through the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Gerald, and good morning, everyone. As I take you through the numbers, my comments will follow the quarterly earnings review beginning on Page 2.</p>
          <p>Earnings for the quarter were $0.42. As Gerald noted, that included a restructuring charge of $107 million or approximately $0.06, and that was related to our efficiency efforts. And there was about $0.02 of charges related to a higher provision and higher M&amp;I expenses.</p>
          <p>Our results included the impact of lower volumes, as Gerald mentioned, generally reflecting the uncertainty in the financial markets. And we saw that especially late in the quarter. Combined share volume on the exchanges was down meaningfully; year over year, key international markets were down substantially; and the U.S. indices were flat. And more specifically to our results, we were impacted by the new seasonality that we experienced in our Depositary Receipts business. So in this environment, our success is really based on our ability to reduce the growth rate of operating expenses, and we made some pretty good progress, as Gerald had noted.</p>
          <p>Now let's look at the highlights on a year-over-year basis. Total revenue was $3.5 billion; that's down 6%. Investment services fees were down 8%, and that's primarily due to the lower DR revenue. But it also was impacted by lower volumes and higher money market fee waivers. As you'll recall, the seasonal spike in corporate actions in our DR business that normally occur in the fourth quarter now occur in the third quarter. If you adjust for that seasonal impact, investment services fees decreased 3%.</p>
          <p>Investment management and performance fees were down 9%. That, too, was driven by higher money market fee waivers, lower performance fees, and weaker international equity markets that were partially offset by net new business. Net interest revenue here was a bright spot. It was up 8%. And that largely reflects the additional client deposits and the growth in secured lending, as well as our securities portfolio. The provision was $23 million, and it primarily resulted from the default of a broker-dealer customer. Our noninterest expense increased just 1%, and it was down 2% if we exclude the restructuring charges and M&amp;I expenses, and 3% on that same basis for the linked quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to Page 4, where we call out some business metrics that'll help explain our underlying performance. You can see that assets under management was up 8% year over year to $1.26 trillion. We had long-term inflows of $16 billion in the fourth quarter, and so we've had positive long-term flows in every quarter of 2011. Long-term inflows have benefited from the strength in the fixed income and equity index products. Short-term inflows for the quarter was about $7 billion. Assets under custody was flat sequentially, but it's up 3% year over year, to a total of $25.8 trillion. Most of that was driven by net new business.</p>
          <p>Now, most of the metrics that you see here showed solid growth on a year-over-year basis. Loans and deposits continue to grow. DR programs are up modestly, and clearing and broker-dealer services metrics are up substantially. However, each of our investment services businesses was impact by the sharp decline in volumes in the quarter, though the underlying fundamentals of our business remain pretty strong, and that positions us well for any rebound in the capital markets. Asset servicing fees were down 3% year over year and 4% sequentially. Both decreases reflect lower volumes, a shift in client asset allocations, and determination of client relationships from recent acquisitions that we made. And these terminations result from the fact that clients don't meet our risk profile. That was partially offset by the impact of net new business. We had a very strong new business quarter, with $431 billion in new AUC wins, all of which we would expect to be converted by the end of the second quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>Issuer services fees were down 30% year over year and 35% sequentially. And again, that's due to the seasonally lower DR revenues. If you adjust for that seasonality, fees were basically flat sequentially. Clearing fees were flat year over year, as new business was offset by lower volumes and then higher fee waivers. They were down 6% sequentially, reflecting the lower trading volumes and, again, the higher linked-quarter money market fee waivers. Investment management and performance fees were down 9% year over year and flat sequentially. Sequentially, investment management fees were flat as net new business and higher performance fees were offset by lower revenue and equity investments and higher money market fee waivers.</p>
          <p>Now, you've heard me mention the money market fee waivers several times now. Let me now aggregate the impact across our company. For the quarter, money market fee waivers were a $0.06 drag on our EPS, and that compares to 3% last year and $0.05 in the third quarter. The revenue impact was nearly $65 million for the year-over-year quarter.</p>
          <p>In FX and other trading, revenue was down year over year, but it was up sequentially. Looking at the components, FX revenue totaled $183 million. That's a decrease of 11% year over year and 17% sequentially. Both decreases reflected lower volumes. The year-over-year decrease was partially offset by higher volatility, while sequentially volatility actually decreased. Other trading revenue was $45 million. That compares to $52 million last year and a loss of $21 million in the third quarter. The sequential improvement was primarily driven by a lower credit valuation adjustment.</p>
          <p>Now, some of you have may seen that yesterday we reached a partial settlement in the FX lawsuit that was brought by the U.S. Attorney's Office. The settlement resolves disclosure claims that related to FX marketing. We are pleased with the settlement, but you should be aware that no financial agreement is related to it, and it does not effect any claims for monetary damages. And importantly, it also does not admit to any wrongdoing on our part. As we've said in the past, we will continue to be alert to opportunities for pragmatic resolutions. However, we remain convinced that our legal defenses continue to be rock solid.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to investment and other income, it totaled $146 million in the fourth quarter of 2011. That compares with $80 million in the prior year and $83 million in the third quarter. The increases over both periods primarily resulted from a pre-tax gain of $98 million on the sale of Shareowner Services, and that was partially offset by a $30 million write-down of an equity investment. Now, I'd like to point out that the $98 million pre-tax gain on the sale of Shareowner Services translated into only a $4 million after-tax gain, due to the non-tax-deductible goodwill that was associated with the business.</p>
          <p>Turning to Page 8 of the earnings review, NIR was up $60 million versus the year-ago quarter, and it was up 5% sequentially. Both increases reflect growth in client deposits, which drove the increase in cash at central banks. Average non-interest-bearing client deposits increased $3 billion or 4% versus the third quarter. The year-over-year increase also reflects increased investment in high-grade securities and growth in our secured lending program. The net interest margin was 1.27%. That compares to 1.54% a year ago, and the decrease was driven by just the increased deposit base.</p>
          <p>Turning to Page 9, you can see that year-over-year total non-interest expense, excluding the restructuring charges and M&amp;I expenses, declined 2%, and that's reflecting lower staff expense, which was partially offset by higher litigation expense. If you exclude the impact of litigation, expenses actually declined 3%. The sequential decrease primarily resulted from lower staff expense, reflecting lower incentives, as well as a decline in head count, and lower litigation expense and lower volume-driven expense. All of that was partially offset by higher professional, legal, and other purchased services, which was primarily consulting; software and equipment; and business development expenses. The increase in software and equipment was due to increased license fees and some new software that we brought online. As you can see, the $107 million in restructuring charges was comprised of $78 million for severance costs, and there was $29 million of lease write-offs and consulting expenses.</p>
          <p>Page 10 details our capital ratios. As Gerald noted, our estimated Basel III Tier 1 common equity ratio was up 60 basis points to 7.1% at quarter end. That's a little ahead of what our previous guidance was. A little less than half of the improvement was driven by the reduction in goodwill and intangible assets, as well as the risk-weighted assets related to our sale of Shareowner Services business. Paydowns in sales of investment securities accounted for most of the remaining benefit from the reduction in risk-weighted assets, and the other contribution was obviously the retention of earnings. We continue to expect to generate about 20 to 25 basis points a quarter in Basel III Tier 1 common, and that includes the impact of buybacks and dividends.</p>
          <p>We're fortunate that our business model enables us to rapidly generate capital, and it does not require significant growth in risk-weighted assets. Both of these attributes position us very well to comply with all the Basel III requirements well ahead of the phase-in periods. Our Basel Tier 1 common equity ratio was 13.4% at year-end. That's up 90 basis points from the end of September, driven primarily by earnings retention and the sale of Shareowner Services, as we generated approximately $570 million of Basel I equity in the fourth quarter. Part of the growth resulted from the decision to slow our buybacks in the quarter to strengthen our leverage ratio. Now that we have done that, we're well positioned to continue buying back shares in the fourth quarter &#x2013; excuse me, in the first quarter &#x2013; under our existing program.</p>
          <p>On Page 11, you can see that our investment securities portfolio continues to perform well. The watch list actually declined 15%, and the sub-investment-grade RMBS securities were down about 11%. And those were down, driven by sales &#x2013; excuse me, by paydowns &#x2013; but we did do some opportunistic sales as well. The pre-tax net unrealized gain in our securities portfolio decreased modestly to $793 million.</p>
          <p>Looking at our loan portfolio, you'll see that the provision for credit losses was $23 million. That compares with a credit of $22 million in the prior and year-ago quarters, and the increase provision was primarily the result of the bankruptcy of a broker-dealer that I earlier mentioned. NPAs actually declined in the quarter from $344 million to $341 million. The effective tax rate of 30.6%, that was negatively impacted by the non-deductible goodwill associated with the sale of Shareowner Services, but most of that was offset by a more favorable mix of foreign and domestic income.</p>
          <p>Now, looking ahead, NII should be steady. Fee waivers may not get better, but they should have troughed. Of course, I think I mentioned that on multiple earlier calls, that I thought that they'd troughed. But at this point, there's not much left to waive. The quarterly provision should be in the range of 0 to $15 million. We're focused on driving down expenses through our operational excellence initiatives. As we've outlined at our Investor Day, our initiatives are projected to drive net savings of $240 million to $260 million this year, and we've made some pretty good early progress. Assuming regulatory approval, we plan on a combined dividend and share buyback ratio of 60% to 65% for 2012. As always, the timing of our share buybacks will be based on prevailing market conditions. The significant growth in our capital positions us well for the stress test that we, by the way, we just recently submitted to our regulators. And finally, the tax rate in the first quarter should continue to be approximately 30%.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it back to Gerald.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Todd, and I think we can open it up for questions.</p>
          <p>QUESTION AND ANSWER SESSION</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question today is from Glen Schorr with Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Glenn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. So timing sometimes gets in the way here, but just think it's a little interesting, assets under management up 5% quarter on quarter, fees are flat. Assets under custody, flat quarter on quarter, fees are down, whether you want to include the seasonality in DR or not. Is there a little function of timing there? Is &#x2013; there's a little money market in there. But is the mix of business changing such that the relationship between the assets and the fees don't match as much as they did in the past?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, why don't I start on that and then ask Todd and maybe Curtis or Tim to jump in. I think we saw, one, client activity on the volumes decline. Two, the shift into risk-off mode, so assets went into cash &#x2013; or, frankly, they went into deposits, and so you don't get an asset under custody fee if it's in a bank deposit. The same would hold true in the asset management side. So I think we just saw, as the year-end approached last year, a complete risk-off mode, so a decline in volumes, a movement to cash, more risk-averse, which doesn't allow for fee activity either in investment services or investment management area. We do think that that's short-lived. Investors do have to invest. They do have to get a return, and I just think we saw a very soft fourth quarter that we don't expect to continue for the long term. But I don't know if &#x2013; Curtis, maybe you want to comment on the investment management side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, absolutely. From an investment management perspective, the growth in AUM has absolutely come in fixed income and, as Todd mentioned, equity index products, so lower-fee products generally. We've actually held our own pretty well in equity flows, where the industry had a pretty tough year generally. So we're happy about that. I think that what you're seeing in fees is really the impact of two things. And, Glenn, to your point, it is a bit of a timing dynamic around performance fees. We had a very strong quarter in the fourth quarter of 2010. We had a pretty good quarter this quarter. Just not as strong. And then fee waivers have definitely had a very significant impact, as Todd mentioned. So money market fee waivers and lower performance fees are causing an offset to nice business, new business growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let me add a little bit to that, Glenn, and then maybe Tim wants to add something as well. One of the things that you don't see is, in the fee side, is as money moves out of money market funds, we are seeing it come onto our balance sheet. And that's why we've seen some of the growth in net interest revenue. It's not as meaningful as it would have been in the fee side in this very low-interest-rate environment, but that's masking some of the moves. So there is some modest offset &#x2013; not as much as we would like &#x2013; just in the growth of the balance sheet due to that risk-off trade. I don't know if, Tim, if you have anything to add.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, Todd, the only last point maybe I'd make is, Glenn, that we only converted about $165 billion for the quarter in new business, so on a relative basis, as you look backwards, that was one of our lower quarters. The good news is of the $1.2 trillion that we won, we still have yet to convert about $530 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does that $530 billion include what you just announced as new business wins in the fourth quarter? Is that your won-but-not-yet-converted pipeline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly, and I think as Gerald mentioned in his opening comments, we see a lot of that converting by the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's perfect. One last one. Just curious on your thoughts &#x2013; your comments on the partial settlement. Maybe we could &#x2013; you mentioned the no money component. What's next? In other words, what does the settlement represent with the AG? Is the <mark type="ph" /> principle in (24:28) how you conduct business going forward? And then the &#x2013; it's up to individual clients to go about suits if that's how they want to proceed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, just to clarify, Glenn, the settlement was with the U.S. Attorney, not the AG.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Apologize, yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so it was primarily around our marketing materials, and so we were happy to get that behind us. As far as the AG suits, that continues to progress. There's not much to add on that, other than we think our legal defenses are very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so that's something that might just have a much longer tail. Okay. I very much appreciate it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Glenn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Glenn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Howard Chen with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Howard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You're protecting and growing spread income really well. Was just hoping you could provide a bit more color with the deposit flows during the quarter, given all that's going on in macro environment. We can see a bunch of the puts and takes with the non-interest-bearing and the interest-bearing deposits, but was just hoping you could elaborate a bit there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. A lot of that tends to be &#x2013; in our client base, there's a core amount, and then there's some kind of what I would call episodic amounts. And we did see, especially at quarter end, we saw a spike when we saw it once again. We actually saw negative repo rates at quarter end. So the core custody and trust deposits are seeing pretty continuous growth. And then from hedge funds and even in some in instances broker-dealers, we're seeing some spikes. Those spikes have mostly worn off now in the first quarter, and we're continuing at what I would call the &#x2013; what has become the new kind of core deposit base, which continues to show some modest growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Todd. And at the Investor Day, you outlined some actions focused on stabilizing the NIM. Could you just update us on where we stand on those initiatives, and is it still feasible to kind of think about stabilization, given the rate environment's deteriorated a bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think it is, because we are putting &#x2013; as Gerald mentioned, we're putting more and more of the cash to work. So if we &#x2013; say we move $20 billion out of the central banks where we're earning 25 basis points and we can put them into securities or secured loans at 100 to 150 basis points, that can offset even the lower-rate environment pretty rapidly. So we feel okay that we can stabilize. It's going to be hard to grow the NIM in this kind of an environment. Actually, what would grow the NIM the most is if deposits were to come off a little bit and just normalize.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That makes sense. Thanks, Todd. And then finally for me, you touched on money market fee waivers, but was just hoping you could update us on your thoughts on when and what you expect to hear from the SEC on broader money market reform and how you're scenario planning for all of that. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You want &#x2013; maybe, Curtis, you want -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Curtis, why don't you take that one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. So we're expecting over the next two or three months for the SEC to come out with some proposals. Again, they've gone in the direction of either moving to a floating NAB or to having some capital buffers put in place. There are other things that are suggested, redemption fees and some other things, that have been proposed. We then think it'll take 60 to 90 days of comment period, and then it will go back to the SEC for sort of final &#x2013; any final rule changes, sort of toward the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Obviously, we're spending a lot of time thinking about where it might go, impact on clients, where the money might go if there are significant changes to the industry. We do think that we may capture some of the shift in flows in other places. And we also think that the impact is going to be felt by clients, so we're having a lot of dialogue with them about how to manage their flows, as you imagine.</p>
          <p>The point that has been made &#x2013; Todd made a minute ago &#x2013; though, is I would tell you that the fee waiver dynamic is quite large already, and so if there were a really negative impact, it has already been felt in lower yields. And so today I think that our 2a-7 business is only about 4% of total investment management pre-tax. So it has already &#x2013; the yield environment has already had a pretty significant impact on us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for all the thoughts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Howard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Alex Blostein with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Good morning. I wanted to touch base on the comment, Todd, you made earlier about termination of certain client agreements and client arrangements, I guess, that are falling below your risk profile. Could you, I guess, elaborate on that a little bit further and maybe give us a sense as you go through this sort of client review how many more do you think you could have, and what kind of impact that could have on your revenues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Sure. I think that we've worked our way through that, is the good news. So I don't think we'll see any additional impact. And we have some very high standards around documentation and anti-money-laundering and so forth. And so if our clients aren't going to meet those standards, we won't accept them as clients. And that's what that was related to, and we did bump out a handful of clients, and we felt it in the &#x2013; mostly in the fourth quarter. And now that's built into our run rate, and we're building back off of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. So this had really nothing to do with the pricing and the margining on those clients not being in line with what sort of you're targeting for the business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This was not pricing. This was not pricing related. It was risk related.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And, Alex, they were mostly &#x2013; small alternative managers or small broker-dealers that came to us by way of the GIS acquisition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. Okay. And then maybe a minute on capital priorities. So you pointed out that you guys were thinking you'll be a little bit below 7%, but then you felt like you probably needed to get to 7% by the end of the year, and the buybacks sort of slowed down here a little bit.</p>
          <p>Do you think that either there's a few people out there that, I guess, that want to get to higher capital levels sooner? How do you think about the pace of your capital build over the course of 2012 versus buybacks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We actually &#x2013; we feel pretty good about it. We were a little &#x2013; we actually did a little better in the fourth quarter than we anticipated. A couple of things went on there. We got some meaningful paydowns, and we were a little more opportunistic against some sales of our sub-investment-grade securities. So that added to the benefit of Shareowner Services. And then we had &#x2013; we thought there was going to be a bit of an OCI adjustment that didn't take place.</p>
          <p>Let me make one thing a little bit clearer here, though. We were pretty tight on our leverage ratio with the substantial increase. And we had a 93% increase, and that was just in the free deposits. But we also had a substantial increase in the rest of our deposits. We wanted to go ahead and build that ratio up a bit during the quarter as well. So we got the benefit of having a little pop in our Basel III Tier 1. But that's not what we were actually looking for.</p>
          <p>So now that we've shorn that up, we can go back. We're comfortably in the 60% to 65%, what I'll call capital deployment range, between payouts, between buybacks, and dividend increases. And we're also positioned to restart or complete the program that we announced last year for 2011. The regulators do give you the &#x2013; or they don't object to you as long as we ask for it, and we did &#x2013; they don't object that we continue to proceed against that program in the first quarter, and that's what we intend to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. And then just the last one from me. Just looking at the balance sheet and the shift in earning assets this quarter, it feels like there's a decent amount that came out of the interest-bearing deposits with banks, primarily I guess foreign banks. Is that just reflective of the risk appetite that you guys try to manage to, given what's going on in Europe, or there's something else going on? Because, obviously, there's a big bump at the Fed, and some of that came out of the, I guess, foreign banks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we've been defensive on a risk position as well. We don't need to leave as much short-term cash in the European banks. We're just leaving it in a handful of what we think are the strongest in the right regions. And that ended up building up a little bit in the central banks, which we intend to put back to work, as we described earlier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Ken Usdin with Jefferies. Mr. Usdin, please check your mute button.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, sorry about that. Good morning, guys. I was wondering if you could give us a little bit more color on the issuer services results and then the outlook, given the closing of the Shareholder Services, just to get us an understanding of what we should expect going forward. I mean, it seemed like a month ago you were talking about a decline, certainly, from the pull-forward. So I'm just wondering if you'd kind of &#x2013; sorry for the long question. Can you give us kind of the total? What was the real pull-forward in issuer, in DRs? How did corporate trust act? And then remind us of what goes away with Shareholder so we can understand how &#x2013; the first quarter starting point, it looks like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ken. Let's have Todd take the last part of your question. Then we'll ask Karen to comment about the core business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kind of the way we'd look at it, Ken, the pull-forward from the corporate actions from the third and fourth quarter, what we did is we just averaged the revenues in the two quarters, and we kind of compared that to averaging the revenues in the two quarters in 2010. But if you average those in the third and fourth quarter, our issuer services fees were flat sequentially. That kind of gives you, I think, a good basis, and they are down about 6% on a year-over-year basis, and I think Karen can give some more color on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For issuer service in the aggregate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we're talking specifically about issuer services.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And, Ken, you know, I'm sure, that global debt issuance was down about 7% year on year, and so the difference in corporate trust actually was issuance related and deal related, but also money market fees in that category as well. And then the Shareowner Services business was pretty soft right before we sold it, as would be understandable. So the DR business continues to be pretty strong, and with that seasonality against the corporate actions happening now going forward into third quarter versus the fourth quarter. That's a change that you'll see stick for the future.</p>
          <p>But the business itself, pipeline is pretty good. A very large win in Brazil that'll be public soon, and a pretty strong pipeline otherwise. And we expect both DRs and corporate trust to be kind of in the 3% to 5% range of revenue growth next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On a year-over-year basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then &#x2013; so can you just remind us again &#x2013; so the first quarter versus this fourth quarter number, just trying to understand the trajectory. So you said the run rate when it was announced, Computershare had put out that it was about a, what, $280 million, $290 million revenue run rate. But, Karen, to your point that that was weaker, should we presume that the run rate that comes out was lower than that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes. The run rate was lower kind of toward the end.</p>
          <p>Obviously, we announced the deal in April. And as soon as you announce a deal like that, as you can imagine, new business pretty much dries up. Existing clients, we did lose a couple of clients before the sale. And I think that's all just understandable, based on that news coming out in the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the run rate is somewhere lower than the $70 million. Was it meaningfully different? I'm just trying to get an &#x2013; understand the moving parts between the change in the DR seasonality and then the moving parts of that line going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it wasn't meaningfully different. And from a pre-tax perspective, that's a very low-margin business. So it really didn't have any impact on the pre-tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ken. I don't think you'll see any impact on pre-tax earnings. You will see a bit of a reduction in the issuer services fee line, obviously, probably in &#x2013; I'd call it &#x2013; the run rate in the past couple years has been somewhere around $200 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. My second question, just regarding expenses, which look really good and obviously started to show the benefits. Can you talk us through just the decline in compensation that happened this quarter? How much of that is related to the beginning of the saves &#x2013; the prior expense-save employee reductions that had already been announced, versus what may have been a &#x2013; either a compensation true-up or an adjustment to the actual revenues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ken. Couple of things. One, we did see, as we expected, a decline in our head count of about 900 people in the fourth quarter. So that obviously has some impact on the running rate on the compensation side.</p>
          <p>Obviously, our earnings were off, and so that lowers compensations. And so the combination of the two, plus our initiatives, starts to put in place a lower run rate in both of those categories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my last, final thing just on the capital front. Again, you mentioned that you had slowed the buyback this quarter. In advance of getting the CCAR results, can you use the remainder of the authorized buyback in 1Q? And do you imagine that you will, or will you just be trying to continue to kind of build, so to speak, build capital faster until you get those results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Ken, we are allowed to continue the program that was approved, or the Fed did not object to last year. And we plan to resume our buyback in the first quarter this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ken, let me add one thing there. In a payout of 60% to 65%, that puts us in a retention every quarter, on average, of about 25 basis points increase in our Basel III Tier 1 common. We think that's a pretty rapid retention rate, and there's no need for us &#x2013; we are now at 7.1%. So if we do that for the year, we're at 8.1% at the end of the year. We think that puts us well ahead of where we need to be to meet our ultimate targets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for that, Todd.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Mike Mayo with CLSA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. It's Rob Rutschow. One question on the commercial loan growth. This quarter was pretty decent. Are you guys seeing any shift out of capital markets and onto your balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The loan growth for us is principally in secured loans to our financial institution clients, and it was really putting some of our excess deposits and cash to work for those clients, rather than traditional loan growth that you would experience at other commercial banks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And a follow-up on the deposits. You mentioned that some of the excess deposits have come off so far this year. Can you give us any sort of numbers or give us a sense for how much they're down so far?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Rob. Probably on average about $10 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Couple housekeeping items. The 900 in head count reduction, how much of that was related to the Shareholder (sic) [Shareowner] (40:35) Services sale?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>None.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>None.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>None of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was December 31.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that was December 31, so that's not in those numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then a second question. I think you guys had around $80 million in litigation costs last quarter. Can you give us a similar number for this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, for obvious reasons, Rob, we don't disclose actual litigation reserves. There's no reason to give anybody an advantage there. But they were down somewhat from what we had experienced in the third quarter, and they were up pretty meaningfully from what we experienced in the fourth quarter of last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Marty Mosby with Guggenheim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I was curious about the deterioration in the waivers on the money market accounts. What was the deterioration between third and fourth quarter? Why did it end up hurting another penny?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was his question why, or &#x2013; it did hurt by another penny. And the reason was that the yields in the money market funds continued to decline. I mean, Curtis, you'd probably give some more -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The drop to the third quarter actually was the steepest drop. The first and second were not terrible. The third was bad, and fourth was just a little bit worse than that. So kind of a full quarterly impact of the decline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the way to think about it is all the money market funds, including our own, went to more cash reserves, less European exposure. That brings the yield down. Whatever securities were already on, the yield has come down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So with less yield available to the investor, that's where the higher money market fee waivers come in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as we've said a number of times, we think we've been at the trough, but there sure isn't much left. And we shouldn't kid ourselves. The money market fee waivers across our firm are quite significant, and we are looking at other alternatives on how to offset that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then on the capital front, you talked about the leverage ratio being the constraint. In other words, it wasn't the Tier 1 common ratios you were really concerned about or trying to improve. Have you looked at &#x2013; is that the ratio we should be looking at more for the trust banks relative to the other ratios?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think so, Marty. I think this was &#x2013; it was kind of an unusual circumstance, as we saw the very sharp spike &#x2013; not in risk-weighted assets, but just in the balance sheet with the deposit growth in the third and also in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Now that we have built that ratio up during the quarter, and the fact that it will grow on a quarterly basis as we retain 35%, we don't see it any longer as a constraint.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you see the impact in Basel I to Basel III in the sense of how your assets can change even in the leverage ratio, due to some off-balance-sheet consolidation, being trading accounts or positions and derivatives and things like that. Is that something as well that we should be kind of thinking about? Is that it or a haircut you would take on that ratio as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Actually, the constraint will be the Basel III Tier 1 common. So that's going to be the ratio, I think, that you're going to really want to focus on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess we don't see leverage as a problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and the last question is the 60% to 65%, have you given any thought in a sense of distribution between <mark type="ph" /> what you would think (44:08) dividends versus share repurchase, and how do you look at that going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I mean, we &#x2013; with our share price below book value, we certainly like buying our shares. So we probably will lean to &#x2013; consistent with what we've said in the past.</p>
          <p>Right now, we'd look for a 20% to 25% dividend payout, and we'll make up the difference in share buybacks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Marty.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Brian Bedell with ISI Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, folks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. A question for Tim Keaney. Tim, could you talk a little bit about your initiative to reprice the core asset servicing business? Basically how that's going in terms of conversations with clients, whether you're seeing any attrition yet, and to what extent? I guess if you can talk about it between different types of businesses, the middle office versus the <mark type="ph" /> core of custody (45:10) business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Brian. I'd say it's still very early days, and I think as we talked about in the Investor Day, we're starting with the smaller clients. And we've got about 1,000 clients we're working our way through on the smaller end. So it's probably still too early to give a full report out to you, but I'm somewhat encouraged by what we've seen.</p>
          <p>Certainly as we reprice current clients, we're doing that with the new economic reality, so we're rebidding our business with minimum target profit margins and not being overly dependent on capital markets related revenue. So I think that's probably the best way to answer your question.</p>
          <p>And when we win new business, and we have been successful with that $431 billion that we did in the last quarter, we're doing that with our new pricing disciplines in mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, right. So the new business is coming on with a more appropriate pricing treatment. Does part of that new business to be converted include Bridgewater?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It does, yep. We'll be converting Bridgewater over the next three quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if you had to sort of say when you think you'll start to see sort of a material recalibration of revenues and expenses in this business, do you think it's more later this year, or more over a couple of years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Brian, it's a cycle. Some of our clients are on three-year contracts. A small number of our clients are on four- and five-year. And I just think it's going to take patience and discipline and work through that cycle, and that's exactly what we're doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, great. Okay. And a question for Curtis. In the investment management business, on the performance side, can you talk a little bit about where you think performance fees are levered to in term of the equity markets and fixed income markets, and sort of how your performance sort of dovetails with that?</p>
          <p>And I guess what I'm looking for is, are new mandates coming on that are structured with large performance fee components within the mix, just so we can sort of get a sense going forward of how we might model that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we have an array of investment products that have performance fees that are linked to benchmarks, either benchmarks or to absolute return goals. And so it's hard to say if equity markets are up, the performance fees are going to be up.</p>
          <p>And they are correlated, as you would guess. We have some fixed-income products as well that have performance fees. But, again, they're really geared more to the benchmark, so they aren't the absolute level of markets. Really, it's a wide array of products that drive performance fees, so it's hard to correlate it to anything specific.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just to &#x2013; flipping to foreign exchange trading. Can you talk a little bit about &#x2013; obviously, volatility and volumes were a weak factor for everybody this quarter, but can you talk about the mix of standing instruction within the total core foreign exchange trading?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Brian. Let me pass that to Art Certosimo, who runs all of our global markets activities now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi Brian. We're starting to see more volume through our negotiated channels as the FX market becomes more competitive, and we continue to develop products for our clients that should offset that with our ability to capture more volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And what is the standing instruction mix overall? Is it still close to 40%, or it is down significantly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's about 42%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just lastly, what was net interest revenue discount accretion for the quarter, in terms of a dollar amount?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was <mark type="ph" /> $94 million (49:04), Brian. It was down slightly but not much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from John Stilmar with SunTrust.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Real quickly, the move from 39% international revenue composition to 34% &#x2013; clearly de-risking and currency can have a pretty profound impact. But is there anything more that we should be thinking about, aside from just specific concentrations in Europe more rapidly de-risking than other parts of the world? Or is there another sort of business trend that might be underneath that move? Or is that just kind of the result of the couple themes that we've talked about earlier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The simple answer is the vast majority of the quarter-to-quarter decline in the percentage was depositary receipts. Depositary receipts, or non-U.S.-sourced revenues, with the change in the seasonality, and the significant swing in it. And you saw the decline in non-U.S.-sourced revenues. So we think when you normalize all that, there might have been a percent or so decline, but not much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perfect. And then really quickly, just wondering if we can dig in a little bit more in terms of fee waivers. And one of the discussions that was brought up earlier is it was potential offsets to fee waivers as you're thinking about product structure in the future. Can you go into a little bit more detail about what some of those product structures are, and how enthusiastic you are for being able to recapture those fee waivers, absent any macro movement in the rates?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Let me start on the servicing side, and then, Curtis, maybe you can think about it a little bit on the investment management. The servicing side, we provide a lot of administrative services for clients to sweep their cash through us, either onto our balance sheet, into various liquidity options, or various money market funds. And so we may have to find a different way to structure those administrative services that we provide that have traditionally come through distribution fees. So that's one of the things we're working on. Pershing's a great example where they're trying to take some initiatives on their platforms, but it is a bit of a conundrum because the yields on the investments are so low. How much can you keep hitting the client for no return? So it is something we're looking at. We're trying to find structural ways and other ways to deal with it. And on investment management, Curtis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, I would say &#x2013; listen, clients &#x2013; there are an array of clients that use money market funds for various reason. Generally, they want to have tremendous liquidity and get the best yield that they can. If the rules actually change on making a floating-rate NAV or with capital buffers make it a difficult product, we think that clients are going to look for alternatives. And we've had conversations with them about everything from ultra-short duration fixed-income products that would be the highest-quality assets and try and maintain as much liquidity as possible. Floating-rate funds obviously are potentially interesting to them, because of the more stable net asset values that could be had, but not necessarily completely fixed as they are today. And clients, again, depending on how they use them &#x2013; how they use money market funds &#x2013; have different levels of interest in each of them.</p>
          <p>But we think that if the changes do occur and everyone has to step back and think about what they're really going to do in a new environment, that people will have to shift to these products. And of course, Todd talked about our deposits. Banks are clearly going to see some of the flows go to deposits, and we think we've seen some of that. So it's good to have the ability to offer both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, if I could, maybe Brian Shea could comment a little bit about what Pershing's trying to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would just build on Curtis' comments, that the retail investors are starting to shift some of their cash management sweep to FDIC-insured bank deposit sweeps, and we have a growing array of cash management sweep vehicles from traditional money market funds to FDIC-insured bank deposit sweeps. And we have a growing array of cash management sweep options, including FDIC options. So while we had cash management growth on our platform of about 9% to 10% year over year, we had 34% growth in FDIC-insured sweep, which is where customers &#x2013; investors &#x2013; are seeking slightly higher yields and the protection of FDIC as well. So I think what we're working on is trying to create more capacity, not only internally but with other banks, and working with Promontory Financial and others to get that accomplished. Hopefully, we'll see more growth in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Betsy Graseck with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Betsy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to ask how client flows and activity have been more recently. I know you gave the information for the full quarter, but in the middle of December we had <mark type="ph" /> El Tiro (54:00) in Europe, and first couple of weeks of this year &#x2013; I know it's only two and a half weeks in. But just wanted to get a sense, too, of how client activity inflows have been kind of latter half of 4Q and into the beginning of this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, certainly the last part of the fourth quarter was very slow. It started off the year a bit slow as well. We're hopeful that once we get through earnings season and investors start realizing they have to put money to work for yields, we'll see normal client activity. But we did start off the year a bit slow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And that's consistent across geographies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our final question today is from Gerard Cassidy with RBC Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Gerard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A question, Todd, on the sale of the sub-investment-grade securities. What is the total now of the old <mark type="ph" /> grand third trusts (55:05) in sub-investment grade, about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a little over $3 billion &#x2013; it's right about $3 billion, is the book value that we have on them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there any expectation for sales this year of any of those securities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't feel the urgent need to sell any of them. If we see that there is a decent bid or we don't like the particular risk profile of any security, we've offered it, and if gets taken, that's fine. If it doesn't, we'll live with it, is pretty much the position that we've taken. We've actually seen an improved bid in the &#x2013; so far in the month of January. But at this point, we really haven't done anything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You mentioned that one of the real positives to the net interest margin expanding would be if the deposits started to shrink. Is there any evidence that your customers are taking deposits off the balance sheet, or just the opposite, are they continuing to put them on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there's &#x2013; I would say that the &#x2013; what I had mentioned, Gerard, there are some spikes that we see from some individual clients that might leave a significant amount of cash because of some kind of a transaction or something that they were doing. So that tends to &#x2013; that has fallen off. The underlying, what I'd call the core component of it, has been pretty stable, just showing modest growth over the last three quarters. We saw the big spike back in June, and then it's been growing modestly thereafter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then when we look at your loans outstanding, you had a nice increase in the margin loans, I believe, in the quarter. Was that existing customers taking on more loans, or new customers? Where did the good growth come in that area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Brian Shea. It's primarily driven by growth in the prime brokerage business, Pershing's Prime Services group, and also somewhat by our traditional &#x2013; the growth of our broker-dealer business. But I would say &#x2013; I'd give a little more credit to the prime group as we're growing momentum in that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And thank you very much, everyone, for dialing in on a busy day, and if you have other questions, please follow up with Andy Clark or the rest of our Investor Relations team. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. If there are any additional questions or comments, you may contact Mr. Andy Clark at 212-635-1803. Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. This concludes today's conference call. Thank you for participating.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>