<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1526920" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-01-16</date>
    <companies>
      <company>77</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Andy Clark</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman, President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Gerald L. Hassell</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice Chairman &amp; Chief Financial Officer">Thomas P. Gibbons</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Howard H. Chen</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice Chairman &amp; CEO-Investment Management">Curtis Y. Arledge</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="President-Investment Services">Brian Thomas Shea</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Betsy L. Graseck</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Securities International, Inc.">Glenn Schorr</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice Chairman-Management Board">Timothy Francis Keaney</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co. LLC">Luke Montgomery</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">Ken M. Usdin</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep" affiliation="President">Karen B. Peetz</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Alexander Blostein</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Brian B. Bedell</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Inc. (Broker)">Josh D. Levin</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Fourth Quarter 2012 Earnings Conference Call posted by BNY Mellon. At this time all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later we will conduct a question-and-answer session. Please note that this conference call webcast will be recorded and will consist of copyrighted material. You may not record or rebroadcast these materials without BNY Mellon's consent.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Mr. Andy Clark. Mr. Clark, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Wendy, and welcome, everyone. With us today are Gerald Hassell, our Chairman and CEO; Todd Gibbons, our CFO; as well as our Executive Management team.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, let me remind you that our remarks today may include forward-looking statements. Actual results may differ materially from those indicated or implied by the forward-looking statements as a result of various factors. These factors include those identified in the cautionary statement on page 13 of the press release and those identified in our documents filed with the SEC that are available on our website, bnymellon.com. Forward-looking statements in this call speak only as of today, January 16, 2013, and we will not update forward-looking statements. Our press release and earnings review are available on our website, and we will be using the earnings review to discuss our results today.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to turn the call over to Gerald. Gerald?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Andy, and good morning, everyone. As you saw from our release, for the fourth quarter we generated net income of $622 million and earnings per share of $0.53. Just as a reminder, we reported $0.42 per share in the fourth quarter of last year, which included restructuring charges related to our operational excellence initiatives of $0.06 per share.</p>
          <p>Now I'm pleased to report strong growth in a number of our businesses. Investment management had another excellent quarter, benefiting from the 13th consecutive quarter of long-term inflows and higher market values. We've had $56 billion in net long-term flows over the last 12 months, which included $14 billion during the quarter. Our success in attracting new assets helped drive assets under management to a record level of $1.4 trillion.</p>
          <p>In investment services, asset servicing, clearing and treasury services all saw nice growth in fee income as well. Now that being said, the market environment continues to be challenging to some of our revenue streams as volumes, volatility, interest rates and tepid capital markets all continue to trend below normalized levels.</p>
          <p>These factors resulted in a decline in revenues in our lower variable costs businesses such as depositary receipts, foreign exchange and net interest income. And we were able to offset the decline in these revenues with growth in investment management and other investment services businesses but the growth occurred in those areas than had higher variable costs. So the shift in the revenue mix was the principal cause of the growth in expenses year-over-year and sequentially above the level that you might have expected.</p>
          <p>In addition, we acquired the remaining 50% interest in the WestLB Asset Management joint venture, which we renamed Meriten; that brought with it a higher expense base. And finally, we had some seasonally higher expenses in the fourth quarter and we are investing in our brand, businesses and strategic initiatives to help our clients succeed in a very difficult market.</p>
          <p>Now we have a relentless focus on creating organic growth, continuing to drive some of the opportunities we've outlined for you in the past. Some examples: accelerating our asset management growth strategies, particularly in Asia and the retail space; capturing opportunities through our Global Collateral Services business; leveraging our Pershing platform and distribution capability; and building out global markets to capture more order flow.</p>
          <p>And we recently received approval to launch our new issuer central securities depositary based in Belgium, which will enhance our offering for investment services and collateral management for clients in Europe. All these initiatives will help drive our long-term growth but do in fact require investments today that are showing up in our expense base. So we are not standing still waiting for the markets to improve and we are in fact taking actions to strengthen our revenue streams.</p>
          <p>In that regard, we announced several executive appointments to accelerate our progress. Karen Peetz was named President of the company and she will focus on one of the three key pillars of our firm: our clients and employees. So client management, the regions, innovation, collaboration, employee training and development and some of our key growth initiatives will come under Karen.</p>
          <p>The second pillar is investment services and Tim Keaney is now CEO of all of our investment services businesses and this brings together all of our capabilities under one manager, which will improve collaboration and enhance our ability to offer integrated solutions.</p>
          <p>Brian Shea is now President of investment services and very importantly, head of operations and technology for the company. These businesses are technology and operations intensive and we want those attributes closer to the clients and part of the fabric of any business decision.</p>
          <p>I also firmly believe and we have the opportunity to simplify our operating model and get better operational efficiencies across our businesses beyond the operational excellence initiatives we are currently tracking. That is one of Brian's challenges and I know he's up for it.</p>
          <p>And finally, the third pillar of our firm is investment management, which Curtis Arledge continues to run. We have built some very nice revenue momentum here and the team is executing on our important growth opportunities. So we have a broad, deep leadership team, we are sharpening our client focus, better collaborating across our businesses and driving further productivity gains in our operating platforms, all while maintaining a strong capital position and returning capital to shareholders.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it over to Todd to go through the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Gerald, and good morning, everyone. My comments will follow the quarterly earnings review and we start on page 2.</p>
          <p>Reported earnings per share were $0.53 this quarter. Our results included a $0.03 benefit related to a credit to the loan loss provision where we've seen some progress or continued progress in reducing the risk to the portfolio. It's really paying dividends.</p>
          <p>We did have a lower tax rate and some securities gains but in the end, we don't think that they were really unusual and I'll talk about that in some detail in a minute. And there were also some seasonally higher expenses not indicative of our core underlying run rate. If you take all those items into account, we see this is about $0.50 quarter. This compares with $0.42 in the year ago quarter which as Gerald mentioned included the negative impact of about $0.06 per share related to restructuring charges.</p>
          <p>Looking at the numbers on a year-over-year basis, total revenue was $3.6 billion, that's up 2% while fee and other revenue was up 3%. Investment management fees were up strongly and we had nice fee growth in asset servicing, clearing and treasury services and those were partially offset by declines in FX revenue and NIR as well as softness in issuer services.</p>
          <p>While the current low interest rate environment continues to negatively impact net interest revenue, it has driven a significant improvement in the value of the investment securities portfolio and that's given us the opportunity to realize some gains there.</p>
          <p>Expenses were up 7%, but if you look at on a core basis &#x2013; that is on a core basis, which excludes amortization of intangible assets and litigation and restructuring charges and some direct expenses related to Shareowner Services. As Gerald had mentioned earlier, the biggest factor in the increase was the change in the revenue mix and I'll give you some color on that in a moment.</p>
          <p>Turning to page 4, where we call out some business metrics that will help explain our underlying performance. You can see that AUM of $1.4 trillion was up 10% year-over-year and up 2% sequentially resulting from higher market values and net inflows.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we had net long-term inflows of $14 billion and short-term outflows of $6 billion. It was our 13th consecutive quarter of positive long-term inflows with long-term flows of $56 billion over the last 12 months.</p>
          <p>Assets under custody and administration were up 9% year-over-year to $26.7 trillion. Those were driven by higher market values and net new business. Linked quarter AUC was up slightly. As you may see here AUC in our prior periods was down about 4% to 5% as we restated to reflect the correction of a double account of legacy Mellon assets. The restatement had no impact to our growth rate, our revenues or our earnings.</p>
          <p>A number of key metrics showed growth on a year-over-year basis. All clearing metrics improved, margin loans were up nicely and collateral management GAAP balances continue to grow at a robust rate, a trend that our global collateral services group is positioned to capitalize on.</p>
          <p>Looking at fees on page 6, asset servicing fees were up 7% year-over-year and flat sequentially. The year-over-year increase primarily reflects net new business, higher market values and higher collateral management revenue. Sequentially, those positives were partially offset by a decline in securities lending revenue and that was driven by a slightly lower balances as well as lower spreads.</p>
          <p>We had $190 billion in new AUC wins for a total of $1.5 trillion in AUC wins over the last 12 months. If you look at issuer services fees excluding the Shareowner Services business, which we sold at the end of last year, they were down 12% year-over-year and 31% sequentially. The year-over-year decrease primarily resulted from lower DR revenue as volumes are down quite a bit this year, also lower corporate trust fees resulting from that continued net runoff of structured debt securitizations that we've mentioned previously.</p>
          <p>The sequential decrease primarily resulted from the $107 million decrease in DR revenues that we'd indicated, which was largely seasonal. As you saw last quarter, this is a relatively high fixed cost business, so a gain or loss of revenue doesn't have much in the way of expenses associated with it.</p>
          <p>Clearing fees were up 6% year-over-year and 2% sequentially. Both increases primarily reflect higher mutual fund fees driven by increases in positions and balances, higher cash management balances and also an increase in DARTS. So all in all, not a bad performance considering the weaker volumes we're seeing on the exchanges. The year-over-year increase also reflects the impact of higher clearance revenue.</p>
          <p>Investment management and performance fees were up 17% year-over-year and 9% sequentially. Both increases were impacted by the Meriten acquisition. If you exclude Meriten, investment management and performance fees were up 15% year-over-year and those were driven by higher market values, net new business and slightly lower fee waivers.</p>
          <p>In FX and other trading, revenue was down 39% year-over-year and 24% sequentially. If you look at the components, FX revenue of $106 million was down 42% year-over-year and 12% sequentially. Both decreases reflect a sharp decline in market volatility and that's consistent with the index that we show you on page 5. That's the JPMorgan G7 Volatility Index. We also saw in the period a modest decline in volumes.</p>
          <p>Other trading revenue was $33 million, and that compares with $45 million in the year-ago quarter and $61 million in the prior quarter. Both comparisons reflect lower fixed-income trading revenues driven by lower interest rate trading.</p>
          <p>Investment and other income totaled $116 million in the quarter compared with $146 million in the year-ago quarter and $124 million in the third quarter. The year-over-year decrease primarily reflects the pre-tax gain on the sale of Shareowner Services, while the sequential decrease reflects lower seed capital gains and equity investment revenue.</p>
          <p>Turning to page 8 of the earnings review, NIR was down $55 million versus the year-ago quarter and $24 million sequentially. The year-over-year decrease was principally driven by the elimination of interest on ECB deposits. We had lower accretion and there were lower yields on the reinvestment of securities. Partially, that was offset by higher interest-earning assets as we saw a significant increase in deposit levels.</p>
          <p>The sequential decrease in NIR had all of the above, and in addition, it was impacted by the decline in LIBOR after the Fed announced QE3. We have quite a few floating-rate assets that are linked to LIBOR, and three-month LIBOR fell about 10 basis points on average for the quarter.</p>
          <p>The net interest margin was 109 basis points compared with 127 basis points in the year-ago quarter and about 1.2% in the prior quarter. During the quarter, the margin was negatively impacted by the sharp rise in deposits that I mentioned, as that cash was primarily left at the Fed where it earned only 25 basis points. Overall, the increase in deposits, we estimate reduced the margin by approximately 6 basis points sequentially and about 8 basis points on a year-over-year basis.</p>
          <p>Today we have a $2.4 billion unrealized gain in the investment securities portfolio, and we have sold, and we would expect to continue to sell in this environment, securities to rebalance the portfolio and manage our duration risk. As such, the gains realized on these sales should be considered along with net interest revenue in evaluating our overall results. In the fourth quarter, combined NIR and securities gains totaled $775 million. That compares with $770 million in the year-ago quarter &#x2013; excuse me, $777 million in the year-ago quarter and $771 million in the linked quarter.</p>
          <p>Now turning to page 9, you can see that total non-interest expense ex amortization of intangible assets, M&amp;I, litigation and restructuring charges, and also the direct expenses with Shareowner Services, were up 7% year-over-year and 4% sequentially. Both increases were primarily driven by the revenue mix, as the low-rate environment and tepid capital markets activity drove a decline in our fixed-cost businesses.</p>
          <p>For example, DR revenue was down $107 million, FX and other trading revenue declined $43 million, and NIR was down $24 million sequentially. All of these have very little variable costs associated with them, unlike the revenue that replaced them in investment management, asset servicing, clearing, and treasury services. Expenses over both periods also reflect higher software and business development expenses, as well as the operating expenses associated with the Meriten acquisition.</p>
          <p>M&amp;I, litigation and restructuring line item of our P&amp;L included expenses related to our operational excellence initiatives, just as it did in the year-ago quarter. In the fourth quarter of 2012, the restructuring component also included severance expense and a lease restructuring charge, and these were offset by the gain on the sale of a property. The net restructuring charge totaled less than $1 million for the fourth quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>For the full year, total expense was up about $220 million and that &#x2013; in terms of that increase, M&amp;I, litigation and restructuring offset the reduction that was related to the sale of Shareowner Services last year. The operational excellence initiatives ended up offsetting the headwinds in compensation and other operating expenses that we have spoken about in the past. As a result, the overall increase in expenses was largely driven by the impact of the revenue mix that I just described.</p>
          <p>Turning to page 10, you can see the progress of our operational excellence initiatives, which are improving our efficiency, helping to offset Meriten &#x2013; and benefit increases, and positioning us for an improved operating environment. You'll see that the full year, we exceeded our target on a gross savings basis, with about $397 million versus the target of $360 million to $390 million. For 2012, the incremental program cost total is $88 million, resulting in net savings of $309 million versus to $240 million to $260 million target.</p>
          <p>As you can see, our program cost were largely the driver for this, as they came in lower than expected and the reason for that is the significant portion of the lease restructuring and severance expenses were allocated to the restructuring charges that I just mentioned.</p>
          <p>As you can see on page 11 our capital ratio strengthened. Our estimated Basel III Tier 1 common equity ratio was 9.8% at quarter end that compares to 9.30% at the end of the third quarter. This increase was chiefly attributable to lower risk-weighted assets as well as some earnings retention.</p>
          <p>During the year, we repurchased nearly 50 million common shares for $1.1 billion so we're executing on our 2012 CCAR plan and our strong capital position provides us with the flexibility to continue to return capital to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Moving onto our loan book on page 13, you can see that the provision for credit losses was a credit this quarter of $61 million. This compares to a provision of $23 million in the year-ago quarter. The credit was largely driven by a reduction in the allowance for credit losses related to the residential loan portfolio, which has experienced better performance when you compare it to the industry's historical losses.</p>
          <p>During the quarter we began using our actual loan loss experience rather than the industry data in order to get a better estimate for the allowance for credit losses and hence the release.</p>
          <p>The effective tax rate was 24.3%, which primarily reflects the benefit associated with the reorganization of certain foreign operations. But the good news here is the lower tax rate should continue as we benefit from increased investment tax credits against a lower earnings stream and we also have a larger tax-exempt municipal bond portfolio.</p>
          <p>Before I provide some updates for your models, I wanted to give you another look at how the revenue mix is impacting our expenses. So if you turn to Page 16 in the earnings review where we break out investment services fees as a percentage of non-interest expense, I can walk you through this impact.</p>
          <p>The reported ratio was 90% for both the fourth quarter of 2012 and as well as for 2011. But if you recall from our revenue commentary, depository receipt fees are down year-over-year due to lower volumes. This decline in revenue only results in a minimal reduction in expenses, so if you adjust for the year-over-year impact of DRs, the fourth quarter 2012 ratio would have been in the 92% range rather than 90%, and that demonstrates that we are making some progress in our operational excellence initiatives particularly in asset services.</p>
          <p>Now a few points to factor into your thinking about the current quarter; we don't &#x2013; and looking forward, we don't see &#x2013; foresee a significant improvement in interest rates and FX volatility in the near term. In terms of NIR and securities gains, we expect them to remain flat and that's if we're able to execute on our loan growth related to our global securities services businesses. Operational excellence initiatives should be on plan. The quarterly provision should be around zero. Preferred dividends will be about $0.01 a quarter and the effective tax rate should come in a bit lower than we'd previously guided, say about 25% or so.</p>
          <p>During the quarter and all of 2013, we'll be focused on four main activities: creating organic growth, executing on our operational excellence initiatives, continuing to maintain our strong balance sheet and strengthening our capital position, and returning some of that capital to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it back to Gerald.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Todd. And, Wendy, I think we can open it up to questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question today is from Howard Chen with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Gerald. Hi, Todd.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Howard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just throughout the commentary you spoke a lot about the fourth quarter environment being one of which you had low client activity and low volatility. Just curious, given we had a couple idiosyncratic events like the U.S. election and the fiscal cliff and we're into 2013 now, have you seen any meaningful changes across the business or early signs of re-risking, whether it's custodial and servicing side of the business or things like frictional deposits rolling off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Interesting question, Howard. What we did see towards the end of the year just as we saw in August of 2011 was with the fiscal cliff looming, we saw a fairly significant increase in our deposits on our balance sheet. And so we saw a run up $20 billion, $30 billion in our deposits. Most of that has already moved back off the balance sheet, some of which has moved into traditional money market funds, and some of which appears to be going into investments.</p>
          <p>I think we're going to be facing in some ways a bit of &#x2013; a number of cliffs. I think the debt ceiling limit is going to put another potential concern in the eyes of investors. Hopefully we'll get through that but we are seeing people trying to put some money to work but still there's an enormous amount of cash sitting on the sidelines waiting for better certainty and clarity. I think some of the investment management flows which maybe I can ask Curtis to speak to. He's seeing some activity pick up there; it's showing up in some of our numbers. So maybe, Curtis, you want to just touch upon that a little bit too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, absolutely. I mean there's been a lot discussed in the media about the flows that have been into equity funds in the first part of this year and we have seen that and then some. I think at the end of 2012 clients broadly were waiting to see kind of how the fiscal cliff played out and obviously with debt ceiling in sequester and budget and other things still in front of us, there still are some uncertainties. But I think as each uncertainty gets removed, we definitely see a reason to not act fall away and the flows that we've seen and the conversation that we're having would lead us to believe that investors, and when I say investors, I mean everything from retail, mutual fund investors to some of the world's largest sovereign wealth funds are absolutely looking at this as an environment to begin to put money back to work. Again, I think uncertainty has dampened people's activity in terms of making a decision to invest and as we get past each of these events, we've seen people absolutely take action. And I know other parts of our company see flows as well.</p>
          <p>Brian, I don't know if you...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Brian, maybe you want to talk about what you see on the Pershing platform on the retail side particularly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we've only had a couple of weeks of data to monitor but so far this year there's a significant shift, both an increase in net inflows into mutual funds on the platform and a big shift from what was in 2012 primarily fixed income oriented funds to more of a balance and so you're seeing a big growth in equity mutual fund inflows at least for the first couple of weeks. So hard to tell if that's a long-term trend yet but definitely a positive sign.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, everyone. That's really helpful. And then, Todd, you provided some near-term outlook for spread revenues. Just putting aside that outside deposit movement that we just spoke about for a minute, can you just discuss the reinvestment environment for the securities book as you see it? I mean we're clearly seeing some movement on the longer end of the curve but not a lot on the shorter end where I think in my opinion historically has mattered more for you guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think that's a good observation, Howard. The shorter end of the curve is more important at this point because the duration of our liabilities is more &#x2013; better matched there. When you look through the course of the year or even a quarter, the decline that we've seen in the net interest margin is a reflection of two things. One is spreads and the other is balances and it's about 50-50. And so we don't see the spread environment in the short end improving. In fact, we've pretty much gone through the re-pricing as you would've expected with the resets and the lower LIBOR rates. So it's a headwind and we expect more of the same as we had indicated. We're not expecting a better environment in 2013. We're expecting more of the same. We got a couple of pretty tough punches in 2012 when the ECB eliminated credit on excess reserves as well as QE3 which dragged down mortgages as well as some of the short end of the curve. So hopefully we won't see those kind of events again in 2013, but we don't expect a lot of improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fantastic. Thanks. And the final one for me just on capital return, Todd, you mentioned the capital ratios continuing to grow and just continuing to plug along on the buyback but on the near-term in the fourth quarter did the buyback slow down due to timing of year or potentially the Meriten acquisition or something else? And then do you have any more evolved thoughts on CCAR in 2013 as you enter the year with really strong Basel I and Basel III ratios? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, at the end of 2012 as Gerald had mentioned we saw a pretty sharp spike in our balances and most of that spike has since whittled away. But when we saw that we actually saw a little bit of &#x2013; what could have been a little bit of pressure on our leverage ratio and we thought it was in our interest to hold back on about $100 million or so of buybacks that we probably could've done to make sure that we had a strong leverage ratio and a strong CCAR that we could present for 2013. So we didn't want it to interfere at all with our 2013 efforts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks so much for taking the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Howard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Howard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Betsy Graseck with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you, and good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Betsy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions. One on the expense ratio, Todd, you mentioned that the expenses reflect the revenue profile that you have right now. Should I take that to mean that we shouldn't anticipate a higher expense ratio going forward until we see some rate hikes? Or that there's going to be another round of efforts on trying to lower the expense ratio or is this about as low as it can go?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No, I think mix will be key to it, Betsy. In the fourth quarter it was particularly soft for DRs. So if you just imagine $100 million with very little variable expense from quarter to quarter, so it's going to be &#x2013; it's going to be the revenue mix and DRs was the noisiest component of that revenue mix. So we'd expect it to improve a little bit as the revenue mix gets more normal and just some of the seasonal impacts. So I think, in your model you'll have to average that out a little bit better. We probably should have given you a little clearer guidance on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You are running ahead of your expense programs in terms of targeted improvement in the expenses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we're slightly ahead of where we would have expected to be. The costs are slightly less to get there and the reason for that largely is because we allocated a lot of those costs in a restructuring charge against a gain that we took on the sale of a property.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. And then from here, how should we think about the benefit of the program on earnings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's going to be consistent with what we have indicated in the past. Effectively, what the operational expense initiatives are doing for us is they're offsetting some of the growth related to pension, related to other benefits expenses, related to merit increases and some slight inflation of our other operating expenses. So those are matching themselves off.</p>
          <p>So in order to generate operating leverage, it's pretty hard if we don't show a little bit of growth outside of that to generate a whole lot of operating leverage. If we can generate 2% or 3% or 4% of revenue growth, then we can see some operating leverage but again, we want you to be mindful of the revenue mix in that. So, if NIR is flat and FX is flat and we're seeing in the lower margin business the revenue growth, then you're going to &#x2013; then the operating leverage is going to be more challenging.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then second question is on the capital ratio and you mentioned that part of the reason for the improvement this quarter was the lower RWA. Could you describe what's backing that? And I guess the follow-up on that is are you as able to pay out against lower RWAs as you are against earnings accreted improvements in the capital ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, a couple of questions there. The reason for the little improvement in the Basel III Tier 1 common ratio, the numerator accounted for about 10 basis points as we did see about $150 million or a 10 basis point increase in the capital and that's pretty consistent with what we would expect to retain in a quarter, in a normal quarter. The denominator, we'd expect to get some benefit as we see some runoff typically in some of the higher weighted risk-weighted assets. This quarter, for the same reason that we got some improvement on the reserve, we got some improvement &#x2013; using the similar models, we got some improvement on the risk-weighted assets as our historical data against a lot of retail and also some commercial ones have improved dramatically. So as we've improved the quality of our portfolio, it's reflected in our risk weights and we've readdressed those risk weights in the quarter, so we picked up some of the benefit of that. So that was a little bit more but the 40 basis points in the denominator is probably heavy by about 20 basis points to 25 basis points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just thinking on the payout ratio, we hear that sustainable earning is obviously very critical for payout ratios and I'm just trying to understand, do you think that the improvement in the capital ratio that you got this quarter feeds into that much higher of an ability to do the payouts in 2013? Or should we really be looking at what the earnings generation is driving in terms of improvement in the capital ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me make a couple of comments and then Gerald will probably want to make a comment or two. Where the CCAR looks to fit things under normal and also under stress, and as we've indicated in the past, we tend to do pretty well because we've got some &#x2013; we've got really two things going for us. One is we don't rely on a lot of risky assets in order to generate our revenues, and the other thing is the mix of our businesses is a little less equity intensive so that a steep drop in the equity markets has a little less impact to us. So as a result, we can kind of continue to generate even through a pretty ugly environment like the ones that we've gone through for us. So it's really based on &#x2013; the payouts will be based on where we see our performance and what we see as being prudent, given where our capital ratios are. But certainly, it puts us in a position with stronger capital ratios than we would have expected at this point of the year to do a little better. Gerald?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, maybe I can add on to that a little bit. I think we're quite pleased with that 9.8% Basel III Tier 1 common ratio. I think it gives us an increased flexibility to consider capital actions. I would generally say that a dividend payout ratio in the 25% to 30% is probably something for all of us to think about. And a total payout ratio, last year we guided you to about the 65% range. I think we'd have the flexibility to see that north of that 65%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Betsy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Glenn Schorr with Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Glenn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello there. A quickie, as I think this has been asked in the past but just always want a little more color. If you look at assets under management, they are up nicely 10% year-on-year and the fees associated up 15% ex acquisitions, that's great and normal. Assets under custody up 9% year-on-year. The servicing fees are flattish. You gave some pieces to that. But I guess the question is, is there a reason why that over longer periods of time wouldn't have the same rational relationship? Is something changing in the mix that we shouldn't expect fees and assets to grow in line with each other?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think some of that, Glenn, has to do with the fact that corporate trusts and DRs are included in the investment services revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so I think our asset servicing fees have in fact been growing, but the corporate trust and DRs have been declining, particularly in this quarter. DR is more seasonal than structural, and corporate trusts, we've just seen a runoff in the structured products, which are impacting the overall revenues. Asset servicing fees have been growing, maybe not totally in line with the assets under custody, but maybe I'll ask Tim to comment specifically on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure. Glenn, it's Tim. Year-over-year, just a reminder, the asset servicing fees grew at 7% versus AUC of 9%, and I think you see a couple of things. I think you see a little bit of a mix shift. I think some of it is timing. I would certainly say that more of our new business converted towards the back end of the year. And then frankly, a little bit of it is lost business by maintaining our strong pricing discipline. So hopefully that answers your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Definitely. I appreciate all of that. Maybe a quickie on not the biggest number, just more curious if you ex FX, if you look at fixed income trading, it's had big swing up last quarter and down 46% this quarter. The explanation was lower interest rate trading revs. I'm just curious, we see &#x2013; if we look at the big broker-dealers we're looking at like 15% swings, not a 46% swing, so just maybe a little explanation on what you are trading for whom on a quarterly basis as you grow out the global markets business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. There are really two activities there outside of &#x2013; or two key activities outside of FX in the other trading category. One of them is general fixed income trading where we do make markets for our clients, so we saw that a little softer. And the thing that's more episodic is really around some interest rate trading, so we saw &#x2013; interest rate derivative trading, so we saw a fair number of interest rate derivative trading activity in the third quarter that we didn't see replicate itself in the fourth quarter. The nature of that business, it is for us, it's on such a small number, Glenn, that a little change is a pretty significant impact, percentage-wise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, now I hear you, I hear you. Just more curious than anything else. Last one on &#x2013; a lot of talk about the collateral management opportunity, I know you are investing in it. We've seen some of the market participants not ready for central clearing so maybe a question on timing, but also if you can even size the opportunity of and where you're at in the investment cycle for that opportunity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Glenn, we continue to build out the capabilities. We've seen very good interest from the buy side. Traditionally, our collateral management has been supporting the dealer community, and we've seen some nice growth in our tri-party collateral balances. I think we produced a number for you. We are experiencing some fee growth in the area already. We're also seeing some net interest income growth in that area as we help optimize and transform some of the collateral for the dealer community in particular.</p>
          <p>So we're starting to see some good further traction in this space. Part of the CSD announcement that we made is to support collateral services in Europe into the future so we're excited about that. I know you all are anxious to see more transparency and information around this and later in the year I think we'll be able to put together some better numbers and direction for you. But we feel good about our progress and continue to see very good interest in it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Luke Montgomery with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thanks for taking my call. I was intrigued by your announcement last week that you are going to start the central security depository in Europe. You just mentioned it. I am wondering if you might comment on the cost of that and really the longer-term strategic possibilities? And then also, do you think that's an opportunity that's unique to BNY Mellon because you have the corporate issuer client base or can it be replicated by your global facility and peers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great question. I love that question. So Tim, it's in your area. I'll ask you to address it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Luke, it's a bright spot for us. You know the regulations are changing. Both Dodd-Frank and EMEA are coming up on us very quickly. So that's driving people to make decisions partly around the collateral question that was just asked to Gerald. But more importantly there's a number of CSDs in Europe. We're the only one that provides full value chain of services, particularly the notary function, so the things that happen before secondary trading. And we think that's a unique differentiator for us.</p>
          <p>We started to do this initially to defend our issuer services business in Europe, but as the bond business and issuer services business grows, we think this could become a needle mover for us. So I would say watch this space, but you correctly connect the CSD strategy to collateral because in a post Target-2 securities environment, T2S should go into effect in June of 2015, you have to be a CSD to play at central bank money collateral. So that's the other reason why we did this, which has a much more strategic aspect to it and connects our collateral ambitions here in the U.S. to our collateral ambitions in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, and then just could you quickly come back to whether you think that's a unique opportunity to you and could State Street do it, for example?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say relative to our traditional trust bank competitors, I don't think I see anybody that can offer the level of services that we have. The landscape is changing in terms of the current players, like Euroclear and Clearstream, but again, I would say they're missing one important part of the value chain. But again, just think of this in terms of impact in 2013 as being somewhat modest and building over the next, I would say, two years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. That's helpful. And then on the collateral management, clearly people are talking a lot about the revenue opportunity, but I think a lot less so about what this means to risk and the interconnectedness of the financial system. And I think in one sense this is just repo, but I'm wondering whether the types of collateral transformation I hear you say that you're going to engage in, say like lending out treasuries for corporate bonds, whether we should be concerned about the contingent liquidity risk you and others are going to be taking on to facilitate those types of activities for your clients?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. No, it's a very good question. It's something we're very, very mindful of. We obviously need to continue to enhance our risk management capabilities in this space and ability to liquidate collateral if we had to. But don't think of all of the transformation occurring on our balance sheet. Some of our role is to be an intermediary between parties where we act as the agent. So in some cases, we'll use our clients' treasuries or our treasuries in that transformation process; in other cases, we'll simply be the agent between the parties.</p>
          <p>So we don't always have to be the lender. Obviously, there's a lot of value in that, but you're correct in saying there's risk associated with it and we have to be mindful of that risk and manage it very, very well. And so we are enhancing and building out our capabilities in that space to be able to handle it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Luke, if I can add something to that. I mean, we're sitting on $90 billion, or up to $90 billion in central bank deposits. If we can put a little bit of that to work through relatively short-term secured floating rate loans that effectively can convert a corporate bond to cash that can then be posted at a central clearer, that's a great trade and it comes with very little &#x2013; we certainly have liquidity to handle it and it comes with very, very little incremental risk and some incremental income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just a follow-up on that one final question. Do you envision the bulk of your activities to be as the agent administrator or as principal? Like which of the two of those is the bigger revenue opportunity for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the immediate quick hit is net interest income shows up with virtually no expense and therefore, bottom-line income, so you're going to see the more quick revenue hit in that space. But longer-term, we want to have it be more in an agent position where we get continuous repeatable fees. And that's what we expect out of this and so it's creating that neural network as we refer to it and have all the parties use us as agent rather than acting as principal and using our balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks for taking all my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Ken Usdin with Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, guys. Just to follow-up on the NII and securities gains topic, Todd, I heard your comments about hoping to keep that combination of the two flat. But can you talk a little bit more about how risk is changing within it? And you obviously have a lot of unrealized gains left, but at some point, you're going to sacrifice net interest income for gains and that could run out. So I just want to understand how long you can see the visibility out on keeping those two kind of working together? Because at some point you may not be able to keep the gains going in lieu of protecting your NII.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, I look forward to that date because it probably implies a little higher interest rates, Ken. But I think the simple way to think about this is we try to maintain a portfolio of about two years in duration, relatively very low credit risk as you can see from looking at it. So each quarter a quarter burns through, and as we take &#x2013; as some of those securities come down and they get very rich because there's strong interest on the short &#x2013; on the relatively short end of the curve for those assets, we'll sell some of the richer securities and then we'll reinvest back out on the curve. That gives up &#x2013; it can give up a little bit of NII on a go-forward basis, but it's not too much, and that's why &#x2013; and it maintains the portfolio balanced where we want it. And that's why, as we started to look more and more at this, it's exactly what's been going on and we wanted to make sure investors see that and that we would intend to do that as long as interest rate environment stays where it is. If the rate environment changes, so if we see a rise in rates, there'd probably be a little of extension duration, there would be no need for that type of activity, but we would be making up for it in our NIR.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just a cleanup one. Can you tell us what the accretion portion was this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't recall off the top of my head. It was probably around $60 million. It tends to come in about $5 million or so a quarter as we've indicated in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay. And then, on a separate topic, good trajectory on custody, but what's getting harder to understand within that asset servicing line is how the custody fees are going. Following on Glenn's question, this quarter also looked like you had about the slowest win rate of new custody wins, so I was wondering if you could just kind of talk us through what's happening just on core custody revenues, because you have to ex out collateral management, ex out broker-dealer services, ex out securities lending, and we don't see any of that. And then also, if you just could touch on like is anything changing with regards to the speed of new wins on the core custody side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim, why don't you take that one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure. I'll take that. First, let me take them in kind of reverse order. Don't be overly concerned about that new business win rate because less of the business is geared to AUC and that's something we need to think about. I've gone back and looked at over the last six quarters in terms of win and pipeline. It's been pretty consistent. And the mix in the ratio between AUC going up 9% year-on-year and fees going up 7% I talked a little bit about earlier. I wouldn't be overly concerned about that although the mix is changing a bit and so we are doing more of middle office outsourcing and transfer agency and things. But there's also some good news in there. You're also seeing the re-pricing that we've been implementing now for some time has some traction. So I wouldn't say &#x2013; I'd also just say that business continues to be very competitive, especially in the large end of the market. So no, I can't tell you there's been any significant shift there, Ken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The assets under custody wins from quarter to quarter are pretty lumpy. If you get some big ones in one quarter, you won't necessarily see them in the next quarter, so that's not a steady state. But we are seeing a steady-state in terms of the increased interest in mid-office and derivatives servicing and a variety of other things, some of which require &#x2013; that are slow to ramp up on the revenue side, even with the announcements that we make, and over time that we expect those revenues to come in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, and then my third question, last question, is just on issuer services. You guys had very much given us an understanding of the seasonal &#x2013; the seasonal decline that we would expect to see in DRs and then also the ongoing challenges on the structured finance runoff, which you've given that kind of 50 basis point to 75 basis point headwind. So how close are we to &#x2013; it's tough now to talk about it sequentially because of the seasonality, but as far as just the business is concerned, as we think about the year ahead, knowing what we know about the environment, at what point are we getting to kind of a bottoming of those two line items? And do you expect growth in issuer services as we look ahead on a year-over-year basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll make a couple of comments there. First of all, let's split issuer services into two businesses: there's corporate trust and there's DRs. So DRs is a cyclical business. It's really largely driven by the developing markets and the BRICs, so we're seeing softness in new capital development there and M&amp;A and any type of corporate action. And that tends to be somewhat cyclical. So with the global downturn, it's reflected even more dramatically there.</p>
          <p>Back in September, when we did an analysis, unfortunately we don't &#x2013; we haven't computed these numbers yet, when we looked at the total number of corporate actions in the DR space, it was down about 30% year-over-year and that's what really drives the revenue base there. So that's going to come with the cycle. So if you expect an uptick in the combinations and corporate actions in the developing world, we'll see that. But if not, it'll stay here. And that will have some impact, as I mentioned, on leverage because it doesn't come &#x2013; both ways, there's not a lot of expense associated with it.</p>
          <p>In terms of corporate trust, that's more a reflection. We're seeing okay business in most components of it, but the non-agency book and the CLO/CDO book continues to run off. There are some CLOs being created and we're getting our market share of those. At least that's <mark type="indiscernible" /> (50:45), but it's not fast enough to stop that decline that we've seen, which we would probably expect over the next couple of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ken, the only thing I would add &#x2013; it's Karen Peetz &#x2013; is that we did see some bright spots. It's not enough to kind of set a trend for depository receipts, but December of the quarter we had some optimism where the pipeline is up pretty significantly as we head into the New Year. And then only thing I'd amplify on Todd's comment about CLOs is we are the market leader as the new CLOs are coming to market. There were 127 all of last year, of which we won 33%. So hopefully it will begin to offset the decline that's happening on the existing book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for all the color. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Alex Blostein with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, guys. I want to go back to NII for just one sec. Todd, you talked about in the past trying to keep net interest income flatfish. Balance sheet is up about 12% year-over-year and I get that interest rates are lower, but you guys talked in the past about trying to, I guess, reinvest a little bit more. So I guess should we think about the decline in NII just from a dollar perspective as a sign you guys are not able to reinvest quickly enough or I guess the rate compression is a little bit worse? And again, what gives you confidence that you guys can again kind of keep the number flattish from here if rates stay where they are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say there are two things. Number one, the contraction rate was a little heavier than we had expected and QE3 drove some of that. And the one thing that hasn't moved as quickly as we had hoped is some of that secured lending that we just described. So our view is we're going to see some burn off of assets. We can fight that headwind if we have the growth in our collateral services business and the principal lending side of that business. That will basically moderate it, along with the repayment of some of our trust preferreds. And &#x2013; but spreads are tough. I mean there's no question about it. And with the Fed in there buying mortgages, they've become so rich it doesn't really make sense to put some of the shorter duration mortgages in our book. So that's the way we sustain the NII that we have and the securities gains is going to be a combination of managing the portfolio the way we had described and putting more of that money to work at a little faster pace. We weren't as successful as we would have liked to have been this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and a follow-up on the collateral transformation opportunity for you guys. I understand there's still lots of questions around the size of the market and how much collateral is actually going to be needed over time. But I guess when you think about the incremental NIM pickup for you guys, what is it today? You mentioned $90 billion sitting &#x2013; deposits with the Fed or just in treasuries earning 25-ish basis points. What do you guys get currently on secured lending, which I guess we could try to use as a proxy for what you would do on the &#x2013; what you would get on the collateral transformation opportunity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It could be all over the place based on the counterparty and the collateral underneath it, but it would certainly be 35 to 75 basis points higher that what you would see holding the money at the Fed, Alex. And the way to think about it is we would like to see the book grow by $20 billion and so that would be our ability to offset some of that spread contraction headwind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Alex, just a little bit of other color. The fourth quarter between the fiscal cliff and Europe and a variety of other things that were going on, I think people, particularly towards the end of the quarter, were really in a risk-off mode in terms of leaving a lot of cash all around the world. We're already starting to see some of that cash go back to work. Hopefully, we'll see some more capital markets activities and therefore demand for borrowed securities in the SEC lending side, demand for further collateral transformation as people pick up their trading activities. So we're a little bit more hopeful than certainly the fourth quarter activity that market activity will pick up in that space and therefore, we'll be able to put some more money to work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. And then just the last one for me. I was hoping you could dissect the issuer services a little bit. I think kind of the picture on the DR side of the business is clear, some of that is cyclical and that's certainly shown up in the numbers. But when you think about the corporate trust business, 2012 was still a pretty good year for total DCM activity so to speak. Corporate high yield was probably one of the better <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:34) the year as we've seen. So is there a way to kind of tease out, I guess, the sensitivity to your business if we see a decline in kind of corporate issuance, and I guess couple that with the fact that the structured credit stuff, which I guess is about $100 million of annual revenues or so, keeps running off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So it's Karen again. The high-yield and the corporate debt types tend to be our lower fees and there's also, even though high-yield, as an example, we always dominate, it's still a small number of deals in the realm of global issuance. So that can't carry the day. The other thing is the structured book has historically been the highest fee and margin, and so as that's run off and also as new deals are coming in priced less than the old deals were, you get this kind of real churn that's happening in the business. So to a large extent, how we're reacting is to just transform the business model. We've gone to a more functional alignment so that we can manage the expenses and we're in this wait-and-see mode. We have a great footprint. We have a great strategic capability, but we're very much going to have a lot more flexibility in how we can manage expenses as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Brian Bedell with ISI Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, folks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you just flesh out the expenses a little bit more in the fourth quarter? I'm just looking to try to understand the trajectory as we go into 2013 in a few lines such as professional services and software and equipment and business development. They looked a little high. I was wondering if you can frame out the seasonality of that versus what we might see in 2013? And then also talk about the pace of the cost-saving initiatives. I think you are targeting a little over $400 million for 2013. Is that still the number we should be thinking of? And so I guess what I'm getting at is are we still looking at around a $2.8 billion quarterly run rate or do you think you can improve upon that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Brian. Answering the question around our initiatives, I think you should look at what we had, the guidance that we had previously given and we expect that we will be in line with that guidance for 2013 and that's what we certainly budgeted for. In terms of some of the quarter-end drive and expenses, I mean we saw some seasonal things like our donations were up. Our marketing expenses were up. We tend to have a conference. In fact we had one conference that we only have every four years came in this fourth quarter. As well it tends to be &#x2013; we take a hard look at some of our assets in terms of software and there were a couple of write-offs there and typically that will happen in the fourth quarter and it can also be related to our operational excellence initiatives as we start to sunset some of the systems. We're also making some investment in our brands as well and we'll roll that out in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That being said, Brian, given the environment that we're operating in we do have to be very, very disciplined around our expenses. It's one of the things I said in my opening comments that we're going to continue to try to drive efficiencies across our operating platforms and our expense base. So it's something we have a lot of focus on and a lot of attention on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so it sounds like that $2.8 billion is a little elevated and as you go into 2013, the cost-saving initiatives should help offset some of the natural inflation from a base that is a little bit lower than $2.8 billion on a quarterly basis. Is that a fair statement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you're spot on, on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's fair and be careful to as you design your model think about the revenue mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, of course. Okay. And on asset servicing, Tim, maybe can you talk about how the pricing initiative is going? I know you re-priced a lot of the lower base or do you expect some more attrition to come from some of those re-priced agreements in 2013? And if you can talk about that in conjunction with the business that you are winning on the mid-office, maybe just sort of a net outlook for growth in assets service and revenue in 2013 in that area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Why don't I start with something I haven't mentioned yet, Brian, which is we have an excellent pipeline of business that will convert over the next three quarters. So of the wins that we have not converted yet which is significant, it's a little over $800 billion. So it's one-and-a-half kind of quarters of activity and value that hasn't quite converted yet into the run rate.</p>
          <p>But on pricing, just to remind you, this is a long-term strategy for us structurally realigning the business. We start it with the low-end of the client base as you'll recall. The way I would think about it is if you look at asset servicing fees, not investment services fees but asset servicing fees, we think we've got pricing power over let's say 10% to 12%. We've been raising prices steadily, where we're allowed contractually to do so. We're retaining 75% of the clients with about a 20% uplift. I don't think that's going to change at all. We're staying very disciplined on that. And the great news there is that all drops straight to the bottom line.</p>
          <p>So we've only got about 10% of that showing up in the run rate yet. So I think there's upside there but because of the nature of when clients are re-pricing, we're largely tying to re-pricing now to when clients contracts come up for review, that will largely be done by the first quarter of 2015. Personally I think the more impactful thing over time will be the other end of the spectrum which is those very large clients where we see opportunity to do a lot more in places like collateral in our global markets capabilities and that's something where we can be focused on as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And a large part of that $800 million is mid-office that's coming in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's really mixed, Brian. You would see a core bundle of asset servicing with securities lending and foreign exchange and accounting and then you'd see about half of it which are things like middle office outsourcing, transfer agency, fund administration, and that is something that mix has shifted slightly over time. So it's about 50-50.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful. And then just real quick on the net interest revenue outlook of staying flat, does that include the assumption of deploying some of the $90 billion of central bank deposits into higher-yielding secured loans, Todd?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It does, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then money market fee waivers for the fourth quarter, you mentioned the EPS hit from that and then whether you see fee waivers moving up in the first quarter given a little bit of a decline in short-term rates?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the money market fee waivers were consistent with what we had seen in the third quarter. So there really hasn't been much of a change. It's actually slightly improved from where we were on a year-over-year basis. So right now and I don't &#x2013; of course if you're seeing any, I don't think we're seeing any real change into the first quarter as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now any investment management fee waivers were the lowest &#x2013; negative impact to us because they have been six quarters and it's been pretty steady so far. We're still sorting through sort of the year-end flows and impact on repo markets and whatnot. So &#x2013; but I would say it's definitely improved from a year ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Great. Thanks. That's helpful. Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wendy, we have time for one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our final question today is from Josh Levin with Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Josh.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So someday interest rates will go up and when interest rates go up that's certainly very positive for your business overall. But given that most of your assets are fixed income, is there a partial drag on your revenues because higher rates means lower fixed income volumes just because of the way duration works and that means translates to lower servicing fees? How should we think about that relationship?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe a few of my colleagues can jump in here on this question, but if you had a very sharp sell-off in fixed income, that would &#x2013; it would probably be a price change across the portfolio. Pretty modest if it was 5%, that would be a lot. And for most of our asset servicing business, it's our fees are not necessarily a function. It's not like AUM where it's a basis points &#x2013; there's a little bit of that. But most of the fees are related to transactions as well as to accounts. So there's three different sources of fees. So you might see a modest decline in the AUC, assets under administration, and a very modest decline in the amount of fee-related, fee revenue to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Todd, if I could just add one other thing. Josh, it's Tim. Back to this whole collateral thing, I would hasten to guess we're the largest custodian of U.S. Treasuries in the world. And as these regulations take effect, where we've talked a little bit about what the increase in volume will demand in terms of posting a collateral, a lot of those U.S. Treasuries are going to be needed. And that's why we link that back directly to an inherent medium-term strength. Whether it's transforming the collateral or through our traditional securities lending and financing capabilities, I think that's going to be a big plus for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my final question is on the tri-party repo market, there have been some changes there in terms of structurally and working with the Fed. Are you seeing &#x2013; are any changes to pricing or margin in that market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Essentially, no. We're putting through the, "tri-party reform", working with the industry, both the buy side and the sell side. Pricing for our services has held up, as it has been in the past. There's been more activity. I think the main issue around tri-party reform is taking risk out of the system, and I think we're making very good progress on doing that. So it's not a pricing issue, it's really a reform issue on taking risk, intra-day risk out of the system.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the only thing I would add is that we have been pricing for daylight that hadn't been priced to before. And so there has been some revenue benefit from that, but it's modest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you very much, everyone, for your interest in dialing in today. Sorry we couldn't get to everyone's questions. If you have further questions, please give Andy Clark and the team a direct call and we will be happy to follow up with you. Thanks again, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. If there are any additional questions or comments, you may contact Mr. Andy Clark at 212-635-1803. Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. This concludes today's conference call. Thank you for participating.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>