<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1405138" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-07-19</date>
    <companies>
      <company>77</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Investor Relations Contact">Andy Clark</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Bob P. Kelly</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; SEVP">Thomas P. Gibbons</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co., Inc.">Betsy L. Graseck CFA</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Alexander Blostein CFA</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (United States)">Howard H. Chen</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Securities International, Inc.">Glenn Schorr CFA</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer-Asset Servicing">Timothy Keaney</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Executive Vice President">Brian Thomas Shea</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice Chairman &amp; CEO-Investment Management">Curtis Y. Arledge</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">Ken M. Usdin</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Agricole Securities (USA), Inc.">Mike Lawrence Mayo</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="SunTrust Robinson Humphrey">John Stilmar</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Brian B. Bedell CFA, MBA</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Stifel, Nicolaus &amp; Co., Inc.">J. Jeffrey Hopson CFA, MBA</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Gerard Cassidy MBA</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the second quarter 2011 earnings conference call hosted by BNY Mellon. At this time all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later we will conduct a question-and-answer session. Please note that this conference call webcast will be recorded and will consist of copyrighted material. You may not record or re rebroadcast these materials without BNY Mellon's consent. I'll now turn the call over the Mr. Andy Clark. Mr. Clark, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Wendy. Welcome, everyone. With us today are Bob Kelly, our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer; Todd Gibbons, our CFO; as well as several members of our executive management team. Before we begin, let me remind you that our remarks today may include forward-looking statements. Actual results may differ materially from those indicated or implied by the forward-looking statements as a result of various factors. These factors include those identified in the cautionary statement on page 13 of the press release and those identified in our documents filed with the SEC that are available on our website, bnymellon.com. Forward-looking statements in this call speak only as of today, July 19, 2011, and we will not update forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>This morning's press release provides the highlights of our results. We also have the quarterly earnings review document available on our website which provides a quarterly review of the total company and individual businesses. We will be using the quarterly earnings review to discuss our results.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to turn the call over to Bob. Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Andy, and good morning, everyone. In Q2 earnings per share were $0.59 or $735 million. That was up 18% versus the first quarter and 9% versus prior year. First on the revenue front, both fees and net interest income increased year-over-year as well as sequentially. And revenue was up 15% year-over-year, including acquisitions. So excluding acquisitions, which is the way I look at it, revenue growth was about 7% year-over-year. This trend is frankly encouraging because if you look back, we had 5% growth Q1 versus Q1, and 3% growth in 2010 versus 2009.</p>
          <p>Fees were up about 18% or about 8% excluding acquisitions as we benefited nicely from new business trends and improved market values. And net interest income was actually up from Q1 and last year, driven by much higher client deposits reflecting the appeal of a strong balance sheet. And speaking of the strong balance sheet, we still had a gain -- had a zero provision for credit losses during the quarter.</p>
          <p>In terms of expenses, they're too high. We are up 21% year-over-year or 12% without acquisitions. If you kind of peel that back a little bit, about 2% or 3% of that growth came from increased regulatory compliance and litigation costs. These, frankly, are the unpleasant realities of a post-crisis environment. So net of these factors, expense growth was in line with our fee revenue growth. However, the bottom line is we're not getting positive operating leverage year-over-year. We need to and we will. We plan to hold an Investor Conference this fall, likely October or November, and we'll provide you with lots of details about our expense reductions initiatives as well as some thoughts on revenue growth opportunities as well. Investor Relations will get back to you soon with the date.</p>
          <p>A few thoughts on our two major businesses, Investment Management and Investment Services. In Investment Management the results are strong and there are no acquisitions affecting the numbers. We had 11% revenue growth year-over-year, 8% expense growth, and this generated 300 basis points of positive operating leverage and a 20% growth in pre-tax earnings.</p>
          <p>In terms of metrics underneath it, we had AUM growth at 22% year-over-year which took us to a new high of $1.3 trillion. We are in our 7th consecutive quarter of positive long term asset inflows or $32 billion dollars, also a new record. I would also like to note that in Wealth Management we opened an office in Chicago and are currently planning to expand in D C and Dallas.</p>
          <p>In Investment Services, we had 16% growth in revenue year-over-year, as asset servicing benefited from acquisitions, new businesses and improved market values. Assets under custody were up 21% year-over-year, to $26.3 trillion, which is a new record for us. Issuer Services had a very nice performance through the depositary receipts business. Pershing was up 21% year-over-year helped by some very large new business wins and it was also good to see sec lending revenue was up 73% year-over-year. So within securities lending, we had nine new clients and another 26 existing clients either expanded their mandates with us or they expanded their collateral guidelines which, of course, leads to increased activity.</p>
          <p>In terms of our capital account, we generated more than $800 million worth of new Tier 1 common equity before dividends and share repurchases. As you know, our dividend was raised from $0.09 to $0.13 in the quarter. We also bought back 10 million shares almost and we generated an additional 45 basis points of Basel III capital. We don't know what our final SIFI buffer will be for us, but we hope to know in coming months. But given our high quality balance sheet and rapid capital generation, we feel very comfortable that we can continue to repurchase shares and comply with any regulatory capital requirements.</p>
          <p>So beyond that, there are two main issues that currently concern us. First is Washington's inability to resolve the nation's debt and deficit issues. The debt ceiling must be raised and is really just a sideshow to the real issue. We must have a real plan to eliminate the deficit. Not reduce it. Eliminate it. And we need to couple it with a pro-growth agenda to get people back to work over time.</p>
          <p>We're also keeping a close eye on the situation in Europe and being very cautious. Our exposure is in three areas: balance sheet, money market funds, and securities lending collateral funds. Good news is, our primary exposure on balance sheet is deposits with banks. They're only to the largest and healthiest banks and short term in tenor. In terms of money market funds and securities lending funds, we have greatly increased liquidity and our exposure is also limited to the largest and healthiest banks. It's hard to speculate about what are the ultimate ripple effects should the situation deteriorate further, but we feel good about how we're positioned in this environment.</p>
          <p>So to summarize, we continue to consistently grow revenue; expenses are running higher than we'd like and we'll manage them lower. Our balance sheet is of the highest quality. We generate a lot of capital every quarter and we expect to continue to return some of this to our shareholders via share repurchases. With that, let me turn it over to Todd to go through the numbers and then we'll open up for questions. Todd.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bob. It was a solid quarter overall with good fee growth and a nice pickup in net interest revenue. Earnings for the quarter of $0.59 were up 9% from a year ago. This includes a total of $0.04 per share, similar to last quarter, of litigation and MI expenses. It also reflects a benefit of approximately $0.06 from loan and security gains. So the way we look at our core earnings, it nets to about $0.57 for the quarter.</p>
          <p>As I take you through the numbers, my comments will follow the quarterly earnings review, beginning on page 2. Some highlights, on a year-over-year basis, total revenue was $3.9 billion, up 15%. Our core fees are growing nicely, Investment Services fees were up 27% and, as Bob mentioned, that's 9% excluding acquisitions, reflecting net new business, higher depositary receipts and higher securities lending revenue. That's partially offset by higher money market fee waivers this quarter as well.</p>
          <p>Investment Management fees were up 14%, driven by higher market values and net new business. Net interest revenue was up 1%, largely reflecting growth in client deposits. Non-interest expense increased 21%, that's 12% excluding acquisitions. That's reflecting the higher litigation and legal expenses, this is the quarter for our annual merit, as well as higher volume related and business development expenses.</p>
          <p>Turning to page 4, where we'll call out some business metrics that will help you understand our underlying performance. You can see that AUM and AUC reached record levels, reflecting new business and higher market values. AUM was up 22% year-over-year to a record level of $1.3 trillion. Second quarter long term inflows of $32 billion were also a new record. Long term inflows benefited from strength in fixed income, especially our liability driven investment products, as well as equity index products. Short term outflows were $1 billion.</p>
          <p>Assets under custody was up 21% year-over-year to a record level of $26.3 trillion, benefiting from the higher -- from the acquisitions, new business and higher market values. The other Investment Services metrics continue to show positive trends with one exception and that is corporate trust, where the trend's relatively flat given the continued softness in the structured debt markets. DR programs and net issuances increased, most of the major drivers of our clearing business improved and the broker dealer collateral management book continues to grow as we gain market share, develop new products and benefit from the need for security exposures globally.</p>
          <p>Turning to page 6 of the earnings review, which shows fee growth. Assets servicing fees were up 47% year-over-year, as we continue to benefit from the acquisitions made last year. Ex acquisitions, asset servicing fees were up 14%. We also benefited from high higher market values, net new business and higher securities lending revenue due to higher loan balances and spreads, as Bob had mentioned. Asset servicing fees were up 6% quarter over quarter, reflecting seasonally higher securities lending revenue and net new business.</p>
          <p>Our 2010 acquisitions of GIS and BHF are both performing as planned with solid revenue growth. During the quarter, we won an incremental $196 billion in new asset servicing business for a total of $1.5 trillion over the past 12 months, of which $516 billion is yet to be converted. Issuer services fees were up 3% year-over-year and 4% sequentially, that's driven by higher DR revenue from higher corporate actions and service fees, and partially offset by lower shareowner services and corporate trust revenue. Clearing fees were up 19% year-over-year due to growth in client assets. We set a record during the quarter of exceeding $1 trillion in client assets for the first time and we also benefited from other new business. That reflects the positive impact of the significant new clearing businesses we were converting over the last couple of quarters and the impact of the GIS acquisition. Sequentially, the growth in assets was offset by lower transaction volumes and higher money market fee waivers.</p>
          <p>Investment Management had another strong quarter, higher market values, net new business was partially offset once again by higher money market fee waivers. FX and other trading was up slightly both year-over-year and sequentially. FX revenue totaled $184 million, a decrease of 25% year-over-year, reflecting lower volatility, partially offset by higher volumes. FX revenue was up 6% sequentially, reflecting higher volatility. Other trading revenue was $38 million versus $25 million in the first quarter and that was driven by fixed income trading.</p>
          <p>Now, let me give you some perspective on our FX activity. It is currently 5% of our total revenue. Of that 5%, approximately 40% is done through standing instruction while the majority 60% is negotiated. Of that 40% done under standing instruction, only 15% is related to U.S. public pension funds and that's where the recent publicity has centered. In other words, the recent publicity is related to the FX activity that comprises less than one-half of 1% of our total revenues. Investment and other income totaled $145 million, flat from a year ago and up from $81 million in the first quarter. The sequential increase largely reflects gains related to loans held for sale retained from a previously divested banking subsidiary.</p>
          <p>During the quarter we took securities gains of $48 million as we saw an opportunity with the very low dip in interest rates to reduce the risk of our portfolio by selling longer dated U.S. Treasury and agency securities, shortening the duration in these very uncertain times. Turning to page 8 of the earnings review, NIR was up $9 million versus the year-ago quarter and up $33 million sequentially. Both in increases were primarily driven by growth in client deposits. Interest earning assets were up for the quarter and particularly spiked at quarter end driven by negative repo rates, market uncertainty and the substantial level of liquidity that's still in the system. Revenue was also enhanced by the purchase of high quality asset-backed securities in the first two quarters.</p>
          <p>Net interest margin was 1.41%, compared with 1.49% in the prior quarter. The decrease was primarily driven by an increase in deposits. Had we not seen that growth in deposits, we estimate that the net interest margin would have increased slightly. So it would have been probably a little bit above 1.49%. But earnings would have been down probably in the vicinity of about $8 million. Given the volatility we're seeing in our balances, we're really not currently trying to manage to the net interest margin. Frankly, earning 20 to 25 basis points on cash in a zero risk asset is not bad even if temporarily hurts the margin.</p>
          <p>Turning to page 9 on expenses, non-interest expense increased 21% year-over-year. That was driven by the impact of the acquisitions as well as litigation and legal expenses. Excluding the expenses associated with acquisitions, we're up about 12%. On a quarter over quarter basis, expenses grew 4%. Both increases reflect the fact that we had the second quarter 2011 merit increase and that was -- that becomes effective the first day of the quarter on April 1, as well as higher volume related and business development expense. Other expenses were up $15 million, primarily due to a gain on a credit support agreement in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>On page 10, you can see that we continued to generate significant capital during the quarter. We generated more than $800 million in new Basel Tier 1 common, most of that through earnings, a little bit through intangible amortization. Net Basel Tier 1 common less dividends and buybacks was up $510 million.</p>
          <p>Looking at our capital ratio table, you'll note we're now disclosing our pro forma Basel III Tier 1 common ratio, which we estimated was 6.6% at the end of the quarter. I would like the emphasize that we continue to like our capital position. Our Tier 1 common Basel III ratio increased 45 basis points in the second quarter, reflecting the capital generation and slightly lower Basel III risk weighted assets for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, our earnings net of dividends and buy-backs are generating about 20 to 25 basis points of Basel Tier 1 common per quarter. And the expected quarterly paydown of our sub investment rate securities should add an additional 10 basis points. So you can expect us to generate somewhere in the 30 to 35 basis points a quarter. On top of that, the anticipated closing our Shareowner Services transaction is expected to add approximately 20 more basis points to our Basel III ratio when it's closed.</p>
          <p>We also like the performance of our sub investment grade portfolio. However, it is important to note that we could sell this portfolio and add approximately 250 additional basis points to the ratio. It's certainly nice to have this flexibility, but our capital position is already so strong that we have no intention of doing something uneconomic. Bottom line, we remain confident in our ability to exceed the Basel III 7% target by year-end, if not earlier. Given our current capital position and the strength of our balance sheet, we don't anticipate accelerating our time line to meet the proposed Basel III capital guidelines. As Bob said, we don't know what our SIFI buffer will be, but we're confident that we can comply while continuing to return capital to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>On page 11 you can see that our investment securities portfolio continues to improve and is actually performing quite well. The value of the portfolio has increased over the first quarter and the pre-tax net unrealized gain in our securities portfolio increased by $201 million to $770 million. I might add that paydowns in the sub investment grade securities were approximately $330 million in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Looking at our loan portfolio, you'll see that, just as with last quarter, we had no provision for credit losses in the second quarter compared with the charge of $20 million in the second quarter of 2010. MPAs declined from $386 million to $351 million and the total allowance for credit losses decreased $19 million driven by charge-offs. The effective tax rate of 26.9% compares to 29.3% last quarter and 30.2% in the year-ago quarter. The lower tax rate is a little misleading in the second quarter because it was driven primarily by the impact of the consolidated investment funds. On a going forward basis, excluding the impact of investment fund consolidation, we continue to expect the effective operating tax rate to be in the range of 30% to 31%.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, while there's a great deal of uncertainty in the markets given the event placing out in Europe and our own unresolved debt issues here in the U.S., we're encouraged by the revenue momentum we've achieved the last few quarters. We had nice fee growth and it felt like we turned the corner on NII. We continue to work on addressing our expense growth and look forward to sharing more specific plans at our Investor Day in late fall.</p>
          <p>A few points to factor into your thinking about the coming quarter. Both NIR and fees continue to be impacted by this persistently low interest rate environment but should benefit from our ongoing investment program. We would expect to continue to generate NII at the level we did in the second quarter. Litigation remains a risk. Third quarter earnings have traditionally been impacted by seasonality that's associated with lower levels of capital markets related revenues, particularly securities lending and foreign exchange, so we'd expect to see that.</p>
          <p>One thing that's a little bit different in the third quarter is we expect the seasonal spike in dividend payments that normally occurs during the fourth quarter may actually -- we might actually see some of that in the third quarter, so that's going to be a positive. And we expect the quarterly provision to be in the range of 0 to 15 as we've seen for the last few quarters. And finally, we expect to continue our buyback program. In summary, we had a solid quarter. With that, I'll turn it back to Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Todd. Why don't we open it up for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question is from Betsy Graseck with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Betsy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just want to hone in a little bit on the capital ratio discussion that you breezed through earlier on page 10, and link it with the securities disclosure that you give on page 11. Just wanted to make sure I understand how you're thinking about the run-off in the non-investment grade securities from here, is it going to be at the same pace as you had this quarter? And how do you think about how your common Tier 1 under Basel III changes over the course of the next couple of quarters as the non-investment grade pays down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Betsy, the securities are running off at about $100 million a quarter -- excuse me, a month. And there is some accretion, so some of the run-off is reduced by the net impact of the accretion. But our best estimate for the next few quarters is we should see about a 10 basis point benefit to our Basel III ratio from that securities run off. So it's reducing our risk weighted assets and it's almost a dollar for dollar impact on risk-weighted assets. So every $100 million down is like having another $100 million of capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that rate of change, that pace of change, is expected to be consistent or accelerating, decelerating?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's -- it will slightly decelerate over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And have you given what the yield is on those securities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have not, Betsy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And so you're saying your Basel III ratio, you think, is going to accrete a little bit faster than your Basel I?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, because you don't have the same treatment of those securities so that's an additional ten you just get right there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. And when would you reapply to the regulators for the next round of capital management activity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We think the way this is developing it's going to be an annual process. So we will pretty much just go through our typical budgeting season, have things approved by the board and submit some kind of a plan with the regulators. I'm pretty sure that's how it's going to work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Alex Blostein with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Good morning, guys. Just hoping to maybe talk a little bit more about expense management. I know that it's maybe a little bit premature, but can you give us a sense of what areas you particularly might be targeting, I guess, in your expense management plans over the next few quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So, Alex, it's Bob. So we have been working on this for some time and, of course, we have a lot of expense management stuff flowing through our income statement right now as we continue the reposition ourselves and there's investment costs involved in getting cost out over time but the basic categories are moving people to lower cost locations that aren't in major cities; real estate and working down the number of locations, the number of buildings, that we have; procurement, where we're doing a good job but I wouldn't call us first quartile in our capabilities. And frankly, we have too many applications in our company in terms of systems. And we want to cull those fairly materially over the next few years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. So this is over and above from what, I guess, you guys have been doing already because you have been moving some people to lower cost locations for quite some time, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep, and that's been pretty successful but we're now looking at things that are materially above that run rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then just a couple other nuances in the quarter. Can you give us a sense what the discount accretion was, just in dollar terms, for the second quarter and then maybe a sense of what money market fee waivers were?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. The discount accretion was down a little bit in the quarter, almost $10 million, so I think it was about $95 million, $96 million. And the money market fee waivers actually picked up during the quarter, probably worth about a penny to our earnings on a sequential basis. So they haven't gone back to the highs that we saw last year but with the very, very low treasury rates we're getting pretty close to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. So that was like a $60, $65 million number or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Glenn Schorr with Nomura. Mr. Schorr, please check your mute button. We'll move on to the next question. Howard Chen with Credit Suisse, your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob, thanks for the commentary on peripheral Europe. I realize it's a fluid situation. Just maybe was hoping to get more details on how you're thinking about some of the potential pluses like customer inflows and acquisition environment, and how you're weighing that versus some of the minuses, things like increased counterparty risk and a tail event within the money market fund business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. From a business standpoint, I really like our positioning from both an asset management standpoint as well as our various Investment Services products standpoint. I think we have really good opportunities to gain market share in Europe over time just because of the quality of our products and services that we have. I'm not getting a sense that there's a lot of acquisition opportunities in the near term but I would think over 2 or 3 years some of the major banks in Europe have to really think about how they're creating value for shareholders in coming years and over the longer term. And that may or may not, it's just too early to tell, result in other opportunities for us, like joint ventures or more outsourcings, longer term partnerships from a middle office and back office standpoint and from the standpoint of providing more asset management products to these firms, where perhaps they don't have to manufacture their own products. There's a pretty long list of opportunities here.</p>
          <p>So the real question is how quickly and aggressively will European counterparties and banks generally, financial institutions, want to act to refocus their business models and to free up capital. So we'll see. And I worry much less than perhaps the market is from the standpoint of the impact on our balance sheet as well as our off balance sheet activities. We have been watching this extraordinarily closely, of course, and we're really cognizant of what happened several years ago in the markets with market instability. So we have learned from that and we're being pretty proactive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe just following up on that, Bob, just honing in on two specific things. On the positive side, during the crisis you saw significant amount of balance sheet growth. Has that -- what's the pace of that specific to Europe and the events in Europe now? And on the potential negative side within asset management can you think about -- is anything changing with respect to how you're managing the money market fund business and, again, a potential tail event there? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say on the latter we're much, much more liquid than we ever have been in the past. In fact, enormously liquid so that it provides us with maximum flexibility for our clients as well as from a risk management standpoint. We have been extraordinarily careful in terms of where our investments are in terms of the countries and in terms of the entities. We only want the biggest, healthiest companies within our funds. So that has been a real time activity for us as we continue to stay on top of the developments in the market. And what was &#x2013; one more question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take that, Bob. In terms of the balance sheet growth, it's really hard to attribute it to anything particular, Howard, because you've got a confluence of events. You have had repo rates in the U.S. go negative, so rather than having funds holding negative repo, they're leaving money in their DDA accounts, 0 is better than negative 8. So we're seeing a bit of noise from that. Certainly some of the disruptions in Europe is going to be contributing somewhat to it. And our balance sheet is probably running -- our deposit base is probably $30 billion higher than we would have expected because of the noise around the world right now would be our best guess. There's also an awful lot of excess liquidity in the system and so we're the beneficiary of that as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is the big difference from a few years ago, in that we have all been pretty well trained and hardened to market volatility over the past three years. Plus we have an enormously liquid financial system around the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very helpful, thanks. Separate topic, Todd. And then on the NIM and net interest revenue outlook, I appreciate what you're saying on the challenging environment over the near term, but just thinking longer term, how are you thinking about the longer term leverage, the rising rates in the business model now that things have changed on the NIM and the balance sheet? You have previously framed that as maybe a $500 million revenue opportunity with very high incremental margins. Can you refresh that for us today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I would stick with that, Howard. I don't think it's changed much. We might have dipped a couple of quarters ago with the move in the fee waiver started to decline a little bit but with these very, very, very low Treasury rates right now, fee waivers have increased so the opportunity is probably in the $450 million to $500 million range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's pre-tax too, Howard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And then, final one for me, again, thanks for the detail on the Basel III capital, just curious, any updated thoughts on Basel III liquidity and leverage proposals, updates similar to what you have done on capital for things like net stable funding ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's still a little bit early. I mean, the net stable funding ratio really isn't, there's nothing out there to really work with. The liquidity coverage ratio is one that seems to be gaining some traction in its current form. And just look at the nature of our balance sheet, Howard, you could just see how well we would expect to do on that ratio. We're sitting on massive amounts of cash.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Howard, I'd also &#x2013; it's Bob again. I'd also mention that we're getting the strong impression from the regulators that they're not going to be quick to act on the various liquidity components of Basel III. They want to really study this and understand the system-wide implications of this over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's really helpful. Thanks for all the updates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Glenn Schorr with Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much and sorry about earlier. Quick one is I think you mentioned earlier, I just didn't write it down quick enough, the won but not yet converted pipeline in investment servicing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was I think about $560 billion, Tim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>$560 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>$560 billion, that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you've had a steady flow of new business through thick and thin in these tough markets. Are you seeing any signs of clients looking to outsource more given the market pressures and what that can do for them on the expense side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim Keaney here. Yes, pipeline is almost double what it was a year ago and this has been a continuing trend, I think we talked about this last quarter. About 40% of our new business wins year-to-date, and as it turns out, about 40% of our pipeline is outsourcing. And certainly what we continue to see is as banks, insurance companies and fund managers remain profit challenged, they're turning to outsourcing non-core activities and we certainly feel that that plays to one of our strengths.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe Brian Shea can add to that from a Pershing perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say we're seeing similar trends on the clearing side as well and an increase in the level of interest by self-clearing firms to variabilize their cost structure and free up regulatory and investment capital. So our pipeline is also solidly up year-over-year on the traditional clearing side. And we're also seeing a doubling in the pipeline of revenue associated with the cross-selling between Pershing related activity and the PNC GIS legacy businesses, specifically Albridge Solutions and the managed investments side, so a good pickup in pipeline activity there as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>While we're on new business trends, Curtis, why don't you give us your views on the quarter and where you see opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had a good quarter again on the net new business front and our wins not yet funded have also remained pretty strong. In the quarter, the bulk of our net new business did come in fixed income, both active and LDI strategies. On the equity side net new business did -- as Todd mentioned, was more on the index side. I would say our wins not yet funded would follow that trend. Active opportunities where we are competing and we have a reasonably strong belief that we're going to be in the hunt, the business mix is a little broader with more clients looking to put money to work in active equity strategies. But I would tell you that our real strength has been on the fixed income side in the second quarter and looking into third quarter at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As an aggregate comment, would you agree it looks like all the related fees are growing enough in line with the assets so pricing is reasonably stable across all the businesses; is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think the short answer is yes, Glenn. There hasn't been any big change I would say. And again, as we talked about, as we reprice current clients as contracts come up and as we price new business we take very, very conservative views that clearly incorporate the current economic environment. We're certainly driving clients to higher fees as a percentage of total revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And the my last question is on -- BofA had a proposed settlement with its investor base where you guys act as trustee. And I'm just curious to get your thoughts on what that read-through is for you as role as trustee? In other words, at first when private label put-back issue came up, there were some people asking lots of questions about the role of the trustee and where they fit in. It looks to me like the settlement backs up your previous comments but wanted to see how you feel as your role of trustee and what your thought is -- happens if it doesn't get approved?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We think that's exactly right, Glenn. I think it is consistent with what we have said in the past. We did participate in the negotiations in our role as trustee and we believe the proposed settlement is reasonable and ultimately in the best interest of the trust. It imposes no financial obligations on us, nor are we going to receive any part of the $8.5 billion settlement in our capacity as trustee. We continue to be fully indemnified as trustee for any losses, liability or expenses associated with this. So we think that it makes a lot of sense and we think it's reasonable and we think the courts should approve it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much for the answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Ken Usdin with Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. Couple of little clarification things, if I might real quick. Todd, you gave it to us in the per share terms at the very being but can you quantify for us the magnitude of the loan sale gains and also the incremental litigation reserves that you set up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The -- between the loan sales and the revaluation and the securities sales, it's about $100 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then in terms of litigation and M&amp;I, you can see our M&amp;I expenses directly but we don't really care to show litigation on a regular basis in that kind of detail and give too much advantage to some of our plaintiffs here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the litigation point, though, just generally speaking then, I believe this is the first reserve that you have explicitly set up aside from the commentary in the conference call. Can you walk us through your process and your thinking and how this could evolve over time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ken, can you repeat that? I didn't hear exactly what that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a broader comment on the litigation reserves, not the ongoing legal expense, but just on the specifics of the legal reserve. Just how you how do you get to the point you start to set aside the specific reserves and, I guess, just a general thought on how this litigation is progressing and evolving?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We follow very much the FASB guidelines and it's based on estimable and probable. So if we feel something that we can estimate what a loss is going to be and it's probable, we will reserve for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. My second question relates to, Bob, just coming back to your points on expenses, the laundry list of things that you gave seemed to be very logical progression of cost saves but things that necessarily wouldn't necessarily be out of line with normal operations of the business. So just wondering like when you're thinking about going forward and starting to really attack the cost base, is it because there's really some low-hanging fruit or is it anything that you see in terms of the long-term profitability and revenue trends of the business that have just put it -- put the company on higher alert that there needs to be a realignment there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think the fundamental is pretty straightforward, Ken, ad that is -- it's operating leverage. I want to get some -- I want to get revenue growth higher than expense growth so I have been encouraged on the revenue side, and the expense run rate remains pretty high. And as we indicated back in January in the fourth quarter numbers, we are expecting quite a few headwinds this year in terms of higher pension costs, higher healthcare costs, people are still, of course, getting raises and they should be.</p>
          <p>We have higher depreciation costs, we have this litigation environment. We have higher compliance and regulatory costs. There's a lot of headwinds in our industry right now. And but we got to manage through it. So what I would say is we're going through all of our programs, but more aggressively than we have in the past to create more favorable trends and to moderate these growth in expenses. And that even goes to the level of looking at individual client profitability and making sure that we're doing the right thing, not just from a client standpoint but also from a shareholder standpoint.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Ken, if I can add a couple of points here. There is some low-lying fruit. If you think &#x2013; we've gone throw a number of acquisitions over the last 3 or 4 years so when we go back and reflect on our technology infrastructure, there's quite a bit that we can attack there. We've got too many desktop configurations, just the nature of our business model and we're going to go after that. We also have some applications dating back to the Mellon Bank of New York merger which we think we can sunset. So -- and we've also for the first time we're really looking at combining some of our common operations not just within asset servicing but even across some of our different businesses. I think that's an advantage that we have -- that we can leverage so these are the types of things in addition to the normal course. We do see some fruit here that we can go after.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The other thing is we have very good process around this, we have been working on this for some time. We're going to treat it just like a merger integration and we'll have &#x2013; we'll be very metrics driven, very specific initiative driven with definitive numbers and people signing on the bottom line for what they can get and when.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Okay, thanks a lot for all that color. Appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Mike Mayo with CLSA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Can you just summarize this $30 billion increase in deposits? Is this similar to what we saw during the crisis in the U.S. a couple of years ago and you're getting a lot of deposits in Europe or what's the geography of this deposit increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I would say it's quite a bit different in its nature. I would say there's a fair amount of it is just this negative interest rate, especially the spike toward the quarter end, Mike. This negative interest rate just created an arbitrage with better leave it in cash with your custodian than to put it out on repo at a negative rate. So that's a significant component of it. There's -- I'm sure there's some of it related to dislocations but it's got a very different feel to it than it did after the Lehman crisis where it was just an immediate spike in hedge funds and everybody just dumped their money on us. It's not quite like this. This has been a slower build and a build related to not just the risk off trade but some market disruptions in the Treasury market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So how much of that is from outside the U.S. of the $30 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have that off the top of my head. It feels like it's &#x2013; I'd really be speculating. We'll get back to you on that, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then separately, I know you touched on this, what is the dollar amount of your money market assets under management that are invested in European bank debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our prime assets, we have roughly $34 billion in our 2a-7 prime funds that are in the euro zone core. We had a view that about -- less than 20% of all the eligible European banks actually make it through our credit screen. So that represents roughly 28% of our total prime 2a-7 assets in our main money market business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've done a pretty good job of selecting the right names and quite frankly the stress tests that came out last week confirm exactly that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess you have over $300 billion of money market assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, again, we have money market assets that would include treasury funds and other offshore funds. I'm giving you the U.S. prime 2a-7 assets. I certainly can work with you -- if you want to talk offline, we can certainly walk through our statistics more broadly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I just -- there were big articles just a few weeks ago. Wall Street Journal said money market mayhem and that this is a big risk, and I just want you to give us some reassurance that it's not as big a risk as highlighted in this lead editorial in the Wall Street Journal June 27. So if you look at the overall complex of money market assets that you have, what would be the total amount that would be invested in European bank debt? And I guess the reassurance part might be you have a lot invested in that but you don't have support agreements where you would have to make up any shortfall?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the thing to remember, Mike, is these are extremely senior instruments, the tenor is extremely short and these assets are in the biggest, healthiest names in Europe. These aren't to countries or two markets that you'd view or names that you'd view as being unstable. And we have been very proactive in being extremely liquid in all these funds as well to provide us with maximum flexibility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just so you know, there are in the euro zone there are 124 Tier 1 2a-7 eligible banks. Again, less than 20% of those make it through our credit screen. So where we do have exposures in that segment, they are again as Bob said, to the largest most significant institutions in those countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no exposure and haven't had exposure to Greece and Portugal directly and have de minimis exposure to the rest of the more troubled sovereigns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we feel like we're well-positioned here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up on that last point. So to the countries that are defined as PIIGS, how much investments do you have in banks in those countries through your money market funds for the overall complex? If you don't have that now, it would be nice to have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have none in our prime funds and de minimis in our sec lending activities. De minimis being less than 1%. And where we have exposure in those countries are actually to -- we have some Irish mortgage-backed securities but, again, less than 1% of sec lending exposures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from John Stilmar with SunTrust.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. Most of my questions have been answered but just a real technical one. Investment in other income, Todd, moved up a little bit, I was wondering if you could kind of drill down and maybe reveal a little bit more of the drivers of what's going on underneath that statement line? I think I missed that in your commentary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are a couple of items that are in there, a couple of our joint ventures or our minority ownership interests, for example, are in there. And they're doing pretty well. We have an interest in Wing Hang Bank, for example. We have an interest in ConvergEx, which continues to be do pretty well, so that's been a positive. It did run high in the -- are you specifically referring to Investment Management other income?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, just to other fee and revenues on a consolidated basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what I was referring to. I wanted to make sure I had that clear. So we have a number of items. We expect that, John, to typically run in the $80 million range, so it was a little high because of the gains that we had taken on those loans that we talked about during the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and you had mentioned the ConvergEx. There's some commentary, obviously, in the headlines of ConvergEx being taken out. Is there any residual positive impact that that can have, at least in the near term? How should we think about that as we thinking about our earnings estimates going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no comment on any -- we have heard rumors of a transaction. I really can't comment on that. But what ConvergEx has done is filed for an S-1 for an initial public offering where we would monetize some of our interest in the company and that would be -- certainly be a positive for our capital position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perfect. Thank you, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Brian Bedell with ISI Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, folks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to go back on the expenses, Todd, you're talking about obviously the sunsetting of systems and the consolidation across the businesses. Has anything changed from what you said last quarter in terms of sort of a 3 to 4 year overall time line of integrating those systems? Or has that advanced?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're honing in on this right now. We're honing in on it right now and it's going to actually be a subject of our Investor Conference in the fall. And we're going to walk you through exactly what the time lines and what our expectations are. As Bob pointed out, we're going to have commitments around the table here about how we're going to achieve the positive operating leverage we're looking for so we'll give you more color but it's around the same general themes, this concept of re-engineering and combining common operations, improving our technology infrastructure, that's some of the lower lying fruit. And looking at our application portfolio and seeing if we can reduce it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, okay. So stay tuned for that. And then maybe on the regulatory cost, not the litigation or legal reserves but the actual costs that you would attribute to the regulatory environment? Could you frame out what that is right now? And then any kind of expectation of how those might abate over the next several quarters? Or is it too early to tell?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have pored through our numbers. It's pretty difficult to tell what's ongoing and what's not but, obviously, complying with Basel II, Basel 2.5 and Basel III, there's quite a bit of systems infrastructure associated with that. Over the past couple of years, as you would expect, your FDIC charges have gone up quite dramatically and then we've invested in one of our fastest growing shared services is our risk area as we've continued to invest in that. And legal costs continue to rise. I don't see the growth rate continuing at the level that we have seen over the past couple of years. FDIC is still high but it's at least flattened out, for example. And I would say that's consistent with some of the other things, so I think the -- kind of the step-up has occurred and some of it will -- eventually we'll get a dividend here but that's probably a year or so away.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Clearly we have added hundreds of millions of dollars to our cost base over the last two or three years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It would be nice to be able to address that. But sounds like you can talk about maybe a hilt bit more on Analyst Day as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just maybe conceptually on the -- this whole prospect of the U.S. debt potentially being downgraded, obviously you guys have a major stake in the infrastructure, the country's infrastructure. What -- maybe if you can talk a little bit about what you're thinking for your collateral management businesses and the corporate trust business and maybe even the money market business if U.S. debt is downgraded? And maybe contrast the long-term debt being downgraded versus any risk of the short term debt being downgraded, which doesn't appear to be an issue right now? But if you could just talk about that through some of your ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a lot of questions, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I know. I know. Maybe just in the -- maybe focusing on the collateral management business, because obviously...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as Todd's thinking about that, I just want to reinforce that we've got to raise the debt ceiling and we have got to balance the books. Not over ten years, over like three or four years. We've got to get some growth back in this country again. So this is important to the whole nation and the global economy and we should just stop fooling around with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we have -- we have worked to make sure that our -- in fact our team has been working on this all the way back as early as April of this year. We have been working to make sure that our systems are flexible and we'll be able to manage whatever happens here. We're obviously coordinating with Treasury and the regulators and also within the industry. There's still some uncertainty, we don't know how treasuries might trade. We don't know whether the pricing services -- how they're going to put value on them. We don't know whether counterparties are going to want treasuries as collateral. I would expect that they would but we're going through our contingency planning, we're not doing this unilaterally. We're working with industry groups and, obviously, we're talking with the Treasury and will do as directed. But we do have the flexibility in our systems to accommodate what we think could happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It doesn't require any systems changes and we are very ready for any eventuality but I don't expect it will be necessary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's hope for that. And then just a couple other housekeeping ones. Shareowner Services business, when do you expect that to close?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now we would expect in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>4Q. And then the seasonal spike in dividend payments in the third quarter instead of the fourth quarter, that's in the DR business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it is. There's a little bit of uncertainty, I wanted to point that out. I think we might get a little bit of that in the third quarter so the third quarter might look a little better than we would have otherwise expected.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, our next question is from Jeff Hopson with Stifel, Nicolaus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks a lot. You talked a little bit about pricing being stable. You also talked about looking at client -- individual client profitability. So I guess the question is, are you having renegotiations -- significant renegotiation conversations with clients, any kind of net result of that? And then on expense, in terms of some of the systems work, are we talking about evolutionary or potentially revolutionary changes here because you're talking about expense cuts in one respect, but also given that you're having to continue to invest significantly to keep up with -- keep your systems up to date and moving forward, how can you reconcile those two thoughts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the former, do you want to talk to that for a second, Tim, and just how you think about client profitability?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Jeff. Tim Keaney here. We talked a little bit in the past where if you look at the duration of contracts for public funds, it's 3 or 4 years; for corporate type pension fund clients, it's probably 5 years or so. So our clients come up for review regularly. They did last quarter and they did this quarter. We're having very, very open discussions with clients around the new economic reality as it relates to capital markets revenues. And we also have very open discussions with clients about how our costs are escalating around things like helping clients comply with a myriad of increased regulations around the world. And we have been very, very successful retaining clients. And very successful at repackaging our relationships with clients so that our fee revenue which we can count on is the lion's share of our total revenue base. And it's just the new attitude we have taken in dealing with clients in terms of renegotiations and bidding on new business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One of the things that &#x2013; and just on the systems side, what I would say that we have been &#x2013; historically, we have been pretty decentralized in how we run our operations. As a result, we have a lot of overlapping applications that do very similar things, that are almost identical but aren't quite. So we have been bucketing those into various categories, everything from trade entry to reconciliations to you name it. And we're going to get to common platforms by having more centralized utilities and be able to reap the benefits of that. Ultimately what it will mean is that we can reduce our maintenance and turning on the lights run rate cost and we can invest a bit of that into new systems activity and product enhancements over time as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on the former issue, would you say there's been any change in the client retention rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeff, it's Tim. No. Our new business win rates and our retention rates are very, very solid. They have been since we've been tracking it. One of the things we do look at is giveaway and takeaway ratios. We continue to win about three times more than we lose when we do lose a client. So we continue to be a big net winner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wendy, we have time for one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our final question is from Gerard Cassidy with RBC Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, guys. Can you give us some thoughts on Basel II? I think if I recall you folks were part of the group that's testing Basel II? Is that going to become a reality or they going to leap right to Basel III from your understanding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take that one, Gerard. We don't know. But it certainly feels like we'll never see Basel -- Basel II is kind of the backbone for Basel III, so everything that you do in Basel II you need for Basel III. But my expectation is we'll go straight to Basel III but that's just speculation on my part.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we need is a level playing field with the rest of the world here. We never implemented Basel II. We're all focused on Basel III now. Let's just get it done and my hope would be that with the FSOC oversight group in Washington and given the fact that we have way too many regulators, hopefully we can get consensus through the FSOC group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then a couple of balance sheet questions. You guys mentioned about the great growth in the non-interest bearing deposits that you had in the quarter because of some disruptions. If markets become more normal, would you expect to see that line item come down in the third or fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We certainly hope so. We would -- and if you noticed, a lot of that was just left at the central banks. So we would like to see some normalization. There would be a little give away of NII if we do it. So we don't mind having it, Gerard. It's a terrible ROA, it's not a bad ROE since there's really no risk associated with it. But we like everybody else would like to go back to a little more normalized environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, and then just the last question on the liability side of the balance sheet. Can you share with us the borrowings from the FRB related to the asset-backed conduit? It looks like it was $1.3 billion, it looks like versus nothing in the prior quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know, Gerard, what you are actually referring to. I don't think we borrowed anything from the FRB in asset-backed, but we'll follow up with you on that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, everyone. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>