<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1188117" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-10-21</date>
    <companies>
      <company>812</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Robert P. Connolly, Managing Director and General Counsel</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Ann Marie Petach, Managing Director and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Laurence D. Fink, Chief Executive Officer and Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="4">Hojoon Lee</participant>
      <participant id="5">Laurence Fink</participant>
      <participant id="6">William Katz</participant>
      <participant id="7">Roger Smith</participant>
      <participant id="8">Ann Marie Petach</participant>
      <participant id="9">Craig Siegenthaler</participant>
      <participant id="10">Prashant Bhatia</participant>
      <participant id="11">Laurence fink</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, my name is Christie and I will be your conference facilitator today.  At this time I would like to welcome everyone to the BlackRock third quarter 2008 teleconference.  Our host for today's call will be Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Laurence D. Fink, Chief Financial Officer, Ann Marie Petach and General Counsel, Robert P. Connolly .  All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise.  After the speakers' remarks, there will be a question-and-answer session.  (Operator instructions).  Thank you.  Mr. Connolly, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone.  This is Bob Connolly.  I'm the General Counsel of BlackRock.  Before Larry and Ann Marie make their remarks, I want to point out that during the course of this conference call we may make a number of forward-looking statements.  We call to your attention the fact that BlackRock's actual results may differ from these statements.  As you know, BlackRock has filed with the SEC reports, which lists some of the factors, which may cause our results to differ materially from these statements.  And finally, BlackRock assumes no duty to and does not undertake to update any forward-looking things. With that, I'll turn it over to Ann Marie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone.  I'm going to start out just mentioning that our third quarter reported GAAP results are $1.62 per share but from here forward, I'm going to focus on as adjusted results.  I would note that in our press release, we have included an as adjusted measure for both operating and non operating results.  We previously have not shown an as adjusted measure for non-operating.  We thought it was helpful to adjust for the same deferred compensation related movement that we have been adjusting for in operating; as one effectively hedges the other.  The investment income in non operating exactly offsets the compensation related expense in operating.  Third quarter as adjusted earnings are 229 million or $1.71 per share.</p>
          <p>The as adjusted results reflect as adjusted operating income of 431 million or 2.09 per share and as adjusted non-operating losses of 79 million or $0.38 cents per share.  I'm going to first discuss operating results.  I'll come back to non-operating in a minute.  As adjusted operating results are up 2% compared to the third quarter of 2007 and down 3.5% compared to the second quarter.  Year to date operating earnings 1.3 billion are up 25% compared to 2007.  Revenues of 1.3 billion are down five percent compared to the second quarter and up about 1% compared to the third quarter of 2007.  Third quarter revenues reflect are being driven by three primary factors, first the effects of markets and foreign exchange, particularly on our international equity and alternative products which include large investments in funds related to energy and natural resources.  Markets affect both base fees and performance fees, which are often dependent on absolute performance, a difficult threshold in this market.</p>
          <p>Second, for the month of September, flows out of our prime money funds, which are reflective of a general market retraction from these products, note that cash assets are about flat compared to a year ago and average cash assets are up materially from a year ago.  And third, strong growth in our BlackRock solutions revenues driven by the advisory business and growth in Aladdin assignments.  Compared to a year ago, base fees are up about 6% driven by alternatives including the addition of the former Quellos assets and higher average cash management assets offset partially by lower base fees on equity.</p>
          <p>The lower equity base fees reflect market and foreign exchange factors more than offsetting net new equity and balanced assets of 14 billion dollars.  Compared to the second quarter, base fees are down 7%.  6 percentage points of the 7% decrease is explained by based fees and equity products particularly on our international mutual funds.  Operating margins as adjusted in the third quarter is 38.4%, an improvement compared to prior period.  GAAP compensation expense of 468 million in the third quarter includes the marks on deferred compensation and the compensation to be funded by PMC and Merrill.</p>
          <p>Adjusting for these factors, compensation expense of 490 million is down about 4% from as adjusted second quarter compensation expense of 510 million primarily explained by lower incentive comps.  Compared to a year ago comp expense is up 1% reflecting growth in people and expense recognition of historic stock awards offset by lower incentive comps.  The third quarter compensation revenue ratio, as adjusted for these factors, is 37.3%.  Third quarter general and administrative expense of 171 million is down 35 million from the second quarter and 29 million from the third quarter of 2007 explained primarily by foreign exchange effect 32 million compared to the second quarter and of about 27 million will compared to a year ago.  The balance sheet related foreign exchange adjustments had a positive effect on third quarter operating margin.  The absence of closed end fund launch cost in the third quarter also compared G&amp;A compared to prior periods.  Portfolio cost are reflective of asset sales primarily into our liquidity products and other mutual funds.</p>
          <p>Now moving to non-operating earnings.  As adjusted non-operating losses of 79 million in the third quarter reflect marks on BlackRock's capital invested side by side with our clients and seed in new products.  These investments are not proprietary in nature.  Put this number into perspective the 79 million represents about a 6% decline on our 1.3 billion portfolio and when I talk about the portfolio right now, I'm excluding the deferred comp assets.  And this is relative to markets which were down substantially more than 6%.  As a reminder, our portfolio is comprised primarily of five asset categories, hedge funds and fund to funds, distressed credit funds, private equity fund to funds, real estate and marketable securities, which we hedge as appropriate.  Each asset category represents between 15 and 25% of the total portfolio.  Many of these investments are long term in nature while the marks represent the market valuation of the portfolio at a point in time.</p>
          <p>These marks do not reflect BlackRock's expectation of holding these investments for a long period of time or in the case of some of the distressed credit until maturity.  The 79 million loss is explained primarily by marks on distressed credited funds totaling 48 million, hedge funds totaling 18, real estate totaling 14 and private equity totaling 4 million, offset partially by net interest and other.  The marks on the distressed credit funds are reflective of the severely distressed marks on this asset class and the leverage in these funds.  Again, these are long-term funds.  The cash flows on these investments continue to perform in line with our expectations when we launched the product.  I would also note that year to date non-operating losses on Peter Cooper Village total 31 million and that 2007 non-operating gains on Peter Cooper Village totaled 31 millionBeta has affected the entire market, including our business results.</p>
          <p>Our business has grown and our operating results have improved compared to a year ago.  We have a diversified business by asset type, client type and region.  We expect this will continue to provide balance to our results and growth opportunities over time.  Our solutions and advisory businesses are growing and we are seeing incremental opportunity in an adverse market.  Our pipeline remains strong at 62 billion.  With that I'll turn it over to Larry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone.  The best way to start to discuss this quarter I need to quote Dickens when he says these are the best of times and worst of times and I would say the third quarter for BlackRock and our industry was the best of times and the worst of times.  The macro environment has been very hostile to the investment management business and hostile also to BlackRock.  As I said in the press release, we are not immune to this.</p>
          <p>Like all in the industry, we are affected by the markets.  We've lost assets as investors have withdrawn in markets such as money market funds as there's been a flight to quality and everybody is rushing to bills, NAVs are down significantly in equities, in fixed income and in hedge funds.  I've never seen in my 32 years of business all markets deteriorating all at the same period of time.  So all this means is revenues are down.</p>
          <p>In our -- in our non-operating earnings obviously we took some significant losses, albeit only a 6% loss, I'll discuss that a little later, but this is another indication of what has happened in the marketplace.  In other words, it's very hard for us to control these macro elements that are in the marketplace.  Like everyone else in the industry, we are facing these winds.  But let me talk about the differentiation of BlackRock.</p>
          <p>So we are facing some very tough headwinds, but I am -- I could sit here today and say we are in a better position today in building BlackRock into a global financial investment firm with a global platform, a global brand, we are in a better position today than we've ever been before.  We are differentiating ourselves more than anyone else in the world right now in terms of being in front of this, being in front of our clients, which I'll discuss a little later; working on situations that are very public and being a very good advisor to some institutions that are looking for advice and are trying to mitigate some of the troubled problems within their company.  We are being asked globally now to work with companies.  We are being asked globally as to what should be solutions in terms of how do we manage our portfolios going forward.</p>
          <p>So I believe we -- our long standing approach and working with clients to solve problems, whether they're inflicted problems or just macro issues, we are in a very good position, especially when the market turns around, to really benefit from the increased visibility and positioning BlackRock has.  I believe more than ever our One BlackRock model, bringing all our capabilities together to provide the best thinking independent advice and timely products to our clients is more important than ever before.  Because of all products we have correlated from money markets to fixed income to equities, to hedge funds, to real estate, our clients are looking for more advice that interconnects all the different products.  I don't believe advice with one product will solve any problems in this marketplace today in a more connected, integrated approach like our One BlackRock approach is the approach that clients are looking for and I believe is an approach that will allow us to grow above industry trends in the future.  So we continue to work with pension funds and pension funds are worried about now they're mismatched between assets and liabilities because of the incredible decay in their assets.  More and more clients are looking for liability driven solutions.</p>
          <p>Clients are looking for more holistic solutions like fiduciary outsourcing where we are involved with more and more clients especially in Europe in terms of trying to help them navigate their entire balance sheet issues.  And all of these conversations require us to provide more global solutions, products that are worldwide, and across all multiple asset categories.  So since this crisis has began, and I would say it started probably March of last year, not March of this year, it started to get much worse last summer, we've actually raised over 18 billion dollars of products in terms of trying to help clients solve solutions. And taking advantage of the market volatility and the market imbalances.</p>
          <p>We have been very visible in terms of the wider range of services we're providing our clients in terms of our BlackRock solution platform. Working with clients with long term portfolio liquidations, balance sheet valuations, complex risk management, monitoring assignments and operational risk management solutions so we're involved more than ever and I'll talk about that in a little more detail later on.  So our one BlackRock model has helped us even in these troubled times, our one BlackRock model is giving us a position to continue to build even with these hostile winds.  I just would like to say very loudly, though, without -- with all these new winds and with all these new opportunities that we see, it is very hard to mitigate those winds versus the extreme market decline that we've witnessed.  The beta in the world, the macro issues are far more overwhelming than some of the incremental changes that we are making.  But in terms of how BlackRock navigates and how BlackRock is positioned I believe it's those little transactions, they may be little and invisible but those little transactions relative to beta is what's differentiating us, is what's making us a better firm and will provide us opportunity in the future to continue to grow.  So I can't be prouder of our firm.  Times are very hard.  BlackRock is not immune but I think our operating results in terms of operating income is a good example of how we've been able to navigate opportunistically in this marketplace.  Before I discuss some of the specifics of our quarter, let me talk about how BlackRock is positioned for the future.</p>
          <p>With a transformation that's going on in our banking industry, the nationalization of banks; capital infusion by government at the banks; consolidation of the banking industry worldwide and most importantly, with banks being required to have a much higher capital position -- in Europe, some of the countries are demanding a capital tier one capital position of 12%, some countries at 10.  If the market continues to demand these high capital ratios for more than ever, for the commerce to survive globally we need a vibrant global capital market.  So as banks require more capital obviously it means A) they're going to have less leverage, they're going to have less assets on their balance sheet, and one of the outgrowths of this will be a larger more integrated capital markets.  The capital markets will need to be larger for our world to continue to grow and it will only grow as we grow our global capital markets.  I believe firms like BlackRock are as well positioned for those outcomes than any firm and I believe the role of the independent asset manager as global capital markets need to grow these global capital markets -- these global investment management firms should thrive in this environment.</p>
          <p>I'm not here to say we are around the corner yet but it's very clear to me that we need to have a vibrant global Capital Markets so as the world starts healing itself and I believe we will play a much larger role in these global Capital Markets.  I'm not here to suggest it's going to happen in a week, it may be a year from now, it may be two years from now but it's very obvious to me with the transformation of our large national lenders, our banks, they're going to have to be a bigger role for global investment firms in the global capital markets.</p>
          <p>Because of that, as I said publicly in the past, I do believe all investment firms should be regulated too.  Because the role of global capital markets is only going to be more important and all participants in these global capital markets should be regulated. And I look forward to the time when we have a regulators who are working together on a global basis and making sure we have a better market, a safer market and a market that can allow capitalism globally to survive.  Good indication how we are beginning to see some thawing as a result of the global transformation from national, from the central banks and the monetary authorities to recapitalize our banking systems globally, we are beginning to see some thaws.</p>
          <p>LIBOR from last week is down 100 basis points.  We still have about another 125 basis points of reduction of LIBOR to get it more normalized but we've published, a good 40%, 45% of the re-normailzation of LIBOR and that's only just a beginning.  We need to continue to see yield spreads in bonds narrowing.  Without citing names, two of our largest banks in the United States, one of them is trading 500 over the five year treasury.  In other words, they are funding five-year liabilities at seven and three-quarters.  Another large bank, one of our top five banks in the United States are funding five year debt at six and three-quarters.  If you add a normalized return on assets, you add another 125 points, so you're seeing, to lend any money up in the five year, whether it's a non-conforming mortgage, whether it's a student loan, whether it's a small business loan, we need to have -- they need to get above 8 or 9% to make it profitable.  And this is what's causing the stress in Mainstreet.  So we are seeing this breakage finally in LIBOR, we have not begun to see breakage in the credited market beyond five years.</p>
          <p>And the reason why I'm saying five years, as you know the FDIC is insuring new bank paper three years or less. And so the five year area, which is very critical for small business loans, for the mortgage industry, you know, we are still seeing very high interest rates. And I would recommend that everyone pays attention to the funding rates of these large national banks in the U.S. and other players as to what their funding rate is to see if there is a true thawing in our capital markets to allow us to have a better Mainstreet market.</p>
          <p>The last thing I'd like to just alert everyone is that is in the high yield area.  The high yield area triple B index as of this morning is 950 basis points over comparable treasuries.  So we're talking about, we're talking close to 13% for double Bs and we're talking a spread of 14.25 for the high yield index over treasuries.  So we're talking about interest rates that are exceedingly wide, they represent in many cases some very good value. But this is just a indication of the stresses in the marketplace and we have to just take note of that and when these markets start unthawing I believe we'll start seeing a better economy and hopefully with that unthawing we're going to see better flows and a better equity market going forward.  Let me get into the specifics without talking about the world and just but I do believe we needed to talk about where BlackRock is positioned in the world.</p>
          <p>As Ann Marie suggested, our AUMs fell about 12%.  We feel affirm to be exact, we fell by 169 billion dollars, which is an awful painful number.  109 billion of that was market, between market and FX, which is another way of market in my mind and the $53 billion was liquidity, which I'll get into in a minute and 6 billion dollars was long dated assets which was in my mind a very large surprise for us.  But if you look into the details, about a $9 billion client terminated us because of a merger.  They merged into another insurance company and they managed the assets internally.  This is something that we were aware of for 6 to 9 months.  We were hoping to have a portion of it be managed internally and they have decided to keep it all internally.  So away from that one problem, you know, overall we were fine and I'll go into some of the other outflows.</p>
          <p>Some of it was international equities where the retail business in Europe has been very, very hostile, and we've actually done very well in a very hostile environment.  The one thing I am particularly proud of Ann Marie discussed is our operating income of 209 was very strong and it is an indication of despite the hostile market environment BlackRock has been able to incrementally add revenues, be it BlackRock solutions or other types of assignments to be additive to our operating platform.  And obviously we were very -- that's been offset by a $0.58 loss in our non operating income.  Let me talk about the liquidity business and at BlackRock.</p>
          <p>First of all, while we were on this conference call the Federal Reserve has announced a new facility for liquidity funds.  This is something that the industry has been working on diligently now for the last three weeks.  This is a very big event.  In my mind, this is going to help commercial paper.  This is the first thawing that I really see in terms of helping the commercial paper market unravel itself.  This is creating a -- a conduit facilities in which we will be able to, if necessary, sell commercial paper into the conduit, the conduit will repackage the commercial paper into ABCP, which is a legal asset that the Federal Reserve can acquire and buy and then -- but it provides liquidity if necessary to the liquidity funds.</p>
          <p>Why this is so important because of the fears of illiquidity because of the fears of outflows that we witnessed last quarter, which we're starting to see a reverse this quarter money market funds have refused to extend any commercial paper beyond a day or a few days.  This has put enormous, enormous stress on the commercial paper market, enormous stress on corporations funding their liquidity needs and this facility in our mind is going to be one of the -- a great event in terms of creating the unthawing of the commercial paper market.  It will allow people like BlackRock and other money market funds to start extending our purchases of CP if we think that's appropriate investment to do, we believe that duration is the appropriate duration to have for our money market funds and it gives us the flexibility.</p>
          <p>We are not reliant on illiquidity in the marketplace, we can now take on more responsibility of trying to unglue the marketplace, we can take on commercial paper way beyond one day, if we want 180 day or whatever, we can buy that paper now, knowing that we will ultimately have some form of liquidity at the back-end.  So we look at this as a very big facility.  As I said, we've been working on it very strongly and I just wanted to emphasize that because it just broke while we were on the -- on this call.</p>
          <p>So having the large outflows, all the large outflows was in the prime rate funds.  As Ann Marie suggested our average assets are much higher than our spot assets.  Most of the outflows occurred in the last three weeks, certainly right after the reserve fund broke the dollar and after the Lehman Brothers bankruptcy, which caused tremendous disruptions in the industry.  The industry loss over $400 billion net, that's after the run-up in government funds.  BlackRock and a few other firms had about similar outflows without getting to the other names, our -- if you asked me why we had these significant outflows, we were one of the biggest winners in terms of growth in the money market industry.</p>
          <p>We had opened up many new portals working on institutional portals with different platforms.  And I would say because of the fears in the marketplaces it was these portals that experienced the greatest amount of outflows and so we were particularly harmed working with some of these portals in our direct access to our clients we probably had more stability than through these portal platforms where we are participating in.  If we had more retail platform assets we would have probably had less outflows because a good majority of the outflows were in the institutional side.</p>
          <p>As Ann Marie suggested we have now witnessed over 12 billion dollar of inflows in the first three weeks of October.  So there certainly is growing stability in the money market business.  I believe there's a great future for firms like BlackRock in the money market business.  We were very responsive to our clients.  There was not one day in which we delayed payments to our clients.  There was not one day that we were frightened of any issue of having any one of our clients fearful of breaking the dollar.  Our credit team in the liquidity side performed brilliantly.</p>
          <p>And so we believe we will be a larger player in the liquidity management business in the future and we are starting -- and we believe we can position ourselves in that way.  I do believe the one lesson to be learned, especially with the reserve fund, is I believe these small little orphaned money market funds are going to be very vulnerable, I believe larger platforms are going to be the net beneficiaries, the well capitalized firms are going to be the biggest beneficiaries.  So I believe there's still much to be changed in the liquidity business and I believe, we will see a consolidation in a very large scale in the liquidity business.  In fixed income, it's fair to say performance has been mixed, in some product areas very strong, some product areas very weak.</p>
          <p>What I can say, though, across almost all platforms we've done better than most of our competitors in terms of this, and we are winning some large assignments.  Most recently, we made a presentation a little sheepishly where in one of the products we were 300 under the benchmark.  We won because the terminated manager was 1200 under.  And so, I'm not here to suggest we're proud of what we have done, I'm not here to suggest we don't have much room to improve, we do, but I believe our risk management platform, our ability to minimize and mitigate risk and fixed income has proven to be successful, albeit not successful enough. And we have -- this is something we can't be proud of, but it's something that we are on a net-net-net versus our competitors, we've done fairly well in terms of that.  In equities, we had some great opportunities and great disappointments.  The opportunities we continued to differentiate ours in our global allocation fund and we continue to be one of the largest net in flows in that product area globally.  It has been a very large win.</p>
          <p>Our team has done exceedingly well in the up and down markets and calming investors as this has been a very large growth fund for us.  Dennis Stattman and team have navigated quite successfully in terms of trying to minimize exposures.  As we see meltdowns globally as you look at the emerging markets have melted much more than the US markets, in some cases down as much as 70%.  India down 50%, China down 50%.  So when you think about the market disallocations globally and having our global allocation fund mindfully doing much better than some of the giant pit falls and keeping our clients calm it's been a very strong positioning for us and I believe it will position us well for the future.</p>
          <p>The second area where we are just beginning to see some real nice inflows and that is our European equity team.  This is a team that came over to us a year ago.  We've had great relative performance.  This is actually the single category the greatest outflows in Europe.  And yet we are now because of our performance we're starting to see some real inflows and I believe as the markets start unthawing in Europe and as equity flows begin to turn positive in Europe this will be one of the large, large products that we will grow in the future.</p>
          <p>Some of our large NAV declines, though, which are obviously disappointing are in the areas that we did so well for the last year and a half.  I think as I suggested in many other conference calls we have always had a very strong positioning in our natural resource funds, our energy, mineral and mining funds.  But if you haven't noticed these are the products that have probably gone down as much as financial institution products.  Metals and minings and products are down in some cases 50, 60%.  And this is some of the reasons why we had a larger NAV declines in the last quarter because of the breakdown in these product areas.  It is not because of bad performance, it is just a function of how we're positioned and we have large exposures in the energy and mining area and we continue to believe having a large platform in these products in the long run will prove to be a good business strategy.</p>
          <p>But these are some of the areas that are offsetting some of the great strengths that we are building upon in equities.  In alternatives, I think it's fair to say there's not one product that alternatives have done well unless you call treasury bills and alternatives.  Hedge funds, private equity real estate all are under extreme pressure, our funds were under pressure.  We continue to believe in the alternative space, we believe they're going to be a huge washout in hedge funds. We believe they're going to be a very large washout in private equity and this is where our clients are asking so many questions as so many of our clients rushed into alternatives in many cases some of our clients be it pension funds or endowments have 30 to 50% of their assets in alternatives.  I don't think any of them expected to have these type of setbacks in terms of declines and NAV but I think more certainly no one ever expected to see such illiquidity.  So I think one of the lessons to be learned will be a greater appreciation for liquid assets and I do believe a lesson to be learned will be clients are going to be -- are going to have a more conservative portfolio.</p>
          <p>I am still a believer in alternatives, I believe there are going to be great opportunities for successful hedge fund strategies. I'm actually very bullish on real estate strategies as I believe in some of the real estate platforms, especially multi-family will be a product that will be able to provide coupon and some price appreciation.  Albeit, it's going to be much lower than historical returns for these product areas but I do believe real estate will provide a very safe platform for a lot of investors.  Let me break out retail and institutional businesses.  As I said earlier in terms of what's going on in Europe, we did see outflows in our equity platform of $4.4 billion in our international retail platform.  This is not something we're proud of but I could give you some statistics as of August.  Unfortunately the European industries have not provided us with the September numbers.  But as of the end of August year to date outflows and equities in Europe and I'm not talking about European equities I'm talking about the mutual fund platforms in Europe, outflows as an industry, not at BlackRock, were 68 billion dollars in equity outflows.  As of August, we had 2.5 billion dollars.  We actually have gone up in the rankings in terms of the largest mutual fund platforms in Europe.</p>
          <p>As of August, I don't know what September is, because I haven't seen the numbers, as of August we are now ranked the second largest mutual fund platform in Europe.  This is up from like six when we did our merger two years ago.  So we continue to build, we continue to enjoy greater presence, we continue to drive more and more business, albeit in a much more hostile environment.  In the U.S., I'm pleased to say despite much outflows we have $1.4 billion in net in flows in Europe -- in U.S. retail.  Our team continues to build our strength in third party distribution and some of the large third party distributors where we were ranked as low as 18th place we are now ranked as high as their place with external managers and we continue to build a very strong presence with third party -- with the third party platforms.  For those who were following us when we announced our merger two years ago, we said this is going to be one of the large year opportunities for BlackRock and I could say fairly, we are achieving those opportunities and we are differentiating ourselves.  Our goals in the next year are to continue to build out this area even with the hostile equity markets.</p>
          <p>We hope to be expanding our footprint in the independent channels in the retail space.  We believe this is a very important point for us to continue to build out.  So overall, retail flows are negative but overall we believe we're well positioned and we're looking forward to continue to build out that platform.</p>
          <p>On the institutional side, we are clearly differentiating ourselves.  We have had conference call sometimes twice a week conference call globally with our clients.  Our clients are looking to BlackRock more than ever before to help them understand what does this all mean?  And we, as I said, we've had these weekly because every week has been transformational changes in our business environment, transformational changes in how we should be looking at the future and our clients are looking to BlackRock to provide more and more leadership for them.  And I believe we are doing this.  We are very well positioned to continue to build out our platform, we are involved as you saw in our pipeline, which I'll discuss a little later, very involved in some very large searches and wins.  And so I'm not here to suggest institutional clients have not frozen, I am not here to suggest in the month of September and actually in the first few weeks of October many clients from sovereign wealth funds to insurance companies globally, clients were frozen and asking what does this all mean. Clients globally were reassessing what does it mean for them and how should they be looking at the environment.  I can tell you now, we are starting to see clients acting more proactive questions how to better utilize their cash, how to better utilize their investment strategy and most importantly, what should BlackRock be doing for them?</p>
          <p>So I look -- I do believe we're very well positioned globally with our institutional client base.  BlackRock Solutions, obviously in the news a lot.  We continue to differentiate ourselves in a very large way.  We are involved with so many large visible assignments.  This is an area that, you know, we could not be more proud of.  They have risen to the occasion ever time.  The team I don't believe has had a weekend now for six months.  There's no such thing as weekends.  I feel sorry for some of them, I apologize publicly to them and their families because they've missed a lot of weekends with their families to get the job done.  But most importantly our clients are respecting us, our clients are looking for us to do more.  We are involved in some very sensitive discussions with our clients, we're involved in very large advisory assignments and how to rebalance clients balance sheets and potentially we're -- we will be involved in some very large assignments that require either forms of liquidation of assets or, B, restructuring of assets and liabilities.</p>
          <p>We are very proud of year to date winning 52 new assignments in this base and 60 new assignments in the last quarter.  We have been a beneficiary of some of our -- some of the downsizing of Wall Street because we've been able to hire some people to be very additive to our existing team.  So whereby in the last few quarters I've said, you know, we were being stretched.  Well, I'm here to say we are still being stretched but we have so much more capacity today than we did last quarter.  And we're taking on these assignments even as of today I'm aware of another new assignment and evaluating another 20 billion dollars balance sheet of another institution that is sitting with some problems.  I would also like to just announce which we announced earlier that it is the addition of impact to our BlackRock solution space.  It is going to give us far better functionality in the equity risk management space.  Hopefully by early next year as we integrate that technology on to the Aladdin system we'll be able to provide functionality in all credit areas and in equity areas, and I believe it will give us much more opportunities to build larger, more comprehensive relationships.</p>
          <p>I also believe with some of our clients who have already had the Aladdin platform on their platform they're going to be looking to add possibly the equity component to it.  And impact did bring some very large clients globally to us and hopefully we'll be able to add some functionality in the fixed income space for those clients.  So we continue to play a large role.  We're involved in some very important discussions right now.  I believe this will continue to differentiate us for the coming year and I believe we will continue to build a more important platform in this space.</p>
          <p>Last few things I just want to add.  Pipeline, pipeline remains to be very strong.  We mentioned earlier $12.5 billion of new cash mandates, $14 billion new fixed income assets, $3.2 billion of equity mandates.  I will say, though, we have about a  1.05 billion in outflows in alternatives though.  We are seeing some of our inner fund to fund spaces outflows, we are seeing some of our single strategy funds some outflows and I think this is an industrywide issue.  I think our outflows are actually fractionally smaller than -- than the industry itself.  And then we are one more big BlackRock solutions advisory assignment that should fund sometime, I thought it was going to fund last quarter, should fund this quarter for about $32 billion.</p>
          <p>On a non operating side, Ann Marie spoke about that very loudly, loss of $0.58 or 6% of the NAV of a 1.3 billion .  I think it's -- I can say very clearly about 98% of those losses should come back to at least break even.  Ann Marie did suggest in many of those products we have term law assets, term liabilities and term equity.  We have no mismatch but because we're a GP we do mark to market everything and in the three cases where we've had some extreme mark to market changes I can tell you, the cash flows that we projected in terms of the payment stream to ourselves and to our clients are actually better.  The default and delinquencies on these big pools of mortgages are actually less than what we forecasted. And yet the marketplace has continued to drive down some of the prices obviously in the market calamities with the Lehman failure and with the now the deleveraging of hedge funds, who were big buyers in these products only four months ago have become huge sellers of these products now as they are deleveraging.  We believe this impairment is temporary and we believe we will get most of this back.  Out of the entire losses in our non-operating platform over the course I believe there's less than 9 billion dollars of what I would define as probably real losses that may be permanently, you know, in terms of real losses.</p>
          <p>So we do have some losses, I'm not here to suggest we don't have some, but the majority is purely a mark-to-market issue and I'm very comfortable with the assets and our strategies within our platform and I can tell you very clearly, our clients who are investing in these products are fine, too.  They understand the vagaries of mark-to-market and they see the cash flow characteristics and they're meeting their exactly what we have forecasted and what they have forecasted.</p>
          <p>So in conclusion, I think BlackRock is differentiating ourselves more than ever.  I think we're differentiating and I should state we're differentiating in a positive way more than ever.  I believe we have some great opportunities to build a better future.  I believe we are -- we should take a lot of pride in all of the calamities in the marketplace, we're doing a very good job in risk avoidance.</p>
          <p>We've navigated very tight, a very tight procedures in terms of risk mitigation.  Our risk management teams under Ben Golub have done a very unbelievable job in terms of helping us minimize our exposures, maximizing our knowledge of where we have exposures and helping us navigate and mitigate any problems in these hostile times.  I believe much of the hostile times in terms of -- in terms of insolvency is behind us.  I believe what the national banks have done globally in terms of putting capital into the bank -- banking systems of the various nations and two, by guaranteeing their debts for a period of time, have really minimized the insolvency risk that we just had very loud in the first -- in the month of August and September. And certainly the first part of October.</p>
          <p>I believe the credit markets are going to stabilize because we don't have that fear in the bond market of insolvency today. And I believe now we've just got to get back to lending and hopefully the actions of the Federal Reserve and commercial paper will get us back to lending to corporations on a CP level. With the declines of LIBOR we'll start to see inner bank lending start to pick up and we will see a unlocking of the credit markets and through that unlocking of the credit markets despite a recession that we're going to be facing with the equity markets can stabilize, too.  So with that, I want to thank you all the employees of BlackRock.  I know this has been a tough quarter.  I'd like to thank all our shareholders.  This was a tough quarter for you, too, but I could tell you very clearly we are in a very good position to take advantage of the opportunities that the new global capital markets will give us.  And we're well positioned to take that position and run with it.  Thank you very much.  We'll open it up for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  Your first question comes from the line of Hojoon Lee of Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a question on Quellos and your outlook on hedge fund more broadly.  I think the industry had something like 31 billion in outflows in the third quarter so about 5% annualized rate.  Can you give us a sense of how flows were at Quellos maybe in terms of kind of sales and redemption behavior?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know if I have that here.  We can do that offline.  I would -- I know we had some good inflows and we had some outflows.  As I told you in our -- I have somebody looking at that.  We don't break it out.  Net -- so we are flat net in the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  How does that compare to the first half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First half we have in flows probably.  Hold on, I'll get it.  So year to date we were positive 1, 3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And one question on BlackRock Solutions.  I think a quarter ago you commented around some of the human power or potential capacity issues there, given your very busy with new mandates.  Could you give us a sense of where you stand there and, how much growth you think you could support with the current infrastructure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said earlier, we have hired a number of people.  We've added a lot more depth in our Solutions space.  We have more capacity today than we've ever had before.  That is not to say that we're not working weekends and weeknights and, but we are in a good position to take on more business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you don't see any slowdown in the momentum you've had over the last several quarters there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the contrary, I think we've seen a rapid speed up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.  And just my last question, with respect to TARP [Troubled Asset Relief Program], I mean, from the perspective of acquiring assets for your clients, could you discuss some of the types of products or opportunities you're focusing on and maybe help us bracket how much business that could potentially generate on the asset management side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know, first of all, the Treasury has not finalized who are the selected managers.  Hopefully that will be done shortly.  Hopefully, BlackRock is one of the participants of the plan.  We certainly have submitted many different submissions, RFPs.  So, until I know more about it and until we know if we are one of the selected firms, it's very hard for me to describe what it means.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have a sense of timing in terms of when you should be hearing about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is my expectation, and only mine, I would say it's days away.  Listening to the Secretary of the Treasury, from his public statements is he wants to do things quickly and in our conversations with Treasury I believe it is fair to say they do want to do some things quickly, so it should be days, maybe a week until, we'll know as to the game plan of the TARP.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Larry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of William Katz of Buckingham Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone.  Thanks for the broad based comments. Tough to follow-up with some questions off that, but just a few. Just following up on the TARP, sort of lot of speculation around the economics of the business, sort of wondering if you could help frame how we should be thinking about the earnings impact from any mandates that you might win?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will be good if we win.  I really don't want to get into it. I don't like talking about businesses that we may or may not win.  Clearly if we do win, I believe -- I think it's fair to say that margins are going to be lower for TARP business than other products.  I think without getting into too much detail in our submission, which I'm not here to suggest we're going to win but in our submission we did assume that margins are going to be much smaller than other product areas.  But also we did assume that, you know, the size that each manager will have to manage will be quite large and, you know, so it should turn into a good business.  But, you know, I think it's appropriate that the managers work for a very tight spread in these markets to help the economy unlock itself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would that include any type of performance fees subject to workout?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're assuming they are going to do performance fees and I don't know if anyone knows what the type of -- how the Treasury will design the advisory management fees.  I don't think we know that yet.  Maybe somebody does know, and they won and we didn't.  I don't know.  We'll find out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Second question is on performance fees, given all your commentary both leading into the quarter and on today's conference call, I'm surprised there's any sizeable performance fees, maybe just a little description on where these fees came from? And then just so as we look forward apart from just the outflow accelerating a little bit into the new quarter, how should we think about high water marks and go forward performance fees?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good question.  Performance fees in some of the performance fees some of them were struck at the end of September and that's why we had some performance fees going forward in the third quarter.  Going forward, high water mark depending on the products area could be they're going to be some areas, some funds we have a 5 to 7% high water mark hurdle and some of them it could be 20 to 30% depending on some of the energy funds.  I would imagine --I don't have it specifically but I know what has happened in the last few months.  So they can be significant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So last question, just sort of follows-up on your commentary about consolidation in the money market business.  Just sort of wondering, given what seems to be kind of like becoming utility and financial services globally now based on the nationalization of the banks, et cetera, would you envision just broader based consolidation among asset managers and if so would you be thinking about roll-ups now in addition to any other product specific things going on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, I think up until last week everybody was worried about solvency and stability.  I don't think there was a moment in which anyone was focusing on mergers other than quick defensive ones.  But I think as we restabilize our markets, which I believe will be happening, I believe they're going to be huge opportunities in the investment management business consolidation.</p>
          <p>So let's think about this, Bill.  The setback in equities with global equities down about 40% and U.S. equities at around 33%, companies, small companies are not going to be able to survive this. They're not going to be able to afford be it the credit research, or the equity research or risk management, with the idea that we're all going to have more regulation and more cost associated with the regulation going forward, and I think that's a certainty within 6 months of the New Year.  I believe there's going to be a great need for consolidation in the investment management business.</p>
          <p>I believe more than ever before brand name global platform multi-products are going to be more important than ever.  So boutiques, whether they're just a boutique in money markets, boutiques in bonds, boutiques just in equities I believe it's going to be a hard model to build a platform.  And so I -- I believe we will have at BlackRock as much opportunity to do consolidation and roll-ups than we've ever had in the past. And I would tell you we've had more inquiries recently about merger opportunities than we've ever had, albeit I would say we have not really begun any of the conversations because I think it was inappropriate to focus on those things until we felt more stable.  But I do believe once the stability is back in our marketplace a higher degree of confidence in the executive and board levels of the various firms we are going to see a huge consolidation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks very much, Larry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Roger Smith with FPK [Fox-Pitt Kelton].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey Roger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Thanks a lot for taking the question.  I guess really hat I want to understand is how flexible really is the expense model on a go forward basis? Because it sounds like what you guys really want to do is continue to build out the business quite a bit and we've seen AUMs come down again so far in the third quarter so how should we really think about those expenses going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good question. I think it's fair for me to tell you that we are looking at all expenses right now.  We are actually looking at our business model, the areas that we're going to be emphasizing a growing and quite frankly there's some businesses that we are going to downsize and there may be a business that we may get out of.  I mean, there are going to be &#x2013; we --on Thursday I have my operating committees and executive committee meeting.  We've had many meetings already looking and addressing all those issues and I believe that's -- we have to be in front of all that, we have to be from a top downward look, looking at areas that we need to grow and we're going to continue to build out those areas.</p>
          <p>And I could think about our BlackRock Solutions space we've got to continue to grow, our independent advisory push into our retail space will have to continue to grow, those areas that would be foolish not to continue to invest.  There's other areas without naming them right now that we are going to have to reduce.  And we will.  And we are looking at -- we are looking at all ways of minimizing and reducing our expenses going into the next year and I think that's the only appropriate thing to do.  I can tell you we are very much in front of it, Roger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Great.  Thanks.  And then on the performance fees, I know that Bill just talked about them a little bit more.  Is there any performance fees that would be tied to relative performance or are there any longer term performance fees that would perhaps sort of been accumulating over some period of time that we should be thinking about coming into...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had some long data performance fees in real estate up until probably the last 6 months we've had growing NAV but real estate has fallen, too, but that's more of an absolute, that's relative to the NAFRI Index so there are a few of them.  But most of them are absolute.  But some of them are a three year rolling fee. So a three year review, how we perform.  So some of them are not just in a month to month, they're longer dated in terms of how we are performing and so some of those we may have still growing performance fees. Ann Marie?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to say in the third quarter really the bulk of our performance fees came from hedge funds out of our EMEA region and then on a growing basis we do get performance fees on separate accounts that do take into account relative performance methods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay great. And just on the alternative business or the fund to funds business at Quellos, it does seem like there's a lot of discussion in the marketplace about a potential outflows and it seems like the high net worth client base I guess is getting somewhat nervous and  the institution allocations are kind of moving higher.  How does the fund to funds business at Quellos really prepare itself for redemption levels that might be coming in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know you're identifying it as Quellos, we call it BAA now so it isn't Quellos.  You know, no different than how we prepare ourselves in money market liquidations.  I mean, we talk to our managers, who we're working with, we identify that, we --you try to stay in front of it, we try to give notifications to our managers in advance with the idea that we may have excess cash.  But you've got to stay in front of it and I think this is why we have such a tremendous market decline in the last part of September and early October where a lot of fund to funds and a lot of managers were giving excess notice in anticipation of outflows and so that's what you're saying.  I -- it's just knowing your clients, talking to your clients as to what are their needs, finding out what their expectations are and then going back and managing your cash and liquidity with your managers accordingly.  And as you know, on the institutional side, most of it is 60 plus days notice for redemption, so you have time to plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.  Fair enough.  I guess and then the last question --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's reflective in my pipeline, when we talked about outflows some of the outflows were there.  So when we said earlier in our BAA platform we basically are flat for the quarter and up for the year but we are forecasting, you know, as I said the entire alternative space about a billion five of outflows.  So that's it, our pipeline number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough.  Lastly on the redemptions of the money market time assets, you know, where did that money really go, because I would have assumed that you guys could have kept some of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know, it went to our government funds and if you go, if you asked Jamie Dimon [JPMorgan Chase] and other banks how much deposits they received, keep in mind bank deposits are guaranteed and so the giant banks were the biggest beneficiary in this flood outside the money market industry.  I mean, this was an industry outflow and it was -- and keep in mind, a lot of the money that we manage is for other financial institutions.  So they actually pulled their money back, too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So when you manage portal money, some of the portal money is for other small banks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.  I know, fair enough.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And they're pulling all their liquidity to keep it there, too.  Much of it was fear.  I do believe the Fed action today is going to cause more stability in the primary funds. And will give the primary funds actually the ability now to invest longer, which in my mind will give more opportunities for the prime funds because the yield spread between government and prime funds are so enormous but they were not so enormous because everybody was keeping their money so close to overnight money.  With this new platform it allows us to extend our maturities and really reap the benefits of the spread in commercial paper versus governments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Craig Siegenthaler of Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Craig.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking the call. Good morning.  Just a question on counterparty risk and how it really faces the industry, specifically with liability driven investing and also sec lending.  With the dislocation in the lending markets has the ability for LDI strategies to hedge future liabilities impacted I guess your investment process at all, and then on sec lending I'm just wondering if traditional fixed income strategies actually lend out these securities enhanced yield? And is there any risk of selling these assets at distressed prices as leverage is brought in here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think to answer your last question, I think we've seen so much just hedge fund liquidations and unwinding of leveraged platforms is one of the big reasons why we've had such a tremendous decline in some of these asset categories.  In terms of sec lending, we continue to see as we said $12 billion of our outflows in liquidity was sec lending.  We're a very small player in sec lending, I think our balance today is about $6 billion in sec lending, it is not a major portion of our business.  We are doing it as an adjunct of our equity platform but it is a very small component of our business and it will remain to be a very small component of our business.  It only pays us about a basis point anyway, so in terms of fees it's very de minimis.</p>
          <p>And in terms of counterparty risk for LDI, obviously, we pay attention to that.  Our risk team, our Chief Risk Officer, Ben Golub, and team, they spend a lot of time looking at our entire counterparty risk and that is a counterparty risk on behalf of our client so we look at every swap, we analyze every type of risk we have.  And there is no question during the last three weeks of September after the bankruptcy of Lehman, the first couple weeks of October, we were very frightened of some large exposures we had with some institutions that were stumbling.  And you know, we were doing a lot to mitigate that during that time.  As I said, everybody over the course of this four week tsunami many, many people were spending a lot of time trying to just mitigate risk and manage risk downward instead of trying to look for investment opportunities.  We did a great job in navigating that.  As I said, we did not have -- we did not have any issues with our money market funds, we did not have any issues with counterparty risk with any of our swap parties and so we actually are well positioned in that and we stayed in front of all those issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then Larry with your money market business I notice your fee rates are actually, or your profitability process has actually improved over the last year.  When I look at the product one year forward with increased regulation, potential premiums to a U.S. government or third party, possible rating agency regulation, maybe even capital charges because there is kind of -- for some asset management there is kind of imbedded capital charge to support these funds for the funds that have broken the buck. But I'm just wondering, do you see profitability declining off these products going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  But first of all, regulatory issues is a relative for everybody in the world and I don't think we're going to be adversely harmed in it, actually I think we'll be on a relative basis we're going to look -- we're much better prepared for that.  In terms of &#x2013; well my general counsel says fees are paid by the funds anyway on that, on the insurance.</p>
          <p>But let me -- in terms of capital charges, we are the first to believe -- to have reserves for losses in money market funds.  We have been fighting our auditors and this is now a public admonishment of my auditors who have done a very fine job. They're listening, so I can tell them again, for the last 10 years we always believed we should have reserves for money market funds because it is the firm's responsibility and we don't indeed want to break the dollar.  So we have always been -- we've been always very much in favor of a -- of having some form of capital that is reserved for money market funds.  Quite frankly, we were not allowed to ever put a reserve down because BlackRock never had a credit loss up until our <mark type="inaudible" /> funds of last year where we had 35 million dollar charge in our cash strategy fund.</p>
          <p>So I guess definitionally that means it's a higher cost of doing business if we did reserve something for our capital charges for money market funds we would welcome it, we believe it's another reason why you're going to see consolidation, it is another why you need to have large scale assets for liquidity to make the appropriate returns.  So all those issues do not frighten me, in fact they give us a greater -- gives me a greater comfort that we'll be one of the leaders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thanks a lot for taking my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Prashant Bhatia of Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello Prashant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Larry you talked about the washout you think that's coming on the alternative asset side.  I guess one, do you have a feel for just a quantity, the amount of AUM that could move out of the space?  And I guess, two, once the fear subsides where do you think that AUM actually flows to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, I don't.  I believe it's going to be very hard for small hedge funds to survive.  I think it's going to be hard even for some large hedge funds to survive.  You are going to have a washout.  I think monoline firms -- I know everybody, especially hedge funds were railing on monoline finance companies but nobody was railing on monoline hedge funds and, I believe there's going to be a greater need for institutions that have broad based products to survive.  Where the money will go actually I think more and more money will go into the traditional products again back into equities.</p>
          <p>As you saw in the first six months Prashant, the greatest outflows were in large cap space in the U.S. area.  And I do believe they're just massive opportunities in the credit markets; we've never seen yield spreads like this and so once there is a stability, the returns, the opportunities you have from corporate credits, how about as I said five year bank paper at 9%.  And another bank at 8%.</p>
          <p>To me the opportunities are quite extraordinary now for those who are trying to reduce risk in some of the alternative space to move into more traditional products that are -- that we have yields or returns that are something we dreamed about over the last 10 years.  So I believe it spells -- it's going to be a very large opportunity once again for those boring non -- boring traditional asset managers but those asset managers that are positioned in a global setting to take advantage of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then based on that, the investment portfolio that you have about a billion 9ish, I think, is that a portfolio, is that the right size based on the environment here?  Would you consider shrinking that portfolio or can you actually grow it here?  What is the right size?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the portfolio size you're talking about is gross of minority.  We like to think about it net.  Are you talking about the -- you're talking about our co-investments, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'm talking about the 1.9 billion total investment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>1.4 billion</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Net of minority interest at the end of the second quarter, that was about 1.4 billion.  And so we tend to think of it net.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I guess the question you're asking is we hope we have as much opportunity in the future as we did to co invest with our investors and our clients. And so to me that is a -- despite the setbacks we've had in NAVs, to me that is a major components of our engine of growth for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To co-invest with our investors in these alternative products, especially with the opportunities we have in bank loans and distressed debt, in preferred stocks, in bank credit.  I mean bank credit today is ridiculously cheap so there's just going to be great opportunities in that if out investors are looking for BlackRock to co invest with them we will.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  On one of those, I think the UBS portfolio that you're managing could you just give us an update on how that's performing versus plan, maybe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>According to our forecast of defaults and delinquencies, we expected a cash flow return in the 18ish percent.  The cash flow returns are actually 18.4.  And so the defaults and delinquencies are approximately what we thought they were, and so the cash flows are very strong and so obviously it's only five or six months.  However, because the fund is levered, and there has been a decay in the mark to market of these assets, there's been about a 30% decay in NAV in those type of products just because of the leverage and they're down on a mark to market, the assets are down about 9ish percent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  But if the defaults continue to track...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're going to get all the money back, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You'll get it back. Yeah..</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Here's an example of accounting questions.  I mean, we have term equity in this and term liability.  There is no mismatch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And yet we have to mark to market.  I hope my auditors are still listening to that one, too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then do you have a view on whether Banc of America will keep the investment in BlackRock or is that too early at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  I've had numerous conversations with Ken Lewis, the CEO of Banc of America.  I think he's very excited about working alongside BlackRock.  But we have not had any conversations yet.  You know, I could tell you in the next few weeks we will begin our conversations with Banc of America, and I'm sure they're going to be very positive.  And as I said, our positioning within Banc of America is going to be strong.  As you know, with Merrill Lynch on a change of control, our global distribution agreement extends by five years at the date of closing.  So we have this very strong position within the Banc of America platform.  I think we're well positioned.  We're working very closely with the entire Merrill Lynch system and we look forward to working very closely with the entire Banc of America system to help their shareholders and to continue to nurture BlackRock shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And just on the investment portfolios you get called into evaluate a lot of different portfolios across the industry.  Can you just give some color on are there still areas or asset classes that are being mismarked and what types of asset classes there are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I actually wouldn't say mismarked, actually in the most recent appraisals we're looking at, marks are, I would say people are getting closer and closer to the fair value marketing than ever before.  I think where you're going to have greater, greater -- well, let me state it two ways.  I think certainly in the subprime area you're seeing marks are approximate now throughout the market.  I think in the areas like the option arms there's a huge disparity between one evaluator and another evaluator.  We've seen some people believing they're worth in the '60s and some people believe they're worth in the 40s.  And so there is still some large disagreements in terms of evaluation of option arms.  We are beginning to see more stress and more consumer like products and HELOC loans, more stress obviously coming from credit cards.  So we are not -- some of the more visible problems are in the healing process.  But I think in some of the more consumer oriented products there's probably still more pain to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we have reached the allotted time for questions.  I will now turn the conference back over to Mr. Fink for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>So once again, thank you.  This is a long conference call.  As I said this is the best of times and worst of times.  It doesn't feel good to see the NAV erosions that we've seen, it doesn't feel good to see the outflows in liquidity, but nevertheless I actually believe the entire BlackRock platform was very severely tested and we won.  It doesn't feel like a big win today, but I do believe the organization, all our employees have done a great job in mitigating problems. Have done a very good job in hand holding our clients who are our ultimate -- who and that is the life blood of our future, hand holding our clients, and I believe we're positioned to build stronger relationships with our clients globally.  Thank you everyone.  I'll talk to you in a quarter.  Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's conference call.  You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>