<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1244652" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-21</date>
    <companies>
      <company>812</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Robert P. Connolly, Managing Director and General Counsel</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Ann Marie Petach, Managing Director and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Laurence D. Fink, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">William Katz</participant>
      <participant id="5">Michael Carrier</participant>
      <participant id="6">Roger Freeman</participant>
      <participant id="7">Roger Smith</participant>
      <participant id="8">Craig Siegenthaler</participant>
      <participant id="9">Mike's</participant>
      <participant id="10">Doug Sipkin</participant>
      <participant id="11">Marc Irizarry</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Tina and I will be your conference facilitator today. At this time, I would like to welcome everyone to the BlackRock Incorporated Second Quarter 2009 Earnings Teleconference. Our host for today's call will be Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, Laurence D. Fink; Chief Financial Officer, Ann Marie Petach; and General Counsel, Robert P. Connolly. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. After the speakers' remarks there will be a question-and-answer period. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>Thank you. Mr. Connolly, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. This is Bob Connolly. I'm General Counsel of BlackRock. Before Larry and Ann Marie make their remarks, I want to point out that during the course of this conference call, we may make a number of forward-looking statements. We call to your attention the fact that BlackRock's actual results may differ from these statements.</p>
          <p>As you know, BlackRock has filed with the SEC reports, which lists the factors, which may cause our results to differ materially from these statements. Finally, BlackRock assumes no duty to and does not undertake to update any of these forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll turn it over to Ann Marie, our Chief Financial Officer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. I'll be discussing primarily as adjusted results. Second quarter net income was 239 million. That's a $1.75 per share and include $1.44 per share of operating earnings, $0.20 per share of non-operating income and $0.11 favorable associated with resolution of tax matters. Excluding the resolution of tax matters the tax rate was 35%. During the second quarter we saw substantial improvements in equity and fixed income markets compared to the first quarter. These improvements and market tone positively affected long-dated asset flows as investors began to pull out of cash and seek higher returns. While markets are still well below year ago levels, market improvement positively affected the revenue, operating income and non-operating income trends. At the same time we maintained cost discipline and continued to benefit from our diversified business model. Our strong pipeline including over 45 billion in long-dated assets combined with positive markets in July are a good start to continuing the positive momentum we experienced in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>AUM levels have done well over the past year. Despite market and foreign exchange driven declines on equity, balanced and alternative assets of about 25%, AUM declined only about 4% compared to a year ago, driven by over 90 billion of net new business. The net new business was supported by our strong advisory capability, which attracted new clients and assets, though admittedly at lower fee levels.</p>
          <p>Net income improved 117% compared to first quarter and was down 16% compared to a year ago. We have moved from non-operating losses to non-operating gains, as the balance sheet value of our co- and seed investments are recovering from the trough values in the first quarter. Revenues of $1.29 billion improved by 4% compared to the first quarter reversing a negative trend, which began in the third quarter of 2008. The improvement in revenues reflects both positive long-dated asset flows and positive market movement. Revenue declines compared to a year ago were driven by the decline in equity markets over the same period.</p>
          <p>BlackRock Solutions and advisory revenues remained strong at $116 million, albeit below the exceptional levels of the last two quarters as stabilizing markets have dampened the peak level of demand for short-term valuation and advisory work. BRS continues to have a strong pipeline of financial market advisory, Aladdin, and risk reporting opportunities.</p>
          <p>As adjusted, operating income of 302 million included 18 million of balance sheet related foreign currency effects. Excluding these effects and supported by expense initiatives, period-over-period operating income changed in line with revenue. Specifically, as compared to the first quarter, operating income improved 15 million or 5% excluding balance sheet related FX effects. Given the balance sheet effects are a spot measure, it is helpful to isolate them when assessing the operating trend, a trend which is clearly positive.</p>
          <p>We have maintained strong operating margins. The operating margin as adjusted of 34.4% included a two point drag related to the FX effect I just mentioned and also was affected by increased incentive compensation, driven by higher net income. Excluding hedged changes in deferred comp, compensation cost changes were driven by changes in incentive compensation and by reduced staffing levels. As I mentioned, we have increased the bonus accruals to reflect improvements in net income.</p>
          <p>G&amp;A expense reflected continued cost discipline and was about equal to the first quarter when you exclude the balance sheet related FX. Also GAAP G&amp;A expense included 15 million of costs related to the BGI transaction.</p>
          <p>We estimate total BGI integration costs in a range of 300 to 350 million, a range we'll be continuing to refine over the next several months. The key cost drivers will include transaction costs, professional fees, restructuring costs, technology synchronization, re-branding and marketing expense. I'd also remind you that with the new accounting standards, more costs are expensed then would have been historically, when they would have been capitalized.</p>
          <p>BlackRock co-invests with our clients. The majority of these co- and seed investments are marked-to-market through non-operating income. As adjusted non-operating income &#x2013; and it feels good to be saying income instead of losses &#x2013; were 42 million in the second quarter reflecting primarily improving spreads on distressed debt and positive movements in equity, we're still seeing a little bit of negative movement on the real estate front. This is a clear change in direction compared to recent quarters.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet exposure remains at levels greatly reduced from a year ago. Total value of the investment portfolio is about 775 million, or excluding items which really are acting as hedges of deferred comp or which are hedged themselves, this number is 675 million. Also of note, towards the end of the quarter, we issued a little more than two million of shares of common stock associated with the equity raised to fund the BGI transaction. We expect that other share issuances to be concurrent with the close of the transaction. We've got the cash invested in really high-quality, short-term instruments, and we'll keep it that way until close.</p>
          <p>So in summary second quarter results reflect positive business momentum, improved markets and market tone, as well as our disciplined approach. This positive momentum is continuing as we begin the third quarter, and we can see it both in the markets as well as in our very strong pipeline.</p>
          <p>With that I'll turn it over to Larry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Let me begin by stating the BlackRock business model is clearly working. As our clients worldwide began to accept that the global economies were not falling into the abyss, fear has dissipated and questions about asset allocation began. Clients asked should they keep as large of asset allocation in cash earning close to zero. In the fourth quarter and the first quarter of this year earning close to zero was better than losing capital in longer dated or higher earning assets.</p>
          <p>As we closed the second quarter, clients began to ask do they have too much cash. These questions are exactly what the Federal Reserve and other central bankers are looking for. They're looking for clients to start unlocking markets and starting to invest out long term, reinvesting back in the equity markets, and importantly looking for balance sheet lenders to begin to lend. I can't speak about balance sheet lenders beginning to lend, but I can clearly tell you globally clients worldwide are asking the question, can they take more risk in the future.</p>
          <p>And so, importantly these questions are being asked by BlackRock. Having a global, a fiduciary and independent platform, the global clients &#x2013; both institutionally and retail &#x2013; are asking BlackRock this question. Our comprehensive platform or risk analytics through BlackRock Solutions and our product range allows us to work with clients more than ever before. In these uncertain times our dialogue with our clients has never been more robust. The conversations in retail and institutional are really, really strong at this time.</p>
          <p>Let me review some of our results that I think speak loudly about our quarter and I believe our momentum going into the third quarter and into the end of the year. AUM for the quarter was up 7%, almost to a record level, which actually even surprised me. Our asset level was up to $1.373 trillion, and so if that is not an indication of the type of comprehensiveness we're having with clients and how our business model is working. Most importantly, unlike some of the trends of last year where so much clients left long-dated products into cash as fear was so enlarged, we saw in the second quarter $28.5 billion of long-dated inflows, of which it was basically split, basically through equities and fixed income which I'll talk about.</p>
          <p>As a result of this restructuring we did witness some outflows in cash, and our objective now is to try to get as much of that cash and try to find opportunities where those clients as they look to redeploy cash into longer dated or more risk earning assets. But clearly we saw long dated flows strong and we had about $7.5 billion of outflows in our cash management side. I think this reflects mostly industry trends. I don't think we're that unusual in that but we did see unusually large outflows in cash in our retail platform. Much of that has to do with because of the fees, and the essentially zero earning types of returns on cash which is an industry issue.</p>
          <p>In addition, we had about $2.6 billion of net outflows in our alternative space. We did have through the acquisition of our three headed added assets in our alternative area, but I can say at the end of the second quarter rolling into the third quarter we're now seeing a more robust outlook towards our fund of funds product. We had closed a fund of funds of private equity in the second quarter and we're starting to see new RFPs, new requests in our fund of funds of hedge funds and so for the first time it's clearly in about nine months we're seeing clients are looking again in the space of hedge funds for the first time in some time. And so overall, with the changes in liquidity and the alternatives, our net flows for the quarter was approximately 15.2 billion.</p>
          <p>Let me break it out by product for a moment. In our fixed income area, we had a very strong quarter; we had $15.5 billion of net inflows in the quarter. This has to do with performance which has been very strong year-to-date. Our performance is very strong certainly with the reversal of some of the credit markets and we've stood by some of those positions; and as a result of that we are seeing some very good return this year, very competitive returns and that's indicative in our flows. And we completed the integration of R3 in our fixed income unit and are quite proud of the integration and the retooling of our fixed income platform. The enthusiasm, the momentum that we see in our fixed income platform is very robust.</p>
          <p>Equity assets, because much of it to do with market was up $64 billion. However, we also saw a little over $15.6 billion of net inflows in our equity products. This is driven by some of our high-yielding equity products, high-return equity products. So we saw a great growth in our World Mining Funds, our emerging market products and equities, our global allocation products, and very large flows in our European equity products.</p>
          <p>Much of this has to do with some strong performance especially with some of our European products. And this is &#x2013; and our global allocation product and this is why we are seeing continued strong flows.</p>
          <p>On the cash management side as I discussed earlier, the near zero returns in cash. We are seeing clients questioning the amount of assets they have in cash and we are having dialogues with our clients as they are looking to redeploy assets. We had outflows as I discussed before but our job in the future is to try to recapture some of this movement from cash into other alternative space.</p>
          <p>I think this will be a trend in the cash management side for some time, especially if we start feeling even more comfortable after the summer months. I think it's important, if we continue to have strength in the equity markets and importantly if we have just global stability, I think you're going to see more movement from cash into longer-dated items in the fourth quarter of this year. And so, I am a believer that the markets are stabilizing and we're seeing that by evidenced by our clients worldwide.</p>
          <p>On BlackRock Solutions, we had 12 new assignments in the quarter. We had six completed short-term assignments, engagements to help clients understand their risks in their balance sheets. We had &#x2013; we completed one new Aladdin relationship and we have a very strong pipeline in new short-term assignments and importantly we're working on some very large Aladdin business. I would say in the latter part of the second quarter as markets stabilized the emergency room atmosphere in Solutions calmed down. Clients were not in weakened mode of trying to stabilize a balance sheet but more importantly now as clients are feeling more relaxed about the future not necessarily constructive, but less of an emergency room atmosphere.</p>
          <p>They're now asking more questions about how do we employ more substantive risk management tools so we don't have this problem again. And so we're involved with many conversations with more and more clients on our Aladdin system. And I would say another major trend for BlackRock with Aladdin space. Last year we did acquire an equity platform called Impact and we've rolled that into the Aladdin space and hopefully now and then in coming months we're going to be rolling out an equity component of our Aladdin space and we are now talking to some of our existing Aladdin clients to add their equity platform onto this space. This could be a very large movement for our Aladdin business. And I will talk about how BGI fits into Solutions in a little bit. But clearly, with its positioning in equities and quant equity this will really embrace our platform in the Aladdin space for equities.</p>
          <p>Our pipeline is very strong. We had about $46 billion of wins unfunded. Most of this is long-dated; I think this is a record amount in our history of long-dated wins unfunded. Much of these wins are more comprehensive relationships that are multi-asset strategy wins. By winning these large assignments, it confirms to me that scale is important, being global is important. And I'm more confident than ever before, clients are looking for fewer relationships. They're looking for more substantive relationships with a few. This is a real change in our business, in the business of asset management. Historically people were frightened of scale. Historically people were frightened of having too large of a relationship and we are clearly seeing this change where clients are very appreciative of all the products insights, global views, product views that we can offer to our clients.</p>
          <p>Let me just go over a few issues related to retail and institutional. Our retail platform is growing nicely; our brand recognition globally is growing very powerfully, our international retail products are up to $87 billion. On a rolling 12 months from May to May, that's the most recent data we have, our net sales in international retail, we are ranked number three worldwide, and we have very large momentum with our clients in terms of working on a distribution platform.</p>
          <p>More and more of our partners, distribution partners are looking again for fewer relationships and we've seen quite a bit of interest in having us talk to our clients related to our product range and now with the pending BGI transaction, our clients are asking for more meetings with us ever before in the retail space domestically and internationally.</p>
          <p>In the U.S. retail, we had very strong long-dated flows in equities and fixed income and very big outflows as I discussed earlier in the cash management side. But with the BGI product range and the iShare product range we believe which I'll discuss shortly some very large synergies between our platforms.</p>
          <p>Let me just bring up one other point related to institutional, very strong momentum in institutional. And much of this has to do with our strength in our fiduciary multi-asset class strategy and our taxable institution business. As I said this is a good part of our wins that we have in the pipeline and it has to do with the comprehensiveness of what we can bring, bringing a BlackRock Solutions, risk management solution alongside our full products range. And this is why we are seeing actually more solid RFPs and more multi-asset class strategy wins.</p>
          <p>We are in the process of two very large RFPs of greater than $10 billion and once again these are clients that are looking to have fewer relationships and a more exhaustive relationship. And so the trend institutionally continues, and I think some of the pundits out there who talk about scale and how scale is bad; I think they're going to be proven wrong. I think, scale, full range of products is going to be key for the successful model of asset management in the future.</p>
          <p>Let me briefly discuss the BGI integration. I have Mr. Connolly here who is going to tie me up if I say anything too exhaustive as we are in a process of going through the integration. In terms of closing we expect closing to be some time at the very, very late fourth quarter or at the very, very early part of the first quarter. We are in the process, we're working on all the regulatory signups and we have gotten some already, and the big issue is getting all the approvals for our mutual fund platform, making sure that we get all of the necessary shareholder approvals through a proxy solicitation which takes some time. This is actually consistent with our MLIM integration and timetable too. So, there is nothing inconsistent about the timing of this integration. But in a very short time we have traveled now to the majority of the large BGI offices.</p>
          <p>We have had teams of people from BGI here in New York and in our London office. We've had teams of people from BlackRock in BGI's main office in San Francisco. We've been to London. We've been to their Australian platform, their Hong Kong platform, their Tokyo platform, and it is very clear to all of us the opportunities of the combined firm are greater than we believed when we did the transaction. We see more revenue synergies today then we did when we announced the transaction. Obviously, we have a lot to do making sure that we achieve those, but the opportunities are even more thrilling to us than when we announced the transaction.</p>
          <p>We believe we are fully involved in the integration, which is going to take time. We have teams from BGI and teams from BlackRock working together business-by-business, product-by-product working on integration plans as we speak. And so in the very short period of time of our integration with BGI it's going as well as we've ever dreamed it could. We visited many clients who wanted to talk to us related to our proposed transaction and these are clients who've had either money with BlackRock, have money with BGI or have money with both. And I believe, I could say with probably 99% certainty, our clients are very excited about the combination.</p>
          <p>Even yesterday I was with one of the largest clients of our combined firm at a Board meeting in which the Board and the staff enthusiastically approved the transaction and saw great merit for them. This is happening more and more where clients are looking &#x2013; are seeing the opportunities, the synergistic opportunities of having the indexed products along side with the active products and with &#x2013; in between with our quantitative products that we can both bring together that we offer even a fuller range of products to our clients, retail and institutional.</p>
          <p>On the retail side, I'm particularly surprised at how some of our large distribution platforms have come to us and talk about how can we engage even a more fulsome relationship offering not just our active mutual fund products but also now the ETF products onto their platform. Clients are looking for &#x2013; are asking in asset allocation, how do they blend passive or indexed products with active products. I think we are seeing as a result of this of the collapse of the equity markets and the collapse of credit, we are seeing more clients taking a more conservative approach as they think about rebalancing.</p>
          <p>Clients are going to have probably overall a little less exposure than they did in alternatives and equities. So many clients had an under allocation and fixed income. And so where we think we're going to see and we're seeing evidence of that clients are going to &#x2013; are looking possibly to rebalance a little more into fixed income as an overall asset allocation. Now some of them because of the collapse of equity markets are already there as a percent and they're not just doing the rebalancing but clearly we're seeing clients looking towards a more conservative approach over the next few years in their asset allocations.</p>
          <p>In addition, clients are looking at passive strategies probably a little more than they did before, not that active strategies are a problem. In fact, I think as an industry active strategies are doing quite well. But I think clients are looking to stay closer to home and then on top of that clients are looking to barbell this more conservative foundation of their platform and are looking for more, I would say more robust active strategies and alternative strategies. The days when clients are looking for equity managers to manage 200, 300 stocks is probably over. Clients are going to be looking for &#x2013; portfolio managers are going to be managing probably under a 100 stocks.</p>
          <p>We're looking for more concentrated active strategies and if they have the ability to actively outperform, they're going to be big winners. And so we're seeing a total change in how our clients are looking at asset allocation but also we're looking at how they think about how they should allocate in the equity space between active and passive. And we are seeing clients starting to relook at some of the alternative strategies as they feel more comfortable with their foundation platform of a little more indexed, more fixed income and are looking for more of a barbell approach of looking more as I said more fundamentally active approaches.</p>
          <p>The ETF space I think, as you all know as an industry continues to grow, and we believe there is going to be great application and great opportunities for the combined BlackRock mutual fund platform, working along side, the ETF platform that we will have at a new BlackRock Global Investors. I believe the dialogues with our clients, retail and institutional, will be quite expansive as a result of this whole product mix.</p>
          <p>So overall, in a very short period of time since we've announced this transaction, integration is going great, clients' response are overwhelmingly positive, revenue synergy opportunities are greater, and we are very excited about the opportunity, and we are looking forward to closing this transaction as quickly as we feasibly can.</p>
          <p>Let me just bring up one other point that really speaks loudly about our proposed BGI transaction. This morning I received an e-mail from our London office. We won an $800 million mandate this morning; this is from an existing client. This is a client who when we announced our MLIM transaction three and a half years ago, they put us in the penalty box for a period of time. They were worried. They were worried about what does this mean for them and at that time they actually questioned scale. Obviously, how they awarded us, the fact that they awarded us this business today and through our dialogue with the client, they believe this transaction has great merit.</p>
          <p>They believe scale is more important for them in working alongside with BlackRock and what they said to us, what's more important to them, which speaks loudly to everyone at BlackRock, the number one objective is client service and performance. And BlackRock has delivered client service and performance to this client and I think that's going to be clear for all our clients.</p>
          <p>As we continue to work on this integration, as we continue to build out the opportunities ahead of us with BGI and merging our two platforms into BlackRock Global Investors, we have to pay attention to performance in client service; and if we continue to do that, the merits of the transactions speak for itself and this is a message to all of BlackRock employees and this is a message from all our clients. They are very excited about this transaction, but that does not mean we could stop. We need to be on top of our clients, working with our clients, being engaged with our clients, and we need to continue to perform as we have so far this year-to-date.</p>
          <p>So to sum it all up, I think the one BlackRock business model is proving to be successful. One global technology platform is proving to be the right business model. That is our expectations with BlackRock Global Investors, one global platform, one technology platform and one unified organization worldwide. I believe, we'll be able to achieve that. I am very excited with our new partners. The intellectual capital of the team is terrific. The opportunities we have with our new partners, with BlackRock are enormous and the opportunities for our clients are going to be very large.</p>
          <p>So, with that thank you everyone. Let me open it up for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And our first question will come from the line of William Katz with Buckingham.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone. I am just wondering if you could talk &#x2013; it's a little technical, I apologize but in terms of the guidance you provided now in terms of the integration costs ahead of, maybe during the early part of the acquisition, that plus what you said are the revenue synergies are running a little bit better than what you thought at the time of announcement which may be not that surprising to me but &#x2013; but any update you're thinking on the ultimate synergies as we look out to 2010 and the combined company relative to what you initially announced? And I have a follow-up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we're going to continue to do quite a bit of work over the next several months Bill. So, we're really going to work on those. I don't have a specific update to give you on the synergy numbers at this point in time. Other than just say as Larry said, we're very excited and looking forward to getting down and really materializing those things as soon as possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all else being equal though, Larry your comments that you feel better about the revenue synergies today than a few weeks ago when the deal was formerly announced. If I was going to overlay that to the initial guidance then everything else the numbers would be higher even as we think about these integration charges upfront?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the second question I have is, you swore off acquisitions during the conference call to discuss the BGI transaction yet interestingly the media is linking you with a particularly sizable transaction on the cash management side which may be a little bit counter to how you're thinking about maybe the industry in the short-term. I just wanted you to reiterate your views on acquisitions right here right now, beyond the BGI deal obviously.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I really can't speak about any deal specifically but I will complete &#x2013; I'll reiterate my statement related to, we are not interested in doing acquisitions. We have a great opportunity in terms of our relationship, let me just &#x2013; I'm getting, my general counsel is telling me not to say anything other than what has been reported and I am not going to confirm or deny anything on what is reported. We are not interested in working on any large-scale mergers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just one last, and I apologize. As you think about the merger itself, you mentioned that the client feedback has been quite positive and you gave a lot of statistics this morning which was helpful, what about the consultant community itself?  Are they the pundits that are more worried about scale? I was wondering if you could answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, it was very interesting. Some of our consultants have merged themselves into a behemoth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer is I would say the consulting community generally has nothing to gain generally to be effusive about any merger. They have to be cautious. But I would say to a consultant they all are, they have respected how we did our past integrations. They understand how we did &#x2013; how we worked out in the past and they were enthusiastic with the results, for them and their clients. And I think there is a high level of interest in terms of their belief that we can get this done too. But to date I don't think we have been put into the penalty box with any consultant.</p>
          <p>I think, consultants have a wait-and-see attitude. I think that is the best way to frame it. But I don't believe we've been stopped with any type of client RFP because of consultants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Mike Carrier with Deustche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, how you're doing, thanks. Yeah, I think when we look at the flows and even the pipeline, particularly on the fixed income side but also on the equity side. We can see clients taking more risks; I think it's a little surprising on the fixed income side. When we look at the &#x2013; the relative performance, yet the flows still seem like they're holding up extremely well and the pipeline looks extremely robust. So, just based on the client conversations, performance is one thing and if the short-term performance is starting to improve, then maybe clients are still confident in BlackRock's strategy and their process because they know that things will eventually turn around. But besides long-term performance, what are clients asking, or what are their priorities, when they are &#x2013; when you're competing with other firms where they allocate the money to BlackRock relative to someone else who has better performance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, a) not all our competitors have better performance, so let's start off with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>B) some of the largest wins that we have won in fixed income are associated with a more than just the fixed income platform. They may be an associated with both fixed income and a BlackRock Solutions assignment, maybe our risk management assignment working along side with them providing some form of green package or Aladdin platform. And so it is the uniqueness that we can bring to the table to clients related to risk management and asset management that I think we have a distinct advantage over many of our competitors. And again, so I think what it confirms Mike, more and more clients are looking for more fiduciary type of relationships that are more than just an asset management relationship. They're looking for multi-products. They're looking for risk management. They're looking for an expanded relationship.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, makes sense, and then for Ann Marie, just on the expenses, that you ex some of the noise with the FX and the BGI integration, and even the comp related to the deferred compensation, when we look at kind of stripping all of that out, are we at a fairly good run rate when you look at the cost initiatives that are put in place, and then going forward, we're back to depending on how the businesses is and how the market is, expenses can go up from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I would say that's a pretty good assessment of where we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Roger Freeman with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Roger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning. I guess the first on the PPIP program, Larry, can you just comment on what your expectations are around that now. You had talked about five to $7 billion, you were looking to raise a quarter ago; I think that number has come down, I can't remember what you said lately -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It feels like appetite has come in here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, first of all, I still think we could have raised that much money. The program, obviously this is all public information, the Treasury appointed nine managers, each manager was given $1.1 billion; and so we're going to raise $1.1 billion on top of the 1.1 Treasury will give us in terms of equity, and then we'll have leverage to play. And so, if you think about that in terms of assets with three to one leverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That does come up to about $6 billion. But equity raised is about 1.1 that we're going to be looking for; and that's going to be true with all the nine managers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is your sense that it's going to be that you're actually going to be able to raise that amount? Is the fundamental demand there now, particularly with institutions that <mark type="inaudible" /> have raised a lot of equity this quarter ?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Roger, we're not including that in the pipeline or anything but the reality is, if the program was larger we think we could raise the equity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, okay. In your money markets business, you talked about the retail outflows. On the institutional side, was there any elevation at the end of the quarter as institutions were trying to move money out of cash accounts? <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, if you look at spot and all that stuff, it's not as down as much. You had a lot of it. You're seeing more and more rebalancing at quarter end and things like that, but I don't &#x2013; we did get some outflows institutionally. Some of it was stock repurchase and other programs like that. So, we are &#x2013; institutionally there is some industry outflows but not as much as retail, and we saw it in both cases. I think we saw probably a little more retail outflows than industry in our retail space though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just if I heard you correctly, the catalyst really to get a more significant outflow for money market funds, because we really haven't seen significant outflows, is just going to be continued stability in your view, and then do you think that's going to go more to fixed income than equity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I actually think as an industry we're going to see outflows over the course of the next year. That's a function of the psychology of the markets. As I said earlier, if you believe you're going to earn less than zero, you're going to lose money; you're going to keep more money in money market funds. If you believe there are going to be greater opportunity to add some return, depending on your risk assessment, you're going to be moving more cash, more money out of cash.</p>
          <p>Chairman Bernanke had an op-ed piece today talking about their plans. Clearly there was no timing but most certainly there is talk in the future that there is going to be rising rates and so that's how they're &#x2013; and there's no timeframe as I said. I don't believe that's going to happen for at least another year, but &#x2013; or some time around there. But we see &#x2013; we're in more dialogue of clients asking what should they do with the cash, and that's just not the U.S. I was in Asia this past week, and I think almost every client was asking me what should they be doing now, how should they be looking at reinvesting. And so more and more clients that have been frightened and put a lot of money back into cash are now looking for other strategies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just lastly advisory AUM was down slightly sequentially, and is this, are we done seeing this line go up now there we're past the worst of the financial crisis. And then just in terms of the revenues from Solutions, are we seeing a little bit of a lull here. Some of the short-term assignments have come off and now people are looking at Aladdin and maybe that starts to build?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think that's fair. Let me, the outflows in the, as we said in the press release, the outflows was really a principal payment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some of these are scheduled amortizations, and so some of that was that. But the answer is, we are actually talking to a couple non-U.S. entities for assignments and so; in fact we're talking to one institution right now that is exceedingly large. I don't believe &#x2013; as I said, we're out of the emergency room. So I don't think we're going to have the same type of flows in the advisory platform. Nevertheless, we are working on one very large one as we speak. And I, our hope is to take those assignments and move them more into Aladdin, and that was always our long-term plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a more sticky business and a more robust business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Roger Smith with Fox-Pitt Kelton.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Roger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How are you doing? Thanks very much. Just staying on that BlackRock Solutions, it came down I guess to $116 million this quarter and if I look or listen to what you are saying is the difference between the two revenue numbers really the amount in the short-term valuation products or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mandates, that's how much really went away?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's exactly it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perfect. And then really on the retail money market funds, it sounds like you're seeing greater outflows there than you would on the institutional side. Is that, and I'm assuming based on your comments that money really is going back into the markets, that's not going to some other type of cash management product like a bank deposit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, now I think I would say let's, I don't want to be, I don't want to say 100% of the retail money is going into longer-dated items. I think some of the retail items probably are going to bank deposits and that's, I think you hit the point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so I think it's a combination of both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now do you think...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But if you look at our retail long-dated flows in mutual funds they're pretty strong and so there is some of both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, now do you think that the retail investors are really kind of coming back here faster than the institutional investor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think the institutional are coming back faster than retail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, got you. And then in the alternative space can you just maybe give us a little bit more information of what might be happening there from an institutional client versus a high net worth client or in the fund of funds business, is that...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we don't &#x2013; most, almost the great, great, great majority of our alternative base business is institutional, and it's institutional in the fund of funds or in the direct accounts. As I said we did close a fund of funds in private equity in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Where we saw big outflows in the first quarter, in the early part of the second quarter, was our fund of funds of hedge funds and that has really stabilized in the last few weeks. And actually we've just won a very competitive assignment from one of the more important clients worldwide, and so we are beginning to see a turnaround there, our performance there has also turned around. And so I don't want to say we're out of the woods yet in the alternative space, but we are starting to see a real turnaround in performance and a real beginning of a turnaround in flows in the fund of funds space.</p>
          <p>On the real estate side we're still going to have another period of time of indigestion. I think it's very clear that the real estate market, the commercial real estate market and the multi-family real estate market is the last market to really find a bottom and it has not found a bottom yet. And I think that's true if you look at all of the bank earnings and other company earnings that have any commercial real estate exposure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. And then just...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not seeing any flows in that business at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's flat line for the moment and I think that is industry wide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then just lastly so I understand the BGI. When you are out talking to clients, is that more really on a high level basis or are the sales folks starting to really be integrated at this point where they're going out and selling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Only when clients ask us to meet with them, okay. We are not permitted. We're two separate entities, they're operating, they belong to Barclays, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so when clients request a meeting, we are there together and it has to come from clients or we are not, we cannot be there in front of clients. And this is no different than what happened with any transaction with the MLIM transaction. But there are more and more clients who are requesting meetings with both firms together. As I suggested yesterday we did meet with one of the largest clients of the combined organizations and it was a very positive meeting. When I was in Asia last week, I did have a number of meetings with clients who have strong relationships with both organizations, who equally said they're very excited about the combination and the opportunity.</p>
          <p>So, I have to be very clear in how, the roads of the map and how we can navigate. So, if clients request meetings, we are there. And next week I will see two other very large clients again. Again, clients have asked to see us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Craig Siegenthaler with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Craig.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning, maybe Larry, or if Paul is around, one of you could help me with a question on the money market funds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Paul's not here; so I guess, I've got to do it or Ann Marie is going to do it, or somebody else here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh that works, but maybe you guys can help me with the risks of fee waivers here, kind of where we stand or maybe an update on the prospects for regulatory reserves or capital charges in light of the Treasury Insurance program going away?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we did analysis of fee waiver and to be honest our fee waivers have stayed very steady, so we haven't seen any real change in fee waivers compared to where we were in the first quarter. So, I think there is not much of a story there when you are looking at our results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the capital charges at the federal, if the insurance program goes away, I think as I said in the past we are in favor of having more self-regulation, more reserves of capital within the firm. We believe it is the right thing to and it's a sign of strength of any organization. Again I think you're going to see a consolidation of the money market business as capital is being required. I believe they're going to be some form of replacement of the fees that we're being charged by the Fed. We could use those fees to build up capital in place of the Federal Reserve to stand by to our clients.</p>
          <p>So we are working with the industry. We've been in dialogues in the proposed regulatory reforms and this is something we're in favor of. We think it, we need to make sure that the money market industry is competitive with deposits. And if you don't have capital behind it, deposits are a more capital &#x2013; are a safer investment because of the FDIC insurance up until a point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we agree with that one. But also on a follow up to Mike's question on credit, bond flows are very strong now but, given that the secular trend seems to be a shift to DB plans &#x2013; to DC plans and now a lot of these DB plans are also overweight fixed income assets just based on what happened in the market the last two years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am wondering how do you see the demand and not endowments, foundations, other sovereign wealth funds, but the core U.S. defined benefit plan. How do you see that demand and that organic growth trend over the next year or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know that, you're right on the DB plans, we're not going to see that much in fixed, because they are over allocated in fixed because of the decline in equities. But we are seeing on the taxable institution space more and more outsourcing. We're seeing in Europe and with the DB plans outsourcing. Similar to our Philips transaction or when we announced I think in the first quarter the, the Henkel assignment and these are outsourcing their DB plans to external managers. So, we are seeing that fiduciary outsourcing trend continue in Europe. We're seeing more outsourcing of asset management services where the taxable institution platform &#x2013; chiefly insurance companies.</p>
          <p>But in the U.S. defined benefit plans we're &#x2013; nothing rings loudly. I could look at our flows of any large trends in DB. We have won some and those were as a result of clients moving from underperforming management to BlackRock. But aside from the reallocation of managers, I don't think the flows are that strong right now. But I will, we are meeting with more and more DB plans than ever before and they're looking for topical conversations. My two big conversations &#x2013; meetings next week are two DB plans that I'm having related to the merger and other things. And they are large DB plans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks for taking my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Douglas Sipkin with Pali.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Just two questions here; a couple have been answered. Just can you guys provide a little bit of color on the outlook for performance fees, potentially some of them coming off of the good performance for fixed income? I know the performance fees are generally seasonal, stronger in the second half of the year. And then just the second question, just trying to get a little bit more color about how &#x2013; are we to assume you guys are going to start running through BGI integration expenses pretty much every quarter now through the close and then thereafter?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doug, first of all with respect to performance fees, clearly there is seasonality in our performance fees and that has to do when the locks are and we do have more locks in the third and the fourth quarter. We've tried to provide you some data in the Qs and the Ks. So I think if you look back you'll see where probably we're going to be generating more performance fees on our separate accounts when it's about really relative performance where we have absolute performance threshold, we still do on the preexisting products have a little ways to climb out before we're earning those again. But as we introduce new products again those become an opportunity to earn performance fees. With respect to the integration costs, you're totally right these are expenses we've begun incurring already. We'll incur some prior to close and then of course there will be a chunk that come in the month and short quarters after close.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then just one follow-up. You guys have talked about bringing more passive strategies into the 401(k) market subsequent to the close of BGI and iShares, and you had indicated that there was still some back office challenges getting ETFs in 401(k)s. Can Larry or someone else maybe provide an update on how that's progressing? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this is all part of our integration process; there is no question. We've had dialogues with some of the large distribution platforms for 401(k) and most certainly they are very interested in talking to us about some type of association or ability to work together in terms of offering ETFs onto their distribution platforms for 401(k)s and other retirements. But Doug, it's too early for me to be really specific but the dialogues have begun. It is clear to me that so many 401(k)s are in need for lower fee products, more transparency and I believe the whole dialogue around ETFs with 401(k)s are going to be an industry conversation over the next year or so and we will be a large participant in that discussion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you for answering the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Marc Irizarry with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey Marc.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Marc.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Hey Larry, how are you? Could we just hit on the trend of clients doing more with fewer managers? And if you think about the multi-asset portfolio group that you have maybe you can help size that group now versus what it was. And then also I think you mentioned the $10 billion RFP that's on the table. Is that in the pipeline, and if you could just give some color on the MAPS group, and how big that is now and how fast that's growing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let me clarity two things. One of the large wins in the $46 billion is a fiduciary outsourcing type of assignment. The two $10 billion plus assignments let me &#x2013; it's not yet assignments, RFPs or opportunities are not in the pipeline. And we are in dialogue and we're competing with some of our major competitors on that right now. In fact one of the big assignments, the client is coming in and doing in-house due diligence at BlackRock. And some of our large wins in the last quarter have been these type of assignments. BGI has a very large &#x2013; they call it solutions-based business and we have something called the MAPS business, multi-asset product strategies. So we both have these businesses.</p>
          <p>I don't know what the combined platform is going to look like in terms of personnel. I see Sue rapidly opening her book and trying to come up with that number. But it's going to be extensive. And what's impressive where BlackRock historically has been strong in the multi-asset strategy really in some of these fiduciary outsourcings, the BGI platform is actually stronger in the LDI. And so if you look at the styles in which they and us have pushed this business it is very complementary. This is another thing that we saw some real opportunities together. But the combined multi-asset strats combinations of products &#x2013; can I say the number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I am just making sure in public I can talk about it, so I've got my General Counsel talking. The combined multi-asset strategy platform is approximately $301 billion. This is before these wins of this quarter. So, this is really at the end of the first quarter these numbers that I am discussing with you. So, a very large platform and a very large platform that's growing both at BGI and at BlackRock. And then hopefully obviously as we put these units onto one common platform I think we're going to have an exceptional business in this area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great and then just to clarify as you've been meeting with some of the clients where potentially there is some overlap between yourselves and BGI, are you walking away feeling that the likelihood of retaining some of that business is now greater than it was when you originally set forth the deal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely. But, now let me put the caveat. So the meetings are going great, the enthusiasm is going great. We've got a long time between now and closing. And I do &#x2013; so at this moment it feels great. The client meetings are very strong, but we have a lot to do between now and closing, and we've got to make sure that we continue with this momentum, and we have to continue with the dialogue with our clients. If we continue with the pace that we have done in the most recent whatever five weeks, yeah I think it's fair to say that we are more comfortable with the, as I said revenue synergies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Chris Spahr with CLSA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey Chris. It sounds like no Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Sir, your line is open. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, I am sorry. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Yeah, I was just wondering you've talked in the past about some of the regulatory legislative initiatives that might be &#x2013; hurt the market longer term, such as the contract law, change of the rating agencies and so forth. Can you just expand upon that, or where you see things stand today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am very worried about the whole issue of loan modifications. That's the whole issue on contract law, whereby there are proposals in the Congress to allow the modification of a first mortgage without the extinguishment of the second mortgage. I was happy to see last week Senator Dodd and Senator Frank actually wrote a letter stating, the reason why so much mortgage modifications aren't been done is because banks are refusing to write-down their second liens. So that was a step in the right direction.</p>
          <p>But the proposal in this loan modification is allowing the existence of a second lien with a modification of a first lien. And as I said I finished an Asia trip; there was not one client who has invested in some form of this securitization market asked me where does that stand. And it would put a real, would put real pressure in the securitization market in the future if we don't have as first lien holders an understanding of our legal rights. And so this is a big issue that's in my mind slowing down the rebuilding of the securitization market. And I have been very vocal about it; in fact in some cases too vocal about it. But I do believe there is, somebody has to stand up and speak, and this is another example of the transformation of the investment management industry.</p>
          <p>Historically, we as investment managers relied on Wall Street to be the safety guards to the capital markets. And in many cases the securities firms have dropped that responsibility and it's now falling on some of the large investment management firms. And actually we're trying to do this on behalf of our clients. I mean this is not our balance sheet. We're doing this on behalf of clients, so our motives are to protect our clients. And we are now working with lobbyists and all that stuff, on behalf of our clients and we're not getting paid for this to do this work to try to make sure that the securitization market is being protected. And so I'm probably getting too much on my soapbox now, but I do believe this is an important issue. It will be an important issue as we try to navigate out of this recession and as we start rebuilding our capital markets and the securitization markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on a related note there has been a lot of talk about normalization of fund fee levels between institutional clients and retail clients, at least some of them have reached the courts. And I am just wondering if you guys thought about that and if there'd be any potential impact on BlackRock.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am looking at my general counsel on that question. I know it's moved up in the courts. As a business matter, I have not truly addressed it so I'm really not &#x2013; I can't speak about it but Bob, do you have any comments on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think we just let the court process play out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I don't know if you heard him, he just said we'll let the court process play out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Roger Freeman with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey Roger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, just a couple of follow ups here. So just back on the performance fees I think you've answered much of this, but the improvement sequentially this quarter, how much of that is because of relative benchmark funds versus absolute funds. I assume it's all relative, right, because your absolute funds are all below high water?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just relative, I think there was one absolute in there as well. I can get you the details, we'll have that set out for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. How far on average would you say alternative funds are below high water marks at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's probably hard to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolute...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would still say, on the fund of funds, I'm going to &#x2013; I would still say 10% plus. I think, I am not &#x2013; we can have that off-line for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay no problem. And then looking at your some of the principal gains, in the seed investments, the distressed hedge fund returns. If I'm doing the math right it looks like you had something like a 23% mark up in the quarter, is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah that's good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am sorry, so my question is I mean did you &#x2013; how much of the easy returns have been achieved here as we bounce off the bottom in some of the distressed assets? Or do you think these kind of returns are we could still see that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, it really depends on asset category and a lot of those returns were in the bank loan market where you had a tremendous rebound from the free fall of the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You have not seen a remarkable increase in some of the residential mortgage securities. You've seen some; much of the, some of these markets have not rebounded like others. A lot of that has to do with what is your right as a first lien lender, and so it gets back to this whole issue of loan modification. The values of these securities can change dramatically if they allow in a modification the second lien to be preserved. And so in some of those products, we've not seen as significant a rebound.</p>
          <p>Now, maybe with the PPIP, through those that facility maybe you're going to see more demand and a stronger rebound, but to date, in some of the asset categories, we have not seen a remarkable improvement. But in some areas we saw a real big improvement and that's probably it. I mean so it really, if there is a rotation in some of the asset categories we can continue to have some upticks, but I would say in some of the bank loan products, maybe modest growth but not much more. The market went too far down and it rebounded closer to fair value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, okay. And you know actually, I just had a thought in terms of you are a large buyer, trader of fixed income assets, credit assets. As you look at some of the fixed income returns that the dealers have been putting up in recent quarters, can you comment from your side of the table, how &#x2013; particularly the credit markets have been functioning with respect to bid-ask spreads? There has been the commentary has been some very large revenues is being generated from client flows and you're obviously a big source of client flows. Can you just talk to that side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's very fair to say, as evidenced by some of the returns from some of the security firms, bid-asks are abnormally large. It is a deep concern of ours. As we get more scale we are looking at other ways of trying to reduce the bid-ask spread. But it is a good example how the markets are still not normalized, how despite the big rally credit markets are still abnormal versus any historical standards. There are fewer players. There are fewer &#x2013; there is very little capital being committed by these dealers. They're just taking the spread between the bid and the ask and they are making very luxurious returns. And that is a big issue for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Have you seen bid-ask spreads comes in sequentially from 1Q to 2Q and secondly are there any dealers that were not active in terms of capital commitment, stocking bond inventory in the first quarter that were in the second?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Roger, I'm not that close to day-to-day spread and who handles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, so I am sure, somehow, we can find out if we, but I can't answer those questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine, I am just curious for a comment. Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time there are no further questions. Mr. Fink, Ms. Petach, are there any closing remarks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think, thank you for spending so much time with us this morning. We have a big objective in getting our BGI transaction completed and a lot of hard work in front of us and all the employees at BGI and BlackRock. But I am excited at this moment to say that our enthusiasm is very large and the opportunities ahead of us with the combined organization. If we realize all our integration issues are going to be significant and the opportunities for us in working with our clients are going to be quite enlarged. And so we'll be able to tell you more as we finish up the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Please maybe this summer everyone could have a vacation. That's probably the last thing I could say to everyone, the last two summers July and August were terrible going into September and hopefully we could have some stability in the markets so we could enjoy some form of summer vacation. So have a good one. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's teleconference. You may all disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>