<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1100384" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-05-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1401</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Viki Lazaris, Senior Vice-President Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">William Downe, President and Chief Executive Officer, BMO Financial Group</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Russel C. Robertson, Interim Chief Financial Officer, BMO Financial Group</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Thomas E. Flynn, Executive Vice-President and Chief Risk Officer, BMO Financial Group</participant>
      <participant id="5">Jim Bantis</participant>
      <participant id="6">Thomas Flynn</participant>
      <participant id="7">Robert Sedran</participant>
      <participant id="8">Frank Techar</participant>
      <participant id="9">William Downe</participant>
      <participant id="10">Mario Mendonca</participant>
      <participant id="11">Russel Robertson</participant>
      <participant id="12">Viki Lazaris</participant>
      <participant id="13">Sumit Malhotra</participant>
      <participant id="14">Michael Goldberg</participant>
      <participant id="15">Andr&#xE9;-Philippe Hardy</participant>
      <participant id="16">Ian De Verteuil</participant>
      <participant id="17">Brad Smith</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, and welcome to the BMO Financial Group's Second Quarter 2008 Conference Call for May 27th. Your host for today is Viki Lazaris, Senior Vice President of Investor Relations. Ms. Lazaris, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good afternoon everyone and thanks for joining us today. Presenting today on the conference call are Bill Downe, BMO's CEO; Russ Robertson, our Chief Financial Officer and Tom Flynn, our Chief Risk Officer. The following members of the management team are also here this afternoon, Tom Milroy, Head of BMO Capital Markets; Gilles Ouellette from the Private Client Group; Frank Techar, Head of P&amp;C Canada; Ellen Costello from P&amp;C US and Barry Gilmour, Head of Technology and Operation.</p>
          <p>After the presentation the management team will be available to answer questions from pre-qualified analysts. To give everyone an opportunity to participate, we ask you that you please ask only one or two questions then re-queue.</p>
          <p>At this time, I'd like to caution our listeners by stating the following on behalf of those speaking today. Forward-looking statements may be made during this call and there are risks that actual results could differ materially from forecasts, projections or conclusions in the forward-looking statements. Certain material factors and assumptions were applied in drawing the conclusion or making the forecast or projection in these forward-looking statements. You may find additional information about such material factors and assumption and the material factors that could cause actual results to so differ in our caution regarding forward-looking statements set forth in the news release or on our Investor Relations website.</p>
          <p>With that said, I'll hand things over to Bill now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Viki and good afternoon, everyone. As noted my comments may include forward-looking statements. Russ is going to take you through the details of our second quarter financials in a few minutes, but let me provide the highlights upfront. BMO reported much improved results for the second quarter today. Net income was 642 million, 4% below Q2 2007, but substantially above Q1 2008. Fully diluted EPS in the quarter was $1.25 a share and cash EPS was $1.26. Our return on equity in the quarter was 17.9%, a very solid return in the current environment and we remain very well capitalized. Our balance sheet is strong. And our common shareholders' equity is up almost 500 million from a year ago.</p>
          <p>I told you in Q1 that management was addressing market difficulties while continuing to concentrate on our core businesses and our customers. And for me, Q2 demonstrates that we delivered against a timetable and an agenda that were clearly expressed. Specifically, our performance in the quarter reflects the following three criteria that I've been highlighting in recent calls. First, fundamentally better performance in our core Canadian retail operations, which is attributable, in large part, to our renewed focus on customers and investments we've been making in the business. Second, in our capital markets business, the ongoing demonstrated success in reducing risk related to off balance sheet exposures. And third, maintaining visual and supervision of our loan portfolio with a closed eye on provisions for credit losses in a deteriorating economic environment.</p>
          <p>We see credit issues, primarily in US real estate. And these are visible and well understood. And Tom is going to provide some detail in this area shortly. But in sum, I am very pleased by our team's performance against the three points on this slide and about the momentum we're building.</p>
          <p>Moving to the operating group's results from our retail operations were strong in the quarter, particularly in Canada. In total, net income from retail operations, including wealth management was 470 million, up 3.3% from Q2 last year and 10.3% from Q1 2008. These results reflect success in executing the customer focus strategy we laid out in detail at our Investor Day in April. And the focus continues to build momentum. We're seeing real progress on a number of important metrics, including improved customer loyalty scores, a growing customer base and strengthening customer relationships. The result, our market share has now improved for six consecutive quarters in personal lending and in five of the last six quarters in commercial lending.</p>
          <p>Our market share in mortgages declined quarter-over-quarter, because of the expected impact of our decision to exit the broker channel. However, again this quarter we experienced volume growth as mortgage originations outpaced the last volume related to the decision. Most importantly we've increased spreads on new originations by 31 basis points year-over-year. Personal deposits, balances were unchanged and market share was down just slightly in a competitive environment, but we know we can do better in this area.</p>
          <p>Cards revenue is again up this quarter and growth is accelerating. Revenue was up 9.2% year-over-year this quarter, compared to 5.6% last quarter. And we continue to bring innovative new efforts to the market, such as Shell Mosaik, MasterCard and an improved offer for Gold MasterCard holders. So the story of Canadian P&amp;C is that we're continuing to grow in the areas we said we would 18 months ago and we're confident that these trends will continue.</p>
          <p>And in PCG we had a great quarter with record net income, while assets under management and administration have been affected by softer equity markets, we're encouraged by market share growth in investor lines, Canadian private bank and our term products business. Income growth was attributable both to a diversified revenue base and to proactive effective cost management.</p>
          <p>P&amp;C US recorded net income of $30 million for the quarter. In the quarter we closed two Wisconsin acquisitions and added 41 branches to our network. Year to date, we recruited 37 experienced commercial bankers, increasing the workforce in that area by 15%.</p>
          <p>Harris' had a longstanding membership in Visa USA, both as a Visa card issuer and as a merchant card processor. And although we sold the Harris merchant card business eight years ago to Moneris, BMO's merchant card joint venture, we maintained our Visa membership and as a consequence, we were able to participate in the Visa IPO and in the quarter, realized US 13 million after tax that more than mitigated the impact of a number of one-time expense items in the quarter.</p>
          <p>And finally, in BMO Capital Markets, equity and debt underwriting and M&amp;A activity were slow in the quarter for the market as a whole, and are reflected in our results for the quarter. However, the outlook is improving, with indications of funding costs turning towards less elevated levels. We think that earnings in Q2 reflect the lower end of the sustainable range going forward, assuming we don't see a major reversal of the market conditions experienced most recently.</p>
          <p>We made substantial progress in Q2 to reduce our balance sheet exposures, and I'm pleased with the progress made with structured and off balance sheet entities. In March, we concluded agreements to restructure Apex/Sitka, and as a result, reversed a portion of the valuation reserves recorded in the preceding periods. The restructuring preserves asset value for BMO and other investors and places the trust on solid footing. And Tom Flynn will provide more detail around the market events, environment rather, in a moment.</p>
          <p>Obviously, our results going forward will be affected by the economic environment. The US economy has slowed sharply with housing activities still weakening. We expect growth to improve modestly in the second half of the year in response to aggressive interest rate cuts and fiscal stimulus that's already in place. In the Midwest, house prices should remain under pressure through 2008 until inventories are worked off and affordability improves.</p>
          <p>Personally, I don't think that we're going to see price increases in the market before 2010 and consumer activity will be slow-stable in 2009. Low growth in commercial sector is also expected for the remainder of this year. In Canada, the economy has also slowed due to declining exports to the US, however, domestic demand remains strong and supported by low interest rates and high resource prices. Although housing activity is expected to moderate, economic growth should pick up in the second half of the year in response to recent interest rate cuts by the Bank of Canada and a steadier US economy.</p>
          <p>Investor sentiment has improved significantly since the Bear Stearns rescue in mid-March, though some credit spreads remain wider than usual. And while we're not ready to say the worst of the credit turmoil is behind the industry, we are encouraged that the downsides are very clearly defined now, and I can certainly say here at BMO, we're maintaining a firm grasp on the issues that are affecting our business.</p>
          <p>As a result, as we go into the second half of the year, I'm encouraged. Our core businesses have performed well despite tough conditions. We're making real visible and steady progress in risk reduction and the economic forecast for the second half is more constructive. We're building momentum, we're coming off a quarter we're please with because it confirms progress on a number of fronts and we're looking forward to the second half of the year. And with that, I'll turn you over to Russ to talk about the results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Hello and good afternoon. <mark type="inaudible" /> cash basis earnings were $1.26 per share. We had strong results in P&amp;C Canada. In fact, it was one of the best quarters ever, improving significantly from the first quarter and year-over-year. Adjusting for the prior year's insurance and investment gains, net income was up 12% with good revenue growth and expense management. P&amp;C US results were up quarter-over-quarter and year-over-year. Included in these results are a one-time Visa gain, higher than usual expenses.</p>
          <p>Private Client Group earned record net income reflecting diversified revenue and disciplined expense management. Earning in BMO Capital Markets reflect the current operating environment. And I'll provide more color on the net recoveries reported in this group on slide 7. The tier-one capital ratio remains strong at 9.42% based on Basel II.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 4. You'll see the revenues were up about 29% quarter-over-quarter. Revenue was up 4% excluding the significant items reported in Q1 '08. Revenue in this quarter reflects much softer market conditions. Year-over-year revenues increased 4% on a reported basis or 3% lower on a core basis. Net interest income was 1.2 billion in Q2 down slightly from both comparative quarters.</p>
          <p>Looking more specifically at the margins on slide 5. Total bank margin was up 3 basis points from Q1. Margins increased in P&amp;C Canada both quarter-over-quarter and year-over-year. The increase year-over-year is due to better spread on mortgages and improving product mix, partially offset by competitive pricing pressures and personal and commercial deposits. Margins in P&amp;C US were down 4 basis points quarter-over-quarter. The total bank margin has also benefited by items that lowered corporate net interest revenue last quarter. Looking forward there will be continued downward pressure on margins. There is still some volatility in prime versus BA and competitive pressures remain. Mix in pricing may not be enough to maintain margins.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 6. Non-interest revenue, or NIR, improved significantly on a reported basis quarter-over-quarter. Non-interest revenue in P&amp;C Canada was up slightly due to securitization and cards revenues, partially offset by lower insurance revenue. We are pleased to announce that subsequent to the end of the quarter we have entered into an agreement to transfer the liability associated with our credit card loyalty rewards program to Loyalty Management Group Inc., LMG. Our partner in the AIR MILES Reward Program. There will be no gain or loss on the transfer.</p>
          <p>In addition, we have renegotiated and extended the term of our agreement with LMG for the issuance of AIR MILES. As part of this agreement we will no longer retain the liability for future AIR MILES redemptions and hence will have no exposure to changing redemption patterns. We expect negligible change in run rate costs as a result of the agreement. PNC US' NIR benefited from the sale of Visa shares during the quarter. Private Client Group's NIR was down due to lower fee based revenue in Mutual Fund businesses.</p>
          <p>BMO Capital Markets results in Q1 reflected charges of 488 million related to the deterioration in capital markets. Results in the current quarter include a 42 million net recovery, which I will discuss further in a moment. Despite the continued challenging market conditions our debt and equity under-writing fees improved over the prior quarter. However, there were lower investment gains and reduced cash management revenues.</p>
          <p>Slide 7 summarizes the effects of the capital marks environment on Q2 results. The impact this quarter was a net recovery of 28 million after tax or $0.06 cents per share. And these adjustments were reflected in trading non-interest revenue, other revenue and securities gains and losses other than trading. Notable items are as follows, an $85 million pre-tax reversal of previously recorded charges on Apex/Sitka Trust. This amount was determined based on a 90% probability of restructuring determined as of April 30, up from 70% at Q1. As the restructuring was completed in May we expect to record a reversal of a further portion of previously recorded charges in Q3. As part of the restructuring, we've received notes whose value are subject to a quarterly discounted cash flow analysis.</p>
          <p>BMO holds 325 million in third-party asset-backed commercial paper related to the Montreal Accord. A $36 million pre-tax charge was recorded this quarter based on a 90% probability of restructuring compared to 85% at Q1. However we have increased our estimate of the expected discount on the notes, which we will receive when the restructuring is completed. A $23 million pre-tax charge relates to the capital notes we hold in the two SIVs. Our approach is consistent with prior quarters as we record the capital notes at their net asset value. BMO's investment in the capital notes was 10 million at April 30. A $128 million pre-tax mark-to-market gain on counter party credit exposures. The methodology applied is consistent with Q1 where a mark-to-market loss was recorded.</p>
          <p>BMO's credit spread has moved out relative to various counter parties. And that has resulted in gains in our derivatives portfolio. A $93 million pre-tax mark-to-market charge for other trading and structured products, these charges are similar for the prior quarter and are a result of the continued deterioration of credit markets.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 8. Expenses have increased both quarter-over-quarter and year-over-year. Quarter-over-quarter NIEX was up 66 million. BMO Capital Markets performance based compensation along with salaries and benefits as well as professional fees across the operating groups contributed to higher NIEX. There were reductions in the quarter related to stock-based compensation for employees eligible to retire, lower revenue base costs and PCG and lower capital taxes. Year-over-year foreign exchange had the impact of reducing expenses by 51 million. In addition, there were increases in salaries and professional fees and computer costs and business development, while capital taxes decreased. Current quarter results in P&amp;C US included a Visa litigation expense of 17 million.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 10, our tier-one capital ratio on a Basel II basis is 9.42%. This ratio remains very strong and well above our targeted minimum of 8%, and we have excess capital of 2.7 billion over this target. Under Basel II our risk-related assets increased by 7 billion. The increases in risk-rated assets are attributable to the liquidity agreements in respect to the SIVs, the impact of Apex and the closing of our Wisconsin acquisitions, in part offset by RWA management initiatives.</p>
          <p>Slide 11 highlights the most wholesale capital markets term funding mix. BMO has a corporate policy establishing maturity limits by market and term, and as you can see we are well diversified in both. We are an active issuer in a variety of markets.</p>
          <p>Before wrapping up I'd like to direct you to our press release where in connection with the recommendation of the financial stability form, we have expanded our discussion of financial instruments. In summary, this was a good quarter for BMO, especially in light of the current environment. As Bill mentioned in his comments we are continuing to make good progress against a specific agenda, and these results reflect this. With that I will turn things over to Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Russ, and good afternoon. Before I begin I would like to draw your attention to the caution regarding forward-looking statements on slide 2. Slide 3 summarizes some of the key credit-related information for the quarter. Gross impaired loans and formations remain elevated as expected given the economic environment. Specific provisions were 151 million in the quarter, and benefited from recoveries being higher than the previous two quarters.</p>
          <p>The key messages on the credit front for the quarter include the following: the Canadian and US consumer portfolios are performing well with provisions flat quarter-over-quarter and not materially up year-over-year; performance in this area continues to be better than peers. Like others, we are seeing some migration in the portfolios. Second, the non-real estate related commercial and cooperate portfolios are generally performing in a solid fashion.</p>
          <p>That said we are experiencing softness in certain sectors, including Canadian manufacturing, certain agricultural sectors and forest products. Third, certain US real estate related exposures are continuing to show weakness, given the challenges in the market. I would note that BMO's US operations have less US commercial real estate exposure than US peers. Lastly, looking forward, given the environment, we expect that specific provisions over the balance of the year will exceed those experienced in Qs one and two.</p>
          <p>Slide 4 shows the increasing trend in consumer delinquencies, reflecting the weakness in the economy. The US delinquency level, at approximately 40 basis points, compares favorably to our US peer group at approximately 85. Our Canadian consumer portfolio at 37 basis points is inline with expectations. In Q1 our Canadian installment loan and lines of credit delinquency levels ranked first among the Canadian peer group. As seen on slide 5, gross impaired loan balances have increased. Two specific loans that totaled approximately 600 million account for a little over one half of the increase in impaired loans year to date.</p>
          <p>These two loans were originated in our Fairway conduit. We have funded these two loans and one other from Fairway in part so that our Special Asset group can better manage the exposures. These three loans are tied to the US residential real estate sector.</p>
          <p>As seen on slide 6, the largest sectors within gross impaired loans are commercial real estate and financial institutions. Including a US entity that is in the business of purchasing distressed mortgages that is classified in the financial institutions category, commercial real estate related loans represent approximately 45% of gross impaired balances and most of these loans would be related the US residential housing market. While there has been weakness in US real estate, our exposures in this area are well within our risk tolerance. US commercial real estate related loans are approximately $5 billion or just 1.5% of assets. This includes developer loans and investor owned real estate. Residential mortgage and home equity line retail exposures are 6.5 billion and 4.5 billion respectively and these are performing in line with expectations.</p>
          <p>On slide 7, specific provisions remain above last year's levels, consistent with the increase in impaired loans and the economic environment. Consumer provisions are performing well, being flat quarter-over-quarter and up modestly year-over-year, while commercial and corporate provisions have increased for the reasons I mentioned earlier.</p>
          <p>Slide 8 provides a breakdown of the Q2 specific provision. The largest portion is driven by the Canadian portfolio and within that the credit card business, which tends to be quite predictable over time. The US and the Commercial Real Estate segments of the two pie charts each include a $35 million provision for a single account.</p>
          <p>Slide 10 gives an update on the SIVs. The SIVs are under half the size that they were in July of last year. The liquidity facilities that we have provided continue the orderly reduction in the size of the SIVs and rank senior to the capital notes. The capital notes have a par value of 1.7 billion in the case of Links. The market value of the capital notes is less reflecting in part reduced liquidity levels in the market and also higher market credit spread expectations. The asset quality in the SIVs remained strong, 92% of the assets are rated AA or better by Moody's and over 75% are rated AA or better by S&amp;P.</p>
          <p>Given recent asset sales, the size of the liquidity facilities that we are providing has been reduced to US 8.8 billion and 746 million euros down from 11 billion and 1.2 billion at January '08. Based on scheduled assets and debt maturities as well as estimated asset sales we expect that actual draws on the liquidity facilities will be less than 65% of the current facility size.</p>
          <p>As noted on slide 11 the restructuring of Apex/Sitka has closed substantially in accordance with the terms that we announced in March. The credit characteristics of our investments are strong given the largely investment grade nature of the underlying credit, the diversification in the portfolios and a significant first loss protection that is in place. The underlying investments in the trust have been rated AAA.</p>
          <p>Slide 12 summarizes mono lined related positions; our exposures here are not material with the mark-to-mark exposure being 214 million at quarter end. Slide 13 reviews our US conduit, which is called Fairway, this entity was formed in 1997 and has provided financing to many clients since then.</p>
          <p>Fairway's ratings are strong at A1 and P1 by Moody's and S&amp;P respectively. Fairway has performed well in the market since the market disruption began last summer. Overall, Fairway's assets are well diversified and rated, all of the assets are rated investment grade equivalent and approximately half are rated by external agencies.</p>
          <p>Three of Fairway's credits that are related to US residential real estate have experienced problems given the weakness in that part of the market and have been funded by BMO. Two of these assets are classified as impaired and generated provisions in quarters one and two.</p>
          <p>Commercial real estate related commitments currently represent just 12% of Fairway's total commitments. A review of these positions has not identified other immediate concerns. On slide 14, the large trading -- underwriting gains and losses on a few days were driven by the types of valuation adjustments that Russ referred to earlier.</p>
          <p>Lastly on slide 15 we have an update on the market environment related issues, this slide summarizes our positions in topical areas. Overall the trend for these items has been positive. We have very modest exposure to sub-prime, asset-backed commercial paper inventories are down, the previously announced restructuring of Apex/Sitka has closed, we've seen a continued reduction in the size of the SIVs and our monoline exposures are modest. And with that, operator, we'll open the call for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now take questions from the telephone line. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question is from Jim Bantis of Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, question for Tom. Tom, looking at the level formations, and I know you've detailed that Fairway is the bulk of the information this quarter, but maybe you could walk through how the provisioning is going to catch up to the level of formations going forward, and whether you, how are we going to look at, I know coverage ratio isn't the be all and end all metric at the Bank of Montreal's risk management team, but how could we look at the expanding net impaired loans?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I'll tackle that by giving you a sense of where we think provisions might go over the balance of the year. The impaired have grown as you've commented on, and what we see is that the retail portfolios generally are performing well. We've seen some migration in the portfolios, but we don't consider it to be significant. In the commercial and corporate portfolios generally the performance is solid with a couple of areas of weakness, and the weakness relates to Canadian manufacturing, forest products and parts of the agricultural sector. So generally, from an overall perspective, we feel pretty good about the portfolio given where we are in the cycle. The lumpiness in the formations, as you've mentioned, have come from some credits that are tied to the US real estate sector, and more specifically commercial real estate exposures that are tied to the US residential part of the market, and that part of the market as everyone knows is experiencing some weakness. Our exposures that are exposed to it are experiencing weakness as a result, and given the US economy looking like it's going to weaken a bit over the second half, and the state of the environment in the real estate sector, we think provisions over the balance of the year will be higher than what we've seen so far this year. Last quarter we said that we thought specific provisions of the 170 that we had in the first quarter, would be indicative of the kind of level that we would see over the balance of the year and these things are hard to predict given the nature of the number of variables that are involved, but we're now thinking that the number might be 10 to 20% above the level that we were talking about before on average over the balance of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Okay, Tom I appreciate that. I just wanted to follow-up on the size of these impaired formations and these are BMO sponsored ABCPs so; I'm surprised that the single name size of these formations. Can you comment on that and obviously this is coming out of the corporate wholesale division?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. The largest loans that have contributed to the formation growth are relatively large, single entity concentrations, but each of the exposures has diversification within it, in the sense that they're all in one business or linked businesses, but they were running portfolios under the corporate umbrella. And so, we saw, when we were underwriting the loans, diversification given the nature of the underlying portfolios both from a geographical perspective and from a development perspective in the case where we had multiple developments being conducted within single exposures. So there's concentration at the enterprise level, as you've noted, but diversification within.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Okay. You know what I'll re-queue. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Robert Sedran of National Bank Financial. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good afternoon. I'm trying to get a sense of what the -- I guess if you look at P&amp;C Canada, I guess it's 10% or 12% year-over-year growth, depending on what you decide to exclude from last years results, but what I would like to know is if you include actual loan loss performance as opposed to expected loss, what would the equivalent growth rate be? I guess I seem to be able to get consumer and commercial I seem to be able to get Canada and the US, I'm just not sure I can get P&amp;C Canada actual performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert, it's Frank. Just consistent with what Tom just talked about; our portfolios in P&amp;C Canada are performing well. And as you know we use EL's expected losses in our reported results, not actual PCLs but if you did include the PCLs at least through the first half of the year, there wouldn't be a material change in the results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and just one other question. If I listen to Tom talk about provisions and then Russel mentioned the potential for some margin pressure in the back half to mean to stay. And then, Bill, you mentioned the $1.20 odd that you earned this quarter seems to be at the low end of what you think you can earn. I'm guessing the markets are probably not the area you're looking for the ramp up earnings? Can you perhaps talk about where you're looking for the stronger performance to come from in the back half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think where the strength was in the first half of the year was in P&amp;C in Canada. And all of the predictors of revenue growth that we have been marking are performing very well. So I expect us to continue to grow market share in P&amp;C, Canada. Frank and his team, as you know, Rob, have a lot of initiatives under way and we have confidence in those as they're playing out. I think the wealth management business will continue to be a good contributor, from the first half of the year, notwithstanding the fact that large portions of the equity market, if you exclude the resource businesses, didn't do that well. I think that the control of expenses and the building of the business is paying off. Capital markets has been really going into very heavy headwinds, the last number of quarters. And my comments really were to the point that we think that to a large extent, those big issues that we were dealing with on the asset valuation side have unfolded exactly the way we hope they would. We've been able to tick off consecutively issues as we said we would. So I think to some extent what we're calling for is not an adverse economic environment and failing a significant downturn in the Canadian economy, we expect to continue to see long growth. And I did make the comment about deposit gross because I am looking for P&amp;C to open more accounts and show some growth in that area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Mario Mendonca of Genuity Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. One quick technical question first. On page 18 of the supplement, it's the one on asset securitization. I'd like to understand that 76 million contribution to net income. Historically, when I've asked questions like this, both off and on line, my understanding was that, that essentially nets to zero, so it's not entirely relevant. What drove the 76 million in the quarter, and did that have a bottom line effect? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're just pulling the number up and getting to the page, Mario, so we're all looking at the same number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Russel Robertson speaking, that is the gain on the securitization of bank owned assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, every quarter prior to that as has been described to me, there shouldn't really be much of a bottom line impact. So, I guess what I'm getting at is, the 76, what did that add to the bottom line this quarter and why was it so different from prior quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's different because there was more of it, there was more assets securitized.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess the point is, why wouldn't that have been offset in the NII line? It always is, I guess, is what I'm getting at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, just that -- it would be, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The point is, it wasn't. It's 76 million in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was, Mario at our end. Maybe I could just take that offline, but from our perspective, maybe you're looking at it differently. It is being offset up on the NII line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The way -- when I've asked this in past, you've always explained that the net income effect is negligible as I can see here. Was there a positive impact to earnings this quarter of $76 million pre-tax?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there wasn't.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There wasn't? I don't understand then because every other quarter you have pointed me to that line as the reason why there is no impact, and it's showing that the impact of securitization on net income before income taxes was 76 million. That doesn't jive with how you've just answered me. The caption says the impact of securitization on net income before taxes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll tell you what, given the benefit of the fact that the question has been answered to you specifically in the past, why don't we take it offline. We'll reconcile the previous answers to where we are and I think Viki's answer is factually correct. But we want to make sure that we take you back to your reference point if that makes sense, Mario.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really. I'll ask something else though, the page 17 of the Fairway assets and Fairway, the -- what I understand, what is it about Fairway? Like when you talk about the 600 million or so, what particular lines is it coming from? Like that 600 million, would it be from the commercial real estate loans?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It would have been from the commercial real estate loans, that's right. So, you see the numbers for commercial real estate, and that's the area that the three loans that we have funded came from.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that 800 million that we see is CP outstanding. That's net of the 600 million that's come out, is that right? The number would have been larger, I suppose?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is correct. These numbers are after the removal of the three loans that came out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess what I'm getting at here is, where is -- when we look at the schedule on page 17, we look at CP outstanding, how much of this could actually come back at BMO, and where would you point, what particular line items would be the areas of risk? I guess it would be the 800 million remaining and commercial real estate loans, that would be one are, because presumably that's where we saw it from before, maybe the residential mortgage is prime 200 million? Is there anything else you'd point me to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We -- this is a portfolio that currently funded is about $7 billion. You see the breakdown. Overall, the portfolio is we think high quality as we've talked about earlier. The paper issued by Fairway is well rated, and the individual assets within Fairway are investment grade rated, either on our own scoring system or as rated by external agencies, and about half are rated. So we think the assets are good, and really that we're in a situation here where we've a sector in the US that has been hit very hard, as people know, and exposures to that area are feeling some pain. So we based on the work that we have done, right now we think that it's isolated to those areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so I'll leave it here. But it sounds to me like the issue is, that 800 million, that's the only stuff that looks similar and feels similar to the 600 million that's already been brought on. Is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is fair by category, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But not in terms of the underlying quality --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think &#x2013; obviously, the categories are different. We've got a diversified portfolio here. And based on the work that we've done over the quarter, we haven't identified other issues of immediate concern in the portfolio. And as you said, given the world that we're living in, commercial real estate is an area generally that is of focus and concern for people. That said we don't see immediate concerns in the commercial real estate that's sitting in Fairway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful. Thanks, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Sumit Malhotra, please go ahead -- sorry of Merrill Lynch, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good afternoon. It was interesting to hear Russ talk about probable margin pressure in the back half of the year because it's quite different from what we've heard from one of your competitors about an hour ago. Specifically, can you give us a little bit more detail on whether you're more concerned about your yields on loans or your funding costs and I bring it up in a context that it was just one week ago that we saw BMO announcing pretty substantial declines in your posted mortgage rates which made me think you're feeling better about your funding. So I'll leave it there and get your thoughts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Sumit, it's Frank. I think we're happy with the performance in Q2 as Russ has already mentioned with margins up quarter-over-quarter and year-over-year. And I think the way I would characterize it is, I am resisting the urge to be optimistic about the second half. We think we're managing our mix extremely well. We think we're being able to re-price in the marketplace and be competitive to support our margins, but we're still seeing pressure from a term funding perspective. And it's just too difficult to predict what's going to happen over the next six months, so I'm cautiously optimistic around margins for next year and feeding into our overall performance in P&amp;C Canada. I do think the second half of the year is going to be better than the first half of the year and I'm not sure that we can do that without our margins holding up. So, we're feeling pretty optimistic about our ability to support the margin going through the second half of the year subject to again managing our funding premiums as the next couple of quarters unfold.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I take that into account. I see where you're going with this. I guess the thing I'd ask is making the move on the mortgage rates last week, is this an attempt to stem the decline in market share that we've seen for a long period time? And obviously we know with the broker network changes that's been an issue or, I just can't see why if you were that concerned about your funding costs, you would make such a, as I recall, I think you led the market in this move?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't think we did. We moved along with the rest of the markets, so I wouldn't characterize us as being the first mover. The market moved, the short-term rates came down. We moved, we still preserved our spreads on the business we're doing for those terms. And we feel comfortable that we're going to be able to compete and do so effectively. We don't want to be off-market as well as we continue to try to manage our margin which is why I'm so optimistic about and confident and positive about what we've done in this quarter, because we've been competitive. And we've been winning more than our fair share as we move forward with this mortgage strategy. So, we're going to compete, Sumit. We're not going to be off marketplace from a pricing perspective, and we were just moving with the rest of the market. I think everybody's in line at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for that. Lastly, commercial banking in Canada, the source of pride for the bank, obviously we all know what's going on with the credit market in the US. But a little bit of chatter about, I think it was agriculture, manufacturing, some issues in Canada. Can you talk about the health of your Canadian commercial book, and is that just the mix here? Is most of that in P&amp;C, Frank, or does some of that go through &#x2013; it's not IBG anymore, the Capital Market segment, maybe just an update on how the commercial business in Canada is trending, because their revenue growth at least in P&amp;C Canada seems like it's pretty flat?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We are real happy with the market share gains that we've seen in our commercial loan book. And as you know, from a commercial perspective, that is a portion of the business. It's one side of the balance sheet. It's the only one we can measure externally. So we're happy and it's an indication of how we're doing from a competitive perspective, and we saw another increase this quarter. So we're happy about that. The revenue growth is being challenged again by some of the spread issues, not only the spreads on the loan side, but also there's been an increase in competition on deposits. And so spreads are under pressure from a deposit perspective as well, and we've got a lot of customers that don't borrow, that are cash management and deposit only customers. So, there's two sides to the business. Relative to our credit quality in our loan book, we are still feeling very good not withstanding the comments that were made about a couple of the sectors that are under pressure. And we're only talking about those because it's reality in the market place. We are seeing a little bit of softness, but we're not concerned about the overall quality of the portfolio and our strategy with respect to the commercial business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Michael Goldberg of the Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Wonder if I could get more detail on the $128 million mark-to-market gain on credit derivatives. I'm told this isn't the Section 3855 Financial Instruments adjustment. So what is it? Is it a net of long and short credit derivative positions? And secondly, where and how much are the 3855 Financial Instrument items?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Russ Robertson. Let me first address the question on the counter-party credit holdback exposures. The fair value of our derivative portfolios are impacted by the market credit spreads for both ourselves and our counterparties. And in the current environment when the credit spreads are changing more than they have in the past, this does create volatility in our trading revenue. You may recall in the first quarter we recognized a loss of 78 million pre-tax, 52 million after tax, because the spreads of our counter parties had moved out compared to BMO spreads. In Q2 we recognized a gain of, as you mentioned, 128 million pre-tax because BMO spreads have moved out compared to spreads of our counter parties. So we calculated this adjustment on a counter party by counter party basis, and it's reflected in the results of our trading portfolios that contain derivatives. And on the second question, it's not material in NII.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, but I'm not hearing you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, he answered the question. He said that the second question, it is not a material amount.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I thought there was something else he was going to add.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. He said in NII, I thought he was going to say something else too, but --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Also, can you tell us how much the Wisconsin acquisitions added to personal loans, mortgages, business loans, personal long-term deposits, and risk weighted assets in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, <mark type="inaudible" /> I only have -- we only have a third of the assets and deposits in the quarter, because we closed part way through the quarter, and I have that information handy, if you could just bear with me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Don't you get all the assets once you close?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We only adopt them on a proportional basis for the time that we own them. So they show up in our results as earning assets for that one-month period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm talking about the balance sheet assets though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They show up on our balance sheet on the same basis as the ownership, which is a third through the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So what are those amounts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The amounts on the deposit side looked to be -- I think these are commercial, aren't they? Quarter-over-quarter would be 577.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is this just personal long-term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's all loans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no. Deposits.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the deposit number is 521.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is that just personal long-term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have that breakdown with me, Michael. I can come back to you with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're talking about core versus non-core?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I don't care about the non-core.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll have to come back to you with those numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the personal mortgage and business loans?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Home equity loans total about 110 million. Mortgages are about 300 -- I'm rounding here a little bit -- and other retail is probably about 60. C&amp;I would be a total of -- and I'm giving you the total balance sheet here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably about 500, and on the real estate side you're talking 200 plus another 375. These are really rough, so I probably should come back to you and firm them up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't you do that? And what about the impact on risk-weighted assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll have to come back to you on that one too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And I'd like to go back to the non-performing loan formations. Latest quarter includes the Fairway gross formation and also, excluding Fairway, it's about $400-odd million up from -- just a second, I'm just -- that's -- just looking for the page in the sup-pack -- oh yes, here it is. So, excluding Fairway, it's 423, up from 249. So I guess the question is, what -- can you give us some idea of what sort of things are in the 423? And also, obviously, there have been -- there's been further change in Fairway from what you expected in the first quarter when you took out a performing loan, as well as a non-performing loan, so why should we feel comfort that there won't be more that you'll have to take out of Fairway?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you just tell me, Michael, what page you are looking at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Looking at page 37 of the sup-pack and I am looking at the gross formation line, 708 in Q1 and 554 this quarter and tying that in with the slide 13 of the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The other areas that we are seeing growth are really consistent with the comments I made earlier. We have US residential real estate exposures that are commercial in nature that are contributing to formations and impaired and that is reflective of the same dynamic that we talked about earlier related to the housing market. We've got some softness in certain other manufacturing sectors. There are sort of two things that play; one relates to the combination of the higher dollar and the weakness in the economy having an effect on some of the manufacturers in the Central part of Canada. And then we have a few cases of manufacturers that are tied to the US residential housing sector experiencing problems. And other sectors of note other than just the normal growth in formations that you'd see at this point of the cycle would be real estate and forest products, and the forest products industry is experiencing some weakness, which has been getting some press. And on the -- sorry, on the agricultural side, there are two issues that we are seeing. One is with the higher cost of feed costs; some protein producers are experiencing some weakness. And then secondly, some hot house businesses are experiencing a bit of pressure because of a combination of the dollar and higher fuel costs. With respect to Fairway and the potential for additional loans to come out of it, Fairway is a roughly $7 billion portfolio on a funded basis. It's diversified, it's high quality like we've talked about earlier, but it is like in some respects a loan portfolio, and so there is the potential for other loans to experience trouble. But we think that the loans are well rated, they are well structured, and we don't see other issues of immediate concern, but that's not to say that there won't be anything in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. It's Russ Robertson for a point of clarification; make sure we're clear on the Wisconsin acquisition. We did take on all the assets of this Wisconsin Bank, which were consolidated at April 30.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Andr&#xE9; Hardy of RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I have two questions. The first relates to page 29 of the supplementary package, and if we look at, in Canada, the increases in credit card delinquencies in the last two years, and same on the mortgage side, what is causing that? Is that a reflection of the bank trying to take on more risk and pricing for that, and getting binged with higher delinquencies? Or is that older business in the areas that have been affected by job losses, which are leading to high delinquencies? And kind of related to that, did that accelerate as the quarter went on?</p>
          <p>And my second question is on Fairway. We've had a few instances of a bank buying loans that were going to have issues, and my question is, at what point is the bank going to have to bring this on balance sheet, because it looks like the bank's going to take the losses anyway? So, when we, or when you do the test of who has the biggest interest in this, it kind of looks like you have the biggest interest in the losses? So I'm just trying to understand what needs to happen for you to bring this on balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andr&#xE9;, I'll take the first question around the credit card business. Over the last year or so, we have changed some of our credit strategies in our card business. So our expectation would be we would see a little higher formations and a little higher delinquencies in that portfolio. The increases that we've seen are completely in line with our expectations relative to those change in strategies. So I would say that the answer to your question is the increase is as a result of management action, not what we're seeing in the marketplace. And relative to mortgages, the mortgage business has been a little lumpy for us over the last couple of quarters from a loss perspective. We have been dealing with some isolated issues in a couple of the marketplaces, dealing with some of our mortgage specialists, and that's really what's driven some of those changes, again not related to increasing our risk profile, and not related to what we're seeing really from an economic perspective in the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Frank. All right, let me speak to the Fairway question because it's -- I sensed the question is being asked, the same question is being asked in a couple of different ways. The transactions that we've taken out of Fairway are specifically deals that we believe that are going to benefit enormously from early remediation from having our Special Assets Group take control of them to work on the workout of the credits. And in that sense, the remaining securitizations in Fairway, not only are they performing in line with expectations, but they're not in that category. The reason why we moved on them very quickly is you're right, we ultimately provide the commercial paper back up to the facilities, so if there were issues with the credits and they were allowed to deteriorate to the point that funding support was necessary for the vehicles, then we would do that. But we don't contemplate consolidation; we don't contemplate having to take additional loans onto our balance sheet. That said Tom has cautioned that the environment will do what the environment will do, but our focus on those three credits is on the recovery of them, on the effective workout of them. And there those commitments were made on the same standards of lending as the bank's commercial lending standards, so it's a product that we're familiar with and believe that are best managed directly by the bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess what I'm not clear on is it doesn't seem like there's been a transfer of risk here if you're going to take on the loans that are having issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that as I said, specifically with these three credits, the nature of them lend themselves so out intervention and workout. The credit loss exposure in the aggregate portfolio is the exposure to the investors and our backstop is liquidity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And the next question is from Ian De Verteuil of BMO Capital Markets, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm referring to page 19 of the supplemental pack, when I look at the RWAs on the Basel II, one of the things that spiked up a lot this quarter was a line called securitization. Can someone speak to why that's up $6 billion? Does it -- the only thing I can think is maybe it relates to some of the structures that have come back on, can anyone help?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's Tommy. And the biggest reason for the increase relates to Apex/Sitka and the restructuring that we completed during the quarter with the other stakeholders who were involved in that. And at the time that we announced the restructuring, we indicated that there would be an impact on the capital ratios as a result of the RWA that flow from the restructuring that was done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. So that's the bulk of that increase. If, following on Andr&#xE9;'s question, there's some debate about Fairway, whether it's an off-balance sheet structure or not. What would be the impact if it were consolidated? Is it just sort of a $7 billion times some risk weighting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There currently is a 20% risk weighting against the back-up liquidity that we provide, and that would be on the number that's closer to 10 billion, because that's the liquidity amount. We don't expect to consolidate. We don't see any reason for that to occur given the accounting rules that we live by. If we did consolidate then the 7 billion would be converted into RWA, and would flow through to capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That's very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our last question is from Brad Smith from Blackmont Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I just wanted to make sure that I was clear with respect to the, I hate to say, with this Fairway and the loans that have come back on your books. On page 17 of the presentation pack, Tom, you're showing I think a current balance of $1.2 billion in these commercial loans. I believe on page 13, you indicated that you've taken already 851 million, I believe, it's out of that line item onto your balance sheet for a total of just over $2 billion in aggregate of which 590 million, I believe, is currently non-accrual, which is about 29% performance ratio. And I was just curious. I think I had heard earlier, it was said these are loans underwritten to the bank standard, and I was just wondering is that all just because of concentration? And could you help me out with the 1.2, just in terms of how many loans are actually in that number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think all of your math was right, as I followed it, so you've got those numbers right. And really what's happened here is, the loans that we have taken out were tied to the US residential housing market. And that market, as everyone knows, has suffered a significant decline and we've experienced the impaireds and we've taken some provisions as a result. So to me, what's different here isn't that the loans were underwritten in a fashion that wasn't appropriate. All of the assets in Fairway are subject to our normal underwriting practices. It's a case of having exposure, like banks do, to a sector that is going through a tough crunch. The exposures, really in one case, are not small. One of the loans is relatively large as was commented on earlier, and again, we got comfortable with that at the time because the nature of the underlying portfolio was quite diversified. So that was the thought process with respect to the concentration risk at the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just -- thank you very much for that. Just with respect to the remaining liquidity exposure of 1.2 billion, is there further residential in that, or is that now all cleared out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there would be some further residential related in that number, but I don't have a precise number for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think that was -- I think that was the last question in the queue. I'm going to wrap up quickly before I turn it over to Viki. I just want to reiterate some of the comments that were made at the beginning of the call.</p>
          <p>I think, first of all, since the last quarter, in the last 90 days, we've ticked off a fairly significant list of issues that were prominent on the last call, and done it pretty much in line with the way that we had laid out our expectation, and from that we take some confidence. With respect to credit markets, there is no question that we're vigilant and it's an appropriate time to be vigilant. But I would reiterate that this is an area where, as a bank, we have particular strengths, that we've shown a track record over a period of time. We have the professionals that are qualified to recognize, identify issues early, to intervene quickly and to work them very aggressively, and to the extent that there is an emergence of problem credits in the system as a whole, I have confidence in our capacity to deal with it. And I think through the cycles not much has changed in terms of the professionals that we have on the frontline or the system that we use. So I think it is an appropriate time to be vigilant around credit risk; at the same time I think it's an area of strength. The management of credit risk is an area of strength for our bank.</p>
          <p>And the last point that I would make is that I think this quarter provides some visibility that is really helpful with respect to the operating groups, and the expectation that we have that in all four operating groups, we're going to see growth in the future. Tom Milroy was spared questions on this call, as his first time out with respect to BMO Capital Markets, but that business is, has been a very strong contributor to the company over a long period of time. I think as we've shown very good progress in managing the risk back into a zone we're more comfortable with, I expect it to be, continuing to be a contributor. And with respect to personal and commercial and wealth, we are getting benefits out of the focus on customers. It is paying off in terms of both customer loyalty and in a stronger position in the marketplace, and we intend to compete very hard for business.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll turn it over to you, Viki.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. On behalf of the management team here today, thanks very much for participating on the call with us. And any more follow-up questions, please contact the Investor Relations department, we'd be happy to take care of them for you. Thanks very much. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The conference has now ended. Please disconnect your lines at this time, and we thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>