<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1153133" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-04-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7782</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Maximilian Sch&#xF6;berl, Director of Corporate and Governmental Affairs</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Dr. Norbert Reithofer, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Michael Ganal, Finance</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4">Maximilian Sch&#xF6;berl</participant>
      <participant id="5">Michael Ganal</participant>
      <participant id="6">Norbert Reithofer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to our Q1 Conference &#x2013; the Q1 conference of the BMW Group in 2008. My name is Maximilian Sch&#xF6;berl, the Director of Corporate and Governmental Affairs of the BMW Group. On the phone today we have Dr. Norbert Reithofer, the Chairman of the Board of Management of BMW AG and Dr. Michael Ganal, our member of the Board of Management, responsible for Finance. Both gentlemen will give you an overview of developments in the first quarter and then we will have time to later cover your questions.</p>
          <p>Let me give the phone to Dr. Reithofer right away.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning ladies and gentlemen. Good morning from me too and I must say I am very happy indeed to have you on the phone this year again for our first telephone conference. Let me emphasize three points right away at the beginning of this conference. First of all, we've improved our operational performance in the first quarter of 2008. Second, we are implementing the various steps established in our strategy number one as planned. And thirdly, we are determined to achieve our ambitious goals for the whole business year in 2008.</p>
          <p>However, we are facing significant external burdens mainly with regard to the economic slowdown. So consumers especially in the United States are not in a buying mood. This is why we have stepped up this management, which has had a dampening effect on our first quarter results. We have taken the best possible steps to compensate for additional strains that might arise. Dr. Ganal will tell you more about these activities in a moment.</p>
          <p>Where do we stand following the first three months of the current year of business? Well, let me give you some details. As you know, BMW Group Automobile Retail increased 5.6% year on year to a total of over 351,000 units. Motorcycle Retail for the first quarter stood at some 21,000 units, down 8.6% from the first quarter 2007.</p>
          <p>We experienced this decline in retail due, for example, to unexpected market developments in Spain and France in March. And in Germany, a late set of winter weather delayed the start of the motorcycle season and led to a drop in sales. From the second quarter onwards, we expect sales to pick up also due to the introduction of two new Enduro models.</p>
          <p>In our Financial Services business, the number of leasing and financing agreements administered with dealerships and end customers rose to 2.7 million, exceeding last year's figure by 15.6%.</p>
          <p>Now, how have revenues and earnings developed in the first quarter? Group revenues were up 11.2%, to over &#x20AC;13.28 billion compared with the first quarter 2007. Income before taxes was &#x20AC;641 million, a decrease of approximately 24.8% from the three-month period of the previous year, the first three months.</p>
          <p>As mentioned earlier, the first quarter was characterized by negative effects, &#x20AC;236 million alone, resulting from the increase in risk provisions already mentioned. Adjusted for this amount, we have, therefore, got an entirely different situation. And we also spent &#x20AC;236 million on the change in workforce. So again, without these amounts, our revenues would actually have risen.</p>
          <p>A key factor of our success is the strong attraction in efficiency of our cars, ladies and gentlemen. Let me give you just two examples here. In the first quarter alone, we delivered almost 50,000 units of the BMW 1 Series to customers, over 50% more than in the same period last year.</p>
          <p>An important growth driver in this context has been the new BMW 1 Series Coup&#xE9; and the new BMW X5 in turn was launched in summer 2007 with sales in the first quarter of 2008 amounting to more than 31,000 units.</p>
          <p>This year we're again enlarging our model portfolio with the BMW brand 1 Series convertible has been available since March. The BMW M3 convertible came next in April together with the new BMW MX6, which was first launched in the United States. From May on, it will be available also in Europe.</p>
          <p>MINI has already presented two new models this year, as of summer, the MINI John Cooper Works and the MINI John Cooper Works Clubman will be in the market at the dealership. And the first Rolls Royce Sansone Coup&#xE9; is scheduled to be delivered to the customer in the second half of the year, showing again that we are and continue to be strong in the market.</p>
          <p>And I can assure you that we will be launching further new models this year. Indeed, we definitely have some surprises up our sleeves, surprises still coming your way, surprises in the pipeline. These new models are making our fleet even more environmentally friendly. As you know, we intend to sell over 800,000 BMWs and MINIs this year equipped with our Efficient Dynamics package. This is how we are strengthening our competitive advantage with regard to the reduction of fuel consumption and emissions across our entire fleet.</p>
          <p>Another positive aspect here is the introduction of our first BMW advanced vehicle with blue performance models in the USA this fall. Please allow me to make a few remarks also on the global car markets where we expect further dynamic growth this year, mainly in the emerging countries.</p>
          <p>Compared with the first quarter 2007, the BMW Group, our sales rose over 40% in Chinese markets in the period under report, that is in China and Hong Kong, Taiwan. The new BMW X6 was extremely well received at the recent Beijing Motor Show and China will remain a key growth market for us. This is why we are considering, as you would probably already know to expand our production capacities in China from currently 41,000 units in the medium term to a higher level.</p>
          <p>The example of China in our opinion demonstrates how important it is to be active in the right markets, at the right time. This helps us to compensate for temporary weaknesses in other markets, at least to a certain extent.</p>
          <p>So ladies and gentleman, where do we stand today in implementing our strategy? What is our status quo? Well, you can rest assured that we are right on track. At present the corporate strategy has been cascaded down to the divisions to all divisions and departments. And we are also on course when it comes to enhancing efficiency and implementing the reduction in workforce by 3,100 permanent staff as already mentioned for which purpose we saved 40 million in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>We are, ladies and gentlemen, one of the truly international companies in our industry. The United States is our most important, our largest single market. And that's you know we benefited from our strong presence in the US market in the past.</p>
          <p>You have of course all been observing the developments in the International Financial markets and now also in our business environment. Our operations are experiencing the negative impact of the International Financial prices as well. We have previously outlined the risks for the Automobile segment and the financial services business in our annual report and at several conferences. In the last few weeks the financial crisis has become worse and has hurt consumer sentiment. This has affected the North American pre-owned car markets, to an extent that could not be an anticipated at the beginning of this year.</p>
          <p>As a consequence the resale condition of the cars after the leasing periods have worsened and the fact that a large number of leasing contracts ended in the first quarter of 2008 has compounded the situation. We have nevertheless taken action and will put the necessary risk provisions in place.</p>
          <p>Last quarter, as you know, we published an ad hoc announcement stating that we are increasing our risk provision. We expect these activities have increased to be sufficient as a precaution for the time being, based on the current assessment of market trends. We remain confident that the steps taken will cover the risks involved. However, should the risk situation in the course of the year, especially with pre-owned cars show that there is not the recovery we anticipated, we might have to increase our efforts in taking precautions at the expense of our 2008 financial results.</p>
          <p>Right now, however, we confirm our profit forecast for 2008 as we're convinced that we've taken the right steps and expect the markets to recover in the second half of the year. Therefore, our outlook for the year remains unchanged. We will continue our successful business development in 2008.</p>
          <p>We plan to achieve new retail records for all three brands. We plan to achieve a pre-tax profit on Group level above last year's results, adjusted for the book gain on the Rolls-Royce exchangeable bond in 2007. And we plan to achieve an improvement in the quality of earnings.</p>
          <p>The BMW Group will continue to stand for long-term growth and the enhancement of value. And the Board is fully committed, also in its new composition, to this goal. Today, we have talked a lot about short-term effects, ladies and gentlemen. In conclusion, therefore, let me draw your attention to two current studies, which have made me personally very happy, as they show that our long-term strategy is the right approach.</p>
          <p>First, according to analysis by market researcher, Willard Brown, BMW is the most valuable German brand among all global brands worldwide. Second, the Boston Consultant Group recently surveyed almost 3,000 executives worldwide, ranking the BMW Group number 14 among the world's most innovative companies. They have stated in justifying this that while other car manufacturers are talking about new efficient drive systems, BMW has these systems in the market already.</p>
          <p>And I have nothing to add to that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dr. Reithofer. Now, Dr. Ganal, let me ask you to continue, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, I too would like to bid you a very warm welcome today. Good morning and great to have you with us. Since Dr. Reithofer has now given you a general overview, I would like to provide you with some additional details on the development of our business.</p>
          <p>First, however, let me emphasize a couple of points &#x2013; a couple of important things. The first point is that we achieved positive operating performance in the first quarter of 2008. Despite the difficult market environment, we increased our sales volume by 5.6%, and our revenues are up 11.2%.</p>
          <p>As Dr. Reithofer has stated, this was reflected in an improvement in our operating profits and a significant rise in the free cash flow. However, of course, it was also affected, quite generally, by the world financial crisis, which now has a significant impact also on the overall economy.</p>
          <p>So we are, therefore, faced with another extraordinary external burden, not just the usual currency risks and the additional burden of raw material prices, but also again the financial crisis. This has required us to take special measures in the first quarter, and it has overshadowed the successes achieved in terms of sales and operating profits.</p>
          <p>As a result, our Group EBIT dropped 9.3% in the first quarter to &#x20AC;827 million. The burdens stemming from the financial crisis consist of three effects. First, the decline in demand in the North American pre-owned vehicle market triggered by the crisis. This caused leased cars returns to be marketed at prices lower than in the past.</p>
          <p>Second, the higher risk provision, which had to be taken for cars leased out. This became necessary due to the used car price trend observed with its negative effects. And then the third point, increased bad debts and payment delays in the financial services business which was another reason for the rise in risk provisions, for the need to increase our risk provisions</p>
          <p>Now let me move on to the segments -- the various segments. The first effect is the erosion of prices in the pre-owned vehicle business already mentioned. This bodes well, as I said, to the individual segments where most of this effect is felt by and in the automobiles segment. This is because we take an integral approach to our leasing business.</p>
          <p>In order to ensure that lease returns are marketed with optimum results and generate positive effects on the new car business as well, the automobile and financial services segment work together and therefore share the risk. In principle our automobile business displayed good operating development as planned. Driven by the positive retail trend in the new car business, revenues were up 6.5%, climbing to &#x20AC;12.2 billion.</p>
          <p>However unlike in the new car business the pre-owned car business clearly felt the impact of the less interest and the slowing economy above all in North America. This is to a certain extent because customers in this segment react more strongly to the general economic downturn than the traditional purchaser of a premium car. This is why the prices which are clearly obtained for our pre-owned cars in North America have decreased significantly, but still remain higher in proportional terms in percentage terms than with our competitors.</p>
          <p>In principle, we expected this development at the end of 2007 as well in our risk provision, but of course at the time our forecast was based on the information available back then. Now, we've reached the point where the extent of the development has exceeded even what our old risk provision was able to cover. This has happened above all in March, and the income we've recently generated from the new marketing of lease returns is therefore lower than what we had budgeted at the end of last year. In addition the decline in used car prices means that we have to build a higher risk provision for leased out vehicles that are to be marketed in future.</p>
          <p>This again has had a negative effect on the earnings trend in the automobile segment in the first quarter. We already referred to these risks at our annual account press conference. Since then we have continued to monitor and analyze the situation, and considering that the situation has become much more serious in the first quarter, we've decided to act now and to take precautions for the entire year 2008.</p>
          <p>Due to the development on the pre-owned car markets already mentioned, the effect I've referred to amounts to &#x20AC;157 million in the automobiles segment, again, &#x20AC;157 million. Accordingly EBIT in this segment totaled &#x20AC;619 million, 6.4% below the &#x20AC;661 million in the same period last year.</p>
          <p>The EBIT margin in the automobile business in Q1 was therefore 5.1%. The operating level adjusted for the &#x20AC;157 million special burden. We have however significantly improved both earnings and rate of return compared with the same quarter last year.</p>
          <p>The adjusted EBIT generated by the automobile segment was 17.4% higher year-on-year. The adjusted EBIT margin amounted to 6.4% in turn and was substantially higher than the 5.8% in Q1 2007. The segment profit before tax totaled &#x20AC;539 million, following &#x20AC;609 million in the same quarter last year.</p>
          <p>Now let's move on to the financial services segment. Here again we look back at a good quarter in operative terms, with the business value disclosed in our balance sheet increasing 10.4% to more than &#x20AC;50 billion. The number of contracts concluded with customers declined 18.5% to over 282,000 and segment revenues were boosted 25% to &#x20AC;3.86 billion.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, the situation in the financial markets is clearly being felt particularly. First of all, we have the impairment of the assumed residual values which has had a significant impact. Then at the same time payment delays in credit defaults have required us to make higher risks provisions, our bad debt ratio is at 0.53% as compared to 0.46% for the full year in 2007.</p>
          <p>Taking these two effects together they amount to &#x20AC;79 million, combined that is. Accordingly EBIT generated by the financial services segment in the first quarter dropped considerably falling by 58% or &#x20AC;109 million or fully vetted by 58% or &#x20AC;109 million to &#x20AC;79 million. Net of the one off effect EBIT came in at &#x20AC;158 million and was therefore 60% lower on lower.</p>
          <p>I will state later how the development in this area for the remaining course of the year is expected to continue, but first let me comment on the motorcycle business and reconciliations as well as some key items in our income statement.</p>
          <p>First the motorcycle segment. Here in the first quarter deliveries to customers were down 8.6% to some 21,000 units. We already explained the effects of this at the beginning of this call, the reasons and the effects. The decrease in retail caused revenues to decline by 6% to &#x20AC;345 million. Conversely we kept EBIT in the motorcycle business at a constant &#x20AC;36 million which proves the efficiency measures we've initiated in the preceding years and which of course is still continuing.</p>
          <p>This takes me on to reconciliations. Here, we generated an EBIT of &#x20AC;93 million and a profit before tax of minus &#x20AC;16 million. I will make some comments on the underlying effects later on in connection with our financial results.</p>
          <p>So much, therefore, ladies and gentlemen, on the various areas of business. Now, let me return to the Group level and start, first, with the various items in the Group income statement. I can be brief here and just make a few remarks on the key items and how they have changed.</p>
          <p>First, let me refer to the Group revenues, which in the first quarter increased as a result of retail by 11.2%, to &#x20AC;13.3 billion. The cost of sales increased as well, showing a disproportionately high rise  of 13.3%. This, of course, is attributable to the effects of the impairment in residual value losses already mentioned.</p>
          <p>Selling and administrative expenses also increased in this case by 5.7% or &#x20AC;71 million, to &#x20AC;1.3 billion. This is attributable, first of all, to the expansion in business volume and then to the planned expenses associated with the reduction of our workforce, which as communicated have been shown as a one-off effect in 2008.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter, these expenses, these costs amounted to &#x20AC;40 million. And I can tell you that we're making good progress in the targeted reduction of our head count. Research and development costs were up 12.9% to &#x20AC;719 million, and the capitalization rate was 32.7%.</p>
          <p>On top of all that, as in the same quarter last year, the persistently high raw material prices and carrying through effects were a burden on our cost base. As announced, we expect the additional currency burden for the full year to be lower than in 2007.</p>
          <p>As already mentioned, this gives us a Group EBIT of &#x20AC;827 million and an EBIT margin, as a result again, of 6.2%. Net of the previously mentioned one off effects totaling &#x20AC;236 million, Group EBIT improves substantially rising 16.6% to &#x20AC;1.063 billion. This corresponds to an EBIT margin of 8.0%. We have actually therefore outperformed the 7.6% recorded for the full year in 2007, from an operational point of view we're better than in 2007 as a whole.</p>
          <p>The other financial result was burdened by the negative effects of the fair valuation of standalone derivatives. Due to a change in infrastructure, the market values of these financial instruments experienced a negative trend. On balance, the financial results increased to minus &#x20AC;186 million compared with minus &#x20AC;60 million in the first quarter 2007.</p>
          <p>All in all our Group profit before tax totaled &#x20AC;641 million, that is 24.8% higher than in the first quarter last year. The taxes on profits were &#x20AC;154 million compared with &#x20AC;265 million in the same period last year, corresponding to an effective tax rate of 24%, which means that as announced for the full year, the tax rate is back over 20% following a much lower rate in third and fourth quarters of 2007 owing to the corporate tax reform in Germany. This of course as you know was an exception. Bottom-line therefore, we generated a net profit of -- on Group level of &#x20AC;487 million in the first quarter, 17% down on Q1 2007.</p>
          <p>Now let me move on to our cash flow. Operating cash flow that is the cash inflow from operating activities in our industrial operations amounted to &#x20AC;1.05 billion representing a year-on-year decrease of 11.8% or &#x20AC;148 million.</p>
          <p>The cash outflow from investing activities in the industrial business declined by 23.5% or &#x20AC;201 million to &#x20AC;653 million. Free cash flow from industrial operations therefore advanced by 13.3% to &#x20AC;452 million. As already mentioned we wanted to use our cash and cash equivalents to transfer our pension obligations in three tranches for a  total of &#x20AC;3.8 billion. The first tranche is due in summer and we've already taken the first step by establishing the BMW trust and we will keep you informed of further of ongoing developments in this area too.</p>
          <p>Now ladies and gentlemen in summary, let me make the following points. First, we are doing well operationally despite the difficult market environment. But in the light of the far reaching impact of the financial prices above all in North America we are confronted with additional burdens and risks in the first quarter. As regards to the full year however I would like to emphasize what Dr. Reithofer has already said and that is that even if general conditions becoming worse, we aim to continue our basic business trend in, our successful business trend that is, in the 2008 business year.</p>
          <p>Now you may ask of course, what makes us optimistic? First of all it's the stable growth that we see in our areas &#x2013; in all areas of business. We aim to achieve new retail records with all three of our car brands. Second we are offsetting the increased risks and burdens but I've taken appropriate measures in retail and on the cost side. And we are doing this in addition to the measures we constantly take anyway to enhance efficiency and to improve productivity.</p>
          <p>We are also expecting used car prices will not drop further in the foreseeable future. Over the medium to long term we are indeed looking at a recovery here as the US economy stabilizes. The number of lease returns is always highest in the first quarter; this causes residual values to decline and in the next few months the number of returns will go back down again, and as result the situation of expected to ease up.</p>
          <p>In addition we've initiated an action which has stabilized used car prices even further. We therefore believe that the risk through provision we established in the first quarter will be sufficient for the rest of the year.</p>
          <p>Naturally, we are can not predict the future and we nevertheless remain optimistic, even though of course painting a black picture gives you a better hearing often in bad times. But we must all remember that quarterly reports are of course only a glimpse of general development, with only a limited meaning. Of course as I said already we to cannot predict the future. And should therefore the pre-owned car market will not recover over the course of 2008, the negative effect on our business may become more substantial. That risk is conceivable but from our current point of view we confirm our earnings forecast. We still intend in 2008 to increase our profit before tax over the level we achieved last year, net of the one off effect of the Rolls-Royce exchangeable bond in 2007.</p>
          <p>So we are looking here again at further improvement. Ladies and gentlemen, first thank you very much for your attention. And now we'd be very happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dr. Ganal. Now, ladies and Gentlemen, let ask our colleagues in Frankfurt to give you the technical remarks for the conference and for the Q&amp;A session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>Our first question is from Michael Koontz of <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mr. Koontz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give us a bit more information on the actions you're taking to stabilize used car prices in the USA? What have you done for this purpose? And then what are the impacts of the current situation in reducing your head count? As Dr. Reithofer has said, we're making good progress here. And is it true as well that in administration and management, you also employ far too many people? And can you tell us, if that is the case, how many superfluous people do you have, how many redundancies there are? And then the third point, is it possible that you might take recourse against your former CFO who obviously misjudged the dollar and didn't provide for adequate hedging for this purpose? Is it possible that you might seek recourse against him?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Mr. Koontz..  I think we'll start with Dr. Ganal, first of all, on the action taken by the company on the reduction of the number of employees and associates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the first point is how do we see the US business, the used car business in the United States, what is our output based on? The figures from March, you see, were exceptional figures, suffering from market conditions, suffering from a very difficult situation in the US markets in March, and also suffering from other specific factors and criteria because in March we had an extremely large number of off leases, an unusually large number.</p>
          <p>Taking all of these factors together, we've decided not to take March as a new guideline, you might say, a benchmark, but rather to include March as part of the first quarter's, one month in the first quarter, and to therefore take the first quarter as average, an average period for loss provisions, the average figure. That's the starting point.</p>
          <p>Of course, that does not explain, at least it doesn't sufficiently explain, whether we have the right assessment, the right outlook for the future. Well, what are we doing? In principle as in the past we have got our Certified Pre-Owned business, our CPO which has always given us a very good and stable basis for doing our used car business professionally with stable prices. Last year more than 90,000 cars in this category were marketed successfully. And we know that marketing a car in this category is of course an important stabilizing factor. This is why we have once again got together in our sales and financial services organizations in order to improve our cooperation in order to consistently sell cars through our dealerships and to market them to our dealerships in this class. This we are convinced should give us a significant improvement of business and also reduction of marketing through auctions, which shouldn't happen that much any more.</p>
          <p>In the past up to 30, three-zero of our cars, 30% were auctioned, that's how they entered the market. We know that there price concessions are much greater, and that's why we have put together a very intense working package in order to reduce the number of cars that are auctioned, which are sold in an auction. Of course, we also interact with interviewers in earlier point in time increasing our lease rates accordingly in order to take the market better into account. These activities, therefore, which support the progress made already, that is in March, we had an exceptional, unusual month, and we cannot expect this to continue in the further months. In other words, in further months we have seen an improvement in residual values. In addition we also of course are one of the people who believe that the US economy will, relatively quickly once it reaches a turnaround point, recover again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Dr Ganal. Dr. Reithofer, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Koontz, first of all, let me comment on your question regarding BMW and further redundancies, people being laid off. Actually that's how we should briefly sum up your question. And third, we give you a clear answer. Over and above the signals indicated, we have no plans at the moment and definitely no decisions for further reduction of our head count. As regards the documents that might come from external business consultants, we cannot of course comment on those documents, please appreciate this, they coming, as I said, from external consultants. We continue to endorse our figure of 8,100 people who we split up into two sections 5,000 temp workers and 5,100 regular from the employee comp workers, 2,500 of which will be laid off in Germany and 600 abroad. The last one, Mr. Koontz, regarding recovery against Mr. Charles due to the development of the dollar, here let me just make a statement on behalf of the BMW group, "We don't look into the past; we look into the future."</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Koontz, yes, I'd like to add a point here Mr. Koontz. We are talking here about many things that have happened in the context of the subprime crisis. And I'd like to ask a question to all of us here that is who knew the subprime crisis was coming twelve months ago? I mean, to be quite honest here at the BMW group, we didn't see the subprime crisis coming in twelve months ago.  It wasn't happening in the currency market with the currency shifts in the euro to dollar, the euro to yen, etc. As far as all that is concerned, we of course again see a direct link to the subprime crisis.</p>
          <p>And so if you look at the first three months of this year as well, Mr. Koontz, you see what happened here with raw materials which again increased in price from January to March, then of course with many reports in the new newspapers the last three or four weeks in particular. There was a lot of speculation as well, speculation bubbles.  And so again if there's anything you wish to emphasize, any points you wish to make which really affect us all in all areas, then one of them, one of the items, one of these common denominators is the subprime crisis. And as far as the BMW group is concerned we've been very successful, we've always been very successful in the US market in recent years, which is why of course such effects in the United States are greater on us and also on account of the subprime crisis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Reithofer. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mr. Apta.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to all of you. I've got another question right now. In your press release you refer to additional activities, additional measures in cost management. Can you tell us exactly what you plan here and how you want to add or if you want to add something on the 6 billion you want to save, or are these just other items you are carrying forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dr. Ganal Please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we are continuing our six &#x2013; mid-billion package as before, the package you already mentioned. You can imagine that the general situation and our ambition this year to generate an even better result really does prompt us to step up our efforts to work even faster. But we're working very well at the moment with this package. We, I think, described this very clearly at our last session, as best we can. And let me just say that of course, the reasons for doing this and for making this possible now better influence, to be clear, than ever before. Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Yakan Hatts of FAAZO <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mr. Hatts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes I got two or three additional questions, first of all the reduction of your workforce can you tell us how may of the planned 8,100 people who have already left the company, how many have you laid off in the first quarter? And then the cost expenditure that you mentioned here, the expenditure, is that for the first quarter alone or is it just for the whole redundancy of employees? And then for the entire 8,100 people? And then as far as currency effects are concerned you've said that you're expecting an even smaller burden then in the previous year. Why is that so? Is that because you said you expect the dollar to pick up again or have you increased your hedging activities accordingly? Can you go into a bit of detail please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much indeed, Mr. Hatts. Let's start with currencies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all looking back ladies and gentleman we communicate a figure, the headwinds each year and this takes to what extent we deteriorated in terms of currencies versus the previous year. So it's an important indicator. In '06, we had 656 million.  In 2007 it was 517 million, and in 2008 we said this figure should not exceed 400 million. I'd like to confirm this today the reason not so much that we are making very ambitious assumptions looking forward to the rest of the year. But rather we're closing the year we're hedged up to the end of the year now and we know exactly what turnover, what residue we'll have, what rate of exchange and what hedging agreements we'll review from each case.</p>
          <p>The second question, 14 million in the first quarter and personnel reduction and head count reductions this is a prorated figure in other words it is what we have more or less spent in the first quarter and reduction of personnel, reduction of our the head count. In the next quarter, or quarters, we'll see further expenditure and that's why for the whole year we'll be looking at a three digit million euro figure but more than lower 3 million -- three digit million segment not in the upper segment. Then we have our workforce, the demands of our workforce that was the next question. <mark type="inaudible" /> here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Actually, we wouldn't or don't really make a direct statement as far as the quarters are concerned. But we have announced this reduction for the whole year as a whole, that is the entire figure and I'm working on this reduction step-by-step. Now, the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Christophe Ravald of Dow Jones.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mr. Ravald.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. The first I have goes to Mr. Reithofer. Can you give us an indication of how sales are developing in April? And then my second question it takes up the first point just made. And this goes to Dr. Ganal. Do you expect the dollar to recover in the foreseeable future versus Euro?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Ravald.Thank you, thank you very much.  First of all, we have sales development, Dr. Reithofer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I have a clear answer for you Mr. Ravald. The positive development into sales as you can see now has continued in April. We have now got a further stipulation for April and we can state that the increase in sales in April was in the high single digit range. In other words, we have a high figure here, in the single digit range, and that's important, that's very helpful. That means it will continue to develop very positively.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Dr. Ganal, please on the dollar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well if $1000 is concerned, we don't speculate on the dollar anymore to be quite honest. You've seen we also behave accordingly when it comes to hedging, hedging agreements in 2008, which is why we do not expect any trend any change in trend in the short-term at least. And in the long-term, we're also preparing for the challenges, in another words, we're preparing for a weak dollar over the long term. We've achieved this above all by way of natural hedging, natural hedging activities and so in the long-term again, we want to be and remain independent our fluctuations in currency exchange rates, and I think that's the key point, the most important factor, we mentioned here. And I think that for the right time being we're looking very good versus the others.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Christine Wasiliv of Financial Times, Germany.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello Mrs. Wasiliv.  Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning from me. I would like to know whether like portion of the States you said &#x2013; that's made plans to cut back business to, perhaps not expand that quickly in the States anymore, at least for the time being, until sales become profitable again. Have you got such plans in the States?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you [ Mrs. Wasiliv.  I think that question goes to our CEO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Mrs. Wasiliv, the answer is yes. In fact starting in November, December last year we already started considering the better and optimized global distribution of our products. We checked out the markets, we asked ourselves where could we shift cars to, where we could move our cars to. And we took a management decision here, stating that the US market as far as our original planning budget is concerned is to be relieved of its burden and that those cars, of course, and the operations involved, will be moved to markets with a higher profit contribution such as China and India as well to give you some examples. And so in our customer oriented sales and production process, we're able to shift sales, we're shifting those around. So the answer is, yes, definitely, we're doing this as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Edward Taylor from Wall Street.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning I didn't quite understand why March was an exceptional month with exceptionally large numbers of cars coming back from leasing agreements. Because you pushed leasing intentionally; in another words, given the duration period of the contracts, you should actually know how many cars are coming into the markets. And so why is this unforeseeable development? You said again, that this month is exceptional, but why it is so? And what action will you take to make sure this doesn't happen again in the course of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we can answer that one, Edward.  Let me ask Dr. Ganal to take over.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let us see if we live up to Mr. Sch&#xF6;berl's expectations to what we just said, but you're quite right, sir. We did of course know that in March we would be receiving an influx of these cars, up about 50%, almost 50% over the average figure over the whole year. And that was of course, a burden right from the start. That burden then came together with an extremely difficult market, the marketplace being extremely difficult.</p>
          <p>And in April, things however were not at least become worse than in March, and at the same time of course, we want to prevent this happening in future, want to prevent such effects on our residual value. Which is one of the reasons one of the actions &#x2013; activities we've taken in the future, is to take the burden, the punch you might say out of such peaks. They have of course caused certain changes in the course of the year, but they have a clear effect on the course of the business. Which is why again, we want to prevent any returned cars, giving such piece in the future, which will require us to talk to customers directly, in other words, we'd like to also consider extension of lease agreements or earlier termination agreements as well. But again, there are certain surprises, although I should point out again, that it was a very difficult market in March and the margin of these cars that caused the problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Stephan Kronik of Bergenheisen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good morning, Mr. Kronik.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have got two questions. And one of them is about R&amp;D costs, you said they were up by 13% in the first quarter. Can you tell us how R&amp;D expenditure will develop in the next three quarters, will it continue to go up?  And then how has the dollar affected you in the first quarter, that is the currency burden?  How big has it been and how big has the burden been from raw materials?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Kronik, let me ask Dr. Ganal to take over right away.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all our R&amp;D expenditure in the first quarter of 2008 show new development because you see for the first time depreciations were higher than the amounts capitalized and the sums capitalized, showing you that we are changing our policy, that we are moving in a different direction, and that's why the capitalization ratio is going down step by step, the capitalization rate. You see in the first quarter, we have a quota of 5.4%, which is just about in our corridor.  Included in this change, however, we have an ACB quota that is under the joint commercial code of less than 22%.  But again, those are just current figures. They don't in all describe the approach we've taken -- we're taking. We of course, are still continue to be looking at an R&amp;D quota between 5 and 5.5%, and we believe that this is and remains the right setting as it were to take up future challenges with innovative products and innovative technologies. And so I think that the R&amp;D expenditures shown in the first quarter, according to the ACB and the IFRS rules shouldn't be over interpreted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then the next point that was the decline of the dollar in Q1 and the burden from raw materials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, looking at the first quarter, we see an increasing burden, an additional burden from the Automobile segment due to the lower transaction rates, the transaction currency rates. These deteriorations have been in the medium double digit euro range, and at the same time, we see an additional burden coming from the higher cost of raw materials as already mentioned. But given the wave of such materials, that is some materials have been require and then not been required again, et cetera. We would like to refer to the cost of raw materials here because of the ups and downs inside the waves, but we reduced the additional burden overall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Christian Hedsner of Reuters News.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mr. Hedsner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning from me too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I have a few questions. First of all, regarding your adjusted EBIT margin in the cars business, your automobiles business. This is a significant improvement over the previous year, true.  Will this improvement continue in your opinion '08 Q1 for certain reasons that's more than exception of peak this year, which is a bit different, let's say, from the rest. And then I have a few questions regarding financial services. First of all, will you try to run back -- to cut back your leasing business in the United States in order to overcome such problems that you have there in the used car market? Will that to be one of your strategies? And so with this mind, can you tell us, can you say to what extent used car prices might still be maintained, I mean, it might take some time until you get to that new ways they have to carry out or ask you to provide for new provisions, new risk provisions, and so with this in mind again I'd like to know what the need is for financing is -- the need for financing in financial services, right now, of course, with the situation in the money market, taking account as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dr. Ganal, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, looking at the general figures, the EBIT figures in the automobile segment, you will see that here again taking 661 in the last quarter, last year, we have two exceptional factors here, perhaps semi factors. First of all, our workforce, our manpower down by 40 million in the first quarter, 4-0, and I mentioned that this will now continue in the next couple of quarters. And then, of course, taking the higher risk provisions in the used car market, and I told you before that we have joint risk here of financial services in the Automobile segment.</p>
          <p>Taking this into account we have 157 million. In our opinion that is a single one-off nonrecurring payment and those are the two figures therefore that you have to know in order to understand the adjustment process and this takes us on to EBIT margin in the said course of your segment is 6.4%, again 6.4%. And your expectation of course is quite justified even though we have to still make appropriate changes. On operating terms, we do not plan to go further back, rather we are making every effort not just to improve our absolute results, but also our ratios, our business ratios, the EBIT margin is a very important ratio and that's why the answer is that in operative terms, we want to remain as good as we have been in the first quarter definitely, not allowing any deterioration or decrease.</p>
          <p>You've also referred to financial services, sir, asking how long to continue business. First of all, financial services is important to us for two reasons. You see first we have an increase in revenues per car, thanks to leasing, because here we have more optional excellence, more special equipment in our cars and cars are kept shorter under leasing agreements. We currently work on this of course. And so leasing is not just an economical business tool as it was to make money, it's also an elementary brick or stone within our sales organization.</p>
          <p>And that's why we can't just give up the leasing just like that. That would be the most inappropriate, the stupidest thing we could do. But of course it's that fact that in United States we have now achieved penetration rates, which are very, very difficult, I mean this brings in the operating what you are going to do in the United States? What you are going to do anyway there to improve? This has given us the reason to think about the mix of those tools in sales. But leasing remains a fundamental tool, no doubt about it.</p>
          <p>As far as refinancing is concerned, we pursue a selective strategy first of all which in the last couple of months has really helped us. It's been successful. For example investing in debenture loans and when it comes to the individual instruments we are well diversified, also thanks to our very good rating. And in the market we therefore are also very popular definitely, you might say, if I might say so, from included this way, because we always live up to our commitments. We've also focused more on private placements and despite general conditions being difficult we can state that right now we have everything quite well under control. And we are confident with our refinancing activities in 2008, we once again will run efficiently and well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. We've got four minutes to wrap it up now, ladies and gentlemen. I think we can take one more question, just one more. So the next and last question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. James Freeney from the English Conference. Sir?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Just one question from the statement you released last week on the fall in used car prices. You said this is happening particularly in North America. I was just wondering if you could paint a picture of the situation in Europe for me, please. What trend you're seeing there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, James.  We will give you the answer in German. Dr. Michael Ganal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dr. Ganal. Well, you're quite right. But of course, the fact is that markets have developed very differently. This is also reflected by our risk provisions. Thank god you might say because this doesn't happen at the same time in all markets at the same we see such trends, but again not at the same time in all markets. We've seen the development state and need not repeat that. In Germany, in 2007 and now also in 2008, we saw a positive development, we've seen a positive developments as a result of which our auditors have indeed reduced the risk provision. But we still have a good provision of course, although again it will be under their instructions, we released the provision and in Britain the British markets, we currently do not see any particular development. In 2007 there was a decrease and that also prompted us to increase our risk provisions in Great Britain in the year 2007. And this I think means that we are well aligned for the future growth and set up to meet challenges. In Spain losses are currently increasing slightly, but here again, we are up to date in our risk provisions. In another words we are on the safe side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much indeed Dr. Ganal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We now take one more question, its 10:58. Next please, very last question? Sorry that was the last question I here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So, ladies and gentleman, dear colleagues thank you very much indeed. I know you have more to do today its not just BMW. I'll been able to answer your questions, quickly, well and efficiently. Thanks so much. See you next time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>