<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1429932" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-11-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7782</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Head of Corporate Communications and Policy, Bayerische Motoren Werke AG">Maximilian Sch&#xF6;berl</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman-Management Board">Norbert Reithofer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Member-Management Board &amp; Head-Finance">Friedrich Eichiner</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd. Germany">Christian Breitsprecher</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">John K. Lawson</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Natixis SA (Broker)">Georges Dieng</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Arndt A. Ellinghorst</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Stuart P. Pearson</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Max E. Warburton</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Kristina L. Church</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. This is Maximilian Sch&#xF6;berl, Director of Corporate Affairs. I would like to welcome you all to today's telephone conference for the Third Quarter and First Nine Months Results. With me today are Dr. Norbert Reithofer, Chairman of the Board of Management; and Dr. Friedrich Eichiner, our CFO.</p>
          <p>First, Dr. Reithofer will give you an update on the business performance during the first nine months and some guidance on 2011 as a whole. Dr. Eichiner will then take you through our financial results for the third quarter and the first nine months of the year as well. Afterwards, we will have time for our Q&amp;A session.</p>
          <p>Mr. Reithofer, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. The BMW Group is on track for success. Our strategy is paying off and is our guideline for successful and profitable development within a volatile business environment.</p>
          <p>In 2011, we are on the right path towards reaching our targets. This means new record sales of more than 1.6 million cars; a new group pre-tax record, significantly above last year's level; and an EBIT margin in the Automotive Segment of over 10%.</p>
          <p>Back in 2007, when we launched our strategy, we put forward specific profitability targets for 2012. The business year 2011 is the last benchmark on our way towards achieving these targets. In 2012, we want to achieve an EBIT margin of 8% to 10% in the Automotive segment. Following this milestone, we want to remain on a high profitability level over the long-term. This highlights our sustainable approach in both our plans and actions. This is true in an economic and strategic sense as well as concerning ecological and social issues.</p>
          <p>Regarding strategy, we are facing two major challenges. First, we are presently facing various risks in the global economic cycle. Obviously, we have re-evaluated our strategic assumptions this year, given the current situation. Our long-term planning considers various scenarios for economic development. This approach allows us to react quickly and flexibly. Thanks to our lean structures and low cost base, we are well prepared for potential volatility. What's more, we are focusing on achieving balanced growth across different markets. We are also strategically expanding our global production network.</p>
          <p>Second, we have to master evolution and revolution at the same time. We are further expanding our range of combustion engine cars with cutting-edge technologies through our Efficient Dynamics program. Without a doubt, Efficient Dynamics is the most advanced technology available. While some of our competitors are advertising lower CO2 emissions, they forget to mention they are cutting power from their engines at the same time. This certainly is not our approach. The BMW Group fleet average is around 152 grams of CO2 per kilometer with an average output of over 137 kilowatts. That's 186 horsepower, more than any core competitor. We will always stand by our promise of Sheer Driving Pleasure, dynamic and efficiency; that is BMW.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we are offering our customers new drive technologies, highly innovative car concepts and attractive mobility services, which we will lead to market success. A good example here is our car sharing project DriveNow. In Munich and Berlin, within a very short period, around 8,000 members have already registered. We expect 1 million, I repeat, we expect 1 million users worldwide for our services by 2020.</p>
          <p>So, what have we achieved in the first nine months of the business year 2011? A pre-tax result of &#x20AC;6.16 billion, a Group net profit of &#x20AC;4.1 billion and an EBIT margin in the Automotive segment of 12.8%.</p>
          <p>These are all new record highs for the BMW Group for the first nine months of the year. The same is true of our sale figures from January to September, over 1.23 million cars from the BMW, MINI and Rolls-Royce brands; almost 93,000 motorcycles from the BMW and Husqvarna brands. Customers worldwide are enthusiastic about our models. In Europe, North America and Asia, we managed to increase sales in the two-digit percentage range between January and September. This growth is based on our attractive product line-up, at the moment, the youngest amongst our competitors.</p>
          <p>Following the Convertible, the new BMW 6 Series is now also available as a Coup&#xE9;. The BMW M5 will arrive in December and the MINI Coup&#xE9; arrived at dealerships on October 1. The new BMW 1 Series has been available since September 17. This car brings a variety of innovations to the compact class. Thanks to ConnectedDrive, the BMW 1 Series is the best connected car in its segment.</p>
          <p>In mid-October, we presented the sixth generation of the new 3 Series Sedan in Munich. World Star from Munich, wrote Munich-based tz. The Pride of the Bavarians was the headline in Frankfurter Allgemeine Sonntagszeitung. The new 3 Series will be on the market from February 11, 2012. The three lines Sport, Modern and Luxury, will provide customers with further options to customize their car.</p>
          <p>Our portfolio will become increasingly versatile including drivetrains. Today, our BMW 7 Series and BMW X6 customers can choose between highly efficient combustion engines and a hybrid drive. From spring 2012, we will be offering the BMW 5 Series Sedan as a hybrid as well. And the BMW ActiveHybrid 3, the world's first full hybrid in the premium segment of compact sports sedans, will follow in fall. This is our hybrid offering to the customers in our best-selling series, the BMW 3 Series.</p>
          <p>From 2013 on, we are complementing our product portfolio with an electric drive. At the Frankfurt Motor Show, we presented electric cars for all three brands, which we developed to gain experiences in this field: the MINI E, the BMW ActiveE and the Experimental Car, the Rolls-Royce 102EX. We also showed the first two concept cars in the BMW i range, the BMW i3 and BMW i8.</p>
          <p>But let's move on to my second point, ecological and social responsibility. With BMW i, we are breaking completely new ground when it comes to eco-friendly and resource-efficient production. For the first time, we have determined mandatory sustainability targets along the entire value chain from the first steps of development to recycling.</p>
          <p>In late October, we celebrated what we call a Richtfest or roofing ceremony for the BMW i production site at our Leipzig Plant. The assembly of the BMW i3 and i8 will be completely CO2 neutral. The energy is derived entirely from regenerative sources. This is an absolute first in our industry. We plan to build a wind farm at our Leipzig site. Now that we have the first set of permits, we look forward to beginning construction soon. The generated eco-power will be fed directly into the plant.</p>
          <p>I'm convinced that truly sustainable mobility can only arise from a holistic approach. This is an inherent part of our premium claim and this will keep us in the forefront as the leading premium car company in our industry.</p>
          <p>The BMW Group has been in leading positions in all relevant sustainability rankings for years. Two examples, first, in the Dow Jones Sustainability Index, we have been listed as the segment leader for the seventh year in a row. Second, in the Carbon Disclosure Project, we have achieved our best results so far, 96 of 100 possible points. As the number one among automakers, we are also in the top 10 of all companies worldwide participating in the CDP Global 500 Ranking.</p>
          <p>These first rate positions have to be earned again and again. To this effect, we also believe in having open dialog with our stakeholders. Our most recent Sustainability Report was certified by independent auditors for the first time. Hence, at out Stakeholder Roundtable in New York City in early October, we discussed the possible design of future urban mobility with a variety of social groups.</p>
          <p>Our future tasks will be both complex and challenging. For that we need to have the best and most qualified people on board. In the areas of electro-mobility and CFK technology, we are hiring engineers and other experts, a total of 3,500 people this year. Up to the end of September, our company employed 100,389 people, 4.7% up from the reference period 2010. This figure, of course, includes the 1,220 employees which we added by acquiring ING Car Lease for our Financial Services division.</p>
          <p>Just like every year, over 1,600 young people started their apprenticeship with our company in September, more than 1,000 of them in Germany alone.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, even though business environment might be volatile, we continue to follow our own path, The BMW Way, and this has brought us to success. We are further striving to reach our targets for the business year 2011. And this will position us now to achieve our profitability targets for 2012.</p>
          <p>We are building a sound base in technological and market strategy terms. We are acting responsibly and sustainably. And we are shaping the future of individual mobility in the premium segment.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Norbert Reithofer. And now, Friedrich Eichiner will give you an update on the financials of the BMW Group. Dr. Eichiner, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, good afternoon from my side as well. In the third quarter, we were able to build on our highly successful second quarter. We continue to lead the premium segment with our young and attractive product line-up.</p>
          <p>BMW Group revenue and earnings also continued their positive development. Third quarter revenues rose by almost 4% year-on-year to more than &#x20AC;16.5 billion. Group earnings before taxes reached more than &#x20AC;1.6 billion in the third quarter. The Group's net profit totaled roughly &#x20AC;1.1 billion.</p>
          <p>Let's take a look at the Automotive segment. We sold more than 399,000 new vehicles in the third quarter, 9% more than in the same period last year. We made strong gains in Western Europe, Germany, North America and in Asia. In China, our third quarter sales increased by 21% to more than 56,000 units. China, therefore, accounted for 14% of sales in the third quarter. Our sales were evenly distributed around the world. The segment EBIT amounted to more than &#x20AC;1.8 billion. The EBIT margin, for the same period reached, 11.9%.</p>
          <p>We are now reaping benefits of our profitability measures. Our efficiency continues to rise. The latest BMW and MINI models are better than their predecessors both in terms of profitability and pricing, thanks in part to lower manufacturing costs and better transaction prices.</p>
          <p>The third quarter was impacted, as planned by the ramp-up expenses for the new BMW 1 Series and the 3 Series Sedan. We expect much of the &#x20AC;500 million in additional costs to be incurred in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Demand for the first generation BMW 1 Series declined less than expected before it was phased out. We were still able to achieve good prices on the market and faced lower charges.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, we produced almost 437,000 units in total. Our excellent capacity utilization covered our fixed costs well. We made further extensive investments. In the third quarter, our capital expenditure increased year-on-year. Capital expenditure for the full year will remain at the same level as last year. Our investment ratio will be lower than our targeted 7% of revenue.</p>
          <p>Capital efficiency remains a priority. This also allows us to invest in the future and maintain our position as technology leader in the field of efficient drivetrains.</p>
          <p>We stepped up research and development once again in the third quarter. Despite the increase in revenues, our R&amp;D ratio for the third quarter rose to about 5%, due to new development and vehicle projects. The R&amp;D ratio for the full year will be at the lower end of our target range of 5% to 5.5%, thanks to efficient development processes and the positive revenue performance we anticipate.</p>
          <p>The positive impact from currency was overshadowed by negative raw material prices in the third quarter. This led to a negative impact on earnings in the two-digit millions. We still expect these adverse effects to continue throughout the fourth quarter. However, the impact of currency effects and changes in raw material prices should largely offset each other over the full year.</p>
          <p>Sustained demand in our overseas markets and the launch of the BMW 1 Series, combined with higher stocks of 3 Series models prior to their phase-out, produced an increase in inventories. Vehicles are now being shipped for fourth quarter deliveries.</p>
          <p>Working capital increased accordingly by about &#x20AC;300 million in the third quarter. Together with our increased capital expenditure, this had a dampening effect on free cash flow. In the third quarter, free cash flow in the segment totaled &#x20AC;462 million. Adjusted for the cash outs of &#x20AC;249 million for the acquisition of ING Car Lease, free cash flow in the Auto segment was &#x20AC;711 million.</p>
          <p>For the period between January and September, the unadjusted free cash flow was about &#x20AC;3 billion. We expect this positive trend to continue in the fourth quarter, with an increase in free cash flow for the full year to over &#x20AC;3 billion.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the Financial Services segment also continued to experience dynamic growth. We generated a pre-tax profit of &#x20AC;354 million in the third quarter, an increase of 11.3% year-on-year. The segment contributed more than &#x20AC;1.5 billion to earnings in the year to the end of September. Our business performance benefited from sustained sales momentum on the auto market and from profitable new business. Stable used car prices and credit risks created a favorable business environment.</p>
          <p>The credit loss ratio for the year to the end of September remained stable at 0.46%, 12 base points lower than the same period last year. In the third quarter, unlike the previous quarter, we did not need to adjust risk provisions, so there was no positive impact on earnings.</p>
          <p>Our financing and leasing business continued to perform very well on account of our growing automotive business. We concluded more than 291,000 new contracts in total.</p>
          <p>The penetration rate for the year to the end of September was slightly lower than for the same period last year. This was due to our financial services activities in China since early 2011. Financial Services leased or financed 41% of the new BMW Group vehicles delivered to retail customers. The penetration rate has remained virtually unchanged over the course of the year.</p>
          <p>Leasing contracts were concluded for 21% of the vehicles delivered, with financing agreements for a further 20%. The business volume in balance sheet terms for the year to the end of September totaled nearly &#x20AC;72 billion. The increase of almost 9% since the end of last year is mainly due to the acquisition of ING Car Lease.</p>
          <p>The EU Competition Commission approved the merger between ING Car Lease and our fleet management provider, Alphabet, in September of this year. The new company will operate in 18 countries under the name Alphabet and is now one of the top five fleet management providers in Europe. The move has increased our fleet management portfolio to more than 460,000 contracts. We believe Alphabet provides the ideal basis for further growth in modern mobility solutions and services, including EU mobility.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we were able to make substantial gains in the Motorcycle segment, despite a shrinking total market. With almost 29,000 deliveries to customers, business grew by 6.5% year-on-year. This increase in sales was primarily due to the BMW brand.</p>
          <p>Our segment revenues of &#x20AC;334 million in this segment was almost 15% higher than in the third quarter of 2010. We have begun repositioning the Husqvarna Group to develop new and profitable business fields for the brand. This process had a negative impact on earnings in this segment.</p>
          <p>The BMW Group continues to maintain a strong liquidity position. As per 30 September, we held &#x20AC;10.9 billion in cash and cash equivalents. We took advantage of favorable financing opportunities to increase our liquidity in consideration of the acquisition of ING Car Lease.</p>
          <p>We were also able to boost our liquidity buffer with a new credit line. We recently secured attractive terms for a five-year contract, with renewal options, from an international banking group. We now have a &#x20AC;6 billion loan commitment we can draw upon if needed. These activities provide the BMW Group with a healthy liquidity base for dealing with potential uncertainty of capital markets.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, on the whole, we expect positive business development to continue in the first quarter. The new BMW 1 Series launched in September will also contribute to that trend. In the fourth quarter, we anticipate additional costs from the market and production launch of our new products. We are also aware that economic conditions remain uncertain and subject to volatility.</p>
          <p>However, we remain confident overall that we will be able to meet our guidance for 2011. We expect to sell more than 1.6 million vehicles and achieve an EBIT margin of over 10% in the Automotive segment.</p>
          <p>At Group level, our pre-tax profit will be considerably higher than last year. We expect the Financial Services segment to maintain its healthy business development. We are continuing to implement our strategy rigorously.</p>
          <p>On the whole, we are confident but also well aware of the risks. We expect to see continued volatility due to the high level of national debt, the oil crisis and rising inflation. We will remain vigilant. We have explored various scenarios and made the necessary preparations.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we are getting closer to 2012 and the finishing line for the strategic goals we set back in 2007. We are currently in a comfortable position. Returns in the Automotive segment exceed our long-term EBIT margin range of 8% to10%. We have worked hard to achieve this. The BMW Group has successfully implemented the key measures of its Strategy Number ONE and is more profitable today than ever before. Our financial strength has increased dramatically.</p>
          <p>We will continue to work on enhancing our efficiency and making ourselves more resilient to market fluctuations. We are also using today's profits from our operating business to shape the future of the company with new technologies and innovative products to maintain our leadership in the premium automotive segment. In this way, we are ensuring that the BMW Group will remain profitable and successful in the future. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, very much Mr. Eichiner. Ladies and gentlemen, the line will shortly be opened for questions. Please wait for some technical advice.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now being our question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> One moment please for the first question. First question comes from Mr. Christian Breitsprecher from Macquarie. Please speak now, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Christian Breitsprecher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Christian Breitsprecher from Macquarie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I have a couple of questions. First on CapEx, I think in the press conference call, you said that it'd be at about the same level as last year. I just wanted to confirm that.</p>
          <p>Secondly, on free cash flow and working capital; I mean, you've already reached free cash flow of more than &#x20AC;3 billion in the first nine months, so the guidance for the full year of more than &#x20AC;3 billion doesn't sound that ambitious. I mean, what is going to happen on the working capital side in the fourth quarter?</p>
          <p>And third question, pricing of outgoing models, you said that the 1 Series did better than you had expected? What is going on the 3 Series at the moment <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
          <p>And last question, could you comment on the other entities results in the third quarter, what was the driver there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you have to repeat the last part of your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on the entities? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that better? On the other entities, could you explain, what was the driver for the big negative swing in the other entities result in the third quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, Christian Breitsprecher and this question will be answered by Mr. Eichiner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start with your last question, the driver for that swing was internal business risk related to operating &#x2013; not operating issues, where we had to accrue provisions.</p>
          <p>Now coming back to your question about the free cash flow for Q4, I mean, for Q4 we expect a positive free cash flow in the Auto segment. But there will be a cash inflow change in working capital, especially through lower inventory levels. We have produced more now in the third quarter. It will be less in the fourth quarter. This will lead to lower inventory levels and a positive effect on free cash flow, on the one hand side.</p>
          <p>On the other hand side, CapEx will be higher, so with the ramp up of the new products, we expect a higher CapEx. And there is a tax payment triggered by the positive earnings development in 2011, that will happen in the last quarter. So this will offset, to a certain extent, the positive effect coming from the reduced inventory levels. But overall, we expect the free cash flow to increase in the first quarter and be clearly beyond the &#x20AC;3 billion mark. So that was free cash flow.</p>
          <p>Then your question about CapEx; CapEx clearly, this year is expected to be on par with last year's levels, I can confirm this information. And pricing, 1 Series was and 3 Series, while the 1 Series here is phased out, had a negative impact on pricing but it was less than expected. We've seen around 50 basis points compared to the first half of 2011. And now we have to see what the 3 Series will bring. We are expecting more on this side because the 3 Series is sold on a worldwide basis. For example, also in the U.S. where we possibly have an inference that is a bit higher than the 1 Series. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one follow-up on this other entity, can you say how big this amount was, this one-time provisioning? Or is it one-time and to what does it relate really?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a low three-digit million amount and it's one-time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. John Lawson from Citi. Please speak now, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much indeed. You sounded pretty confident this morning that China was going to continue to grow and I note that in 2011, you're heading for something like a 40% local assembly share. I wondered whether you would share with us, given you've got both a new product line and an additional plant in China for 2012, where you expect or indeed target local assembly share to be then?</p>
          <p>Secondly, I wanted to ask if you could please elaborate a bit on that 1 million car-sharing users, which, if I understand you right, you expect to have? I mean, it does look like another big expansion of the balance sheet to accommodate your customers. I think right now you have two-thirds of your balance sheet in your Financial Services sector. So, does the long-term planning of BMW suggest that this goes even higher with all of these continued initiatives?</p>
          <p>And then finally, I just wanted to know please, can we forget about further provision releases from Leasing and Financial Services business now, given that you didn't do anything in the third quarter? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much, John Lawson. I think we start with China growth with Mr. Reithofer and then Mr. Eichiner. Mr. Reithofer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, the situation in China, let me start in the year 2011. I mean, our production volume, our local production volume in 2011, I think it's not a secret anymore. It's safe to say that it will be above 90,000 units. So the rest are cars from the United States and from Europe, exported from the United States, or from Germany, or from the UK to China. And as I said, the local production volume in 2011 will be a bit more than 90,000 units. So, if I look into the future, and into the local production side, then we plan in principle two expansion steps.</p>
          <p>The first one will be our current plant in Dadong. We will move from our production capacity from roughly 75,000 units to 100,000 units in early 2012. As I said, that is our existing Dadong plant. It is a &#x2013; after the expansion of our Dadong plant.</p>
          <p>So the second step will be a new plant in Tiexi, both by the way, are in the city of Shenyang. And production capacity from roughly early 2013 of our Tiexi plant will be 100,000 units. That means, from early 2013 on, 100,000 units in Tiexi, 100,000 units in Dadong, that means both together from 2013 on 200,000 units, local production capacity. So that is &#x2013; and if I look into the future, then we can say our plant is to expand Tiexi to 200,000 units by early 2014, so that means the total capacity from early 2014 will be 300,000 units in China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Mr. Reithofer. Mr. Eichiner?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hello, John, so I'll try to cover your question about the car sharing. So basically, car sharing is on the low scale actually. We are experimenting on this field because we see a certain demand in bigger cities where younger people don't want to buy and own cars but they want to drive and they are open for kind of new car-sharing concepts. That's why we are now working in joint ventures with Sixt, for example. We are doing our own things within Financial Services but the scale is still very low, though, we are talking thousands of cars, not millions of cars, and it's something we have an eye on. We have to see whether there is an opportunity that we can develop in the future, not a big thing.</p>
          <p>The bigger thing might be &#x2013; you want to know is the reason why we bought ING Car Lease, that's fleet management and clearly, that's very relevant for our European business and from our perspective also very relevant in the future when it comes down to e-mobility, where you need more services around the car and you need a kind of &#x2013; such kind of operations available.</p>
          <p>Of course, this is something we have now on our books. We have to report the portfolio and it's integrated in our balance sheet. But there's no plan that we do much more on this side now. That's it. I think we have now strong position and we can live with it.</p>
          <p>Your question about the provisions and what we possibly could expect. Now, that's a very difficult question. We are quite satisfied with our provisioning. I think it's solid. But there's a lot of uncertainty out there and I mean, if really the market goes down again, then possibly we see deteriorating used car prices and could possibly we need the provisions then very seriously. If this will not happen and first stabilization will come in, and we have to see what opportunities we have, for example, in the year 2012. But I don't expect a lot to come now in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Sir Georges Dieng from Natixis. Please speak now, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, good afternoon. I have several questions. First of all, if you could update us on your current utilization rates both globally and maybe in the main regions, Europe, U.S., and China? And some question on the inventory levels and maybe the outlook you see for inventories?</p>
          <p>And the second question, during the call, you referred to the various scenarios that you have in mind for 2012 and beyond. So, I was wondering if you could share with us your scenario analysis and maybe the countermeasures you would have to implement in the event of a sharp market downturn?</p>
          <p>And I have a final question on the flexibility tools that you have. If you could remind us of the number of times you have in your organization today and the leeway provided by your working time accounts? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much, Georges. I think the first part and the third part will come from Mr. Reithofer and the second part from Mr. Eichiner. Mr. Reithofer, you have to start please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, you mean plant utilization, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, correct. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I give you three figures; then you have a very good comparison between the years. Our plant utilization in 2009 was 86%. In 2010, it was 102% and plant utilization for 2011 is expected to be more than 110%. That means we can really say our plants are in 2011 chock-a-block full.</p>
          <p>So then, from a flexibility point of view, I mean, as you know, we use different flexibility instruments. For example, shift models, flex-time accounts and what does it mean a flex-time account? One of our employees can go up to plus 300 hours and can go down to minus 300 hours. That means it gives us a lot of room to maneuver with such working time accounts.</p>
          <p>And we use on top, of course, as well, temps, that means working time accounts, as I said, plus 300 hours, minus 300 hours per employee; temps, shift models and that means we have a really very good toolbox to be able to react on the increasing volatility of the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Mr. Eichiner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Following your question about the scenarios of the 2012 and, basically, we see two scenarios. The scenarios we are relying on with our guidance is a kind of, let's say, moderate growth scenario that we are not running into a recession but we see flattening in some countries on the economic development side.</p>
          <p>So, this would still support our guidance of 8% to 10% next year. And, of course, this will support growth on the volume side in retail production. And we have to just &#x2013; we support this scenario in order to really take advantage of the opportunities which are still out there, for example, in emerging markets but also in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Critical, from my perspective, is more the European market where we still have some signs that the markets are getting a bit weaker, which is not a surprise, following all the discussions we have today. So, this is normal and this would mean we would deliver our 8% to 10% EBIT margin next year.</p>
          <p>And then the kind of worst case scenario that the crisis would come back again, we would see a recession. Nobody knows how hard this will hit us but we have to prepare for such a kind of scenario in peril. And there are two ways we are doing that. First of all, normally in such a kind of scenario, the demand falls down heavily; you have to manage your working capital, so we immediately would have to run our production down very quickly.</p>
          <p>We would use all the flexibility tools that we have, the working time account, which is slow at the moment. The flexible &#x2013; the temps and all the other shift models and many other tools that are available to us in order to quickly bring production volumes down. That is one thing.</p>
          <p>The other is liquidity. In a crisis like this, liquidity is clearly king. Cash is king. And that's the reason why we prepared a lot for that. Now, as you see, we have &#x20AC;10.9 billion now available. We have this credit line for next five years, another &#x20AC;6 billion for the worse case.</p>
          <p>And in the meantime, we have restructured our banks in the way that our European banks are much stronger. We increased the assets three times more than at the point before the last crisis. And we have access to the ECB, in a kind of a crisis and it's similar to our U.S. bank in Utah, where we possibly could use money coming from the Central Bank. So those are more or less, the tools we have available and we are prepared to use them. And of course, last but not least, we would cut costs heavily in such a kind of scenario. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Mr. Eichiner. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Arndt Ellinghorst from Credit Suisse. Please speak now, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. My first question is on China. We saw in the third quarter for the first time that your imports actually declined year-over-year and also compared to the quarters of the first half of this year. So you mentioned this morning that you expect an ongoing positive momentum of your overall sales in China next year. Could you also update us what you expect to happen with your imports moving forward?</p>
          <p>Second question is on the German corporate car market. I guess it's probably fair to assume that corporate expenditure should go down moving forward. Would you expect more pricing pressure and also volume pressure? We already see quite some heavy discounting with some of your peers in the corporate sector in Germany. What's your view there?</p>
          <p>And then just a remark, I found it quite entertaining, given the history of BMW and Daimler. I think this morning, if I tracked it correctly, for the first time in history, the market cap of BMW was higher than Daimler, so I don't know what to make out of it. But obviously, it's quite entertaining today. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Arndt Ellinghorst. I think these are the right question for the Chairman, Mr. Reithofer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Ellinghorst, we don't what to make out of it either. That means we are in the same situation like you. But let me come to China and let me first give you an assumption how we see the total market in China. I mean, if we see that the total market in China in 2011, as we all know, we expect approximately 7.8 million units. That is 4% from 2010 levels. So if we look into 2012, we expect that the market will continue growing at a rate of approximately 5% in 2012 and we think that premium car manufacturer will even do better.</p>
          <p>But what my colleague, Friedrich Eichiner, said in the morning during the press conference call, he said, in 2010, we saw growth rates of 60%, 70%, sometimes, 80%. We will not see growth rates of 60%, 70%, or 80%. At the moment, I would say, we don't have the final figure for October. But in October, it can be for BMW plus &#x2013; around plus 30%. So that is more or less the growth rate what we can expect during the last quarter. That means between 20% and 30%.</p>
          <p>So if I look into the year 2011, as I said it, we think the market is expected to continue growing at a rate of approximately 5% in premium car manufacturers will do better. So, by the way, the same is in our opinion true for India and a lot of other growing markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I may, just India, my question was more on your imports moving forward, not on your overall sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, if I see the locally produced cars and imported cars, the ratio will be in the year 2011 roughly 40/60. That means 40% locally produced cars, 60% imported cars and the ratio will move towards more locally produced cars. That means 50%, 60%, 70% over the next years, over the course of the next years. So that means in a couple of years, we will see 30% imports and 70% locally produced cars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we think the total number will grow; the total number. And we expect about 50/50. That means 50% locally produced cars, 50% imported cars. And we expect that we grow in China in the year 2012 in total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And also imports.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And also imports. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the German question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The German corporate car market pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay, second part to Mr. Eichiner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, clearly the &#x2013; actually the German car market is not as weak as other markets in Europe now. It's still fairly stable. But there's always a tough competition here between the three peers and the pressure on incentives is clearly to be seen. And I expect more to come on this side. But having said this, I mean, first of all, we are not prepared to make every deal for every price, especially not with our new cars. And we have really attractive cars now.</p>
          <p>First of all, the 5 Series, which is a business car for German businessman and now the 3 Series will come to the market very soon. And this will stabilize our pricing in this sector, in an environment that is clearly highly competitive. So, it's how we expect it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Stuart Pearson from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon. I just had I guess two questions left. Just on the launch costs you were talking for the second half of this year, the &#x20AC;500 million. I'm just noting what you said on the 1 Series pricing being better. I just wonder if you could update us so far on what you're seeing on the outgoing 3 Series pricing and whether if &#x20AC;500 million really is still the right number for the second half? I think it's what &#x20AC;160 million to &#x20AC;170 million in Q3? And I guess, perhaps, more importantly, how that would look going into 2012? I guess, Q1 we'll still certainly see some burden from the old model.</p>
          <p>And then, the second question just regarding the Financial Services business, see the equity ratio, by my estimates, at least around 8.3%. So you're at that level that you &#x2013; the 8% level you wanted to reach. Am I right in thinking you injected some equity into that business from the Industrial side in the quarter? And is that something we would expect to see continue? And what kind of level or actually ratio would you like to get to? I'm not sure if the current environment is changing your view on the right level of leverage in that business?</p>
          <p>And then just finally following on from that, credit losses, I think you gave us a nine months number. I don't know if you could perhaps enlighten us on how the Q3 credit loss change versus Q2 and Q1, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Stuart. The answer will be come by Mr. Eichiner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, so, we disclosed a number of roughly &#x20AC;500 million that is due to the launch cost of 1 and 3 Series in the second half of this year. Now, one-third of this &#x20AC;500 million was occurred in the third quarter and two-third we are expecting in the last quarter, in the fourth quarter this year.</p>
          <p>And I think the first quarter of 2012, yes, there will be a remaining influence of the 3 Series but we are quickly ramping up the new one. And I think that will be offset by the new one because clearly, on the new one, for example, you're not prepared to give any sales allowances or things like that. So this then will be a positive effect, with the growing volume of the new 3 in the first quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>Now, your question about the BSF equity. Actually, it's true, we have 8.3% and we have the required equity in our banks that are legally required. So we are very solid positioned with the two banks in Germany and in United States. So I think this is a level where we don't need further injections coming from the Auto segment. I mean, with the profit we are making in the Financial Services business, the company should be in a position to ramp up its equity if it's necessary. So we think in mid to long-term, 9% is a good number for this segment.</p>
          <p>And credit losses, your last <mark type="audio gap" /> numbers, it's fairly at a very low level. I think it's 0.46% for third quarter year-to-date and it's at a level of &#x2013; roughly at the level of the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Mr. Eichiner. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Max Warburton from Bernstein. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi. I'm Max Warburton from Bernstein. Thanks for taking my question. I've got two that are interrelated. Back on launch costs and your guidance of &#x20AC;500 million, that is, obviously, quite an impressive number, given you're changing over effectively half the volume of BMW. And you may be aware that one of your big competitors is giving a similar number in euro million terms of product changeovers that are less than 20% of their volume.</p>
          <p>I was just wondering if maybe Dr. Reithofer, as a former manufacturing chief, could explain to us how BMW is doing this at such low cost? And whether something's happened in the organization that means your launch costs are much lower than they used to be?</p>
          <p>And just related to this, just confirm for the second question, in 2012, you're basically saying that launch costs will be behind us after Q1. So, I'm just wondering, the guidance for 2012, where I think Mr. Eichiner said, even in a sort of moderate growth scenario, 8% to 10% is the target. That does, obviously, mean margins are coming down. Are you being super conservative? Or is it actually fair for us, as analysts, to think that if we did get that modest growth scenario for next year, let's hope, that actually profitability could exceed the target? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, very much, Max. Mr. Eichiner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, your question about the guidance in 2012. Of course, we are conservative. We've always been that way and we will stay that way. That's the first answer to you. And looking at the numbers, I mean, if the things we always said, if the things are coming better, if you see a stable situation in major markets and it's coming from the positive side, then it could be more. That's what we said.</p>
          <p>In our own calculation, we see the trends in Spain, in France, in Italy, not talking about countries like Portugal, Greece, and so on and so forth. And that is not very positive, actually. And we think &#x2013; we said there's no reason why this should be better next year. So, we are calculating those markets to be weak next year as well.</p>
          <p>We hope that Germany is stable and, hopefully, the UK as well. And we see some recovery in the U.S. and a stable situation in Asia. That's more or less the basic assumption. No big growth are coming out of those markets, but overall, a moderate growth rate that would enable us to reach the range. And I have not said so far whether we're on the lower end or in the upper end of this range. It would be something we should discuss as soon as we have our annual result available and we have a better view on the year 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Ladies and gentlemen, I think five minutes to three o'clock, we have time for one more question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question comes from Mrs. Kristina Church from Barclays Capital. Please speak now, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, Kristina Church from Barclays Capital. Thanks for taking my questions. I've just got a couple of questions left. Firstly, coming back to John's question on the Financial Services business, I note that there's been a sharp increase in your Leasing book of about 20% and I know a lot of that relates to the ING ease acquisition. But I just wanted to know what your thoughts are, given that we are at such a peak in residual values right now? What is it this time around if we were to see a sharp decrease in residual values that would protect you better than in the last downturn?</p>
          <p>And leading on from that, the inter-company loans that you have through the Financial Services division, coming out of the Auto division, can we expect those to continue at a similar level going forward? Or what sort of &#x2013; stated in the markets in liquidity terms, would you need for those to &#x2013; say those company loans to drop out?</p>
          <p>And then just a housekeeping question. I wondered what sort of run rate we should expect for the eliminations line going forward? And very finally, coming back to China again, I note that last year that your local production capacity was about &#x2013; was 55,000 units but that Brilliance is reported 70,000 units of sales within China. And I was wondering if in this year, your 40% local production is a very finite number or &#x2013; and whether that production &#x2013; those cars have to be actually produced locally? Or do they have to be sold through the Brilliance brand? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Kristina. Mr. Eichiner?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Outlook for residual values, so let me start with that point first. Well, I think we have solid provisions and if I compare the situation with 2008 when the last crisis came in, I mean, it's much more solid. That's one thing. The other is that our contractual residual values are lower. And so, there's sort of less risk in the contracts than the risks we had in 2008. So, I'm quite confident that if the same crisis should come in, as we experienced in 2008, the hit on the residual value side would not be as visible as it was at that point in time.</p>
          <p>Now, your second question then was about the inter-company loans. I mean, what we are doing, we are using the cash generated by the Auto sector for internal financing. And we will do so in the future. I think we are well advised to keep liquidity on a very high level and we are using those sources of funding very flexibly and that's the way we want to run it in the future as well.</p>
          <p>And then, your next question was about the eliminations line. Well, I mean, lower group manufacturing costs and the growing Lease business, with higher value mix, will keep the inter-Group profit eliminations rising in 2012. That's what we see now. We expect consolidations to have a much more negative impact on the Group profit before tax in 2011. And as I said, reasons are growing the Leasing business and better margin in the business, which leads us to higher eliminations and, as you know, this money will come back over the next couple of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Mr. Eichiner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for joining in our call today and for your questions. On behalf of the BMW Group Team, I wish you all a pleasant afternoon. Thank you very much and good-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>