<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1262000" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-10-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>84</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John Elicker, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James M. Cornelius, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Jean-Marc Huet, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">John Boris</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Elliott Sigal</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Anthony Butler</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Lamberto Andreotti</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Jami Rubin</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">David Risinger</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Steve Scala</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Seamus Fernandez</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Keyur Parekh</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Chris Schott</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Tim Anderson</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Eric Lo</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, and welcome to today's Bristol-Myers Squibb third quarter 2009 earnings release teleconference. Today's call is being recorded. At this time I would like to turn the call over to Mr. John Elicker, Vice President, Investor Relations. Please go ahead, Mr. Elicker.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tony . And good morning, everybody, and thank you for joining us to review our Q3 results. With me this morning are Jim Cornelius, our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer; Jean-Marc Huet, our Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer. Both Jim and Jean-Marc will have prepared remarks. Also joining us are Lamberto Andreotti, President, and Elliott Sigal, Chief Scientific Officer, will be available for Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>So before we get started, let me cover the legal requirement. During this call we'll make statements about the company's future plans and prospects, including statements about our financial position, business strategy research pipeline concerning product development and product potential. These constitute forward-looking statements for purposes of the Safe Harbor provisions under the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Actual results may differ materially from those indicated by these forward-looking statements as a result of various important factors, including those discussed in the company's most recent Annual Report on Form 10-K, periodic reports on 10-Q, and current reports on Form 8-K. These documents are available from the FEC, the Bristol-Myers Squibb website, or from Bristol-Myers Squibb Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>In addition, any forward-looking statements represent our estimates only as of today and should not be relied upon as representing our estimates as of any subsequent date. While we may elect to update forward-looking statements at some point in the future, we specifically disclaim any obligation to do so, even if our estimates change.</p>
          <p>Jim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John, and good morning, everyone. Our third quarter clearly shows how we are transforming Bristol-Myers Squibb into a BioPharma leader. As you know, we unveiled the BioPharma vision for the first time in December of 2007. Since then we have consistently delivered outstanding financial performance through a combination of marketplace execution and productivity initiatives. We are mainly focused on biopharmaceuticals, but we're building our Mead Johnson Nutrition global business as well as a separate, 83% owned affiliate. And finally, we are discovering, developing, and delivering innovative new medicines, led by the efforts of our R&amp;D and commercial organizations.</p>
          <p>On the top and bottom line, we are driving solid financial performance. Our BioPharma revenues grew 6% globally, led by an impressive 12% sales growth in the U.S. business. Our brands face new and expanded competition, and we are successfully meeting the marketplace challenges. For example, PLAVIX grew 9% globally, ex foreign exchange, despite the launch of Lilly's Effient. BARACLUDE was up 37% ex FX, and ORENCIA up 38% on the same basis, in very competitive markets in both hepatitis B and rheumatoid arthritis respectively. REYATAZ had a 9% growth worldwide, ex forex, and remains the protease inhibitor of choice, even with increasing competition.</p>
          <p>While growing revenue, we also focused on gaining cost efficiencies through continuous improvement. You can see the results of these efforts in our BioPharma gross margin improvement of 170 basis points and at the bottom line, as our non-GAAP earnings per share from continuing operations grew 16% versus last year. Reflecting the strength of our business performance, we are refining our 2009 non-GAAP earnings per share from continuing operations guidance to the range of $2 to 2.05, which is at the high end of our previous guidance.</p>
          <p>Our net cash position at September 30 was 1.3 billion, and that's after taking into account the 2.1 billion net impact of our important Medarex acquisition, the latest in the string of pearls. Also today, Mead Johnson announced it's considering options to refinance its intercompany debt, which could result in a $1.75 billion payment to us upon closing of that refinancing. Our financial strength and strong cash flow has provided us the flexibility to execute the String of Pearls strategy, and we will continue to aggressively pursue acquisitions, licensing deals, and other partnerships.</p>
          <p>With our decisions over the past few years, we've increased the focus on our BioPharma business that is bringing innovative medicines to patients. Our latest launch is ONGLYZA for the treatment of Type 2 diabetes. Diabetes is an emerging global epidemic. We have collaborated quite well with our colleagues at AstraZeneca on ONGLYZA, and we are optimistic about its potential. We have launched in the U.S., Mexico, the United Kingdom, and Germany and are moving quickly to launch in additional markets worldwide.</p>
          <p>We've also recently announced the FDA's acceptance of our biologics licensing application for belatacept, an investigational compound designed to help prevent rejection of transplanted kidneys. In addition, we presented the first Phase III data for dapagliflozin, a novel medicine for the treatment of Type 2 diabetes.</p>
          <p>Research and development at Bristol-Myers continues to be very productive and is preparing our company for leadership in a number of areas of unmet medical need. Through consistently strong operational results, disciplined financial management, advancement of a robust pipeline and continued focus on strategic execution, we are making excellent progress, as I said earlier, in our transformation to a next-generation BioPharma leader.</p>
          <p>Now to give additional color on our third quarter performance, our Chief Financial Officer Jean-Marc Huet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Jim. I will review our Q3 results and our 2009 guidance before we go to your questions.</p>
          <p>In summary, our third quarter performance was strong. GAAP EPS increased 66% versus the same period last year, and our non-GAAP EPS was up 16% versus Q3 2008. Solid operational performance, reflected in sales growth in our BioPharma business, along with continued focus on expense management, resulted in yet another strong quarter for Bristol-Myers.</p>
          <p>Let me turn to revenues. The company posted Q3 2009 net sales from continuing operations of around $5.5 billion, which represents an increase of 4%, or 7% excluding foreign exchange impact, compared to last year. Mead Johnson's net sales were just shy of $700 million in Q3, representing a 6% decrease, or a 2% decrease ex FX compared to prior year.</p>
          <p>Now let me just focus specifically on our BioPharma business. Our BioPharma sales were up 6% in Q3, or 9% ex FX. Our U.S. sales grew 12% to $3 billion compared to last year. And internationally our net sales decreased 2%, but increased an important 5% when you exclude the impact of foreign exchange. Foreign exchange negatively impacted our BioPharma Q3 net sales by approximately 3 percentage points. We had a positive 5% impact from price and again, and importantly, a positive 4% increase in volume. So in summary, when it comes to top line, our underlying business is strong and we have had consistent sales growth this year.</p>
          <p>Let me walk you through some of the highlights. Firstly, turning to Cardiovascular. On a global basis, PLAVIX sales were up 9% excluding foreign exchange. In the U.S., our Q3 net sales for PLAVIX were up 11% versus last year. The increase is driven by price increases, but again, also importantly, volume gains. To date Effient has had minimal impact on PLAVIX sales.</p>
          <p>Turning to Europe, generic clopidogrel is now commercialized in six EU markets: Germany, UK, Denmark, Netherlands, Belgium, and France. We do anticipate generic launches in Italy, Greece, Portugal, Norway, and Sweden between now and mid next year.</p>
          <p>Turning to Neuroscience, in the quarter, ABILIFY worldwide sales, ex FX, were up 18% versus prior year. About two-thirds of our sales growth in the U.S. comes from our indications for bipolar and major depressive disorder. Our strong clinical program for ABILIFY has led to the broadest set of indications for any atypical. As part of the extension agreement we signed earlier in the year with Otsuka, reported alliance revenue is lower by $16 million in this quarter, and that reflects the amortization of the $400 million upfront payment that we made to Otsuka earlier this year.</p>
          <p>Turning to our Virology franchise. The Virology portfolio had global sales growth of 12% excluding foreign exchange when you compare it to last year. This was led BARACLUDE at plus 37%; the SUSTIVA franchise at plus 11%; and REYATAZ, which posted sales growth of 9%, a very steady growth in the face of competition from the new protease inhibitors launched this year. Nearly seven out of 10 new-to-treatment patients are prescribed either SUSTIVA or REYATAZ as part of their initial antiretroviral regimen. BARACLUDE global sales were just shy of $200 million at $191 million in the quarter, and BARACLUDE has market leadership in the EU, China, and Japan.</p>
          <p>Turning to Immunology. ORENCIA sales were at $160 million, plus 38% ex FX. In the U.S., ORENCIA grew at 30%, driven by continued execution, as well as favorable market conditions. Important new data were presented just this week at the American College of Rheumatology meeting. The AGREE study suggests ORENCIA can be used earlier in rheumatoid arthritis patients who are new to biologics. We also for the first time released Phase III data showing the potential for subcutaneous administration of ORENCIA.</p>
          <p>Turning to Oncology. ERBITUX sales in the U.S. were at $175 million, down 4% versus prior year but up 2% since Q2. ERBITUX sales in colorectal cancer have begun to stabilize, despite a continued decline in the overall colorectal cancer marketplace. Total head and neck market growth has been flat versus prior year, as well as prior quarter. Turning to SPRYCEL, global sales were at $107 million, up nearly 40% versus prior year if you exclude foreign exchange.</p>
          <p>Turning to metabolics. ONGLYZA was approved in the U.S. in July, as you know, and in Europe in October. We, along with our good partners at AstraZeneca, have launched in the U.S. and also in Mexico, the UK, and Germany and look to launch in a number of additional key markets in the near future. We recorded 20 million of sales in the third quarter for ONGLYZA. We have made good progress in our launch to date, and positive signs include improved access and reimbursement globally, a rapid increase in brand awareness by physicians, and positive trends in physicians' intent to prescribe the drug.</p>
          <p>Let me go back now to our P&amp;L, and let me also specifically comment on our P&amp;L focusing in our BioPharma business. If you look at gross margins, we realized a 170 basis point increase in gross margins, compared to the same period last year. The key drivers were multifold. One, prices; two, cost savings; three, favorable FX; as well as product mix. When you look at our pre-tax earnings for the BioPharma business, they were up 19%, and the increase was driven by sales, gross margins, as well as the reduction in marketing, selling, and administrative expenses. For the quarter we reduced our BioPharma SG&amp;A as a percentage of sales by 3.4% from 28.2% a year ago to just south of 25% in Q3 2009. This figure has steadily decreased since the first quarter of 2008, when BioPharma SG&amp;A as a percentage of sales was just under 30%.</p>
          <p>Turning to R&amp;D. BioPharma R&amp;D expenses did increase by 5% to $820 million. However, as a percentage of sales, this was flat at 17.1% for the quarter compared to 17.3% this time last year. This was accomplished even with adding expenses from three pearls versus the same period last year.</p>
          <p>Turning to taxes. Our overall company non-GAAP tax rate on earnings from continuing operations was at 24.4% for Q3 compared to 25.3% in 2008.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to cash and our balance sheet. We continue to drive and focus on cash flow, and our employees have fully embraced this philosophy. We currently have 7.9 billion of cash as per the end of September this year, and that includes cash, cash equivalents, as well as marketable securities. This supports the financial flexibility we need to invest in our existing business, as well as potential business development activities to improve the earnings profile of the company in our important Stage 2 as well as Stage 3. Even after the $2.1 billion net impact of the Medarex acquisition that we just completed, we still have a net cash position of $1.3 billion at the end of the quarter.</p>
          <p>Based on Mead Johnson's announcement today that it is considering options to refinance its outstanding intercompany debt, we expect to receive approximately $1.75 billion in U.S. cash upon closing of this potential transaction. Also in the quarter, we announced two strategic divestitures in Indonesia and in Australia for a combined $372 million in cash. This cash we expect to receive in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>We have excellent operating cash flows and continue to make progress on our working capital initiatives, which we announced to the outside world in Q3 of last year. And this has helped drive our positive net cash position. Our net trade receivables, inventories, and accounts payables as a percentage of net sales was at 11.2% in Q3 of this year. This compares to just under 13% at the beginning of the year. So good improvement through the last three quarters.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to guidance. We are updating our 2009 non-GAAP EPS from continuing operations guidance range from $1.95 to $2.05 to $2 to $2.05. We are raising our 2009 GAAP EPS guidance from $1.58 to $1.68 to the new range of $1.72 to $1.77. We are pleased, in summary, with our operating performance to date and expect 2009 full-year EPS to be near the high end of the originally stated guidance.</p>
          <p>A couple of things just to keep in mind for the fourth quarter. There is the impact for the full quarter that takes place from the Medarex acquisition. Secondly, please take note of the fact that we will start to be impacted by the increased generic competition for PLAVIX in the EU, and this will continue to erode in our equity in net income from affiliates line in Q4 and further into 2010.</p>
          <p>We do reaffirm our guidance that non-GAAP EPS from continuing operations is expected to grow at a minimum of 15% compound annually, from 2007 until 2010, i.e. next year, without rebasing for ConvaTec. We are maintaining this long-term guidance, notwithstanding the dilution from the very important ABILIFY extension, the dilution from the Medarex acquisition, which as we disclosed would be between 0.07 to $0.09 next year, as well as the generic competition for PLAVIX in Europe, which I just mentioned.</p>
          <p>In closing, as has been the case with our past several quarters, our third quarter performance was solid by any measure. Strong sales growth with improved gross and pre-tax margins resulted in a 16% increase in non-GAAP EPS from continuing operations. Across our organization, we are accelerating our transition into a next-generation BioPharma leader.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much, and we're happy to take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jean-Marc. And thanks, Jim. Tony, I think we're ready to go ahead for questions. If we could go ahead and start.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Today's question and answer session is held electronically. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And we'll go first to John Boris at Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the questions. Jim, the first question just has to do with 2013 and beyond and how you're thinking about the growth profile of the company. Operationally, the company's running very well. A lot of pipeline visibility is obviously picking up, and then you obviously have a lot of cash to be able to deploy towards pearls.</p>
          <p>So relative to the growth profile in '13 of which we'd anticipate you'll probably share some of that with us in December, how you're thinking about that. And then also on pearl side, just the size of the pearls. I think you've outlined somewhat of a limit on the size of pearls, but how you're thinking about maybe larger pearls going forward versus smaller pearls and being able to enhance that growth profile.</p>
          <p>And then just one question for Jean-Marc on working capital. Kudos on the improvement, but can you help us understand where you'd like to take inventories going forward and how much cash that you might see that unleash going forward? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, John, let me start on a very complicated issue. First of all, we do think about what we call Stage 2 quite a bit. So not 100% of our efforts are devoted to this outstanding short-term performance. But the ABILIFY contract extension, for example, where we changed the cliff into a platform for growth would be an example of how we're thinking about stabilizing Stage 2. You paid us a compliment by saying we're getting increased visibility on our pipeline. We feel very good about the clinical data that's been released this year. We will have more to say probably on December 2 about the longer-term Stage 2 and Stage 3.</p>
          <p>On pearls, big or large, they need to be shiny. And what I mean by that is they need to fit what our disease strategy teams tell us that they need. So I'm going to turn that over to Elliott to add a little color on the String of Pearls.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, John, as we've said before, the primary focus of our String of Pearls strategy is to look at deals that are accretive in the 2012-2013 time period and not detrimental to growth past 2013, as well as deals that build our late-stage pipeline in several key disease areas by 2012. Our priority focus is to migrate into cardiology adjacencies, as you've seen, build our Alzheimer's portfolio, expand immunoscience, and increase the strength of our HIV franchise. Our secondary focus is to expand hematologic malignancy and build solid tumor capabilities. I believe we've been successful to date, and we'll be reiterating the strategy December 2. And the focus is on building a platform in Stage 2 and increasing the slope of what we see as growth in Stage 3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just in terms of working capital, a couple of points. Firstly, we really have built a culture which is focused on cash flow, and that is a real prerequisite to drive cash flow and specifically working capital. And so I think we're very well positioned for further improvements from where we are today.</p>
          <p>The second one &#x2013; and it's very much the approach we have also around productivity &#x2013; is we will try and improve on a continuous basis. So rather than just give a new target, we will just continuously improve year upon year.</p>
          <p>I guess the third point, as you mentioned, inventories, but I'd just like to expand the point. We have receivables, inventories, payables. We also actually are very much focused on CapEx. But those four drivers of cash flow are ones that we're all pushing with the same type of rigor. We also do need to be careful on inventory levels, and while there's more that we can do within the organization, we're also very much focused on maintaining the appropriate service levels. So we're doing this all in a rigorous and in a continuous manner. But I'm very happy with the fact that our culture has embraced the drive to cash flow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jean. Tony, can we go to the next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Tony Butler of Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Jean-Marc, a question for you, and two for Elliott. There has been a launch of several generic clopidogrel compounds in Europe, and I'm curious if that actually has occurred at a time that was earlier than you expected? Or is this congruent with your expectations? And more importantly, how should we think about that joint venture and equity income line?</p>
          <p>And then for Elliott, please, if I may, when you think about belatacept, you obviously were great in following the compound, but are you puzzled as to why the FDA would not give you an accelerated review? And I'm curious of comments you may have around that. And then secondly, with AVERROES and ARISTOTLE to complete in theory next year, is there any change in the timing of when those might complete and/or the thoughts between you and your partner on how that clinical trial should &#x2013; should it be changed with respect to endpoints? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Tony , this is Lamberto. I will start on clopidogrel in Europe, and then Jean-Marc may add something. It is clear that we were expecting generic competition of this size in Europe later. And it is clear that we have taken all measures that are necessary to as much as we can offset the consequences of this generic or multiple generic launch in Europe.</p>
          <p>The PLAVIX franchise in Europe, between us and Sanofi, was well above $2 billion last year. And as Jean-Marc was reminding all of us, most of our work &#x2013; share of that franchise is booked in a approved line of income from minority, or whatever it's called. But it's not we don't book the top line, okay? And this will obviously become noticeable in Q4 and in 2010.</p>
          <p>Now, having said that, we have a positive unplanned event that will allow us to look at the future in the world of cardiovascular metabolics a different way, and this is the earlier launch for ONGLYZA in Europe. For sure in our initial plan ONGLYZA was not for a launch in September of 2009. It was at least one year later than that. And so this is very important because not only we had the contribution of ONGLYZA to our P&amp;L, but we can transition &#x2013; we have transitioned &#x2013; our cardiovascular structures from PLAVIX to ONGLYZA. So in summary, a positive news from ONGLYZA offsetting in the longer term the contribution of these earlier-than-expected launch of PLAVIX.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe just to add on very briefly to Lamberto's comments, we do do a whole variety of internal scenario planning, and have taken that into account, and its generic erosion, when speaking about our 15% guidance, which includes next year, 2010. But this is, again like Lamberto said, a line item in the profit and loss statement that we will need to focus more upon in the next quarters, and will decline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, John, this is Elliott. You asked a question with regard to belatacept filing, as well as an update on apixaban, particularly in atrial fibrillation.</p>
          <p>We now have the FDA accepting our BLA for the filing and review, and our PDUFA date is May 1, and I'm pleased with that. The assignment of a standard review recognizes, in my view, the complexity of the Phase III data for belatacept, one of the first agents in a long time to undergo review in this area, as well as the complexity of the BLA filing itself. And as the data have shown, there are clear advantages, and yet there are challenges associated with belatacept. We're very comfortable with a standard review, and I think it allows the FDA and the sponsor enough time to fully assess appropriately the BLA. So I think this is a good sign in general for the drug, and I don't interpret it any other way.</p>
          <p>With regard to apixaban, certainly the European Society of Cardiology was very exciting in the area of anticoagulation, and we now have even stronger belief that warfarin can be unseated because of the negative aspects of warfarin and probably because there's more anticoagulation to achieve efficacy by new mechanisms. So we are very excited about that and very comfortable with our program that's extensive for apixaban.</p>
          <p>You mentioned about any changes, certainly we are now more confident that we might be able to achieve superiority in certain subsets of patients perhaps, and that's &#x2013; we always evaluate the clinical programs and interact with the FDA to make sure that we can extract as much value from the program, which as you said, includes two important studies. One uses warfarin as a comparator; the other uses aspirin in those patients who can't tolerate or are considered ineligible for warfarin. So we will have these studies completely enrolled soon, and we look forward to this field unfolding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tony. And Tony, can we go to the next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we'll go next to Jami Rubin at Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This is a question for you, Jim. I'm sure you've noticed how well Mead Johnson has done since the partial IPO. Just curious to know how and when you plan to monetize your Mead Johnson stake. I believe that the last time you referenced this, Mead Johnson was trading around $30, and you said you'd need to wait about 18 months or so to make a decision about a split-off or a spin-off. But given that the stock's now at 42, based on our math those strategies would actually yield an accretive impact to your earnings. So I'm wondering if you could just talk about what the options are looking like now and how you are going to assess those options. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I read your report, and it's very helpful in thinking through the many alternatives we have for Mead Johnson. I think we've all been pleasantly surprised at how quickly it's gone up to $42 from its initial IPO. You do the math, that's over $8 billion of value embedded in Bristol-Myers Squibb; we own 83% of it.</p>
          <p>I think we're very pleased. They announced their results this morning, and outlook for the fourth quarter and next year I think are okay. We'll continue to look at the strategic options much like we look at all of our strategic options. So couldn't be more pleased with the stock price, with the performance of the management, the most senior management now in Chicago, and this new Board of Directors with four independent directors. The separation has gone without a hitch, and we're in really good shape as we approach year-end.</p>
          <p>As Jean-Marc pointed out, we're anticipating, if they're successful in refinancing intercompany debt, of a significant cash payment to us for the intercompany debt, which is $1.75 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jami. Can we go to the next question, please, Tony?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And next to David Risinger of Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks very much. I just have a couple questions. First, Jean-Marc, if you could just tell us the FX impact on EPS. And then second, maybe a couple of you could just address SPRYCEL. Obviously you've delivered strong year-over-year growth for SPRYCEL. Could you talk about the sales outlook for that product? And also your development program to expand the label, particularly relative to Tasigna's development plans? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So maybe I'll just quickly take yours. The bottom line impact of FX was a negative approximately $0.03 or so. So that's the specific answer to your question, but maybe I can just also take the opportunity to just talk about our gross margin, because obviously FX is a driver within gross margin. But I think that what makes us happy with the gross margin increases that we've posted in Q3 is that they're coming from product mix; they're coming from pricing; they're coming from savings that are taking place through our manufacturing rationalization. They're also being helped by Mead Johnson's increased gross margin, as well as foreign exchange. So it is a driver, but not &#x2013; there are many drivers to our gross margin improvements. But to give you a specific answer to your question, the impact on the bottom line is approximately $0.03.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So speaking of SPRYCEL &#x2013; this is Lamberto, David. Well, you've seen the results. Growth of sales in the U.S. of 33% versus previous year and international sales up 30% net of our tax versus previous year. So this is a consistent quarter-after-quarter growth, and we'll not change our strategy. We are supporting SPRYCEL as the prepared treatment option in second line CML.</p>
          <p>Our job in the U.S. and EU is to instill urgency among prescribers, among physicians, to identify and treat people that are resistant to Gleevec and switch them to SPRYCEL. And we have been successful so far. And if I look at our performance versus the performance of Tasigna, and I focus on the U.S. for now, well, relative to SPRYCEL, fewer doctors have prescribed Tasigna. Approximately 50% of use of Tasigna is in third line, following SPRYCEL.</p>
          <p>So we have quite a different performance, quite a different profile for our product. And that makes us confident that if we hit a first-line indication for our product, we will be very competitive there too against Tasigna.</p>
          <p>Elliott, do you want to add something on the clinical trial?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Lamberto. David, you asked about our life cycle program, so we're intently focused on a couple different arms of developing SPRYCEL further. First of all it has, unlike Gleevec, the SARC activity. So we are well under way in exploiting the opportunities in solid tumors such as in prostate cancer, which is Phase III, and breast cancer, with a focus on estrogen receptor positive disease in Phase II.</p>
          <p>The next significant potential catalytic event, as you referred to, is unmasking early next year the data for our first-line study, head to head with Gleevec. In many ways similar to the study that was announced in a press release, but not scientifically discussed yet on Tasigna versus Gleevec. Those studies are similar, with I think an important difference in the primary end point.</p>
          <p>And the primary end point in our first-line study versus Gleevec is confirmed complete cytogenetic response. And we took extra time to work out with the regulatory authorities that this would be acceptable for submission in both the U.S. and in Europe. In fact, the European guidance recommends against the type of primary end point I have seen our competitors use. So we need to see the full data of both studies, not just the primary end point conclusions. But the safety profile, for reasons that Lamberto mentioned, is different in both drugs and perhaps more favorable with SPRYCEL in that Tasigna has a black box for cardiovascular potential complications.</p>
          <p>So this is a very exciting area. The positive results that I mentioned so far give me more confidence that we could be looking at a positive study relatively soon, a well-designed study with interaction with regulatory authorities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David. Can we go to the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And next is Steve Scala at Cowen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I have three brief questions. First, what dollar and unit share do PLAVIX generics have in the EU? And then two for Dr. Sigal. First, on OASIS 7, do you plan to file the data, and if so, what would be the objective with respect to labeling? And then lastly, on apixaban, is the ADVANCE-3 data in house? And if so, what are your filing plans in the U.S. and EU for DVT? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will start with PLAVIX EU. The latest data I've seen were indicating that by the end of September, clopidogrel bisulfate, the generic clopidogrel, in Germany had approximately 45% of market share in units. And we have seen that in other countries, generic competition is now pricing their product at 40% of where PLAVIX is. I think this is the French price that has been recently published.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Steve, with regard to OASIS, or also called the CURRENT trial, on PLAVIX where we did the high loading dose, or as it's also been called, the double-dose clopidogrel study, which had some very, I think, important medical information that confirms medical practice and decreases any contrast with an alternative agent, prasugrel, on efficacy by this higher loading dose. I think this is important information for physicians.</p>
          <p>We are still going &#x2013; since this was an independently run trial on the outside, we are still in the process of the usual procedures of going through the database, going through the data. We do plan as an alliance to talk to the FDA. The goal for the labeling would be to put the 600 milligram loading dose and the associated data, which I think's significant, with regard to the practice of medicine and the choices that people should have with PLAVIX.</p>
          <p>With regard to apixaban ADVANCE-3 will be the third orthopedic setting that we have tested apixaban in to prevent clots in the legs. And we do not have those results; I have not seen those results yet. But they will be relatively soon. As you know, we hope to have a late-breaker at the American Society of Hematology on these results. And when we look at the results of all three studies, we will make a decision with regard to: a), filing in Europe, and b), whether we'd consider filing in the U.S. But I don't have any more news at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Can we go to the next question please, Tony?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next is Seamus Fernandez at Leerink Swann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, thanks very much. So just wondering a couple of things. Can you update us on ORENCIA and the timing of when you expect to file and have final data for the subcutaneous formulation of ORENCIA, and whether or not that dosing is once weekly or every other week dosing? Separately, in terms of launch expectations, particularly for belatacept, as it perhaps comes to market next year, how would you characterize your expectations for the launch given the conservatism of transplant physicians in that space? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Seamus. With regards to ORENCIA sub-cu, we were excited to present the safety data part of the program from the sub-cu formulation of the pivotal trial recently at the American College of Rheumatology. These data do show that weekly &#x2013; weekly &#x2013; sub-cu abatacept results in low immunogenicity after repeat dosing and is well tolerated, so that's step one. Step two is the efficacy data; we'll get that early next year. We've done a very comprehensive trial so that we can extend the information we have on sub-cu to make it relevant to every one of the indications we have for the intravenous form. Then there will be a period of time of analysis that's needed to make sure that the pharmacokinetics is all in order for us to make that extension.</p>
          <p>So we don't have an exact filing date right now. It'll probably be in the second half of the year. And we'll be able to update people later as that progresses. It should be filed for sub-cu once weekly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as far as belatacept is concerned, well, the way we see it is &#x2013; well, we are aware that the key mathematical need in the transplant world is the long-term outcomes of both the graft and the patient. So our commercial strategy for belatacept is to replace CNIs as part of the chronic multi-drug immunosuppressive regimen that is a standard of care following transplant.</p>
          <p>Our initial target &#x2013; we are very realistic &#x2013; our initial target indication is for use in new kidney transplantations, and we are realistically thinking that it will take time to build out this product. On the other hand, we know that the data, the Phase III data that we have, is encouraging and supports our target profile. So we are including, I believe, Elliott, two-year data in our submission?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This will be presented in 2010 -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; and this supports our belief in the product. But again, it will be not the fastest update you ever seen, because of the nature of the product and the nature of the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Seamus. Can we go to the next question, Tony?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And next to Keyur Parekh with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and thanks for taking the question. This is for Jean-Marc. Jean-Marc, as I look at the kind of long-term guidance range between 2007 and 2010, and if I use the midpoint of the estimate EPS range for this year, it implies roughly a 3% EPS growth for 2010. And that obviously implies a fair degree of slowdown relative to the last few years. Just a little bit confused about that. I mean, is there material scope for upside on the 2010 minimum guidance range as we stand today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think I can comment on this, but we will come back to you in terms of 2010 guidance when we normally do. I will just reiterate the fact that today despite dilution from Medarex, despite the impact of generics in Europe and despite the extension of ABILIFY, we reiterate a minimum of 15% earnings guidance from 2007 to 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Keyur. Tony, I think we just have time for a couple more questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go next to Chris Schott at J.P. Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. First question on dapagliflozin, can you just tell me your latest thinking on the filing plans here? I believe your partner pointed to a second half 2010 timeline for a U.S. filing with their last earnings call. Can you just comment how you get to that type of date given the FDA's guidelines for new diabetes agents? And then second, on the ONGLYZA launch, would be interested in where U.S. formulary position currently stands and kind of when you'd expect to achieve your target access levels here. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, we'll have more information on our exact filing plan as '10 unfolds. Our alliance partner, AstraZeneca, and us are targeting and getting prepared for an end of '10 submission. However, the cardiovascular safety &#x2013; that original timeline was set before the cardiovascular safety requirements, and we're in constant contact with the FDA. And the types of trials that we have ongoing are all event-driven. So I can't give an exact date at this particular time.</p>
          <p>With dapagliflozin, we are now just looking at our third Phase III study, and this afternoon our second is being presented, and the first was presented earlier. And we have eight Phase III studies, so we have five more to go. I'm very encouraged by the target profile that's emerging, but we have four more Phase III studies in the completion of the assessment of no cardiovascular harm. I remain encouraged by this first-in-class opportunity in diabetes and will be able to update you when we know more about our filing plans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And about ONGLYZA, it is clear that we have devoted a lot of effort and attention to the inclusion in the managed care reimbursement lease. And what we have achieved so far is good. We &#x2013; as far as I &#x2013; there's enough data indicate we have ONGLYZA accessible to 75% of the overall covered lives, and of these covered lives who have access to ONGLYZA, 82% have access without restrictions. In 28% &#x2013; are Tier 2, and obviously our focus is to increase now the numbers in Tier 2.</p>
          <p>Speaking of ONGLYZA, I think that it's good opportunity for me to say that we are pleased from what we have seen so far. We are executing against our plan. We launched in August. We launched in a different U.S. than the U.S. of many years ago, so we could work less on pre-launch awareness. And therefore we are very pleased to see that now that we are in the marketplace, awareness is going up from almost zero at the beginning to a good percentage now. The number of trialists, the number of doctors that are using ONGLYZA, is increasing. I saw some data on intent to prescribe, which is also going the right direction. And access, as I was describing before, is going the right direction too.</p>
          <p>So we and AstraZeneca are confident that we will deliver success here. We are waiting for the approval by DDMAC, the FDA's DDMAC, of our promotional materials of how we can only promote <mark type="inaudible" /> the product profile. And as you can imagine, I and many of my colleagues are spending a lot of time reviewing the performance of this product. We just launched in the UK, Germany, and some smaller European markets, and as you can imagine also there we are very focused on the execution of our plan and looking forward to results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tony, I think we have time for two more questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the next is Tim Anderson at Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. A couple of questions. Going back to Mead Johnson, if you were to sell that, either now &#x2013; or let's say the stock goes up to 50 or something, and you sell it &#x2013; does that then change how you approach the string of pearls? Because you already seem to have quite a bit of cash, and that would obviously give you another big bolus of cash? And I'm wondering what the intent would be with that cash? Second question is on ORENCIA. The product has been doing well and is steadily growing. I'm wondering if you can talk about what you see as the competitive threat of Roche's Actemra, because that product seems like it's going to go straight for the market where you guys sell most of ORENCIA, which is in that infusion space after a TNF failure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with revisiting the Mead Johnson question. You know, it's not out of consideration that we keep Mead Johnson, because it's growing at a very nice rate, important contributor to both sales and earnings. As we gain more confidence in what we described earlier as Stage 2, they may not be as important at that point in time as they are today. A sale, because of the very low tax basis, results in a huge tax liability, so that's one option. A tax-free spin-off is another, and a tax-free split-off is another. So the consideration and timing of those four alternatives is very much what we're focused on, Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And speaking of ORENCIA and Actemra, obviously we are following with attention what will happen in the market at the launch of Actemra. It is true that Actemra goes into the same portion of the market where we compete, the IV portion, and we're very confident of what we have in terms of data, in terms of plan. We have a product that has good efficacy and that has a good durability of efficacy. So the two things combined make us believe that ORENCIA can compete and compete very well. And this is a safe product, ORENCIA.</p>
          <p>So we have a lot of winning points. And if you look at our performance versus REMICADE, that performance has improved quarter over quarter. And we think that we can continue to deliver despite the launch of Actemra. You know that we have the radiographic data out to five years, I believe, which highlights that the ORENCIA inhibits the structural damage. And this is very important to give us confidence in ORENCIA as a long-lasting duration product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And maybe just one comment on our cash position, Tim. As it stands today, we have a very strong cash position, and that will increase, especially once there is recognition for this intercompany debt coming from Mead Johnson. As I also mentioned, we have nearly $400 million coming through from divestitures that have taken place in the quarter. So we can really look at Mead Johnson from the perspective of doing the right thing for shareholders. Our cash position is in a very, very good place to just continue the String of Pearls, as we've been mentioning each and every quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tony, can we go to the last question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Eric Lo at Banc of America-Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. Thanks for taking our questions. Just a couple quick ones. Beyond ABILIFY sales force announcements last week, are there plans to re-evaluate the sales force commitment for any other products in the near term? And the second question is, can you provide perhaps a more specific timing in terms of when we can expect to see Phase III data for <mark type="inaudible" /> IV malignant melanoma?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the sales force question. First of all, just to make it clear, we are not decreasing the support we're giving to ABILIFY. ABILIFY's a product doing extremely well in the marketplace, growing much faster than the market, and gaining market share versus all competitors. So we are obviously not decreasing our support to that product. It is only a different mix of support between us and Otsuka that we are providing. So what we decrease in terms of sales force support, Otsuka will provide or is providing in strict coordination with us. So nothing to do with productivity there. It is only an implementation of an agreement we have with Otsuka Pharmaceuticals.</p>
          <p>As far as the rest of our sales force in the U.S., we have reached a balanced situation for our CVMet sales force. We have sized it to support PLAVIX until we have PLAVIX in the marketplace, to launch ONGLYZA and to provide a limited support to AVAPRO in the various parts of the country where it is needed. So we do not expect, if we continue to deliver successful performance of our products and the new products, to go for major changes in our sales force structure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Eric, on our Phase III first-line advanced melanoma study for ipilimumab in combination with dacarbazine, this is a survival study, so it's event-driven. All we can say is we're expecting results sometime in 2010, but it's event-driven and I can't predict exactly when that's going to occur right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, Eric, and thanks, everybody, for all your questions. I'll turn it over to Jim for some closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, thanks, John.</p>
          <p>We continue to deliver broad-based sales growth, really underlying our excellent commercial execution. As Lamberto just said, we're committed, along with our partner, AstraZeneca, to making ONGLYZA a successful global commercial product. I believe we've had a cultural change here at Bristol-Myers Squibb, and continuous improvement with a focus on cost management is an accepted concept. And it delivers significant improvements, as you've seen, in both gross margins and pre-tax margins and finally this outstanding cash flow performance.</p>
          <p>We have a growing cash balance, a robust pipeline, and we'll continue to supplement that pipeline through the String of Pearls. In summary, Bristol-Myers Squibb is a company that delivers on its commitments. We will continue to do so in the future.</p>
          <p>Thanks very much for your attention and questions today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This does conclude today's conference. We do thank you for your participation. Have a nice day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>