<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1188139" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-10-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>84</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John Elicker, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James M. Cornelius, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Jean-Marc Huet, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Tim Anderson</participant>
      <participant id="5">James Cornelius</participant>
      <participant id="6">Elliott Sigal</participant>
      <participant id="7">Lamberto Andreotti</participant>
      <participant id="8">John Elicker</participant>
      <participant id="9">David Risinger</participant>
      <participant id="10">Jean-Marc Huet</participant>
      <participant id="11">Chris Schott</participant>
      <participant id="12">Roopesh Patel</participant>
      <participant id="13">John Boris</participant>
      <participant id="14">Seamus Fernandez</participant>
      <participant id="15">Steve Scala</participant>
      <participant id="16">Catherine Arnold</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day everyone, and welcome to today's Third Quarter Earnings 2008 Earning Release Conference Call. This call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the call over to Mr. John Elicker, Vice President of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, Mr. Elicker.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Enola, and good morning everybody. Thanks for joining us to review our third quarter results. The release was issued this morning, as well as posted on our website, as well as the supporting financial data.</p>
          <p>With me this morning are Jim Cornelius, our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer; Jean-Marc Huet, our Chief Financial Office, they'll both have prepared remarks, and then joining us for Q&amp;A are Lamberto Andreotti, our Chief Operating Officer, and Elliott Sigal, our Chief Scientific Officer.</p>
          <p>Before we get started, let me take care of the legal requirement. During this call, we'll make statements about the company's future plans and prospects including statements about our financial position, business strategy, research pipeline concerning product development and product potential, that constitute forward-looking statements for purposes of the Safe Harbor Provisions under the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Actual results may differ materially from those indicated by these forward-looking statements as a result of various important factors, including those discussed in the company's most recent annual report on Form 10-K, periodic reports on Form 10-Q, and current reports on Form 8-K. These documents are available from the SEC, the Bristol-Myers website, or from Bristol-Myers Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>In addition, any forward-looking statements represent our estimates only as of this day and should not be relied upon as representing our estimates as of any subsequent date. While we may elect to update forward-looking statements at some point in the future, we specifically disclaim any obligation to do so, even if our estimates change.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn the call over to Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. Good morning, everyone. Thank you for joining us.</p>
          <p>Let me start by saying that our operational performance in the third quarter was excellent, a direct result of our strategy and the hard work by the entire BMS team. We delivered very strong results in the quarter, both at the top and the bottom lines, as we have all year.</p>
          <p>We had double-digit increases in sales in the quarter, and we remain in the period of sustained and improved earnings growth that we forecasted for you last December, and now feel even more confident we can deliver in the future.</p>
          <p>On a non-GAAP basis, we grew diluted earnings per share from continuing operations 39% in the quarter, or $0.46, which was $0.04 ahead of consensus estimates. Our GAAP diluted EPS tripled in the quarter, up to $1.29, which includes an after-tax gain of $0.99 per share from the sale of ConvaTec. This sale contributed 4.1 billion in cash proceeds which will help fund both operations and continuation of the String of Pearls strategy. Also on a GAAP basis, diluted EPS from continuing operations for the third quarter was $0.30 a share, down 21% from last year, reflecting the impact of specified items which Jean-Marc will review in a moment.</p>
          <p>The breadth and strength of the product portfolio underscores good sales execution worldwide in the quarter. Our pharmaceutical net sales grew 18% in the US and 11% internationally. Globally, Mead Johnson Nutritionals grew 10% in the quarter. We increased revenue 14% in the third quarter by delivering growth on key products worldwide.</p>
          <p>For instance, on a global basis, ABILIFY grew 34% and PLAVIX grew 15% and our virology franchise grew 27%, all compared to the third quarter last year. And sales of ORENCIA, one of our more recently launched biologic products, nearly doubled since the third quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>As we've grown the top line, we've also managed our costs quite effectively. As a result, our margins continue to improve in the third quarter. Gross profit as a percentage of net sales rose 170 basis points on a non-GAAP basis compared to the third quarter of 2007. Our non-GAAP net income margin rose 300 basis points as well. I'm glad to say we're well on track to deliver on our productivity initiatives as we projected.</p>
          <p>We're raising our GAAP guidance for 2008, assuming we receive cash this year for the ImClone shares we own. We now expect fully diluted EPS from continuing operations to be between $1.61 and $1.66 per share on a GAAP basis, and between $1.65 and $1.70 earnings per share on a non-GAAP basis, which would be at the upper range of our previous guidance.</p>
          <p>We are reaffirming that we expect non-GAAP earnings per share from continuing operations to grow by at least 15% compounded annual growth rate from the 2007 base, which included ConvaTec, and this is for a period through 2010.</p>
          <p>We're especially pleased about our strong cash position which is now at $7.2 billion, boosted in part by the cash proceeds of ConvaTec. We expect to add to our cash reserves this year proceeds from the sale of our shares of ImClone, as well as proceeds in 2009 from a partial IPO of Mead Johnson. Our balance sheet puts us in a very strong position to continue executing against our biopharma strategy. We told you in December we would be reviewing our non-pharma businesses as a result of the biopharma strategy. Since then, we've sold ConvaTec and Medical Imaging, and we've announced our intentions for Mead Johnson.</p>
          <p>In addition, we continue to rationalize our manufacturing and geographical footprint while delivering growth selectively in emerging markets. For example, we're selling a plant and some mature brands in Egypt to GlaxoSmithKline for $210 million, though we'll remain in Egypt with our portfolio of innovative products.</p>
          <p>On the clinical science front, we're steadily advancing our pipeline and expanding our portfolio. Last month, we saw encouraging survival data for ERBITUX and ipilumimab coming out of cancer conferences, and promising data on ONGLYZA at the European Association for the Study of Diabetes.</p>
          <p>Since we launched our String of Pearls strategy a year ago with the purchase of Adnexus, we've required a growing cluster of innovative start-ups and licensing agreements that complement our existing pipeline. This quarter, for instance, we announced an alliance with PDL BioPharma to develop and commercialize an anti-CS1 antibody currently in early development from multiple myeloma. And while we did not close on our bid for ImClone, I'm very proud of the way the team pursued the deal, with a degree of vigor and discipline that will go a long way toward preparing us for future deals which will ultimately help us emerge as the leading next-generation biopharma company over the long term.</p>
          <p>And now, for more detail about our financial performance, I'll turn the call over to our CFO, Jean-Marc Huet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Jim.</p>
          <p>What I will do is first review our Q3 results and then guidance before turning over to Q&amp;A. Let me start with revenue first.</p>
          <p>Total sales from continuing operations were up 14%. You should note that this excludes ConvaTec, which we've reported as a discontinued operation. Given our very strong year-to-date sales performance and our outlook for the remainder of the year, we now expect full-year sales to be up in the lower double-digit range.</p>
          <p>If we take our sales from continuing operations at 14%, this is an overall sales which includes 3% as a result of FX, 3% due to pricing, and 8% which represents an increase in volumes, which just demonstrates the strength of our business portfolio.</p>
          <p>Pharmaceutical sales were up 15%, including a 3% impact due to foreign exchange. This is a broad-based growth across the portfolio, driven by PLAVIX, ABILIFY, our virology business, as well as our newer products. So let me turn to the specific therapeutic areas, first starting with our CV med business.</p>
          <p>US PLAVIX sales were up 17% in Q3. This is true sales growth and there is no impact from Apotex, unlike Q1 and to a lesser extent, Q2. TRX trends encouraging, plus 7% as stent procedures seem to be stabilizing.</p>
          <p>If we then go to neuroscience, ABILIFY up 34% globally and 32% in the US. We had 26% prescription growth in the US, which reflects execution against the opportunities in bipolar and the &#x2013; new Major Depressive Disorder indication supported by a strong DTC campaign which will continue in Q4. Growth in Europe supported &#x2013; was supported by the bipolar indication.</p>
          <p>Let me turn to have virology. REYATAZ was up 25% globally, including 18% in the US due to TRx growth. Our SUSTIVA franchise sales were up 24% globally behind a strong performance of ATRIPLA. BARACLUDE sales were at $144 million, with over 100 million outside the United States.</p>
          <p>Turning to immunology, our ORENCIA sales were at just under $120 million, up 12% compared to Q2 of this year.</p>
          <p>Oncology. ERBITUX sales were at 184 million, relatively flat compared to the same quarter last year. This was due to a change in the distribution model last year, as well as slower sales in colorectal cancer. We expect this market to be a growth driver long term, as oncologists are able to identify those patients most likely to benefit based on KRAS testing. Global SPRYCEL sales were at $82 million with continued growth in Europe. IXEMPRA launched in the US during Q4 generated sales of $25 million.</p>
          <p>Turning to our nutrition business, Mead Johnson, which represents around 15% of company sales, increased at 10%, or 7% excluding foreign exchange, at around $744 million.</p>
          <p>So in summary, we had quality revenue growth in each business and every geography. The US pharmaceuticals business, of particular note, strong at plus 18%.</p>
          <p>Now turning to expenses. Excluding specified items, gross margin increased 170 basis points to just under 70% at 69.9% compared to the third quarter of last year. This was due to favorable mix between the businesses within the pharmaceutical business, and manufacturing cost improvements, a reflection that our productivity initiatives are well on the way. And this despite lower margin growth at Mead Johnson. Full-year gross margins for 2008 should be up around 100 basis points.</p>
          <p>Excluding specified items, gross margins in the pharmaceutical business were at 71.9, up 230 basis points, and Mead Johnson was at 61.6%, down 170 basis points from last year primarily due to geographic mix, US versus the international business.</p>
          <p>Excluding specified items, marketing, selling, and administration increased 6%, with a 3% impact from foreign exchange. Advertising and promotion increased 7%. This includes a 2% FX impact. A&amp;P will likely be up in the lower double digits for the year. This reflects continued investment, as we mentioned in Q2, in our revenue growth drivers such as ABILIFY and ORENCIA.</p>
          <p>Excluding specified items, research and development expense increased 7% to $797 million, with a 1% impact from foreign exchange. R&amp;D spending for the year 2008 should be up in the mid single-digits, but please remember, this includes R&amp;D spend associated with the Kosan acquisition and licensing agreements with KAI and PDL.</p>
          <p>Our effective tax rate from continuing operations before minority interest and income taxes and excluding specified items was 25.3% in Q3. Our full-year guidance remains approximately 24% as the R&amp;D tax credit has been approved now and will be accounted for in our Q4 results.</p>
          <p>Given the volatility in the financial markets, I'd like to make a few comments about our financial strength. Our financial condition strongly improved in the quarter as our cash and cash equivalents increased to 7.2 billion as a result of strong operating cash flows as well as 4.1 billion in gross proceeds from the ConvaTec sale.</p>
          <p>A significant majority of this cash is invested in Treasury and Treasury-backed securities and this reflects a conservative investment policy that we initiated earlier this year. Also a reflection of our conservative approach, we refinanced 1.6 billion in debt earlier this year, and as such, have no significant maturities in terms of our debt profile until 2013. Our net debt in the quarter was reduced by 4.6 billion, and we are now in a net cash position of 1.2 billion. In summary, we are in excellent liquidity position.</p>
          <p>In addition to this, if Lilly closes the announced acquisition of ImClone, we will receive approximately 1 billion for our shares in this company. In addition, as you know, we also expect to receive proceeds from the proposed 10 to 20% IPO of Mead Johnson in 2009.</p>
          <p>While we recognize the need to maintain a strong balance sheet, we are also in a strong position to continue pursuing business development opportunities. One specified item to highlight, as noted in the release, we did take an impairment charge of $224 million related to auction-rate securities. The original carrying value of 811 million, as you know at the end of 2007, has now been reduced to $213 million.</p>
          <p>So just some general comments. Strong sales, strongly improved gross margins, and effective expense management has driven improvement in pre-tax and net margins. Our non-GAAP EPS from continuing operations grew 39% to $0.46, from $0.33 in Q3 of last year.</p>
          <p>Our GAAP EPS from continuing operations were $0.30 due to specified items. Our total specified items total $322 million for the quarter. Of this, 107 million is related to our productivity initiative, which we are well on our way to delivering, as Jim mentioned. The full reconciliation of GAAP to non-GAAP EPS, adjusted for ConvaTec, is posted on our website.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to guidance. We are revising our full-year 2008 GAAP and non-GAAP guidance. Our non-GAAP EPS guidance is now 1.65 to 1.70 with a bias towards the top end of the range based on the overall strength of the business. As Jim mentioned, we are also confirming our three-year minimum, 2008 to 2010, 15% EPS compound annual growth rate on a non-GAAP basis, and again this is without rebasing 2007 for ConvaTec.</p>
          <p>So in summary, our third quarter underlying operating performance was very strong. We saw double-digit sales and non-GAAP earnings growth, along with improved gross and pre-tax margins. The company has entered into a period where we expect continued growth, improved operating leverage, based on product mix and our productivity initiative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks, Jean-Marc and Jim, for the comments. Enola I think we are ready to go to questions. I would just remind everybody that in addition to Jim and Jean-Marc, both Lamberto and Elliott are here to take any questions you might have.</p>
          <p> Enola?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We'll take our first question from Tim Anderson with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. A couple questions. On the ImClone 11F8 product, what are the next steps to ascertain whether Bristol has rights to that? And regardless of who has rights, can you talk about the likelihood, or maybe lack thereof, that 11F8 would really make a dent in ERBITUX, given the long lead time that ERBITUX has and a lot more clinical data supporting it and that sort of thing?</p>
          <p>And then on SPRYCEL, can you update us on some of the timelines of important data flow, whether that's in CML, like the head-to-head studies versus GLEEVEC, or in solid tumors or in other areas that you're excited about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start by addressing the business side. John Lechleiter and I have already talked. There's a obvious disagreement as to the ownership rights of 11F8. By contract, that should go to arbitration if we're not able to settle that. He and I have agreed, if they're successful in closing, that'll be a topic we'll discuss as soon as the closing happens.</p>
          <p>On the clinical side, Elliott?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Tim. You asked about &#x2013; Well, let me take SPRYCEL first, and then we'll get back to ERBITUX.</p>
          <p>With regard to SPRYCEL clinical events, we did present at ASCO Phase II data on prostate cancer. We were particularly excited about that and we have initiated our Phase III program. This study is being initiated with a target filing in the 2012-2013 time period. We have at ASH two presentations that we are planning for. One is two-year data for the 100-milligram dose in chronic stage CML, and two-year data in advanced CML. We possibly will see first-line CML data from the cooperative study being coordinated by MD Anderson in ASH in 2009. We are progressing our first-line study in CML against GLEEVEC. That is going well, and we hope to see data in 2010.</p>
          <p>The prostate data will be available in the next six months and we'll make a decision with regard to Phase III in that regard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I may take the 11F8 question. This is Lamberto.  We are looking very carefully at how to develop 11F8. We have a team that is developing a plan and has been in discussion &#x2013; interaction with ImClone on that. There are opportunities to develop 11F8 and not necessary cannibalize totally ERBITUX with 11F8.</p>
          <p>Having said that, our focus, our key focus nowadays is on ERBITUX. We are very confident that ERBITUX has the potential to be delivered. The results of this quarter showed a slight decline, a very slight decline, slight versus last year. But we believe that in colorectal cancer, the KRAS confusion there is in the marketplace right now might well develop into an opportunity for this product. There is additional data that is becoming available and published in these very days. So we need to clarify the confusion that exists, especially in the community oncologist.</p>
          <p>We also believe that there are the &#x2013; there is additional &#x2013; there are additional important improvements of the label that might come if the FDA approves them, and I'm speaking about the additional indication in head and neck. And there is a large program, as you know, for starting and continuing to develop ERBITUX in other solid tumor indications. So our focus is on ERBITUX. We are confident that we will continue to develop and &#x2013; successfully this product, and at the same time, we are profiling 11FA in the most adequate way, and we will continue to discuss with ImClone, or at a later date with Lilly, on how to do it in the most effective way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tim. Can we go to the next question, Enola, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We'll go next to David Risinger with Merril Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much. I have a couple questions. First, following up to that response that you offered, could you please explain why you think community oncologists are confused? And is that to suggest that the sequential trends that we should expect in coming months for ERBITUX may be worse than expected, since I don't think that you were talking about them being confused previously?</p>
          <p>And second, in terms of the nutritional business, I was hoping that you could comment on the revenue growth and earnings growth outlook. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I cannot predict what exactly what is going to happen, but I believe that the recent publication on KRAS is going to be very useful to community oncologists and other decisionmakers in understanding the importance of KRAS. There is 60% of their patients that are wide-type KRAS, and those patients are going to benefit from the use of ERBITUX in colorectal cancer.</p>
          <p>So we -- obviously we &#x2013; there is a disalignment between the knowledge that is available and what we have in the label. So there is a little bit of disalignment between what we can say and promote, and what is known to a broader community. And this is where I believe we must work within the boundaries of the limitation of the label, but where some education will be possible also from other parties. And again, I am confident that this KRAS is an opportunity, and it's not an opportunity years from now. It is a short-term opportunity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, David, this is Elliott. There is a very significant and positive medical opportunity here. I think the commercial impact of the data does depend on the rate and the speed that the KRAS data is fully understood in the marketplace as well as adopted in terms of KRAS testing broadly, outside special centers and out into the community.</p>
          <p>This may happen relatively fast, because this is exciting, informative data that does identify responders, and about 60% have the KRAS characterization that suggests that these are the patients that will respond to ERBITUX. And since ERBITUX has only a mid-teen share in second-line colorectal cancer, and a 30 to 35% share at later lines of therapy, and a much smaller, maybe mid-digit level uptake in first line, we do expect, even though there might be a short term flattening of use in certain areas, even within label, there should be an increased interest in KRAS characterization and considering ERBITUX when other therapies are failing. So I see a big opportunity medically in the second-line therapy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a comment, on Mead Johnson, and just to remind you, Mead Johnson is a nutrition business. It has excellent brands, very strong market shares in very relevant markets. So it's a very defendable business proposition. So when it comes to the outlook, it's a positive one. Let me just answer in two ways.</p>
          <p>I think that if you look at our US business and if you look at our performance in Q3, you'll see a decline, and that's very much driven by one-off items between the quarter this year and quarter last year. So we would characterize the growth of our US business to be stable for the first nine months of the year, and it's an area of focus on how we can continue the strength of that business.</p>
          <p>Importantly, a big part &#x2013; a bigger part of our sales contribution comes from outside the United States, markets where we're number one, number two, in places like China, Thailand, Philippines, and Mexico, where we've demonstrated a very solid strong double-digit growth. So a good outlook for the overall baby food toddler business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David. Enola next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we'll go to Chris Schott of JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. Just two questions. First, can you update us on the belatacept filing? Have you completed the Phase IIIs at this point? If so, are you moving forward with filing? And just a reminder of when we could potentially see data on that?</p>
          <p>And then second, with regard to the sales of PLAVIX in Germany, what type of market share have you been seeing for the alternative salt form launched earlier this year, and do you have expectations for generic launches in other European markets in the near future? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me take the PLAVIX Germany question. Just as a reminder, there is &#x2013; there was an approval of a different salt or clopidogrel in Germany, and despite we strongly believe that we have a legal case demonstrating that their approval should not have happened at that moment, we are &#x2013; they are in the market, and we continue to fight our legal battle, and by "we" I mean Bristol-Myers Squibb and Sanofi-Aventis.</p>
          <p>We are also continuing to support PLAVIX and ISCOVER. ISCOVER is the brand that we use for clopidogrel &#x2013; we, Bristol-Myers Squibb, use for clopidogrel in Germany, and we are continuing to focus on the strength of our clinical data. And we consider this asset, an asset that needs to be supported and can be supported for more time.</p>
          <p>The generic -- two generic &#x2013; or I don't know if you call them generic. The two companies that are marketing a different salt or clopidogrel  in Germany has less than 20% market share, as far as I know, and as a reminder their label does not include all the indications that we have for clopidogrel basal state for ISCOVER in Germany.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Chris, with regard to belatacept, this is our agent directed at preventing a rejection of transplanted organs. It's operating on a similar mechanism to ORENCIA but has distinct characteristics for which we think are ideal for pursuing transplant. We're currently assessing data from our Phase III trials and we'll meet with the health authorities shortly to discuss our plans for a submission. Data will be presented on our two Phase III trials in May of '09 at the American Transplant Congress, and submission is targeted for the first half of 2009.</p>
          <p>I would like to remind everybody, we think this is an area of significant unmet medical need, although the calcineurin inhibitors had originally advanced the state of the art, there's still a concern about the effect of that class of immunosuppressants on renal function long term. We are doing two studies therefore. One study, in renal transplant population of broad criteria donors, in which the patients may be receiving their first or repeated transplant, and may be receiving either a liver -- living related donor or a deceased donor kidney.</p>
          <p>But the second study is in renal transplant patients of extended criteria donors, in which patients are receiving kidneys at higher risk for delayed or declining renal function. We're going head to head with the standard of care of cyclosporine, and the end-points are designed to assess efficacy through the end-points of death and graft loss, as well as acute rejection, and the goal is to demonstrate superior renal protection by measuring directly renal function. And again, that data will be presented in May of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris. Next question, Enola, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We'll go next to Roopesh Patel with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. My question is for Jim. I was wondering if you could please share with us your current thoughts on the business development and acquisition landscape, in light of the current equity and credit market environment. I'm curious about the type and volume of deals that are coming your way, and given these, I'm wondering if the company's focus may shift towards more-advanced stage opportunities rather than early-stage opportunities, and also, whether its appetite for near-term earnings dilution is present or not? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I guess the question is about the size and timing of our String of Pearls strategy.</p>
          <p>After being announced, we've made two acquisitions and two significant licensings -- licensing deals within the last year. As Jean-Marc pointed out, in &#x2013; we have a very a strong cash position which puts us in an excellent position to pursue this. Our preliminary studies show that these biotech companies have dropped by nearly 40% in terms of their market capitalization, and in a sense, it's a buyer's market.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, most of our competitors are also looking at some of these same companies. So I think the key will be that our very active and very skilled business development team link up those companies and our strategy, and based on our results the last 12 months, other than ImClone, I'm very confident that we can continue that strategy at a reasonable cost.</p>
          <p>I want to reemphasize, we're not going to do this at any price, and that there's a fiscal discipline in terms on return of investment as we evaluate each one of those. So we've spent significant time, have a long list of companies, compounds, technologies that we'd like to acquire over the next couple years, and I'm convinced we'll do it. Elliott, you want to add anything to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Jim, well actually, the strategic transaction team under Jeremy Levin is quite energized by the opportunities that are out there. We are applying very specific rigorous criteria to the science as well as to the financials. We do have a focus on late-stage pipeline opportunities, and accretive transactions where possible. So we have two goals to that team.</p>
          <p>As Jean-Marc has said many times, we look at the objective to raise the floor in '013 -- '012 and '013, as well as to increase the rebound of earnings that we expect from the pipeline delivery. So the team focuses on opportunities that will lead to Phase III assets in the '011-'012 time period, and where possible, we're looking at earnings contributions in those critical areas, and we're pursuing both types of transactions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Roopesh. Can we go to the next question, Enola, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We'll go to John Boris with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the questions. First question just has to do with your high-dose PLAVIX trial, the OASIS 7/CURRENT trial, for Elliott, just to get an update on &#x2013; I think you were &#x2013; you indicated on the last call that you were supplementing the trial with some additional patients. So just timing for when that might complete and when we might see results from that.</p>
          <p>For Jean-Marc, on cash flow, any thoughts on additional developments on improving working capital?</p>
          <p>And then, on ABILIFY. Exceptional growth in the quarter. Can you just help us understand the elements of that growth? Do you believe it's sustainable, Lamberto, and what percent of it might be coming from the resistant depression, versus bipolar and schizophrenia indication that you have in the label? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to start off on working capital, John, I think that this is something that we are looking at at a much closer than we did at the beginning of the year, and given the fact that we have certain individuals, including myself, who have not grown up in the pharmaceutical industry, as you look at working capital and cash flow, we see within the pharmaceutical industry a lot of upside, and I think there's now increased focus.</p>
          <p>If I just sort of, from a qualitative perspective, look at the three drivers behind working capital, inventory, receivables, and payables, I think that in the area of payables and receivables, there's a lot of scope for opportunities. Inventory as well, but I would rank them payables, receivables, as well as inventories.</p>
          <p>And again, without stating the obvious, given the high level of gross margins historically that pharmaceutical companies had, there's just been less focus on cash flow and specifically working capital. So you'll be hearing more from us about this topic in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me speak about our ABILIFY. As you can imagine, we are very pleased of our results with ABILIFY in both the US and EU. The growth of ABILIFY and strong performance in the US is driven by many things. I would say that obviously, the availability of strong clinical data across all indications that we have is very important. I think that the strong execution of sales force and all relating function is also very important. We have redeployed our sales force in preparation of the major depressive disorder launch, and by redeploying that sales force, which is a good sales force; we managed to increase our target by 15,000 people -- 15,000 doctors, including 8,000-plus primary care physicians who prescribe products of that type.</p>
          <p>And on top of that, we reached an agreement with our partner, Otsuka, to use some of their reps to reach an additional target of primary care physicians. So a good work on the sales force, and good work by our sales force.</p>
          <p>We have increased in the US our DTC efforts. We have just launched our first DTC campaign in major depressive disorder. You will see it on television in these very days, and we continue to invest behind the DTC of the bipolar disease indication.</p>
          <p>So there's a combination of things that make us believe that what is happening with ABILIFY in the US will continue to make us happy. So we have two-third of our sales growth coming now from bipolar and MDD, and therefore, it's not just the MDD, it's a broader growth of the product.</p>
          <p>In Europe, we have the bipolar indication. That is pretty new. They are very excited by it, and there again, we have growth of sales of 43% versus prior year in Europe, and we see &#x2013; markets research indicate that doctors increase their intention to prescribe and interest in and awareness of ABILIFY is growing throughout the European Union.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, this is Elliott. To address your question on the progress of the CURRENT trial. As you know, there's a great deal of medical interest and clinical practice suggesting that the earlier administration of anticoagulation may be beneficial and increasing the dose is suggested by some early Phase II trials. So the current trial is comparing the 300-milligram loading dose to the 600-milligram loading dose, and allowing for it to be administered earlier, as is done in clinical practice than on the table. And that trial is progressing. We have increased the enrollment to ensure some study power, and we expect to present the results by the end of the first quarter of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the specific indication that CURRENT addresses, we have seen stabilization of the number of stent procedures in the US. So after the decline of the previous year, now stent procedures have stabilized, even though our growth, the growth of PLAVIX, is coming mostly from the other indications, PAD and neuroscience indications, but we still have an important contribution from that post-stent indication.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the questions, John. Can we go to the next one Enola please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We'll go to Seamus Fernandez with Leerink Swann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. So just a couple of questions. Wanted to know if you can give us a little bit of an update on other tumor types with regard to KRAS, that you see this occurring most frequently in, and if there's any kind of histologic predictor related to that?</p>
          <p>And then separately, in your &#x2013; in late 2007 when you provided guidance, you did state that it assumed approval of prasugrel in mid-2008. How have those assumptions changed relative to the guidance, and if so how? If not, can you just give us your thoughts on the timing of approval and whether you would expect a panel to be convened to discuss the product? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Seamus, for your KRAS question, we have looked for markers specifically in lung cancer, and I think KRAS will have much less of an impact in lung cancer. There is a lot of experimentation and interest in the FISH analysis of EGFR. Our scientists have not only contributed to the early signs of KRAS, but have identified two additional markers, amphiregulin and epiregulin, that are ligands to the EGFR receptor, and their over-expression may indicate tumors that are under EGFR control and therefore, most amenable to blockade. This has piqued our interest in a variety of tumors. So I don't know that the same results &#x2013; I'm sure the same results, with regard to the frequency of KRAS, will vary from tumor type to tumor type.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. As far as PLAVIX and prasugrel are concerned, as you can imagine, we are following with interest all the news we read about prasugrel, and we are readjusting our forecasts depending on the interpretation of that news. What is very important, though, is that our focus is on PLAVIX. We have been ready for a launch of prasugrel for quite some time now. We have done all the things that needed to be done to be ready. We have a stronger hospital sales force. We've additional efforts even to make, or to remind prescribers, of the strong clinical data that we have for PLAVIX, and again, we are ready if they have a launch, but we are focusing mostly on PLAVIX itself. It's multiple indications, which, as you know, I remember, are well beyond the possible indications that they are going to have in their label.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And maybe just one point to emphasize is that given unknowns on prasugrel in the US, PLAVIX Europe, you should remember that when it comes to our 15% guidance from 2007 to 2010, we did not re-base 2007 for ConvaTec.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Seamus, thanks for the questions. Enola, I think we have time for two more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll go next to Steve Scala with Cowen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. First, for Dr. Sigal on apixaban, would you clarify the filing strategy for the US and the related timeframes, and is VTE likely to be the first filing, or will it be ACS?</p>
          <p>And secondly, does the change in the arrangement with Otsuka on ABILIFY marketing which was mentioned a couple minutes ago in any way change the timing of termination of the collaboration in November 2012 in the US and the end of 2014 in the EU? In other words, does it extend it? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with ABILIFY. ABILIFY is a very important product for us, and it's a very important product for Otsuka, and therefore we are working with them very intensively, and we meet them at different levels in the company. We discuss strategic things. We discuss operational things, and the agreement we reached about the US sales force is one of the operational things we have discussed with them successfully, and as I said, very pleased with the way we work with Otsuka and at all levels of the company, we have very fruitful interactions and discussions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, this is Elliott. The first filing in the US for apixaban is likely to be an atrial fibrillation, and ACS will be sometime perhaps after that. The result that we previously announced with regard to the Phase III result was in deep vein thrombosis, the post-surgical effort to prevent clot and implications from that. It had to do with the US regulatory strategy, not the ex-US regulatory strategy, and therefore, as we announced, we won't be filing next year for DBT prevention in the US, which we thought was a small part of the commercial opportunity, however was going to be our first filing, and the disappointment, therefore, is on the timing.</p>
          <p>We are investigating with our partner Pfizer on a strategy and surgical prevention of clot. However, the results of that study do not change our view of the performance of the drug or the safety of the drug, and the rest of the program is not impacted.</p>
          <p>I'll remind you that we have a comprehensive program and multiple indications being developed in apixaban for prevention and treatment of both arterial and venous thrombosis in acute and chronic settings. There are four Phase III programs in prevention of venous thromboembolism. Two for the prevention of stroke in patients with atrial fibrillation have started as well. The VTE prevention program not only includes surgical patients, but non-surgical patients as well.</p>
          <p>We have two important atrial fibrillation programs going. One uses warfarin as the direct comparator. The other uses aspirin in those patients who can't tolerate or are considered ineligible for warfarin. And our secondary prevention of ACS Phase II study results were reported recently. They have encouraged us to start our Phase III program in acute coronary syndrome in the first quarter of '09.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Steve, and Enola, I think we're ready for our last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our last question comes from Catherine Arnold with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot. I wanted to ask Jean-Marc about the nutritionals business in Asia specific, which is obviously a big chunk of the business. Could you clarify what percentage of that business is paid for by the government versus the consumer?</p>
          <p>And then I wanted to follow up with something, Elliott, you said on the last call, which is about ABILIFY and autism. You said at that time you were reviewing some Phase III studies on autism and you'd be making a filing decision on that. I wondered if you could give us an update, and also give us a little bit more information about what subpopulation within autism, to the extent to which this is used today and your thoughts on that business opportunity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Catherine, this is Lamberto. I will take the question on Mead Johnson international Asia. Most of what we sell in Asia is they buy individuals. There is not such a thing as a government contribution to the purchase of infant formula in Asia.</p>
          <p>As a reminder, we have two-third of our sales of Mead Johnson outside of the US. So it's very important &#x2013; a very important contribution of those sales to the overall business of Mead Johnson, and the results, as we are seeing in China, Philippines and some of the Asian countries, are very encouraging and make us believe that our strategy of processing in those countries with a wide range of premium products is the right strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Catherine, the medical need in autism is to help the children and their parents deal with the behavioral issues associated with that. Two Phase III studies have been designed with that in mind, and they are now completed. I'm encouraged by the data. This data will be presented at the American Academy of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry in late October, early November. And over the next several months, we plan to be submitting this with our partner Otsuka as an indication for ABILIFY.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Catherine, and thank you, everybody, for your questions and your time on the call.</p>
          <p>Let me just turn it over for some final thoughts to Jim Cornelius.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. I'll be very brief.</p>
          <p>A great quarter, the best since I've been here, and more importantly, our strong financial performance was led by double-digit sales growth. And as you heard during the Q&amp;A, our clinical science is moving steadily forward to a regular progression of the portfolio, and we're making progress in our String of Pearls strategy, which is our business development activities.</p>
          <p>We're also improving our margins as we continue executing on productivity initiatives. At the same time, for the long term, we're making the kind of investments we should. We're also targeting completion of our strategy to monetize our non-core assets, as I described earlier, and invest in the innovative medicines to help patients prevail against serious disease.</p>
          <p>Thanks very much for joining us this morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. Once again, that does conclude today's conference. We thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>