<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1448732" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-02-15</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7818</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Jean-Laurent Bonnaf&#xE9;</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Co-Chief Operating Officer">Philippe Bordenave</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Co-Chief Operating Officer">Fran&#xE7;ois Villeroy de Galhau</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Co-Chief Operating Officer">Georges Chodron de Courcel</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Thibault A. Nardin</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Autonomous Research LLP">Virginia Martin Heriz</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Kinner R. Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Patrick Leclerc</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Execution Noble Ltd.">Andrew T. Lim</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Neuez</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Bank Plc (Broker)">Robin F. Down</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Guillaume Tiberghien</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Jeremy C. Sigee</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="SG Securities (Paris) SAS">S&#xE9;bastien Lemaire</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Royal Bank of Canada Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Anke Reingen</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Natixis SA (Broker)">Alex Koagne</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Omar Fall</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the presentation of BNP Paribas Fourth Quarter Results 2011. Jean-Laurent Bonnaf&#xE9;, CEO of the group, will present the results along with COOs, Chief Operating Officers, Georges Chodron de Courcel, Philippe Bordenave and Fran&#xE7;ois Villeroy de Galhau.</p>
          <p>A Q&amp;A session we conclude the presentation. We'll start by questions in the room and then we will take questions from the conference call. Therefore, I'm asking you to turn off your phone because the presentation is webcasted live both on the Internet and over the phone. Thank you very much and I'm now leaving the floor to Jean-Laurent Bonnaf&#xE9;.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon. So I will start with an overview of the key figures for the &#x2013; our group in 2011. 2011 has been characterized by a tough market environment, the Euro sovereign crisis and tensions on liquidity. In this context, BNP Paribas has taken swift and decisive actions to adapt to this changing environment, already reaping additional benefits by year-end.</p>
          <p>If you look at numbers, we achieved revenues above &#x20AC;42 billion minus 3.4% compared to 2010. The net income is &#x20AC;6,050 million which is drop of 22.9% compared to 2010, and we posted a return on equity of 8.8% minus 3.5 point as compared to 2010.</p>
          <p>In terms of performance per share, the net book value per share improved to &#x20AC;58.2. That is 5% increase compared to 2010. Again, I would say a nice growth looking at the general circumstances of 2011. And the dividend payment should be &#x20AC;1.2 per share corresponding to a payout of 25%.</p>
          <p>We significantly strengthened our solvency, as shown by the 90 basis point increase of our common equity Tier 1 ratio to 10.1% in the Basel 2 universe, and this equates to 9.6% under Basel 2.5. Finally, we have taken actions to downsize the balance sheet, as you know, and as shown by the 12% reduction in our cash balance sheet, mostly achieved in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Now if we move to, let's say, what have been those three main issues in 2011. Well, first the exposure to the European sovereign debt. To that respect we provision our Greek debt exposure at the end to 75%, so this is in the last quarter intervention of &#x20AC;600 million on top of what we did before. And we significantly reduced our sovereign exposure all over the year by 28%.</p>
          <p>In terms of market conditions, tension in liquidity and refinancing, well, we've put an adaptation plan to reduce our net funding requirement in U.S. dollar, reducing it by 24%. And we've also increased our medium long-term funding program from &#x20AC;35 billion to &#x20AC;53 billion and extended the average maturity to close to six years. By year-end, our funding needs for customers activity were more than covered by stable funding resources. This is at the global level of the Group but also in the U.S. dollar universe.</p>
          <p>To increase the &#x2013; to address the increased solvency requirements by the EBA, we deployed a deleveraging plan aiming at achieving our 9% common equity Tier-1 ratio and to fully loaded Basel 3 by early 2013. In fact, by the end of 2011, we already reach the EBA target six months in advance.</p>
          <p>So this is the global overview of our Group for 2011. I do believe this is a satisfactory set of results. Philippe Bordenave will give you and will present you in a more detailed way both the liquidity, the financing and the results for last year, then Fran&#xE7;ois will present you all our businesses for the domestic market area. We'll be back again for International Retail Banking and Personal Finance. Georges will cover investment solution and CIB. Then again, Philippe will explain you how to reach and how to get that 10% fully budget loaded Basel 3 target by year end, and then I will conclude the presentation. So I'll be back in a minute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. If you remember our deleveraging plan and you remember that we had elaborated on 80% of the plan. And now we have well fully detailed all of the actions we want to take and you see that the complement is coming into the CIB field mostly, essentially indeed. And so, out of the total of 100 basis points, that is our target, 57, more than half is coming from CIB. And those 100 basis points are the equivalent of &#x20AC;79 billion risk-weighted assets to be taken off. We have achieved 32 basis points and &#x20AC;25 billion risk-weighted assets reduction in equivalent in one-half, meaning that we are in line, basically in line with the targets because at first, we were slightly below one-third in the first quarter so quarter of starting. And so we feel being quite in line with the target.</p>
          <p>On the liquidity side, the result is quite spectacular in terms of U.S. dollar. As you can see, we have reduced the assets denominated in U.S. dollar by $113 billion from $370 billion to $257 billion in six months. This of course occurring in the context where, I would say, short-term resources in dollars were dwindling very fast as well on the liability side.</p>
          <p>How did we achieve that? Basically, in two-half, the first half was the sharp decline of dollar funding needs of CIB minus $57 billion due to the adaptation plan. And so this &#x2013; the half was a reduction of the structural needs of the &#x2013; basically, so you can, you can look at those $57 billion as being broadly the same as the $53 billion of funding needs of our customer activity reduction that you see at the bottom of the column, $22 billion reduction in consumer loans and $31 billion reduction in trading assets. And so this is really structural below the black line in the middle.</p>
          <p>And the result was that BNP Paribas swung from a shortfall to $90 billion surplus of stable funding in dollars during this period. And the other half another $57 billion came from, a bit more easy, came from the $57 billion that used to be swapped into other currencies at the time where we had a lot of excess dollar deposits especially from money market funds, that we were largely swapping into other currencies and re-using in other currencies in the Treasury business. And of course the &#x2013; one of very obvious move started &#x2013; was to stop that kind of swaps &#x2013; destroying dollars and hence reducing the dollar assets by $57 billion.</p>
          <p>I would now stress that, well, despite the difficult context; we have also continued to implement ongoing actions such as the integration plan of BNP Paribas Fortis. We have already achieved &#x20AC;1.1 billion of synergies, which is very close from the target &#x2013; very close to the target set for the end of 2012 of &#x20AC;1.2 billion, and so we have increased this final target by &#x20AC;300 million to &#x20AC;1.5 billion and that's going to be the last chapter of the integration in 2012, and it's also going to be helped by a final &#x20AC;300 million of restructuring costs as well. So these results and this integration that was already successful confirm our ability and know-how in terms of integration.</p>
          <p>Moving to the accounts themselves now, first, you have seen that there is a lot of exceptional items. I'm not going to go through each of them because you had time to look at them. Just I would like to stress that if you make the total of the one-off revenues for the year, it's &#x20AC;35 million only, pluses and minuses are broadly offsetting each other, and the same for the operating expenses. The net is only plus &#x20AC;14 million. So, at the end, the big one-off that is really not offset by anything is the big provision for Greece that came into three &#x2013; in three parts as you remember for &#x20AC;3.2 billion cost of risk and an additional &#x20AC;200 million in the &#x2013; through the associate companies. Net &#x2013; well, precisely &#x2013; net of these one-off elements, the downward trend already seen in 2010 was concern in 2011 in terms of cost of risk. Cost of risk shows a &#x20AC;0.26 reduction net of &#x2013; ex-Greece. And the growth trend has been one of stabilization during the year within &#x2013; in the different quarters and more &#x2013; well, similar in most businesses, of course, excluding Greece. And so, at these levels, we can say that the cost of risk arrived at a level close to that of the average of the credit cycle that we have shown over the last 10 years or so, a little bit more than 50 basis points.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter with all that was marked by &#x2013; well, very challenging market conditions. Everybody knows that. And in spite of those difficult marking &#x2013; market conditions, revenues showed a good resilience and contracted only by 6% to &#x20AC;9.7 billion and costs were down by 3%. But again, the real hit was on the cost of risk which increased by 30% to &#x20AC;1.5 billion due to the additional Greek provisions bringing them to 75%. And so, with this provision, the fourth quarter closes with a net profit of &#x20AC;765 million, half of the level of the fourth quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>Looking now at the annual accounts, total revenues amounted to &#x20AC;42 billion, down only 3% on 2010 with cost being reduced by 1.5%. Again, the cost of risk suffered from the impairment on Greek debt and the net profit is down by 22% at &#x20AC;6 billion. But the resilient operating performance of our businesses in a very challenging environment in the second half enable us to achieve a return on equity of 8.8% and a return on tangible equity of 11.1%. That is close to the cost of capitalizing and I think this is indeed encouraging for the future.</p>
          <p>If we look at what went down in terms of revenues, to explain the minus 3% revenues, you see that revenues from retail banking were up, an increase of 1.5%, with all our retail businesses achieving a positive performance. Investment Solutions also showed higher revenues with &#x2013; which reached &#x20AC;6.3 billion, up 2.8% on 2010 despite an increasingly difficult market environment in the second half of the year. And indeed the decline is going from CIB, lower at &#x20AC;9.7 billion due to the impact of adverse market conditions in the second part of the year but also due to one-off losses incurred on the sale of sovereign debts and of &#x20AC;5 billion of credits in the framework of the deleveraging plan. So netting losses on the sale of sovereign debt, we have put that in gray. Euro revenues showed a decrease limited to 12.6%, decent performance for such a year I think.</p>
          <p>So, I hand over to Fran&#xE7;ois for more details about retail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. First, sorry for my voice. I got a bad cold in Paris, not in London. But I will try to comment on our core business which are our retail banking activities in the domestic markets which showed a very strong performance in 2011.</p>
          <p>Let me first comment on France with some snapshots in this slide. First, regarding our volumes in activities, we achieved a rather impressive growth of deposits of plus 8.4%, higher than the growth of our loans. If I look at our revenues, we had as an average plus 1.7% in 2011, a bit slowed down in the last quarters due to the evolution of our fees, negative evolution of financial fees due to the condition of the financial market and also bank card fees due to a new regulation issued by the antitrust authority. We kept meanwhile a strong discipline on our operating expenses. That was a one-off exceptional effect in the fourth quarter due to an exceptional profit sharing which represents as a whole 0.6%. If we take off this exceptional effect, we have a growth of operating expenses of 0.4% only for the whole year.</p>
          <p>At the end of the year, it means an increase of our pre-tax income of 12.5%. We have, as you can see on the right, exactly the same figure for the fourth quarter, so a very robust performance despite the adverse economic environment.</p>
          <p>If we now look at Italy, we had also a good growth of loans with a selected credit policy very risk-aware &#x2013; oriented on some sectors. We had a negative evolution of our deposits but consistent and a bit better as you can see as the evolution of the market. The performance we are quite satisfied with because there was &#x2013; there were some kind of deposits war in Italy. We didn't want to enter it like some competitors but we remained in line and a bit better than the market.</p>
          <p>The growth of our revenues regarding BNL was plus 2.6% which is a very good figure in the economic slowdown we had in Italy, balanced between margin of interest and fees. And the growth of the pre-tax income was much better with 16.2% due also to the strong performance you can see on the right regarding our cost/income ratio. You know probably this curve, year-after-year since we implemented the acquisition of BNL, we decreased strongly the cost/income ratio and in 2011 for the first year, the performance of BNL was better than the one of its peers in Italy. So, cost of risk was stable and it helped to deliver this positive performance in 2011.</p>
          <p>If I now come to BeLux, which is as you know, Belgium and Luxembourg in retail banking, here again we had a very good performance in deposits with an average growth of 7.5%, a growth of loans, which is lower, as an average 5.5%, and a growth of revenues, which is the strongest of our domestic markets with 4.9% driven mainly by the growth of the volume of deposits. So pre-tax income had a sharp increase of almost 19% due also to the diminution of our cost/income ratio, which is still a bit higher in Belgium than in other domestic markets, but we managed in 2011 to decrease it by 2 percentage points.</p>
          <p>We had also cost of risk contraction which contributed to deliver the strong income growth. You can see that the growth of the pre-tax income was especially strong in the fourth quarter, but the figure for the year is more representative.</p>
          <p>If I now turn to our action plan regarding 2011 (sic) [2012], I will not comment in detail through the slide, perhaps two snapshots. So first one is the adaptation of our savings product offers to be consistent with the expectation of our customers and with new regulation of Basel 3. This means among others more on-balance sheet offer with long-term savings and we were quite successful already in 2011.</p>
          <p>Second, in parallel with our commercial policy, we are very committed to improve our operating efficiency. We announced in 2011 plans for cost cutting for the three years to come, so till 2014 in Italy, Belgium and Luxembourg. For Belgium, they represent up to &#x20AC;200 million cost savings in the three years to come. So this is in a nutshell our view for domestic markets.</p>
          <p>I'll now give the floor again to Jean-Laurent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, so Europe-Mediterranean. This division showed quite a dynamic commercial activity in 2011 driven by volume growth. Deposits were particularly strong, growing by nearly 12% with a significant contribution from Turkey. Loan growth was also strong at 7% despite the continuing reduction in Ukraine, minus 20%.</p>
          <p>Focusing now on Turkey, our integration plan for TEB is proceeding ahead of schedule and the operational merger has been successfully completed as well as the streamlining of the network.</p>
          <p>Looking at the P&amp;L, revenues were slightly higher and they actually increased by 2% if we exclude Ukraine. And if we consider the sole Mediterranean area, then the increase was in excess of 10%. Operating costs were higher by 4.5% due to continuing commercial investments, and for example, we have opened 46 branches in the Mediterranean out of which 32 in Morocco. Thanks to the contraction in cost of risk, pre-tax income was sharply higher at &#x20AC;111 million. So in Europe-Med countries, we continue to pursue our selective development.</p>
          <p>Moving to the U.S., BancWest continued to show a dynamic business activity in a gradually improving economic environment. Deposits increased significantly plus 6.6% while loans were slightly lower resulting from lower mortgage loans but a rebound in corporate loans. We've continued to expand the customer relation organization with the launch of mobile banking services, for example, and the introduction of the Wealth Management structure.</p>
          <p>Revenues slightly increased on a like-for-like basis despite the negative effect of regulatory changes on commissions. Operating costs were affected again by new regulatory constraints. Thanks to the cost &#x2013; the strong decrease in this cost of risk, in the end pre-tax income was up by nearly 27% versus 2010 making a strong rebound in the contribution of BancWest to the group results.</p>
          <p>If we look now at 2012, for BancWest, we expect to benefit from an improving economic environment, we shall continue to invest in strengthening our Wealth Management offer and we aim to capitalize on business investments in the SME and corporate segments.</p>
          <p>For the Europe-Med area, we intend to continue to deploy the integrated model on a selected basis. We shall particularly focus on developing cross-business platforms such as the Multichannel and the Fixed Income platform, while at the same time we will keep operating expenses under control.</p>
          <p>Zooming on Turkey, we intend to consolidate our position in a very attractive market. This means, first of all, completing the implementation of the integration plan and also reap the full benefit of cross-selling with other group businesses and I'm thinking in particular of Wealth Management, Insurance with Investment Solutions and Trade Finance and Fixed Income with CIB. To sum it up, in 2012, we expect them to reap additional benefits from our selective business development approach.</p>
          <p>So for Personal Finance then; in 2011, Personal Finance started to adjust its business model to the new operating environment. In France, we've made a significant default within credit access to people on temporary contracts while at the same time providing preventive solutions to customers facing difficulties.</p>
          <p>And on top of that, Cetelem Bank has succeeded in gaining over 25,000 new clients leveraging on asset gathering and the sale of protection insurance. As I mentioned, we are adapting our mortgage businesses to the new regulation by integrating this type of activity with our domestic markets and discontinuing other activities with the exception of the partnership with Santander.</p>
          <p>In Russia, we have signed a major partnership with the country's leading bank, Sberbank, which we expect to become operational in the third quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>In terms of P&amp;L, this has translated in a moderate revenue growth which has been hampered by the impact of new regulations and thanks to contraction in cost of risk, pre-tax income has shown a significant improvement of 34% compared to the previous year. In a nutshell, in 2011, Personal Finance has proven to be a socially responsible player, while at the same time adapting its business model to the new regulation.</p>
          <p>Looking now at 2012, we shall continue to adapt the models into the new environment. In France, we shall continue to change and fine-tune the business model, while planning to expand the sale of savings and protection insurance products, continue to put in best action to facilitate credit access and to start implementing the business partnership with BPCE that is to say the operating platform that is producing and engineering the consumer loans.</p>
          <p>In Italy, we shall roll-out the Cetelem Bank model to Findomestic Banca. This will imply upgrading customer relationship management, marketing deposit accounts and developing the marketing of mortgages and current accounts within BNL and insurance products with Cardif.</p>
          <p>We shall also look at developing new sources of growth in particular Germany, Brazil, Central Europe, and Russia, as I said, with Sberbank. In Belgium, after the cross-sell with Fortis Bank, we are seeking new partnership with Banque de la Poste and we're looking to expand Personal Finance Inside to emerging markets.</p>
          <p>Now, over to Georges de Courcel, who will take you through the performance of Investment Solutions and CIB.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jean-Laurent. Good afternoon. I will make some comments about Investment Solutions and about CIB. First, concerning Investment Solutions, you can see that our assets under management had decreased of &#x20AC;60 billion. Why? First of all, we have bad performance effect due to the fact that stock markets fall during the second half of 2011, this is &#x2013; this mean minus &#x20AC;34 billion. And then, we have some &#x2013; let's say lot of outflows in Asset Management business. As you know, in Continental Europe there were a lot of asset outflows in Asset Management mainly in money market funds but also in equity funds. So this is for Asset Management, but for all the other businesses, Wealth Management, Personal Investors and Insurance, we enjoyed asset inflows. And I would like to make specific comments about Insurance.</p>
          <p>As you know, we have suffered a little on the fourth quarter in Life Insurance in France. We had some asset outflows. So, good news is now that for the &#x2013; as we are by now &#x2013; half of the first quarter of 2012 we are now &#x2013; we enjoy now positive inflows in life insurance in France, I think it was due to specific events in the eurozone for the first quarter. So I think it's a very good news for 2012. So globally we have mixed performances concerning asset inflows and asset outflows, but the market environment was not favorable at all.</p>
          <p>If we look at the figures of the net income and revenues, you can see that globally for Investment Solution the revenues were up of 3% roughly flat for Wealth and Asset Management growing in insurance and in security services. In Asset Management, we have decreased, unfortunately, the revenues decreased of about 10% compared to 2010 because of what I mentioned, asset outflows.</p>
          <p>We naturally work to deliver an adaptation plan reducing costs, I will come back just in a second. We intend to reduced cost of roughly 10% in Asset Management 2012 compared to 2011. And naturally, we continue to develop in emerging countries because the Asset Management is very good in emerging countries. In all the businesses, as I mentioned, the revenues are up. We naturally continue &#x2013; you know very well BNP Paribas, we continue to have always cost optimization. And so, our pre-tax income excluding Greece is minus 6% compared to 2010. So globally, we continue to show that our business in Investment Solution is resilient despite the very challenging environment for 2011.</p>
          <p>So our action plan is very simple, to continue to invest and to adapt in-source businesses. We think those businesses are very good plans in medium term. Even if we have to manage the cost in Asset Management, as I mentioned, we are going to reduce the cost in Asset Management of 10% but we continue to develop naturally in alternative investment and in energy market debts and equity as we develop Asset Management.</p>
          <p>We continue to develop by organic growth in securities services mainly in Asia. And naturally in Wealth Management, we continue to enjoy a very good cross-selling with our domestic markets, as Fran&#xE7;ois explained, but also in other parts of the world mainly Asia where we have very good developments. So globally, we adapt quickly but we continue to invest to develop in those very good businesses.</p>
          <p>So now, I come to CIB. As you can imagine, it is really a revolution into CIB business model all over the world for all the banks. And so, as Philippe mentioned, first of all, we have to deliver the adaptation plan we explained last November. So in U.S. dollar, we have reduced sharply our funding needs. Our objective was to &#x2013; our target was to reduce by $60 billion, end of 2012. We have achieved $57 billion, end of 2011, and so we have increased the target from $60 billion to $65 billion by the end of 2012. Naturally, we have also to reduce our risk-weighted assets.</p>
          <p>It is interesting to see that in Basel 2, end of 2012 &#x2013; end of 2010, we were at &#x20AC;187 billion in terms of risk-weighted asset. After Basel 2.5, we remained let's say at &#x20AC;197 billion due to, first of all, the increase of Basel 2.5, let's say only &#x20AC;37 billion, it's a huge amount but not so huge compared to some competitors. And our adaptation plan, &#x20AC;22 billion in capital market and in financial activities plus &#x20AC;5 billion in also adaptation measures. So globally, at the end, we have delivered a pre-tax income of &#x20AC;3.6 billion for the whole year. And for the first quarter, we were just at a breakeven which was not so bad compared to &#x2013; due to a very, very difficult environment. So globally, we have delivered what we have said and as always, at the level of BNP Paribas.</p>
          <p>Coming quickly to the global chart of our revenues, you can see that the second half of the year was very difficult mainly in fixed income due to the euro crisis. Naturally, you see that we are not at all at the same level that we were in 2010 due to those difficulties and on top of that due to the fact that we have sold some sovereign bonds, we have explained that in November. It was in October after that we have done roughly nothing and due to the loan sales because we have also explained that in our plan, we had to sell some loans.</p>
          <p>So globally, we see naturally the impact of the crisis and our adaptation plan. If we look at the beginning of the year, as of today, as there is a kind of "normalization" into euro market and due to the fact that we are very active also in our debt capital market activities. Let's say the beginning of the year it is not so bad in 2012. We will see after what will happen, difficult to have some anticipation. But let's say, we seem to be in a better trend mainly in financial activities.</p>
          <p>Expenses and cost income ratio. As you know, we continue to be one of the best in the world in term of cost income ratio, which stand at 6 &#x2013; which stood at 63%. If we exclude the losses related to the sale of the sovereign debt which is clearly one-off and the additional costs due to the adaptation plan, the cost income ratio stood at 56%. So hopefully you see that we continue to be around 60% as we have always expressed to the market.</p>
          <p>And global &#x2013; and on top of that, we have changed a little our organization, pointing a lot about regionalization because we think it's much better to be closer to the client region by region. So globally, we will continue to be at the best level in terms of efficiency not only for 2011 but naturally for 2012.</p>
          <p>I go quickly on capital markets for 2011. You can see that as I mentioned, fixed income had let's say a very difficult second half due to the crisis of eurozone. Excluding the impact of losses from sovereign bond sales, we are at minus 18.8%. Equity and Advisory, it was a good resilience because it was only minus 7% despite a difficult second half of the year. And naturally, we have managed operating expenses minus 12.5% if we exclude the bank's levies in loan and in France and the cost of the adaptation plan. So all in all, the pre-tax income of capital market activity stood at &#x20AC;1.2 billion. So globally, we can see that we continue to enjoy a very good client business. Despite the unfavorable markets, we are still in a reasonably good position.</p>
          <p>Just to comment about the Value at Risk, we continue to stay globally at low level &#x20AC;50 million, despite the fact of the parameters of the market are a little higher due to the volatility of the market and what is important is that we have no day of losses greater than Value at Risk in 2011. If you remember in 2008, we have very, very few days compared to a lot of competitors. So that shows you that our internal model seems to be very strong and the calculation of Value at Risk is strong at the level of BNP Paribas. I think it's important to mention that.</p>
          <p>Coming to financing business, let's say that we are to adapt quickly to the new environment. Clearly, we have reduced origination mainly for long-term loans denominated in U.S. dollar but globally, naturally we are much more selective because we have to adapt our business model. I will come back in a second.</p>
          <p>So, globally the revenues are down, minus 4.7%, if we exclude the impact of the losses from asset sales. And so operating expenses are minus 3.2%, if we exclude bank savings and cost of adaptation plan. So all-in-all, I think we posted a good performance with a pre-tax income of &#x20AC;2.3 billion for the whole year.</p>
          <p>So, I will mention quickly what are our targets for 2012 and clearly our target is to be on top in the new business environment beginning of 2013. As you have seen, we have expressed that the global level of the groups that we want it to be at 9% in term of Tier 1 ratio fully-loaded Basel 3. So naturally, it implies that CIB has to make a big move.</p>
          <p>So globally, first of all, we have to adapt our business. As we will see more of this intermediation in the market, we have to make a lot of synergies between fixed income, which are the strong platform at the level of BNP Paribas and financing business, what we call, originate and distribute. So distribute through our fixed income platform, thanks to our institutional clients. So clearly we are in this process.</p>
          <p>And in equity and advisory, naturally, we have to continue to strengthen our franchise, working closely between primary equity market distribution and much more simple, let's say, on liquid products. So globally, we want to be on track end of 2012 to be more efficient in the new environment, which ask less liquidity consumption and not too much capital use.</p>
          <p>So globally, naturally, it will have some cost, first of all non-recurring costs. We will continue to have restructuring cost &#x20AC;200 million in 2012, but we will generate in full year basis &#x20AC;450 million of synergies of reduction of cost. And naturally, we will continue to sell some loans. We expect probably minus &#x20AC;650 million due to disposals.</p>
          <p>Naturally, as we are reducing the portfolio, we have mentioned that we will lose some recurring revenues because we will have less, let's say, not so such a big portfolio. As we have mentioned in November, we expect a loss of minus &#x20AC;1.4 billion before the positive impact of re-pricing. Let's say that in 2012, the positive impact of re-pricing will be low. Probably, we will enjoy that mainly in 2013. And naturally, we have to manage the regulation. So all-in-all, after having doing so, we think we are in a very good position to see &#x2013; to manage a new environment with a very good client franchise.</p>
          <p>And with, let's say, a good at the end, compared to a lot of competitors. So good return on equity, because we think that some competitors will have some difficulties to manage not only Basel 2.5, but also Basel 3. So globally, we have adapted CIB very quickly and we will be on track in the beginning of 2013.</p>
          <p>Now I leave the floor to Philippe, for some global figures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>So you know this slide, indeed, it's very similar to the one I have shown at the beginning of the presentation. But the difference is that at the beginning of the presentation, it was about the dollar only, and here it's about the whole of the balance sheet, all the currencies included. This is a comparison between the end of 2010 and the end of 2011 in the dollar slide, it was since June, the comparison is since June.</p>
          <p>Just here, what is to be noted is that, at the level of the whole of the group, the surplus, if you remember. The surplus here &#x2013; doesn't work, okay &#x2013; is &#x20AC;31 billion instead of $19 billion. We have of course a much bigger surplus of stable funding of the funding needs of the customer activity. Then the evolution of the year is somewhat similar, so we decreased, and starting from the bottom, you see that we decreased the customer loans by &#x20AC;10 billion. You may remember that in dollars, it was $22 billion. So it means that indeed, the dollar &#x2013; the whole of the decrease comes from the dollar and the rest kept going up slightly, especially in the domestic market as you have seen.</p>
          <p>While in the trading assets, the decrease was really overall because you see the decrease was by &#x20AC;61 billion and the dollar part was $30 billion. So we, the traders, really made a lot of efforts in order to address and reduce &#x2013; compress their inventory in order to adapt to the new liquidity constraints and to adapt to the new regulations.</p>
          <p>Then, the fixed income securities have also been reduced by a big figure, &#x20AC;70 billion. In that figure of course you have around &#x20AC;30 billion sale of sovereign debt and this is in that chapter.</p>
          <p>Then Interbank assets were reduced by &#x20AC;11 billion as well and the only category that is increasing in &#x2013; the one at the top is the deposits with central banks moving up from &#x20AC;31 billion to &#x20AC;55 billion as we saw that it was necessary to while have increased deposits at central banks in order to be &#x2013; because this at the end of the day is the real &#x2013; the most liquid assets possible.</p>
          <p>And so, we have of course at the ECB, but also at the Fed in that figure, you have $38 billion at the Fed, so very big. We increased even under the amount of dollar deposited at the Fed overnight, and you have also the Bank of Japan and other central banks. So everywhere, we have kind of the first of a very, very liquid asset in order to be ready to whatever may happen.</p>
          <p>And then overall, it was a reduction to the tune of &#x20AC;130 billion, minus 12%, showing a very rapid adjustment to the new regulatory end market environment. Now, if you add the &#x20AC;55 billion deposit with central banks in yellow with unencumbered assets eligible to central bank, that can be brought to central bank windows in order to get additional liquidity, it brings you to &#x20AC;160 billion of liquid assets reserves immediately available. And given the de-leverage, we have done during the year, at the end of the year, it accounts for 85% of the short-term wholesale funding. So really it's huge, and we can face any further shrinking of the wholesale funding. By the way, we faced a significant one already, so we are ready to see even more without any trouble.</p>
          <p>Now, about the medium and long-term funding especially; in 2011, we all alone kept a continued access to medium and long-term diversified funding despite the crisis. You remember that we even increased the program from &#x20AC;35 billion to &#x20AC;43 billion of which we issued &#x20AC;8 billion in &#x2013; after July &#x2013; during &#x2013; precisely during the crisis.</p>
          <p>For 2012, the program is &#x20AC;20 billion. It's significantly reduced due to the adaptation plan because that will need our reducing as well, and we have already completed &#x20AC;5 billion of new issues. As of the end of January in two months because we are taking into account what we did in December as well because we closed the program last year at the end of November. So we keep issuing roughly &#x20AC;2 billion to &#x20AC;3 billion per month.</p>
          <p>On a pure private placement basis &#x2013; mostly private placement, retail by our own &#x2013; the placement in our own retail networks as well and a few other ways with a private nature I would say like long-term repos, placement through the CRH.</p>
          <p>The average maturity is satisfactory, 6.7 years. So, we don't have any problems with maturity. The cost is increasing 122 basis points, and this is clearly an issue for us. But, well, it would be even more costly in the public market, so we are, I would say, the program was, I would say, it suits &#x2013; it's meant to be achievable without the need to resort to public issues in case the public markets will remain too expensive throughout the year.</p>
          <p>Switching to solvency, as we have already mentioned, we further improved our common equity Tier 1 ratio and exceeded EBA targets six months in advance and we are at 9.6%. But that &#x2013; what is important to see on if you take one step back and you look at the chart on the right, you see that our capital base was doubled, roughly doubled in three years with the ratio moving up from 5.4% to 9.6%. But indeed in Basel 2, it's 10.1% and 9.6% is under the Basel 2.5 also. Apple-for-apple, it's 10.1%, so almost double. And the equity itself &#x2013; the common equity itself went up from 29 to 58 and so we doubled the equity while the risk-weighted assets were moving much, much less basically more stabilized.</p>
          <p>And again, the switchover to Basel 2.5 generated an inflation of &#x20AC;32 billion. You remember we had said that it would be in the region of &#x20AC;40 billion, so at the end it's 40 &#x2013; &#x20AC;32 billion essentially in Capital Markets because, well &#x2013; and at the same time, the de-leveraging plan and the adaptation plan has generated a reduction of &#x20AC;25 billion in terms of risk-weighted assets of which precisely &#x20AC;8 billion related to the lower inflation resulting from the application of the Basel 2.5 rules. So we have almost &#x2013; well, plus &#x20AC;32 billion, minus &#x20AC;25 billion, if you want we have almost, I would say, balanced one with the other.</p>
          <p>Now, from here, we have to be at 9% at the end of the year or at the very beginning of next year under Basel 3 fully-loaded. So, how are we going to do that? So, we start from 9.6% and first, we deduct the 40 basis points conventional deduction corresponding to the buffer set by the EBA for the mark-to-market of sovereign debt. We keep that assumption at this stage. Then, the bill of switch to Basel 3 is currently being evaluated at 180 basis points, so it's a little bit more than what we had said in the past. This is &#x2013; the question is it's a moving target and the tax is still debated. We have new &#x2013; either new proposals from the parliaments on new compromised tax brought down by the presidency &#x2013; the Danish presidency. So currently, our best estimate is 180.</p>
          <p>We have the adaptation plan that is bringing back 68 basis points, 100 minus the 32 we have already achieved. And then, we have the assumption of a strip dividend for both years that is adding 20 basis points and the organic generation for &#x2013; during 2012, we have taken as &#x2013; we have taken the consensus &#x2013; the Bloomberg consensus as usual in that kind of situation with the assumption of a payout ratio of 25% again in 2012. And this gives 72 basis points. Total, 9%. So, it's an ambitious target, but it's a target that is achievable.</p>
          <p>And I'll leave the floor to Chodron for the conclusion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again, our group has a very well-balanced business mix with half Retail, one-third CIB, one-sixth Investment Solutions. We believe that this business mix has represented a key element of funding resilience with no euro flows throughout the crisis.</p>
          <p>As illustrated by the pie chart on the right hand side of the slide, even after the switch to Basel 3 to Basel 2.5 leading to higher capital markets risk-weighted assets, the group business mix is not altered and we continue to represent a crucial factor of stability and resilience going forward. So, maybe it's not so scientific as an approach, but in the end for a bank it might be, for the long run, quite efficient to stay and to keep such a well-balanced portfolio of activities.</p>
          <p>Again, if we look at the net book value per share and this is another way to say more or less the &#x2013; just the same. This business model, I just mentioned, has allowed us to increase year-after-year the book value per share, we reached now &#x20AC;58.2. Over the cycle, in five years, the average yearly growth is 6.3% and last year even in a very challenging environment, we get an increase of 5% from &#x20AC;55.5 to &#x20AC;58.2. So again, a very robust model that can be seen either in terms of profit or in terms of ability to increase the net value per share.</p>
          <p>Now, looking at the dividend, we've proposed to the Board that we'll propose to the General Assembly a dividend payment of &#x20AC;1.20 per share corresponding to a 25% payout ratio. In addition, we are giving a strip dividend option to our shareholders. BNP Paribas earnings generation capacity enabled us to pay dividend year-after-year throughout the crisis and this year in particular, BNP Paribas stands as one of the few banks confirming the payment of a significant dividend. So, this also means that at least three quarters of the earnings will be reinvested in the company to bolster our capacity to finance clients and strengthen solvency.</p>
          <p>For 2012, few are messages, few key messages. First, we aim to strengthen financial solidity as we aim to complete our de-leveraging plan, consolidate again our liquidity position and arrive at the beginning of 2013, end of the year, in fact, with a very strong solvency position compared to the competition. Second, we intend to further pursue commercial development, expanding cross-selling and innovation in our domestic markets, bolstering our business in fast-growing areas such as Asia Pacific and generally capitalizing on our global organization, our leading market position and a strong customer relations.</p>
          <p>Last but not least, we shall continue to focus on improving on operating efficiency by promoting synergies, opportunities, continuing to invest on a very selective basis and streamlining platforms. Hence, 2012 will be a year fully dedicated to laying the foundations to be well-positioned in approaching 2013.</p>
          <p>And to conclude this presentation, three messages. In 2011, we've achieved good operating performances especially in the retail bank, in retail banking but not only in the retail banking; second, we have swiftly adapted to the new regulating environment; and third, BNP Paribas remains a solid bank which is well positioned to service and finance its clients going forward. So thank you very much for your attention and now, we will take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Thibault Nardin from Morgan Stanley. I've got a few questions. The first one is on European market. We have seen some of the European market coming back to some European banks, and I would like to know if BNP Paribas has actually reissued some commercial paper with these funds? And, what will be obviously the long-term ambition of BNP on these kind of funding sources? If it could basically re-engineer some kind of activity there?</p>
          <p>Second question will be on Italy. We have seen again loans growing, deposits falling. It's quite clear that you don't want to participate to conventional deposits, but the funding gap is starting to get quite big so I would like also an update on that front?</p>
          <p>And, finally, as well just a quick one in terms of funding spread for duration on the funding market? And also if we could add a bit more visibility on the nature of these private placements? Are they asset-backed, are they purely unsecured? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Philippe will take the point for anything related to liquidity. For Italy, you will see that the intergroup funding from BNP Paribas to BNL end of the year has decreased. So we're looking at a better balance. And even if we do not like to pay too high prices for deposits, in the end you have to come to the conclusion that you cannot lose too many market shares; so we need to be balanced in this approach. And in terms of lending, well, in the end we are originating loans in a very selective way in Italy. And even in a challenging environment in Italy, the BNL model is efficient, you can see it on the cost income. And even if we stay with quite such a high cost of risk compared to France or BeLux that are absolutely excellent, well, the generating machine from BNL is absorbing the cost of risk. So, in the end, you get a net profit. So this is the way we are looking at Italy. And now, Philippe, for the funding point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About &#x2013; yeah, about the commercial paper market in the U.S., we have &#x2013; yes, we have seen volumes growing back again a little bit since the beginning of the year. Well, our doors are open, we are posting prices and if they come, they come, if they don't come, they don't come. I think they have &#x2013; well, the money markets have also suffered some reduction in their own volumes because their returns are now extremely low and some times even slightly negative after management fees. And so they're &#x2013; in a world that is characterized with a kind of re-intermediation of banks, the full amount they have to manage probably is not going to be what it used to be as well. So it's &#x2013; well, we are taking some more if they come and we are using it and we are using it with short term assets as well in front of that. So we can't &#x2013; we are flexible that respect.</p>
          <p>For the private placement, no, you know, the bulk of what we sell in the private placements is structured issues because in the &#x2013; our derivatives business, be it equity derivatives or fixed derivatives, certain of our clients, they need support of investment. They can't deal &#x2013; either they don't want to or they can't because of their own bylaws, deal in derivatives, in pure derivatives. So they want support, investment support; and so we are providing the issuer, if you want, that is &#x2013; so it's a kind of synergy between the market teams &#x2013; the structural derivatives teams and the treasury, or the asset liability management. And so it's &#x2013; the bulk of it is not collateralized at all, and seasonal, not at all, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, gentlemen. Virginia from Autonomous. So my first question would be related to the LTRO of February. So, basically if you could explain us how &#x2013; give us some guidance on whether you have created any new collateral, or whether you're expect any new collateral under the new rules?</p>
          <p>And now my second question would be about the split of Fortis synergies. You're saying its &#x20AC;200 million. So how much of that do you expect from revenues and how much you would expect from costs?</p>
          <p>And another question also related to the 100 basis &#x2013; to 180 basis points impact from Basel 3. You said that it's going to be more than what you expected initially. So if you could give some color on where the impact would come from and what are your new assumptions? Because I remember when you used to give guidance on Basel 3, you used to say it was between &#x20AC;5 billion and &#x20AC;7 billion impact in terms of capital and then about &#x20AC;70 billion &#x2013; sorry, it would be &#x20AC;70 billion in terms of risk-weighted assets. So, if you could explain whether that still holds or something has changed? And also, if you are also accounting for the conglomerates directive or not in those 180 basis points?</p>
          <p>And, finally also, if you have any kind of target for revenues in the <mark type="ph" /> Febe (66:54) business for this year? Thank you. That was long.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're going to the last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will take the Fortis point and then Philippe anything related to the ratios and the LTRO and Georges about <mark type="ph" /> Febe (67:16).</p>
          <p>So for the Fortis, roughly we can say one-third revenues, two-thirds cost. You have more or less the detail. Part of it is coming from the end of the Turkish plan that has been delayed by 18 months. So these results are coming after 2012. But on top of it even if we did a lot with the first industrial plan within Fortis, we have uncovered additional situation in which Fortis and BNP Paribas can either cross-sell or share common platforms. So this is basically the explanation. About LTRO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the LTRO of February is concerned, we are still studying the collateral rules in details because one of the characteristic of what is on the table, it seems, is that the collateral is enlarged. But the new categories of collateral are assorted with big haircuts, very big haircuts, so that maybe they can be used better in covered bonds, in market covered bonds. So we have to make a very fine-tuned assessment of the optimization of all this. And so this is what we can say about the LTRO of February.</p>
          <p>And, as for Basel 3, yes, we have said the text has changed as well, a certain number of clarifications have been given. And, then the CIB 4 project was somewhat different and is somewhat different from the Basel text. What we are &#x2013; of course we are basing our calculation on the CIB 4 project because this is what we are going to have to comply with. And, just to give one example, and we'll &#x2013; I think we'll have &#x2013; we'll be able to detail more when we have the final text. But, just to give one example of a big change, it's about the insurance. When we had said &#x20AC;5 to &#x20AC;7 billion capital deductions, we were planning some kind of additional deduction for the insurance holding business. And, today, with the last compromised proposal of the Danish presidency, nothing is deducted from the numerator, but the full investment would be weighted at the denominator. So it's a complete change. And so we &#x2013; for the same topic. So I think it's better not to give more &#x2013; too much detail and &#x2013; because it could be changed every day or every week. But &#x2013; well, we are giving you kind of envelope that seems to us as relevant at this stage I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" /> (70:27)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If we come back to slide 28, perhaps I can make some comments. First of all, we have no official target for 2012 because it's so difficult to have target. If we had targets for 2011 probably we would have been wrong. So perhaps I can give you some personal feelings of an old man having seen a lot of crises like this in CIB.</p>
          <p>First of all, bad news, the bad news are the fact that in financial business, probably we will not continue to deliver &#x20AC;1 billion of revenues each quarter. Why? Because as I mentioned during my presentation, as we will reduce the portfolio, the level of revenues will be lower. But then, the question concerning financing business is when the re-pricing will occur and in what magnitude, which is not so easy. We see some re-pricing in some type of business, in some others not. What we'll see is some competitors of medium size are no more there. So, let's say, it will be difficult to anticipate exactly the magnitude and the timing, but probably not &#x20AC;1 billion a quarter.</p>
          <p>Then concerning the capital market activity, clearly we think and I think that the trend of the second half is not at all the trend for the CIB of BNP Paribas because we had to suffer a very strong euro crisis, as you know. And probably the Euro will not collapse, because when I have heard, let's say, competitors, U.S. competitors, some of them thought that the Euro will collapse; it is not my feeling. And so we see that, we see clients coming back to BNP Paribas, as you mentioned money markets form the other clients. So globally, my feeling is the trend will be much better in 2012. In what magnitude it's very difficult to express, but. So all in all my feeling is that we will not come back to 2010, but probably we will deliver much better situation than the second half of 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" /> (73:08)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think with the underlying revenue <mark type="ph" /> is not on nails one loss (73:17) of the specific losses. But as we are very cautious, first of all, we reduce cost, which is ever better whatever could happen, so this &#x2013; so we have management of BNP Paribas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. And could I ask a follow-up question with respect to the LTRO? It's just a quick one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So going &#x2013; because I noticed that the collateral &#x2013; the available central bank collateral went from &#x20AC;170 billion to &#x20AC;150 billion. So should I construe that as &#x2013; the difference would account for your participation in the first LTRO or not necessarily? So if you could explain that difference please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we participate within the first LTRO indeed. I don't know exactly the same figure but it plays a role certainly in that &#x2013; so we &#x2013; through the LTRO, if you want we have some kind of change composition of the buffer with less government bonds and more deposits at the central bank. And as I said, we felt that appropriate. And yes, there is some kind of relation between the two figures, certainly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Thank you. I have just two questions. The first one is related again to the LTRO. Would you envisage using it based on your activity in Italy? I mean &#x2013; or would you use it from headquarters? This is of course to fulfill the funding gap.</p>
          <p>The second question is related to your ROE. Currently the market expectation pushes you, based on consensus, to about 9.5%. How fast would you expect this to grow and what would be the main driver to get to an improvement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the first question is easy to answer. We participated with all the three main banks of the Group in the LTRO: in Italy, in Belgium and in France.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the return on equity, well, obviously in 2012 we will not have the one-off of 2011, especially on the sovereign debt, so this is one point that is positive. The underlying economy in Europe is going to be slow. The economy is slowing down, this is not the recession but the economy is slowing down. This is the second point. But on the &#x2013; other than within CIB, the start of the year is okay. So &#x2013; well, the target you gave to us is something new, it's not the target from BNP Paribas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Kinner from Citi. First question just on slide 27, just wanted to better understand the de-leveraging. So we have the &#x20AC;12 billion benefit on financing on the mitigation and we have 5 billion of loan sales. So just wanted to make sure I understand that the difference related to loan roll-off? And if that is the case, what kind of loan roll-off we would expect per quarter, on average, let's say in 2012? So I'm trying to get a better understanding of the mix between how much you need to sell and how much is natural attrition in terms of the de-leveraging.</p>
          <p>Second question is, historically you've provided some guidance at least in terms of top line outlook for the domestic retail network, France in particular. If you can provide any color on that?</p>
          <p>And the third question, maybe what your views are on the political landscape and what it means for the French bank as we stand today and what your read of the situation is today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One element of answer on your first question is the cost, indeed, we have no pre-set answer because we don't want to be a prisoner of a pre-set scheme, because we don't want to sell our asset at bargain prices. So we have limits to the prices we are ready to accept. You have seen that in the first &#x2013; the second half in practice, or in the fourth quarter of 2011, we have sold 5 billion around at &#x2013; for a cost of &#x20AC;150 million, so 3 basis points and &#x2013; 3%, sorry, 3% discount. That is something we had told you that probably it would be between 3% and 5%, so we try and limit that cost of selling our assets. And we'll keep doing that. So depending on the demand, so we may sell more or less and hence we may slow down the new production of loans, more or less. And so this is something that has to be managed on a week-by-week basis almost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So for certain buyers that means that are never firesale at the level of BNP Paribas.</p>
          <p>About the, I will say the landscape in France, in all dimensions related to the banking industry, there is nothing specific about France. I mean, you have the Volcker rule, you have the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (79:38) rule, you have the Darnier workshop, so there is nothing specific about France. But there is an election, this is the presidential election, this is the main election in France, so as usual, this kind of subject is given a lot of attention, but there is nothing specific about France. So this is the way we are looking at the situation. It's obvious that to finance the economy especially under the Basel 3 rules, you need to have strong banks in terms of solvency. You need to have strong banks that can bring customer to the capital market all over the place. So it's obvious that all these businesses are mainly the businesses we're developing our commercial businesses. So we are not &#x2013; we do not feel at risk in that respect, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just on the revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ah yes, what the top line in retail, right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding your question. We never give outlooks for the year to come including in our domestic market, only some personal and qualitative views. Obviously there is a slowdown in our main markets, so this will a bit &#x2013; break our revenues. But if you look on the opposite side, we have strong repricing actions especially our loans which will help us. We are still committed to improve our cost income ratio on our most important market. And regarding the risk, it's always difficult to have a forecast on risk, but we had a level of risk especially low in France and Belgium in 2011. What we would expect for 2012 would be a stabilization or a slight increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. So, usually you give a guidance in term of growth effect between the revenue growth and the cost growth. Can you give us a bit more on that side please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We believe that in 2012 we'll be in between the regular one point and half a point in liaison with the situation in Italy because we're running Italy looking at the risk side and not at the top line side. What is the key driver in Italy is the cost of risk. So looking at that, we should get next year in between half and the full point. So this is the situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look more specifically to France, we could be helped by problem we had at the end of 2011 which is one-off effect of the so-called Sarkozy premium profit sharing agreement which is really one-off and which where we probably &#x2013; we won't have to pay next year, this year. So it will help the growth effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Patrick Leclerc, Merrill Lynch. One first, quick question on your total assets, so which reduced by 5% in the last quarter and the big part of the reduction coming from the fixed income securities &#x20AC;45 billion, part of it is, well, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (83:13) and what is the other part of it please? And second question regarding your payout policy, so you basically have reduced from about 30% to 25%. Is it a new normal within Basel 3 and the world profitability context we are in? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To answer the second point and then Philippe will answer the first point. The payout level is in line with, I would say, the global situation of the bank and the need to increase solvency capital. And this is a way to be ready, let's say, at once. So there is nothing that is said about the future, this is just the fact that with this level of profit, the clever move is to try to increase equity. It's the far &#x2013; by far the best way to run the company and this has nothing to do with any political circumstances. But on top of it, increasing solvency just to finance customers, so this might be linked to the fact that banks have to delivered what is awaited from them by, I would say, the public opinion that is financing the economy. But the decision on the payout is purely the fact that we managed the bank to be ready as soon as possible that is to say by year end. And for the deleveraging?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We sold &#x2013; beyond the government bonds, we sold some more fixed income securities from the banking book. And also, while part of the in portfolio, for example, or some kind of part of the portfolios that had been reclassified as well from the fixed income in 2008 sort of few things like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Andrew Lim at Espirito Santo. I just wanted to get more clarity of the impact of deleveraging on the revenues and profitability of the CIB business. You already delevered about half of the risk-weighted assets target in CIB, 22 out of the 45. But if anything, actually, the revenues in advisory and capital markets and financing performed quite well in the quarter. So I was just wondering, out of the &#x20AC;500 million impact on gross operating income from your associated RWA mitigation for CIB, how much can we expect of that to be included already in the fourth quarter or is there some sort of a delay maybe into the first quarter of this year? That's my first question.</p>
          <p>Secondly, on the Basel 3 impact of 180 bps, could you disaggregate that from between the impact of capital deductions and RWA inflation?</p>
          <p>And then thirdly, your CIB trading VaR actually went up in the fourth quarter which was a surprise to me. Is that a function of the market conditions or is that a function of the capital allocated to the division? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Concerning your last question is a function of the market conditions, of the volatility, of the parameters not at all of the capital allocation, not at all no, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (87:15).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That the value at risk is calculated based on the actual parameters of the last three months, especially the last three months of the recent period. And hence, as there was a big crisis since August, I mean, parameters wasn't quite a lot, so even if you keep the same position, the same level of risk, it translate into higher value at risk so this is very, very simple.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps, I can comment a little concerning the revenue generated by capital market activities. It's very difficult to see what is recurring &#x2013; it was financing or capital market financing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question. Okay. So, I observed in the slide. Globally, we think that compared to the beginning of the recurring activities of 2011, we will lose &#x20AC;1.5 billion in global year due to the reduction of our portfolio. But on the opposite, we see the beginning of the re-pricing. The difficulty is to know exactly at what type of level, at what speed we will see exactly this re-pricing. We don't anticipate a lot for 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you saying that the &#x20AC;1.5 billion impact has yet to be incurred &#x2013; none of that would actually occurred yet in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Negligible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Negligible because we sold toward the end of the year...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...and hence, the carrying gain &#x2013; the loss of the carrying gain is relatively small in 2011 &#x2013; was small and it's going to be more important in the year to come. So then, it depends on the specific characteristics of the loans we have sold but maybe &#x2013; I know but maybe as you said we have sold half of what was expected to be or we have reduced half of what was expected to be reduced. And hence, maybe the impact in 2012 will be close to half of the total impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. This is Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Neuez from Goldman Sachs. Just had a few quick questions please. And the first one is, since the beginning of the year, we've seen decent tightening of spreads in the sovereign markets, in particular in the Italian bond. I just wanted to know if you plan to resume your disposal process?</p>
          <p>The second thing is on the CIB revenues ,and without having to have an outlook or guidance in a sense, I just wanted to know whether similar conditions to the beginning of 2009 were reoccurring again in the beginning of this year that could provide maybe one-off tailwinds? At least &#x2013; every little helps, as they say, here.</p>
          <p>And my next question is, I saw this morning a headline that Klepierre was not for sale. I suppose you wouldn't say if it was for sale, as you normally do. Nonetheless, do you have vocation to control a company, which has now taken &#x2013; obviously you've started it yourself. Now, it's a fairly big company. And I just wanted if &#x2013; I just wanted to know if longer-term in your stable business mix, as you always show it, the importance of that has grown at some point need to reconsider?</p>
          <p>And lastly, have you got a guidance on the tax rate of 2012 please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About Klepierre, we have no vocation, we are just a commercial bank. There is no &#x2013; there is the earning generation and serving customers. So vocation, I don't know if this is a word for us. Klepierre is no longer part of the operational business of BNP Paribas for years: five, six, seven years; it's part of the investment portfolio. So we are looking at this company in this way.</p>
          <p>We have the majority of this company. And on top of looking at this company as an investment, we are also looking at the company for its own interest. So we'll see what will happen one day. Either we're staying in this position or we're doing something else. So nothing less, nothing more. But this company is part of the investment portfolio of the bank and we are very pleased with that and the earning generation from this company to the Group. So for the time being it's totally okay.</p>
          <p>For Italy, we believe that there is a number of very strong powerful measures that are going on. We have all seen Italy improving. We believe that Italy will continue to improve and that's it. On the other hand, we have a portfolio to manage, government bonds. While looking at this portfolio on a global approach, mainly looking at the potential sensitivity on the core equity of the bank considering the new rules from Basel 3. So there is nothing particular about Italy. We haven't moved since the end of October last year. Objectively the situation is improving. It can be measured at the level of interest paid by Italy 10 years maturity coming down from more than 7% to close to 5%: 5.5%. So it's a huge move. And this is not just a move in the market, this is based upon a number of measures, requirements from Europe, decision from the Italian bodies, and some kind of normalization of the situation. So &#x2013; well, and globally if you look at that portfolio we will continue to manage this portfolio in an opportunistic way. So this is the way we are managing the situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, concerning CIB, we are not at all in the same situation in the beginning of 2012 compared to the beginning of 2009. We will not enjoy "some one-off gain" because if you remember at the end of 2008 it was sometimes very difficult to market some specific situation or some specific position, which was not at all the case end of 2011. What we enjoy in the beginning of 2012 is roughly two things. First of all the debt capital market is very active and so we benefit of it. We will continue to benefit year-after-year of this situation, because also re-intermediation of the market in Europe, which will increase due to Basel 3. So globally, our client business activity is good.</p>
          <p>And on top of that, as I mentioned, in the first quarter, some clients in U.S., in Asia were "afraid" of the eurozone banks. And so they are seeing that BNP Paribas is still a strong bank with a very, let's say good, rating compared to a lot of other banks. They come back to us which is absolutely normal, but which was not the case at the last &#x2013; during the last quarter of 2011. So let's say we come back to a normal situation for BNP Paribas and the situation of the last quarter was absolutely not normal for BNP Paribas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You had a question about the tax rate. Since the guidance has not changed, it's roughly 28% to 30%, something like that. Slightly below 30% probably.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Robin Down from HSBC. Can I actually just follow up on Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois' question there? Because you didn't really sell any bonds in the post-October last year. I mean very little. I think Luxembourg has seen a bit of a sell-down. Was that because of the lack of liquidity or was that because you are, globally, you're happy with the sovereign debt portfolio as it currently stands? And obviously there are two issues that arise from this. One is, whether or not we should be looking for further disposal potential of those sovereign bonds if you do re-style a sell program in this year. And then &#x2013; and perhaps much more broadly, looking ahead three years, to the liquidity rules coming in in Europe. Obviously what we, I think, want to know, is almost what your appetite is in terms of liquidity management, your appetite is for holding sovereign bonds? Because if you've been permanently scarred by events of the last six months, you don't want to hold a sovereign bond portfolio, you want to hold more of your liquidity in the form of cash with central banks, then obviously there is quite a big yield reduction in doing that. So I mean perhaps could you just explore how you feel about sovereign bonds as part of your liquidity portfolio going forwards and what the cost impact of that might be?</p>
          <p>And then completely unrelated, a bit of a trainspotter question I'm afraid. But I always get so confused with the Fortis PPAs, and I can see that you've accelerated or you've taken an additional PPA release in the fourth quarter to do with an asset sale. Could you just remind us &#x2013; and I can't see it in the accounts &#x2013; could you just remind us where we stand now with Fortis PPA, the fair value adjustments? Is there anything more to come through in 2012 there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On that technical &#x2013; the last technical question to start with. Yes, we &#x2013; well, it was also part of the selling effort. So we sold also, as I said, part of the <mark type="ph" /> team (98:00) portfolio, so it creates some write-backs on the PPA. The regular amortization of <mark type="ph" /> PPA (98:12) should keep bringing around &#x20AC;600 million next year &#x2013; this year, I mean, 2012. And then it will &#x2013; well, at starting 2013, it will be much less and drop to very, well, small figure.</p>
          <p>Yeah, about the sovereign portfolio. As we said, we want to be opportunistic and certainly we are not going to sell at the very moment where everybody is completely panicked and the prices are really at &#x2013; very low. So it was not the right time to sell in November and December, clearly. For now there is indeed some rally, so we'll keep this opportunistic approach and we are not excluding, yes, selling again some peers. But &#x2013; well, we have done a lot already and the current level, they are much more sustainable than they were last year, so we are not in a hurry either.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Guillaume Tiberghien at Exane BNP Paribas. I've got two questions. One relates to the corporate center. If I strip out the fair value gain on our debt and the two items of PPA, as well as a small gain on hybrid debt, you actually had negative revenues this quarter and I think normally you generate about &#x20AC;200 million per quarter. So it's nearly a swing of &#x20AC;1 billion per year if we annualize the surprise. So can you maybe explain where we stand, because that's obviously quite big for earnings sensitivity?</p>
          <p>And the other one is relating to acquisitions. Fortis acquisition is now pretty much in the bag in terms of integration. And I appreciate you have to make a lot of effort on solvency. But if you find, particularly in Italy, banks that may not be too expensive what would be your appetite for acquisitions in Italy? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start with the first question. Yes, the corporate center, what happened this quarter is very specific to the quarter. Indeed, we had to face, I would say, additional liquidity cost during this quarter, both due to the fact that we have increased the buffer of central banks on the short-term area, we have increased the central bank's deposits and they are not very well remunerated and this creates some cost. And under medium and long term as well, we have increased our program, as I said, and at the moment where it was relatively more expensive. So it's a technical delay between the time where we have incurred those additional costs and the time where we are going to pass it to the businesses. So those costs, well, are going either to come down if markets come back to normality or better levels progressively or they are going to be passed on to the businesses this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About Italy, this is nothing special about Italy, but as we have said, we are totally investing this 2012 year adapting the business model, adapting to the new regulation and serving already existing customers. So this is the 2012 year and this is it. There is no room for anything else. So just be clear about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeremy Sigee from Barclays Capital. I just wanted to come back on to the questions of funding and regulation. On funding, what are the prospects do you think for restarting public term debt issuance in size and positioning yourselves back among the sort of leaders in that process? And what &#x2013; how important it is that to you and what do you think the preconditions are for playing that role?</p>
          <p>And then secondly I wanted to come back on to regulation in the French context. What are your expectations around the financial transactions tax and the impact and your potential reactions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On funding, you know, we &#x2013; well, we are not going to give you the level we'll find right. If and when the market is coming down and it is giving a better access to the euro-based banks, there is no reason why we wouldn't issue again on the public market. The only thing is that we feel that there was a period where it was really too expensive and not, I would say, not acceptable for us as we have alternative sources. And that's it. But we may come back one day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is your view that you could fulfill your program through the measures you've been pursuing so far? Private placements, your network?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The program has been designed in order to be achievable without any need to use the public market, if so. We wanted to achieve that. So we are free and it's important to have flexibility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry what abut financial transaction tax?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can answer. It's not a specific issue for French banks; it's an issue for the Paris situation because probably this tax will eat, let's say the equity transactions. But it's to date not completely clear. But clearly, it's not a specific issue for French banks; it's an issue probably some equities. So the equities listed in Paris and perhaps for some derivatives and other today, it's not completely clear, but we are clearly in a level playing field. So it's not an issue. I am sorry for, probably for final clients, but this is the situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Jon Peace at Nomura. Just one quick follow-up on France retail revenue growth. The Fed's obviously indicated it intends to keep interest rates low until 2014. If the ECB was to do something similar, do you have any issues with maturing hedges that you've got for your net interest margin that could lead to problems with net interest income growth? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nothing special. I mean we are managing the ALM position of the French retail in a quite proactive way, depending on the situation. So we are prepared to any move whatsoever. So it's a complex situation looking at the balance sheet of a French bank because you have regulated products, you have fixed rates but that are moving. So well it's savoir-faire, it's a business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Few quick questions. First of all, regarding the liquid asset buffer of &#x20AC;160 billion, so you've increased your buffer for central bank deposits. Just to understand, if you could give some color of how you actually managed this over time? You mentioned that it's 85% of your short-term cash resources; is that something you want to increase over time as a percentage or would you have more central bank deposits over time versus the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (106:40) assets? Just to understand how this is managed from the liquidity perspective.</p>
          <p>Secondly, coming back on the risk-weighted assets impact, in particular the &#x20AC;10 billion in capital markets for Basel 2.5, if you could give some color on where this is coming from and what kind of mitigation it is really for Basel 2.5 and should we expect some as well for Basel 3?</p>
          <p>And lastly on your provisions, you mentioned that provisions for 2012 would be probably stable to slightly increased. Could you maybe give some color by divisions, if this is coming from personal finance, Europe, Mediterranean or normalization CIB? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About the first question, we have faced a huge crisis in the second half of last year. And so we reacted as fast as possible in order to be on the safe side. Now if &#x2013; it's clear that those deposits with central banks are not very remunerated. It seems &#x2013; and there is no need to keep so such a huge buffer once things would stabilize and calm down. So we'll have &#x2013; we are going to follow the way the market is evolving. First we are going to follow also to have a kind of proportion between this buffer and our short-term funding. If short-term funding keeps going down, we'll need less buffer as well. So this is something we are going to manage in order to try and optimize between security and cost, as always. So it's difficult to give you &#x2013; to tell you more than that, it will depend on the circumstances.</p>
          <p>You asked about the mitigations, how we mitigate it? That was the question? Sorry, the second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's coming back to basically slide 27 where you showed the Basel 2.5 impact on CIB, which you said &#x20AC;37 billion. And Basel 2.5 in capital markets, the adaptation plan reduced it by &#x20AC;10 billion. If we could get some color on that &#x20AC;10 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x20AC;10 billion, well, the &#x20AC;10 billion it's about reducing certain activities that are hit by Basel 2.5, like the correlation book for example and developing other activities that are not impacted like debt capital markets, for example. So we &#x2013; the businesses are changing, the type of business they are doing. And sometimes also with the same business, the way they are doing it, for example, with less inventories, less cash inventories and more derivatives or things like that for the hedging. So they are trying to change the business and the way they are conducting it in order to make that as efficient as possible, as &#x2013; to optimize it with regard the new regulation. That's quite normal. And as those businesses are conducted on a relatively short-term basis, they are doing that toward the end just before the new regulation comes into force.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can comment about that. Naturally, not only BNP Paribas, but all sorts of banks are reducing, let's say, all the bonds inventory. So, at the end, there's a kind of re-pricing, which is an increasing between the bid and ask. Clearly, as we have always mentioned, naturally, at the end, the cost will be paid by the investors, because all the banks are reducing the inventories because the inventories are costly in term of Basel 2.5 and probably in terms of Basel 3. So, as all of the banks are doing so, it's possible to do so. It would not have been possible to do so if BNP Paribas would have been alone in this target. But if you hear what all the competitors are expressing in term of mitigation of the Basel 2.5 action, you'll see that the mitigation &#x2013; the relative position of the mitigation of BNP Paribas is much lower than the mitigation of some big competitors in Europe. So, it's much easier to do so now; it was not possible to do so two years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how much shall we expect if you continue going into Basel 3, to mitigate part of Basel 3? I think in the past, you never really gave mitigation risk-weighted assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, we don't know the exact rules concerning Basel 3, we have to remind that. So today it's too early to answer that question. Perhaps we will be able to answer in summer, probably late summer. But globally, if all the banks will reduce the position, today we don't express what will happen. I think we see a positive things in the market mainly since the beginning of the year. Let's say, all the sellers in the market are mitigating today Basel 2.5 because everything is clear, so I anticipate that it will be the same situation concerning Basel 3, but not in the beginning of the year, but after. So today, it's difficult to have a quantitative answer, but I'm cautiously optimistic that the market will change for all the banks. So today perhaps I will answer in August.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And the last question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question was &#x2013; could you repeat it briefly, sorry? The outlook on provisioning. Basically, it's what we &#x2013; well, we can look at the slide on the cost of risk. We have seen a kind of a stabilizing trend at the level of the Group and more or less as you can see also at the level of each business line quarter-after-quarter. So, the improvement trend has kind of stopped, ceased and has now replaced by a kind of stabilization trend. So, I think that given the fact that the growth in Europe is not going to be a &#x2013; neither in the U.S., by the way, very big, very buoyant in 2012, well, we expect the trend to continue and at best a kind of stabilization, maybe slightly worsening fixed rate of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from S&#xE9;bastien Lemaire from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. I have four quick questions please. First, I just wanted to come back on the 180 basis point impact on Basel 3 on the regulatory capital. I was just wondering what weighting of the interest capital charge you have assumed in your calculation to which the 180 basis points? And if there were other moving parts, apart from insurance, explaining the higher impact of Basel 3? That would be my first question.</p>
          <p>Second, in CIB the underlying trading revenues were quite impressive in Q4, especially versus last quarter, but costs were also in a sharp rise in the capital market division. I was just wondering why cost have been not adjusted more in line with revenue growth in Q4?</p>
          <p>Third question is on French retail, I get that it was kind of a disappointment in terms of revenue. I just wanted to know if it's &#x2013; was basically a trend or just a weak quarter? I know that it's hard to make some judgments on a single quarter, but it would be helpful.</p>
          <p>And the final question would be the breakdown of risk-weighted asset by division? It would be helpful, say, if you could provide it to us. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About the regulatory capital. As I've said, well, the &#x2013; well, we try and monitor what's happening on the regulatory front. And indeed we had issued this first estimate one year ago, or more than one year already, of the &#x2013; and at that time we were seeing 140 basis points for Basel 3. Now, as it stands now, we say 180. In that evolution, there have been a lot of clarifications of &#x2013; and changes up and down, not only &#x2013; and in particular, indeed, as you say, the insurance treatment that seems now to evolve towards the weighting of the capital invested in the insurance business. While at the time it was more about a deduction from the capital instead of additional risk-weighted asset.</p>
          <p>So this has &#x2013; we &#x2013; at this stage, we are based on the &#x2013; we have based our estimates on the so-called Danish compromise that is on the table for discussion at the European level. But we'll &#x2013; this is the way we did it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just in term of weighting of the insurance capital charge, could you just give a number? Or no?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Weighting is, I think, 370% if I am right. It's the same weighting as a private equity business, because by definition, it's not listed. So I think it's 370%</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In CIB I think the best way is look at the cost of the second half and not only quarter-by-quarter. And as I mentioned, the cost income ratio for the second half was 63% with the government losses; excluding the government losses it was 59%, that's the reason why I mentioned around 60%, which is I think a good level. And the third quarter was too low; we have expressed they were an exceptional provision if I remember that we took back. So globally, I think about 60% globally for the second half, which is not reliable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding your last question about the revenues of French Retail Banking, we should perhaps go to slide 53, if we can have it. And you can see that there is a sharp difference between the evolution of net interest margin in the fourth quarter, which remains strongly positive with 2.4%. And we could expect this evolution to remain positive in this year through the re-pricing actions I already mentioned. But the evolution of commissions has been negative, minus 2.7%, due to two main factors I mentioned. First, financial fees and this is strongly dependent with the situation of financial markets and due also to a new factor which will play a role in 2012, which is the diminution of bank card fees; this is a new regulation by the antitrust authorities. So, this is clearly the story for the fourth quarter, where we were a bit hampered by the evolution of fees. It's not a question of interest margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Anke Reingen from Royal Bank of Canada.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yes, Anke here from RBC, I just had three questions. The first is on CIB and the outlook on earnings. And I understand some moving parts but I just wanted to make sure that I'm thinking about it the right way. If I take first half affirmed 2011 pre-tax profit for the year and make the adjustments in Q4, take out the &#x20AC;1.4 billion of the revenue hit <mark type="indiscernible" /> of (120:05) &#x20AC;450 million come to about &#x20AC;1 billion pre-tax profit per quarter. Is this like longer term the right way to think about it pre any pricing benefit?</p>
          <p>And then I was wondering if, I mean, currently it still seems your equity is allocated at 7%. So will this increase to 9% or 10% over time?</p>
          <p>And then on the &#x20AC;25 billion of delivered risk-weighted assets reduction, I just wondered, you say it's &#x20AC;5 billion from sales, but how much is this in risk-weighted asset terms?</p>
          <p>And then lastly just on deposit trends in your sort of like core retail businesses, I was &#x2013; I mean the volumes in French retail, BeLux and BNL came down quarter-on-quarter, and I just wondered if this is &#x2013; like your strategy continues to be not to compete on price at the expense of losing deposits? Or is there some seasonality in here? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps on the question of deposits in Italy. If you look at the figures, two elements. First, the evolution of deposits, at slide 56, is slightly better in the last quarter than it used to be for the whole year. So it's for us, a good sign that our policy of not entering the deposits war as aggressively as our competitors has been a good one.</p>
          <p>The other element is that if you look at the evolution of the whole market, we remain in line with the whole market. We even slightly increased our market share regarding deposits. So it's, for us, a very good sign that BNP Paribas reputation and image and the quality of our customer relations helped us to keep our clients and deposits despite not offering always the most aggressive prices. So we are clearly committed to keep this policy; we think it's the right mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just coming back to the previous person's question about the risk weighted assets per business. It's on page 89. Just to give you the &#x2013; I did some percentage of &#x20AC;614 billion so just have the figures. And your first question. I missed your first question because of the.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What's the impact on the de-leveraging from CIB, if I understood well. I believe we've given all we could say about if it's impact. That's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm basically trying to understand all the moving parts. Because I mean, clearly is it right if I look about the future profitability of the CIB business, if I take 2011 pre-tax, add back the one-offs, take off the &#x20AC;1.4 billion revenue loss, add back the cost synergies and then I have about &#x20AC;1 billion pre-tax per quarter. I mean, I'm not trying to get guidance here, but is this the right way to think about it? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no guidance concerning CIB because we have never given guidance concerning CIB business. Because as I mentioned, I repeat, I'm on old man, I've seen so many crises, so many volatility that I think it would be very dangerous to make anything, especially in this change of environment. You have to think that the competition is changing. We are &#x2013; there are less competitors, there are &#x2013; some competitors are in great difficulty. So it's very difficult to make the differentiation because between the global decrease in the revenue push and the fact that a lot of competitors are disappearing or decreasing their situation. Globally, I mentioned that the financing activity, we will see less revenues. You have all the figures; I don't want to comment anymore. It depends on the speed and the level of the repricing and so you will see that quarter-after-quarter.</p>
          <p>And second, concerning the capital market activity, I repeat that BNP Paribas is well positioned compared to some competitors because we have very strong client business activities and not at all proprietary trading that we see that the clients work a lot with BNP Paribas. And so, we will see not at the end of the day but at the end of this year, at the end of 2013, that BNP Paribas will succeed after the crisis because BNP Paribas, as you know, is a growing company. We continue quarter-after-quarter to deliver revenues, we say what we make. And so there is no &#x2013; let's say no sex in BNP Paribas. No, but we work &#x2013; we are boring. So, no recovery, nothing, no specific problem, so &#x2013; and you will see that quarter-after-quarter, so I have no further comments on that. Sorry to be boring.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Alex Koagne from Natixis. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, everybody. This is Alex Koagne from Natixis. I just have two remaining question. The first one is on revenue loss in the CIB. From my understanding in your Q3, the &#x20AC;1.4 billion revenue losses was linked to the reduction in RWA of &#x20AC;30 billion. Should I understand that the $15 billion additional that you earned this quarter will not lead to any revenue loss?</p>
          <p>The second one is on your dividend policy. Obviously you are becoming more let's say cautious since you are decreasing the level of the payout ratio and even offering an option for &#x2013; to pay in strip. I'm just wondering what have definitely made you more cautious? I mean, what is the reason behind you becoming more cautious in arena? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't get the first question, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll just take on the second one, dividend payout. We are 25%. There are only a limited number of banks that will have dividend this year. So even 25% should be considered as high because to pay a dividend you need to have a relevant earnings and profit capacity. What is the main driver behind this move is the fact that one of the main objective of the group is to strengthen the capital base, because we really want to be ready by year-end to enter in the new, I would say, paradigm for the bank industry from the first day at the right level, not having to deal with problems or any issues coming from the Basel.</p>
          <p>So we want to turn the page, this will be done by year-end and this is why we are &#x2013; we came to that conclusion that 25% is fair enough. If you compare this payout to other large banks, you can fairly understand that is, well, of the same magnitude. Most banks offer something in between 10% and 20%. And considering the fact that part of the dividend is going to be paid in share, 25% in the end, in line with what has been given by other large banks. So, this is some kind of an equilibrium, so there is nothing else; this is a balance between giving a dividend to the shareholders and the fact that the company need to be prepared as soon as possible. So nothing less, nothing more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Yes, on the first question, the RWA reduction in CIB will lead to &#x20AC;1.4 billion revenue losses. In your Q3, my understanding was that the revenue loss was linked to a &#x20AC;30 billion RWA reduction. As of today in CIB, the reduction will be &#x20AC;45 billion, which means that we have &#x20AC;15 billion more, and I was just wondering whether this will lead to any revenue attrition or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You &#x2013; well, when we say risk-weighted asset, it's a risk-weighted asset or equivalent. And we don't exclude to have some kind of a sale of some part of the businesses, with some good reason, that would create capital with, you know...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With the equivalent risk-weighted asset. And.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our final question today from Omar Fall from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I'm Omar Fall from UBS. Three questions please. Just the cost of risk rise in financing, still at a modest level at 28 basis points, can you give us some detail on whether these were just a few lumpy files? And what's the risk of you making the cycle worse here through your deleveraging in some of the industries you're targeting, like real estate finance, auto finance, et cetera?</p>
          <p>Second question, just on the Fixed Income revenue, which was surprisingly strong, almost best in class in the quarter, up 6% Q-on-Q, can you give some additional color on how you manage this given the bias that you have to the European rates business and the deleveraging, given trading assets have decreased materially as well? I think you may have started answering that but I couldn't hear.</p>
          <p>And then final question, somewhat of a philosophical one on the LTRO, but some of your German and Nordic peers have stated that the long-term benefits of staying away from it, reputationally, et cetera, outweighs the potential short-term P&amp;L benefits for those banks that can manage it. So when you're thinking of the amount you may borrow going forward in the LTRO, do you feel any constraints on the total size that you'll borrow? Or for you it's a free lunch, the stigma's been removed and it doesn't matter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry the sound is really bad. So I understood at least the last question about the LTRO. We see the LTRO as really a technical way of trying and bringing some liquidity into Europe. And so we have taken it as something that we could use. And we have no &#x2013; there is no deal, or no hidden deal, or we do exactly what we want to with that LTRO. And the first thing obviously was to use it in order to stabilize the funding of our portfolios. We are using &#x2013; if we look back at the slide, maybe number &#x2013; the slide about the balance sheet, the total balance sheet that I presented a few minutes ago...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>36.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>36. You see that, yes, the fixed income securities are above the line. And so they are majoritarily funded through short-term funding, as said here. So the LTRO for us was an opportunity to stabilize this short-term funding instead of bringing that kind of securities to the market in repos or sometimes to &#x2013; the first LTRO is three months or six months &#x2013; to an opportunity to stabilize that for three years, with a possibility to opt out after one year, so it's very convenient.</p>
          <p>So we maintained by the way, in the &#x20AC;188 billion, the funds we got from the first LTROs, we maintained that at short-term funding because we see that as just a way to make sure that the short-term funding from the ECB is stabilized for three years, it's the way we look at it. It's not really more than that because it's just a kind of a way to fund the liquid assets we have. And that's it. So there is no other constraint on the LTRO. And I think that psychologically it plays a significant role because it showed that the ECB was ready to make sure that the market would work properly and it would take care of the market. And that's very important.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and one of your questions, the cost of risk at the level of CIB financing, probably we can move to page 49. Let's see, there is nothing in relation with the deleveraging, not at all. And if you look at the cost of risk, it is very low all along the year. So we have some slight increase in specific provisions at the end of the year, but this is not at all a trend.</p>
          <p>The trend is the level, the average level of the year 2011, which is very low. And so there is nothing specific and nothing in relation with the deleveraging. What we can add is that, as we work a lot with large corporate and large institution, we don't see anything specific on our radar screen; there is nothing specific and so that's the reason why we constantly repeat that we don't see at the level of CIB any reason to see the cost of risk increasing in 2012.</p>
          <p>So your first question or your second question, I don't remember, was, if I correctly understood, why are your revenues, let's say, so good in the first quarter on Fixed Income compared to some competitor? I don't know about the competitors. What I can repeat and constantly repeat is that we have a client business model and so the revenues are linked to the activities of our clients. So, let's say globally, it was not so good in the first quarter; as I mentioned, it will be much better in the first quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>So all in all, our client base, specifically on our domestic market but also in U.S. and in Asia, continued to exist in the first quarter and we have no specific proprietary trading and something like that. So all in all, we think it was not so bad but correct at the level of Fixed Income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. Philippe will tell you a few words.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I would like to &#x2013; yes, as we are all here today in London, I would like to &#x2013; just first, two things are important because your interviewers are going to change indeed. First, I would like to introduce Lars Machenil, he is going to be my follower. So Lars is going to become CFO of BNP Paribas starting the beginning of March as was already said.</p>
          <p>Second, I would like to give you a scoop. So B&#xE9;atrice Belorgey will move into the group, so she will stop being your main correspondent in the Investor Relations as the Head of the Investor Relations team. B&#xE9;atrice, well, came in 2005 in the team and became head of the team in 2008. So she spent, I would say, three relatively good years and five, six and seven and four relatively bad years, the crisis years, so she went through everything. I think she made a great job, very great job, so I guess you will have your own opinion, I guess, but, well, we think that she made a very great job at the time where the disclosure tremendously increased and the demand for information and the pressure on Investor Relations team increased considerably.</p>
          <p>She was extremely dedicated to you. I think you &#x2013; well, you know that you can give her a phone call at any time in the day, even in the night, in the weekends, everywhere. This summer, again, she spent the month of August not &#x2013; well, she was supposed to be on vacation but she worked almost every day I think in trying to answer to some worries of the market. She &#x2013; well, she had the good knowledge of the market before coming to Investor Relations team having worked in the past in the Dealing Room I mean &#x2013; and in the Structured Products, selling structural product and building structural product. And she is &#x2013; her professionalism I think is very, very big and she has always been, I think, very &#x2013; well, trying to provide you with all the information you wanted to have within the disclosure that is &#x2013; that has the borders, as you know; so if there are borders, we &#x2013; she &#x2013; nobody is allowed to go over. But within those borders, I think she was really trying to do her best in order to provide you with the information.</p>
          <p>So she will move back to her well business job, I would say. She's the private banking. You may know that she was coming from private banking and she will go back to private banking as the Head of the French Private Banking, so very important position in the bank. So she had a lot of fun, I think, but it's time for another challenge.</p>
          <p>So she will be replaced by <mark type="ph" /> Stefan Devaniak (140:38), maybe you could stand up as well. So Stefan has been working with BNP Paribas for, well, for 20 years around. So he's an old chap of BNP Paribas and he worked in different areas of the group, he knows the group very well. Recently he was more in CIB and very recently while he was just &#x2013; he's leading the position of Head of Leveraged Finance Europe, so he knows a lot these financing businesses of CIB. And so I'm sure that his experience, all his experience is going to help him in his new position.</p>
          <p>So I wanted to take this opportunity, she will &#x2013; he will take his new position in March, mid-March, but we wanted to tell you now, because we are here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So thank you very much, B&#xE9;atrice, and great success in the private bank. B&#xE9;atrice will join the group of the top 100 executive of BNP Paribas by year-end. So this is like the 9% Basel 3 ratio; this is one of our targets. Thank you very much for attending the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>