<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1344418" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-11-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7818</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Philippe Bordenave, Chief Financial Officer and Senior Executive Vice President</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Pascal Decque</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Guillaume Tiberghien</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Omar Fall</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Alessandro Roccati</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Brice Vandamme</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Pierre Flabb&#xE9;e</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Delphine Lee</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Robin Down</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Maxence Le Gouvello</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Anke Reingen</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Neuez</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Kinner Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Antonio Guglielmi</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Pierre Chedeville</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to today's presentation of BNP Paribas 2010 third quarter results. For your information, this conference is being recorded. Slides of the presentation are now available on BNP Paribas Investor Relations Web site. Please go to www.invest.bnpparibas.com. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to hand the call over to your host today, Mr. Philippe Bordenave, Senior Executive, Vice President and CFO. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
          <p>Good afternoon. Welcome to all of you. As usual, I will start with a few introductory remarks before taking your questions.</p>
          <p>Let me say that it's my pleasure to take you through BNP Paribas results, which demonstrates, once again, the strong underlying profit generation capability of the group thanks to its diversified and client-centric business model.</p>
          <p>The net profit for the third quarter 2010 stand at &#x20AC;1.9 billion, a rise of 46% compared to the same quarter last year, and the fourth net income posted by a bank this quarter among those that already published their results. This was achieved, thanks to the resilience of revenues, despite an environment characterized by investors' risk aversion and a drop in the cost of risk.</p>
          <p>I would like to first comment on this quarter's negative jaws effect of 8 basis points regarding our operating divisions, meaning without taking into account restructuring costs. You know that we don't like negative jaws.</p>
          <p>In order to analyze those ones, one should bear in mind that the third quarter of 2009 was a transitory period for bonus rules, leading to not booking deferred bonuses in that quarter, and hence to lower the third quarter booked expenses. And if you'll remember, in the fourth quarter 2009, we managed to find a competent way to fully book those costs, including awarded bonuses to be vested in 2010 and later. And it had, of course, an opposite impact, increasing the cost base over the fourth quarter of 2009 by the same amount.</p>
          <p>So this explains why the basis is not significant, and also therefore, as far as we are concerned, regarding deferred compensations, there are no overhanging costs on future earnings. It's important to note that some competitors announced that they still needed to book a few billion euros for 2009 deferred bonuses. Thus, this also helps explain why, over the first nine months of 2010, CIB's cost income ratio at 52.5% stood at the best level in the industry.</p>
          <p>Second, I would like to draw your attention on the rebalancing of our business contribution to the group's earnings. This rebalancing is well on track.</p>
          <p>In terms of capital allocation, as you know, BNP Paribas' target of 50% Retail, one-third CIB, one-sixth for Investment Solutions was not called into question during the crisis, and by the way, it should not significantly evolve with the new regulatory environment.</p>
          <p>But 2009 results were characterized by an exceptional revenue contribution from CIB in the first half, on the one hand, if you remember, and also a significant increase in provisions in Retail due to the economic crisis on the other hand. And as a result, back then, this one-half, one-third, one-sixth proportion could not be found in pre-tax results, and CIB's contribution has risen temporarily to more than 50%.</p>
          <p>Conversely, over the first nine months of 2010, a rebalancing of our business divisions' results was initiated. CIB's share was reduced to 45%, and Retail's pre-tax contribution bounced back. This rebound of the Retail should continue, as we mainly operate in sound and wealthy domestic markets.</p>
          <p>For reference purposes, let me just highlight the strong volume growth for nine months French and BeLux mortgages, which stood respectively at plus 7.7% and plus 9.2% on a like-for-like basis, while current accounts increased by 8.7% and 6.7%, respectively, and by 5.2% for BNL. Besides these positive increases, cost of risk is also now stabilizing or even starting to abate, though the rebalancing is underway.</p>
          <p>Third, once again, I would like to say that our asset gathering activities performed well this quarter, thanks to the diversity of the business mix. While Private Banking and Asset Management were somewhat impacted by investors' risk aversion, Insurance has benefited from it, with an impressive 20% to 30% increase in gross written premiums in France and abroad.</p>
          <p>Finally, the CIB division posted solid results, thanks to its diversified client-centric business model. Financing business is providing, once again, a stable and recurrent revenue base, while equity derivatives experienced a rebound and Fixed Income confirmed its leadership in Europe, remaining number one for euro-denominated bond issues.</p>
          <p>To sum it up, this strong earning generation capacity has enabled BNP Paribas to reach a high level of common equity Tier 1 of 9% that stood 8% at the beginning of this year, all exclusively due to organic contribution quarter-after-quarter. What is important here is to understand that what makes the solidity of a bank is not the actual ratio at the given point of time, but how it evolves through good and bad periods.</p>
          <p>And the risk profile is a key element, and this reasoning is similar regarding regulation. Our business model, with its categorized diversity, acts as a buffer against crisis, and therefore, BNP Paribas deserves a lower level of capital requirement than pure player peers, which has unbalanced business activities, such as, for example, mainly investment banking or even pure retailers with a significant presence in emerging markets.</p>
          <p>In any case, as you have seen, our solvency has now reached a high level, and Basel III will have a manageable impact, so BNP Paribas has quite some leeway to keep accompanying its clients in their financing needs.</p>
          <p>This is what I wanted to stress at the beginning of this conference call, and I am now ready to answer to your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Philippe Bordenave. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We will now take our first question from Patrick Leclerc from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>It seems that Patrick has left the queue. We will now take our next question from Pascal Decque from Natixis. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon, Philippe. Good afternoon, everyone. A few questions regarding Basel III, if you don't mind. I would like to know if you can disclose the hypothesis you used for your calculation regarding CVA minorities and insurance? Because yesterday SoGen said they were considering still the conglomerate approach for these insurance businesses. The second one, you mentioned a cash dividend in your model, but I don't know if it's purely theoretically or if you are planning any script dividend in the coming years? And the short one, I didn't see, maybe it's a mistake, but I didn't see any target or level you would reach in 2013 in common equity Tier 1? And a follow-up question regarding this level. What would you consider as, say, a good level, if I say, a good level for the common equity ratio for a group like BNP as you described it before, , very diversified and client-centric? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Okay. Let's start with your first question. Concerning the hypotheses, in fact, as far as the CVAs are concerned, let's start with that. While it's true that discussions are still ongoing with the Basel Committee and the exact rules are not yet known, this is something I would like to stress for the whole exercise. We are still in a moving regulatory environment, even if certain of things have been written down. Other things are still to be fine tuned, and there are a lot of implementation rules remains to be defined. So it's extremely difficult to have a complete precise and final view, but as we have understood that, we are not ready to wait until all this would have been completely fine tuned. While we have given a kind of best estimate for each case, but yes, clearly we had to take some kind of views, and this is why frankly also, we are giving a range as far as a numerator is concerned, the capital deductions are concerned because it's even less clear than the denominator of the risk-weighted asset side.</p>
          <p>So on the CVS side, it's what we think now, given the state of the discussions with the Basel Committee. I can't tell you more than that. While it's still we think redundant with the stressed expected potential exposure measuring to counterparty credit risk, so we keep thinking that it's still too much and not close to the actual risk. But if it were to be implemented like it is now, like it stands now in the discussions at Basel, it would be 20 billion additional, a little bit less than that, by the way, but this is the bulk of the 20 billion we are mentioning. Now about the numerator, and the capital deductions. The 5 billion to 7 billion we are mentioning is a kind of a rough estimate of &#x2013; and it's mainly the addition of three elements representing a few billions each, with again, some uncertainties regarding each of these elements. So the minority interest, the impact, of course, will depend on the meaning of minimum. You know that as well as I do. It seems that the threshold will be at least 7%, but it could be higher and, for example, it could be the pillar 2 minimum in each country and hence in that case, of course, it would be less stringent, but the central assumption is the 7%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As for the tax losses carry forward, the bulk of it will be recouped by 2018, but there is, of course, some uncertainty on the final amount, but we have made a reasonable assumption. About the 15% threshold, including the significant participations in financial institutions. Well, you have two things which are, I would say, playing a significant role in that threshold. The temporary differences, the DTAs arising from temporary differences, at the moment we have an amount which is somewhat inflated by the Fortis PPA, and this part of the temporary differences is going to be recouped in parallel with the amortization of the related adjustments, irrespective of the P&amp;L of BNP Paribas Fortis, by the way. Especially, as part of those adjustments may be amortized early due to say earlier repayments, like it happened this quarter. And it's reasonable to assume that temporary differences will come back to a level below &#x20AC;0.05 of the equity, like it was the case before the Fortis acquisition. So the 10% tranche, so significant participations in financial institutions would then be available in full, and in that case, the corresponding deduction would be minimal, especially once netted with what we already deduct under Basel II.</p>
          <p>And so depending on the way those significant participations are computed, especially as far as the Insurance is concerned, as you say, well, there is a kind of range. So overall &#x2013; and this is what we, well we think it's important to keep in mind that it's kind of ballpark figure, but overall, it should be 5 billion to 7 billion. And those are the reasoning behind that. That cash dividend, yes, I mean again, I'm not going to answer to your question because that decision is taken by the Board while closing the yearly accounts, so it's too early to answer to your question. And the target for 2013, I mean, we again, we think that additional capital requirements under Basel III regulation are unwarranted for a bank like BNP Paribas, as I tried to explain in my introductory remarks. And I would like to recall that we neither originated the prime loans nor costed a single euro to taxpayers, and that our capital was not dented throughout the crisis, proving the resilience of our diversified and client-centric business model and also our stringent risk management over the recycle. And we consider clearly that there is no reason whatsoever for BNP Paribas to target a level of capital above the minimum requirements, whatever it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Thank you very much. And then I'm sorry, I still didn't get what method you will use, even if we don't have the numbers, what method you will use for the deduction for Insurance capital? I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's part of the uncertainty. As of now, I mean, as you know, there are two options.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so this remains an uncertainty.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we have taken both assumptions in mind, if you want, in assessing the range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It's one of the extension of the 5 to 7?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Guillaume Tiberghien from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I've got two small questions. One related to the restructuring cost at 40. I think you've only taken 500 million at the moment in the first nine months, and had in mind 800 for the year, so does it mean that we will have 300 in Q4? And the second question relates to domestic Retail. Would you care to give us a guidance for what we should expect next year in terms of revenue growth? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, relating to next year, I think we'll stick to what we usually do, meaning that we give some indications while releasing the full year results. So we give some kind of, well you know we don't like giving guidance in a too precise way. We don't like to promise. We prefer to deliver, but we nevertheless give some indications, but only once we have completed the budget, and at the time of the year end results. As for the restructuring cost, I think we are &#x2013; well, the breakdown which we gave at the beginning of the restructuring plan was a kind of indicative only.</p>
          <p>We are beating the synergies, as you have seen. While we may have some differences on the restructuring cost chapter as well, so I can't tell you that we are going to have the 300 million full at once in the fourth quarter. We probably, again, also by releasing the fourth quarter results and the full year results we are going to update these restructuring plans, including the Turkish spot, by the way currently being studied and fine tuned. So it's going to be an opportunity to update all those figures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Just one follow-up, sorry, I forgot to ask on the Basel III. Could you give us a split currently of the details between tax losses carried forward and timing differences?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. At the moment, at the end of 2009 we were showing 3 billion of taxes carry forwards, and 3.3 billion of taxes carry forwards and 4.7 billion of temporary differences.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Omar Fall from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. I don't know of anyone else who's done this. Could you tell us why you had made the decision to take the option to reflect securitizations through RWA rather than through the 50:50 deduction originally, please? And if you could give us the current value of these securitization RWAs at the moment? And then the second question is could you just give us a flavor of how much in potential mitigation you believe you could achieve, especially as I guess you have got much in the way of legacy assets to run down or sell? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, about your first question, the securitization assets in question for us were representing a relatively small amounts because it's only &#x2013; the option is open for a securitized asset with low rating, in fact, below investment grades. And so you have the option of either deducting them &#x2013; you had the option and you still have the option of either deducting them 50:50 from Tier 1 and Tier 2 of the numerator side or weighing them in the risk-weighted assets at 1,250%, 1,250%. For us, those I would say bad quality securitized assets were representing only &#x20AC;2.6 billion. It's less now, and so the difference between those treatments, between those weights was something like 20 basis points of Tier 1. So because we had relatively low levels of such securitized assets because also we took the decision also because we &#x2013; it's more logical, and it makes more sense if you want to wait to weigh those assets like the others.</p>
          <p>It's up on the asset side, if you want, so it's normal to treat it as a risk-weighted asset, and also we have never been that &#x2013; we had never such a narrow range, such a narrow leeway in terms of Tier 1 such as shaving each of these points of ratio. So we decided to do that that way, which was a more conservative way, I agree, but which was more logical, but I understand that other banks having a bigger amount of such bad assets were inclined or tempted to take another way, which was providing them with short term relief, I would say, on their Tier 1. So this is the answer to your first question.</p>
          <p>The second question about mitigation. Mitigation, while we have several ways yet to write, of course, the sale of the natural redemption of those assets, it's going to provide with some reduction. Under Basel III capital requirements for counterparty risk mostly determined using stressed inputs, and the vow on credit evaluation adjustments is adding a kind of additional and redundant capital charge to that. And so, the putting in place more bilateral, collateral agreements will help produce capital, particularly with the sovereign and supranationals or with a few counterparties who have so far never signed such a collateral agreement. The collateral agreements are already a common practice between banks, but not with &#x2013; between with certain number of clients, so probably some sovereigns, some supra will accept.</p>
          <p>On the client side, while we have to bear in mind that most corporates have little capacity and no willingness to collateralize their exposure, so this is not going to be an available option, I guess, but sovereign, supras, a certain number of other type of institutional clients. The CCPs will also reduce capital as their weighting will be low, so the weighting part of the business to CCPs from bilateral will also lower capital requirements. So this kind of mitigation effects may help, but to be candid, one should not make too much hope on mitigation actions. I think that beyond some adjustments, marginal adjustments like those I have mentioned, significant mitigation would require a change in business model, and it would come at significant cost. So we are not, I mean, I don't think it's something which should be too much made hopeful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Just two follow-up questions. Number one, just to clarify. The 2.6 billion of assets, what does that represent? That's not the weighted number, is it?  Is that weighted number that's currently in your denominator of risk-weighted assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not. It's the exposure of cost. Yeah, it's exposure of cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It's the exposure. Okay. And then just the second question was...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It would represent more than 30 billion risk-weighted assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Understood. Now just the second question would be putting all of this together, including a bit of mitigation, I mean, it looks like you could end up at 10% plus in terms of core Tier 1 by 2013. Given that you're saying that a bank like BNP shouldn't be sizably above the minimums, is there a message that you're trying to send here? I mean, what would you do with a gap?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. I'm not sending a message, especially for BNP Paribas. I'm just saying that we have tried to provide you with figures which are relatively safe and sure, and I think that providing with mitigation figures or mitigation effects figures is a little bit less true, and this is why we have not provided you with such figures. This is what I wanted to say. That's all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Alessandro Roccati from Macquarie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, everyone. Couple of very quick questions. The first one is on risk-weighted assets, which have decreased from 6.33 billion to 6 in the third quarter. Just wondering if you can give us some guidance where the decrease is coming from and what we can expect going forward? And also on risk-weighted assets, if I understand correctly, based on not including the calculation of the capital improvement, operating capital generation from here to 2013. So when you say 200 basis points of operating capital generation, we should deduct something in the region of 60, 80 basis points from that? That's my question. And the second one is on French Retail where we've seen some relatively weak trends in terms of revenues. Both net interest income and fees were down 2% quarter-on-quarter in the last two quarters, and we've seen flat loans. Can you tell us what the outlook is for net interest income and the revenues more generally in the coming quarters? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the risk-weighted assets decrease over the quarter, in fact, it's coming from &#x2013; it's a reduction of 24 billion compared with the 30th of June. Out of those 24 billion, the foreign exchange impact is representing 17 billion, in fact, because the dollar went down sharply, and we are of significant exposure denominated in dollars. And the other significant part is minus 5 billion is due to state and redemptions and also early redemptions of securitization positions, so 17 plus 5 makes 22. So you have the bulk of the 24 billion, so those are the two main explanations. Then about the risk-weighted assets rules. For the future, I mean, we have not quantified them because we wanted to give you the stability to make your own assumption, though as you would have nothing to do, so it would be a pity.</p>
          <p>And more seriously, I mean we are a bank. It's extremely difficult to forecast such risk-weighted asset rules. But first, again, it depends on the dollar evolution, which is difficult to predict, and second, we are a bank of a real economy, and so we are financing our clients when they have needs, and so depending on the recovery, depending on the evolution of the economy, especially in our domestic area of Western Europe, the risk-weighted evolution can be different. So we prefer to make a reasoning without that, just to show where we stand without that, and to show that we have a lot of quite some leeway to accompany our clients given the high level of solvency we have reached now. And about the French Retail. There is a strong seasonality in the Retail banking, and especially in the third quarter, as a lot of clients are in holidays. They tend to be less active, so you should not compare linked quarters.</p>
          <p>We always refer to same quarter of the previous year, and the small decline you are observing was already there last year and the year before, I guess. So it's not &#x2013; the linked quarter's evolution is not significant in terms of trends. In terms of trends, I mean, we again, we are not &#x2013; I mean, we don't like to promise or to give indications too much. The business is very, very, I would say, regular, as you know, very stable, very steady. You can see that the production of new loans and outstanding amounts have gone up regularly over the last few quarters, which is a good indication for the future.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, it's very well known that the next &#x2013; the fourth quarter will be impacted by the increase of the regulated savings rates by 50 basis points we took the 1st of August, so the third quarter was already impacted, but only by during two months of the three, and the fourth quarter will be fully impacted. It will be the first quarter fully impacted by this increase, and this has some impact as well. So these are the kind of &#x2013; but we have to think about nuances, and overall we are confident to keep the bulk of the indication we had given at the beginning of the year as a target for the year, meaning regular and significant increase in the top line and a 1 point jaws effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's fair. So going back to the Basel III impacts, assuming  at 4%, 5% increase in risk-weighted asset growth, which is my estimate. In reality, the pro forma, common equity and Tier 1 2012 is not nearly 9%, but is somewhere between 8% and 8.5%, taking into consideration the risk-weighted assets. Would you agree in line of principle with these comments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you take these assumptions for risk-weighted assets, yes, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Brice Vandamme from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Just &#x2013; sorry, can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. No problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sorry. Just a few quick questions. The first one is the &#x20AC;316 million one-off gain you have incorporated from it seems some disposals which have an impact on the Fortis PPA. Could you just explain us more precisely what you sold, and should we intend to continue such disposals in the future? My second question is related to asset management. You still have a large amount of outflow, more limited than the previous quarter, but still &#x20AC;4.7 billion in Q3. Are you starting to see more stabilization in this field or do you feel that the deterioration may continue in the coming quarters? In terms of common equity Tier 1, I'm not sure I head the answer of this question which had been asked, I think, earlier, which basically what is the level of comfort for you in terms of common equity Tier 1? And finally, just having a look at your Corporate and Investment Banking activity. I was just actually looking at the financing business, and it's right that the revenue is really growing fast there. You are at plus 26% year-on-year still in Q3. This is strong. This probably takes into account an increase of margins. What kind of growth do you think you could generate going forward in this business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. As for Corporate, Investment banking, I start with the last one, but I don't forget the other ones, don't worry. We have &#x2013; what we've said in terms of Corporate and Investment Banking is that the financing business is representing a kind of relatively stable basis for that. We have now kind of firmly established above 1 billion revenues per quarter, and as far as the total is concerned, we have said that the relevant range for the quarterly revenues was between the 2.5 and 3.5 or something like that 2.4 and 3.4, which were the levels of respectively the fourth quarter and the third quarter of 2009. So the post crisis levels and first half of 2009 exceptional levels, we think that the end of the two last quarters of 2009 are setting the range for the current activities in CIB. And once again, it was the case in the third quarter of 2010, so this is the answer to your last question. Now about coming back to your other question about the exceptional capital gains we had. In fact, that a certain &#x2013; well, we inherited from Fortis, we inherited significant amount of securitized assets, and you'll remember that we selected them ourselves in the portfolio, so they are not of bad quality. We took the best stuff, and we left the other one in the out portfolio and we, nevertheless we adjusted the price, the entry price on our balance sheet at the time of the acquisition, as requested by the IFRS.</p>
          <p>And clearly, we took as an assumption that we would hold these assets until their maturity. What is happening now is that this quarter we had both some opportunities to sell a few of those assets because prices were recovering and we were reaching levels which we thought were reflecting the real value of the asset. And also and even more, I mean, more than two-thirds of the 316 is coming from prepayments, early redemption of those assets because, in general, in those assets you have the possibility for the issuer to pay or to buy back or to pay back the asset, and this is what happened. And in that case, of course, we had to amortize to make a kind of full amortization of the adjustments, the PPA adjustments for those assets. This is what happens. It's clearly a one-off, but it's indicated as such. On the asset management. Yes, the outflows in asset management are coming both from the money market mutual funds, which you know it's such low rates clients are less inclined to use money market funds, especially individual clients. But also we still have some outflows also on equity funds because of the aversion to the risk, which is shown by our clients at the moment.</p>
          <p>And so we, I mean, we know that while this is something, which is not pleasant, as far as money market funds are concerned, we think it may continue because beyond the low level of interest rates, all banks now all have a kind of structural inducement to try and attract direct deposits rather than selling mutual funds because the regulation, the new regulation in the making is going to require &#x2013; well, to penalize this way of collecting money, the indirect way of collecting money and to the contrary to give strong incentives to collect money directly from the clients. And so for those two reasons, regulatory changes and low interest rates, we think that the money market funds should keep need or they are reducing their outstanding amount for some time. On the equity side, the equity, we hope to see some rebound because the level, I mean, the markets seem to be a bit better oriented, precisely with very low interest rates, I mean, the attractiveness of bonds, funds of bond investments is lower and lower. So probably at some point, clients will come back to Equity. Equity is to remain on the long run remains a good investment on the long run. On the long run the program is intact.</p>
          <p>So that's all we can say at that time. We'll see, and we are doing, of course, our best to increase the inflows. You have noticed that overall we are flat in terms of new cash for the Investment Solutions division, but so the negative outflows of Asset Management are offset by inflows as well, especially in the Insurance business for the very same reason of risk aversion because life insurance is seen as a kind of safe harbor. Common equity Tier 1, on that, I am sorry, but I will repeat what I have said. I mean, we really think that our business model with its characterized diversity acts as a buffer against crisis, and this diversity, this diversification is not taken into account in the calculations, in the risk-weighted assets calculations at all. So with the same level of risk-weighted assets and the same level of capital, if you take two banks, one being like BNP Paribas, very diversified with half Retail, one-third on CIB and one-sixth Investment Solutions, and another bank, for example, a pure investment bank or an investment bank, plus a bit of investment solution or pure retail bank. Of course, the risk is not the same because if you are diversified, the probability of everything going on at the same time is low, and it provides you with a significant plus in terms of behavior in case of a crisis.</p>
          <p>And this is what happened during the simultaneous financial crisis we are going through, followed by a credit crisis and a more classic economic crisis in 2009, and you have seen that neither in 2008, nor in 2009 we have lost any penny. So we think that because of that, we deserve, BNP Paribas deserves a lower level of capital requirement than most of the peers, and this is why we don't think that we should target a level of common equity Tier 1 which would be higher than the minimum, the regulatory minimum.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It seems that you're targeting 7%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It means that &#x2013; it's not. It means that we are not going to target a higher level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you don't want to be above 7%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't want to be more precise than that. After that, the actual level will depend on a lot of factors, but we certainly don't want to oblige ourselves to be at the level which would be a precise level above the 7%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Pierre Flabb&#xE9;e from Kepler. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Philippe. I have a couple of questions. First is regarding the Personal Finance P&amp;L, quarterly P&amp;L. It seems that there is some sort of strange seasonality factor in the cost base because it's repeated, I think, Q3 last year, and so it seems to inflate a bit the earnings this quarter? Or am I wrong and is it the signal of the first clear improvement in this activity?</p>
          <p>The second point is there was already a question about that, but regarding the financing business in CIB. Could you give us some color about the trend on margins? Because we have some echoes that competition is back again there. Could you give us some color about the outlook for, not only for Q3, but &#x2013; Q4, sorry, but maybe the next quarter?</p>
          <p>And now, sorry, for my other as well on Basel III, but could you indicate to us what could be regarding BNP Paribas business model, the sustainable return on equity which would the group not to restrain on sizing growth opportunities under Basel III environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, concerning the cost of Personal Finance, I don't think there is a lot of particular things to mention. The only thing is that last year in 2009 because the cost of risk was rising and the environment was relatively adverse to consumer lending, capital finance took a very aggressive stance on cost, and cut cost in two ways, first by improving the structural way they were working, cutting cost with a few structural measures which are going to remain. But also, second, by cutting marketing costs aggressively, and putting less on new production of loan and low emphasis on recollection, which is understandable. This year, as now the cost of risk is trending down, as you have seen, and also the economy is recovering in certain spend off countries, and especially in the more big countries of PF, France, Italy, Germany. The PF is now resuming some marketing expenses, and this explains why this quarter, but it's something very punctual. I mean, this quarter, yes, compared with the third quarter of 2009, which was a trough of the expenses. The jaws effect is slightly negative, but on a nine-month basis, as you have seen, the jaws effects remains clearly positive, close to 2 points, if I am right. And clearly, the expenses are under control at PF. No problem to that point.</p>
          <p>On CIB financing businesses, it's true that the margins on new production are now under some pressure due to increased competition. You are perfectly right, and this is translating &#x2013; well, this is translating into the fact that on the outstanding loan portfolio, the margins have reached a kind of plateau last quarter and this quarter, if you want. And so, yes, they start showing a kind of a trend to being eroded, as the outstanding portfolio turnover effect is no longer exceeding the decrease in margin on new production. So this is the situation. And while on sustainable return on equity, well, we keep thinking that given the pressure which is put on the production of new loans and put on the banking supply, if you want, the supply of banking services by the new regulations, there should be a kind of mitigating effect on the revenue side, mitigating the increase on equity, which is now under 3 to conduct a business in the post-Basel III era. And so we keep thinking that the return on equity for a bank like ourselves, a bank that is not affected too much by the new regulatory environment due to our business model, a bank that is well adapted, if you want, through the aftermath of the crisis and through the new regulations. We think that the target, the return on equity target should not be that different from before, and so we keep saying that the 15%, which was our kind of reference point before the crisis, should remain a kind of target for us, probably challenging more than in the past, but should remain the target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Delphine Lee from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. I have a few quick questions. Just to come back again, sorry, on the securitization. You have put in of a sell or redemption that you had this quarter in terms of risk-weighted assets. I mean, do you &#x2013; is that mostly sell or is that most redemption? And do you think that you could have more to come from your assets which you acquired from Fortis?</p>
          <p>And secondly, on the PPA side for 2011 and '12, how much would you expect? And if number has changed since your last guidance because of early redemptions or not at all? And lastly just on risk-weighted assets in the investment bank. If you could give the capital markets number at the end of September? I mean, it's 84 billion end of June, but I guess that the FX had an impact this quarter, and maybe with all the sale of the securitization assets? And generally in the RE that you're expecting in Investment Banking under Basel III, what kind of level do you think you can achieve? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, I'll start with your first question, securitization. The 5 billion risk-weighted asset, of course, due to the weighting in terms of exposure, it's much less. It's something like probably 1 billion or 2 billion, something like that or even less. As I said, it's a combination of three things, in fact, a combination of some regular redemption because redemptions are occurring a little bit every quarter. And this is going to continue, of course, until the full redemption, but on top of that, we had few specific one-off effects this quarter, some selling and some early redemption prepayments.</p>
          <p>And while I think that the early redemption is representing probably something like it's less than half of the total, and this is clearly a one-off, and it's not from lack of control, I would say, so the possibility of selling is something we, while we may use again, it's really depending on the businesses, and we try and optimize the portfolio and clearly, while if we see decent prices we want to get to where we see the opportunity. So this could happen, but while it's not sure.</p>
          <p>And so I would say let's say more than one-half is completely &#x2013; a bit less than one-half is completely a one-off, probably something like 1% or 2% is more or less on a regular basis. And the rest may come or not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up question. What's the average maturity of your securitization portfolio? Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The average maturity duration of your portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maturity duration?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's rather long. I think it's probably something like probably, nominal &#x2013; the problem is that &#x2013; nominal is probably something like close to 10 years, I would say. I guess between five and 10 years. On the &#x2013; sorry, your next question about the capital markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, PPA, first. I had a question on PPA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and the PPA I'll go to. I'll start with the question on the risk-weighted assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So about the vibrant capital market. We have, well as of the end of September it's now representing something like $78 billion now. It has gone down to 78 billion. On the PPA, your last question about the PPA, could you repeat the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just what to expect for 2011 and '12, if any?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, the sure part of it is the regular amortization of the PPA of the banking group, which is representing at the moment around 160 or something like billion  per quarter. Should represent something like 700 gain, 700 billion in 2011. Probably slightly less, maybe well slightly less in 2012, and then there is a sharp decline, a sharp drop beyond 2012. This is this is the banking rule.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Robin Down from HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I'm sorry, back on the Basel III subject. It's very helpful the additional disclosure, but obviously it creates a couple of questions. Can I just ask Delphine's question about the maturity on the securitization position a slightly different way? Could you tell us how much of the 2.6 billion, and I know it's obviously shrunk since then, but how much of that 2.6 billion is likely to roll off the book over the next two to three years? The second question is on the 5 billion to 7 billion deduction. Could you tell us how much of that you think it's likely to be phased and how much it's likely to come in the 1st of January, 2013? And then just a final question, which is really just sort of trying to get a feel for how you're thinking about the capital. I noted your comments about not targeting a ratio higher than the 7% minimum number or whatever the minimum number comes about to be. But if we start from where you are today at the end of Q3, you've got a sort of 9% core Tier 1, and you're telling us that take those deductions and the risk-weighted asset impact of Basel III might be 200 basis points. So we'd back to 7% if you add Basel III with no phasing of deductions. But does that then suggest that the way you're thinking about your capital is that and anything you generate from here on in, in effect is going to be excess to likely requirements within the business from a regulatory perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I will start with the last question because it's the one I well understood. The line isn't very good, so I will ask you to repeat the two other ones, but let's start with the last one. Your reasoning is correct, I would say. It means that every capital we are generating from now is available to finance the risk-weighted asset growth. This is the way you can put it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now could you repeat your two other...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. I know Delphine asked the question about the average life of the securitization portfolio, which I think is a good question to ask because you've obviously got 30 odd billion of risk-weighted assets coming from the sub BB minus tranche. But obviously some of these securitization tranches can be very long in duration, so I was just wondering if you could perhaps tell us more in terms of the 2.6 billion, how much you might expect to roll off, just naturally mature over the next couple of years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I'm not sure I have this amount precisely in mind at the moments on that part, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the second question was on the 5 billion to 7 billion of deductions you've got. Can you tell us how much of that 5 billion to 7 billion is likely to be subject to phasing, i.e. to come through sort of 2014 to 2018 and how much is likely either the minority chunk in effect is going to come through in the 1st of January 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Everything is subject to phasing in. I mean...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One of your competitors is suggesting on the minority deduction that that won't be phased?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The minority deductions are going to be phased in as well I think. Everything is going to be phased in progressively, also the minority interest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The 100 basis point deduction that you're talking about in terms of the 5 billion to 7 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That in effect won't come on the 1st of January, 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, not at all. It's phased in...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to be clear...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's written on the slides, on the slide. I mean it's phased in progressively between 2013 and 2018.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But as we &#x2013; the figure is the aggregated figure for the whole payers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Yeah. Great. Okay. That's very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Maxence Le Gouvello from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Philippe. A few quick questions. The first question regarding the reduction of the Fortis corporate portfolios that was one of the targets of the &#x2013; at that time of the integration. Can you give us a little bit of element of where you are and how much you still need to &#x2013; you want to achieve on the financing?</p>
          <p>The second part, the second question will be on back to the financing into the Investment Banking. We are seeing a big jump of the loan for Q3, plus 10% on the quarter, which seems a little bit surprising for usually we see seasonality. Is there a specific sector that you have been active on? Third point on Ukraine. It seems to be back and willing to reopen the book. Can you confirm that statement, please? And last point, in terms of tax rate, it's another quarter with 30%. Is it the level that we need to stabilize for the future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, the tax rate. I start with the last comment and I come back. The tax rate, yes, 30% seems the kind of new sustainable level now, taking into account the new permit, the new scope of the group. On Ukraine, yes, we are in the process of a kind of deep restructuring, but it's true that we have selectively started to resume lending with mainly two, I would say two main kind of activities. One is lending to low call subsidiaries of international groups exporting or working in Ukraine. So this has been reopened and is running back normally now.</p>
          <p>And the other one is a very short term consumer loans where we have, well in Revnal without any currency risk where we have a promising start in terms of quality of risk. So we want to stick to an area, lending areas where the risk is low and lower than certain number of other activities we were also conducting before. Then the question, your second question was about...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Investment Banking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In &#x2013; sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The big jump of the loan book under Q3 into the financing plus 10% on the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give us a little bit of more color as to the driver, which sector?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's coming mostly from energy and commodity finance. Over Q3, we had a strong business demand is in in every region, as commodity markets are increasingly resilient and vigorous at the moment. And this is continuing. I mean, this is very strong at the moment. That is true.</p>
          <p>And it's relatively &#x2013; the same path is shorter. It's linked to in agree committee straight finance, but it has been extremely buoyant in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>And your first question was about reduction of the Fortis corporate portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that the bulk, yes, the bulk of it is already achieved now. In fact, it started early last year, in fact, very early last year, and by the end of last year, it had been already done to a large extent. And as of today, I think we can say that we are at the end. Reducing the loan portfolio is easier than building the new client portfolio, so we &#x2013; the kind of negative synergies, revenues, revenue synergies, the disynergy in revenue is due to the changing of the lending policy that come first. And we are now more in the phase where we are rebuilding the portfolio with the clients we want to develop.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just, Philippe, on the Robin question. As you said that all the results that you're going generate in the two coming years are going to be dedicated to growth of risk-weighted assets, all with potential that you do also acquisition. Are you still interested about Poland or it's more North Africa? Can you give us a little bit more color on that side? And also when can we expect to have the finalizing of the Turkish merger?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, your other question is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is regarding the finalizing of the Turkish integration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so this &#x2013; well in Turkey, I start with the easy part. In Turkey, we got all the &#x2013; not all, but that the authorization by Central Bank, which was for the merger of both banks. We are still in the process of collecting a few administrative authorizations, but it's well underway and we are in the process of quantifying the integration plan in detail, and so we are going to &#x2013; well, we hope to be in the position to close the deal early 2011, first quarter of 2011 and to stat the integration at that time. So it's going to be somewhat &#x2013; there will be a time lag of more than one year, I would say, with the rest of the Fortis integration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just on that one. That means that we can expect some further synergies from the Fortis deal on the back of the integrations of those two assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we are still &#x2013; the first wave of synergies we gave was without Turkey clearly. So the Turkish integration plan will generate some new synergies, and also some new integration costs. This is going to be disclosed by while releasing the year-end results. We expect to that at that time. Well, for the rest, I mean, we keep, well, you know BNP Paribas. We have a very disciplined acquisition policy, and when we are considering a target, we want not only the target to be, I would say, strategically important and strategically fitting into our setup, but also, we want the price to be in line with our financial demand, meaning both value creation.</p>
          <p>The return on invested equity has to be higher than the cost of capital target within three years, and also, the deal has to be acquisitive within three years. So you know that very well.</p>
          <p>So we keep doing that way, and of course, we are not sleeping, so we are looking at what is available, what is potentially for sale. So we had this opportunity in Poland. At the end, we were not the best bidder, but we are not excluding also of the five. That being said, we are not going to comment on each rumor, and so I don't want to elaborate more than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And also, sorry to keep on that one, but you said last year potentially the U.S. on the back of FDIC deal, roughly all the good deals have been done for the time being. So do you still believe that there is some opportunities in the U.S.? Or some...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know. They may arise. It's true that we had no opportunity to achieve something in the U.S. up to now, but I don't know for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Anke Reingen from Execution. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Anke from Execution. Sorry to come back briefly to the capital. I just wondered in terms of, as you said, your capital would be above &#x2013; and I understand there's uncertainty, but it would be above the minimum level. Would this also mean in terms of capital management, you mentioned acquisition, but might this also mean you might revisit some of your hybrids that you have outstanding? And then, secondly, with respect to systemic capital surcharge. Maybe I missed your comment, but what's your view in terms of will it be an equity surcharge? Or will it more be in the form of contingent capital over more debt instruments? And then just some number questions. I was wondering why your revaluation reserve in the equity base have come down? And then lastly, just on the cost trends in the French Retail banking operation, the cost should we expect for Q4 costs to remain seasonally high? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. About the hybrid, we are still waiting for the final rules about the new hybrids. The Basel Committee is still discussing, and it's not completely clear. What is &#x2013; obviously that at the moment, as the core capital is going up very fast, I mean, while the need for new hybrids is extremely low. In fact, it's nil because you are seeing that the total Tier 1 is already more than 11% or something like that.</p>
          <p>So we don't need to insure hybrids right now, and the former hybrids that are going to be grandfathered, and are going to be phased out according to a certain rule, which is going to ensure progressivity. And so most probably we'll resume the issuance of new hybrids once we know exactly the rules in order to be sure that we issue hybrids that are useful in the new context. And for the moment, we wait for this new regulation.</p>
          <p>As far as the systemic capital potential surcharge. I would like to come back on the very objective of the regulation. The first objective of the so-called Too Big to Fail reform is to reduce the likelihood of a crisis, and this has to be achieved, we think, through, first, through better supervisory oversight that is by right being put in place in Europe with the creation of the three European supervisory agencies, including the European Banking Authority. And also in the U.S. with the Dodd-Frank reform and a certain more of strengthening in the supervisory setup. So we think that's really a good supervision, the improvement of the supervision is the first thing and it's key.</p>
          <p>Then you will tell me that in case a crisis occurs, nevertheless, the second objective is to reduce the severity of the crisis, and we reduce the cost also for taxpayers. And we think that this has to be achieved through an improvement in collective discipline and then through consistent regimes across markets for the resolution of failed firms, including an efficient subordinated debt bail in framework. And also, better cross-border coordination and execution between supervisors.</p>
          <p>So we consider legitimate the introduction of the resolution procedures, including a transnational procedure for banks operating in national, in different countries like BNP Paribas. And also we think that the bail in process is very important, and we think it's legitimate that subordinated debt, including Tier 2, can be converted into capital in case of a crisis. That constitutes a question.</p>
          <p>We think it's more efficient than capital surcharge because it's less costly in normal times, and it provides a stronger, much stronger additional layer in crisis time. So this is why we advocate for this bail in system, and rather something which would be applied to all subordinated debt rather than specific instruments, because it would provide with a bigger buffer, which could be mobilized in case of necessity.</p>
          <p>And we &#x2013; well, we understand that this is going to be discussed in Seoul and further probably in the beginning of the next year. So I think it's too early to say what's going to be the outcome of this reflection.</p>
          <p>Then I missed your third question. Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It was on the valuation reserve and the equity base that came down from, I think, 1.4 billion to 800 million...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I thought everything would be positive in the third quarter, anyway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the dollar...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The dollar went down. It's because of the dollar. The big decline for 1.1 billion is due to the dollar. So everything went up, except for the foreign exchange differences, which went down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Neuez from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. I have three questions, please.</p>
          <p>The first question is on funding. My sense is you actually use quite &#x2013; only a little covered bond in your funding mix, as I can see from your slide. And I was just trying to understand how much free collateral is there on your balance sheet to be used? And I see you have quite a low CDS spread, but it seems to me that issuing potentially more covered bonds would probably even lower that over blended funded cost more. And I was just trying to understand what's the opportunity there?</p>
          <p>The second question is on BancWest. My sense is as follows. It seems to me that it's probably not benefiting from funding synergies from the group, given it's more or less self-funded. It looks like you can't extract much synergy there, at least from what I can see from the outside, whilst you have possible in market synergies in markets like Italy or closer to home when you can do multi-channel banking in emerging market possibly.</p>
          <p>Can you please explain again beyond diversification benefit what is the strategic rationale with BancWest compared to the last few deals, as you've contemplated like for a piece of BNL, where you're actually sure you're basically closing your factory there and all these things ?</p>
          <p>And the last question is on the flip year minority. I suppose this will cost quite a lot of capital, given if you don't even a Tier 1 ratio, I suppose, and I was wondering what was the plan there? And if you had any new consideration with regard to the new capital rules and these things? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Starting with the funding. The covered bonds, indeed we're presenting one-fourth roughly of our funding structure up to now.</p>
          <p>We &#x2013; and you have seen that we have made a step into your suggestion's direction, I would say, as we have that issued U.S. dollar-denominated covered bonds for the first time, meaning that we have raised dollars with euro assets. Because the U.S. dollar covered bond was covered with assets, domestic assets for us, I mean coming from Europe.</p>
          <p>So yes, we are &#x2013; well, we are conscious that covered bonds are sold at lower price that the non-covered bond, that unsecured bond, and we intend to increase the proportion of those bonds in the mix.</p>
          <p>That being said, in the policy, in the funding policy you have to accommodate the need of investors, and so you are not the only one choosing the characteristics of the issue. The investors have their say. And indeed, it's the size of the market which is limiting in practice the possibility of issuing covered bonds. But what we try to widen the investors' pool. And again, attracting U.S. dollar investors with euro assets is a promising new avenue.</p>
          <p>As far as BancWest is concerned. I mean, BancWest is a core assets for us for two reasons, the first one being that it's a retail bank, and as I said, as you know, we are really keen to keep more than half of our capital allocated to retail. And clearly, in order to balance our risk to keep a diversified profile and to also to be seen and to be clearly seen as a retail group primarily with big activities in CIB, one of the leading CIB franchises. But nevertheless, I mean, even for the CIB people, I would say it's a significant comfort to be in the big CIB within a big retail group rather than in the big CIB, true stuff. And clearly, in order achieve those 50% in retail, BancWest is a significant part of it, and so it plays a role in maintaining this balance.</p>
          <p>And even more tomorrow with the new rules, if you make the kind of a computation which now you can do by adding 70 billion to the CIB risk-weighted assets in the future regulation, you will see that the proportion of Retail banking between Basel II and Basel III, if you want, is going to be shrunk a little bit from 55% currently down to 50%. Because of cost, the CIB proposition will be increased by 70 billion, so we stick to 50%, but just 50%, so BancWest plays a role in maintaining those 50%. This is the first thing. The secondary thing is that &#x2013; so BancWest is a dollar-based, and we see how these questions are evolving in terms of dollar market versus the euro market, access of the dollar funding for euro-based bank. I have mentioned the covered bond, which is an encouraging sign. But clearly for us, having a dollar retail bank, a dollar deposit taker, may be a trump card in the future. Then your last question, sorry, I missed your last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's with regards to the potential treatment of your peer minority. I understand that this is possibly a full deduction, given you have a Tier 1 ratio, I suppose. I mean, is this my understanding? And I was just wondering whether that poses the peer minority in question again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we have taken that into account in the 5 billion to 7 billion we have mentioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Jon Peace from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, can I ask three quick questions, please? Firstly, it's in Equity and Advisory. Can you just give us an idea this quarter of what was roughly the split between Equity and Advisory? I asked because you kind of highlighted your Advisory revenues were quite strong this quarter. I just wanted to get a feeling of how much below a sort of normalized trend you thought Equities were in the third quarter? The second question is on the corporate center. You told us last quarter the clean revenues were of the order of 400 million to 500 million per quarter. If I adjust for the items you show as in the last slide, I work out 248 million for the third quarter this year. I just wondered what the reconciling items were? Whether you still stood by that earlier range for a sort of normalized run rate? And the final question is, and I apologize if I missed it, what were your total assets at the end of the third quarter? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the first question about Equity and Advisory. I think you should not exaggerate. I mean, Advisory is a strategic business because it provides you with contacts at the highest level in the company, and it's extremely key for generating business beyond M&amp;A, beyond Advisory. And you have seen, for example, that for a certain number of big deals, we are advising this quarter, at the same time we're also the arranger of the acquisition funding, but in terms of revenues, the bulk of the revenue is coming from the equity derivatives, clearly. So the Equity part is an overwhelming part of the revenues each quarter, and the Advisory part is a much, much smaller and much less volatile.</p>
          <p>As far as the corporate center is concerned, and what we had said, I mean, at the end of the second quarter you remember is that 400 to 500 was a kind of run rate, but for the first half quarter, because in the first half we had explained that there is a seasonally in the corporate center, and the first half revenues are structurally higher than the second half revenues. And so we had said that for the second half revenues, the run rate would rather be 300 to 400, so we are there. I mean, there is no significant gap between what we had said and what is achieved this year &#x2013; this quarter, sorry. Then the total assets. The total assets of the third quarter we are not posting any balance sheet in out quarters. Only twice in the year at the end of June, and the end of the year, sorry. It's probably lower than at the end of June, if only for U.S. dollar reasons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's fine. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our question from Kinner Lakhani from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, good afternoon. Wanted to start off with a kind of boarder question actually. Last week at the EU summit, there was a lot of discussion about a sovereign crisis resolution framework, and obviously burden sharing with the private sector. And clearly that seems to have triggered some pressure on the sovereign market, particularly in peripheries. What I was trying to understand is has there been or would there be any change in behavior of BNP about the ownership of non-core European sovereign bonds going forward? The second question was just to look at your group doubtful loans, and to basically try to understand the source of the increase that we're getting over the last couple of quarters, so where you're adding the doubtful loans? And I know the coverage ratio is coming down, but whether that's kind of a normal part of your budgeting? And my final question was kind of to do with Basel III, but not looking at capital, but thinking a bit more about the liquidity framework, how you see yourself positioned versus the latest kind of draft of the rules that we've got?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the sovereign, , well we aren't going to change our behavior at all. In fact, I mean, we keep thinking that in a given country the sovereign exposure is one of the safest. It's not the safest for a given country.  Of course, we are applying new limits to the different countries, and they are not all at the same level, but we keep thinking that for sovereign, a default is really &#x2013; it's not the solution. It's really something which occurs when there is no other solution. In extreme cases, in cases where either the country is a complete duldrone and in a very bad shape, very poor, for example, like the poorest emerging countries or in cases where you have a serial war or in extreme cases, and it's not the case for the Western European countries at all.</p>
          <p>So we think it make &#x2013; it extremely sounds that the European countries are building a framework in order to promote fiscal discipline between themselves and for each of them. I think it's an intelligent way to draw the lessons of the crisis. And I think that other countries in the world, I mean, may have run into trouble if they don't try to rein in their fiscal deficits as well.</p>
          <p>But it doesn't mean that &#x2013; it's not because you are trying and tackle a problem and addressing it for the future, that it's going to come back more often or going to become more acute. Quite the contrary. Quite the contrary. So this is why we, I mean, we have always had a policy of diversifying our risk, and selecting our risk and we are &#x2013; we are not going to change to that respect.</p>
          <p>And about the doubtful loans, yes, they are still going up. The increase is due to &#x2013; well, you still have some new doubtful loans in the different retail activities. Especially &#x2013; I mean in Italy, as you have seen. And also we had some &#x2013; well, kind of exceptional reclassification of some Fortis legacy assets from watch list to doubtful this quarter, assets which were already reserved within the PPA, in fact, so this is why the impact on loans was minimal. So this is what happened this quarter.</p>
          <p>We still have, I would say, one of the best coverage ratios of the industry with more than 80% coverage of the doubtful loans.</p>
          <p>About the liquidity rules, I think they are controversial, clearly. I think &#x2013; well, our view is that, in principle, it's useful to have both, I would say, one month's liquidity stress test &#x2013; the idea of checking that in case of a big liquidity crisis on your name, or in case of a systemic liquidity crisis, you are able to survive for one month.</p>
          <p>I think this makes a lot of sense. And by the way, we do it for ourselves already. We have models testing the group's capacity to withstand a liquidity crisis, and so we do apply already a strict internal liquidity ratio.</p>
          <p>And the same for the one-year plus &#x2013; the gapping ratio. I would say a ratio limiting the long-term gapping makes a lot of sense because you cannot finance your long term commitments with short term funding for long. It doesn't makes sense. I mean, it's fragilizing.</p>
          <p>So both ratios make sense in principle. Now, the only thing is that the way they are currently being proposed and they are currently being calculated in the proposed regulation is not really close to the actual risk. It's not matching the actual problem, and hence it's highly disputable.</p>
          <p>I understand that for the LSFR, the Basel Committee has realized that and is working again on it, so we'll get a new proposal somewhere by year end I haven't assumed of something like that , or the beginning of next year. So this is something, which, while I think they realized that it was not well designed, I would say.</p>
          <p>On the LCR, they have assisted and so we are in front of a ratio where in order to protect the liquidity and the survival of a bank, the bank is induced to hold a lot of government bonds because the government bonds are the only assets that are deemed to be liquid.</p>
          <p>So back to your first question. We should hold even more sovereign bonds, and of course, we don't think it's realistic, because &#x2013; especially because each bank &#x2013; naturally each bank will tend to hold more bond of its own sovereign, its own country.</p>
          <p>And everybody has seen during the crisis that when the rate of &#x2013; the liquidity crisis is in general is a confidence crisis. So when there is a confidence crisis on one country, there is also a confidence crisis on the banks of the same country. And so the banks are not going to be helped by the fact that they hold bonds of the country.</p>
          <p>So imagine the Icelandic bank with a lot of Icelandic bonds. I mean I don't think it would have helped them when the crisis came.</p>
          <p>So I think the ratio should be reviewed in such a way that the assumptions are realistic and really helpful in case of a crisis. So we'll see, anyway.</p>
          <p>The schedule is such that this ratio, the liquidity coverage ratio, is going to be put in observation for a period up to 2015. So during that observation period, I guess there will be opportunities to improve it, to fine tune it and maybe to amend it in such a way that it becomes a real tool for liquidity management. And so we'll &#x2013; well, I think we'll have time to discuss it again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Philippe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Antonio Guglielmi from Mediobanca. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Mr. Bordenave, and thank you for being patient and taking so many questions from us today.</p>
          <p>My first one is actually on provisioning in Q3. I noted three contrasting trends in these results. There is a significant quarterly improvement in loan loss provisioning at BancWest, pretty much flat trend in European Retail, France, BNS, Fortis and actually no write backs versus Q2 in CID. So the result is is likely increase at group level. My question is can you elaborate a bit more on what we should expect from this trend in the coming quarters?</p>
          <p>And my second and last question is actually on acquisition strategy. I understand you don't want to comment on Pal Bank, but at the same time, as you said, we all know that you are not sleeping. My question is therefore more on deal size.</p>
          <p>What I mean is, in light of the good guidance on capital you are providing today, would you limit yourself only to small cash acquisitions without stretching too much your capital, like Pal Bank for instance? Or should opportunities arise and should they tick your boxes in terms of criterion that you would eventually consider being more aggressive, financing bigger deals through raising capital, a la <mark type="inaudible" /> to be clear? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, well we don't try to comment on rumors. Definitely, I mean, it's not because something is small that we're going to buy it. That's for sure.</p>
          <p>We are taking a small, potential acquisition as in a very cautious way, as we do with bigger acquisition potential targets.</p>
          <p>One thing has to be kept in mind at the same time is that we are in the middle of the Fortis integration, so we cannot handle another big, big, big transaction, because it's already extremely, it's a lot of work. The whole bank is really working at this integration. Fortis was a big bank, a big international bank, and throughout the world, I mean teams are working in product integration.</p>
          <p>And so we cannot really &#x2013; we could not deal with a big acquisition. A very big acquisition, I mean. That's for sure.</p>
          <p>So this is what I can say to what you are saying. And we are more &#x2013; I would just add that we are extremely &#x2013; we &#x2013; for us, what is the most important thing is the quality of potential targets rather than the small size. I mean, if something is small, if it's not the proper quality, it's not going to be of interest for us.</p>
          <p>Now about the provisioning. On CIB, you are &#x2013; well, there is no write back on CIB at this time, but you should not expect a write back. I mean a write back is something exceptional and cannot be taken as a kind of target or something which would repeat itself.</p>
          <p>And we had said that clearly we think that the cost of risk at CIB is now going to be low. It's close to zero since the beginning of the year. It may be slightly below zero, above zero, but the significant buybacks are not something which are normal, but it should not increase back again, if you want. I think we're going to stay close to zero for some time.</p>
          <p>In terms of BancWest, yes, BancWest is improving, and should keep improving. And EU Retail, there was a kind of plateauing. We are now well &#x2013; we see the beginning of an improvement in France &#x2013; the beginning of a decline in the cost of risk in France. And we think that in Italy the plateau has been reached, but maybe the decline is not going to come immediately, but should be the next move.</p>
          <p>The next trend should probably be the decline, but we don't know exactly when. Probably by the next year than this year, which is not abnormal, and which &#x2013; because there is &#x2013; a kind that</p>
          <p>In Retail, the cost of risk is rising more slowly than in CIB. But then it stays high for a longer period as well, and comes down more slowly as well. So the movements are smoother, if you want, than in CIB. So this is what we can say for the next few quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question comes from Pierre Chedeville from CM-CIC Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. A quick question regarding your agreement with Natixis on the consumer credit business. What are exactly the terms of the agreement? What do you share together?</p>
          <p>And don't you fear to build a strong competitor because when you look at the market share of Natixis and consumer credit in France, it's less than 3% or around 3%, but in the meantime the network represents nearly 20%, so there's a huge gap between both. So don't you fear to advent to build a strong franchise that may be a fierce competitor against you like we do, for instance, India crossing this way with the Chinese?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's more about cost cutting through &#x2013; I would say economies of scale, if you want. The two groups have decided to establish a long-term partnership in the form of an industrial alliance. We are the personal finance on the BNP Paribas side, and Natixis Financement on the Natixis side. But each of them will continue to operate the same policy in a completely independent manner.</p>
          <p>So the goal is to be a build a first rate common IT platform to manage consumer loans who caters for the development objective to provide the level of performance that is necessary to be in line with the market's requirement, and to do all that by cutting cost for each partner due to the economies of scale.</p>
          <p>So normally, the target is that as of the 1st of January, 2013, this IT platform should be up and running and should be used to manage all consumer loans, repayments and revolving loans, both, of BNP Paribas and of the Banque Populaire, Caisse d'Epargne networks. So it's a significant amount of loans. It will represent significant proportion of the French market, and it would provide both groups with economies of scale. This is the purpose we have here.</p>
          <p>Okay. If there is no other questions, we can close the conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That will conclude today's question-and-answer session. I would now like to turn the call back over to Mr. Philippe Bordenave for any additional or closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I have no closing remarks, just to thank you for your patience because it lasts two hours, and well, to say bye-bye and see you next time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the call of BNP Paribas 2010 third quarter results. Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>