<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1154431" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-05-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7818</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Philippe Bordenave, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">Maxence Le Gouvello</participant>
      <participant id="3">Philippe Bordenave</participant>
      <participant id="4">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="5">Christoffer Malmer</participant>
      <participant id="6">Cyril Meilland</participant>
      <participant id="7">Pascal Decque</participant>
      <participant id="8">Pierre Flabb&#xE9;e</participant>
      <participant id="9">Philip Richard</participant>
      <participant id="10">Guillaume Tiberghien</participant>
      <participant id="11">Mamoun Tazi</participant>
      <participant id="12">Pierre Chedeville</participant>
      <participant id="13">Antonio Guglielmi</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the presentation the BNP Paribas 2008 First Quarter Results.  For your information, this conference is being recorded. Slides of the presentation are available on the BNP Parbas Investor Relations website at www.invest.bnpparibas.com. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand the call over to Philippe Bordenave, Chief Financial Officer.  Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Hello, everybody.  Thank you for listening.  I'm not going to read all the presentations through.  I think, I mean it's a little bit like when you take a guided tour in a museum, would be a little bit too boring to stop in front of each painting, so I will maybe drive you and will stop only in front of a few slides.</p>
          <p>Maybe I'll start on slide six which is something of an overview of the revenues of the different business lines.  Just to stress that, of course, all the retail banking business side has enjoyed an increases in their revenues.  Quite significant one in the case of International Retail Services, IRS, which is one of our growth achievements as you know.  But also AMS has enjoyed a smooth but positive increase in revenues which is quite good. And as far as CIB of course which is in the clients most impacted by crisis.  We nevertheless have a level of revenues which is comparable with the fourth quarter of last year even if the price has been much, much stronger and fiercer than in the first quarter especially in March than at the end of last year. So overall, solid revenues in front of the crisis.</p>
          <p>If we move now down to the slide eight about the costs, I would like to stress the flexibility of our costs with of course main explanation being the flexibility of CIB costs with, one, the mechanical aspect, mostly the mechanical aspect of variable compensation, the bonuses, with of course in BNP Paribas expenses are variable, and so we in that quarter they are very low.  And also, but it's not very significant at this stage, it will be a little more in the next quarters, some targeted right sizing.  We have started to implement in certain areas which are the most affected by the crisis.  But in our case it's necessarily of a limited size and it's the kind of measure which is bearing fruit with the lapse of time because at the beginning you have some severance costs.  So the bulk of the reduction in costs here in CIB is coming from the mechanical effect of the bonus adjustments.</p>
          <p>If we go now to, going down further in the P&amp;L to slide ten, with the cost of risks, I would like to stress that overall the cost of risks remain contained.  In France you see that we are, well we have a very low level and very sound portfolio in France with the cost of risk which is at 12 basis points and further down from already low level of 2006 and 2007.  So it means that we are really &#x2013; we keep focusing on the quality of the portfolio and we are very keen not to boost the top line with no reduced risk.</p>
          <p>In BNL bc stable. In IRS, we of course have some rise at BancWest but not that huge and we'll come back on that. In personal finance, we have some higher customer rates in Spain as we had already said in the first quarter by releasing the first quarter results and so it continues. And more generally, we have some impact of the development of the consumer finance business abroad and eventually in some emerging counties like Brazil where the cost of risk is structurally very high. And in CIB, I'd like to stress that in CIB the cost of risk is not very huge.  I mean we are, of course, it's a small million provision coming after right back in the first quarter of 2007 last year, but it's a sign of change; but nevertheless, it's not such a huge amount as shown by the figure in terms of proportion of the risk-weighted assets which is 11 basis points, which is not big.</p>
          <p>Moving to the kind of summary of all of this on slide 12. We are very proud to see all divisions contributing profits this quarter, even CIB in the quarter where clearly the crisis has reached a kind of climax in March with extraordinary violence and nevertheless, CIB is contributing positively at 300 million like in the fourth quarter of 2007. And I insist that this doesn't include the own debt revaluation, which we have credited to the corporate center which is &#x2013; I mean which seems to be, we think, appropriate relevant place for such an impact which is coming from the debt of the whole company. So a robust model again, say evident by what happened in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Now if we try to look a little bit in more detail in certain business lines, maybe I would like to comment on the French retail banking on slide 15. Just to insist on the fact that we have very good, very strong sales and marketing drive we enjoyed &#x2013; I think it's interesting to look at the chart on slide 15 because it shows that the rate intermediation is under progress I'd say.  With the deposit growing now over one year faster than the loan and both growth rates being double digit growth rates, so very, very robust and sustained growth rate. But the 12.7%, I think, deposit growth is very interesting because it shows that we &#x2013; I mean, both that there are opportunities for retail networks and speaking that for banks like ourselves with a very strong client franchise, is the opportunity to increase the deposit bank spend of course, the revenues as well, and it explains &#x2013; this increase explains a lot of the good evolution of the net interest income.  And of course, this kind of random addition, increasing net interest income on the deposit side because we take a margin of course on each deposit.</p>
          <p>And within those 12.7% increasing deposit there is a significant increase in side deposits which are even better because they're for free.  And you have seen that it's a 7.4% increase in side deposits is something which is quite strong.  We are over-performing the market.  And it's a base which is &#x2013; which keeps being strong quarter-on-quarter compared with the fourth quarter of the seven &#x2013; it's 1.5% positive.  So meaning that four times that makes 6%, so it's the same kind of strong yearly trend, even if you take the most recent trend, and this is the really crucial, I think, the crucially issue particularly these days I would say where the ability of gathering deposits, especially high deposits of course is something which is extremely important.  And so I think it's very key for us and it's a real satisfaction.</p>
          <p>This good development of the client franchise is also evidenced by the number of new check and deposit accounts, 60,000 for the quarter, which is also a very, very good level, very good number.  And this, I would say, in the context where, of collectively also good performances in terms of asset gathering because we are thinking on the fact that the life insurance asset inflows.  Even if somewhat lower than first quarter of 2007, which had been a record quarter for all the markets and for ourselves in particular, I mean nevertheless it's at minus 4.5% where the market is at minus 10% and some of our competitors even lower than that so we have over performing asset gathering.  And nevertheless, increasing quite significantly, the debt was obviously decided earlier, something which is very good, very promising for the future.</p>
          <p>On the next slide on page 16 about BNL, so we have released the increase of expected synergy this was a move which was somewhat expected by you I guess because we were ahead of the schedule so the natural question was are we going to be able to break the level of synergies and so yes by 15%.  So we are going to before the end of 2009 I'd say we are going be able to achieve and to take it to our account 550 million total synergies which is an increase of &#x20AC;70 million .  Both cost synergies mainly in BNL banca commerciale and revenue synergy 21 mainly in the other side.</p>
          <p>Now I'm moving to into International retail services.  I would like to comment on BancWest.  I will answer your questions if you have questions but because the activities, other businesses, and IRS but I would like mostly to comment on BancWest.  To on slide 19 just to tell you that while BancWest is in the U.S. was half of the crisis to a certain extent and so a number of you are aware maybe a little surprised by the prospect book for BancWest and would be overly happy about BancWest.</p>
          <p>I think that this quarter is showing that BancWest is running relatively well. We have a strong sales and marketing drive. The outstanding loans are growing helped by the I would say plus $0.10 around per year in dollar. The fees are up as well, plus 6.8% is quite good in the U.S. and the fact that the short term interest rate has been cut quite aggressively by the Federal Reserve. We &#x2013; the yield curve is now back to a normal shade and so it is a better environment for a retail community bank like we have in the U.S.</p>
          <p>So we have seen the net interest margin is much less eroded than would be the case a few months ago, almost stabilized and so we are able to post, let's say a positive evolution of the revenue in dollars plus 8.6% which is much better than what we have seen over the last few quarters. So it's a positive evolution. Of course, we still have a cost of risk which is high, due to a kind of tail effect of the impairment from the investment portfolio. So you know that when you have an investment portfolio and you start carrying and number of lines you have to mark them to market precisely &#x2013; you can't take a buffer, you have to mark them to market, strictly to market which means that if the market prices are going further down you have to follow and so the &#x20AC;35 million  are the kind of the tail effect of the impairment we have seen, the 131 million impairment we have made in the fourth quarter of 2007 and we have also added a provision of portfolio basis linked to the real estate sector in order to take into account the overall deterioration of the real estate sector in the U.S.</p>
          <p>So the risk remains relatively high in BancWest at the time, but after all and after cost of risk you have seen in the appendices that the pre tax results of BancWest is &#x20AC;851 million  which is fourth quarter and even if you multiply that by four it makes kind of return on equity of 26% which is pre-tax, which is not far from the average of the group. So, even in such a bad failure in the U.S. BancWest is faring relatively decently, I would say, and everybody knows that the U.S. economy is cyclical and there are very good periods and bad periods. I think at the moment we are more in a bad period, so being able to post 26% return on equity in such a quarter, I think it is a decent and promising performance for BancWest.</p>
          <p>Now, if I go to the next core business, Asset Management and Services, I would like maybe to comment on Slide 24. Especially about the asset inflows we had good net inflows I think that beyond the falling equity market and beyond the fall in the dollar that the net asset inflows are the most predictive factor or sign for the future, Well, we had a slightly negative asset inflow in the Asset Management, the pure Asset Management activities mostly from equity funds, out of equity funds due to the drop in equity prices.</p>
          <p>And the money market funds were collectively positive inflows so this is good because you remember that towards the end of last year the money market funds were in negative flows, so we are now back to solid plus 3 billion inflows. But we have seen some of our clients moving out of the equity funds and back into money market funds.</p>
          <p>And apart from asset management everything is very positive and I would like to stress the very good performance of the Private Banking business, very strong growth in asset inflows &#x20AC;3.4 billion which is the very good in such a quarter, really. And I think it's showing, really, that our clients' funds side in private banking is growing and it is still very encouraging.</p>
          <p>Moving to Corporate and Investment Banking on Slide 25. I would like to stress that while we had 1.3 billion revenues, but as you can see in the chart up the clients' revenues were very good again, with a plus 16% as compared to the first quarter of 2007. So, this is also very encouraging. We are not seeing any slowdown in the clients' business; quite the contrary, and so even if the positions on the books were difficult to manage during that period, and it's explained in the next slide. And I can come back on that if you have technical questions about the management of derivative books, Even if it's more difficult to manage and even if we saw we had some trading losses, we see that the underlying client flows are there and very strong. And this is very good.</p>
          <p>Again I insist on the fact that we have not offset the fair value adjustments by the gain on our own debt &#x2013; because we have recorded that in the corporate center. And so this is a very clean result, I would say. Very clean revenues. We hold the negatives and no positives, exceptional.</p>
          <p>On the expenses, I have already commented about the flexibility of our CIB bonuses. And on the cost of risk I would like to stress that in the 54 million provision of this quarter we have 94 million provisions linked to market counterparties which means that in the financing businesses we are still enjoying a write-back. Meaning that our loan portfolio at this stage remains very healthy and we are just have to face into the turbulences of the market and some counterparty risks are materializing in the market businesses.</p>
          <p>Now, moving to Slide 28 we have tried to make a step back and to look at what happened since the beginning of the crisis and we are proud to be one of the very few CIBs to remain profitable every quarter since the beginning of the crisis and to have a total of nine months a total of 1.4 billion pre-tax income which while very risky, still caught all the markdowns and so on which is quite nice especially to take into consideration the fact that from the first quarter we are ranked at third and the two others from the list have not reported March results. I would say, and March really was the climax of the crisis, so we, I think, in terms of comparison, I think &#x2013; and once again, we index our CIB model is more resilient than a lot of others. You remember that we had published a few quarters ago, we had published a comparison of the quarterly volatility of CIB results and it was before the crisis, good failure and it was already showing that we were among the less volatile CIBs in the business, which remains volatile, of course.</p>
          <p>During the crisis, it's even more clear, even clearer that we have a resilient and stable, but then we see which is a mix of the fact that we are client driven bank, CIB and that we have a favorable business mix base mostly on derivatives and a few global franchises and some &#x2013; well, we are not in the crisis most affected businesses and we have also a favorable geographic mix I would say with a low volatility, lower exposure to the U.S. and higher exposure to Europe and Asia and also it's due to our stringent policy which is of use and why we are very well known to the &#x2013; conservative in terms of risk taking.</p>
          <p>And to conclude I would like to draw you to Slide 29 about liquidity because the crisis is clearly a great number of liquidity issues, of course a number of competitors. I think that it is extremely interesting to see that the BNP Paribas AA rating is not only a matter of being proud of I think a good rating, but it's also of money because you see that the CDS spread is extremely low, and in fact we are hand in hand with Rabobank which is, all the Triple-A and other well-rated banks in Europe. And we, I mean it's clear that here we are good the 5-year CDS because it's something which is comparable and which is easily comparable from one to another, but you have to bear in mind that in the real life what is the most important is the cash spread because it's about raising money, cash. And in the cash market, as the price is coming from the cash market from the fact that people are selling and so the profit is led by the cash market. The price in the cash market &#x2013; the cash market even wider than what you see in the CDS risk, and so the spreads are wider; and the difference between the banks are also bigger than it is in the five years CDS spread.</p>
          <p>So we have the real competitive advantage and we were able to raise &#x20AC;16 billion with comparable rates, good conditions since beginning of the year which means that we are able to keep growing and serve ourselves even in those very difficult periods.</p>
          <p>So this is what I wanted to tell you as a kind of introductory remark, and now start answering to your questions. So you have the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Philippe Bordenave.  Ladies and gentlemen, the question and answer session will be conducted electronically.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We will now take our first question from Maxence Le Gouvello from Morgan Stanley.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Maxence.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.  I will have just three questions.  The first one is regarding the investments in the French retail.  I would <mark type="inaudible" /> yourself the permanents on the loans on the deposit side of the corporate, if you can give us more granularity on that one?</p>
          <p>The second question would be on the private banking.  There is very good inflows, but can we have an idea of is it domestic or is it &#x2013; which part of the world it's coming from, Asia or the offshore business?  And the last one is can we have an additional comments regarding the fall of the equity business in Q1?  There has been many banks losing a lot of money at the end of March on the equity derivatives. Many <mark type="inaudible" />.  Can you please give us an idea how your derivative business has been over the month of March?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  We'll start with the French retail.  I think we should try to go to the slide where you have the volume, slide 37, where you have the French retail banking volume.  On the loan side, you see that the corporate loans are growing by 15% at &#x20AC;50 million.  In fact it's the combination of both sustained volume, in both investment loans and also the treasury loans and I would say that as far as we are concerned, the main difference is coming from the treasury loans as the investment loans were already relatively sustained at last year.</p>
          <p>What happened is that there's a still strong demand for investment loans, they have been reinforced by a recovery in the treasury loans outstanding growth, with part of that coming probably from the fact that market funding is becoming more difficult for, I would say, the highest layer of our corporate clients, and they have &#x2013; to a certain extent, they have to come back to us, if you want.  But I think, and compared with the market it's also, we are over-performing the market.  It means that it's also, I think, due to our position as the main bank for <mark type="inaudible" /> part of our corporate clients and the results also of our new sales organization where we have corporate centers which are entirely dedicated to corporate and even if, as you know as well, even if we are not trying really to increase those volumes of loans, which is not our first priority &#x2013; our first priority being the cross selling, as you know &#x2013; but it's clear that loans corporate is an essential part of the relationship and so we are happy to be able to help our clients that way and to have this healthy growth in volumes.</p>
          <p>On the deposit side, we are not giving the breakdown between corporate and individuals, but in <mark type="inaudible" /> terms I can tell you that the good evolution of the cheque and current accounts, beside deposits, is coming from both the corporate and the individual, and I think that this good evolution of the relationship with corporate is also bearing fruit on the deposit side.</p>
          <p>Moving to your second question about the private banking volumes, we have &#x2013; well, out of the 3.4 billion net inflows we had a positive &#x2013; France is representing more than one third, in fact &#x20AC;1.3 billion so it's more than one third, and outside France it's 2.1 billion, the balance, and it's coming mainly from &#x2013; well, it's coming mostly from four parts. Asia is doing fine, very fine; we have also good performance in Italy which is a normal evolution, I would say, of the integration of P&amp;L, and the development of private banking in Italy, which is at the very beginning, at its inception I would say, but it's starting well; and we have also a good performance of our European offshore centers in Switzerland and Luxembourg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just back to the France private banking, have you seen some, I would say, exceptional outflows, specifically due to the difficulties of one of your competitors on the domestic market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't like to comment that way on competitors.  Sorry, I'm not going to answer to your question.</p>
          <p>Now, in coming to your questions about equity derivatives. I think we have to have a look at the Slide 6, where we are explaining the unfavorable market context and clearly, you're right.  Clearly it's about March, and what we have seen in March was something we never saw in the back of the States, really, a climax in the prices. And not only in the credit market but also in the stock exchange market, because what we have seen is that we had a kind of &#x2013; not only a high volatility, which after all is something which is rather favorable for an equity-directed business &#x2013; but from one day to another the volatility itself was ascending very fast.  So it's the volatility of the volatility, it means that the implicit volatility &#x2013; if you look at the implicit volatility in the product which are traded &#x2013; this implicit volatility was changing very rapidly from one day to another and this was really very difficult to manage.</p>
          <p>The other thing is the correlation between, in general, if you have a market index which is moving, take the whatever, the S&amp;P or whatever, which is moving let's say close to 1%, in that index you have some underlying stocks moving by 2 or 3%, others by zero or even negative.  And one is just average of a pack which gives relatively &#x2013; <mark type="inaudible" /> itself.  And what happened in this period was that all the underlyings were moving the same way and by the smallest, the same amount, and so very low [deflection.  And even the different indexes were moving the same way.</p>
          <p>And this kind of lack of deflection is something which is extremely penalizing in the management of our equity-directed books because structurally, due to the kind of product we are selling, we are helped, we are naturally helped if there is some recession in the different underlying components of the indices.  Plus the fact that this is really related more to January, well depending, January, February that if we had this money possibly in January, we had a big drop in dividends, which were not expected at all, and you know that structurally we are long dividends.</p>
          <p>Our long dividend expectations I would say when we are, for example, sur ligne, POA guaranteed plan or similar structured product, the client is implicitly giving us the dividend which is in the product.   We are taking the dividend and we are delivering the performance, and by &#x2013; we are planning to launch the dividend evolution in the management of the books, and clearly we had some unexpected fall in dividends this quarter.  And so those are the most, I would say, the three main factors which are explaining the fact that beyond the equity derivatives themselves, even if they're not directly affected by the credit crisis, they were affected by the market some more in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in light of the <mark type="inaudible" /> have you changed your way of managing the business for the coming months, as we are still in a very shaky period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not &#x2013; I would say not significantly.  Some positions have been reviewed, but this is something which is very flexible and may change from one day to another, but not significantly.  I think really that what happened in March is truly exceptional &#x2013; thank God, I think April was quite different, and I think it's reasonable to expect that we're not going to see other months like that before long.  And so you can't adapt just because you have gone through the storm.  So, once the storm is over you just resume your normal course of business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Kian Abouhossein from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions. The first one is on BancWest. Could you tell me how big your homebuilder exposure is at this point and how much you have written down so far in homebuilder exposure?  The second question is on fixed income revenue. You had the very useful Investor Day, where you gave a bit of a split interest rate derivative; FX derivative's a big part of that. Can you tell me roughly what advantage would come from that revenue line and if you're talking about record levels in the first quarter of 2008 for FX derivatives rates derivatives? And thirdly, Slide 27, you break down kind of a regional split of the revenues. Asian emerging markets, if you could give some indication how much it's related to equity, fixed income and financing? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay so, the home builder at BancWest. You can go to Slide 45 where we can get indexes and where we are giving some breakdown about BancWest portfolio. So we are spending that the home-builder sector is part of what we call a commercial real estate and in the commercial real-estate portfolio, half is about loans to condo buyers and the exposures to the home-builder sector is relatively limited, in fact it's &#x20AC;1.2 billion , there is a strong effect, in the line which is 1.9 billion, so our commitments are at &#x20AC;1.9 billion  but only 1.2 billion are drawn at this stage and this is the home builder. We have provisions as a kind of on a portfolio basis, if you want something like overall close to 100, I think 100 million or something like that which was done last year.  Yes, &#x20AC;97 million , exactly last year as a kind of provisional portfolio basis because up to now we have not yet seen any significant charge off.   But it's clearly an industry which is fertilized by the crisis so we are expecting to suffer some losses.  But for now it has not yet occurred, but we have these 100 million provisions on a portfolio basis.  They're low ones for the portfolio basis which is here in order to say the detachment if necessary.</p>
          <p>The fixed income, was yes we have given one for the sake of the investors there, we have given more detail than usually.  But by definition because of the exceptional day.  So we are looking to give that every quarter.  Sorry.  What I can tell you clearly is that you can imagine &#x2013; I guess you know &#x2013; is that the total of interest rates, derivatives and fixed-income derivatives revenues, is higher than the total of fixed income because from the credit side it's negative as you can imagine.  So the results are very good, I would think.  In interest-rate derivatives and fixed-income derivatives in the &#x2013; because in a good market for the full market and &#x2013; which we have started our concerns.  We are pleased with the results which have been amazed by these activities.  But I'm not going to disclose the figures quarter to quarter.</p>
          <p>The original split of the Slide 27 &#x2013; we can go back to Slide 27.  Now you would like some flavor of the breakdown by businesses or &#x2013; it's &#x2013; I don't have that here with me.  What I can tell you is that we &#x2013; I don't think there is a significant difference, I would say, in terms of proportions between the market activities and the financing activities depending on the region, let's say, we are very active in Asia, also in France in activities in trade finance, in project finance, in shipping you know, across finance that's all.  We sometimes energy and commodities finance.  So also in France in activities, we are strong in Asia and in the emerging countries.  But we have also and in the gulf yes within the Asia and emerging countries you have the gulf of course and in the gulf, you have energy and commodities finance, so obviously, Russia as well. So I don't think we can say that the Asia would be overweight market activity, neither North America no I think it's more or less the same proportion I don't have the precise figures in mind, but I don't think there is a big difference in proportions financing activities such as market activities within the different regions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful if I may ask a follow-up just on French retail as well.  You had very good growth deposits and lending volumes seemed to hold up quite well.  Is that the trend you are seeing throughout the quarter and you expect that this trend can continue specifically lending growth or do you think even deposit can accelerate that people become more cautious and put money into deposits do you see any change dealt up in these growth numbers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know, the future is always difficult to assess, no? Of course, but in retail activities there is a kind of stickiness in the behavior of clients.  So in general the trend of the latest quarter, the latest trends are remaining, there is a kind of stickiness, it is changing less fast than in the bigger corporate and investment banking.  So yes, I would tend to think that the recent trends should continue but I can't tell you more than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Christoffer Malmer of Goldman Sachs.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon. Chris Malmer here from Goldman's. I had two questions please.  First one is just wondering if you can give us any indication of the potential positive implication on your CIB revenues in the quarter from the fair valuation of your EDS positions, the ones that you've been building for protection against a corporate-loan portfolio, if any magnitude?  And also if there's any indication well how much of that has actually been realized by &#x2013; you've closed those decisions?  Any color you can provide us on that element in this quarter would be helpful.</p>
          <p>Second question, again to the extent that you want to make any incremental comment to your CO this morning.  On the topic of SocGen, now I was just trying to understand.  You obviously referring this to the financial criteria that you're using.  Now it is just from really an outside point of view, given your valuation and your relative out-performance versus September of about 20% since the start of the year, including today.  It's quite easy to actually get the numbers to work, just mathematically, actually without synergies.  Should we assume that actually the market uncertainty is an important factor in your decision-making process as well?  And as long as we have got a turmoil lack of visibility, this is not the time to undertake merger of that size?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Christoffer.  For about CIB we have very low positive impact of CDS position for the very simple reason that remember we had very low level of CDS's.  In fact the kind of hedges we had put in place over the last few years were mostly made of sensitive securitization.  And there was reason, mostly in order to optimize the capital usage under Basel I.  And so then, I mean the impact in P&amp;L is very limited &#x2013; has always been limited in both ways, and especially this quarter.  So it's negligible, if you want, compared with &#x2013; it's very negligible.  On the SocGen, while I'm not going to elaborate on what I said this morning, we have made a very clear statement, which is a relatively recent statement.  It was in March, if I am right, and where we said that the conditions were not met, realized a shareholder value-creating merger.  Given the street acquisition discipline we have.  And the acquisition to explain we remind you that for any kind of acquisition we have the two aspects: the price aspect, the value creation for our shareholders, and the execution risk aspect also.  I'm not going to elaborate more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Cyril Meilland of Lehman Brothers.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon.  I have three quick questions I think.  The first one is you're in a kind of paradoxical situation of having probably the lowest capital base of the four main French banks now and then showing the best rating.  Is there any kind of pressure from regulators to increase your sale-on ratio above your 7.5% target possibly to 8%?  And do you intend going forward to retain a bit more profit just to strengthen your balance sheet?  The second question is regarding the cost in retail banking in France. There seems to be a very nice development in the cost base i.e. down from Q3, Q4 last year?  I don't quite remember whether there were some one-off items, but would you say that the first quarter should be taken as a reasonable run-rate for the cost going forward?  And the last question is regarding the spread in France, and you emphasized the very nice development in your net-interest income.  This is due to as you said the funding mix but it's very near positive impact from the credit side as well and so could you give us some granularity about this in the different lending markets?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Cyril.  So just about the capital base, I would like to strike that, it seems to me collectively &#x2013; well, it's not a contradiction to see that we are the best-rated bank and also the bank with one of the lowest capital base.  You understand that it's precisely because the demand from regulators and rating agencies is depending on the kind of quality of the portfolio of activity, and the regulators and the rating agencies clearly when they assess the capital needs for BNP Paribas, they take into account the fact that we &#x2013; well, the business links we have, the diversification of activities we have, they're relatively, the lower risk, yes, I mean we have.  The fact that we are always among the less risky banks whatever the business segments you look at, we are one of the less risky banks with the lowest of the risk. As with lower exposures and so it's normal to boast to give us a high rating and to ask for lower, sorry, I hear something in the phone, no.  I keep going.  So it is not contradictory.</p>
          <p>Second, I would like to say that we are referring to a 7.5% target which is not, well, not the target like we have said.  We have said that under Basel I, we had targets of 7%, which had been set, and for Basel II, we have said that during this kind of interim year of 2008, as we are still working half and half, Basel I, Basel II, because the flow of 90% of the Basel I restricted  assets is still keeping us in the  Basel I, world and while we are in fact living in the  Basel II world, and the businesses are living now in the  Basel II capitalization.</p>
          <p>So because we are in that interim plan, and also because we don't know yet very well the how the  Basel II ratio is going to evolve because it's supposed to be more, you know, cyclical &#x2013; pro-cyclical than  Basel I ratio.  So we want to take a kind of period to assess before assessing the new target. So we have not disclosed any new target.  We are in the kind of observation period.  And so at this stage we have no pressure &#x2013; to come to the question itself, we have no pressure to increase anything at this stage.  I think we have &#x2013; I think as well, we have completely adequate level of capitalization, and you know, the best way to evidence that, is that we are able to fund our organic growth and even the small acquisitions we are making with our own capital generation, which is I think the sign that it is perfectly healthy.  So this is your first question.</p>
          <p>The second question about the cost base of the French network. There is some seasonality in the cost base as you have seen in the past, so I don't think you can take the first quarter and divide by four.  What we think is that we, as you know, we are very keen to deliver the one point positive growth effect as far as the French retail banking is concerned.  And clearly this year, even if the 4% growth of the revenue line remains a kind of a trend, a multi-year trend for the next few years which we confirm, we think that this year we are not going to reach it after the first quarter, and due to the crisis mostly.  And while we're not going to directly or indirectly, due to the crisis, we're not going to retreat and probably we will be closer to 3% this year in terms of revenue growth.  So, we are keen to curb the cost as well, and the cost growth we have achieved this quarter of 2.2%, and we are going to try keeping to curb it further in terms of growth compared with last year in order to achieve a full 1 point growth effect during the year, even if the top line is growing only at 3% or around.</p>
          <p>Now, your third question about the net interest income &#x2013; the net interest income in France?  Yes, it's coming from the funding.  On the credit &#x2013; on the asset side, we're not seeing significant widening in the spread between France and the States.  On the mortgage loan, we have seen a slight improvement, but it was coming from a level which was completely not reasonable, very, very low, an exaggeration just before the crisis.  So the small improvement we're seeing since then is not by any means providing us with a satisfactory situation.  So we still have very low margins in the mortgage market. We have too low margins as far as the corporate loans are concerned; really we see a very strong &#x2013; we have not seen in the corporate market in the retail the same &#x2013; we have not seen the same kind of correction &#x2013; widening correction which is visible in the big CIB international market.  And in the consumer lend loans &#x2013; well, it will be the same, there is no significant improvement.  So, we can't say that there is a widening in the margins in the French retail bank. So, the improvement is again on the net interest, it is coming mostly from the resource side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if we extend this question to the large corporates in France and Europe in your <mark type="inaudible" /> business &#x2013; you were mentioning that the large corporates were finding it more difficult to finance themselves out of the market, therefore they were turning more to you. Does this mean that the spreads are improving there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes; on that stuff, yes.  The large corporates clearly are taking into &#x2013; well, they were the main beneficiaries of the tightening we have seen in the spreads over the last few years, and now they are taking into account the new market conditions, and clearly it's more possible for us to adjust the spreads up, especially in the CIB environment, so clearly yes.  But the small corporates and the retail world is not wide.  Well, obviously they were not beneficiaries of the spread tightening either if you look back -- I mean, they are in a different market, that's all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Pascal Decque from Natixis.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Philippe.  Good afternoon. I had I think four questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First, the cost of the new social plan that you mentioned for BNL &#x2013; currently an agreement has been signed with the trade union, Is it fully impacted already in your P&amp;L? I think you mentioned in the corporate sense of &#x2013; something like 140 million cost. Is it the fully integration of this plan?</p>
          <p>Second, you are some of whom for the first time mentioned in your &#x2013; in detail, your final taken your LDO portfolio.  Does it mean that there are any potential risks &#x2013; potentially on the future in this portfolio? I think the market is getting a little bit more worried about any problem of valuation or refund, this kind of portfolio ending up on the underwriting one?  And regarding the underwriting portfolio, could you give us the exact level of depreciation after the last provision you are mentioning this quarter?</p>
          <p>Another question is wearing the stigma &#x2013; you mentioned a fund that you closed and that cost you 29 million in the asset management. Are there any other funds of that kind in your business at BNP Paribas? And the last one, I'm sorry, could you give us some detail on the big increase in capital allocated to the Jeep division,  especially this quarter, with 50%?  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Pascal.  So the cost of the new social plan, yes, it's 127 million.  It's explained on Slide 62.  So we &#x2013; yes, everything is there.  It's in the rules for accounting in that kind of a <mark type="inaudible" /> cost are very clear.  In fact, for such a social plan as early as you have identified the rules you are going to apply, and that the people concerned, they know about it; you can take it fully in your accounts.  So, we have taken the whole cost this quarter, which is different from the for example, the computer systems cost, where as you are building something for the future you have to expense them only when they have occurred.</p>
          <p>And so you have the same way you had one big &#x2013; I think it was the fourth quarter of 2006 or something like that, we had the first social plan that we had everything continue at once.  For the same reason, we had everything at once this time.  And in between, you have seen that the flow of <mark type="inaudible" /> costs got much lower, in the region of 20 or 30 million <mark type="inaudible" />.  And this quarter for example it's 19 million on top of the 127 which is a one-off.  You have the 19 million which is the normal flow of restructuring costs and which is going to be there until the end of the year.  So overall, we are &#x2013; it is explained on Slide 62, and we are expecting the total restructuring cost to reach &#x20AC;240 million .  We are giving the breakdown per year: 240 this year, in 2008 I mean, which is the meaning that we still have something like 100 million or less than  100 million for the three quarters to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's it. So this is then your first question.  The second question, yes, we have disclosed &#x2013; so it's on slide 70 on the screen.  We have disclosed the final stage because we have tried and it's a good opportunity for me to stress that. Thank you for your question Pascal, we have tried this time to comply with the successions of the financial stability form, the guidelines where the regulators who are together gave the kind of grid of the main topics which should be touched by the bank when they release their results .  And remember that they had said that they wanted all banks to comply with that on the occasion of the half-year results.  So, without waiting for the actual results, we have already given the information &#x2013; most of the information which are suggested according to that grid; and in that grid, clearly they were mentioning not only the syndication book which is what we have given up to now quarter after quarter, and we are giving it again this time, but also, they are mentioning in that report, the total finance take book of LBO.</p>
          <p>So, as we are one of the significant LBO players in Europe, we have disclosed the main characteristics of our book which &#x2013; we had already disclosed that by the way earlier before the crisis at the last Investor Day, which was about CIB, which we were referring to few minutes ago. And this time as it is requested by <mark type="inaudible" /> we have again given some details about this book, which is on Slide 70.  You can see, predominantly European, 78%, and almost exclusively comprised of senior debt and, well, &#x20AC;6.3 billion .  It doesn't mean that we are especially worried by this book at all.  I mean, so this book is like every kind of banking book or loan book.  There are loans serving better than others.  And we, it's a risk management which has to be done on a day-to-day basis.  But we don't have any specific worry on that book.  And, and it's not, we are not trying to raise a flag at all; we are just trying to comply with the SSF guidelines, that's all.</p>
          <p>The seed money, yes, we, we have a weak one.  The seed money is something which is quite normal I would say in our business.  We have something like a total of &#x20AC;300 million  &#x2013; and I have found the figure &#x2013; &#x20AC;300 million , which is invested in different funds which are in the process of being lumped as seed money &#x2013; I mean it's very clear why, you know what we &#x2013; it just happens that in certain cases it's a big success and we can then sell the units outside and we withdraw our own investments.  In other cases, like in this one, well, it's the wrong timing and the wrong strategy for the wrong timing.  So this fund has very bad debt <mark type="inaudible" />, in fact very, very bad debt <mark type="inaudible" />.  We came to the conclusion that we would never be able to sell it because the track record would not be very satisfactory, so we closed it.  And in between we had lost 29 million on our investment. So, very bad performance.  So that's it. It happened.  It was a strategy which has especially not, I would say, adapted to the crisis.  So that's it.</p>
          <p>Now the capital, the increase in capital in Jeep, the capital located to Western Asset Management has reached &#x20AC;1.1 billion  this quarter and it's compared to 700 million at the first quarter of 2007, and to 800 million in average in 2007.  I think we had given that in the restatement we published in data two.  So you have to bear in mind a few things.  The first thing is that we are locating capital at the beginning of each quarter, and so this capital location is reflecting the level of risk and, which is taken at the beginning of the period, so it means that this evolution has taken place between the beginning of 2007 and the very end of 2007.  And we are, it's a business, which is developing, while we work; in fact it's a combination of two things I would say.  One is the normal development of the business.</p>
          <p>We, as I was saying here, in average 2007 it was 800 million.  And I think the normal trend would have been 900 million or something like that towards the end of the each of the year.  And we have an additional capital location of something like 200 million, which is the impact, visible impact at the end of the year, offset, of the kind of limited operational support we gave to our money market funds in the <mark type="inaudible" />  towards the end of the year.  At the time where the money market funds were deferring some outflows, remember?  And so at that time, we, while we temporarily invested in those funds in order to make up for the outflows, at that time where it was difficult for them to sell at a decent price, the market.  So since then there are no positive inflows you have seen since the beginning of the year so we are, were able to reduce that and tell you we probably see some reduction in their liquidity in the next two quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.  If I may I have one last quick question regarding spend in domestic and your legal situation with the, yesterday said that the legal situation was still pending.  If I remember correctly the calendar, initially was for the end of the first quarter then nothing is coming.  What is your view on the calendar and still no view on who is going to be the winner there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We think we'll be the winner and, no, arbitration is a really a nightmare, I mean, it's not the first time, Michael, you know. You put arbitration procedures in contracts because you think it's going to be faster and cheaper than the full legal proceeding, procedure.  And in practice it's as long and as painful as the &#x2013; the only difference that the arbitrators are competent, always, because you select them and so by definition they know about better, while sometimes the judges are not always very well aware of the matter.  But it's really the only advantage of the arbitration procedure.  And so it takes a lot, a lot of time.  We don't, well, really, we don't understand why our case, while we think it's very clear, and we what?  We can't do anything and more, more than wait until the arbitrators are taking their decision.  We have no way to accelerate the process and we hope it won't last too long but I can't tell you more than that.  It's really something which is beyond our control and no more, it's an arbitration process so we have no, you know, we have no means to accelerate but it takes really, we were expecting a much, much shorter, much shorter decision process in this arbitration period.  And so I can't tell you more than that, it's.  I agree with you it's really a pity and we would like, really, to see that being done as fast as possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good luck, thank you, very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Pierre Flabb&#xE9;e of Landsbanki Kepler [Kepler Equities]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I have a couple of questions.  Especially first about French retail. While the life insurance performance seems to be outstanding relative to market, Pierce, could you tell us what is the proportion on the credit links solved in the first quarter relative to the previous period?  And did you manage to have some commercial temping, which might explain your gain in market share?  The second point, it's regarding the improvement of the interest margin due to the Sunday mix.  I have some difficulties to understand how with the mix of deposit going increasing toward money market issuance there might not be such a positive trend.  So, maybe, could you give us some color of what derivative advantage of the deficit spending mix today relative to what it was one year ago and relative to market trends?  And I also, a question on Corporate and Investment Bank, could you provide us with the trend in the client revenue just for the market advisor report?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes, yes, sorry.  Yes, your first question, if you look at the flows, it depends who had the flows or the outstanding the stock.  It still has the flows, the new proportion of unit-link has gone down to 25% toward the &#x2013; we used to sell up to 45 or even 50% at 7.5, but we are now only at 25% of unit-link product.  We still in fact are going to the general refund of the life insurance, so we try to explain to our clients that when the prices are low it's not a bad time to invest in unit-linked products but to no additive.  People tend to be afraid when just after a decline in the stock exchange price.  So we are $0.25.</p>
          <p>And then, in the stock, I mean the outstanding amount is now down to 35%.  It went up to 40 or even more and now down to 35, 30%.  So this is about the proportion of unit-link.  Why do we gain market share?  It's not because of a specific campaign, no.  It's I think really it's just because of our, first our commercial positioning.  You know that we are relatively oriented more towards upper, affluent clients, upper, affluent clients when we compared with the average of the market.  And it's also due to the fact that, I think, we have a very good development of our private banking business in France and with clients being extremely loyal and staying with us and we are even developing that much higher of velocity consumer.  So this is, while there is no specific campaign, just the normal development of our business.</p>
          <p>Now about the deposits and the improvement in the net interest income you have to bear in mind, I mean, that the strong development of the term deposit &#x2013; which you're right, are paid on the basis of the market's rate &#x2013; but it's a retail business which markets rate less the margin.  And you have to bear in mind that this has not been increased at the expense of the side deposit.  Quite the contrary, as I had explained as an introductory remark, that the side deposits are growing very fast as well.  We are also over-performing in side deposits.  So the term deposits are coming at the expense of investments in funds, in fact, mostly.  So you, we see people which otherwise would have invested in money market firms or in bond funds, I don't know, deciding to invest in deposit.  And if they have invested in funds, we would have placement seeds in the retail network.  So the final short fees are lower because we don't have those statements here.</p>
          <p>But on the other hand, we have the retail of the net interest income, because we are selling the term deposits with a discount, compared with the real market price.  There are no more discounts because it's their business, so we take a margin on the client.  And so this is why, in fact, this development of expensive resources &#x2013; I agree with you &#x2013; but as they are not, not, you know, they are not replacing cheap resources.  They are 52.2 investments in funds in post-balance sheet, if you want investments in things which are not bringing any net interest income at all.  And that's why the, that's why, the evolution is that's why.  And then, the trend of clients' revenues in your question is about...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Corporate and investment banking.  The market and advisor report.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The market and advisory business compared with the &#x2013; yes. Well the, we &#x2013; I don't have the precise figures.  In fact, I think if you compare with the first quarter of 2007 I think we had good performances throughout the capital markets without significant difference between the fixed derivatives and fixed income.  But we had also the growth in the final scenario, which is probably lower than 17%, so if I had to make a bet &#x2013; sorry I don't have the precise figures but if I had to make a bet I would say that most of &#x2013; we can say that to a certain extent most of the final revenues with our clients' margins, our clients' revenues and they have grown by, well, if you adjust for the one-off, they have grown by something like 3%.  So most probably the bulk of the growth content is the first quarter of last year is coming from the market, I would say so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Philip Richard of Execution.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi there.  I've got two questions, please. The first is following up on the earlier question on capital when you said you're happy with your 7.6% Q1 ratio. Can you say what sense to that is made up by hybrid of minorities, and therefore what your core Tier 1 ratio is, and whether you're happy with that level or you're planning to gradually increase that going forward?  The second question refers to Slide 66 where you give your RMBS and CMBS net exposures.  Can you give us the size of the gross exposures behind them please?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the core Tier 1, our core Tier 1 is 5.7% &#x2013; 5.7% excluding hybrid, excluding what &#x2013; core Tier 1 is 5.7%.  On your second question, let me go to Slide 66.  This is what the RMBS &#x2013; it &#x2013; that's the BancWest from Slide 66, huh?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's the gross exposure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>They're all gross  Okay, fine</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a gross &#x2013; everything's a gross exposure.  It's just net of differentiation.  It's net of the mark-down we have already taken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay that's fine.  So on that first question, can you elaborate a bit further, whether you think the 5.7% is a level you're happy with given the number of other banks raising capital recently?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, again, I mean it will become a fashion to raise capital, I mean, when you look at who has raised recent capital, the banks obliged to raise capital are banks suffering losses.  And we are not &#x2013; you know, the crisis is hitting a certain number of banks.  As far as we are concerned it is just slowing us down a little bit I would say.  So we have no reason to raise capital at all.  I mean, they also are raising because they don't have any other choice.  We are perfectly happy with the level of capitalization we have at the moment.  It's not different from what we had a few quarters ago.  You know, we have not been obliged to take control of a lot of assets and we have not deteriorated anything.  Before the crisis we were in the region of 7.3, 7.4.  We are at 7.6 and there is no material difference.  And arguably you will say the crisis is making times tougher.  But precisely you can observe that we are not that much affected by this at the time.  So there is no reason why we would be obliged to have a higher level of capital.  I mean we go through the crisis with our own level of capital, with our own business model.  With relatively limited impact and it's okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we will now take our next question from Guillaume Tiberghien from Credit Suisse.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, Guillaume Tiberghien from Credit Suisse.  I've got four questions, one related to the asset management, which you call <mark type="inaudible" /> but asset management and private banking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wealth management?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, yes.  Could you please elaborate on the development of the margin on that business?  Even if you restate for the 29 million of markdown from the seed money; it seems quite affected.  Could you give us a flavor as to where you think that's going?  The second one relates to the 143 million off charge that you took with regard to credit adjustment for other counter parties in investment banking.  Could you maybe tell us who these counter parties are, or actually what categories?  And whether we should expect that to continue and get worse in the following quarters?  The third question is on the provisions in the CIB, but in the capital market portion of that division, 94 million for some counter parties. Could you also elaborate on who they are and what we should expect?  And finally, on the portfolio of LBO of underwriting portfolio you took 44 million this quarter and I think you took &#x2013; sorry, 86 million this quarter and I think 44 million last year.  That's 120 which is 6% markdown.  Am I missing some charge from previous quarters?  Or do you think 6% coverage of that portfolio is sufficient?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  A lot of technical questions, so we'll address them one after the other. Asset management first, we don't know if we can call it with those margins.  What happening on Wealth &amp; Asset management is clear.  It's that we &#x2013; even if we still have positive inflows, the value of assets of our management has gone down because of the equity component and the drop in the share price plus the impact of the dollar, plus the impact of the crisis in bonds as well. So you can imagine that as the values are going down, the revenues, which are made up of fees based on value I think are also going down.  If I look at the return on assets under management, which I have now under the eye, the comparison between the margin, between the first quarter and the previous quarters, there is not a lot of change in fact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's down eight basis points year-on-year and five basis points quarter-on-quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Year-upon-year bank, if you take what &#x2013; I had that broken down.  So if I take private banking, you're right.  It's somewhat down, you're right, by eight to ten basis points, you're right.  If I take asset management itself, it's stable, in fact, around 63 basis points.  So, yes, it's a little bit down in private banking; you're right.  But I think it's not &#x2013;  I don't think it's really &#x2013; you know, what happened because &#x2013; why it is down in private banking, it's just because when prices are going down in the stock exchanges, the clients tend to have a lower turnover. They sell less; they buy less and historically it has always been observed that in the volumes are growing in the market going up and for retail <mark type="inaudible" /> (92.36) and private banking clients.  And they tend to be less active when markets are going down.  So that's why.  So less fees to the return on assets is lower but I don't think it's more than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now the credit adjustment on other counter parties.  You know that credit adjustment is a permanent feature of the mark-to-market of any derivative.  If I infer; if I goes into a directive with Deutsche Bank for example, or let's take an interest rate swap with Deutsche Bank, I always, when I'm going to mark this swap I take the futures.  But compared with the ETF, I'm not going to quote exactly the same price, than if I made the same deal with AAA, brom-brom name like the Agence France Tr&#xE9;sor, what they call the French agency in charge of the French debt.  Because necessarily there is a slight probability; which is very, very small but there is a probability of default a little bit higher than for the French agency.  And by definition I am going to adapt slightly the pricing to that.  In normal times it's very small, a negligible expense for counter parties, which would not be very good, which may happen, but with some clients <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>But in those times what happens is that all the spreads of all the counter parties in the world have widened.  All the banks, including ourselves, all the spreads have widened, in certain cases a lot, in other cases less.  But all the spreads have widened quite a lot. So just the normal mark-to-market of all the derivatives have to be adjusted for that.  And so this high time say, pre- adjustment which in normal times representing maybe the stock in the 20 or 30 million for the whole bank, for all the counter parties.  And changing from one quarter to another by less than 1 million or something like that.  This time it's changing by hundreds of millions, from one quarter to another because of the huge widening of spreads we have seen in March.  And so this is something which is both incredible and not really significant or worrying.  But it's a fact.</p>
          <p>So we have; to answer your question is that &#x2013; the other counter parties, all the counter parties of the world, all the banks, all the clients, everybody we are working with.  And the products are all derivatives and it makes a huge amount which is just the kind of precise mark-to-market adjustment due to the widening of the CDS spreads which we have seen in one of the slides.  So this is where it comes from.  And in fact, it leads to your next question.</p>
          <p>One can argue that this widening is also reflecting the actual possibility of certain counter parties to default, and you remember that we were among the first ones already in the, back in October or November to stress that the counter party risk was rising.  And in fact it now happens that counterparties default; we have seen that, and if it <mark type="inaudible" /> which has created other default of certain counterparties in the market; have created this 94 million, which is the topic of your next question.  So we have seen this number of counterparties defaulting, and when they default, what happens?  Of course, we write this of as of completely the corresponding credit adjustment.  And on top of that we now <mark type="inaudible" /> (97.15) and so the loan or transaction; it's an amount which we have to recoup and we assess how much we are going to recoup.  <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>And now your last question about the LBOs.  We had provided for LBOs every quarter.  The 86 of this quarter, the 44 in the fourth quarter, but also 192 in the third quarter. So the total of the markdown we made over the three quarters of the crisis makes 322 million, 322.  And so it's probably much more than 6%.  In fact it's closer it's higher than 10%.  In fact because at the beginning of the crisis we were on the origin of 3 billion if I remember well, in terms of LBO indication book.  So we are more in the region of 10% compared with the initial volume.  Okay? Are you there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Mamoun Tazi from MF Global.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.  I just have follow-on question on the managers' margin in French retail.  I assume that the French &#x2013; the net interest margin declined year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter.  Can you just give us an indication of how far down it went?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you repeat sorry.  I missed your question.  Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course.  It's about the net interest margin in French retail banking.  I assume from the difference in terms of growth of lending and the managers' income that we've seen a decline in net interest margins.  I'm just trying to get a sense of how far down it went year-on-year, and quarter-on-quarter.  If you can give us the also the level where it's at based on your calculations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  The net interest income has gone up by 6% over one year, and the volume has gone up by something like 20% I would say on an average basis.  So it makes the kind of contraction of net interest margin of around 6%, I would say roughly speaking.  Now this is of course the mix of a lot of things, which are playing a role, especially the fact that we have a mix effect to the extent that certain loans are growing faster than others.  And in fact, over the next two years the corporate loans have grown a little bit faster than the mortgage loans.  Outstanding as far as we are concerned and both much more than the consumer loans, which have grown at least by 3% or 4% something like that over the year.  And those ones are the best margins.  So the fact that the overall margin is down doesn't necessarily mean that it was down product to product.  But it can be a mix effect where the consumer loans with the biggest margins have grown less rapidly than the other loans.  Overall, I would say if I take a more qualitative approach to your question, I would tend to think that there has been over the last few months &#x2013; the last year; there hasn't been any significant change in the margins in the French retail banking. Product-to-product I'd say.  No improvement, I was answering that question a few minutes ago, no significant improvement but no significant deterioration either further across, and then a lot of mixed effects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of basis points decline if you were to look at it year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter, could you give us some indication of some...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of &#x2013; sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Basis points decline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of basis points, we are not &#x2013; we are not giving any synthetic indicator again because of those mixed effects, which are blurring the complete picture.  I think it is not necessarily relevant for the management for the action if you want to look at the overall margin because again it's the addition of too many different margins, which are very different from each other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we will now take our next question from Pierre Chedeville from CM-CIC Securities.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon.  Actually you partially answered my question. But I have some additional question regarding what you said on Basel II.  You insisted on the fact that the Basel II reform is a more pro cyclical reform in terms of calculation of &#x2013; and <mark type="inaudible" /> the low season.  And as we know, the calculation model as in the sector in the period of extraordinary time of benign credit environment. What is your perception regarding the fact that the calculation model will take into account the current credit, which is so fond of the case to my opinion, this is my first question.  And the complementary question to this is what is in your opinion the impact it will have on the ROE of the sector for BNP?</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> question, we know that the United States, when the calculation of unexpected closures were made in that specific benign credit environment, huge but the need in capital was very low due to this very good credit environment and we're serious to apply Basel II. Do you think that it is competitive disadvantage or advantage compared to American banks that does apply Basel II?</p>
          <p>And my last question is regarding the ROE of the CIB.  In Q1 2008 your earnings are around 10%.  SocGen has planned to reach here within 2 years ROE in normal time of 30%.  You have any guidance regarding what you consider as the normality ROE in your CIB division?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  About Basel II, we &#x2013; as I said earlier, we think it's a little bit too early to ask exactly as to how much it's pro cyclical or not, because on one hand as you've said it's supposed to be pro cyclical because it's supposed to reflect actual risk and it's based on the internal rating.  And so we see normally when the crisis is &#x2013; the crisis is developing, the ratings stand to worsen and when the situation is very good, ratings tend to improve.  But at the same time, it's written, I mean in the basis to rule, it's written that you have to rate your client on the &#x2013; through the cycle basis.  So it means that the risk especially &#x2013; the risk officers when they assess the rating of a client or counter party, they should assess the store ratings for the cycle meaning rating which is bulletproof if you want piece of the crisis card, that the rating should not change because it has been assessed through the cycle theoretically.  And the last given default parameter is calculated on a downturn period, so you have to take into account when you assess your loss even default.  You have to take into account that default would necessarily occur in the period before, may procure in the period where there is a crisis and so you have to watch them.  If you want to have a conservative assessment of this loss given default because it will happen most probably in the back period.  So all those technical parameters make that normally.  I mean if everybody is doing a thing very well, and our risk people are saying that normally it should not be that much pro cyclical, okay?  But in fact we don't &#x2013; well I think it's really too early to say and we are all learning by doing and I think that's why we said that it was too early to assess the target for us, in terms of Q1 and Basel II, because we want to see and we have the opportunity, as you say, of playing these new rules.  At the moment, where we are entering into a strong crisis or going through a strong crisis so it's going to be a kind of stress test in real life and we are going to see if there is a real pro cyclically or not and by how much.  My personal view, if you ask me for my personal view, is that probably there will be some pro cyclicality, but probably less than everybody's theory.  This is my view, but well, we'll see.</p>
          <p>The U.S., I think at the end, I think that the main characteristic of Basel II is that you are obliged to look at your risk in detail to assess of each file the precise rating, the precise predictability of default, the precise <mark type="inaudible" /> default and then to manage all of that.  And so necessarily when you start looking at your portfolio in such detail and when you start really trying to maximize each component and improving the quality of your clients, reducing the probability of default of your portfolio, trying to get down seasonal debt to reduce the loss default and so on and so forth.  At the end you are &#x2013; it's a help &#x2013; there is to better manage your books.  And so I am convinced that we are at the moment, in the process of implementing Basel II in BancWest, is not yet done, BancWest is still in the standard method and we are going to &#x2013; we are in the process of implementing the advent missiles at BancWest.  It will take some time, but I am sure that at the end we are going to &#x2013; it's going to help the risk management at BancWest. And so, of course, it's costly, but at the end I think it's the banks apply the advance models Basel II, I think have at the end an advantage in terms of risk management.  I think it's worth investing in that effort.  Now the recent equity of CIB, well, it's the kind of a little ironic to speak about the recent equity target, equity on CIBs, when they're all losing money or being very close to zero and it's probably the banks, which we are talking about the highest return on equity which are now losing the most money.  So, I'm not going to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Not going to force it then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not going to tell you a precise figure.  The only thing I wanted to tell you is that we &#x2013; I mean, clearly CIBs have volatized this mess.  And we always stress that.  You know that one of our key strategy feature is to keep more than half of our allocation in retail in order to have CIB represent only around one third of our application in order to avoid the spillover aspect of this volatility on our reserves.  So we're really &#x2013; we are keen to keep &#x2013; to keep the proportion &#x2013; we want to grow everything, to grows the idea as well.  But by keeping it in such a proportion of the total of the group that we can weather any crisis or any volatility in terms of return equity.  If we have disclosed our own return on equities over the last few years, in fact over the last four years: 2004, 5, 6 and 7, including 2007, I think we were above 30% &#x2013; at or above 30% in return on equity, pre-tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pre-tax.  Which means above 20% plus tax or a little bit more even, equals...  Let's say that, once over.  And with the peak in 2006, that's 39% pre-tax, which is the equivalent of, let's say, maybe 28%, something like that plus tax.  Well, I can't tell you more than that.  I think that in good periods we can easily bid 30% pre-tax.  We have done that over the four years.  Well, is that a normal level?  I mean, I think we have to be very pragmatic and I don't think there is really a normal level for CIB, I think CIB can't go much &#x2013; well, have very high risk on equity and those figures I've given with Basel I.  I mean, I think in Basel II measurement it will be even higher because in advanced places, CIB by first given the type of business we're doing and the good identification and the low risk level we have, lower capital allocation to CIB in Basel II.  So, it can grow very high in periods and we had intelligence in that it can be lower in that period and personal banking can be negative so I've &#x2013; well, the normal level would be difficult to assess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our final question from Antonio Guglielmi from Merrill Lynch.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, Mr. Bordenave.  I have four questions.  The first one is on your remarkable, but a bit unusual to me flexibility cost from the asset management division.  There is a substantial drop in the cost showing an even higher cost control than we have in the CIB.  I'm just wondering if there is anything unusual or we can take the Q1 as a sustainable run rate for the rest of the year.  The second one is on the mark-to-market of the actual position.  If you could just give us an idea of the situation in Q2, including the mark-to-market on your liabilities?  The third one is, on your core set target that you mentioned 5.7% in Q1, which compares, for what I remember with 6% at the end of '07.  Now, given a very low single-digits with the asset growth in the quarter and solid net profit in the quarter which I assume you are accounting per quarter, I'm just wondering, without sense of 30 basis points, it's roughly 1.5 billion of core capital, which I cannot reconcile?  And the final question, I agree with you on not commenting on the outlook as CIB at we, but given that you recently disclosed a target revenue &#x2013; reported revenues for the CIB division flat versus last year, I'm just wondering if you feel confident reiterating such a target?  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I have not count this and I'll answer all of your questions but you will &#x2013; you will repeat some of them.  The first question is about the flexibility in asset management.  Well the asset management cost gross is still year-on-year, first-quarter-on-first-quarter is plus 8%.  So it's a kind of flexibility if you have in mind that last year before the crises we were growing those expenses by close to 20% because of business was developing very much.  So the business was expanding very fast at plus 20% a year, and in the crises we had slowed down a lot this expansion.  And we have even reduced the year-on-year gross to 8% and compared with the fourth quarter we have even been able to reduce by 6%.  But it's not &#x2013; I mean it's just the kind of &#x2013; we are stuck the growth rather than the cost cutting.  We have just cut the growth and what we have done is very clear.  I mean, we have just postponed the number of development plans.  We have a kind of a hiring freeze and so often.  We hold the usual measures you take in order to stop the growth because we want to see how the crises developing before resuming the growth of the business.  On the medium-term basis, we are fully confident that this business is going to resume growth and to develop itself quite nicely.  So some flexibility but nothing to compare with the furnace cut in CIB and the minus 25% in CIB year-on-year here is plus 8%.  Your second question, sorry, I missed your second question.  It's about the mark-to-market of the total liability, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  I was just asking that the situation in Q2 in terms of mark-to-market on your position, also on the liabilities, both in the corporate sense and now in Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we have booked plus another 83 million this quarter and there had been a review of something in the third quarter of last year, full amount.  We are going to see at the end of the quarter &#x2013; this is completely linked to the level of the spread at the end of the quarter.  So it's too early to say.  I mean, the calculation at the end of January would have been very different from what it was at the end of March for example.  So you can't draw any conclusions from what happened in May.  You &#x2013; going out from this (117.50), you have to wait until the end of June to know exactly what's going because it's really a point in time value.  That's the beauty of the fair value, it's just an instant value at the very end of the period.  So it's too early to say what's going to happen.  In any case, even if nothing happens, meaning even if the spreads remain the same at their new level, those figures are going to be reversed to the P&amp;L over the maturity of the debt for everybody.  So meaning that you take the average maturity of the debt in question, and the figure has to be reversed with the P&amp;L, which creates losses for the next few quarters on a kind of amortization basis, even if the spreads are not moving any more.  And if they are moving of course you have to adjust one way or another depending on what's happening.  Your next question is about the core capital.  The core capital?  The 5.7% we are  referring to was not very different at the end of 2007, and it was more or less the same, 5.6 or 5.7.  There has been no change, in fact, no significant change.  This is a figure under Basel II, but you have to bear in mind the Basel II figure of course.  And I missed the rest of your question, you have something which you could not reconcile but I'm not...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, I was just asking, well first of all on the core Tier, I mean I remember but I don't know if I didn't check it's 6% core tier ratio at the year-end, because my question was 5.7 now, and there were some...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no at year-end &#x2013; no, no, at year-end under Basel II we were at 7.6% of the total Tier 1 like today.  And the proportion of hybrid was the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have never changed &#x2013; we have not significantly issued any average of &#x2013; it was 5.6%.  So we have the figure of 5.6%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  No my last question...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And now your last question is &#x2013; yes, the all true across the AB.  Yes, the problem, I agree with you, that I mean, there are &#x2013; the outlook is difficult at the moment because we are in the crisis, if you will.  It is easier to give outlook when you are in normal time.  We had said that at the beginning of the year that even the situation we were taking as a kind of a challenge to try to match the 2007 revenues for the whole of &#x2013; in 2008, having in mind that clearly 2007 had two &#x2013; we had two very good quarters, the first and the second quarters and then two quarters impacted by the crisis, the second half of the year.  And in 2008 we were anticipating that the crisis would hit the two first quarters, it will be the result.  And then maybe after the summer we would come in the more normal time.</p>
          <p>But clearly what we had not anticipated at all was what happened in March which really was a dislocation of the market which went well beyond what we had seen in 2007 and which is something completely unprecedented, withdraw violent  And clearly after this last month we can't tell you that we are going to match the 2007 revenues.  And it's, and we feel uncomfortable to give any prediction &#x2013; I mean any guidance for the rest of the year.  The only thing we can say that &#x2013; as I said already business, the client's business remains solid and we feel that we, compared with the others, with all the competitors. We are faring somewhat better, to say the least.  So we think that's normally in relative terms we should keep over performing.  And that being said we, it's impossible to give a guidance in such a year and after such a &#x2013; we fail first quarter and a marchement which could come again at any time in the future.  But nobody knows.  I mean, we can't give any target or any guidance.  Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Very welcome. So thank you &#x2013; I think the last question.  So thank you, everybody.  And well we'll keep working in this interesting period and do our best to keep weathering the best way possible.  Bye-bye and thank you for listening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that will conclude today's conference call.  You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>