<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1511870" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-11-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7818</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Lars Machenil</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Neuez</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Delphine Lee</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Kinner R. Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Kepler Capital Markets SA (Netherlands)">Beno&#xEE;t P&#xE9;trarque</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Natixis SA (Broker)">Alex Koagne</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods Ltd.">Jean-Pierre L. Lambert</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Nick A. Davey</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Execution Noble">Andrew Lim</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Cheuvreux SA">Pascal Decque</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Maxence P. Le Gouvello du Timat</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Autonomous Research LLP">Stefan Stalmann</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Anke Reingen</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the presentation of BNP Paribas Third Quarter 2012 Results. For your information, this conference is being recorded. Supporting slides are available on BNP Paribas Investor Relation website, www.invest.bnpparibas.com. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would like now to hand the call over to Lars Machenil, Chief Financial Officer. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to our third quarter results presentation. As usual, I would like to give you flavor of our quarterly results by selecting a few of the introductory slides and focusing on selected topics before, of course, handing it back over to you for questions.</p>
          <p>So, if I could ask you to peruse our presentation and start on slide four which gives the synthesis of the third quarter and which basically confirmed a solid profitability for BNP Paribas with a good performance of all our operating divisions. In particular, I would say the revenues of these operating divisions showed an 8.4% rebound compared to what I would call a subdued third quarter 2011.</p>
          <p>This quarter 2012 also saw a continuation of the deposit growth trend seen in previous quarters with an acceleration for the whole Retail Banking where deposits were up 8.1% versus previous year as well as for Domestic Markets, which saw deposits increase by 5.3% with growth in each network.</p>
          <p>Once more, also this quarter, our strict risk management approach allowed us to keep the Group's cost of risk at a low level of 55 basis points compared to the &#x2013; 55 basis points compared to the customer loans. This is only slightly higher than what we saw in the previous quarters when we exclude, of course, Greece.</p>
          <p>Moreover and while awaiting the finalization of regulations, we continued to bolster our buffers as shown by the further increase of our stable funding surplus, which reached &#x20AC;71 billion at the end of September. This means a massive &#x20AC;19 billion increase in the quarter. By the end of Q3, we also achieved our target of reducing the RWAs of our CIB division. You'll remember that we had a target of reducing it by &#x20AC;45 billion compared to June last year, and we basically achieved this and we achieved this earlier than foreseen, and this helped us to boost our fully loaded Basel 3 ratio beyond our 9% target. And in fact at the end of September, it stood at 9.5%. If I peruse other presentations, it turns out to be one of the highest amongst our competitors.</p>
          <p>So, all in all, we confirmed a good profit generation capacity with a net income of &#x20AC;1.3 billion. However, if we include &#x2013; exclude the two most significant exceptional items, which I will relay on in a second, net income basically stands at &#x20AC;1.6 billion in the quarter. So, if with this, I can ask you to flip or slide whatever device you're on or just turn to page five of the presentation and allow me elaborate somewhat on the two main exceptional items. The first is the own credit adjustment as it now tends to be called, which is totaling minus &#x20AC;774 million and which bizarrely reflects the improvement in market conditions and specifically the lower cost of funding for BNP Paribas in this third quarter.</p>
          <p>Second, there is a one-off accelerated amortization of Fortis PPA due to an early redemption with a positive impact of &#x20AC;427 million. This relates to an instrument, which was put in BNP Paribas' balance sheet at market value in 2009 &#x2013; so, May 2009 and &#x2013; which was originally in the heritage balance sheet of Fortis and which amortized over a very long period, but as this product was called in September at par, it generated, of course, a capital gain reflecting this acceleration. The combined effect of those two elements led to a negative &#x20AC;279 million, which is why, if I correct the results for that, I came to the &#x20AC;1.6 billion.</p>
          <p>Now, if you can again proceed to slide seven, I would like to say a word about the Adaptation Plan. As you can see, it's basically now totally done and ahead of announced schedule. In particular and as a reminder, the U.S. dollar funding needs we reduced by $65 billion, but we already did that or achieve that back in April. The CIB RWA reduction of &#x20AC;45 billion we've basically done, and here I would like to stress that we accomplished this with less than a third of the sale cost originally envisaged, that is to say for those who follow us for a while that it is not the &#x20AC;800 million that we announced that it cost us, but it was limited to &#x20AC;250 million.</p>
          <p>And the third point is that the 9% target Tier 1 ratio that I talked about, we have exceeded this and we now stand at 9.5% as I said one of the best in the industry. With this, if we go a little bit in detail on slide eight, and as I mentioned at the start, the revenues of the operating divisions progressed well in the quarter and driven, of course by a rebound in CIB as you can see on this slide eight.</p>
          <p>In particular, Retail Banking revenues were 1.3% higher, where revenues in the Domestic Markets were slightly softer, where lower revenues in France were countered by increases at BNL and in Belgium, so Italy and Belgium. Elsewhere, the Europe-Mediterranean showed double-digit growth driven by volume growth in particular in Turkey, but with the other Mediterranean countries also performing well.</p>
          <p>BancWest's strong performance as you can see I must say was somewhat flattered by the appreciation of the U.S. dollar over the period and Personal Finance was a touch lower as a relative good performance in Consumer Lending was offset by the continued and search for decrease of mortgage loans.</p>
          <p>Then if we switch to Investment Solutions, it saw its revenues climb 3.7% as Insurance and Security Services continued to show positive dynamics, especially outside France. And last but not least, CIB, with rebound in revenue, was lead by strong Advisory and Capital Markets departments.</p>
          <p>Now, if you slide forward to nine, and you'll see that as a complement of the revenues, you also see the benefit of the continued cost control actions, as it is reflected in slide nine in the gross operating income performance. In fact, you will notice that Retail and also Domestic Markets show a positive evolution and within Retail, some performances are certainly noteworthy such as Europe Mediterranean, but also Belgium and BNL. A similar story emerges for the other two operating divisions; Investment Solutions shows a 5.5% improvement and that of CIB increases to an impressive 43%, but as I said, I'm bearing in mind the low comparison base in Q3 with respect to CIB.</p>
          <p>Now, that is about what cost control does to you and now if you go to slide 10, you can see what management of risk does to you. As I said, we saw a slight increase as is visible on slide 10; however, we are still talking of relatively low cost of risk and the main variables in it are a moderate drive in CIB following previous quarters, which as we relayed at that time had been marked by write-backs of provisions, and so probably for CIB, the nine months is a good indication of the results more than the individual quarters. Also, there is a stable cost of risk as BNL quarter-on-quarter and as you know, of course, there is some pickup as we saw it versus last year given the recession, but as I said, relative stability quarter-on-quarter.</p>
          <p>And then as the third one, I would like to highlight the continued decrease of BancWest's cost of risk and a stabilization at Personal Finance.</p>
          <p>With this, if you could cast your eyes on slide 14 and take a quick look at the cumulated nine months net income and if you don't mind compare it to our main competitors, you can clearly see that despite the significant adaptation which we've just done and finalized and have behind us, but that still we have implemented and we're still coming with the strongest results among European banks and one of the strongest in absolute terms as well.</p>
          <p>So, if you could swipe to slide 15 and you basically find the reason for the resilience of our results rest on our diversified business mix. And particularly if you look at the pie chart, if you could go and look at it at slide 15, as I said, it shows how our equity is allocated under the different business lines.</p>
          <p>I am sure you will agree that we show a highly diversified profile where France represents just 13% of the total. Obviously, those who follow us, they know that this is the Retail part, but even if I would add other relevant bits of France in other activities, France would not represent more than a quarter of the total, as also for example in terms of pre-tax income. That is to say while we are certainly registered and headquartered in France, we are a well diversified banking group across businesses and geographies or even said other words, we are its franchise &#x2013; French fries.</p>
          <p>Now on this lighter note, let's maybe turn on to slide 17 and look at our Domestic Markets. Domestic Markets delivered solid performance at a high level. Deposit growth accelerated in the third quarter as deposits increased by 5.3%, or &#x20AC;14 billion year-on-year. Slowing demand affected loans which were actually marginally lower. We continued to reap benefits from our One Bank for Corporates initiative through which, as you know since 2011, some 2,200 new accounts have been opened by corporate clients of our Domestic Markets.</p>
          <p>Similarly, we have recently launched our Priority offering across the four networks aimed at individual clients this time. We first rolled it out in France and Belgium where we have already reached close to 200,000 users and more recently also in Italy and Luxemburg.</p>
          <p>Revenues were slightly softer as I said, due to lower demand for credit and due to the low yield environment. This was particularly the case in France where French Retail Banking was hampered by the prolonged decline in interest rate. However, as you've seen in Italy and Belgium, revenues continued to increase on the back of re-pricing actions implemented in previous quarters and actually still ongoing implementation.</p>
          <p>Moreover, as I said on the overall slide, our continued mastering of cost control in all four main activities meant that Domestic Market achieved a positive jaws effect. This was also reflected in the improvement in the cost/income ratio which was particularly noticeable in Belgium and in Italy.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, Domestic Markets confirmed high levels of profitability with &#x20AC;1 billion of pre-tax income, thanks to good cost control and also, as I said earlier, risk control. So, if with this, I can ask you to go and take a little hop across the ocean to the U.S. and it is a good day to do so.</p>
          <p>On slide 22, we show that BancWest continued to benefit from sustained volumes both in terms of deposit and loans, the latter driven in particularly by corporate activity. This helped counter the impact of lower interest rates on revenues which was slightly softer due to the impact also of regulatory changes as we have been commenting in the past.</p>
          <p>We continued to invest in our corporate and small businesses, configuration that is for them, leading to a slight increase in operating costs. Also, we continued to deploy the Private Banking model and we opened the sixth Private Banking center in Q3. So, all this is basically driving the cost increase.</p>
          <p>The favorable environment in the U.S. contributed positively towards cost of risk, which continued to show a declining trend year-on-year, meaning that ultimately BancWest confirms its position as a strong and growing contributor to the Group's profits.</p>
          <p>Now, if we round up with this, the Retail, and I can ask you to go to slide 25, we shall take a quick look at Investment Solutions and its performance in the third quarter. So, what we see here is that the revenue growth accelerated compared to previous quarters of the year, driven essentially by Insurance businesses and Security Services. Wealth Management also saw growing revenues, while Asset Management, as you know, suffered due to the reduction in managed assets which have been taking place over the quarters.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses increased at a lower rate than revenues. As you know, that is basically what we aim for. This was essentially due to two contrasting factors. The first is the benefits kicking in from the Adaptation Plan in Asset Management, where costs showed a 6.8% reduction to that, but secondly and on the other hand, the fact that we continued to develop our businesses in Insurance and Security Services, especially in Asia. And so, all in all to conclude, and net of the one-off impact from Greece in 2011, pre-tax income showed a healthy double-digit improvement compared to previous year.</p>
          <p>Now, if we turn to slide 27 on the third leg, well, not the third leg, the third part of the activities, which is then CIB and on slide 27, you can clearly see that Advisory and Capital Markets bounced back. Its revenues bounced back significantly from, as I said, a crisis hit third quarter 2011. And this we're confirming a very low level of VaR in this quarter, which actually decreased to &#x20AC;40 million. If we look a little bit more in detail, it was Fixed Income that performed strongly with a high level of primary activity, especially in September. This helped us confirm our strong position on bond issues where we consolidated our number one spot in euros and while ranking seventh for all international issues for the first nine months of 2012.</p>
          <p>We enjoyed a handsome performance in Credit and Rates activities while ForEx was actually stable. If we look at the other part, which is equities, it also bound back strongly, but the effect is magnified, I must say, by a very low base in the third quarter 2011 as I mentioned already before due to the market crisis in particularly at that time. In fact, transaction volumes remain fairly subdued during the summer, but we did very well on equity-linked issues where we ranked number two in the EMEA region, and in addition, we were book runners on seven deals just in the month of September.</p>
          <p>Now, as you know, our CIB is more than fixed income and equities and on page 28, you see the other part which is Corporate Banking. Corporate Banking whose revenues decreased, but they decreased in line with the deleveraging we have been doing, and despite this, we confirmed our strong position in origination, ranking number one for number of syndicated loans in Europe. At the same time, we continued to roll out our Originate to Distribute business approach, gaining some significant deals in Asset Finance, which we then largely distributed, retaining only a residual part on our books.</p>
          <p>Alongside this, we continued and here I'm re-beating the drum as I have been saying before, we continued to develop our Cash Management offer where we are ranked number five worldwide and we rolled out at the global level our dedicated Corporate Deposit line which is the complement with respect to deposits as we had it already in the financing and why we rebranded this activity Corporate Banking out of Financing as it was called before. And so, through this combined approach, we're successfully boosting our client deposits as confirmed by the &#x20AC;5 billion deposits we gained in the third quarter and as you can see.</p>
          <p>So, with this, I would like to conclude my focus on the different business lines. Before I hand over to you, I would like to illustrate a few significant evolutions in our balance sheet as well as in our liquidity and solvency. If we start with slide 30, starting with the balance sheet, the cash balance sheet, which you see on slide 30, you can see that in the third quarter, we have further increased the surplus of stable funding over the funding needs of our client activity. This is the greenish part of this slide. This increased, as I said, this accident increased by &#x20AC;19 billion and now stands at a high &#x20AC;71 billion. Or expressed if I look at those green liabilities over those green assets, it leads to an equivalent of 110% of the financing needs of our customer activity.</p>
          <p>In my view, this ratio is much more significant than what I would consider the simple loan-to-deposit ratio. These elements I mentioned are true in euro, but they're also true in U.S. dollars, where the surplus has increased to $53 billion by the end of September. The main change, if you look at those slides, and you compare it to previous quarters, is basically under deposits with central banks. So, it showed for the lack of a better word, a sizeable increase of &#x20AC;34 billion in the quarter. On the other hand, as you saw customer loans, customer loans decreased partly due to slowing retail demand and partly due to the ongoing deleveraging in the Corporate Bank and so these elements of course drive the fact that we have increased at the central banks.</p>
          <p>If you go to the next slide 31, we look now at the liquidity buffers. You can see that also those have further increased in the third quarter. Our immediately available liquid asset &#x2013; and assets reserves now stand at &#x20AC;239 billion, up from &#x20AC;160 billion at year-end 2011 and so these cover now 114% of our short-term wholesale funding. So, in a nutshell, BNP Paribas has ample liquidity</p>
          <p>And this is also apparent actually, if you look at the update on our 2012 medium and long-term funding program, which we closed in mid-October, having raised &#x20AC;34 billion in total. We went beyond, with this amount, we went beyond initial estimates in order to capitalize on market opportunities. In fact, we confirmed competitive funding conditions with an average price of 109 basis points above six months mid-swap considering an average maturity of over 5.5 years. So, that basically means we are now closed for this year and any funding from now on will be pre-funding for the 2013 funding program.</p>
          <p>I'm almost there, I'll always give it &#x2013; almost give it back to you for questions. There's basically slide 32, that I want a talk about on the solvency. I already told you that we exceeded 9% Tier 1 target fully-loaded Basel 3 and actually we're at 9.5%, which basically means we indeed exceeded it. This corresponds to 11.4% under Basel 2.5. If I look at the evolution of the quarter, this means that the Basel 3 fully-loaded ratio improved by again, for lack of a better word, a mighty 60 basis points with half of the benefits accruing from the combination of the net income, which we showed you are solid and the RWA reduction stemming from our Adaptation Plan. However, the other half of the benefit came from the revaluation in the available for sale portfolio. So, it's on the upside. This clearly illustrates the volatility introduced by Basel 3, so those who would have forgotten about it, this is what the removal of the prudential filters do to you and it basically confirms in our mind that it was wise for us to reduce our sovereign debt portfolio.</p>
          <p>But in a nutshell, I think that BNP Paribas also has &#x2013; I'm running out of adjectives, ample solvency and its fully loaded &#x2013; and its fully loaded Basel 3 is one of the highest amongst competitors. So &#x2013; and basically to conclude, you know that we tend to be, if I may paraphrase someone, a boring bank and like simple straight-forward things like net book value per share, which you can see on our final slide.</p>
          <p>We are basically, at BNP Paribas, we're proud of the fact that we have consistently increased this net book value per share for our shareholders and this is confirmed in the nine months 2012. In fact, our net book value per share has topped &#x20AC;60, while the tangible book value is just shy of &#x20AC;50, and our share price is like just above &#x20AC;40. So, with this, I hope to have conveyed to you, that thanks to another set of solid results in the third quarter, BNP Paribas confirms its standing as one of the most profitable banks, especially in the European context, one of the best capitalized in terms of fully loaded Basel 3 ratio and one of the most prudent in view of the huge buffers that we have put in place.</p>
          <p>Finally, ladies and gentlemen, I thank you very much for your kind attention. And I am now very happy to open the floor or the phone at least to take your questions. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have a first question from Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Neuez, Goldman Sachs. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Lars. Thank you for the presentation. I have a few big questions if I may. The first one is on the BNL net interest income, it looks to be growing quite rapidly year-on-year despite loan shrinkage and this is pretty unique in the Italian context as far as I get it and I just wondered if you had more color on that and how sustainable you reckon that is? The second question is on your level of liquidity, can't help noticing the huge amount of reserve build-up that you've done this quarter again and I just was wondering whether, first, you take that down if the LTA rules were to be softened a little bit?</p>
          <p>And secondly, is this in anticipation of possibly repaying some of the LTRO? Thirdly, a competitor of your started to talk about PVA, if you've heard about that, that was hurting their Basel 3 impact. I think it was Barclays and I just wondered if you had an update on these type of things and whether that was in your estimate for Basel 3 impact? And lastly, I can't help asking, we've seen one of your major competitor in the fixed income market announcing a major retreat from some of the markets and I have read in the press that you guys have ambitions to actually grow in these type of businesses. I just wondered whether you could share some colors on why you think these guys do that and what's different with you essentially? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois, thank you very much. That's a lot of questions and I'll take them one by one. If I look at BNL first and as I said, BNL is part of the Domestic Markets and is indeed, given our positioning actually in the Italian market, we have been able &#x2013; actually already since the end of last year, we have been able to re-price handsomely, I would say, and so this is something which started at the year-end already of last year and which basically has continued and has seen its effect in the third quarter. So, it's a fact that is, I would say, on the back of indeed the positioning of BNL, the client segments in which they are and which has now been continuing for a couple of quarters. And, of course, as you know, it's essentially for a big part in the Corporate segment that this taking place.</p>
          <p>With respect to your liquidity question, indeed as you have seen, we have stored or stashed a lot of deposits at the central bank which is, of course, not the yielding much, not to say anything at all, which is one of the reasons as you can see in our Corporate Center where part of these, let's say, costs so to speak or foregone revenues are reflected upon. At this stage, this is just the reflection of our prudent stance. I mean, as you know, it is still relatively uncertain out there and so at this stage, we prefer to continue the prudent stance and store it there. With respect to the LCR, I think our stance remains that it is way too early to say something given the uncertainty about it and the LTRO is the same thing. You know that the LTRO, we also took it last year out of prudence. As you know, we put it in our short-term funding. We don't do any carry trades with it; we don't use it in any of our, between brackets, green assets and, of course, we will review in January when it's up we will see how stormy it is outside and we will decide at that moment.</p>
          <p>With respect to your third question, I think you &#x2013; if I understood well, you referred to DVA which is so, as you know, where we start to use or there is this kind of nomenclature which is getting out which is what we used to call own credit. It's basically being called OCA &#x2013; own credit adjustment &#x2013; and then you have the CVA and the DVA which basically will be shaped somewhat with the upcoming IFRS 13 which is something for next year. And so, of course, this DVA when it will come will induce some further volatility, so this is P&amp;L volatility, very similar to what you have under OCA but this time, it will be on our derivatives. But again, typically, this is something which at the text &#x2013; as the text stands today, should not impact the capital just as is the case for the OCA. So, this is something, which will indeed come in 2013 with IFRS 13, and which will lead to further volatility and volatility as you know, in a strange way. I mean, as &#x2013; whenever the perceived risk on the bank goes down, you will have a positive impact and the other way around. And, as you know, for me that is a little bit of an accounting aberration, but it seems that, that is what IFRS 13 wants.</p>
          <p>With respect to your last question where you, I guess, I don't know if you pronounced it, but I suppose you referred to UBS. So, there is two things. So, first of all, as we have finished our deleveraging where we basically, indeed you saw we were impacted somewhat in U.S. dollars and as you have seen and has also been very clearly articulated by our CEO, we're now totally back in business. And so, yes, we are back in business. And if you look at our Fixed Income activities, you have seen that they were already back in business in the third quarter, and don't get me wrong and I don't want to say anything about UBS.</p>
          <p>So, let me just give you some figures. I mean, not every Fixed Income is necessarily the same. If you look at first, our fixed income part of total BNP Paribas is not as sizeable as it was for UBS. Also, if you look at the rankings, if I look at the rankings, you saw that BNP Paribas ranked number one book running Eurobonds, UBS was outside to top 10. If you look at International bonds, BNP Paribas was ranked seven; UBS was not ranked within that top 10. And I could go on; I mean our management of Fixed Income has been stable ever since. Also, there is no legacy portfolio out of our Fixed Income. So, I could go on and give you many reasons why one fixed income is not the other and why we believe that Fixed Income fits very well in the Originate to Distribute, which is clearly something that the regulators want and as you know <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:08) sorry for my French with respect to that, so we believe that we are in a very fine position and we cherish our Fixed Income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much. Very clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Jon Peace of Nomura. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. I have two questions please. So, the first one was around your capital management strategy. Now you've hit that 9.5% Basel 3 core Tier 1 and you're probably generating 20 to 30 basis points per quarter. Looking beyond the buyback, when you have discussions with your regulator about share buybacks, what do they actually say to you? Is there a certain level that they would expect you to reach, 10% or more, before they would give their go-ahead to buy back shares? And how are you thinking about the mix of dividends versus buybacks?</p>
          <p>And then the second question is if you could just talk a little bit about your expectations from the French Banking reform bill at the end of this year. Do you imagine it will be similar to the Liikanen proposals and could you give us any idea of potential costs? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me be very clear with respect to the capital management. We have no discussions whatsoever with whomever about share buyback. As you know, we've put ourself a 9% target. The rules we still wait for them to be cast in stone or chiseled in marble, whatever recipient you prefer, and as long as that has not happened, we just continue minding our business and once things are clear, we will be able to share some news on that. So, that is that.</p>
          <p>With respect to the French banking reform which is normally also due before year-end, I think you know as much as I do from what we see, it is something which has always been articulated as something which would want to indeed separate speculative activities which has always been clearly stated as such by the candidate, Hollande, at that time and so we expect that that will be the gist of the proposal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Delphine Lee, JPMorgan. Madam, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Delphine Lee from JPMorgan. Good afternoon. Just a very few, a couple of very quick questions. First of all to come back on BNL, is it possible to get some color maybe on kind of the progression between end of June and basically end of the year between securitization and maybe the Retail bond issuances that you've done and at what level, the impact it has had on revenues? And then, secondly, just on the provisioning, on <mark type="ph" /> the DIP (36:11) maybe just if you could give some color on what has happened in terms of the increase and what kind of a run rate we should expect in the next few years? And also, just to come back on capital, has the guidance on Basel 3 &#x2013; on the Basel 3 impact really changed, because I think if you look at slide 32, it looks like it has decreased slightly and since we have had some revaluation on the asset side, I'm just looking at the moving parts if anything has changed from that perspective? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Delphine, thank you very much for those questions. So, indeed, if I elaborate first on BNL, so what you refer to is indeed the topic of the intra-group funding and you know that &#x2013; as you know in the past, we basically funded ourselves at head office and basically re-injected that into our activities. In anticipation of upcoming LCR and other regulation, we basically decided to have in BNL increased self-funding and so, for example, we were at &#x20AC;18 billion still of intra-group funding at the previous quarter. We have brought that down to &#x20AC;13 billion and so that basically means, of course, that we use a mix of indeed retail bonds, but also we use covered and other elements in order to have that funding and as you see at the same time, of course, Italy allows us to have the re-pricing which basically all in all, at this stage, makes that manageable.</p>
          <p>And as you know, so we came from &#x20AC;18, we were at &#x20AC;13, and we have an effect or we have an ambition to basically be single digit, so to be below &#x20AC;10 billion before year-end and allow me to just limit it to say that it is the mix of, let's say, covered; it is the mix to Retail. It is also the fact of the loan-to-deposits ratio changing that basically does that to us. With respect to your second question, I think your question on provisioning is on the Corporate Banking side, I guess that's what you have asked...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, so indeed Corporate Banking &#x2013; just give me a second, I took a sip of water, with respect to the provisions, as you know, at Corporate Banking, it is not as, let's say, portfolio-based as it is on the Retail, so which basically means that as we told you last quarter, you should not take it as a run rate, because we had write-backs. You should see that in this quarter, we had several files, never a file of 100, but several files which basically impacted the cost of risk. So, for me, if I would have to guide you, I would say that none of the individual quarters is a good proxy; however, the nine-month evolution in the year is probably a good proxy, is probably a good base, for what you would have the year, and then I'll let you be the guide if that would deteriorate somewhat going forward in the elements where there might be some impacts on recession. So, that will be my answer for that. I suggest you look at the nine months to be a better proxy than any of the individual quarters.</p>
          <p>With respect to your Basel 3, there are no, if your question is on moving parts, if we have reviewed our impact, no. We have always guided that we were somewhat around 180 basis points in difference between Basel 2.5 and Basel 3. So, what basically changed here is the important point of the 30 basis points of available for sale. I informed you the last quarter, not you in particular, but we informed all of you that we had a 40 basis point negative impact going into Basel 3 due to the unrealized latent losses. And given that the economic situation in the third quarter has improved, these unrealized losses have decreased and have, therefore, impacted the Basel 3 by a positive 30 basis point. So, the moving part so you wish that you have observed is basically that one, and that one will continue. It will continue as long as there is no prudential filtering of these effects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Kinner Lakhani, Citigroup. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, good afternoon. So, few questions. Firstly on capital, I just wanted to get your sense on how you think about payout ratios. If I look at the history over the last 10 years, clearly there have been times when your capital ratios have been consistently around the kind of 35% mark. Is that something we could think about going forward?</p>
          <p>Secondly, on the Fixed Income business, just wanted to get a better feel for what kind of investments and what kind of opportunities you see in the U.S. market, and how that fits into your model? It's much easier to understand how your Fixed Income business fits in your European model versus the U.S. model. Thirdly, just on the French Retail business, to get a better feel for the net interest margin, it seems like the pressures have increased in the very recent past, and therefore what's really changed and what your views are going forward. And maybe just a final one, just on your thoughts on the Liikanen proposals, how you think that might evolve? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you very much for your interesting questions. On the first one, I will have to give you a very similar answer to what was asked in a previous question. At this stage, and moreover, the payout ratio is something that, in the end, the board and even the General Assembly will have to decide upon. And I think it is too early at this stage to address that question. As I said, once the regulation is clear &#x2013; if I would now tell you we're going to move something and then regulation comes in a way which is different than anticipated, that would not be a sensitive thing for me to do. So, I will have to ask you to hold that question until there is further clarity.</p>
          <p>With respect to Fixed Income, the investment and indeed the opportunities, well, there is several things. Of course, there is the regular business that we did which is basically U.S. distribution platform for the Eurobond issues on investors, where we want to claw back to the positions that we have. I mean given our deleveraging, we bumped a bit out of the league where we want to be, so we want to first of all claw back to the position that we believe is a natural one.</p>
          <p>The second thing is that we are also further pushing on the works together with our BancWest activities which has also a focus on &#x2013; and developing own corporate which is basically another platform that we are investigating for further growth. So, that will be the two main axis of clawing back on the thing that we have and further improving it and on the other hand exploring our further growth within our total constellation of activities in the U.S.</p>
          <p>With respect to French, so as I said, the French, let's not forget the Retail as I try to make a little joke if you allow that, that we are not necessarily &#x2013; as I said, we are as French as French fries because the French Retail is part of the domestics and which, of course, has some impact. You have seen that on one hand we have persistent low yields, so that basically impacts and, of course, you've also seen a marked slowdown on the credit demand and that in particularly if you compare it still with what we had last quarter, is one of the elements that impacted. And so, in France today, we are at quite a high level of income, and we, of course, we use the levers we have that, for that to use. And, of course, as I said, as always, we continue on the cost side to basically counteract and ensure that we have gross operating income growth.</p>
          <p>With respect to your last question of Liikanen, I think there is not that much more that we can say and Liikanen has basically a two-step approach. The first one is basically identifying, it's very crisp on identifying which banks fall into his perimeter and I think the majority of the larger banks under his parameter would fall into that, but afterwards, basically my read is that he falls into the same difficulty as everybody else to define what to do where he basically relays it to local regulators. So, for us, at first stance, the important point is, what is to come and particularly in France with the local law. And as I said for us, for us, what is very important in Liikanen is that he really confirmed the general bank approach, which has a mix of activities, which for us, as you know, is very important. We believe that we have proven that it works for us. I have shown you that our resilience is coming from that. I've shown you that we have one of the strongest results, all that is coming from that and so we're very pleased to see that basically that is underscored in that document.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Beno&#xEE;t P&#xE9;trarque, Kepler Capital Markets. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's Beno&#xEE;t from Kepler. Hi. Couple of questions on my side, first on the liquidity, your surplus stable funding improved considerably over the past year. You grew your deposits, and you basically finalized your deleveraging plan. I know you have difficulties to answer the question but where do you roughly stand on LCR and NSFR ratio? I know the regulators are still finalizing them, but just broadly, just to give us a feel on the &#x2013; how much effort you still need to realize post-deleveraging and where you stand on those ratios now?</p>
          <p>And on the, again on the liquidity, you grew your deposit with Central Bank. Is there any P&amp;L impact to be expected in Q4 again on that? And then on Belgium, I was pretty surprised to see the top line holding pretty well in fact. Do you think you have much more room to re-price your deposits? I know you've done a lot already there, and will that be enough to eventually offset the impact on the low yields environment in Belgium. And then also on the PPA in Fortis, how much you still have there, considering you have taken a big amount back on the P&amp;L this quarter? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, they are interesting questions. With respect to the liquidity, I will have to give the similar answer as earlier. I mean there is still a huge set of uncertainty about the LCR. I mean just what I observe is that there is more and more people voicing that in the &#x2013; not about the concept of the LCR which is something I think is a good thing to have. But on the parameters and particularly in the stress, there's more and more people voicing that these will have substantial negative, probably unintended or intended consequences also on the economy, particularly the ECB is articulating this point of view and so these things are evolving very much. So, I mean, honestly, I can give you a number &#x2013; or I cannot give you a number and if I would, it would be wrong. And so I would be totally guiding you wrongly on it. So, you have to bide with me and wait until we have clarity and, at which time, we will be able to say something sensible.</p>
          <p>On the, your question of the central banks, as I said, yes, we keep on accumulating. It's also the effect of the deleveraging and the fact that we have been able to attract a lot of medium and long-term funding given the environment. And, of course, as I said that does impact, sadly, Draghi doesn't pay as much as I would probably like and so, indeed, there is a negative impact on the Corporate Center. I have been guiding you in the past, at the Corporate Centre you can see that we are not making that guidance, it's &#x2013; we are below that and that is because of the forgone revenues in this. So, yes, as long as we will have an excess at Central Banks, you will see an impact in it, in the Corporate Centre.</p>
          <p>With respect to Belgium, there is a couple of things. Yes, re-pricing, we keep on doing it. I told you that we did it in April. We even re-priced under Draghi. We did it again, in November, we re-priced, so it's not yet in the figures but in November, we re-priced another 10 basis points. So, if I may just crack up a little bit this meeting where we're now into it for a while &#x2013; when will it stop? When we reach zero basis points I guess. So, but there is re-pricing, yes, we've done it, but again in the Domestic Markets, like it or not, we will have to continue our mastery of the costs as we have been doing. As you have seen, it led to the RBA and we will continue to do so.</p>
          <p>With respect to the PPA, so I remind you all this is &#x2013; we told you that the PPA is typically, and we give you the number explicitly in Corporate Center. We've always said that we had a run rate &#x2013; that the majority &#x2013; so, I remind you that the PPA is basically products that in May 2009 that we found in the heritage Fortis and that were put in the balance sheet and that were basically amortized.</p>
          <p>The majority had a maturity of around four years and so, basically, it amortized at this stage at around &#x20AC;150 million a quarter for this year, but we always said that it would basically be close to zero as of next year. So, you should anticipate that there will be hardly anything left next year.</p>
          <p>And so, on your question of this one, this one is a product with very long maturity and which was basically amortizing till 2033. So, it would have &#x2013; it would have not been &#x2013; or it is basically not visible, if it would have amortized at that speed, but of course it materialized due to the fact that it was called and paid back at par, which realized basically that PPA. So, a bit of a long answer to basically say that, next year, you should not expect too much out of the PPA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Alex Koagne, Natixis Securities. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. This is Alex from Natixis. Just have few questions. If I may start with a request. Would it be possible to have in the Retail Banking, the breakdown of commission between the Financial commission and the Service commission to see how these two part moving altogether? Then if I go through my question, in Personal Finance, would it be possible to have your guidelines in the cost of risk, and I will say mainly on the cost obviously in France as this &#x2013; the decrease in this area is the only explanation of the stabilization of the cost of risk in this division?</p>
          <p>Secondly, the trend of the revenue in the Corporate Banking we see over here a drop of 16% year-on-year and 8% Q-on-Q. Now that you have finished your deleveraging, what is the trend in term of revenue over here? Then coming back on the capital, sorry for that, but just to be sure that I have understood it clearly, have you removed the negative impact of 40 bps in term of mark-to-market on the sovereign debt on your calculation? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for your questions. I'll duly note and I look at the people here around the table with respect to your breakdown. We will note it; we try to improve every time. We've added the balance sheet, which was one of your requests. So, we jot it down on the list and we'll see how we can attend to it.</p>
          <p>With respect to the cost of risk on Personal Finance, as we said, we are basically at a relatively stable level as we stand. But, as I said, you should disregard some of the exceptional elements, which if you refer to France, which we have adjusted. So, I think the run rate roughly that, or the run rate, the cost of risk that you see today in the third quarter is relatively representative for the picture and the risk environment as it stands today.</p>
          <p>With respect to Corporate Banking, yes, indeed, the main part of Corporate Banking is behind us. There will still be in the next quarter a little bit of an impact of deleveraging which is done, but which is &#x2013; I mean, it still has to take its effect, it's signed but the deal is not yet finalized. So, there will still be a little bit of an effect, which is &#x20AC;35 million, and so that is something which will exceptionally weigh still a little bit on the next quarter, but what you see for the moment in your Corporate Banking is a run rate, which is roughly, let's say, the run rate following the deleveraging.</p>
          <p>With respect to capital, yes, thank you for allowing me to clarify the situation. What we have done is we have shown you the Basel 3 as it is fully loaded. So, we have taken the rules as they ramp up and have taken them as if they are active in 2019. In 2019, there is no longer any filtering of unrealized losses or gains. So, that means in the figure that you have seen, those are in. A quarter ago, these weighted for 40 basis points, and so, they were in and they were weighted for 40 basis points. Today, they only weigh for 10 basis points. 10 basis points negative because there was an improvement of 30 basis points. So, it's fully in and it's something which was negative, which became less negative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I get it. If, I have a one last question if I may, coming back on BNL, now that you are registering the intra-group funding, I guess that one part of, I mean, if we have to consider that the interest of having BNL was also based on the fact that you have this intra-group funding, now that you have to finance originally your subsidiary, could it hurt the interest for BNL for your Group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not at all. As we said we, our Domestic Markets with our clients, we have a very strong drive to serve them. You have seen that the contribution, the profitability of BNL is very handsome for, if I may use that Italian word, and so there is no change in stance with respect to that. And so, allow me, thank you for allowing me to clarify, we're not retracting any way or another out of our BNL activity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Jean-Pierre Lambert, KBW. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Three questions on my side. The first one is on the Corporate Centre. You provided the guidance in the past. It seems like there's a difference, delta if you want, in the revenues where the underlying revenues are negative &#x20AC;98 million in my estimate, and the costs are also higher, something like &#x20AC;147 million, versus the guidance of &#x20AC;100 million. So, at the gross operating level, that's a delta of about &#x20AC;100 million per quarter. If you could provide some further update on the guidance?</p>
          <p>Then on the Basel 3 ratio, if you could just provide two magical numbers, maybe risk weighted assets and the core equity Tier 1 in absolute terms. And also, does that include, does your estimate include potential for favorable amendments and the corporate CVA and the change in treatment of CCP? Finally, the cost base in Italy is quite seasonal in the fourth quarter, has there been some smoothing or shall we still expect this seasonality in this year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jean-Pierre thank you very much for your question on the Corporate Centre, because indeed I think on the NBI, I think I have provided the answer. It's the fact that the depositing at the central banks which basically provides forgone revenues versus a normal redeployment in banking activities is impacting the Corporate Centre. So, as long as we will have an excess at central banks, yes, versus the guidance I have given, there will be weighing on the NBI. But on the other one, I thank you very much and very well spotted and bad for me that I haven't guided you on it, and the cost of Corporate Centre is impacted for &#x20AC;91 million by the doubling of the systemic tax in France. So, in August 4, as a reminder for those, there is a systemic tax, which is active, but France has it, but many other countries do have it and it was voted to basically double it. It's something which cost us &#x20AC;120 million a year and so as it was voted, we had to accrue for the three-quarters of the year, which is &#x20AC;91 million and that is what we have accrued at this stage in Corporate Centre.</p>
          <p>As you know, things that happen in the year, we basically put it in Corporate Centre and then when we restate our accounts, we basically allocate it. So, the initial systemic tax is well into the polls, now this one is put in there, so that is basically in there. So, that is a &#x2013; let's say a one-off effect which you will still have the remaining complement of the fourth quarter coming into the fourth quarter. So, there is another &#x20AC;30 million that you should expect in the third quarter due to that. So, again thanks for allowing me to qualify.</p>
          <p>On Basel 3, as I said, we have &#x2013; we haven't changed any of our hypotheses. We stuck to what is the so-called Danish proposal, which is the one that we'll see. We anticipate that would basically be voted and that is on which we have done all the calculations and which basically leads to that. And again also here, once things are clear, we will provide further elements.</p>
          <p>With respect to the cost base, I'm not entirely sure that I understand it. There is, I understand that it is to do with the seasonality that we typically have in the fourth quarter and which is something, I mean, from my point of view, that is probably something you might expect just like you see it on the revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Nick Davey, UBS. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon everyone, Nick Davey from UBS. Three questions from my side, please. One on BancWest, one on asset quality, one on funding. On BancWest, I just hoped you could elaborate a little bit more, please, on slide 22 in the cost growth, please, in that division, and you've obviously mentioned a bit about the build-out of the Private Banking set-up. If you could maybe just give us some more color, please, on the scale of the aspirations there, for how many more quarters we should expect investment coming through?</p>
          <p>On asset quality, please, I'm just looking for some sorts of lead indicators. And you give us some color around doubtful loans on page 38 of the presentation. I wondered if you'd be happy to talk us through any trends on growth for doubtful loans, or whether or not there's a big difference between the two? I would imagine there is a little bit of a collateral build going on through the Retail networks with your corporate customers. So, is there any difference really between gross and net NPL progression please?</p>
          <p>Thirdly and finally on funding, on slide 30, just interested to note that the amounts of medium and long-term funding placed through your networks declined on the quarter. Could you please just flesh out a little bit what trends you're seeing there? Is it when you're bringing down the intra-group funding in Italy, are you really focused on replacing BNP bonds with BNL bonds? Is that really the key trend and in what regions is the amount declining? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you. With respect to BancWest, as we said, so BancWest, we &#x2013; has re-found let's say its growth and we basically have or are rolling out the concepts that we basically apply in the Domestic Markets, which is sort of if we take the Private Banking, Commercial set-up is ensuring that we have proximity with respect to the clients that we can basically offer that. So, we have offered, we have opened another site, so this is basically the stuff that we are doing. Also, what we are doing is catching up on mobile banking, so we basically really copying &#x2013; so you wish, well copying, replicating so you wish the things we are doing, which, of course, do cost some money and that is something I think for the next quarter or may be quarters you might or you will, or you might expect to see. So, that is basically on BancWest.</p>
          <p>On asset quality, indeed, if you look at page &#x2013; I'm going through it, if you look at the total page, where is it &#x2013; 38. If you go to 38 and if I comment, indeed, the two, so we look at figures, of course, excluding Greece and for the bank, you see that if you look at our coverage ratio, our coverage ratio basically improved somewhat. But I must say this is in particularly also on the back of, let's say, further guarantees that are being put in place, that basically improved the coverage ratio. If you look at the non-performing loans which had a little tick-up from 4.4% to 4.5%, where you basically &#x2013; if you look at it, there is two things, that there is one which is, of course, a certain effect of the deterioration that you see at BNL, of course, which is doing in. But there is also another element which, well, unjustly but fuels it a bit is the fact of amongst others, the deleveraging but also, the &#x2013; well, the Dolphin, well, that's the internal name, but the instrument which has been called, which basically removes also elements out of it. So, that is what you see, so a gentle pick-up on that one, I would say as a general trend. With respect to funding, I must honestly that I didn't fully understand your question. So, if you could maybe rephrase it or just repeat it to be sure that I capture it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course. On slide 30, I just noticed small note, note six I believe saying that the amount of medium and long-term funding placed in the networks, seems that it slightly declined on the quarter. I just wondered if there was any...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, no, no, it is just, it is just, I mean, you know how that goes. We try to be opportunistic in these things. And as you have seen, we have been very opportunistic in the debt markets, and so there is nothing in particularly that you should read into this. Just as you should not read anything particularly when I compared fixed income of UBS, for example, if you heard me on that one. So, nothing &#x2013; nothing particularly to be read in that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Andrew Lim, Execution Noble. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Afternoon, Lars. Got a few questions please. Firstly, coming back to potential ring-fencing,  I was wondering if you could disclose how much of your total trading assets are actually market-making assets, which might be excluded from ring-fencing? And then, secondly, I appreciate that you can't disclose your Basel 3 LCR ratio, but perhaps you'd be in a better position to disclose what your Basel 3 leverage ratio is, so including off balance sheet assets and guarantees in the denominator there?</p>
          <p>And then, thirdly, now that you've completed your deleveraging, what kind of risk weighted asset growth should we expect for the Group on an annual or quarterly basis? And then, fourthly, just a technical question here, obviously, you said that you've had a 30 bps improvement from the reduction in your AFS losses. But if that goes into positive territory, does the whole benefit translate to your core Tier 1 ratio or does any of that part from minus 10 bps to zero, which is taken as a benefit and then the rest goes to Tier 2? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your questions. With respect to your first question, as you know, what is really speculative &#x2013; the speculative part I would say instead of using market making, because market making is in our mind a much too generic term, the speculative part for us is really very small. And while we haven't disclosed that number, but it's very minimal. As you know, what we do is mainly for our clients even &#x2013; I mean things like if you have a price, I mean if you do market making to ensure that you have sufficient demand of products which are appropriately priced or for a clearing house or for your clients in Direct, we are convinced that, that is something which is a solid economic client-related activity. So, in our mind what is speculative is very limited.</p>
          <p>With respect to your question on leverage, again I mean what I can say is that if &#x2013; and I don't know if we have published it actually, but if we look at the leverage ratio, which is the simplest one that we use, if we compare ourselves to U.S. banks where we basically strip out the derivatives because IFRS and U.S. GAAP, they will never find a common way. You will see that, that leverage ratio for us stands around 20. And we believe if you would do a rough calculation that you will basically see that that brings us in line with what a Basel 1 would be. So, we believe that for us at the situation where we are, we are in fine waters.</p>
          <p>With respect to the RWA growth, as you know, I mean I don't have a crystal ball and therefore we don't give outlooks, but you could assume that indeed and particularly in the areas where we have deleveraged and others, that we aim to pick up growth. What will it be? It will depend a bit. It will depend on the mixture of the stabilization of the regulation, the pick-up of the demand, but our aim is to be firmly at the side, as it has always been and as we've never shied away from it, with our clients.</p>
          <p>And with respect to AFS, yes, allow me to say, but again I mean we have counseled on it, and I observed that the U.S. regulation hasn't pronounced more reserves with respect to those OCA, but indeed the OCA are not filtered at all. So, that means that you have all effects, positive and negative, that you have. So as we said, it can induce things. It can inflate and deflate your capital. So, again, as I said, for us, this is probably not necessarily the widest impact because it does volatility and it meant that we, and I reiterate it for good reasons, reduced our AFS and in particularly govvies portfolio because of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Many thanks, Lars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Pascal Decque, Cheuvreux. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Lars. Good afternoon, everyone. I still have three questions left. The first one is, I wanted to be sure that there will be no more adaptation cost &#x2013; restructuring cost in CIB and Personal Finance starting in Q4? The second, could you give us an updated number on your intra-group funding with Spain? And the last question is about the provision, the cost of credit on the French Retail in Q3. I was a bit puzzled by the very low level in the so-called recessionary environment where we had to go back to the third quarter of 2008 to find a lower level in term of provision.</p>
          <p>Then I was wondering, if there was any special effect or write-back on any kind of specific file or not and if you had kind of a guidance, and I know you don't like it, you don't like that word, but kind of guidance for the cost of credit in French Retail going forward, because 17 bps looks very, very small to me in that environment as I said. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if we look at the &#x2013; with respect to your first question on the restructuring, as I said, first of all on CIB, there will still be the remaining impact with respect to the deleveraging. So, as we said, we have been selling some of the aspect. We said that there is &#x20AC;250 million is the total impact; there is still &#x20AC;35 million of that to come, so that's basically deals which are signed but are not closed. And so, there is still some effect to come, and also on the restructuring cost, there will still something be left because it is &#x2013; and people that are going that are not yet gone because they had to hand over and stuff like that. So, there will still also on the cost side some remains are to be expected, but they should not be material.</p>
          <p>With respect to your question on intra-group on Spain, the total amount had basically not budged. So, we're still at &#x20AC;7 billion intra-group. And with respect to the cost of risk in France, what can I say, I mean you know us. I mean we should maybe bring back also a slide to illustrate. Given the size that we have, and given the model that we have, we are very restrictive at origination. That's one thing. Second thing is, as you know we are not everywhere in France. So, as I said, and I am going to say it anyway, that we are not the French bank from that point of view. We are not everywhere, we are in &#x2013; if you look at our market shares, our market shares are basically linear with respect to the GDP in certain areas. So, all that means that we have been very selective and that's one of the reasons. Will it stay like that? I cannot say. I don't know, but at this moment, in those economies and the same thing as you will see it in Belgium, we are indeed at low levels of cost of risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And I thought Belgium was a bit specific because you had a lot of provision when you consolidated Fortis for the first time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is, well, no, no. There is two things. For having been on both sides, I can tell you. What has happened is that, it's basically the heritage Fortis was put at to the norm of what BNP Paribas is doing. And so, that is basically that. But indeed, there is &#x2013; but it's not necessarily related to that, but indeed, there has been some write-back which have flattered to some extent in the Belgian, the Belgian situation. That is correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Maxence Le Gouvello du Timat, Credit Suisse. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Lars. I will have two quick question. The first one, can you give us more color on the performance of the Insurance, because in such a low interest rate environment, I'm a little bit struggling to see the reason for such a good performance and especially the breakdown between the domestic activities and the foreign one? And then the second question will move back on the fee generation in the French Retail, can you give us a little bit of color of how the fees performance has been between the financial fees and the banking fees and have you seen a massive change of trends on the last months of the quarter in September? Many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's going to be a bit, the theme of this, with respect to your question on Insurance, I am going to give you the same answer. After I said, we're not a French bank, allow me to just indulge myself and say that we're not a French insurer neither, and as you know, part of the Group, actually, of insurance is indeed coming out of the International activities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Which part?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pardon, which part of the International activities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Allow me to quickly look it up. It's basically relatively in most of the parts. So, out of France, in Europe, there is still a good growth. There is double-digit growth if you would look in Asia and the Americas. So, it's relatively similar pace of growth that you would see in both Asia and the Americas. So, that is a bit driving that.</p>
          <p>With respect to the commissions on French Retail, because as somebody has asked indeed, for those we publish it, but I am browsing to the page, but intrinsically there is no material evolution, just allow me to look it up. If you look at it, there is basically no material evolution on the commissions if you compare it to the previous quarter. Overall, if you would look at it nine months on nine months, you would see that there is a little dent on it, which has to do with lower fees related to Financial Markets. Again, given the environment in those markets. So, that one is relatively or is a little bit weighing on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Stefan Stalmann, Autonomous Research. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. And thank you for taking the question. I have two questions, please. The first, looking at your balance sheet from a slightly wider perspective, maybe one or two years out, some of the trends that we have seen in the third quarter are likely to continue. You have weak loan growth or actually declining loans, you have deposits flowing in. You have already 30% of your funded assets in a liquidity buffer. How are you going to deal with this if these circumstances continue for another one or two years and then what are the implications of that kind of dynamics for your revenue?</p>
          <p>And also considering that your costs keep growing at a very measured pace, but nevertheless they do grow, are you planning to do further cost management and then to introduce further cost management measures? The second question and it's a very short one, could you add any color to all &#x2013; to the particular files that were impacted in your CIB division by loan losses? Was it primarily France, was it more International, was there any pattern at all? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you for your question. And with respect to the balance sheet, there is indeed a couple of things. So, first of all, the loans going down is indeed, well, for a big part, driven by the deleveraging. So, that part should basically be over. As we said, it's done, we've taken no prisoners, we move on. So, you should anticipate that &#x2013; the strong decrease that you have seen is not something which you should extrapolate going forward. So, that is basically meaning that there should be a re-deployment into assets that you would have to expect which would, at some point, basically also bring down the accident that we have in the central bank. So, that is &#x2013; so, you cannot take the trend and continue it. You should basically see we've done something. The war is over, we move on. We grow.</p>
          <p>And with respect to cost, of course, we are in a low interest rate environment. For everybody who has looked out, that's what it is, for everybody who's older than 40 years know what it means. It means continued focus on the cost, and we have been doing that. As you can see, if you look quarter-after-quarter at the jaws, look at our Domestic Markets, positive jaws, RBA generation, and so we will continue &#x2013; we will continue to do so.</p>
          <p>With respect to CIB, I mean, I cannot give you any names, you know how that goes. There are periods where there are &#x2013; I mean at CIB, it's not a portfolio approach. The only thing is, there is a slew of things which is spread over several domains and geographies. There is no particular concentration that I have to draw your attention to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Anke Reingen, Royal Bank of Canada. Madam, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon. I have three areas of questions, please. The first one is again on capital management. I understand you remain quite cautious in terms of what you're going to do actually with your 9.5% core Tier 1 ratio relative to the 9% target, but I was just wondering &#x2013; how should we think about giving you the credit for the excess capital in the way or is it far too early to talk about it? So, would we find out maybe with the full year results or is it possible to sort of like rank your priorities in terms of risk-weighted assets growth, dividend, buyback or acquisitions?</p>
          <p>And then secondly on French Retail banking, is it possible to give us a bit of an outlook what you expect for revenues and also, do you expect to continue to deliver your 1%-ish point jaws? And then lastly just on BNL, was a bit surprised to see loan loss charges flat to slightly down, are you surprised as well? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anke, thank you very much for allowing me to clarify this. On your question on capital management, if I paraphrase your question, how to give BNP Paribas credit for its 9.5%, I think the best credit if you allow me just &#x2013; is to say that &#x2013; give us the credit that we can look forward. If we look at the ranking and again of other banks, we are one of the best capitalized. So, for us, we look forward. We have taken off &#x2013; for those who have kids, if you have a band-aid you can rip it off quickly or you can rip it off slowly and I was always told that ripping off quickly is the best way to do. So, we look forward.</p>
          <p>So, we are in a position to grow, we are in a position to help our clients. So, if you want to give us credit, remove the discount that I have versus my tangible net asset value per share. That is how you could give me credit for that. And jokingly aside, as I said, it is too early. I mean the moment things get clearer on regulation, we get &#x2013; hopefully that might allow us to get by the time when the Board and the General Assembly have to clarify things, we might be able to clarify.</p>
          <p>With respect to BNL, am I surprised? No, I think you've heard me say that when we saw the pick-up in the first quarter and the second quarter, we thought that we would be along those waters for the rest of the year and that is basically where we end up being, so there's no surprise from that point of view.</p>
          <p>And on French Retail, or I'd say, a general &#x2013; I mean we have been committed to creating value, we have done this also always expressed by our jaws. You have seen that in Domestic Markets we have done so, and we will continue to do so. And in a low yield environment, the focus will be a bit more on the cost than it is on the top line. But again, you being young, might not have had a full cycle of low interest yields. But that is basically what we will do and continue to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no more questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Then, with this, I want to thank all of you for your interest into BNP Paribas. Be aware that we're fully open for business as we've always been, and this time even with 9.5% capital ratio and ample liquidity. So, thank you again for your interest in the company, and have a very good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the conference call of BNP Paribas Third Quarter 2012 Results. Thank you for participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>