<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1295192" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-03-09</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1555</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Luc A. Vanneste, Executive Vice-President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Rick Waugh, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Brian J. Porter, Group Head, Risk and Treasury</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Christopher J. Hodgson, Group Head, Canadian Banking</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Robert H. Pitfield, Group Head, International Banking</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Mike Durland, Group Head, Global Capital Markets, and Co-Chief Executive Officer, Scotia Capital</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Cheryl Pate</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Steve Theriault</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Brad Smith</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Michael Goldberg</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep">Jeffrey Heath</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">John Reucassel</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Mario Mendonca</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Sumit Malhotra</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Robert Sedran</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Darko Mihelic</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Abrupt Start] Scotia Bank's First Quarter Results. I'm Luc Vanneste, Chief Financial Officer. Rick Waugh, our CEO, will lead off with the highlights of Q1. Next, I will go over the financial results including a review of business line performance. Brian Porter, our Group Head, Risk and Treasury, will then discuss credit quality. Brian will be followed by our business line heads, who will provide an outlook for their respective businesses. We will then be glad to take your questions.</p>
          <p>Before we start, I would like to refer you to slide number two of our presentation, which contains Scotiabank's caution regarding forward-looking statements. Rick, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Luc. Well, as everyone can see, the first quarter was a very strong quarter for us. Net income of 988 million, up 17% from last year. Our earnings per share were $0.91, and that's up 14%. This strong performance has been driven by our business line strategy of sustainable revenue growth together with the disciplined risk management and expense control. This contributed to a very strong return on equity of 17.4% in the first quarter, and this, of course, we take great pride in delivering strong returns to our shareholders and have one of the higher ROEs amongst banks globally.</p>
          <p>We compared our 2009 return on equity to our peers in the FTSE Global Banking Index, and based on reported full year 2009 results and the year-to-date results of those banks who have yet to report, we believe our return on equity is in the top 10%. We were one of only a few banks to increase our earnings in 2009, and the only of the big five Canadian banks to do so. Our credit performance during this downturn, and indeed historically, has been industry leading and this quarter was no exception. Our PCL ratio was 55 basis points, and which continues to be well below the average of our Canadian competitors and even well below our previous highs in past downturns.</p>
          <p>We have always maintained that our conservative underwriting of both retail and wholesale loans has been beneficial, but we continue to benefit from the changes we have made since the previous credit cycle, and you will recall these. Specifically, we reduced our relative exposure to both the United States and Europe. We decreased our industry concentrations and that was led by U.S. commercial real estate.</p>
          <p>We lowered our single name borrowing limits. We exited the high leverage LBO market, but yet, still participate in properly structured acquisition financing. Significantly, we increased the percentage of investment grade loans relative to our total portfolio and we increased the relative size of our retail portfolios, primarily residential mortgages and secured personal lending. These changes are a key reason behind our industry leading PCL ratios. We believe that our outperformance is further proof that risk management continues to be a core competency of Scotia Bank.</p>
          <p>Also this quarter, despite a cautious approach to the market and economy, we established another record for revenues at nearly $4 billion. Each of our business lines made strong contributions and in true Scotia Bank form, we kept a close eye on our expenses during this downturn. We accelerated several cost and productivity initiatives, but as you can see from our topline revenue growth, we have a record productivity ratio, and at the same time, enabled us to maintain a positive operating leverage.</p>
          <p>And from a capital standpoint, we continue to have strong high quality and growing capital ratios with Tier 1 from &#x2013; now up from 10.7% to 11.2% this quarter. Our tangible common equity and our Tier 1 ratios grew by 60 and 50 basis points respectively quarter-over-quarter.</p>
          <p>As our numbers show, we have strong risk metrics and revenue growth and a high level of profitability which demonstrates that our strategies and our &#x2013; in our markets have supported by a high quality and diversified assets have us well-positioned to move forward.</p>
          <p>This diversification combined with core strengths and risk management and expense control has served us well during this downturn and will continue to serve us well as we move through 2010 and beyond. We are achieving our targets and while we cannot remain complacent about potential over-regulation and lower growth rates in developed markets, we believe we have the ability now to capitalize on many opportunities we see before us.</p>
          <p>We entered the downturn stronger than many of our competitors and we are emerging in a stronger position than when we went in. And with that, I'll now turn it over to Luc.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rick. Q1 was a strong quarter. Compared to Q1 '09, increased earnings resulted from broad based strength across our businesses and were driven principally by a higher margin which benefited from repricing, stronger trading and wealth management revenues, and significantly lower available for sale securities write-downs.</p>
          <p>Partly offsetting was a significantly higher tax rate as Q1 included a $55 million write-down of our future tax asset resulting from the Ontario tax rate reductions enacted during Q1. This charge was recorded in the other segment. Also partially offsetting was ForEx, which impacted earnings by $124 million or $0.12 per share versus Q1 '09, and we had a modest increase in specific provisions which were up $90 million year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Looking quarter-over-quarter, earnings were up strongly at 10%. The increase was from higher revenues due to growth across numerous product categories, lower expenses, and a decline in specific provisions. The only major offset was a higher tax rate, and our productivity ratio was a record low this quarter at 50.5%.</p>
          <p>Moving to revenues on slide seven. Q1 revenues were nearly $4 billion, a new quarterly record and up 5% compared to Q4 and 16% higher than last year. The increase from Q4 was driven mostly by broad based gains across most businesses with particular strength resulting from wider spreads in volumes in Canadian retail and international banking, increased trading revenues and securities gains, and the positive impact of financial instruments, partially offsetting were lower credit fees, wholesale loan volumes and a $32 million write-down in the carrying value of our Venezuelan affiliate due to the accounting for hyperinflation. This was partially offset by strong local earnings.</p>
          <p>Looking now at expenses, which were down 3% compared to Q4, resulting in our record productivity ratio. The decline was largely due to seasonal spending on advertising, professional fees and technology, which typically peak in Q4. Last quarter also contained a $23 million expense relating to Visa reward points and higher legal provisions. Both these items show up in other expenses and help explain why this category was down by $94 million from Q4. Partly offsetting these declines were increased salaries and stock-based compensation.</p>
          <p>Turning to capital on slide 9, you can see that our Tier 1 and TCE ratios continued to move higher this quarter. The increases reflect solid internal capital generation, our dividend reinvestment program, and a $6 billion decrease in risk-weighted assets. The decrease in risk-weighted assets is attributed to the planned run-off of several bridge and term loans to clients, which were repaid due to the return of the capital markets. There was also an improvement in credit migration during the quarter as a number of borrowers saw upgrades in internal and external ratings.</p>
          <p>With respect to the proposed Basel capital rules, we are providing feedback to all of the key players, including the IIF, the CBA, OSFI and BIS. In our view, it is unlikely that the proposed rules will be adopted in their entirety. We do expect capital requirements to increase and we are confident that we will comply with whatever regulations are eventually enacted.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the business line results beginning on slide 10. Canadian banking had its third consecutive record quarter with net income of $560 million. Compared to last quarter, net income was up 11%. Revenues benefited from asset and deposit growth, improved spreads on mortgages and personal lines of credits and higher commercial banking revenues, which increased due to lower write-downs of securities, increased credit fees, and higher spreads.</p>
          <p>Effective this quarter, $10 billion of broker sourced deposits were transferred to Canadian banking to better align the product offering with the retail deposit strategy. These thinner spread broker sourced deposits had a negative effect on the margin as the interest rate paid on these deposits is above the 30, 60, 90 day rate which we use to transfer funds to business lines.</p>
          <p>Excluding this transfer, the underlying margin was up quarter-over-quarter. Expenses declined 3% largely due to the $23 million expense relating to Visa reward points in Q4 '09.</p>
          <p>Moving to international banking, net income increased $11 million from Q4 to $294 million. Revenue growth was very strong up 10% benefiting from the positive impact of financial instruments and higher securities gains. Expenses were well managed, down 5% creating high positive operating leverage.</p>
          <p>Part of the decline in expenses was due to timing as advertising and professional fees decreased from seasonally high levels in Q4. In addition, we benefited from the release of the legal provision in Peru. Despite the strong operating leverage and stable PCLs, an unusually high tax rate offset most of the pre-tax earnings growth.</p>
          <p>The increased tax rate was due to lower income in low tax jurisdictions, non-deductibility for tax purposes of the write-down and the carrying value of our Venezuelan affiliate, and a correction of a tax expense related to a prior acquisition.</p>
          <p>Looking at slide 12, Scotia Capital had another strong quarter with net income of $381 million, up 8% from a very strong Q4. Compared to last quarter, revenues were flat. Increased trading revenues in Global Capital Markets were offset by reduced revenues in Global Corporate and Investment Banking. The declines in GCIB were due to lower credit fees which while still very strong were down from a record Q4, also lower Investment Banking fees and loan volumes, partly offsetting was a positive fair value change in securities.</p>
          <p>It is worth noting that this was the second highest trading quarter ever that was accomplished through broad based strength with strong contributions from each of our five trading businesses. This demonstrates the success of the investments we have made in the past couple of years to strengthen and diversify our trading platform. Expenses were up 8% mainly due to higher performance based compensation related to incentive plan changes in Scotia Capital.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn to the other business segment, which incorporates the results of Group Treasury, smaller operating units and certain corporate adjustments. The other segment reported a loss of $247 million in Q1 comparable to the loss last quarter as interest rates remain stable; however, there were two largely offsetting items this quarter.</p>
          <p>First, as I mentioned in my review of Canadian banking, effective this quarter, $10 billion of broker sourced deposits were transferred to Canadian banking to better align the product offering with the retail deposit strategy. Extended price deposits had a relatively higher term funding cost in comparison to the short-term wholesale transfer pricing rates. Second, this quarter, there was a net write-down of our future tax asset related to the recent Ontario tax rate reductions which totaled $55 million.</p>
          <p>Excluding this item, the net loss in other would have been $192 million or $45 million lower than in Q4. This concludes my review of the financial results and I will now pass it over to Brian who will discuss Risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Luc. I will now review the key dimensions of our risk profile. The risk in our credit portfolios continues to be well contained and manageable. We are now clearly seeing gradual improvement in a number of our key credit metrics. This quarter saw further decline in our net impaired loan formations to 511 million from 627 million in Q4 '09 and quite a significant drop from the billion dollars in formations in Q2 '09.</p>
          <p>As a result, our specific provisions were 372 million, down 12% from Q4 '09 and 20% from the level in Q3 '09. We continue to have strong coverage ratios. In particular, our earnings provided five times coverage of provisions this quarter. Our ratio of total allowances to gross impaired loans was 71% and our ratio of total allowances to loans and acceptances remained quite strong at 1.06%.</p>
          <p>Slide 16 shows the trend in net impaired loan formations over the past five quarters. As I mentioned a few moments ago, we are clearly seeing a reduction in net formations since the peak in Q2 of '09. The formations in Canadian banking were essentially flat quarter-over-quarter, as an increase in commercial was offset by a reduction in residential mortgages. The increase in international formations was due entirely to the classification of one large credit in the hotel and leisure sector in the Caribbean, which we had been anticipating for some time. The net declassifications in Scotia Capital largely reflect a number of U.S. accounts that were declassified. On the other hand, one paid-in account was classified this quarter.</p>
          <p>Slide 17 shows the trend in specific provisions over the past five quarters, which generally tracks the trend in net impaired loan formations. As you can see, the decrease in specific provisions this quarter came primarily from Scotia Capital, 14 million versus 65 million in Q4 last year. Turning to retail, we saw a reduction in Canadian provisions this quarter due to some actions we took in 2009. However, we expect retail provisions in both international and Canada to remain at elevated levels. Overall, we are pleased to report our PCL ratio declined to 55 basis points this quarter from last quarters 63 basis points.</p>
          <p>Slide 18 shows the relative performance and specific provisions over the past nine quarters as compared to our Canadian peer group. Although, provisions remained elevated we are encouraged by an improving trend overall. Within that context, however, we are pleased that we have been able to consistently achieve a PCL ratio that is industry leading.</p>
          <p>Overall, we are very comfortable with our asset quality and the positioning of our credit portfolios. We have weathered the worst of the global economic downturn and our portfolios are now responding favorably to the economic recovery that is taking hold here in Canada and elsewhere around in the world albeit on a somewhat lagged basis.</p>
          <p>With respect to our retail portfolios, they are performing as expected. It is worth repeating that retail provisions have traditionally lagged the economic recovery. We expect this pattern to continue through 2010. Our corporate portfolios are performing better than expected. In summary, we believe the level of provisions in our credit portfolios appears to have peaked.</p>
          <p>That concludes my comments on risk on I'll now turn it to Chris &#x2013; over to Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Brian. As Luc indicated, Q1 was a record quarter for Canadian banking with net income of 560 million. We achieved strong market share gains this quarter in both mutual funds and mortgages. Growing our presence in wealth management and in mutual funds in particular is a key priority for us and we've been making good strides over the past three years.</p>
          <p>Scotia Funds was ranked number one for total net sales in the Canadian marketplace for the 2009 calendar year, and in Q1, we had the highest year-over-year market share gains among the six banks of 38 basis points. In addition to our organic growth we continue to be very pleased in our strategic investments at CI and Dundee both of which are performing very well.</p>
          <p>In mortgages, we also had strong market share gains, up nine basis points from Q4. This was the largest quarterly gain among the banks as we continue to benefit from our strong product offerings. Credit performance was stable this quarter down 10 million from Q4.</p>
          <p>Looking forward in 2010, retail portfolios are expected to stabilize and benefit from a gradual economic recovery and modest reductions in employment levels. Provisions in the commercial portfolios are also expected to decline. Expenses continue to be well managed.</p>
          <p>The Q1 versus Q4 decline is typical and was not unexpected given the VISA rewards points expense incurred in Q4. Expenses will likely increase through 2010 but we will do so while maintaining positive operating leverage which continues to be a key priority for Canadian banking.</p>
          <p>On the revenue side, we see continued opportunities in our Wealth business. For example, the integration of our direct investing businesses under Scotia iTRADE continues to progress. In insurance, the launch of ScotiaLife Financial with a number of new products and partnerships is a key focus for us and finally we continue to accelerate the business development efforts within commercial banking. Revenue growth should come from increased market confidence as well as investments we've been making in our key businesses. I'll now turn it over to Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris. Overall we're pleased with the results this quarter. Our markets are still feeling the impact of the global economic slowdown. We anticipate stronger GDP growth in our major markets such as Mexico and Peru by the second half of 2010 and into 2011, although it will take some time before this translates into higher loan growth.</p>
          <p>In Q1, volume growth continued to be slow; however, we were able to offset this with continued strengthen margins as well as a focus on ancillary businesses such as wealth and insurance. As our markets rebound, we are systematically reviewing all our geographies and business lines to determine where and when we could prudently ease our lending policies.</p>
          <p>We are aggressively managing day-to-day expenses and I think we're doing it well. We're also improving the efficiency of our platform by looking at our procurement practices, consolidating the systems and processes in our operations and investing in technology that improves the customer experience while reducing costs. These actions are paying off as you can see through our productivity ratio of 51.4%.</p>
          <p>Finally, acquisitions continue to be a key part of our strategy. Earlier this month, we announced an agreement to acquire the Royal Bank of Scotland's wholesale banking operations in Columbia. This acquisition which is subject to regulatory approval will enhance our unique Latin America footprint which already includes strong operations in Central America, Mexico, Chile and Peru. In summary, 2010 has started well. We have a very good, very resilient international franchise and we're cautiously optimistic about the year ahead.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll turn it over.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob. Scotia Capital had a strong quarter highlighted by strong diversified global capital markets revenues and lower PCLs in global, corporate and investment banking. From a credit perspective, the portfolio continues to perform very well. Loan volumes, however, have been soft because of the result of several factors. One, companies have taken advantage of the capital markets to refinance bank debt. And two, there's been a lack of M&amp;A activity. In addition to this, our loan balances have contracted in Canadian dollar terms as a result of the weaker U.S. dollar.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, we remain confident in our portfolio, but provisions may not remain at this low level for the remainder of 2010. In terms of pricing, lending margins have stabilized and we are feeling some downward pressure in spreads, which will offset the effect of the recent repricing. Investment banking had a solid quarter. However, revenues did decline from Q4, which was a very strong quarter. Global Capital Markets had a strong quarter, generated through broad based strength. We have strong performances in fixed income, ScotiaMocatta and derivatives, and solid performances in FX and equities.</p>
          <p>In terms of market tone, we continue to see the capital markets normalize. Liquidity has improved significantly and the competitive landscape is returning to normal. In terms of headwinds, concerns continue to emerge around European sovereign risk. This together with the evolving regulatory situation has created a significant level of uncertainty in the market, which is affecting the risk appetite, CapEx, and M&amp;A. As a result, we expect GCM revenues to be more normalized in the next several quarters. We continue to remain focused on executing our strategy of investing in segments and businesses, which provide opportunities for sustainable revenue growth. Energy trading, fixed income, emerging markets and global wholesale banking.</p>
          <p>And with that I'll pass it back to Luc.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mike. That concludes our prepared remarks. And we'd be pleased to take your questions. Operator, can we have the first question on the phone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your first question today comes from Cheryl Pate of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I just had a quick question for Rob Pitfield on the &#x2013; I understand that one of the loans was the major reason for the increase in impaired. Can you give us a sense of the underlying trends for the rest of the portfolio, retail versus commercial?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The commercial portfolio, Cheryl, as you probably know, has been basically pristine for the last several years with the exception of this one loan, the portfolio continues to be very solid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how is the retail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the retail has, again, I think, been well managed since really the summer of 2009, we've been spot on where our retail provisions have ended up and we're right on plan right now. So we're feeling very good about it. There's a certain softness in the Caribbean, in the Bahamas and Jamaica, and that's been an issue for a while. It's being addressed well. Mexico, we think that that portfolio has solidified very well and it's ahead of plan as far as its PCLs go so overall, it's trending well and in line with our expectations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. That's helpful. And just a second question for Chris Hodgson. I wonder if you can give us sort of an outlook for your view on loan growth and the margin for the year. Is the full impact of the reprice on the unsecured portfolio in the run rate at this point in particular?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we experienced good loan growth as you can see from this past quarter. We actually believe that through the balance of the year, we will still have reasonable growth in that area in spite of some of the competitive pressures and in terms of the repricing of the portfolio, we still believe that there is some modest margin uptake or uptick over the course of the balance of the year, but as you know, the competitive side is quite aggressive at this time and that's actually moderating some of the pricing increases that we did last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Steve Theriault of Bank of America, Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. A question to start for Brian Porter, if I might, hoping to get some additional details on the Caribbean hotel exposures. So Brian, has visibility improved there over the last couple of months? How has the winter tourist season been playing out and what does the watch list look like versus a quarter ago?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Just to add on what Rob said to the prior question is the large classification this quarter was something that we identified a number of quarters ago. It's a fluid situation, we're negotiating with a variety of different stakeholders and we've got vast experience working the Caribbean in terms of restructuring these type of loans, so we'll work it through like we have in the past.</p>
          <p>The tourism season is spotty at best at the low end of the market. It's quite active and quite blunt. At the high end of the market, it tends to be all right. It's the middle part of the market that's still feeling some sort of stress. It varies from country to country, but I think it's fair to say from both a commercial perspective and a retail perspective the Caribbean would be our most challenged part of the portfolio and we're going to see that for the balance of the year and it's going to take some time to work things out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to follow on the numbers there maybe it looked to me like about 40 million of provisions against the impaired which again looked to me like about 150 million, so a pretty sizeable write down and I guess I'm having trouble reconciling that with the average LTV I think that you provided on the portfolio previously of about 40%, so I don't think I understand why there would be such a sizeable provision, maybe I'm not getting the math quite right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, no, you've got the math right, the gross impaired loan is about 150 million. The provision is about 38 million to be exact. This is a one loan that conditions change rather dramatically. I can tell you I'm reinforced that on the balance of the portfolio, LTVs are very conservative in the 40-50% range and as I said on prior calls that if you look at the top 10 gross impaired loans in the bank, three or four of them would be classified without a provision because we're very comfortable with the underlying value of the property. This was a fluid situation between a developer and a complicated development project restructuring. And unfortunately, given events, it's gone sideways. So we have some work to do and it's going to take some time to work it out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks for that color. If I could just follow-on with one more for Chris Hodgson, two-part question; the efficiency ratio in the quarter, quite impressive at just over 50%. Could we reasonably expect that figure to head south of 50% in any sustainable fashion in the near-term? Is there anything unusual we should be aware of going through the line this quarter? And then secondly, you mentioned the market share gains on the mortgage side, but a pretty big pick-up in personal lending, looks like about 40 basis points of sequential improved share in personal lending. That's as big a jump as I can remember ever seeing on a sequential basis. So Chris, could you talk a bit about the nature and the sustainability of the share gains there? That's it for me. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the efficiency, we've indicated in the past that one of our goals is to show positive operating leverage for the business, and so we don't make any predictions quarter-to-quarter. I think that in terms of the quarter we just went through, we managed the expenses very, very well. There was some seasonality to it. We're going to continue to make investments in some of our key growth strategies going forward. So you will see some movement in that efficiency ratio as the year goes on. But we're very diligent. We watch it very, very closely. We will expect to see expenses rise somewhat through the balance of the year, given some of the things that we're doing.</p>
          <p>So I'm hesitant to give any projection on that ratio, but it is something we watch very, very closely and we've made it very clear that it's something we're going to continue to generate a good number on. On the market share gains for personal lending and mortgages, yes, we did have a very good first quarter. We are seeing some pretty stiff competition right now in terms of pricing, but we actually feel good because we have a two-pronged approach both in our direct and indirect channels.</p>
          <p>We're number one in the broker channel in terms of a market share on that side and that gives us an opportunity to do quite a bit of cross-selling. We are employing a number of strategies on the direct side to grow our lending. 45 basis points was a big gain and it would be not realistic to assume that we'll necessarily have that type of market share gain going forward. But we expect to continue to have market share gains over the balance of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Brad Smith of CI Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thank you very much. I had two quick questions. First of all, just with respect to your Caribbean hotel portfolio. If somebody could just refresh my memory as to sort of the order of magnitude of the in-force loans there. And then two quick questions, you've referred several times to a legal provision released in Peru. And then in your Mexican operations to a gain on the sale of a pension related business, I was wondering if you could just quantify those for me. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'll take the last two questions there. On the sale of the pension assets, that was 11 million after-tax, Brad. Legal provisions, that was related to our acquisition initially and a case was heard that was in our favor, so we could reduce the legal provision that we had originally set up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And so did that impact earnings in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was around $15 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>After-tax?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>After-tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then just again with the hotel portfolio, what is the order of magnitude of the total portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The total portfolio, Brad, is about C$1.4 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Michael Goldberg of Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. A question for Brian. Your loss provision continues to run lower than your net formations, your net NPLs continue to rise. You also say the overall provisions appear to have crested. Should I conclude that you see net formations falling back significantly from where they are now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think, Michael, the trend that we're seeing, I think it's fair to say that provisions peaked in Scotia Capital and some of the other business lines in Q3 last year. The formations that we've seen are ones again that we identified some quarters ago, so it's no surprise that they're coming through the system, they are working their way through the system. We would expect economic conditions being stable and normalized here that the gross impaired and the net impaired numbers will start to tail off here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And with the significant swing in unrealized available for sale gains, should we be looking for higher investment gains to continue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll respond to that one. I think as I mentioned on the call last quarter, we would see moderate gains potential this year, probably roughly in line with what the first quarters looked like, not outsized gains that we might have seen in some of the prior years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You mean, continuing at about 90 million in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In that neighborhood, yes. It would be a reasonable expectation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and finally, can you comment on the competitive situation and the Canadian residential mortgage market? Could I conclude that some of the rates that are out there right now, you would be meeting through your broker channel but your rates would remain probably somewhat higher on proprietary originations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, it's Chris Hodgson and the short answer is, yes. It's a very competitive marketplace and what's going on is that with the repricing of the retail loan portfolios last year, a number of institutions are giving that back right now in terms of some margins, so a couple of competitors as you know are at 375 on five years and through our broker channel, we have the ability to go to a level that's very competitive.</p>
          <p>It's slightly higher than that, but we also have discretion in our direct channel to be very competitive, so we're watching the market very, very closely, but we want to be careful about generating profitable margins also.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. So you in effect have a chance to sort of split the margin that you earn on this product because, that would be &#x2013; would it be fair to say that you've got the potential to split the margin because of the diversity of channels that you have?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we don't quite look at it as splitting the margin. We look at it as a coordinated strategy, so about 52% of our sales are coming through the direct channel, 48 through the indirect side, and we've actually put it all under common leadership too. John Webster who is the Head of Our Maple Trust business is responsible for all of our mortgage business through the Canadian banking side. So it's very much an integrated strategy and not looked at in terms of gross margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you find that you have the same success in cross-selling through the broker channel as through the direct channel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There has been less success in the broker channel, but that again is something that's been worked at very aggressively by the management team, and we think that there is some good upside there but clearly, the direct side has shown historically that there's a greater cross-sell opportunity. Michael, Jeff Heath wants to make another comment on your earlier question. Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, just back to the AFS securities question, while we think that we're not going to see outsized gains in prior years, which is where I started my comments, given some expected volatility in the markets, there is still the potential for write-downs. So it's hard to predict a very forward view, so there could be some volatility in those numbers going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from John Reucassel of BMO Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you and a question for Rick or Rob. There was a transaction for Butterfield recently. Could you comment why you passed or were there just other opportunities, or was it valuation or you're full up in the Caribbean? Could you provide some comments on that or some thoughts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't comment on any specific M&amp;A transaction, it's a long policy and we are going to continue that policy. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Rick, and then maybe I'll ask you one other question. You did mention that the capital rules are unlikely to be implemented as proposed. Is there any specific rules you don't think they will be included? Or is there just overall limits or could you add some color on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The color I would add would be gray because I think or cloudy or whatever you want to use. It's too early and there's a lot of confusion out there in the international arena based on these Basel III and all the international banks are busy putting their numbers together to get back to their local regulator by April 30. And I'm sure you've all studied those 70 to 100 pages of data. And let me say this, there's very little &#x2013; there's no clarity yet from the policy setters and won't be for a while.</p>
          <p>Having said that, any rational look at those will mean that there's lots of issues that would have to be solved before they could come out with more specific proposals. So it's uncertain. What I will say is from our own perspective and we're still continuing to work on this thing. I don't see anything in there. I mean, we all expect at the end of the day more capital and better quality. But as for Scotia Bank, the quality of our capital is the gold medal. And also the level of capital for the Canadian banks is the gold standard.</p>
          <p>And so we'll be able to work those things, but the whole international framework has some challenges ahead if they were to go forward with those initial proposals and therefore one could conclude the probability as seen &#x2013; what you saw on December 17, actually seeing the light of day in its entirety is very slim, but one we all have to take seriously in our forward planning but as I say one that we believe we can manage through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for that and just last question for Chris or Brian. On the Canadian HELOC portfolio, could you tell us the size of that portfolio or &#x2013; and what the LTVs might be on that portfolio and would you make a HELOC loan to someone that doesn't have a residential mortgage with you?</p>
          <p>A &#x2013; Brian Porter&gt;: I'll start on it. We would not make a HELOC loan on an individual where we didn't have a mortgage. The size of the portfolio, there's two basic portfolios here. There's a secured line of credit and there's an unsecured line of credit. One portfolio was about 18 billion and the other portfolio in a round number is about 12 billion.</p>
          <p>We watch those portfolios closely in terms of trends and in terms of outstanding and drawdowns in a climate like we've been through over the course of the past year-and-a-half, two years in terms of how it affects our customers overall debt service capability, those type of things and how it may affect the overall mortgage market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And would the secure line be the 18 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Mario Mendonca with Genuity Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question for Rob, there were a lot of moving parts in international this quarter. Excluding some of those things, actually maybe start with loans first, ex of anything to do with currency or acquisitions, what would you say the loan growth was year-over-year, quarter-over-quarter. Would it be fair to say it was about down 3% &#x2013; up 3% in retail and down 6% in commercial? Would that be a fair characterization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That would be about right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And aside from the loan growth because I understand that loan demand has changed, is there anything you can offer us in terms of &#x2013; is that business still growing and maybe you could talk about the number of customers or market share, anything like that you can offer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mario, I think what you've got is a very good set of countries and there's weakness as Brian was alluding, there is weakness in the Caribbean, certain of the English Caribbean countries so they are not experiencing the growth that they have historically. That will come back and it will be dependent in part on how the United States does, but the rest of these countries, if you go by country by country, Mexico has been through a tough time.</p>
          <p>You saw a bunch of banks come on line and a bunch of PCLs flood the market but that's largely being managed now. The growth is starting to come back into that portfolio and I think that Mexico will be fine. I think Chile and Peru, we've gone through integrations. The countries themselves are good. All three countries should have GDP growth of around 4%, so all three countries will start to grow normally and we're just waiting for that to occur. We're seeing signs of that right now, through Central America, Central America has been very stable for us and its loan growth will start, so this was the country itself but it was also precautionary moves that we took in terms of wanting to safeguard our portfolios. And we're looking at that, as I said in my notes, we're looking at that as well. So that loan growth will come back. It may be the latter part of 2010, it maybe 2011, but they will do fine. As far as the English Caribbean, as far as PCLs, etcetera, they've pretty well been stabilized and the growth might take a little longer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So perhaps just to paraphrase in there, there hasn't been much in the way of customer loan growth in international recently but you're still confident that the fundamentals are there to drive that loan growth, say, late in 2010 and into 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's fair.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the fundamentals haven't changed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then maybe a final question, in terms of the Bank's capital base and some of the discussions around acquisitions in the press, how large a transaction could Scotia do? And I'm not sort of asking about CI or any of your wealth management, I'm talking more about the international business. How large an acquisition could the bank do with cash that is not having to raise equity to finance the deal? Is it something like about $1 billion dollars before or could you do that on your own?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm not going to give you the number. Every investment banker in the world would be listening for it. And again, it's not a number I really want to talk about. Having said that, look at our history and what we have said, we've resisted doing transformational acquisitions. We don't like large acquisitions, regardless of what the environment is. So we like to build on what we've got and what we're talking about are add-ons. And we think adding on in moderate size is better than doing something de novo and big size.</p>
          <p>And you can see by our past acquisitions, we've done a lot in the last two years. And those numbers that are out there will be a good indication of what you have. But I'm not going to quote a number because you just don't know what you don't know. But again, we're going to prudently manage and see what happens and manage our capital and our cash accordingly. So I'm not specifically obviously answering the question right now, but other than we see opportunities and we will prudently look at them as they come up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just squeeze in one final question. Is the bank still positioned for higher interest rates and how would that manifest itself? Would we see the benefit in retail or not in retail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeff, do you want to answer that please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll deal with the first part of the question. Yeah, so in the Canadian balance sheet, we would still be positioned for rising rates in particular short-term rates. Our foreign currency balance sheet tends to be a bit mixed and where we're not positioned that way, it's largely due to bond positions, which we could change fairly quickly should we take a view that that needs to be done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the effect on retail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pardon me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The effect on retail, Chris?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think as the year goes on, if rates start to move up, there will be an impact. That being said, this quarter we did transfer in, as Luc indicated, 10 billion in broker deposits, which has helped reduce our funding gap. But we still do have that funding gap within the Canadian business and as the year goes on, that will have an impact. That will be moderated though by some of the pricing changes that we've made over the last year or so both in our commercial and retail portfolios. And also some of the growth that we expect to come from our strategies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to be clear the impact would be negative but offset by things like the broker deposits and the repricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Sumit Malhotra of Macquarie Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. First for Luc on the 55 million tax write-down in other, did you say that was almost completely offset by the transfer of the broker deposits to Canadian banking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No, I didn't say that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How much is the difference there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's about 15, 20.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, 20 million. Let's stay with that interest margin for a minute and this might be for Jeff as well going back to some of the last topics. Net interest margin for Scotia, since you had a big increase from the bottom in Q1 to Q2 in 2009, since then it's been pretty flat in the 175 level, whereas most of your peer group has continued to see increases. Does this really come back to the asset sensitivity of the bank that we're not going to see that margin change too much? We heard some comments from Chris and from Mike Durland on Scotia Capital that we shouldn't see too much change in NIM. It looks like it's more on your asset base than it is on the funding side. So when I think about Scotia's NIM, is it really status quo until we see short-term interest rates increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would think when you look at the other segment, slide 13, the funding net interest income, I don't think we expect to see a significant change in that line item for the next few quarters and that will largely be driven off increasing short rates when it does change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the decline in that line or shall we say the reduction in funding cost will be as that line, we'll see that line start to move lower?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, as short rates move up, that line should come down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so that's really the catalyst here to get all bank NIM moving higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There will be asset repricing both on our wholesale portfolios and definitely because the customers have been reluctant to reprice because it means higher prices and so that will be in effect and we're I don't know maybe half way through that one that's going to be positive and then of course, as Chris has committed to me right now, he's going to get much more add-on on his retail portfolios and certainly with what we see in international. Now we aren't going to give you quarterly proposals but we are going to drive it so the spread increases, but we aren't going to give you a number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That leads me to the question number two which is more for Mike and Steve McDonald and Scotia Capital. I was kind of surprised to hear that comment that net interest margin in the corporate loan book for Scotia Capital is now starting to see downward pressure. It seems in the new world order of pricing risk capital, it seems kind of early for us to be thinking about NIM having already peaked there so that's one point and to overlay that with trading, you guys have been pretty candid in saying that capital markets revenue should normalize.</p>
          <p>Yet we have a quarter in which both trading securities average and as that seem like they're pretty flat and your spread on your trading business still seems pretty wide so maybe just a review on what's happening in the corporate banking NIM if I can call it that, and which areas of the trading business you see as most likely to normalize here in the near term? I'll leave it there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on the banking side, I think the word I used was stabilized. It has &#x2013; we have seen spread levels stabilize. In terms of the downward pressure on our net interest margin, a lot of that's coming from the improved liquidity and the reduced bid offer spread in the trading businesses, which are reflecting that. On the trading business, I've been of the view for the past couple of quarters that we're going to continue to see normalization.</p>
          <p>And what I mean by that is we're starting to see the return of the competitive landscape, so there's more competitors participating in the business. The liquidity has improved remarkably. We've got some regulatory headwinds, which I think has disrupted that a little bit. So we were normalizing relatively quickly some of the headwinds and the regulatory landscape have affected that. But I am still of the view that you're going to see over the next couple quarters a continued move towards normalized capital markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I could just add, Steve's not with us today, so on the trading portfolios and what I would call the spot market, the spreads have normalized to use Mike's word. And on our corporate lending, we're not seeing the peaks for new money that we saw a few months ago. But on our existing outstanding portfolio, assuming that that rolls over and doesn't get paid out on capital markets bonds and equities, which it has been happening to some of the rollovers, that rollover because these are loans that are put on in the heady days of '06 and '07, as they mature over a duration of two to three years, will start to come in. And that will be add-ons even at these levels of normalized spot rates. So we see spreads probably being right now appropriate given the risk returns of what you see now. These spreads though are certainly higher than they were in '06 and '07 and that's where we get that formula from.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Robert Sedran of [CIBC] (sic) [National Bank Financial Brokers] Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. Just a couple of quick ones. Luc, even excluding that write-down that you mentioned, the tax rate was still pretty high. Was most of that just the noise in the international segment and can we expect the consolidated rate to settle back down to a more normal rate next quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on a full year basis, Rob, we're sticking with our 22 to 26% range for taxes, but I expect it will be at the high end of that range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks and Rick, just a follow-up on one of Mario's question even though I fear I may get the same answer. You mentioned that you've got a gold medal balance sheet, but it does seem like you have a number of potential opportunities for investments in the coming years. So most of your peers issued stock at much lower levels. Is now a good time to think about bulking up a little bit more or would you prefer to go and get it only if and when you need it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again, if we saw an outstanding opportunity and our return on invested capital of that opportunity makes sense, I believe the cost of capital certainly more appropriate now than it was a year or so ago. So we obviously have got a good capacity to raise additional capital and at a cost and a price which is much more attractive, but it depends on the opportunities we see.</p>
          <p>We're going to keep the discipline on our numbers and make sure it's on the strategy, so we're blessed quite frankly with what we always wanted optionality, and we entered this cycle with I remember a lot of you guys calling, not you of course but others, excess capital and we did use a little bit from acquisitions and still made a prudential level and paid our dividends and how this world turns out in the next two years is obviously there's a bunch of ranges but with return on equity of over 17% depending on what we do with our risk-based assets which will be dependent upon the risk return we see in them.</p>
          <p>We could be self-financing even with acquisitive strategies, but if we saw something special out there, our people tell us and I certainly believe it, we've got lots of access to capital but the numbers are going to work. The numbers work a lot easier now today than they did a year ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One last question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Darko Mihelic of Cormark Securities, Inc.. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I get to be last, a few questions actually then, so I'll sneak a few in. I wanted to go on international a little bit more. I think we've got some color here on some of the items that hit in the quarter but one of the things you talk about in your MD&amp;A was the $22 million movement in fair value on some instruments for asset liability. How should I view that? Is that one-time in nature and is that really just coming from Treasury?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, those were mainly interest rate swaps that didn't qualify for hedge accounting, Darko, so you're going to have some fluctuation quarter-over-quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So why was international banking the beneficiary of those and not the other segments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They're in our Latin operations specifically in Chile.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then a question then for Rob with respect to, you mentioned there was a review on when and where to loosen credit standards as they start to grow balances and you mentioned that you really don't see any growth happening until like late this year and maybe 2011. I'm interested also in the deposit side of the equation. It looks like you had 3% deposit growth. What kind of growth is that? I mean, is that good high quality deposit growth or is that sort of fast money commercial kind of thing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, it's locally the deposit growth is well over 10% and it's really core stuff. We've concentrated very much on building up quality day-to-day deposits and we have been very successful doing that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I'll just add a little color to that. Our international business is essentially a locally funded business, not a globally funded business, and of course, with all the things you're hearing in the regulatory world, it's important to understand that our international business is basically local funded and local business and so it is retail or core deposits and each of these countries do have a wholesale market, but it's not a global wholesale. What global wholesale funding we do is in our wholesale books, which is in Scotia Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Darko, just a follow-up to that, we put on 300 branches in Mexico over the last three years, so those are starting to build up their deposits. It's been a focus in Mexico because of the hard attention we have on loan growth to grow that part of the balance sheet and if you look at other operations like Peru and Chile where we've got larger retail operations, larger branch networks, there's been a focus there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and just last question. You mentioned that one of the things, apart from the Venezuelan write-down, one of the things that hurt your income tax in international was that you had a lot of low income or you had lower income from low income tax jurisdictions. Why would that change in the next couple of quarters? And I'd imagine that that would be one of the drivers of getting back to your 22 to 26% tax rate. Why would that change though in the next couple of quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're hoping to generate higher income in those jurisdictions than we did this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood, but where would that come from? Where is &#x2013; I mean, from my understanding, the low tax jurisdiction would be basically Bahamas and Barbados where it didn't sound like you were all that optimistic on the business prospect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, some of our local provisioning, of course, would change and that will have an effect on your tax rate if it comes from a low tax rate jurisdiction. So it's not a, let me say, a revenue driven on your tax rate. It's provisions that are not as totally tax effective when you take them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, understood. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for joining us on the call today. Have a great day. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>