<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1317377" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-06-01</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1555</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Luc A. Vanneste, Executive Vice-President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Rick Waugh, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Brian J. Porter, Group Head, Risk and Treasury</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Christopher J. Hodgson, Group Head, Canadian Banking</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Robert H. Pitfield, Group Head, International Banking</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Stephen D. McDonald, Group Head, Global Corporate and Investment Banking, and Co-Chief Executive Officer, Scotia Capital</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Rob Sedran</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Michael Goldberg</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Andre-Philippe Hardy</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Mario Mendonca</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Steve Theriault</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Sumit Malhotra</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="corprep">Mike Durland</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="corprep">Jeffrey Heath</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">John Reucassel</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Brad Smith</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, and welcome to the presentation of Scotia Bank's Second Quarter Results. I'm Luc Vanneste, Chief Financial Officer. Rick Waugh, our CEO will lead off with the highlights of Q2. Next, I will go over the financial results, including a review of business line performance. Brian Porter, our Group Head, Risk and Treasury, will then discuss credit quality. Brian will be followed by our business line heads, who will provide a second half outlook for their respective businesses. We will then be glad to take your questions.</p>
          <p>Before we start, I would like to refer to slide number 2 of our presentation, which contains Scotiabank's caution regarding forward-looking statements. Rick, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Luc. Well, as you've now been able to see, the second quarter was a record quarter for us. Net income of almost 1.1 billion and earnings per share of $1.02. Both net income and earnings per share were up 26% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Our results reflected strong contributions from personal and commercial banking, wealth management, as well as excellent performance from our wholesale businesses. International Banking has not reached its potential due to foreign exchange and global economic headwinds. However, it is substantially achieving the plan we set out for it at the beginning of the year. Its underlying operations are sound, and we expect improvement going forward.</p>
          <p>Our return on equity continues to be very strong, at 19.9% this quarter, which is at the top end of our target range and places us very favorably among our global peers. One of the reasons we've been able to produce such a high return on equity is because of our strong risk management performance during the downturn. The second quarter was no different. PCLs were down quarter-over-quarter for the third straight quarter, a clear sign that our credit portfolios are improving. Market risk was well maintained, yet yielded very satisfactory results across a broad range of client-related products.</p>
          <p>During the second quarter, we made 2 notable investments. First, Thanachart Bank, which is 49% owned by Scotiabank, announced the acquisition of Siam City Bank in Thailand. This is in line with our commitment to grow in Asia. In particular, it expands our existing presence in Thailand, making us the fifth largest bank and the third largest bank in the important Bangkok market, which is a very attractive market.</p>
          <p>Despite recent turmoil, Thailand remains a growing economy, solid sovereign debt rating, a stable currency, and a trade surplus. It also has a large population, 66 million people with favorable demographics. While the political environment is unsettled, we do not expect that this will affect our results or our strategy.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we acquired R-G Premier Bank in Puerto Rico in an FDIC-assisted deal. This gives us important critical mass in Puerto Rico, with over 10% market share in deposits. The FDIC covers 80% of loan losses, which limits our downside risk substantially.</p>
          <p>However, it is the growth potential which is exciting for us. Underlying the 3 significant FDIC-assisted deals that were done is a significant rationalization of the Puerto Rican financial system, underpinned with a $6 billion fiscal stimulus provided from the U.S. and a major fiscal austerity plan undertaken by Puerto Rico.</p>
          <p>While the Puerto Rican economy has been under pressure for some time, almost 4 years now, prospects are much better with a return to economic growth forecast. Both of these investments are consistent with our growth strategy in a disciplined and a consistent manner. We were able to take advantage of these opportunities because of our strong capital position, and our ability to generate capital internally, and our strong on the ground presence in these countries.</p>
          <p>In summary, we are very pleased with our results, both this quarter and year-to-date. These results position us well to meet and/or exceed our targets for 2010.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll pass it off to Luc and then the rest of our management team.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Rick. Q2 was a very strong quarter. Compared to last year, increased earnings resulted from broad-based strength across our businesses and were driven principally by significantly lower PCLs, strong contributions from personal and commercial banking, as well as wealth management, and higher securities gains and trading revenues.</p>
          <p>These positives were partly offset by foreign exchange, which impacted earnings by $112 million or $0.11 per share compared to Q2 '09, higher expenses and lower securitization revenues compared to a record level last year.</p>
          <p>Looking quarter-over-quarter, earnings were up strongly, 11%. The increased was from several factors, including higher securities gains in trading revenues, lower provisions for credit losses, decreased expenses, given the shorter quarter, and the lower tax rate versus Q1, which was unusually high. Our return on equity was extremely strong at 19.9% and our productivity ratio was a record low this quarter at just under 50%.</p>
          <p>Moving to revenues on slide 7, revenue generation continues to be very strong, up 7% year-over-year or 15%, excluding Forex. We benefited from solid underlying net interest income, increased wealth management and trading revenues, and higher securities gains, which also benefited from fewer write-downs. The strong increase came despite a $197 million decline in securitization revenues.</p>
          <p>Q2 revenues came in just under the record level earned in Q1 despite 3 fewer days in the quarter. Other income was particularly strong, driven by higher securities gains, stronger trading and increased wealth management revenues. Partly offsetting were lower underwriting and transaction-based fees. Net interest income was down versus Q1 due to a slight decrease in the margin and the impact of 3 fewer days in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Expenses were up 4% compared to last year, or 9% excluding Forex. The increase was largely due to higher performance and stock-based compensation. Expenses were down 2% compared to Q1. The decline was largely due to 3 factors; lower stock-based compensation, mainly due to timing; the positive effect of FX; and the impact of a shorter quarter.</p>
          <p>Partly offsetting these declines were higher performance-based compensation in line with our strong results. We expect expenses to normalize in the second half of 2010, and consequently do not believe that this quarter's productivity ratio is sustainable.</p>
          <p>Turning to capital on slide 9, you can see that our TCE and Tier 1 ratios remain strong at 8.8% and 11.2% respectively. Even with our investments in Thailand and Puerto Rico, our ratios remain constant with Q1. This demonstrates our commitment to maintaining strong capital ratios. We were able to maintain our ratios because of the following:</p>
          <p>We had strong internal capital generation of $543 million for the quarter and $980 million for the year-to-date. We also had $172 million contribution from our dividend reinvestment plan, and we did a $265 million preferred share issue. There was no movement in risk-weighted assets despite adding $5 billion in loans in Puerto Rico.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the business line results, beginning on slide 10. Canadian Banking continues to exhibit strong earnings momentum. Q2 marked its fourth consecutive record quarter with net income of $584 million, up 42% year-over-year. Revenues were particularly strong, up 17%, driven by strong assets and deposit growth, the higher margin, and increased wealth management revenues.</p>
          <p>Compared to last quarter, net income was up 4%. Revenues benefited from a higher margin due to improved spreads on deposits and the short quarter impact of monthly-pay mortgages and higher wealth management revenues driven by solid underlying growth and higher contribution from CI, principally due to the tax recovery announced in CI's fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Expenses declined 1% as the impact of the shorter quarter more than offset growth related to spending. In the second half, we expect Canadian Banking expenses to rise as we continue our growth initiatives.</p>
          <p>Moving to International Banking on slide 10, net income was down 13% year-over-year. However, if you exclude Forex, the decrease was only 1%. Quarter-over-quarter, earnings decreased slightly to $288 million. Revenues decreased 8% versus Q1. Excluding Forex, the decrease was 6%.</p>
          <p>The decline was all in net interest income due to the following factors: We had margin compression in the Caribbean, lower treasury results in Mexico and Chile, and an unfavorable fair value change in financial instruments used for asset and liability management. This was primarily attributable to a swing in forwards used to hedge inflation index mortgages in Chile, reflecting a sharp increase in inflation expectations following the earthquakes there. Fair values of these instruments have largely recovered since the second quarter ended.</p>
          <p>On the positive side, other income increased benefiting from higher insurance revenues in the Caribbean and increased securities gains. Higher securities gains were due to a $36 million gain on the bank shares in Siam City Bank prior to its acquisition by Thanachart Bank.</p>
          <p>Expenses in International Banking continued to be well managed, down 4% compared to last quarter. Part of the decline was due to Forex, the remainder was due to lower professional expenses and seasonal reasons. Overall, the results were somewhat disappointing. However, International Banking's operations are substantially in line with its planned objectives set out at the beginning of the year.</p>
          <p>Looking at slide 10, Scotia Capital had its second best record ever with net income of $391 million, up 19% from Q2 '09. The increase was due to continued strong revenues and a significant drop in PCLs, which more than offset higher expenses. Quarter-over-quarter, earnings were up $10 million from a very strong Q1. Compared to last quarter, revenues decreased 5% due to lower loan volumes as borrowers continued to refinance debt in the capital markets. There was also a small decrease in loan spreads and slightly lower, although still very strong, trading revenues.</p>
          <p>Within trading, institutional equities had a particularly strong quarter. Expenses decreased 3% compared to Q1 due to lower performance-based compensation, as the changes to the incentive compensation plan impacted the first quarter to a larger degree.</p>
          <p>Lastly, Scotia Capital had an exceptional performance from a credit standpoint with net recoveries of $24 million. This was due to a $19 million reversal of a portion of the sectoral allowance and net recoveries and reversals across the remainder of the portfolio.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn to the Other business segment, which incorporates the results of Group Treasury, smaller operating units and certain corporate adjustments. The Other segment reported a loss of $166 million in Q2, an improvement of $81 million from the prior quarter. As you will recall, Q1 included net write-downs of future tax assets related to the recent Ontario tax rate reductions, which totaled $55 million.</p>
          <p>After adjusting for this, the net loss in the Other category has improved by $26 million from last quarter. This improvement was driven by higher realized gains on bonds and equities, as well as lower write-downs on available-for-sale securities. In addition, there was a positive impact from slightly lower term funding costs and the shorter quarter.</p>
          <p>This concludes my review of our financial results. I'll now turn it over to Brian, who will discuss risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Luc. I will now review the key dimensions of our risk profile. The risk in our credit portfolios continues to be well managed. We have clearly seen steady improvement in a number of our key credit metrics. We saw a further decline in our specific provisions and net impaired loan formations this quarter.</p>
          <p>With concerns about the automotive sector having largely abated, we reversed 19 million of the sectoral allowance we established in Q2 '09. We will likely reverse the remaining sectoral allowance over the next quarter or two.</p>
          <p>We continue to have strong coverage ratios that improved in the quarter. With respect to the R-G Premier Bank loans acquired a month ago, our loss sharing agreement with the FDIC has been structured in such a way as to limit downside risk.</p>
          <p>Our sovereign exposure to European countries in the news is negligible. And lastly, a brief comment on market risk. It remains well managed and well within our risk tolerances. Our average one-day VaR was 13.4 million, down from 14.6 million in Q1, and we only had 2 trading loss days in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Now let me elaborate on the above comments. Slide 16 shows the trend in specific provisions over the last 5 quarters. As you can see, the decrease in specific provisions this quarter came primarily from Scotia Capital, a net recovery of 5 million compared to a 14 million provision last quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to retail, we saw a slight increase in Canadian provisions this quarter, whereas the provisions declined slightly in International. The provisioning in our Canadian and International commercial portfolios remained unchanged. The outlook looks promising, as evidenced by slowing impairments and improving delinquencies. Overall, our PCL ratio remained unchanged at 55 points.</p>
          <p>Looking next at slide 17, with total net impaired loan formations of 300 million this quarter, we are clearly seeing a consistent downward trend in the total formation since they peaked a year ago. The formations were down quarter-over-quarter in both the Canadian retail and commercial portfolios.</p>
          <p>International formations were down significantly as a result of improvement in retail delinquencies in some markets, and the fact we did not have any large classifications in our commercial portfolio as we did last quarter. The net declassifications in Scotia Capital largely reflect a number of U.S. and Canadian accounts that we declassified in the quarter.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, we continue to have strong coverage ratios. In particular, our earnings provided a higher coverage of 5.6 times provisions this quarter. Our ratio of total allowances to gross impaired loans improved from 71% last quarter to 81%, or 75% excluding the R-G Premier Bank acquisition. And our ratio of total allowances to loans and acceptances came in at 152 basis points, or 104 basis points excluding R-G Premier.</p>
          <p>Slide 19 shows the composition of loan portfolio acquired from R-G Premier Bank in the FDIC-assisted transaction on April 30. As you can see, the total loan portfolio of 5.4 billion has reserve coverage of 26%. Under the loss sharing agreement with the FDIC, they will provide up to 80% loss coverage on the acquired loans. Hence, the downside risk on these loans to the bank is very limited.</p>
          <p>Looking next at sovereign debt exposure, we have very modest exposure to Ireland and Spain, and our exposure to Portugal, Italy and Greece are all nil.</p>
          <p>To wrap up, we are very comfortable with the asset quality and positioning of our credit portfolios. Our portfolios have responded favorably to the economic recovery that is taking hold here in Canada and elsewhere in the world.</p>
          <p>With respect to our retail and commercial portfolios, they are performing as expected. It is worth repeating that retail provisions have traditionally lagged the economic recovery, and we expect this pattern to repeat itself in this cycle as well. In particular, we expect the Caribbean to lag the rest of our international operations. Our corporate portfolios are performing better than we expected. Looking ahead to the second half of 2010, we expect credit trends to improve with some degree of variability.</p>
          <p>That concludes my comments on risk. And I'll now turn it over to Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Brian. As Luc mentioned, Q2 was a record quarter for Canadian Banking with net income of 584 million. Revenues from core businesses continue to grow and benefit from strategic investments made over the previous quarters. For example, our strong mutual fund sales performance continued as we ranked number 1 in aggregate net sales among the banks and number 3 in the industry during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Wealth management will continue to grow as the rebound in equity markets since the beginning of the year will help grow assets and increase transaction activity. At the same time, market volatility continues to exist. And as a result, we remain cautiously optimistic about the wealth management revenues.</p>
          <p>Earnings from our retail and small business segment will remain strong through selective asset growth and targeted deposit growth. Revenue prospects for commercial banking have improved. In particular, we see continued growth in our auto portfolio. We also expect that our Roynat business will continue to outperform in 2009.</p>
          <p>Margins remain stable. Although rising interest rates will increase the cost of deposits and a competitive pricing environment will put lending margins under pressure, we continue to see moderate revenue growth for the remainder of 2010.</p>
          <p>Provisions for credit losses are likely to remain elevated for the balance of the year, while delinquencies are expected to decline. For the remainder of the year, the retail portfolios are expected to stabilize and benefit from a gradual economic recovery and further stabilization in the labor and housing markets. Provisions in the commercial portfolios are expected to decline.</p>
          <p>Expenses remain well-managed and in line with revenue growth. Expenses will increase, as Luc indicated, through 2010 as we continue to make investments in strategic initiatives for future growth. Operating leverage for the whole year will remain positive, which continues to be a key priority for Canadian Banking.</p>
          <p>While we've had great success in market share throughout our businesses, as we said last year, we are not chasing market share at the expense of pricing. As a result, we're pleased with our results and our market position.</p>
          <p>I'll now pass it over to Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris. While we would have preferred greater loan growth and therefore higher earnings this quarter, foreign exchange and global economic headwinds continue to be an issue. Given these factors, however, we're pleased with our underlying results this quarter.</p>
          <p>Loan volumes, particularly in the Caribbean, have been slow to return to growth and have been adversely affected by the strength of the Canadian dollar. This slowness is being compounded on the retail side by our decision to keep credit policies relatively tight. On the corporate and commercial side, slow growth is partially a result of intentionally downsizing certain businesses and maintaining disciplined pricing and account conditioning practices.</p>
          <p>This quarter we saw stronger growth in our commercial portfolios in Peru and Asia, as well as growth in our retail portfolios in Peru and Mexico. Chile, while just completed its integration, was stalled by the recent earthquake, but is starting to rebound. We anticipate overall loan growth will resume sometime in the second half of 2010 and into 2011. With the exception of a single loan in the Caribbean, commercial PCLs are very stable. Our retail portfolios are continuing to improve and are performing better than we had expected.</p>
          <p>Margins have held up well, particularly in Mexico, Peru and the Spanish Caribbean. We're seeing some margin compression in Chile, the English Caribbean and in Asia. High levels of liquidity and the continuation of a low interest rate environment in most markets will likely contribute to some margin compression in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>We continued to maintain a very disciplined approach to our operating expenses. We're still investing in our platforms, including putting in 21 branches thus far this year, upgrading our contact center in Mexico, and building out our contact center in Peru, as well as growing our wealth management operations through bolt-on acquisitions.</p>
          <p>Acquisitions are an integral part of our strategy and key to expanding our presence in existing markets and entering new markets. This quarter, we added 5.4 billion of gross loans through the acquisition of R-G Premier Bank in Puerto Rico. TBank is in final stages of acquiring Siam City Bank, which will make TBank the fifth largest bank in Thailand, and importantly, the third largest bank in Bangkok. TBank and Siam City together create a strong growth platform.</p>
          <p>In summary, our franchises have performed well in a difficult environment. We're anticipating a solid second half and a good 2011. The outlook of almost all countries where we operate shows a solid economic rebound, better than most developed countries, as illustrated in the appendices attached.</p>
          <p>I will now pass it over to Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob. As Luc mentioned, this is another very strong quarter for Scotia Capital with net income of 391 million, representing the second highest ever achieved. Recoveries of $5 million in the second quarter, exclusive of the reversal of a portion of our sectoral provision in auto, were well below expectations and are reflective of a quickly improving loan portfolio.</p>
          <p>Our success in this regard is the direct result of the action taken over the past several years, increasing the proportion of investment grade borrowers, reducing single name exposures, and exiting highly leveraged lending in the United States and Europe. We expect to continue to benefit from very low loan loss provisions in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Lending volumes have been trending down steadily over the past year as the current environment of low interest rates and open capital markets allowed many companies to reduce or refinance debt. In the second quarter, loan volumes continued to drop, but at a somewhat slower pace. We do however expect the downward trend in loan volumes to moderate and ultimately reverse sometime in the next 6 months as M&amp;A activity picks up.</p>
          <p>Spreads in the second quarter dropped slightly, reflecting some pressure on margins, as competition for loan volumes increases. We expect spreads, going forward, to remain fairly stable.</p>
          <p>Looking now at global capital markets, where we benefited from strong performance across all our businesses. Our client trading businesses, including ScotiaMocatta, our precious metals dealer, are performing well, while at the same time controlling our VaR and market risk. During the quarter, there were only 2 days of trading losses.</p>
          <p>Despite our continued strong trading revenue in Q2, we continue to see signs that markets have normalized considerably since last year. In the face of uncertainty surrounding global market conditions, client flows are somewhat reduced at present. Thus, while we have substantially outperformed our target for the first few quarters, it is unlikely that trading revenues will continue at these same high levels. On the plus side, our growth initiatives should contribute more in the second half and mitigate these effects somewhat.</p>
          <p>As we mentioned previously, our relative strength compared to many global financial institutions over the past couple of years has served us well. Not only have we been able to take advantage of opportunities presented by the market during periods of volatility and uncertainty, we have been able to invest in the fundamental parts of our businesses and to attract and develop top talent. This has allowed us to develop a broader base of revenues for sustainable growth.</p>
          <p>For example, we are enhancing our fixed income platform to take advantage of opportunities in the markets. Our London team is now operational, and New York is progressing in adding the required talent and systems. We are continuing to benefit from our strengthened equities platform. This is an area which provides strong opportunities for cross-sell and collaboration.</p>
          <p>Our earlier investment in our infrastructure platform is starting to pay dividends, and we are pleased with its progress. We are seeing more activity and winning mandates. We are on track with our expanded energy trading business and report increased revenues in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Finally, we will continue to focus on growing the Bank's global wholesale banking footprint in partnership with International Banking. The recently announced wholesale banking acquisition in Colombia adds to our strong presence in the Latin American region.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Steve. That concludes our prepared remarks. Now, we'll be pleased to take your questions. Operator, can we have the first question on the phone please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question today comes from Robert Sedran with CIBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. Good afternoon. Brian, on your slide 16, if I was to look at the 5 categories there and probably think which one was likely to see the sequential increase, I don't think I would have picked Canadian retail. So I can appreciate where the formation number is declining. Is there something unusual about this quarter that saw them back up a little bit on the provision side? And can we expect a similar pace for the decline in provisions that we saw in formations this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, Rob that as I said that we're comfortable on an all-Bank basis that portfolios are stabilizing where our credit trends are becoming more positive. Keep in mind that retail portfolios by their very nature are going to lag the economic recovery. And in Canada, we saw delinquencies down across the board, across all products here in Canada, and we view that as a good sign for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And would you say, looking out at the prospect in the next several quarters I guess, that the outlook for recoveries &#x2013; and not just in retail, more across the Bank, the outlook for recoveries &#x2013; can you talk a little bit about the prospect and should we expect them to continue or to come, or is this more of just a slowing provision?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there's a high degree of variability in recoveries, as we all know. International, commercial, we were the beneficiary of recoveries, to some extent in Mexico and Peru this quarter. I can &#x2013; I've been asked this question a number of times. It's hard to say we can benefit from them quarter-to-quarter. And from Scotia Capital we had a number of recoveries or reclassifications or cures in the U.S. and Canada, which were kind of bunched together candidly this quarter. So I wouldn't expect to see that on a quarter-over-quarter basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Trend is for down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Michael Goldberg with Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. So my question is about the comment in the quarterly report talking about higher gains on sales contributing to profit in Canadian Banking. How do you generate investment gains in Canadian Banking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>2 things, Michael. We had gains on the sale of Visa, and as well we have some equity positions in one of our subsidiaries in Canadian Banking and that was the smaller of the 2 items.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So how much was the Visa?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>14 I think, 14 million pre-tax. And the subsidiary that I referred to is Roynat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Roynat, you've got regular gains there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right. That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. My other question is for Brian. Would you like to get to a point where your total allowance is greater than your gross impaired loans again? And how long do you think that this might take?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well it's &#x2013; we've been very comfortable with our allowance trend throughout this downturn. As I've articulated on a number of calls, we thought we were adequately covered from a total allowance perspective. Michael, it depends how the different countries fall into sequence in terms of the recovery. As I said earlier, we're seeing a lot of variability in the economic recovery of the countries. So it's not going to all happen over the span of the next quarter or two. So I think it's going to take some time to get there. But given our conservative nature in terms of how we run things, it would be nice to have higher coverage ratios.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my last question related to the R-G Premier acquisition is how much did that add to risk-weighted assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, that transaction was only done on April 30, so we have not finalized the purchase price equation at this stage of the game. The combination of our 2 acquisitions that we did this quarter were totally offset by our internally generated capital, including the DRIP and the option exercises. So there was no impact on our capital ratios from those acquisitions on a net basis this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you even give us a ballpark or a range of the impact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, it's around 5 basis points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Andre Hardy with RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. On slide 20 in the exposure to the 5 countries that are more troubled, how much will there be in loans and how much will there be in exposure to banks, or did you not disclose it because it's zero?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is good for sovereigns. For banks it's relatively limited, Andre. For example, we would have &#x2013; we've got &#x2013; in terms of Ireland, we've got &#x2013; the exposure would be a couple of hundred million, and that would be deposits with the Central Bank. In Greece, it's non-existent. In Spain, it would be under 500 million. In Italy, it would be a stick higher because we have &#x2013; as part of our ScotiaMocatta business, we have LCs with jewelers in Italy and these lines would be either cash, collateralized or very short-term indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you said Spain was 500?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pardon me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Did you say Spain was 500? Sorry, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And those are big banks. And those are -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's fully -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nothing in the middle tier, Andre. They would be the largest 2 banks that you would know by name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And its cash collateralized mostly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm talking about our alliance with Spanish banks. That would be largely to the &#x2013; it would be to the 2 largest banks. There is no <mark type="inaudible" /> there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, do you have a lot of loans in those countries?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Portugal would be zero; and Ireland would be less than 100 million; also less than 100 million in Italy. In Spain would be approximately 200 million; and in Greece it would be 350 million and that would be to a group of shipping companies where we have had exposure for decades. We know the families well and we have security and collateral.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for that. And my other question is also for you, Brian. I presume there is a certain seasonality to impairments in hotel loans in the Caribbean. Would Q3 be a typical quarter where hotels don't make it just after the tourist season ends?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Again, there's a lot of variability to the Caribbean hospitality portfolio. For instance, the lower end of the markets performed fairly well. Dominican and Jamaica actually had a pretty good year. Some areas at the higher end of the market had a very good year. The middle part of the market generally has been soft. But as we enter the summer months, that's generally the slower time for these operations. But we collectively would think that we're through the worst in terms of our exposures. And again, we're very comfortable with our portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The worst is behind in your mind?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Mario Mendonca with Canaccord Genuity. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Along the same lines, the $35 million provision in hotels and leisure this quarter, was that related to the same hotel project from last quarter, the one that drove 150 million in GILs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Look, I'm not going to get into specific names, other than we had one project in the Caribbean that was not symbolic or indicative to the rest of our hotel portfolio in the Caribbean, which is 1.4 billion. We think we have &#x2013; the additional provision certainly contains our risk and we're comfortable with our exposure going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm just trying to ensure that this isn't another project, this is just the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it is not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Nothing new here then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you refer to improving expenses &#x2013; or sorry, expenses normalizing, moving a little higher, it was sort of in the context of retail. Are there any other segments that you see expenses moving higher?</p>
          <p>And sort of along the same lines, for Chris, you referred to operating leverage being positive for the year. But given that operating leverage in your segment has been about 10% plus the last 2 quarters, isn't that sort of a given unless something &#x2013; unless your investment spending is going to climb materially higher? If you could help size the sort of investment spending you're referring to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mario, the short answer is yes. The reality is that historically our expenses grow as the year goes on, and we have been clear in the past that we don't really predict operating leverage and we don't forecast that to the Street on a quarter-by-quarter basis. We believe that our expenses will increase from this point through the balance of the year to support a lot of the strategic investments that we have talked about in the past, but we made a commitment some time ago to generate positive operating leverage. And I get the question regularly about what's that number. We're not really going to give that out, but to say that it will be a decent number at the end of the year. But we expect our expenses to increase as the year goes on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of the increase in expenses as the year goes on, is it just a few projects you're working on? Is there anything you can offer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in combination. Yeah, Mario, it's a combination of things. We've opened some new branches this year. We've opened 7 up to this point. There will be at least another 4. We have a number of technology investments that we will be completing over the balance of the year. We are adding a number of people. By the end of the year, we'll have added 600 people, and it's all in more in the front end of our business, so sales facing individuals.</p>
          <p>So there will be compensation related expenses on that front. We have some expenses going on with our iTRADE business, where we're converting 6 platforms onto 1, which was all part of the acquisition when we were looking at doing that.</p>
          <p>So I could kind of go on and on and on, but each one of these is really supported by our strategic imperatives. And at the same time, we're going to watch our expenses closely through the balance of the year, but we're just signaling that we expect to see some rise as the year goes on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then finally on interest rates and the move in interest rates. On the retail segment, I understand it's a little &#x2013; it's less straightforward because of some of the transfer pricing. But on a total bank basis, what do higher short-term rates mean to Scotia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We would see higher short-term rates as a positive to net interest income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And could you just elaborate as to why?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Given our, basically interest rate position, as you can see, we're asset sensitive. So rising short rates and being asset sensitive go together to produce better income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Steve Theriault with Bank of America, Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. A question to start, for Rick, on capital. You completed your QIS at the end of April, I believe. So after having gone through the process and discussing with regulators, do you feel more comfortable with your capital situation relative to, I guess, some of the concerns we had in December? Can you give us any sort of range of volatility we might expect as a result of the eventual implementations of the new capital guidelines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, we feel comfortable with our capital position and we'll be able to manage through whatever comes out. But I'll tell you, it's an uncertain world out there on the international capital and re-regulation front. And we're right into this critical period after the QIS's. The individual regulators are probably fairly well along preparing their numbers, and then there will be a collaborative effort, which I understand is ongoing. Of course, the issues in Europe haven't helped because there's obviously some self-assessment that has to go on there with regards to just what's happened in some of the banks and sovereign funds.</p>
          <p>It's a very &#x2013; in essence, we want certainty. And the sooner we get, the sooner the better, because there is quite a lot of opportunity. And as you can see, and we're proceeding with the opportunities we want. But there is a lot of ambiguity there, and I think the regulators are right in the stage now of assessing, and there will be a macro assessment over and above the QIS assessment. And then of course, with the two G-20 meetings coming up here in Toronto and then Korea, the political leaders, at my understanding, are now starting to put it back on the agenda. So I'm hedging a little bit because it is &#x2013; anything I'd say would be highly speculative, other than the Canadian banks and Scotia in particular will be able to manage through it.</p>
          <p>What we really want, at least what I really want, is just let's get it over with and capital levels internationally will go up, and that's fine and we can deal with that. The quality of capital will improve, and that's fine, we can deal with that. There are a number of what we call deductions to whatever shareholder bases are in whatever country. That's where the uncertainty is. But let's get that on with and then we can go ahead. Growth rates in these countries that we're in are definitely going forward, and all of them need credit and we're going to be there to provide it. But I just want to get this global uncertainty over with and the ongoing discussions in the next few weeks and months on this one.</p>
          <p>But hopefully, by the fall, late fall, we can all start to move forward with certainty. But it is really an uncertain issue right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for that. If I might, one more. Pretty dramatic drop in margins in International. Luc, you gave us some good color. But I'm still not sure how sustainable you might be telling us this decline could be. You mentioned that some of the factors have swung back in the right direction, but in the back half of the year would you expect margins closer to Q1 or closer to Q2 for International?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're expecting the International margins to increase somewhat, Steve, but it's going to be mixed depending on the region. I'm going to turn it over to Rob to give some commentary on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Luc. We've got a lot of liquidity right now in various parts of International. We've got it in certain parts of Peru, we've got it in certain parts of the Caribbean. That's going to impact our margins. But relatively speaking, it should be steady. So we don't anticipate that margins are going to drop in Q3 or Q4 to any material degree.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But not necessarily going higher to any material degree?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not really. They should be relatively steady.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Sumit Malhotra with Macquarie Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. First, just to clarify, Luc, on that International margin question. That issue you mentioned, I think it was related to the situation in Chile. How much did that take off the International margin alone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The mark-to-market on the instruments, financial instruments, was around 45 million in Q2. That came back quite nicely over the last 3, 4 weeks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I mean, when you talk about margins stabilizing that's &#x2013; I'm assuming ex of this item?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's why I suggested that we might see some increase in it, but it's not going to be material, as Rob indicated. We don't expect to see a decrease of instruments the way we did. That was a one-time situation short term because of the earthquake situation in Chile.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the steadying factor will be, on the one hand you've got the excess liquidity on it. On the other hand, you'll have the recovery of Chile. So it should be relatively stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Staying with that liquidity comment, we've seen this from a few of the banks this quarter &#x2013; this might be for Mike Durland and for Luc as well. Trading securities on the balance sheet up pretty noticeably quarter-over-quarter, about 11 billion, how much of that is actual assets within the Scotia Capital institutional trading operation? How much of that is general liquidity on an all-Bank level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike, can you talk to Scotia Capital, what's happening there with your trading securities. And then, Jeff, on the liquidity side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That might be a question I've got to come back to you on. I don't think that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll come back on the capital &#x2013; Scotia Capital side. Jeff, can you comment on the liquidity side in terms of the securities you're holding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Available-for-sale securities actually were down quarter-over-quarter, so we have not been adding from a liquidity point of view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I'm looking at the trading securities. Is that all &#x2013; or what you mark as trading securities on the balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some of &#x2013; the majority of that incremental change over the quarter is coming &#x2013; is part of our equity business. So it would be equity securities that are part of our equity derivative activity that would be &#x2013; there would be offsetting hedges to them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Maybe I'll circle back with Luc on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's really the fixed income and global equity finance where the growth is. And I'll call you back on that, Sumit, to give you greater commentary, color on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Last one, a little bigger picture and I'll leave it here. This is for Rob Pitfield, maybe Rick. Obviously with the consolidation in Puerto Rico you have, according to my math, something like an 8% market share. You kind of talked about historically in international a sweet spot of about 10% market share. You're pretty close to that. Of course, you still have that 10% stake in the number 2 player in the country as well. When you look at Puerto Rico's consolidation, can you update us on your relationship with FBP and where you think your potential share in Puerto Rico could go with or without further consolidation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sumit, we're very comfortable with our market share right now. By certain measures, it's more like 9, 10. And we've been able to, through this crisis anyway, grow our Scotiabank operations and increase our market share just on that. So we think that we're essentially there. That 10%, as we've said before, is just an arbitrary critical mass number for us. It's really just saying we need to have critical mass in these markets. We have it in Puerto Rico. Could we play in the consolidation game that will continue in Puerto Rico? Yes, we could, but we don't need to. We needed to reach a certain scale in Puerto Rico. The acquisition was designed to do that. It did that. So going forward is &#x2013; we'll just see if a good deal comes along.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And FBP, are you still &#x2013; do you have seats on the board? Just remind me of the situation there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're still involved in the board, and we've still got an interest in that bank. And we'll see what transpires.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from John Reucassel with BMO Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. A question for Rob. Rob, just the International business has in the past generated ROEs of 20%. Could you tell us &#x2013; obviously lower PCLs are required to get back to the ROE of 20%, but could you &#x2013; do the margins have to improve? And what is the best guess on timing to get back there? Are we still a few years away or could you kind of update us on the ROE expectations out of International?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it &#x2013; a big factor has been Chile, which is a strongly investment graded country, has lower ROEs. And we've been working through our integration in Chile, and that and other acquisitions have dropped that. As volumes increase, as the various initiatives that we're now underway on, as they take hold, and you've seen the volumes from International, they've been very slow to rebound, which probably speaks very positively for the franchise going forward. We see that the ROE will rebound and that will be just a natural course as the markets themselves rebound.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Rick Waugh. And of course, year-over-year, this time last year or a few weeks earlier, we were sitting at an $0.80 dollar. Now we're at, I guess we're at the mid 0.90s. So we've had quite a year-over-year adjustment on the translation of earnings. And so that has not been good. As we've looked at &#x2013; under our return on invested capital, they are not what we want, nor what we think they can produce, but we're still comfortable on our original hurdle rates into the high teens. And as we go through time, we will see that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Rob, just a clarification. Chile has a lower ROE, is there a structural reason Chile is lower or is that just the process of integration and optimizing that platform?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a combination of factors. It's a combination of the market, it's an investment grade market, it's a very stable market, it's got very good banks. It's a process of our acquisition costs, it's a process of going through the integration and not having that franchise firing as it should. The fact that we no sooner got through the integration than we, bam we ran right into the earthquake, which stopped us for another 3 or 4 or 5 months. So once we work through all of those things, as Rick said, it will come in due course and it will be fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think also that acquisition cost to the bank we bought down there. And if you remember the scenario, none of the Chilean banks were for sale other than this one. And so, it was more expensive than we've ever &#x2013; I think, I felt very uncomfortable paying that price, but that's what the scarcity value of only having 6 or 7 banks and this moves us up to scale. So we got a little bit more goodwill on that, that we normally like.</p>
          <p>But I think given the outlook for Chile, the fact that it's a fairly concentrated banking market now, not only is the purchase price we paid money good, but that has had some shorter run impact on return on invested capital, which we don't normally see, that when we made those great acquisitions in Peru, Mexico and some of the other countries. So it was an expensive &#x2013; relatively expensive buy, but it was the only bank that had been for sale and probably will be for sale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. And Just Rick, while I guess I have you, just the ROE in the quarter was 19.9% for the Bank, yet International is below its historical or where it should be probably and will get back. And then your PCLs are quite high as well. Why &#x2013; is this, your range of 16 to 20% ROE, too conservative or are these capital rules going to be too onerous, or what &#x2013; it just seems like the 16 to 20 seems a little low. Can you tell us why or why not that may be the case?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think 16 to 20 &#x2013; I think we have one of the highest ROEs in the world, certainly in Canada, but I think we would rank very high in the world. It's a median target. It's a target we're going to stick with.</p>
          <p>I don't want to increase it for a whole bunch of reasons, because I'm very comfortable with our risk appetite. And giving that high level, we're not going to push the envelope to get some high ROE, point one.</p>
          <p>Where this normalizes out as we get into the new norm? I don't know. But the other thing on ROE, we didn't increase the E. We didn't increase our equity other than this nominal amount, so obviously that hardwires a certain amount of ROE. But I am, maybe my conservative nature here, not going to push our targets up to management because I think if we continue in that range, which I'm very confident we will, that's going to be very good for shareholders, however we handle our capital going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have time for one more question. So last question on the phone please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your last question today comes from Brad Smith with Stonecap Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Just actually 2 quick ones. Chris Hodgson, you mentioned in your prepared comments that you were number 1 in gross sales, and then you also mentioned that you are targeting hiring 600 front-line people in your group. I was just wondering if you might talk about your positioning vis-&#xE0;-vis your productivity of your people? And if you could put the 600 in perspective, what percentage of your opening front sales organization does that represent?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Brad. Of the &#x2013; and 600 is an annual number. We've actually hired 300 for the first 6 months of the year and it is spread across the bigger Canadian Banking business. There is a small component which are account managers of small business. We've also opened 7 branches, so there is about 100 for that group. And we've added financial advisors, which is really, to your point, in expanding our mutual fund business.</p>
          <p>So as we move forward, we're going to add more financial advisors, which adds to the sale of our &#x2013; or market share of our mutual fund business. We've increased our market share significantly, as you know, in mutual funds, and we think we have good momentum in that proprietary business to continue to grow on that side. And it isn't just on the front line, by the way.</p>
          <p>I think in terms of some of the product innovation, we launched a product called Anova, which is a $50,000 type of wrap product which is launched through our branch system. And we're over $1 billion in sales in that particular area. It's very profitable for us. But the point that I would leave you with is it isn't just related to that business. We're also adding some front-end people on the commercial banking business. So it is spread across all of the Canadian Banking side.</p>
          <p>And the productivity, I think you see our productivity numbers and they're actually quite high. We're managing the bottom line very carefully. And I indicated that our expenses are going to go up over the balance of the year, but we're going to be careful about that. We still believe that there is good momentum in the business and we expect decent growth. Even in spite of some rising rate environments and some of the competitive nature of the business, we're expecting reasonable growth in our portfolios. And we're not going to let our expenses get away from us, otherwise I'll have a problem with my friend down <mark type="inaudible" /> there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He means me and Luc.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I was curious about the productivity at the sales level in terms of sales per sales agent that you're working with. That's what I was curious about, where you think you stand amongst your peers domestically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're in the middle of the pack on that, Brad. I would &#x2013; without naming names, I can &#x2013; I know who they are. There might be one or two who are actually a little more productive than we are. We are focusing on cross-sell, and we are spending quite a bit of time on that and we're in the process of enhancing and revamping our 3-year strategy for the next 3 years for the overall business.</p>
          <p>And a large portion of that is increasing the sales capacity at the front-end of the business. One of the things we're doing in that respect is we are &#x2013; we have a number of projects that &#x2013; from an operational efficiency perspective that will take out some expense in the Canadian Banking business, and we will take a significant portion of that and reinvest it in the business, but we'll also take a portion of it and put it to the bottom line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That concludes our call for the day. Thank you for joining us, and until next quarter. Have a great day. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the conference call for today. Thank you for participating. Please disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>