<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1137783" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-04-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>94</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Scott Freidenrich, Director, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Vikram Pandit, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Gary Crittenden, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Guy Moszkowski</participant>
      <participant id="5">Gary Crittenden</participant>
      <participant id="6">Glenn Schorr</participant>
      <participant id="7">Michael Mayo</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jason Goldberg</participant>
      <participant id="9">Meredith Whitney</participant>
      <participant id="10">Vikram Pandit</participant>
      <participant id="11">Betsy Graseck</participant>
      <participant id="12">James Mitchell</participant>
      <participant id="13">William Tanona</participant>
      <participant id="14">David Hilder</participant>
      <participant id="15">Lawrence Greenberg</participant>
      <participant id="16">Jeff Harte</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to Citi's First Quarter 2008 Earnings Review, featuring Citi Chief Executive Officer Vikram Pandit and Chief Financial Officer Gary Crittenden. Today's call will be hosted by Scott Freidenrich. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Mr. Freidenrich, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator, and thank you all for joining us this morning. Welcome to our first quarter 2008 earnings presentation. The presentation we will be going through is available on our website, so you'll want to download that now if you haven't already done so.</p>
          <p>The format we will follow is Vikram will begin the call. Gary will take you through the presentation, and Vikram will have some concluding remarks. And we'd be happy to take any questions that you may have.</p>
          <p>Before we get started, I'd like to remind you that today's presentation may contain forward-looking statements. Citigroup's financial results may differ materially from these statements, so please refer to our SEC filings for a description of the factors that could cause our actual results to differ from expectations.</p>
          <p>With that said, let me turn it over to Vikram.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott, thank you. Good morning everyone. To start with, we are not happy with our financial results this quarter, although they are not completely unexpected given the assets we hold. I do want to start by emphasizing a few points, and then I'll turn it over to Gary.</p>
          <p>Firstly, despite the bottom line results, we had good operating performance in a number of areas. We had record revenues in Transaction Services, where revenues grew 42% and net income grew 63% versus a year ago. International Consumer revenues were up 33%, or 22% excluding onetime items. Deposits in our International Consumer franchise were up 23%. International card revenues were up 37%, ex the onetime items.</p>
          <p>Within fixed income markets, we had very good results in our client related, or flow rates and currencies business, with revenues up 17% versus a year ago and up 52% versus last quarter. Of particular note was the strong performance of our Local Markets business in the emerging markets, a franchise that is unique to Citi. Revenues at Smith Barney grew at 18% and the Private Bank grew 10%. So we had continued strong momentum in many of our businesses.</p>
          <p>Secondly, our capital ratios were up versus fourth quarter with our Tier 1 ratio slightly higher than our internal target and our TCE ratio slightly lower than our target. But more importantly, we are executing on our capital plans and are enhancing capital by reducing legacy assets and non-core businesses.</p>
          <p>I'm sure you have seen the many announcements we have made, including the sale of most of Citi Capital to GE, the sale of Diners and Redecard, and the planned reduction of our mortgage portfolio.</p>
          <p>Apparently we are on top of our risks, and have focused on prudently managing our legacy risk assets and are reducing risk assets in a way that does not dilute our shareholders. For example on CDOs, at year end our net super senior gross exposures were about 30 billion. At the end of first quarter, they were down to under 23 billion, with the reduction driven mostly by marks. We have done extensive analysis on our assets and believe we have a very good understanding of their value and have marked them appropriately.</p>
          <p>We have also been working hard on reducing our risk in these structures. Some of our riskier positions have been hedged by covering the underlying exposure with CDSs. On the super senior liquidity puts, we believe that at these levels, the cash on cash returns are very attractive, and there is significant equity in front of us.</p>
          <p>On leveraged loans, at year end we had 43 billion of highly leveraged finance commitments. At the end of first quarter, that number was 38 billion. We have sold some of these loans and Gary will tell you more about that. As of today, our remaining position is 28 billion. Of the 28 billion, 17 billion were unfunded commitments at the end of the quarter. More importantly, the leveraged loan market is beginning to trade, and that is good news.</p>
          <p>Lastly, I believe we reduced our risk in our institutional business. We continue to have risk in our consumer loan portfolio, but that is also not completely unexpected given our historical loan positions. We can continue to say that we have a strong earnings base that will offset issues arising from this book. We have some other risk issues that we are on top of that Gary will talk about more.</p>
          <p>Through all of this, even as we expect economic news to be challenging, my confidence in this company's abilities and our future is extremely high. I'll share some of these thoughts with you towards the end.</p>
          <p>Let me turn it over to Gary who is going to take you through the results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Vikram, and good morning to everyone. Thanks so much for joining us today. Once again this quarter, I have a lot to cover so I apologize in advance for the length of my prepared comments but I'm going to go quickly. Please turn to the slides that are available to you on the website. I'm obviously going to begin on the first slide. Slide number one shows our consolidated results for the quarter.</p>
          <p>The first quarter results were driven by two main factors, write-downs and losses related to the continued disruption in the fixed income markets and in higher US Consumer credit costs. As I take you through the results of the quarter, I'll discuss the actions that we are taking against the key risk exposures for the company.</p>
          <p>To summarize our first quarter results, net revenues declined 48%, driven by the continued disruption in fixed income markets, partially offset by underlying growth in several of our other businesses. Expenses were up 4%. The reengineering plan for 2008 is well underway and we are very focused on managing expense levels in the company. The cost of credit more than doubled over last year, primarily due to higher net credit losses and a subsequent change to the increase in loan loss reserves, both principally in our US Consumer business.</p>
          <p>These factors drove a loss of $5.1 billion for the quarter or a loss per share of $1.02. This EPS is based on a basic share count of 5.1 billion shares. Our diluted share count for the quarter was 5.6 billion, but in accordance with GAAP is not used in the EPS calculation in a net loss situation.</p>
          <p>I'm turning now to slide number 2. Slide number 2 shows the number of items which significantly affected our results for the quarter; first, $6 billion from write-down and credit costs on subprime related direct exposure in our fixed income markets business. At the end of the quarter, our net super senior ABS CDO direct exposure was $23 billion, and our gross direct subprime exposure related to the structuring and lending business was 6.4 billion. We had $3.7 billion in net credit losses and $1.8 billion in charges to increase our loan loss reserve in the global consumer businesses with the majority of that being driven by the US Consumer business; $3.1 billion in write-downs on our highly leveraged finance commitments; $1.5 billion in credit market value adjustments related to our monoline exposure; $1.5 billion write-down of our inventory of auction rated securities; a $1 billion write down net of hedges on Alt-A mortgages in the CMB business.</p>
          <p>Additionally, we recorded $622 million in repositioning charges related to this quarter's installment of our reengineering plan. It was offset by a $663 million gain from the sale of our Redecard shares, a $633 million benefit related to the gain on Visa shares, and a partial release of previously established Visa related litigation reserves.</p>
          <p>Revenues included a $1.3 billion gain related to the inclusion of Citi credit spreads in the determination of the market value of those liabilities for which the fair value option was elected. Excluding the write-downs and the benefits affecting the market and banking segments listed on this table amounting to 11.8 billion, revenue for the company would have been $25 billion or close to flat versus the prior year period.</p>
          <p>Turning now to slide number 3, this shows a 5-quarter trend for some of the key drivers in our business. It is encouraging to see that this quarter, most of the drivers have continued to grow at a fairly consistent pace with the second quarter of 2007, which was the best quarter in the firm's history. Strong momentum continued across these drivers especially in our international franchises.</p>
          <p>Slide 4 shows the first quarter year-over-year revenue growth in each of our major businesses. Markets &amp; Banking reflects the write-downs and losses that I have already mentioned. Alternative investment revenues declined &#x2013; the alternative investments revenue decline reflects sharply lower revenues from our proprietary activities and the write-down of some of the SIV assets. Offsetting these results was revenue growth in International Consumer and Global Wealth Management, driven by both organic growth and acquisitions. In addition, US Consumer revenues were up on a GAAP basis by 3%.</p>
          <p>International revenues were up in every region except EMEA where the decline reflected a $1.4 billion subprime related write-down and $460 million in write-downs on highly leveraged finance commitments in the region. Acquisitions produced year-over-year revenue gain in the quarter of 2%.</p>
          <p>Let me turn now to slide number 5. The graph on slide 5 shows the 12-quarter sequential trend of net interest margin for the company. Net interest margin for the quarter is 2.83%, up 30 basis points sequentially and 36 basis points over the prior year period. The primary driver of this improvement is from significantly lower cost funding, and driven primarily by deposits and Fed funds, which is reflecting the benefit of the Fed rate cut. Partially offsetting the benefits from lower funding cost was a decrease in asset yields primarily related to Fed funds. In the sequential quarter comparison, the assets were down sharply last quarter and remained virtually flat this quarter. This is primarily due to an increase in trading assets driven by higher revaluation gains from interest rates, the impact of foreign exchange, and derivative investment movements offsetting a decrease in Fed funds sold. You have seen us announce many actions in the quarter to reduce our non-strategic assets. We continue down this path &#x2013; we expect to continue down this path and be extremely focused on enhancing asset productivity.</p>
          <p>Let me turn now to slide number 6. Slide 6 shows the trend of our expense growth. Expenses in the quarter grew 4% versus last year, and foreign exchange accounted for 3 percentage points of that growth. Excluding acquisitions, expenses were actually down 4% in the quarter. The major components of the change are: a $622 million repositioning charge related to a number of activities such as head count reductions and branch closings, including an expected reduction in force of over 9,000. This is in addition to last quarter's expected head count reduction that we announced of 4,200. We'll continue this process throughout the year as we make progress in our productivity and continuing reengineering program.</p>
          <p>We also had a $250 million reserve to facilitate for Global Wealth Management clients an exit from a specific Citi managed fund, and a $200 million write-down on the hedge fund intangible assets related to Old Lane. Offsetting these were three items. Upon Visa's funding of the escrow accounts, Citi released $166 million of a previously established reserve based on the pro-rata Citi ownership of Visa shares.</p>
          <p>Secondly a $282 million benefit resulting from a legal entity restructuring in our Mexico business in March of 2008; finally in last year's first quarter, we recorded a $1.4 billion restructuring charge.</p>
          <p>Excluding the impact of acquisitions and the items I just mentioned, expenses grew 2%. Savings from our reengineering efforts were reinvested in expenses related to branch build-out and more collectors in our consumer businesses as well as in our highest return businesses. In International Cards, for example, we opened 2.3 million new card accounts during the quarter and continued to actively expand our partnership programs, reaching 209 total partners by the end of the quarter. Similarly, we have invested in our Transaction Services business to extend our global and product reach. The results of these investments are clear in the underlying growth metrics that I discussed on slide 3.</p>
          <p>Sequentially, expenses declined 2% and excluding the impact of foreign exchange declined 3%.</p>
          <p>On slide number 7, as I have said before, a good way to track our progress on expense management would be to track head count growth and the expense growth related to revenues. And slide 7 shows the trend in our head count growth. The graph indicates that we have significantly slowed the head count growth from the 12 to 16% range to 8%. Acquisitions and divestitures contributed 7 percentage points to the year-over-year growth rate, so that excluding acquisitions and divestitures, year-over-year growth was 1%. In a similar comparison, head count declined &#x2013; I'm sorry &#x2013; in a sequential comparison, head count declined 2% versus the prior quarter, while expenses are also declining 2% excluding the repositioning charges.</p>
          <p>Turning now to slide number 8 on credit, it shows the year-over-year growth rate in the components of our total cost of credit and the key drivers within each component. The total cost of credit increased by $3 billion with 1.7 billion driven by higher net credit losses and 1.4 billion driven by incremental loan loss reserves. First, higher net credit losses were driven primarily by our US Consumer businesses where NCLs increased by $1.1 billion. Consumer lending net credit losses were higher by 762 million over last year, driven primarily by higher losses in the consumer mortgage portfolio. In US Cards, net credit losses were up by 102 million, reflecting higher write-offs and lower recoveries. Delinquency levels were higher, and the increase in write-offs reflected higher bankruptcy filings and the impact of customers that are delinquent advancing to write-off at a higher rate.</p>
          <p>In the US retail distribution, net credit losses were higher by 228 million, reflecting higher losses in personal finance, sales finance, and home equity portfolios. Second, as shown on the chart, the loan loss reserve build was higher this quarter versus the prior year by 1.4 billion. We strengthened the loan loss reserve by adding 1.9 billion, primarily driven by the US Consumer reserve build of 1.4 billion. Approximately half or 659 million of the US Consumer build was in the Consumer Lending group, reflecting continued weakness in the mortgage portfolio and a higher expectation of losses in the auto portfolio. The auto portfolio is primarily subprime with the loans sourced indirectly through dealers.</p>
          <p>With the addition to reserves in our US mortgage business, we are at a 14.7 month coincident reserve coverage ratio for the real estate lending portfolio, 13.3 months and 15.6 months of coincident reserve coverage in our first and second mortgage portfolios respectively. As we said last quarter, we expect higher losses in the portfolio and this quarter, these ratios have declined accordingly but remain at very strong levels.</p>
          <p>In US Cards, we added $302 million in loan loss reserves. The build reflects recently observed trends which point to an expectations of higher losses in the near term. As I mentioned, the rate at which delinquent customers advance to write-off has increased. This is especially true in certain geographic areas where the impact of events in the housing market have been greatest, driving higher loss rates. Bankruptcy filings have also increased from historically low levels. These trends and other portfolio indicators led to a build in the reserve for US Cards in the quarter.</p>
          <p>In US retail distribution, higher delinquencies in the Retail Bank home equity portfolio and the consumer finance personal loan portfolio and portfolio growth and a generally weakening credit environment led to a $362 million reserve build. Markets &amp; Banking credit costs declined 2% over last year to $249 million.</p>
          <p>Slide number 9 shows consumer net credit losses and loan loss reserve as a percentage of loans for the US Consumer business in the top box, and the same data for the International Consumer business in the bottom box. Looking at the top box, loan loss reserves and net credit losses as a percentage of the consumer loan portfolio have risen sharply, reflecting all of the factors that I have discussed. The largest contributor to the increase in the US is the consumer mortgage portfolio.</p>
          <p>As the bottom graph shows, the two credit ratios in International Consumer are increasing. The increase is driven in large part by our cards business in Mexico and in India and our consumer finance business in India. Mexico and India accounted for approximately one quarter of the net credit losses and three-quarters of the reserve build in the International Consumer business. Outside of the specific businesses in Mexico and India, International Consumer credit remains generally stable.</p>
          <p>On slide 10, the graph shows that the losses for the entire mortgage portfolio have increased substantially since September 2007. The yellow boxes indicate the delinquency for our highest risk segments, that they have increased much more relative to the entire portfolio. Our reserve actions for our mortgage portfolio primarily reflect this significant deterioration. One point to note, the FICO, LTV, and delinquency distributions for our first and second mortgage portfolios that we have shown you in the past few quarters have remained consistent; and therefore, we have not included them in this presentation.</p>
          <p>Let me turn now to slide number 11. Slide 11 shows a different cut of the first mortgage portfolio, which is the buyer-selected low-documentation portfolio by LTV and by FICO bands. We have 58.1 billion of such mortgages, which are a subset of our first mortgage portfolio of $151 billion. The box on the left shows you the FICO and LTV distribution of the loan balances as a percentage of the entire first mortgage portfolio. The box on the right shows the FICO and LTV distribution by delinquencies. This category of loan represents cases in which the borrower has elected to pay a higher interest rate to avoid assembling a full list of documents.</p>
          <p>As a percentage of the total first mortgage portfolio, 33% of the buyer-selected low-documentation loans have a FICO score above 660 and an LTV below 80% as shown in the box on the left. For the same FICO and LTV band, the entire first mortgage portfolio has a delinquency ratio of 1.6% versus 2.2% for this subset of loans as shown in the box on the right. Conversely in instances &#x2013; I'm sorry &#x2013; in extreme cases represented by a FICO band, a FICO below 620, and an LTV at or above the 90% band, which had a delinquency rate almost three times as high as the corresponding cell in the first mortgage portfolio. However, importantly, this cell represents only 1% of the first mortgage portfolio.</p>
          <p>Conversely, in instances where we as a lender have chosen to accept a borrower with limited or no documentation due to a pre-existing relationship with the borrower or other borrower characteristic, delinquencies for that portfolio are very much in line with the loans that have complete documentation. The weighted average delinquency for this entire portfolio is 3.8% versus 3.2% for the entire first mortgage portfolio. We have stopped originating stated income and stated asset loans and we are actively working with borrowers to mitigate losses in this portfolio.</p>
          <p>Let me also spend a moment talking about real estate originations. You saw the announcement we made in March where we were committed to reduce real estate assets by $45 billion during the course of the year. A key contributor to this decline is that we plan to originate loans that we can sell as opposed to loans that we hold in our portfolio. Of the total consumer lending group mortgage originations of 34.3 billion in the quarter, we decreased the proportion of those held on balance sheet to 29% versus 42% in the prior year's $39.6 billion of originations.</p>
          <p>Slide number 12 shows a 20-year historical view of net credit losses in the US Cards portfolio. While the mix of our cards in the portfolio has changed over time, there are some interesting observations to make about this history. There are two spikes that are driven by unusual events. The first one occurred in 2005 as a result of a large private label portfolio acquisition which carried higher losses. The second one occurred in the 2005 and 2006 period and related largely to the change in bankruptcy legislation and the aftermath of Hurricane Katrina. Putting those two events aside, there are three clear periods in the chart where losses have increased steadily. And first, in the period from 1989 to 1992 lasted eight quarters during which unemployment increased by approximately 200 basis points and housing prices declined by more than 5% and our net credit losses increased by 175 basis points.</p>
          <p>Second, the period from 2000 to 2003 lasted seven quarters. Unemployment increased by nearly 200 basis points but housing prices increased significantly and losses in the portfolio rose by over 200 basis points.</p>
          <p>Finally, the current period of increasing losses started in the third quarter of 2007, when home prices started to decline. Two quarters in, unemployment has risen by only 40 basis points and housing prices are already down 7.8%. And losses on our card portfolio have increased by more than 125 basis points. If historical trends were to repeat, there is a potential for higher losses in our cards portfolio into 2009.</p>
          <p>We have shown you historical trend data for losses in our mortgage portfolio and in our card portfolio. Using this information as well as internal assumptions for each of our consumer portfolios, there are scenarios which could result in significantly higher credit costs for the remainder of the year. Our reserves reflect our best estimation of losses embedded in our portfolio today.</p>
          <p>Slide number 13 shows the historical trend in a number of our key capital ratios as well as a progression in our Tier 1 ratio from the fourth quarter to the first quarter. As the graph shows, all of our capital ratios declined during 2007, driven primarily by acquisitions, organic growth in assets, and negative earnings in the fourth quarter. In the fourth quarter, we ended with a Tier 1 capital ratio of 7.1% and TCE ratio of 5.6%. As a consequence of the capital raising we did in the first quarter, our Tier 1 ratio was 7.7%, exceeding our internal target. The TCE ratio was 6.2%, below our internal target and it is not our expectation that we will achieve the internal target in the second quarter as we had previously stated.</p>
          <p>In the last four quarters, we have added $8.7 billion net to our loan loss levels. In the last two quarters, we added approximately $35 billion to our capital base. Both of these actions combined have strengthened the balance sheet of the company.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to the individual businesses. I'll start on slide 14 with the results of the US Consumer business. Revenues were up 3% on continued momentum from our strategic actions. Excluding the $349 million gain on Visa shares this quarter and the MasterCard gain from last year's first quarter, revenues were up on a GAAP basis 1%. Managed revenues in US Cards increased by 14% on 6% growth in managed receivables. Excluding the gain on Visa shares this quarter and the MasterCard gain in the prior year period, managed revenues were up 10%, driven by new product introductions, the reconfiguration of our rewards programs, and investment in higher growth segments. Both retail distribution and consumer lending revenues were higher on strong volume growth.</p>
          <p>Expenses in US Consumer grew by 6%, reflecting continued investment in building branches and higher costs related to managing deteriorating credit such as adding collectors. Credit costs increased by $2.2 billion, driven by the factors I discussed earlier. The decline in net income results primarily from higher credit costs.</p>
          <p>Slide 15 shows the results of our International Consumer business. This quarter, the results are affected by a number of the items that are disclosed in the schedule on slide 22. Excluding these items, revenues increased by 22%, although net income would have declined significantly due to higher credit costs. Higher credit costs were driven in large part by our cards and consumer finance business in Mexico and India, as I have discussed already. As usual we have shown you our results with and without the Japan consumer finance business. As the results show, Japan consumer finance did not have a major impact on our business during this quarter.</p>
          <p>Slide 16 shows the results in our Markets &amp; Banking business. Revenues were a negative 4.5 billion and we reported a loss, a net loss of 5.7 billion. The last two weeks of March were particularly difficult in the securities and banking business. Partially offsetting the severely affected businesses were strong results in certain areas. In Global Transaction Services, as Vikram mentioned, revenues increased 42% to a record 2.3 billion, driven by higher customer volumes stable net interest margins, the acquisition of BISYS Group, which closed in August of 2007. Key revenue drivers continued to grow at strong double digit rates with each of the three major businesses, cash, securities and fund services, and trade posting record revenues.</p>
          <p>In equity markets, prime finance had its second strongest quarter in revenues, driven by a number of new account acquisitions and increased customer activity. Cash equity revenues driven by customer activities were strong, but were offset completely by a decline in proprietary cash trading. Within fixed income markets, we had very good results in our client related or flow rates and currency businesses, with revenues up 17% versus a year ago and up 52% versus last quarter. We had record foreign exchange and local emerging markets revenues.</p>
          <p>Strong results in Asia reflected the strength of the franchise in the region and the fact that the market dislocation in the US while increasing the volatility in many markets, did not extend uniformly to all global markets. Expenses increased 3% versus last year. Excluding $321 million from this quarter's expense relating to repositioning, expenses were down by 3%. Lower compensation costs in Securities and Banking were offset by higher costs from acquisitions and foreign exchange and higher compensation costs in Transaction Services.</p>
          <p>We continue to focus our efforts on realigning certain businesses. This effort is embedded in our current reengineering plans. As a result, there was a head count reduction of over 1,300 in Securities and Banking in this quarter.</p>
          <p>Slide 17 shows write-downs that are taken against each category of our direct subprime exposure. The total write-downs including higher credit costs for the quarter were 6 billion, which is shown at the bottom of this slide, including $336 million taken against the Lending and Structuring position of $8 billion. Within the Lending and Structuring positions, the CDO positions are virtually entirely written off.</p>
          <p>Moving now to the top of the table, we recorded a $5.7 billion write-down against the net super senior exposure of 29.3 billion, shown in the middle of the first column. We started this quarter with a gross exposure of $37.3 billion, shown at the bottom of the first column. In addition, there was an incremental loss of 1-point billion (sic) [1.5 billion], shown towards the bottom of this slide, principally related to credit rating downgrades of hedged counterparties with subprime exposure, primarily monoline insurers.</p>
          <p>As to the $29.3 billion of net super senior direct exposures and the associated $5.7 billion write-down, these exposures continue to be subject to valuation changes based on a discounted cash flow methodology and not on observable transactions. As in prior periods, we used a proprietary model to calculate vectors for conditional payment, default rates, and loss severity. A key input for this model is the projected home price appreciation or HPA. We used the outputs to calculate the projected cash flows for the collateral assets, which we then run through the CDO distribution waterfall for each transaction. Finally, we discount the cash flow by a discount margin that reflects factors including a liquidity discount and the uncertainty associated with structured investments.</p>
          <p>The methodology that we use has been refined and the inputs have been modified to reflect current conditions. The two principal refinements and modifications this quarter are the use of a more direct method of calculating projected HPA and a more refined method for calculating the discount rate. First, in the last quarter, the projected HPA was based on a series of factors including projected national HPA and differences between subprime and other sectors of the mortgage market. This quarter, the HPA is based on a forward looking projection of the S&amp;P/Case-Shiller home price index that embodies greater subprime representation. While this change allows a more direct projection of HPA without requiring additional separate adjustments for subprime, it has a relatively small impact on our valuation.</p>
          <p>The HPA used in our valuation methodology this quarter reflects a cumulative price decline from peak to trough of 20%, 9% which we saw through the end of 2007. Our assumptions reflect a remaining price decline of 8% and 3% respectively for 2008 and 2009. As in the past, an adjustment was made for the geographic concentration of the relevant mortgage pools.</p>
          <p>Second, our methodology for calculating the discount rate was refined this quarter. In the past year, we used observable CLO spreads and applied a liquidity discount to those spreads to arrive at our discount rate. This quarter, we have used a weighted average combination of the implied spreads from single-name ABS bond prices and ABX indices and CLO spreads depending on vintage and asset types. This refinement was made in part in response to the combination of continuing rating agency downgrades of RMBS and ABS CDOs and a lack of CLO spreads at the resulting rating levels. Many analysts have been using the ABX as a rough proxy for the value of senior seniors. While we have considered the ABX, we believe that care has to be used in applying it to determine the value of super seniors for several reasons, one of which is that it does not contain earlier vintages that make up a substantial portion of our portfolio.</p>
          <p>As to the $8 billion of gross lending and structuring exposure and the write-down of 336 million, of the 336 million total, 78 million related to the CDO warehouse inventory and unsold tranches of ABS CDOs. As to the $1.5 billion incremental loss taken with respect to our hedged counterparties, we have now taken $2.5 billion in cumulative credit market value adjustments related to our monoline exposure since the third quarter of 2007. The market value direct exposure to monolines increased from $5 billion at the end of the fourth quarter to $7.3 billion at the end of this quarter.</p>
          <p>Now slide 18 provides vintage and rating data for each of the exposure types. 82% of the collateral backing asset backed CP, the asset backed CPs that we hold is of 2005 or earlier vintages, as no ABCP transactions were originated after early 2006. In contrast, the collateral backing the high grade and mezzanine CDOs have a higher proportion of 2006 and 2007 vintages as those transactions were primarily originated in 2006 and 2007. 89% of the ABCP portfolio has a credit rating between A and AAA.</p>
          <p>Another impact of vintage can be seen in the downgrades that have occurred within the collateral pools of high grade ABS CDOs, which initially owned collateral pools with an average rating around AA. Our CDO research team looked at all high grade ABS CDOs and found that for those transactions which were issued in 2004 and 2005, which would include most of our ABCP transactions, approximately 10 to 12% of the collateral pool has been downgraded to BBB or below. For transactions are that were originated in the first half of 2006, the percentage of the pool downgraded to BBB or below rises to about 25%. And for the second half of 2006 and the first half of 2007, the downgrade rate increases to 38% and 45% respectively or about 4 times the rate of the 2004 and 2005 vintage issues. This is another reason that we have view our ABCP transactions where most were issued between 2003 and 2005 to be of higher credit quality than the later vintage high grade ABS CDOs.</p>
          <p>Slide 19 provides more detail on the other four major drivers of negative revenues in Markets &amp; Banking. On the top left, in leveraged lending our commitments for highly leveraged transactions totaled $38 billion at the end of the quarter, with $21 billion in funded and $17 billion in unfunded commitments. This compares to total commitments of $43 billion with 22 billion funded and 21 billion unfunded at the end of the fourth quarter in 2007. During the first quarter, we had a net $3.1 billion pre-tax write-down on these commitments. Since the end of the quarter, approximately $8 billion of these funded commitments to financial sponsors have been sold in a structure which allows us to lock in the price and eliminate potential downside price risk associated with these commitments. While we still retain a portion of the credit risk associated with this $8 billion sale, we believe the underlying credit quality of the borrowers is strong and that the credit risk is manageable. We sold approximately $4 billion of funded commitments in the normal course of our business activity after the end of the quarter.</p>
          <p>In Alt-A mortgages, we had $22 billion in market value of such securities at the end of 2007 and are now down to $18 billion. Of the $18 billion, we have a $4.7 billion mark-to-market portfolio where the marks for the quarter were approximately $900 million net of hedges. The remaining 13.6 billion is held as available for sale securities in which we recorded a $120 million impairment in the quarter.</p>
          <p>As the graph at the bottom left shows, our commercial real estate exposure is split into three categories. For the first quarter, the blue bar represents assets subject to fair value assessment, including a $2 billion portfolio available for sale securities and a $2.3 billion trading portfolio in the alternative investments business. Excluding interest earnings, we recorded almost $600 million of write-down net of hedges on this portfolio.</p>
          <p>The second category represented by the green bar is loan commitments of approximately 21 billion, which are reserved to the extent necessary in our loan loss reserves for unfunded commitments. Finally, as the gray bar shows, we have approximately $6.4 billion in equity investments from for example limited partnership &#x2013; limited partner fund investments which are accounted for by the equity method. We have announced just this last week that we have hired Thomas Flexner, who will be responsible for directing commercial real estate activities across investment banking, commercial real estate finance, and Citi alternative investments.</p>
          <p>In mid-February we experienced our first failed ARS auction, driven by continued deterioration in the credit markets. The market continues to experience failures and there is no secondary markets for trading the paper. The most significant markdowns have been taken on student loan paper where we recorded a $971 million mark-to-market loss as ABS spreads widened significantly. In addition, we took a $355 million write-down on municipal bonds and a $132 million write-down on tax exempt and other assets. We are starting to see and are actively involved in transactions being restructured and refinanced.</p>
          <p>At the end of the first quarter before accounting for the write-down, we held ARS securities with a par value of $8 billion in our inventory, down from a peak of $11 billion in mid-February. After accounting for the write-downs in this quarter, the inventory stood at $6.5 billion as is shown on the chart.</p>
          <p>Slide number 20 shows our results in Global Wealth Management. Revenues were up by 16%, driven by strong customer activity, the impact of the Nikko acquisition, and the inclusion of Quilter. Assets under fee based management were up 15% but down 5% sequentially, due mainly to the adverse impact of market action. Revenues in the Private Bank were up double digits again, reflecting strength in structured lending and in capital markets products. Expenses were up 32%, 20% excluding a $250 million reserve, driven by acquisitions, increased customer activity, and a repositioning charge.</p>
          <p>GWM is facilitating the liquidation of investments in a Citi managed fund for its clients that have been negatively affected by recent market stress in certain fixed income assets. GWM has established a $250 million reserve to cover the estimated cost of this offer.</p>
          <p>Net income declined 33% on higher expenses and credit costs. Excluding the reserve, net income would have been up 3%. The Private Bank had a strong quarter with net income up 27% due to robust domestic and international revenue growth. The performance was outweighed by Smith Barney, where credit costs and an adverse market action drove net income down by 56%.</p>
          <p>Slide 21 shows results in alternative investments and corporate and other. Alternative investments recorded a net loss of 509 million on sharply lower proprietary revenues, a $202 million write-down of hedged fund management contract intangible assets related to Old Lane, and a 212 million mark-to-market loss on the SIV assets. Let me spend a minute on each.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, Old Lane's management team sent out letters to investments on its multi-strategy fund offering them redemptions in light of the change in the management at Old Lane. It is our expectation that a number of investments will redeem from this fund as they consider possible reinvestment in new Old Lane funds. As a result, we have written down fully the multi-hedge strategy fund intangible assets related to Old Lane.</p>
          <p>The value of the SIV assets and liabilities at the end of the quarter was $47 billion, including $170 million of junior notes. Though some of the junior notes are still intact, we have recorded a loss because losses are calculated for each SIV independently. While in certain SIV assets, write-downs have not exceeded the value of the junior notes, in others the junior notes have declined to zero. We continue an orderly wind-down of SIV assets by selling them into the open market.</p>
          <p>Corporate and other net income increased $248 million. The current period included a $212 million pre-tax write-down of an equity investment held by Nikko Cordial. The prior period included a $1.4 billion charge related to structural expense review offset by a gain on certain of our corporate owned assets.</p>
          <p>To wrap up, let me first address the areas where we continue to see risks and the actions that we have taken against each. The fixed income markets continue to be disrupted and investors remain wary, resulting in continued illiquidity in many product areas. However, we are aggressively managing our position to reduce our expenses. As I've discussed, we were able to sell down a significant portion of our leveraged finance commitments and are working very hard at reducing these positions methodically.</p>
          <p>The market for auction rate securities, while still very thin, is starting to show momentum in certain areas such as in municipal bonds and in the preferred markets. We have exposures to the commercial real estate industry, monoline insurers and to Alt-A mortgages in our Markets &amp; Banking business. All of these exposures are being managed opportunistically to reduce them in an economically viable fashion.</p>
          <p>As we look to the magnitude of disruption in the fixed income markets that have already occurred, we believe we have substantially reduced our risk given the size of the write-downs that we have taken in the last three quarters. As I explained earlier, credit costs in the Consumer business may continue to rise throughout the year. You have seen us build reserves and as this trend continues, we believe that consumer credit costs could have a meaningful impact on our results for the remainder of the year. The situation in the Japan consumer finance business remains difficult.</p>
          <p>We have taken a number of specific actions to reposition our company. We are focused on expense management and the results for the quarter demonstrate significant progress in reducing expenses and head count growth. Our 2008 reengineering plan is well underway and we expect efforts to generate cost savings that will be redeployed to our highest return opportunities. As we make progress, we expect to continue to show discernible results from these actions.</p>
          <p>We are making substantial progress on Asset Management. Just yesterday we announced the divestiture of Citi Capital, which had $13.4 billion in assets.</p>
          <p>We are building reserves to manage our expectation of higher credit costs and are working actively to mitigate credit costs within our portfolios.</p>
          <p>Our underlying business momentum is strong and we are well positioned in many of the fastest growing countries. We expect our broad presence and the depth of our client relationships to generate results. Our new organizational structure is designed to enhance exactly these competitive advantages in every region where we do business. With our capital raising efforts, the new organizational structure and management team firmly in place ,we expect to be able to continue this growth momentum and take advantage of many new client and market opportunities across the franchise.</p>
          <p>That concludes the final review of the quarter and let me now turn it back to Vikram for his final remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Gary, thank you. I want to reiterate many of the things that Gary just said. We had good operating performance in a number of areas. We are executing on our capital plan. We are executing on managing our legacy assets down. We are executing on positioning the company for the future, and we are very, very focused on efficiency.</p>
          <p>And I hope you have all been watching the announcements we have been making over the last three months. We have brought in a tremendous amount of new talent into the company. Starting with risk, we have Brian Leach as our Chief Risk Officer. Just yesterday we announced Richard Evans, who will be joining us as Head of Risk in our Institutional Clients group. We asked Suneel Bakhshi to be the head of our risk area for our consumer businesses. We also hired Charles Monet, Adil Nathani, Greg Hawkins, and John Davidson, all as senior risk professionals. Together with our current team, I believe we now have a world-class risk organization.</p>
          <p>In addition to risk, we announced significant additions in several of our businesses. You saw our announcement on Terri Dial, who is a world-class consumer banking leader; John Havens, who is now running our institutional clients business; Ned Kelly, who is running our alternatives business; Tom Flexner, who will be head of our real estate business across the entire institutional area; and Paul McKinnon, who is leading talent. And you should expect us to continue to bring in new talent to the company to add to our very deep talent pool that we already have here. As you can see, we have a fierce focus on having the right people in the right places doing the right things.</p>
          <p>As I said, we are also completely focused on efficiency, both in terms of driving our client business as well as in cutting costs. You might have seen that we announced that Mark Rufeh, a world-class productivity expert, is joining Citi. And Gary is taking the lead on our firm-wide reengineering efforts that are going very well, and you see that we finally reported a sequential decline in expenses. This will be clearly enhanced by some of the reorganizations that Gary talked about, particularly in our functions where we are going to centralize all our functions.</p>
          <p>We have also made changes to other areas of our organization. We do have a new organization which will create accountability at many levels. I believe that we finally have the right organization structure focused on clients, product excellence, and execution.</p>
          <p>Other announcements we have made this quarter include repositioning of our Wealth Management business, the realignment of our mortgage business, and the sale of non-core assets that Gary has talked about. So as you can see, we have been very busy over the last three months.</p>
          <p>I also want to tell you that I'm looking forward to seeing you all on your day, which is Investor Day on May 9. And at that time, we'll provide you more detail about all the changes we are making. We can also share with you what we can build on and build with, and we'll tell you why we think we are positioned so well in many of our businesses like cards, emerging markets, GTS, and others. And we'll also tell you what we are doing to improve our positioning in others. After hearing about these things, I think you'll see that we are taking all of the actions you would want us to take in order to maximize the value of this franchise.</p>
          <p>We are going to stop there. And with that, I would like to open it up for Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Vikram. Operator, we are ready to begin the question and answer session. Before we begin, may I ask that all callers observe a one question and one follow-up limit? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question will come from the line of Guy Moszkowski with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Guy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wanted to follow up on your discussion of consumer allowance for loan loss compared to the coincident write-off rates. As you pointed out, although in the US you are now slightly ahead in terms of allowances, internationally you are below. And when I look at the page towards the end of the supplement, which does it on a global basis, you are about 10 basis points below your coincident loss rate in terms of your allowance. Your global allowance is 2.41 and your coincident loss rate is 2.50. Given some of the trends we are seeing, I'm just wondering why you wouldn't have wanted to bring that more in line or even ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Guy, I'll take the question. If you look at most card competitors that have businesses that are outside the US, card businesses outside the US, generally you find the loan loss reserve to be somewhat lower outside the US as it is in the US. And importantly for us, if you look at the 90-day delinquencies in the card business or in our international card business, or in our international Retail Banking business, the 90-day delinquencies are dead flat with a year ago. In fact, they are actually slightly better than they were a year ago. We feel that with the additional things that we have done in Mexico and India that we properly captured the amount of reserves we should have in that portfolio. I think as you rightly point out, we feel very good about our overall level of reserves. We have taken very aggressive action as I mentioned, and we have added $8.7 billion to strengthen our reserves over the course of the last four quarters and feel good about our aggregate reserve position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And with respect to that international delinquency rate which, as you correctly point out, is very, very consistent, it doesn't really seem to predict either very significant increases or decreases in the coincident loss rates. And we did see that loss rate pop up on the international cards by a couple hundred basis points again this quarter, on a 12-month lag basis or a coincident basis actually. So I'm just wondering why you have as much faith as you do in the delinquency data to predict your long term losses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't &#x2013; I guess the way I would think about it is we have many, many different reserve pools across the company. This is one of the reserve pools we have. We look at each one of those independently and make a valuation about what we think is appropriate. The impact of acquisitions in any given quarter can have a fairly significant impact on the loss rate. So for example, when we acquired Egg &#x2013; that's primarily an international card portfolio, the losses that are embedded in the card portfolio at the time we do the purchase end up in the goodwill rather than being embedded in the loss rate calculation, and so that loss rate calculation can go up because of things like that acquisition noise where the underlying delinquencies can remain relatively flat. So as I said, we look at each one of these things individually.</p>
          <p>There is some noise in it from quarter to quarter but we feel like we are properly reserved for that at this point in time. Having said that, we are carefully watching Mexico; we are carefully watching India and we'll be reporting on that to you as we go forward and we are very focused on taking the right actions in those markets to ensure that credit doesn't deteriorate beyond what our forecasts would indicate that it will. But I think most of what you are seeing there is probably acquisition noise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to follow up, one more question on the US card business; can you comment on the sharp decline in the managed yield that we are seeing there, two quarters in a row now? It is now about 100 basis points below where it was six months ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there are a couple of things there. The Federated &#x2013; so the Federated impact is included in those numbers, and so there is some mix change associated with that portfolio. There is also, if you look at the way LIBOR and Fed funds have moved together and this is I think the primary factor, some of our pricing take place off the Fed funds rate while our underlying funding cost is based off of LIBOR. And the combination of, as you know, LIBOR and Fed funds have not moved in concert in the same way they have over the course of the last couple of years. The last six months have been a distinct difference from where it had been before. And that difference in LIBOR versus Fed funds has resulted in some of that yield squeeze.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thanks. I'm going to try and respect your restriction on questions, so I'll let you move on. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Guy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Glenn Schorr with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Gary. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, Glenn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That wasn't my one question. The balance sheet grew a little bit sequentially and a little bit more than a little year on year. Tier 1 is in reasonable shape all things considered but if you look at the tangible common equity ratio, it is pretty low. How do you and regulators, rating agencies, how much do you care and what exactly are you managing towards as you think about your decisions on what to sell off and capital raises and things like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, there are actually a number of different points to the question that I think are important to respond to. If you look at the balance sheet, you correctly say the balance sheet was flattish during the course of the quarter, but a fair hunk of that was revaluation gains that were driven by widening spreads that took place during the course of the quarter. The actual balance sheet itself if you actually look at the management of assets, the management of assets continued pretty much unabated during the course of the quarter and we feel good about the progress that we are making in that regard.</p>
          <p>We obviously have a commitment to having a very strong capital structure and you saw rightly that the Tier 1 ratio improved from 7.1 to 7.8 and the TCE ratio improved substantially. And we do have an ongoing plan to continue to reduce assets. So we announced about three weeks ago that we expected the mortgage business to have a roll-off of assets of about $45 billion over the next 12 months and we are continuing to manage other non-core assets very aggressively. The legacy loan sale that we announced last night is a good example of that. We continue to manage those non-legacy assets very aggressively and that will generate capital.</p>
          <p>Additionally, we have had three major transactions this quarter, the Redecard transaction, the Diners Club transaction, and now the Citi Capital transaction with GE that we announced yesterday. I think a good way to think about that is that that is a pace that we expect to continue through the remainder of this year. Obviously those things take time, but we don't anticipate reducing the pace of those kind of divestitures during the year. And all of that will add to our capital base as we go along. That said, we are very focused on ensuring that we have the right amount of capital in the company. We proactively raised capital when we thought that was the right thing to do. We are very focused if opportunities come up that we think are appropriate for the company, or if the risk environment should be fundamentally different, we will do whatever is necessary to ensure we have a strong capital base.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks, and just one last one. On slide 11 given that full detail on the 58 billion of the low-doc borrowers, I guess if you could provide any color on &#x2013; it feels like a little bit of a mismatch. Most of these people are reasonable high FICO scores or at least above the Mendoza line and then low LTV, but it feels like a mismatch of what I think of as a high quality borrower but doesn't want to fill out documentation. In other words, are these all wholesale funded or are these being derived from your platform?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They are both; they come from both sources. But I think you actually pointed out exactly the point that we were trying to make on this slide and I probably didn't do it very well on my written script. I actually think there is good news associated with this. So of our $151 billion portfolio or so, $58 billion fall into this category. It was this category that was characterized by a somewhat higher loss rate. But even though for whatever reason the buyer selected to provide less documentation about these loans, we were very careful to ensure that we had borrowers that had very strong credit ratings.</p>
          <p>And so the net result of that is, is that 33% of the entire prime mortgage portfolio falls into this category. 33% of the total 150 is in that top left hand box and the delinquencies against that are very, very manageable. And you can see how different that would be if more of the borrowers were down in the bottom right hand corner where we have actually had very high losses against the portfolio. So as we study this issue and dissect where losses exist and where reserves need to be taken, we thought that this provided valuable additional information of the true exposures of the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I appreciate that, but no split out on wholesale originated versus in-house?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, cool. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Mike Mayo with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question on capital. What are your thoughts for needing additional capital, and I understand that's in the context for your outlook for problem assets? You mentioned consumer credit is likely to get worse this year. And also if you could describe that in the context of the short term money markets, LIBOR is not behaving very well. So can you address the potential need for additional capital given those considerations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I mean it is exactly as I described it, so we feel very good about our capital position. As you know, we moved very early to raise capital and as I mentioned, with all of the actions taken we have raised about $35 billion. That is reflected in the way our ratios have improved during the course of the quarter. We are trying to be very prudent about this and we are managing our assets down. We have a large pool of legacy assets that we hope are not part of the family here a couple of years from now that we hope to continue to manage through. And we will continue to do divestitures but we are committed first and foremost to having a strong balance sheet.</p>
          <p>And so either in the event of opportunities that come along that we think are very valuable opportunities, or as you mentioned, factors in the environment become significantly difficult, we will be properly capitalized. We have a firm commitment to be properly capitalized and that's the way we have thought about it in terms of our capital position overall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So do you feel good about your capital and that means you don't need more capital unless things get really bad or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The fact is you can never say never with regards to these things. I mean our commitment is to have a strong capital base, and so we will monitor this and we do monitor this virtually every day. I mean we look at what the situation is and we act appropriately. We have got a schedule by which we hope to reduce assets. We have a schedule by which we hope to sell businesses. We have to achieve that plan. We have an expectation of what we think losses are going to be going forward. And we monitor our results relative to those losses and we try to be very realistic about it. What I really try to underline here is that we have been proactive and we intend to continue to manage our capital such that we have a strong balance sheet and the ability to both take advantage of the opportunities we have and withstand a difficult environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then as a follow-up, what is your outlook for the increase in problem assets? You mentioned consumer credit; any other areas that you are watching more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I tried to do was give you a pretty good feel around the card business because around the card business, we have a lot of history. You can go back and look at that and it gives you a sense of the volatility and how much that has moved and that's obviously an important factor for us.</p>
          <p>We don't have that same history around the real estate business. We are kind of in uncharted territory there. But what we have done obviously is we have chosen to take very significant reserves there. I had mentioned the months of coverage that we have as a result of our reserving methodology, the months of coverage that we currently have around the losses that we have in that portfolio, and we are watching it very vigilantly. But it is in fact trending up, as you saw, very significantly during the course of this quarter. We are going to continue to monitor that. We believe obviously that we have properly accounted for the losses that are currently embedded in the portfolio and the reserves that we have taken but we are going to monitor that. And if things change then, the reason why I mentioned near the end of what I said that there is a possibility of additional losses if things change, we will continue to try and stay ahead of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Jason Goldberg with Lehman Brothers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just with respect to I guess on head count, I guess last quarter you mentioned you are going to reduce I think 4,200 positions I think mostly in banking. And I think this quarter it was 1,300. Is there more to go on that 4,200? And then is the 9,000 you mentioned this quarter incremental to that and I guess from what parts of the company is that coming from?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is incremental. So we announced 4,200 last quarter. We announced 9,000 this quarter. The way to think about this is these are the heads that we can reserve for 12 months in advance. So you are limited to taking reserves for a 12 month time period. So this is the severance that we have paid out to these individuals or will pay out to these individuals, so these are identified positions. And the way I would think about this is that we will continually as we go through the year be focused on reengineering. I think it is unlikely that you will hear some very large significant number that we are going to announce but I think it is highly likely you will continue to hear that we are very focused on improving our cost competitiveness and as a result are consistently working away from a productivity perspective.</p>
          <p>If you split the two of these pieces out, on the consumer side, about 7,000 of the 9,000 comes from the consumer business and the actual number is 9,300. 1.3 comes out of &#x2013; I'm sorry, so the actual number is 9,000, 1.3 coming out of the commercial banking business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, just a follow-up, I guess you have announced roughly 15,000 position reductions since April of last year. I guess of that, how many have actually left the company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look at the charts, the best way to track that is to go to the head count chart without acquisitions, right? So if you &#x2013; we actually don't split the acquisitions out of this number but if you pulled the acquisitions &#x2013; so the big driver of our head count increase that we went through was the acquisitions that were added in the second, third, and fourth quarters. We're down from the peak that we had in terms of head count of 375,000. So actually I don't have a split that would show the total number that have left the company.</p>
          <p>I mean we have &#x2013; in terms of the strategic initiative that we did in the first quarter of last year, we expected 14,000 people to come out by this point in time, and those 14,000 people have come out. As regards to the 4,200 that we announced last quarter, I believe the number against the 4,200 was about 1,500 or so that had come. So if I add that up in aggregate, it would be somewhere in the 16,000 range, something like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Meredith Whitney with Oppenheimer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Gary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Meredith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I had two questions. The first is with respect to Smith Barney. You guys show the net asset flows. They look like for the last four quarters anyway &#x2013; actually you go from the flows, five quarters. You have not had much inflow. And then from the last four quarters, revenues have been really flat. Can you comment on what's going on there and what's the reaction of your customers to what's going on in the SIV market, what's going on with the auction rate security markets? Give some color on that and then I have a follow-up, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is accurate. I mean what you said is true. So our flows have been flat in Smith Barney. There are two parts of the revenues that we recognize there. The fees that we earn on assets which are heavily driven by the level of asset markets; as the asset markets go up and down and since that's primarily a US based number, as asset markets go up and down in the US, that number has gone up and down with the level of the market. So as you know, equity markets weakened as we came through the month of March. They have obviously rebounded over the last three weeks or so. But equity markets weakened for the most part during the first quarter of the year and the overall revenue level associated with that was weakened as well.</p>
          <p>The second element of their revenues are transaction revenues. Transaction revenues were actually quite strong in the fourth quarter, have weakened a little bit as we have come through the first quarter, and tend to go down during time periods where customers are concerned about what the levels of equity markets are going to be. Both of those things impacted their revenues in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Obviously focusing on flows is a key initiative that Sallie has underway. One of the things that she has done is she has revised the FA comp plan to specifically provide incentives to our FA team to increase customer flows. And so it's certainly one of the strategic objectives that we have and we hope to be able to have a positive impact on that trend.</p>
          <p>Auction rate securities is not a happy outcome for anyone. It is not a happy outcome for those who operate these auctions where we have had warehouses and have operated those auctions ourselves and where we took marks. And it's certainly not a happy outcome for customers either. We have tried to be very thoughtful about providing support to these customers. And we have made a decision to do a couple of things: one to provide a liquidity facility for our customers and that has already been done; and secondly, to mark these securities at a level that we think is appropriate for their valuation in their account. We are working on what's necessary to do the latter of those two and anticipate being able to do that over the next little while.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. My follow-up relates to real earnings visibility for the remainder of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it fair to say that you feel you are properly &#x2013; you said you were properly reserved on the consumer side, so you wouldn't expect special reserves along the way unless something materially changes. But it also sounds like you are going to have persistent restructuring charges and more moving parts than less moving parts. I wanted to get an outlook on operating leverage, when you think you are going to turn the corner, this year or is it an '09 phenomenon and how much earnings visibility any of us have and particularly you have, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, we hope to be able to provide at Citi Day a good sense of what our long-term view is on our financial model, and that's a couple of weeks away. I am very sympathetic to the difficulty that you have in trying to sort out all the moving parts that we currently have. I'm afraid it is going to be like that for a little while.</p>
          <p>There are some big blocks that you can look at. I mentioned in the comments that I made that if you took the marks out of the Markets &amp; Banking business that it impacted it significantly in the quarter that our revenues would have been roughly flat. Obviously on the page, I think it's page 2 of the deck, I talked about a number of charges which if you rolled those back into pre-tax income, you could do some kind of an estimate of what the run rate would be for the company. And it would give you a little bit of a sense of what our core earnings might have been during the course of the first quarter. But we hope to do a good job of telling you about a steady state company with the core businesses when we get together on Citi Day.</p>
          <p>As regards to reserving, I think I carefully said that we feel very comfortable that we are properly reserved for the losses that are embedded in our portfolio today. But we are watching both the real estate and the credit side of this thing very carefully and you can see that historically, there have been increases in credit card losses that have happened during the course of cycles like these. And this cycle could be particularly difficult if the real estate issue is compounded by significant increases in unemployment. We have not really had cycles where both of those factors were happening in magnitude at the same time. And that could result in losses that extend beyond where we have seen historical levels go. And we are in unprecedented territory I think from a real estate standpoint.</p>
          <p>We have tried to slice and dice our portfolio in as many ways as we could: by broker channel, by the amount of documentation to give you the maximum amount of transparency around where we think the exposures are in this portfolio. But we are in uncharted territory. So there were a couple of times as I went through some of that detail where I emphasized that we could in fact face significant headwinds as we go through the remainder of the year resulting from these increases and that is certainly a possibility.</p>
          <p>And we are dedicated to ongoing reengineering. There are going to be some dispositions that are going to take place in this quarter, in future quarters as we had in this quarter. And in this quarter, the amount of income from dispositions actually exceeded the amount we took in severance charges. I don't know whether that will happen perfectly in all of the quarters that we have going forward. But we obviously are making an effort to be thoughtful about when those severance charges hit and the timing at which we decide to sell certain of our businesses. And so we are going to try and operate the business in such a way that provides some consistency going forward. But nonetheless, you are right about what you said about noise.</p>
          <p>Operating leverage is going to be a difficult thing to measure us on for a white for a couple of reasons. We are in the active process of divesting businesses. That's a lumpy process almost by definition. There is no assurance that the amount of marks that we have taken in this quarter are finished. We are three quarters into this. I think we have substantially reduced our amount of risk but there is always the prospect that you could have additional marks and that throws the calculation of that number pretty much out the window. What I would say is that I think you should hold us accountable for a couple things: that we make significant progress on head count; and that we make significant progress that is discernible in our numbers on expenses. Those are things that you should be able to see if we are doing a good job on reengineering. And I think for now, that's going to have to be the best way to think about our progress on expense management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could I have just one last one, please? When you talk about non-core assets, just conceptually how big could a non-core asset be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess the way I would think about it is we have been engaged in a pretty significant effort of selling businesses for the last little while. You have seen what we had sold. I said that you should expect the same kind of a pace going forward in future quarters. And so I think about it roughly in that context. In aggregate taken over a long period of time, that's a fair amount of asset reduction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as important, Meredith, on Investor Day, at least you will know what our core assets are. That will give you guidance on the other side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Betsy Graseck with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. On the leverage in the Investment Bank, could you give us a sense as to where you feel you stand on that and how you see yourself trending? Do you anticipate further deleveraging or do you feel that you are done for now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we are going to continue to work down those exposures. A way to refer to that is deleveraging, but I think we are going to continue to work away at that. Some of these positions we actually feel very good about. I talked in some detail about the remaining CDO positions that we have. I think it is very important that &#x2013; there was a chart that I showed that talked about the collateral position that we have against those positions and the amount of delinquencies against various types of collateral. We feel actually pretty good about those positions and the potential of those positions if we hold those positions through to maturity.</p>
          <p>Leveraged loans have now been marked down pretty significantly and we see pretty good opportunity frankly at these pricing levels to hold those kinds of positions to maturity. That being said, I think we are very dedicated to the word I will use is narrowing the guardrails here a little bit so that the inherent volatility that we have on any individual position is not as large as the inherent volatility that we have had historically. Whether you call that deleveraging or whether you call that narrowing the risk parameters around warehouse or carry trading positions that we have, I think we are very dedicated to trying to move those into a category that will expose us to less volatility from shocks in the environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and on the head count, is any of the head count numbers related to the businesses that you will be exiting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously so far, no because we just &#x2013; real business divestitures have just happened.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But the eventual head count numbers will be what our real head count numbers are and that would include whatever divestitures that we do. It would include if we off-shored activities and moved those clients, move those jobs outside the company. It would include all of those activities. We'll report to you what our real underlying head count numbers are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the 13,200 in head count does come with some top line associated with it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It does come with top line associated with it; that's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm just trying to estimate what expense falls to the bottom line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes it is a very, very accurate. It is a small portion of the number that we are talking about here. But it does come with some top line impact associated with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then lastly on Japan, could you give us an update as to how you are feeling about the reserve ratio that you have for your Japanese consumer loan business relative to domestic peers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The domestic peers have a different accounting regime and they have taken very large multiyear reserves, and it's not US GAAP to be able to do that. We have been very vigilant in managing that exposure. And each quarter we evaluate with exactly what our position is and we are very careful to take the reserves against that business that are necessary.</p>
          <p>This is a difficult business environment. There are no easy solutions here, no silver bullets. And our intention is to manage this as effectively as we can, and to ensure that we are reserving each quarter for whatever exposures evolve. This happened to be a quarter where there was not a lot of news around that business fortunately, but that shouldn't take away from the fact that there is still risk associated with that, but we are just managing it. As I said in my comments, it is in a difficult environment. We are going to continue to manage it reflecting the difficulty that surrounds it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just make sure I understand, you are required to have &#x2013; you are limited to a one-year look forward as opposed to a cume [cumulative] loss expectation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's essentially correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of James Mitchell with The Buckingham Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe just two quick questions. One on the CDO, the ABCT paper, obviously it is older vintage. Can you speak to the duration of that portfolio and at what point would you expect if you aren't seeing material actual losses start seeing some time value accretion into the valuation of those assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About four years is about the duration of the portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>From today or from when they were originated?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful. And how much in SIV assets do you have left?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How much in SIV assets do you have left?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are down by 9 billion, so the total is 47.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>47 now. Okay, great; thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of William Tanona with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys; I've just got one question. On the Alt-A portfolio, obviously you guys have 22 billion there and looking at the write-down of 1 billion. When you compare that to other industry participants who had taken things down to 70 cents on the dollar, it just seems like it is a little light. I don't know whether or not we are just looking at that incorrectly or if there are hedges involved or is there something that we should be looking at differently or comparing that 1 billion to the 6 billion in trading as opposed to the available for sale. I'm just trying to get a sense as to why that write-down was so light relative to a lot of your peers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is the last point that you made. If you look at the chart, we split it out into available for sale versus trading. Obviously we do have some hedge positions against the trading book, but it is the available for sale versus the trading. So we took the 1 billion in write-down against the trading book essentially. 120 million of the write-down was associated with the 15.4, the larger, in the top right hand side of slide number 19. 120 million of the write-down was associated with the 15.4. The remainder was associated with the 6.7.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of David Hilder with Bear Stearns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning; two separate questions. Looking at the chart on page 12 in your presentation, you mentioned that the nature of the credit card portfolio in the US has changed a bit over time. How relevant do you think the prior maximums are for &#x2013; as we look forward to what a potential peak write-off ratio might be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do have private label portfolios that are bigger today than we had in those earlier cycles. That's an important difference. If you look in the supplement, you can actually get a pretty good breakout of the amount of private label versus the bankcard portfolios that we have. The private label portfolios do have higher losses. They have higher net interest margin as well but they do have higher losses. So that mix change will cause the number, all else being equal, should cause the number to be higher.</p>
          <p>That said, I think it is important to point out that the real high points that you see in '05 and '06 were driven by unusual factors. So the '05 was driven by a private label portfolio where we had some unusual losses right after acquisition. And the '06 spike was obviously caused by the anticipation running up to the bankruptcy legislation and by the Katrina reserves that we took. So those two real high spikes I think are not necessarily indicative things one should plan off of.</p>
          <p>This is a very, very difficult thing to do. We provided this information to give you the best look at what the ranges might be. But this particular situation, economic situation, is different than others that we have confronted in the past. So none of this is necessarily dispositive about what the eventual outcome is going to be but I think it does give you at least a handle on where things have been historically with all the caveats that I think you've rightly pointed out about looking at the data.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And then separately on page 7 of the supplement, it looks like there was a negative swing of about 2.7 billion in accumulated other comprehensive income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm wondering if you could break out what the major sources of that were.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is primary funding essentially. We obviously have interest rate hedges to try and protect us from negative surprises in the environment and obviously there was &#x2013; interest rates have improved somewhat during the course of the quarter and so that's an impact on that. We also have losses in our AFS book, which at this point are not fully recorded in our regular income statement and in addition to the losses on those interest rate positions. The losses that we would have on those AFS positions are recorded through that particular line item, OCI.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But those would have been the two biggest components rather than currency?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those are the two biggest components.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Larry Greenberg with Langen McAlenney.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Gary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Larry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was wondering if you can give us an idea of what portion of your CDO portfolio has EOD language allowing you to liquidate, and in cases where you can, what factors govern your decision. And in cases where perhaps you have liquidated, are the levels received consistent with the written-down valuations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In answer to the first question, I don't actually know the answer. I'm sure Rick Stuckey if he were here could give us an answer to that question but I don't know that. I'll tell you what we do in this process. I went through a long explanation of how we actually do the valuation of these securities to ensure that we are properly marking these. That said, we also look at the underlying trading value of the collateral and we cross-reference the underlying trading value of that collateral versus these positions. Now you can't use that to value because it covers a relatively, the collateral that's trading covers a relatively small portion of the total. So it is not necessarily representative of the value we have in the portfolio. Where we can, we cross-reference that. I can assure you that having completed that cross-referencing process, we are very comfortable that the marks represent what observable trades would be in the environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have any examples of where there has been liquidations and what that has amounted to relative to valuations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I don't have the detail on this one to offer to you. We have, as you know, we have a team under Rick Stuckey's leadership that is very focused on managing our exposure down here. And there is a lot of activity that's taken place to try and hedge particularly our highest risk exposures here but I would be overstating it to say that I knew the detail of it or that it would make sense for us to disclose it frankly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And this morning's final question will come from the line of Jeff Harte with Sandler O'Neill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning ,Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you talk a little bit about the loan growth you are seeing on the commercial side of the business? I suppose I'm curious as to whether &#x2013; what's driving that? I mean are you starting to see lines of credit being drawn down and things like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it really is -- I mentioned this a little bit. If you turn to page 7 of the supplement and step down through some of the categories here, you see for example brokerage receivables that are up a fair amount. So part of this, these are very idiosyncratic things. Because of the trading in the quarter, we did a higher amount of treasury trading that has a longer settlement period associated with it. That had an impact on that number during the course of the quarter. We had revaluation gains against our trading account assets. Those revaluation gains had an impact on the numbers in that particular column. And so they are very idiosyncratic factors that are driving each of those individual line items.</p>
          <p>If you were to take the real day-to-day management of assets, the real day-to-day management of assets has been very, very tight. And I think particularly our Markets &amp; Banking team have done an outstanding job of managing the exposures that they have and eliminating less productive areas where we have capital invested. That's a long term process. It doesn't happen overnight. We are still going to be working on this diligently I'm sure a year or two from now. But the team itself has made good progress. And the areas where you see increases here generally are caused by these idiosyncratic factors that happened to impact us in the quarter.</p>
          <p>In aggregate taken over the last two quarters, assets are down very nicely. You can see how the matched book for example is down both on the assets as well as the liabilities side here. And so we feel pretty good about how these assets are managed. We haven't seen anything in terms of draw down of credit lines that would be out of pattern in any way in particular.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And can you talk a little bit about the net interest margin? Some nice expansion we saw. You reference cost of funding being down and that's a big part of driving it. But then also I think in the credit card comments you talked about LIBOR versus the Fed. How should we be looking at the net interest margin going forward? Is it sustainable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This was a little more than I think you should plan on going forward. As you know, there's a part of this that comes from the Investment Bank and there's a part that comes from the Consumer Bank. If more of this benefit had come from the consumer side, I would feel better saying it is sustainable at this kind of a movement up. A lot of this improvement in this particular quarter came out of the trading parts of the CMB, the Markets &amp; Banking business. So I don't think you should extrapolate off of this kind of improvement. We could even see some backtracking against that as we settle down to a more normalized level. So obviously, we had nice improvement in the quarter but I wouldn't necessarily use this as the basis from which you would do a projection.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you all for listening today. If you have any questions regarding what has been discussed today, please call Investor Relations. This concludes the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude Citi's first quarter 2008 earnings review. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>