<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1323196" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call - Fixed Income</title>
    <date>2010-07-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>94</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Ilene Fiszel Bieler, Fixed Income Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John C. Gerspach, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Eric Aboaf, Treasurer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Tom Chistolini</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Barry Cohen</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to Citi's fixed income investor review with Chief Financial Officer John Gerspach and Treasurer Eric Aboaf. Today's call will be hosted by Ilene Fiszel Bieler, Head of Fixed Income Investor Relations. We ask you that please hold all questions until the completion of the formal remarks, at which time you will be given instructions for the question-and-answer session. Also as a reminder, this conference is being recorded. If you have any objections, please disconnect at this time. Ms. Fiszel Bieler, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator. Good morning and thank you all for joining us. On our call today, our CFO, John Gerspach, will speak first. Then Eric Aboaf, our Treasurer, will take you through the investor presentation, which is available for download on our website, Citigroup.com. Afterwards we will be happy to take your questions.</p>
          <p>Before we get started, I'd like to remind you that today's presentation may contain forward-looking statements. Citi's financial results may differ materially from these statements. So please refer to our SEC filings for a description of the factors that could cause our actual results to differ from expectations. With that said, let me turn it over to John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ilene, and good morning, everybody. We are very pleased to be hosting our fixed income investor review this quarter. Last quarter, we discussed some of our key accomplishments, particularly our strong capital position, robust structural liquidity and disciplined balance sheet management. This quarter, we're going to update you on our progress in these areas as well as provide you with some additional transparency into our funding strategy. Eric Aboaf, our Treasurer, is going to take you through some specifics on credit fundamentals, our capital position and liquidity profile, and then discuss our current funding plans for the remainder of this year as well as 2011 and 2012.</p>
          <p>Many of you may have joined us on last Friday's earnings call, and there are some key points from that call that I would like to reemphasize to start us off here on slide one. First, I'm very pleased that we have produced solid operating results for the second consecutive quarter. We continue to execute diligently on our strategy and our plans. There were some very tough decisions that we had to make in 2008 and 2009, and we're seeing the results, including the wind-down of our non-core assets in Citi Holdings. During the second quarter, we reduced Holdings assets by $38 billion. These assets now stand at 465 billion and are now less than 25% of Citigroup's total assets.  At the same time, Citigroup reported second quarter net income of 2.7 billion this quarter, and while we have maintained expense discipline, we are reinvesting in our core businesses &#x2013; that is, Citicorp's businesses, including continuing to make investments in order to enhance our technology.</p>
          <p>We're also seeing a number of positive trends in our businesses. First, credit losses improved for the fourth consecutive quarter and are down 31% from the second quarter 2009 peak. Continued reduction in NCLs, combined with improvement in our delinquency statistics, enabled us to record a loan loss reserve release this quarter as well. We are encouraged by the credit story internationally. In the U.S., we're all watching job creation closely.</p>
          <p>Second, in line with our growth in emerging markets, we continue to see good underlying performance in Citicorp's international businesses, particularly in regional consumer banking and transaction services. And, despite the market environment and the impact of the UK bonus tax, securities and banking still earned $1.7 billion this quarter and $4.9 billion for the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>Our profitability is a positive to our capital strength. We remain one of the best capitalized large banks in the world, with a Tier 1 ratio of 12% and a Tier 1 common ratio of 9.7%. We have loan loss reserves of $46.2 billion, and we continue to maintain significant liquidity. Going forward, Citi is well aligned with the economic growth trends we see around the world, and, despite economic conditions, we believe the decisions and execution by our management team have put in place all the elements for sustained profitability.</p>
          <p>Let me highlight some of our quarterly results for you, starting on slide two. Despite a challenging environment in securities and banking, as I just noted, Citigroup reported second quarter net income of 2.7 billion or earnings per diluted share of $0.09. Revenues of 22.1 billion were down 13% sequentially, mainly due to lower revenues in securities and banking in Citicorp and lower positive net marks in the special asset pool in Citi Holdings. Expenses of 11.9 billion were up from last quarter, primarily related to the UK bonus tax of approximately $400 million as well as continued investments in Citicorp businesses, partially offset by a decline in expenses in Holdings. Net credit losses of $8 billion improved for the fourth consecutive quarter, and we recorded a net loan loss reserve release of $1.5 billion, as credit performance continued to improve. Also, remember for comparison purposes that the second quarter of last year included the 11.1 billion pre-tax and 6.7 billion after-tax gain on the sale of Smith Barney.</p>
          <p>And now, let me turn it over to Eric.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. Let me turn to slide three. In 2010, we are fundamentally a different company than we were two years ago. We have a focused strategy to grow our three core businesses &#x2013; securities and banking, global transaction services, and regional consumer banking &#x2013; and more than half of our earnings in these businesses come from the higher growth emerging markets. We continue to make progress in reducing and de-risking the balance sheet through asset disposition, which provides us with ample liquidity to strategically invest in the future. We are seeing continued improvement in credit trends, which we'll delve into in more detail in just a moment, and our capital base is strong, no matter which capital measure you use. These changes taken together position us well to return to sustained profitability.</p>
          <p>Let me start out by taking you through our credit trends, which show continued improvement for the fourth consecutive quarter. Slide four shows total Citigroup net credit losses and loan loss reserves. NCLs continued to improve, down 5% sequentially to $8 billion, and we recorded a net LLR release of $1.5 billion, roughly half related to consumer loans and half related to corporate loans.</p>
          <p>Let me describe our credit trends in three broad areas. First, at the top right, corporate credit was a $211 million benefit this quarter. Net credit losses increased 30% to 472 million, principally from the charging-off of loans for which we had previously established specific FAS 114 reserves, which were then released during the quarter. We also recorded a net LLR release, which reflected the continued general improvement in the credit quality of our corporate loan portfolio. In fact, corporate non-accrual loans of 11 billion were down 15% versus the first quarter. At the bottom right, you can see that the majority of the credit costs were generated by our consumer businesses. Consumer NCLs declined 7% sequentially to 7.5 billion, and we released 827 million in net loan loss reserves.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide five, you see the second major area, international consumer credit, where we are seeing sustained improvement in credit trends. The trends remain very similar to last quarter, with net credit losses and delinquencies down in every region. In Asia, credit trends throughout the region continued to improve, while India showed the most significant improvement in both NCLs and delinquencies. In Latin America, Mexico remained the main driver of improving credit trends, and improving trends drove reserve releases in these two regions. In EMEA, charge-offs and delinquencies improved across most markets, and the international consumer portfolios within Citi Holdings sustained their improvement this quarter, as we continued to sell assets in Europe.</p>
          <p>Slide six shows the third major area, North American consumer credit. This includes our card portfolios at the top and our Citi Holdings mortgage businesses on the bottom. We continued to see improving credit trends across these portfolios. In cards, as we have disclosed in the past, we've been very focused on loss mitigation such as tightening underwriting criteria, closing inactive accounts and decreasing high risk credit lines. As a result, we have seen an improvement in the credit quality of the underlying portfolios.</p>
          <p>In Citi branded cards, NCLs declined 2% from the prior quarter to 2 billion. On a percentage basis, however, NCLs were up slightly due to a decline in loans. In retail partner cards within Citi Holdings, NCLs declined for the fourth consecutive quarter, down 8% to 1.8 billion. Early and later-stage delinquencies improved this quarter across both portfolios, though the pace of improvement has been faster in retail partner cards than in Citi branded cards.</p>
          <p>The bottom of this slide details the historical trends in our mortgage portfolio in Citi Holdings. 90-plus day delinquencies in both first and second mortgages declined again this quarter, leading to lower NCLs. In the quarter, in fact, we sold 1.3 billion in delinquent mortgages. Also, as of the end of the quarter, we converted 2.5 billion of HAMP trial mods into permanent mods. This is up from 1.6 billion at the end of the first quarter. Consistent with what we said in last quarter, early results continue to indicate that redefault rates for HAMP modified loans will likely be lower than for non-HAMP mods. Our loan loss reserves continue to reflect the impact of modifications including expected redefaults.</p>
          <p>Against these three major categories of loans &#x2013; corporate, international consumer and North American consumer &#x2013; we wanted to share with you the size of our loan loss reserves on slide seven. Loan loss reserves were $46.2 billion at the end of the first quarter, or 6.7% of total loans. Consumer loan loss reserves were 39.6 billion, or 7.9% of loans, and corporate loan loss reserves were 6.6 billion, or 3.6% of loans. Along the bottom of the page, you'll see that the coincident months of coverage of our consumer portfolio increased from 15.5 to 15.9 months and is significantly above the 12.7 level from a year ago, despite the reserve release.</p>
          <p>Now that I have covered credit trends and reserves, let me describe our progress in reducing the amount of higher risk assets. Slide eight shows the asset trends in Citi Holdings. We ended the quarter with 465 billion of assets, a reduction of 362 billion, or 44% from the peak in the first quarter of 2008. We have made significant progress in reducing Citi Holdings assets, particularly since this includes the impact of adopting FAS 166, 167 last quarter, which added 43 billion of assets to Citi Holdings in the beginning of the year. Citi Holdings assets now make up less than a quarter of our total assets at Citigroup. The $38 billion reduction in assets that you see in 2Q was driven by three factors: 19 billion of asset sales and business dispositions, including 6 billion from the Primerica IPO and 4 billion from the liquidation of sub-prime CDOs; approximately 15 billion of net runoff and pay-downs; and 4 billion of net credit losses and net asset marks. Local consumer lending, which we covered in detail in the credit section, drove approximately 60% of the asset decline, while the special asset pool accounted for the other 40%.</p>
          <p>Now turning to page nine, we provide additional breakdown of the end of period assets in the special assets pool over the last five quarters. As you can see, overall, these assets have been decreasing at a good pace, down 38% from the end of the second quarter of last year. As you scan the information here, I want to highlight a couple features of this asset base. First, we have made very good progress with respect to reducing our exposure in higher risk areas such as sub-prime securities and monolines, which are each now under $1 billion in assets. And second, many of these positions have been significantly marked down, as you can see on the right side of the page, looking at their face value as compared to the current carrying value. As I said, clearly, we've made good progress.</p>
          <p>Now that we have covered improved credit trends and continued asset reductions, let me update you on slide 10 on how we are optimizing our liability structure. First, at the bottom of the slide, you can see our equity base, which we have continued to build up over time. Second, you can see that we increased our long-term debt in the middle of last year, as we reinstated our issuance program. Part of the reason this amount trended down to $413 billion in the second quarter is because our cash position afforded us the flexibility to retire liabilities with shorter remaining life while maintaining our structural funding. Thus far in 2010, we tendered for approximately 4 billion of older senior and subordinated debt securities nearing maturity.</p>
          <p>Finally, we get to the deposits, our most stable and lowest cost funding source. Quarter over quarter, we saw some reduction in deposits which was due to FX. Along the bottom of the page, you can see that on an ex-FX basis, our deposits are flat. As I've said before, as financial markets have stabilized, we now have the ability and the willingness to lower our price point, moderate balance growth and widen our spreads and margins, while still remaining competitive.</p>
          <p>So let me turn to slide 11 and talk about capital, which is an area of significant strength for us. This slide reflects our strong capital levels at the end of the second quarter, making us one of the most well-capitalized large banks in the world, with 121 billion in tangible common equity and 99 billion in Tier 1 common. Relative to the first quarter, our capital measures are up, driven by net income. And compared to the pre-crisis era of 2006 and 2007, our capital measures are up between 20 and 45 billion. Our capital base is one of the strongest in the industry.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 12, at the end of the second quarter, our Tier 1 and Tier 1 common ratios were 12% and 9.7% respectively, up from yearend and also up from the first quarter. With these strong capital ratios, we believe we are well positioned to weather any economic uncertainties while at the same time have the flexibility and the appetite to take advantage of growth opportunities around the world.</p>
          <p>While the credit markets have clearly reflected these improvements, we believe that the rating agencies have started to recognize our progress as well. You will recall that since late in the fourth quarter of 2008 and early in the first quarter of 2009, our ratings at the Citigroup level have been unchanged, at A3 with Moody's, A for S&amp;P, and A+ for Fitch. During the first quarter of 2010, however, S&amp;P upgraded our standalone credit profile by a notch. Just this week, Moody's changed the rating outlook on our standalone bank financial strength rating to stable from negative, based on our strengthened capital position and improved risk profile. Moody's also changed the outlook on our hybrid securities to stable from negative, as they are linked to our standalone financial strength rating. As you would expect, we are in ongoing discussions with the rating agencies and provide them with continuous information about our significant progress.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to slide 13, given that so many of you have asked, let us touch upon some of the provisions included in the U.S. financial reform legislation signed into law yesterday. As you all know, there are a lot of details to be worked out. The ultimate impact won't be clear until we know some of these. But you also know that we have been managing our businesses in line with the principles of the reform, and as you've heard Vikram say, we have been advocates of strong regulatory reform all along.</p>
          <p>So this is all based on our preliminary analysis. On the institutional side, on the Volker Rule, most of Citi's trading businesses are client-driven. On the derivatives side, we believe the majority of the derivatives we did in the bank we can continue to do in the bank. Bank entities can enter into swaps needed to hedge traditional lending exposures. Based on our current understanding, bank entities can continue customer facilitation and market making in interest rate, foreign exchange, centrally cleared investment-grade CDS and gold and silver swaps. On the broader issue of changes in markets, because of the derivatives legislation, we're all going to have to see both the regulations and the impact on the markets.</p>
          <p>There is also a bit more clarity in consumer banking. Here are some initial thoughts. On fees, such as debit card overdraft fees, we generally did not allow our debit cardholders to overdraft their accounts in the first place. On debit charge interchange, debit purchase is not a significant business for us. Another key point on consumer reform is that our regional consumer bank is much more international than most. 53% of our consumer bank revenues during the first half of 2010 came from outside the U.S., and they reflect a substantial part of our profitability. And on the Collins amendment, as you know, Tier 1 credit for TruPS will be phased out over three years beginning January 1, 2013. Given our current capital position, we do not believe that this change will be significant for us. Of course, we are all waiting for certainty on what capital requirements are going to be as a result of reform legislation and continued discussions around Basel II and Basel III.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 14, let's take a closer look at our liquidity levels. As we've reduced and reshaped our balance sheet, we've strengthened our structural liquidity as measured by one of the traditional metrics that you see here on the left side. Together, equity plus long-term debt plus deposits form the heart of a bank's liquidity. This combination of structural funding has risen from 62 to 71% of total assets during the three and a half year timeframe you that see here. On the right side of the page, you see our aggregate liquidity resources, defined as cash and liquid securities, which were approximately 313 billion at the end of the second quarter. We have increased these resources over the past year and currently believe they are proportionately calibrated to the size of our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>In addition to successfully building these high liquidity levels, let me take a minute to talk about fungibility of our liquidity at Citi. In general, Citigroup can freely cross-fund legal entities within our bank vehicle, and Citigroup's non-bank vehicles can fund our bank vehicles. In addition, under section 23A of the Federal Reserve Act, our bank can fund our non-bank entities with as much as 26 billion, as long as it is collateralized appropriately.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 15, part of the way we've strengthened our structural liquidity was by implementing a sound funding strategy. Our current funding strategy is designed to provide ample, high quality liquidity to ensure we are well positioned to grow our core businesses and navigate various market conditions. In both the bank and the non-bank, short-term liquidity takes the form of cash and highly liquid securities, such as treasuries and agencies and other G7 bonds.</p>
          <p>We execute on this strategy in both our bank and the non-bank businesses by leveraging a spectrum of appropriate funding sources. In our bank businesses, our funding is primarily in the form of stable, globally diversified deposits and is supplemented with some asset-backed securitizations as well as underlying equity. In our non-bank businesses, we use a modest amount of short-term funding such as commercial paper and repo to finance liquid assets. We then use a broad range of long-term debt instruments to cover our broader business needs. These longer-term debt instruments include fixed and floating term debt, both senior and subordinated, and of course we use our underlying equity.</p>
          <p>Turning now to slide 16, as I mentioned earlier in the presentation, at the end of the second quarter we had 413 billion in long-term debt outstanding. Approximately 64% of that debt is used to fund our non-bank businesses, with the remainder, or 36%, funding the bank. In fact, the 36% long-term debt that is found in the bank is primarily related to asset-backed securitizations, largely credit card securitizations that were brought onto the balance sheet last quarter due to FAS 166, 167 consolidation, which you can see here in the green at the top right bar on the right. Securitizations are a supplemental form of funding for the bank, as I just mentioned.</p>
          <p>In our non-bank entities, you can see on the bar on the right in dark blue, the vast majority of our long-term debt is comprised of senior term debt, which is both fixed and floating, along with senior and subordinated instruments as well as TruPS.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 17, you can see that in keeping with our relative proportion of bank and non-bank long-term debt outstanding, the majority of our long-term debt maturities this year and over the next three years are in the non-bank, shown here in blue. This chart clearly shows the maturities peaking in 2012 and coming down in 2013. As we see across the bottom of the slide, TLGP debt represents a significant amount of maturities in 2011 and 2012.</p>
          <p>Many industry observers have noticed that this wave of maturities is an industry-wide situation, which came about as many banks issued TLGP and other government-guaranteed debt. For us at Citi, however, we do not expect to refinance TLGP maturities. The reason is very simple. As we've discussed before, and as we continue to reduce and de-risk our Citi Holdings balance sheet in both our bank and non-bank entities, our need for long-term debt is just coming down.</p>
          <p>So let's start with the bank. Turning to slide 18, you see the maturities and currently expected issuances of long-term debt in our bank entities year by year. As I mentioned previously, the majority of our long-term funding in the bank comes from our deposits, which are our lowest cost source of funds, and as you might expect and I just mentioned, our maturities in the bank are relatively modest in the coming years and largely comprised of TLGP debt. Given both our strong liquidity position and ready access to deposits as well as the continued wind-down of the Citi Holdings balance sheet, we do not expect to refinance TLGP debt coming due in the bank. In addition, with limited maturities coming due, local country issuance by our international bank subsidiaries and branches is expected to be small. This makes our bank largely deposit-funded.</p>
          <p>On slide 19, we have maturities and currently expected issuance of long-term debt in our non-bank entities. In keeping with the overall maturities profile, you can see here that long-term debt maturities peak in 2012 here as well, with a significant portion attributed to TLGP. As we continue to de-risk the balance sheet and reduce our Citi Holdings assets in our non-bank entities, we do not expect to refinance TLGP debt. That said, as part of our strategy to solidify structural liquidity and extend the duration of our liabilities supporting our businesses, we plan to issue an additional 3 to 6 billion in long-term debt this year over what we previously communicated. This will result in approximately 23 billion of total long-term debt issuance for 2010 including local country debt. As I mentioned earlier, we have successfully retired $4 billion of short remaining life long-term debt in the first half of year, which we will be effectively replacing with this term issuance. This makes sense in the current market environment and positions us very well going it into 2011. We will obviously continue to provide updated guidance to you on our funding plans in the coming fixed income reviews as appropriate.</p>
          <p>Slide 20 details our broad-based issuance franchise. Given our global reach and strong capital levels, issuing approximately $23 billion a year is quite modest and well below our historical annual issuance amounts. To this end, we have built a broad-based issuance franchise in recent decades that gives us access to reliable and diversified funding sources. As many of you know, this includes issuing in multiple currencies, including US dollars, Euros and sterling, among others, issuing across tenors including 3s, 5s, 10s, 25s and 30s, and satisfying investor demand across a breadth of segments. As the pie chart on the bottom shows, our investors, all of you, are quite diverse and represent a wide variety of institutions. As always, we greatly appreciate your sponsorship. Thank you.</p>
          <p>Moving to our last slide, let me summarize with four major points. First, we see continued credit improvement. Corporate credit is improving. International consumer credit trends continue to improve and North American consumer credit trends are showing signs of stabilization and improvement. Second, our capital base is one of the strongest in the industry, and this is reflected across every one of our significant capital ratios. Third, we have significantly improved our structural liquidity by increasing our capital base and deposits, reducing assets and extending liability duration as appropriate. We believe we have ample liquidity with a flexible balance sheet that can be redeployed for growth. And fourth, we will have a significantly lower proportion of wholesale funding going forward. We currently expect modest reissuance needs in both of our unsecured long-term debt and card securitization programs, and we do not expect to refinance TLGP debt that is coming due.</p>
          <p>That concludes our fixed income review. John and I will be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from Robert Bernou</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Robert , how are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I'm good. The line is a little bit difficult to hear. I'm getting a lot of echo. So sorry if this is garbled.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can hear you very clearly, Robert , so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well, hopefully that will turn out okay then. Could you review some of the last slides with respect to maturities and debt issuance? Specifically, you mentioned that you won't be refinancing the TLGP debt, so I'm guessing that's going to mature at the bank level, but you're going to do additional funding at the &#x2013; at, I guess, the group level, 3 to 6 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert , it's Eric Aboaf. Here's how I would summarize. If you take a quick look at page 17 to start, you can see the total maturities, call it 45 in 2010 and 45 in 2011, and you can see the TLGP component of that at the bottom of the page, the 6.4 and the 20.3. All right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The situation is that we don't expect to need to reissue the TLGP that is coming due. And so, what you see on the issuance agenda, in particular on page 19, right, is issuance or reissuance of our more, of our traditional long-term debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so that's &#x2013; I'm just trying to follow through. So that's the 4.7 and the 10.5 &#x2013; no, that's not bank TLGP. I'm sorry. So what would those numbers be for the rest of 2010, 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So for 2010 and 2011, right, let's take them in turn, you have 45 billion maturing in total in 2010, 6.2 billion of that is in the bank, right, and the good bit of that is TLGP in the bank. We won't need to reissue that bank TLGP this coming year, at the end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And in fact, we're only going to be issuing about 23 billion in total of the remaining 39 or so of maturing debt in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you do the same math in 2011, you see $45 billion of total maturities on page 17.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you go to the bottom of the table, you see 20 billion of TLGP debt maturing. That leaves 25 billion of non-TLGP debt maturing in 2011, and of that 25, we expect &#x2013; non-TLGP debt maturing &#x2013; we expect to reissue approximately 23, and you see that on page 19.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So in terms of long-term debt, and I'm assuming that this is &#x2013; you're categorizing that as three years and out &#x2013; for the rest of this year, you're going to do an additional 3 to 6 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the best way you can understand our issuances for this year are by looking on the left side of slide 19. You can see what's maturing in total for the year, and then at the bottom left, you see the year-to-date maturities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You can see what we expect to issue, which is about 23 billion in total, including that 3 to 6 that I had mentioned. Right? And of the 23, we've issued 19 billion so far, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which leaves the balance for the remainder of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, so the rest, if you, so 23 minus 9 is 4, I know that &#x2013; 19 is 4, I know it's fixed income call, so you have to do this stuff with us, and the 3 to 6 may be pre-funding for 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'd say it's partially pre-funding and partially just matching the ladder of debt that we like to have out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And does this include the refinancing of the upper decks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it would include the refinancing of the upper decks, which is sometimes talked about as the OTIA transaction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so the OTIA transaction is just under 2 billion, and you're going to have to get that done by the middle of the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct. There's a sequence of steps that happen, and I think the issuance comes to market typically in the third month of the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can I ask one question on that, and then I'll get off? It seems like the last two times these were done, they were either done and there was some confusion in the market as to what the security was, or it seemed that they were done right at a time, right at the deadline, and you guys seem to pay up for them. So I guess my question is how should we think about this? How should we think about timing with that? And you know, last two times, the deals were &#x2013; came at a good concession. Should we look forward to that again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The background I'd give you is that the legal requirements around those upper decks and conversion to equity and issuances, right, have specified time periods. You know, clearly that, those specified time periods can sometimes come at positive cycles in the market or more modest cycles in the market, and we'll obviously figure out how to issue based on those time periods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're very welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from John Carolan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. A couple quick questions. I didn't fully follow what you said on slide 14, particularly. Could you just run through that section again, particularly that, what you're trying to convey with that 26 billion carve-out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think the basic principle &#x2013; and it's Eric Aboaf here. The basic principle around liquidity is that we have the liquidity in our bank chain of about 210, $229 billion on that slide on, in the second quarter of 2010, and 84 billion in our non-bank vehicles including our dealers and other non-bank entities. As you know, within the U.S., we have a separation of legal vehicles within a bank holding company, and so liquidity tends to be used within vehicles. That said, as a large financial institution in the U.S., we also have some ability to provide liquidity from one vehicle to the other, and in particular, the 26 just describes how much could be provided from the bank to the non-bank as a way to just inform you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how does that compare to the amount of vehicle outstanding that this could help in a liquidity situation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The amount of what I would describe as liquidity resources, right, are sometimes thought of as a cash box, are literally the numbers on that bar, 84 and 229 billion. And the 26 just provides for some additional fungibility were we to want to use it between the bank vehicles, in light blue, the 229, and the non-bank vehicles, in gray, the 84.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And why did you not have an updated slide 17 from the last stack, where you detailed the short-term borrowing? The, slide 16 in the current deck shows short term &#x2013; or I'm sorry, not slide 16. It was &#x2013; slide 10 shows the short term borrowing at 93 billion, and in the last quarter you had a slide that detailed that 97, which is now 93. Is there any reason you left that off this time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think what we've chosen to do is just help you with additional detail where there are some material changes. You can see on slide 10, if you turn to that at the top, the light green if you have it in color or the very top little part of the box is the short-term borrowings. They didn't change materially from 2Q versus the prior quarter, and so we didn't add the page in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So can you say what the &#x2013; what the multi-seller conduits number was for Q2?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have it handy, but I think 2Q is reasonably similar to the first quarter, and you're certainly welcome to call Ilene Fiszel Bieler and she can, in our Fixed Income Investor Relations, and she can take a look.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just a big picture, last question. I was wondering if you could share with us what you &#x2013; how you're thinking about maybe some unintended consequences that could come out of the FASB proposal to mark to market the loans?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's John Gerspach. I think you actually, when you get into something that's unintended consequences, you know, we're trying to think through the entire proposal, and obviously, it's just a proposal at this point in time. It's just an exposure draft or whatever the current term for an exposure draft is. We obviously, along with everyone else in the industry, and I assume many in the investor community, will be providing FASB comments in the September timeframe, and we'll have to see how it goes from there. As of how we're preparing for unintended consequences...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, in terms of how it might change how you operate the business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, I think that's a great question. I think that's one of the questions obviously that everyone will comment on in their responses to the exposure draft. I think the entire industry now is trying to look and see what some of the unintended consequences &#x2013; actually some of the consequences would be. I don't think we've even gotten into the unintended consequences, but we're trying to just outline what the potential consequences of the what at least purports to be a fair value accounting for loans in a multi-step process, but then an asymmetric approach where you don't have fair value accounting for the liability side of the balance sheet, deposits.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Ryan O'Connell with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I did miss part of the discussion, just because of the technical issue, but on TLGP, I think I've got most of it. Let me just try taking another cut at it. If I look at the bank level TLGP, that looks to be about $22 billion. Sorry, can you all hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we can hear you, Ryan .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, about $22 billion, and I get that deposit growth. You take care of that. Then you've got another 40-odd billion outside of the bank level, and I wasn't quite clear, I mean is that because you anticipate lower asset levels over the next several years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ryan , it's Eric Aboaf. That's exactly it. In both the bank and the non-bank, we are seeing lower asset levels as that Citi Holdings' balance sheet continues to come down, right? You've seen the reduction that we've had over the last two years. You can see it quarter after quarter as that comes down, right? That requires less of a need for long-term funding, and thus we don't need to reissue the TLGP.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's very helpful. And then on the 84 billion of liquidity, and it's very helpful to see this broken out, so that's for the parent, the broker-dealers and I take it that's cash, unencumbered securities. I guess my question is Citi, of course, operates across the world, London, Tokyo, I don't know how many other centers. How much of that liquidity, that 84 billion, is available to the U.S. operation? My question here, I guess, is how much liquidity has to be maintained in various different jurisdictions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's a &#x2013; it's Eric Aboaf, Ryan . It's a good question. The way I would frame it is that that liquidity supports, as you described, the various parent vehicles and the various broker-dealers that we operate. We operate large broker-dealers in the U.S. and the UK, and effectively it's there &#x2013; and small one in Asia, and that is effectively available to support those dealers. What we also do as part of managing the liquidity is to make sure that we keep both liquidity within some of those individual vehicles as well as the top of that vehicle chain, so that the resources are available where necessary, and that provides us the maximum amount of flexibility and obviously ability to use that liquidity as necessary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, okay, so in other words, you're taking those various potential regulatory restrictions into account, of course?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct. What I would say is we are very cognizant of liquidity by individual legal vehicle, by jurisdiction, and you know, obviously, we need to be certain that the liquidity that we described to you and that we have has sufficient fungibility characteristics that it can be used where necessary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, and then I just have one last one. Just on the fundamentals, it sounds like there's been good progress in Mexico and India in the credit card operations. I know you don't go into a whole lot of specific country detail, but are those basically kind of breakeven now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ryan , we don't go into individual business profitability country by country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so I hear you, John. So we're going to say there's progress. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Tom Chistolini with Fidelity Investments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. First question, just to clarify, on slide 19, the issuance year to date on that slide it says 9 billion, but I think, Eric, you mentioned 19 billion was issued year to date. Which is the right number there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is 9 billion. If I said 19, that was a mistake. I meant to say 9 billion of issuances year to date.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So we should expect the second half then you would issue roughly 14 billion of long-term debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In those non-bank vehicles, that's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and on the TruPS, any additional color you can provide relative to how you are thinking about that when that phases out? Are you thinking about will you exercise your par call rights? Will you try to exchange these? Any color you can provide on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Eric Aboaf. As I said on the slide where we covered the legislation, that was all based on a very preliminary analysis. Clearly, we're going to learn more, and we also need to learn more about the capital requirements that we will all have as an industry. You know, between the time of when it comes to &#x2013; we need to begin to consider and the three-year phase-in, right, it seems like there's going to be a lot of time to study, analyze, clearly understand and we'll certainly come back to you and brief you with what our plans are as that plays out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then one other thing on the, as far as changes on the FDIC, the new deposit calculation, any guidance or color you can give us on what the incremental cost of that is likely to be for Citi?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is John. I'd say the best is we are looking at everything that is in the bill. With the signing of the bill, we've now kind of gone from &#x2013; we've passed now the unsigned and now we're entering into the realm of the undrafted and the unintended. So we're looking to see, as things get a little bit more specific, we'll be able to address in a great deal more detail all of the various aspects of the bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's the one, is it fair to say that's the one that is going to have the greatest impact on you relative to your peers, just because you have such a relatively small deposit base in the U.S. and now the insurance premium will be based on effectively your liability base going forward, which includes all the international?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, that is somewhat dependent on how rules get drafted, what counts towards assets, what counts towards deductions against those assets. There is &#x2013; again, there's just a lot of detail that needs to be put down on paper in order for to us really assess with any degree of vigor and specificity what the impact would be on us, but clearly, it's one of the areas that we are being look at very closely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And your next question comes from Barry Cohen with Knott Financial (sic) [Knott Partners] .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, it's Knott Partners, but good morning, gentlemen. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I've got a couple questions, I just want to center around on the Holdings portion of it. Could you actually break out the dollar amount by year in your maturities schedule that you estimate is coming out of the Holdings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Eric here. We don't actually go into that level of detail, and it's actually difficult to do it precisely at this point, because if you think about the chart we showed on the asset reductions quarter over quarter and year by year, right, what you'll realize is that some of those assets may have been shorter-term, some of them medium-term, some longer-term, right? There's a whole ladder of assets that are currently being funded, right? As we wind that down, that ladder reduces, but whether the longest-term or the medium-term or the intermediate-term comes down more or less is kind of hard to predict. And so what we've provided here for you is some guidance based on our estimates, but we think it's reasonably reliable and will give you an indication for the funding needs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, maybe instead of thinking of it that way, maybe I'll try a different way, which may be a little easier to answer. If you were to actually look at the cap structure of the Holdings, and you were to look at short-term debt, medium debt, long-term debt and then your equity component, what would that look like?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's a good theoretic question. The issue is it's not a practical question, because Citi Holdings businesses actually span a number of different vehicles. They span banking vehicles, non-bank vehicles, and so there's not a all-in capitalization structure within and across those businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand. How much equity then would you estimate is actually underneath the Holdings group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's not a figure that we've ever tried to put out, exactly because of all the reasons that Eric just outlined. There's one equity pool for all of Citigroup, and it supports businesses that we report both as part of Citicorp as well as Citi Holdings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I guess I'll just ask one final question then. If you look at Citi Holdings and you look at the components of pre-tax profitability, if you strip out North American real estate and you start going through the lines, when you look at everything else other than North American real estate, when do you think on a pre-tax operating basis do you think that they more or less start turning positive?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, we've never given any specific guidance on the profitability of the Holdings units. What we have given you, and I assume this is the genesis of your question, if you go back to the investor deck that we used in the earnings call from last week, there's a slide 29, which is in the appendix, where we did break out the pre-tax components of the local consumer lending business. And there you can see that in local consumer lending, which is the largest piece now remaining in Holdings, for the second quarter, local consumer lending on a pre-tax basis would have lost $2.1 billion, of which 1.8 came from the North America real estate lending business. So clearly the vast, vast majority of the pre-tax losses remaining in Holdings are coming out of that North America real estate business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I appreciate your help. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Final question comes from Michael Rogers with Kearney Asset Management .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. The recent rating agency actions with respect your standalone financial strength have certainly been encouraging, and in that regard, has this increased your optimism within Citigroup that you may be able to sustain the top tier short-term ratings across the three principal rating agencies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Eric Aboaf. We are encouraged by some of their recent actions. Clearly, it takes time after an industry event that we've seen for folks to reassess ratings, but each of the agencies tell us that they are continuing to assess and reassess, and obviously, we're working closely with them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have numbers, Eric, in the unlikely or maybe the undesirable event of losing one of those short-term ratings down to, let's say, a P2 status, will you have information available once again, if you don't have it available now, as to the potential incremental liquidity requirements that you may be forced to post?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we have actually disclosed a fair amount of information in our 10-Q. We'll obviously continue to do that. If you go back to the last Q that was filed for the first quarter, you'd see that we fully dimensioned the size of our commercial paper program, about $10 billion. We also dimensioned derivative triggers and several other immediate calls on liquidity, which were worth around 4 billion, so you kind of have a 14 billion immediate impact. In contrast to that, though, what you have to think about is the large cash box that we hold at the Citigroup level, right? 313 billion in total, 84 billion in the non-bank, and so we clearly have multiple times those amounts in resources available to us, were something to change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. One last part to this I guess is how concerned are you, if do you lose one of those top tier ratings, that the ability to fund in the broad fashion that you've always been able to fund in translates &#x2013; and the loss of that, translates into somewhat of an impairment of the investment bank's current franchise?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the best way to answer that question is as you think about what could happen from a rating standpoint, I think what most observers have noted is that it looks like an industry-wide question, right? There are, I think, four institutions in a similar position with government supporting their ratings. Clearly, that's going to play out and we, among others, are getting stronger and stronger, right? Were we to have a downgrade in the short term, I'm pretty confident that we would see that across a number of players in the industry, and I think that will mean that the businesses will need to readjust, but we don't think that they will readjust in such a way as to dramatically impair or affect our operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, there are no further questions. Ms. Ilene Fiszel Bieler, are there any closing remarks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Thank you, operator and thank you, everyone, for joining the call today. If you have any follow-up questions, please don't hesitate to reach out to us in Fixed Income Investor Relations. We'll talk to you all again soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's Citi's fixed income investor review conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>