<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1300722" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call - Fixed Income</title>
    <date>2010-04-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>94</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Ilene Fiszel Bieler, Fixed Income Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John C. Gerspach, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Eric Aboaf, Treasurer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">David Knutson</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Louise Pitt</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Kabir Caprihan</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello and welcome to Citi's Fixed Investment Investor Review with Chief Financial Officer John Gerspach and Treasurer Eric Aboaf. Today's call will be hosted by Ilene Fiszel Bieler, Head of Fixed Income Investor Relations. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Also as a reminder, this conference call is being recorded today. If you have any objections, please disconnect at this time.</p>
          <p>Ms. Fiszel Bieler, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator, good morning and thank for joining us. On our call, our CFO, John Gerspach, will speak first. Then Eric Aboaf, our Treasurer, will take you through the investor presentation, which is available for download on our website, Citigroup.com. Afterwards, we will be happy to take any questions.</p>
          <p>Before we get started, I would like to remind you that today's presentation may contain forward-looking statements. Citi's financial results may differ materially from these statements, so please refer to our SEC filings for a description of the factors that could cause our actual results to differ from expectations.</p>
          <p>With that said, let me turn it over to John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ilene, and good morning everyone. We're very pleased to be hosting our Fixed Income Investor Review this quarter. Last quarter we discussed some of our key accomplishments in 2009, particularly, our strong capital position, robust structural liquidity, and disciplined balance sheet management. This quarter, we're going to update you on our progress in those areas, as well as provide you with some additional transparency into how we are transforming our balance sheet. Eric Aboaf, our Treasurer, is going to take you through some specifics on credit fundamentals, our capital position, and liquidity profile, and then discuss our current funding plans for the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>Many of you may have joined us on Monday's earnings call and there were some key points from that call that I would like to reemphasize to start us off here on slide one. The first quarter results we announced on Monday are a reflection of all the progress we've made at Citi: net income of 4.4 billion, 25.4 billion in revenue, and operating costs of 11.5 billion. Net credit losses were down for the third consecutive quarter. Non-performing assets were down for the second consecutive quarter, and loan loss reserves were 48.7 billion. Our financial strength is substantial, with a Tier 1 common ratio of 9.1%, Tier 1 of 11.2%, and total allowance for loan losses of nearly 49 billion or 6.8% of total loans.</p>
          <p>Citi is well positioned to take advantage of the longer-term growth rates we see in the global economy. Our franchise is strong. Our global footprint is unique. We are having great success attracting talent, and we believe we are building momentum.</p>
          <p>Let me highlight our quarterly results for you on slide two. As you know, results for the first quarter of 2010 include the impact of FAS 166/167, which resulted in the consolidation of certain off-balance sheet assets, including securitized credit card receivables. Therefore, GAAP results for the first quarter should be compared to managed numbers for prior quarters.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter, we reported revenues of 25.4 billion. Operating expenses were 11.5 billion, down 6% from the fourth quarter. Provisions for credit losses, claims, and benefits were 8.6 billion, consisting primarily of net credit losses of 8.4 billion. Net credit losses were down 16% from the fourth quarter on a comparable basis. And we recorded a modest net loan loss reserve release of 53 million in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>We reported net income of 4.4 billion or earnings per share of $0.15, based on average diluted shares outstanding of 29.3 billion. As those of you who joined us on Monday may have heard me say, this 4.4 billion represents the highest quarterly net income since the second quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>On slide three, we summarize the balance sheet impact of FAS 166/167. As of January 1, 2010, we consolidated approximately $137 billion of assets and $146 billion of liabilities onto our balance sheet, the majority of which was related to credit card securitizations. This translated into $10 billion of additional risk weighted assets.</p>
          <p>We also added 13.4 billion to our loan loss reserves, which decreased our tangible common equity by 8.4 billion. And in total, these adjustments lowered our Tier 1 common ratio by 138 basis points. Importantly, we were able to largely offset the impact on tangible common equity and Tier 1 common during the quarter.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'm going to turn it over to Eric to take you through the rest of the review, and then he and I will be happy to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide four, we entered 2010 a fundamentally different company than we were two years ago. We have a focused strategy to grow our three core businesses: Securities &amp; Banking, Transaction Services, and Regional Consumer Banking. We are seeing continued signs of improvement in credit trends. Our capital base is strong, no matter which capital measure you use, and we continue to make progress in reducing and derisking the balance sheet through asset dispositions, which provide us with the ample liquidity to strategically invest in the future. These changes position us well to return to sustained profitability.</p>
          <p>Let me start out by taking you through our credit trends, which we described as showing continued signs of improvement. Slide five shows total Citigroup net credit losses and provisions. The net credit losses of 8.4 billion were down 16% versus the prior quarter. And as you can see, the net credit loss trend peaked at 11.5 billion almost a year ago.</p>
          <p>Let me decompose that for you. At the top right, corporate credit costs were 87 million in the first quarter, down 89% sequentially. Net credit losses were down 66% to 364 million, and we recorded a net loan loss reserve release of 277. The decline in corporate credit cost reflects continued stabilization in credit quality across most segments and regions of our corporate loan portfolio.</p>
          <p>At the bottom right, you can see that the majority of the credit costs are generated by our Consumer businesses. Consumer net credit losses of 8 billion declined 10% versus the fourth quarter, and the net loan loss reserve build of 225 million was down 78%.</p>
          <p>Within Consumer, it is actually helpful to think about the drivers of credit in terms of our businesses in both North America and in international. Looking at our international businesses, slide six shows the consumer credit trends. Net credit losses and delinquencies were down in the first quarter in every region, Asia, Latin America, and Europe.</p>
          <p>In Asia, credit trends in Korea remain stable to improving, while India showed the most significant decline in both net credit losses and delinquencies. In Latin America, improving credit trends were driven by Mexico and Brazil. In Europe, net credit losses and 90-day delinquencies improved across nearly all markets; and for the international consumer businesses within our Local Consumer Lending group, net credit losses and 90-day plus delinquencies were also down, driven by asset sales in Europe.</p>
          <p>Slide seven shows our consumer credit trends North America. This includes our card portfolios at the top and our Citi Holdings mortgage businesses at the bottom. We continue to see stable to improving credit trends across these portfolios. In Citi branded cards at the top left, higher fourth quarter delinquencies created an expected increase in first quarter net credit losses, up 7% to 2.1 billion. However, dollar delinquencies declined in the first quarter both in early and later stage buckets. In Retail Partner Cards at the top right, net credit losses declined for the third consecutive quarter by 2% to 1.9 billion, driven by loss mitigation efforts and declining loan balances. Both early and late-stage delinquencies also improved in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>And the bottom of this slide details the historical trends in our mortgage portfolio and Citi Holdings. Both first and second mortgages experienced lower net credit losses and lower 90-day delinquencies in the first quarter. Net credit losses on first mortgages declined 24% to 819 million, driven by HAMP loan conversions and improvement in loan loss severity and roughly $1 billion of asset sales during the quarter. For second mortgages, net credit losses were down 14% to 851 million, driven by roll rate improvements.</p>
          <p>Given the underlying credit trends, we also wanted to share with you the size of our loan loss reserves on slide eight. Loan loss reserves were 48.7 billion at the end of the first quarter or 6.8% of total loans. Consumer loan loss reserves of 41.4 billion or 7.8% of loans increased versus year end, driven by the consolidation of securitized credit card receivables onto our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Corporate loan loss reserves were 7.3 billion or 3.9% of loans. As John mentioned at the beginning of this presentation, we had no significant releases of reserves in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Now that I've covered credit trends and reserves, let me describe our progress in reducing the amount of our higher risk assets. Slide nine shows asset trends in Citi Holdings, which ended the quarter with assets of 503 billion. Citi Holdings now represents approximately 25% of our assets as compared with one-third of our assets just a year ago. We continue to make significant progress in our Citi Holdings strategy, which you heard me speak about at our last call.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter, we reduced assets by 27 billion, driven by 14 billion of maturities, 9 billion of asset sales and business dispositions, not including the impact of the Primerica IPO, which closes in the second quarter, and 4 billion of net credit losses net of positive marks. However, these reductions were offset by $43 billion of assets which came on the balance sheet with the adoption of FAS 166, mostly related to credit card receivables and student loans.</p>
          <p>At the end of the first quarter, on the far right, the 503 billion in assets was composed of three segments. Brokerage and Asset Management was the smallest segment, primarily related to the Morgan Stanley Smith Barney joint venture. Local Consumer Lending had 346 billion of assets, which contains primarily mortgages and private label cards, whose credit trends I just described as being stable to improving. And finally, the Special Asset Pool had 126 billion of assets.</p>
          <p>Now turning the page to slide 10, we see a breakdown of the assets in the Special Asset Pool over the last four quarters. As you can see, overall these assets have been decreasing at a good pace, down 30% from the end of the second quarter of last year. We continue to reduce these assets across all categories through sales and maturities.</p>
          <p>As you scan the information here, I want to highlight a couple features of this asset base. First, many of these positions have been significantly marked down, as you can see on the right side of the page, looking at their face value as compared to the current carrying value. Second, we had made good progress with respect to reducing our exposures in higher risk areas, such as subprime securities and highly leveraged finance commitments. So in addition to seeing signs of continued improvement in credit, we have also been derisking and reducing our exposures.</p>
          <p>Many of you have asked about our ratings, so let me describe to you our current status. Slide 11 shows our current ratings across the three major rating agencies for both Citigroup and Citibank. On the top half of the chart, you see our senior debt and commercial paper ratings for Citigroup, and on the bottom half are the senior and short-term ratings for Citibank. As I just mentioned, these are our current rating levels, and they have not been changed by the three agencies in over a year.</p>
          <p>Some agencies, as you know, are following the financial regulatory reform discussion in Washington that is underway. Of course, we are following it as well and will continue to do so as things develop.</p>
          <p>In addition, as you would expect, we continue to have ongoing discussions with rating agencies. In particular, we keep them abreast of our progress in derisking the balance sheet, and beyond that capital and liquidity are clearly critical.</p>
          <p>So let me turn to capital, which is an area of significant strength for us. Slide 12 reflects our strong capital levels at the end of the first quarter, making us one of the most well capitalized banks in the world with 117 billion in tangible common equity and 97 billion in Tier 1 common. Relative to year end, our capital measures are up after adjusting for FAS 166/167, driven by net income. Compared to the pre-crisis era of 2006 and 2007, our capital measures are up between 18 and $40 billion. Our capital base is one of the strongest in the industry.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 13, as John mentioned, at the end of the first quarter our Tier 1 and Tier 1 common capital ratios were 11.2 and 9.1% respectively, up significantly from year end, adjusted for FAS 166/167. With these strong capital ratios, we believe we are well positioned to weather economic uncertainties, while at the same time have the flexibility and the appetite to take advantage of growth opportunities around the world.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 14, let's take a closer look at liquidity levels as well. As we reshaped our balance sheet, we've strengthened our structural liquidity as measured by one of the traditional measures that you see here on the left side. Together, equity plus long-term debt plus deposits form the heart of a bank's liquidity. This combination of structural funding has risen from 59 to 71% of total assets during the four-year timeframe that you see.</p>
          <p>On the right side of the page, you see our aggregate liquidity resources, defined as cash and liquid securities, which were approximately 321 billion at the end of the first quarter. We have increased these resources over the past year, and we currently believe they are proportionally calibrated to the size of our legal vehicle balance sheets. As I mentioned, we have been able to build these high levels of liquidity by successfully derisking the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Overall, these higher levels of structural liquidity, as I have said before, give us the increased balance sheet flexibility to invest in earning assets and take advantage of growth opportunities across our businesses.</p>
          <p>As we have increased capital and liquidity and successfully reduced the asset side of the balance sheet, we have also been optimizing our liability structure. On slide 15, let me describe from a liability management perspective some of the actions that we have taken.</p>
          <p>First, at the bottom of the slide, you can see our equity base which we have built up over time, as I mentioned earlier. Second, you can see that we increased our long-term debt in the middle of last year as we reinstated our issuance program and prefunded most of our 2010 needs. As I just mentioned, our current cash position affords us the flexibility to invest in earning assets or retire liabilities.</p>
          <p>Last quarter during this call, we announced a plan to retire generally older debt nearing maturity. We successfully tendered 3 billion. This morning, we announced another tender offer to retire approximately 1.1 billion of older subordinated debt nearing maturity. As with the first tender offer last quarter, this deal is expected to have no impact on our strong structural liquidity or our capital levels.</p>
          <p>Finally, in the middle of the page you can see our continued progress in growing deposits, which are one of our most valuable and lowest cost sources of funds.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 16, firm-wide deposits were up approximately 9% year over year to 828 billion at the end of the first quarter. Quarter over quarter, we saw some reduction in deposits. This was partly due to the seasonality. But also as financial markets have stabilized, we now have the ability and the willingness to lower our price points, moderate balanced growth, and widen our spreads and margins while still remaining competitive. We have a high quality, diversified, and stable deposit base across businesses, as you can see.</p>
          <p>Slide 17 summarizes our short-term borrowings, which have been another area of focus. As we have successfully reduced Citi Holdings assets, cash generated from those asset sales has been utilized to selectively pay down certain short-term liabilities. The consolidation of FAS 166/167 brought our short-term liabilities to 131 billion on a 4Q '09 pro forma basis. In the absence of those liabilities brought onto our balance sheet, you can see that we have systematically reduced our reliance across all categories of short-term borrowings over the last five quarters.</p>
          <p>Looking quarter over quarter on a pro forma basis, short-term borrowings declined approximately 34 billion through initiatives and reductions in short-term funding programs. While we reduced the size of our commercial paper programs, as I just noted, we have also extended the weighted average maturities of the existing program, which now are in the 35 to 45-day range.</p>
          <p>Turning to page 18, as I mentioned last quarter, you will notice a significant shift in our funding plans relative to 2008 and 2009 issuance levels. Last year, we reduced our assets, strengthened our liquidity position, and focused on long-term debt issuance. As I have said, we are largely prefunded and will be looking opportunistically at issuing debt this year while preserving our key investor relations.</p>
          <p>As we maintain deposits and reduce the loans in Holdings, we have a less of a need to reissue our maturing debt on a dollar-for-dollar basis. Our current expectation remains that we will issue less than 15 billion of long-term debt this year. This will include several components. First, we had a very successful issuance of 2.3 billion in TruPS [Trust Preferred Securities] in the first quarter; many thanks to those of you who sponsored us in that offering. Second, we'll also currently anticipate issuing approximately 4 billion net in structured notes as part of our overall plan. And third, the remainder will be issued in unsecured senior debt.</p>
          <p>Slide 19 shows our maturities and issuance of card asset-backed securities over the past two years and our plans for 2010. We are covering these today because as part of the FAS 166/167 consolidation, these liabilities are now part of the debt structure of our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>As with our long-term debt issuances, in 2009 we issued a significant amount of Term ABS and participated in government sponsored programs which provided favorable terms and market access. As you can see, we currently plan to securitize approximately 50% of maturing ABS this year.</p>
          <p>Moving to our last slide, let me summarize four major points. First, we see continued signs of credit improvement. Corporate credit is improving. International consumer credit trends continue to improve, and North American consumer credit trends are showing signs of stabilization and improvement.</p>
          <p>Second, our capital base is one of the strongest in the industry, and this is reflected across every one of our significant capital ratios.</p>
          <p>Third, we have significantly improved our structural liquidity by increasing our deposits and reducing loans and assets. We are liquid with a flexible balance sheet that can be redeployed for growth.</p>
          <p>And fourth, we will have a significantly lower proportion of our wholesale funding going forward. We are largely prefunded and currently expect modest reissuance needs in both of our unsecured long-term debt and card securitization programs going forward.</p>
          <p>That concludes our Fixed Income Investor Review. John and I will be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of Regan Burdett with Liberty Mutual.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I just had one question. On page 18 of the deck, the 59 billion of the TLGP [Temporary Liquidity Guarantee Program] issuance is all shorter paper maturing assuming in the next two to three years. What's the plan for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good question. It's Eric Aboaf. That TLGP paper, as you've described, has maturities in a small amount late this year, in 2011, and 2012. And then what you find is that the non-TLGP maturities that we have are stretched out over a longer time period. As you know, that TLGP debt tends to create a bubble in maturities for the broader industry.</p>
          <p>We're actually in a fairly unique position, as I described. We don't have the same need to reissue debt on a dollar-for-dollar basis as we continue to drive down the size of our Citi Holdings balance sheet. And as a result, most of the TLGP debt won't need to be reissued. And instead, we're going to be focused on reissuances of a modest amount of our historical Citigroup debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from the line of John Carolyn with The Hartford.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I just was just wondering on slide 17, where you talk about the short-term debt, could you clarify for me, of the 97 billion, how that would be impacted by a potential downgrade to Tier 2, short-term issuer status. Just specifically talk about within each one and whether there's a reaction that could occur and how you're preparing for that. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Eric Aboaf. As you can expect, we always prepare for any possibilities out there with regard to liquidity. We have an extended process to create continuing Citi funding plans. We do that at the top of the house. We do that in legal vehicles around the world, and have thought about this question for years and for decades, to be frank. Any possibilities out there, some are fairly remote, and I think one of the areas that we explore and think about when we go through the possibilities is to think about what's more likely and what's less likely.</p>
          <p>The first question you have to think about with regard to a downgrade of the short-term rating is whether that would happen at the bank or the holding company. Clearly, the bank is notched higher than the holding company. And so the first focus for that kind of scenario analysis would be on the holding company. If you go through the $97 billion, decompose it in that way, it's really the unsecured commercial paper obligations, the 11 billion of the 97 that are obligations of the holding company. The rest are primarily obligations of the bank, which because of its higher rating I think is a much less likely issue to consider.</p>
          <p>That said, I think secondly what I would say is the preparations are actually fairly extensive. We understand our investor base and those that would be particularly sensitive to ratings changes. We have alternative mechanisms to create liquidity. I described earlier on our cash box and our significant amount of highly liquid securities that we hold, that we could liquefy either through sales or through repo. And there is, beyond that, a long list of contingency funding actions that we would be ready to take in the sort of eventuality that you described.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How would the repo activity change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good question. I think the repo activity you have to think about in a couple ways.</p>
          <p>Firstly, you've got to think about repo activity across the various collateral types: Collateral A, B, C, and D. Right? There's clearly a tiering. Class A is governments and agencies typically. Class D is typically not out on repo.</p>
          <p>And so part of the thinking we do as part of our scenario planning and contingency planning is to consider what's the mix of our repo, what's the mix of our collateral that we have out on repo, and how we might adjust in anticipation of any potential outcome.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we also consider the type of repo counterparties that we have. As you can imagine, some are more sensitive and others are actually quite a bit less sensitive to counterparty rating. And that mix, and our ability to modulate that mix, also gives us capacity to weather different disruptions. And then even within those investors, we actually have quite a bit of knowledge and consideration around whether repo capacity would be lost in some select cases, or whether maturities would just be shortened and still allow for a very healthy funding of the firm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it fair to say that &#x2013; am I correct in saying that the new 2a-7 rules require a look-through, regardless of whether it's A, B, C, or D type securities? So that could impact it, to a certain extent, and that's why you're talking about the mix?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That would be one angle that we would certainly consider, and that is clearly why mix of counterparties is particularly important.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would it be crazy to think maybe 50% of the repo is with that type of a customer, just in general, in the market, or is there any framework you could throw out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think I have market data on that kind of concentration. I think one would be quite hesitant, I would expect &#x2013; I don't know how others operate &#x2013; but quite hesitant to have concentrations of that sort and exposure as part of one's business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So if I were to try and model this, there's nothing you would suggest that I try to think about. Just try and do a sensitivity and say 25% of your repo could fall off, or 50, or 75, and I just have to guess what's the highest probability outcome?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the best thing I'd actually encourage you to do, John, is if you've got some very specific questions about a modeling framework, I'd encourage you to follow up with Ilene Fiszel Bieler, our head of Fixed Income Relations, and she could certainly talk with you about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Knutson with Legal &amp; General.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking the call. Some of the questions were answered a minute ago.</p>
          <p>On the sovereign systemic support uplift, which was the essence of the prior question, what's your current view on implementation this year and rating action this year? Maybe 0% to 100% probability, if you have that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, it's Eric. It's a very tough question to answer. I think it is certainly driven by the legislation being developed in Congress. And that clearly is going through a lot of changes, evolutions, and the timing is uncertain.</p>
          <p>I think, at the same time, you've seen that we, as an institution, are getting stronger, and that also needs to be factored into the calculus.</p>
          <p>So I think those are the broad observations I'd make. To be honest, it's probably one of the questions that you want to address directly to the rating agencies to get their direct perspectives.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On another topic, the Transaction Account Guarantee Program was extended. Did you extend from the original maturity, and do you plan to extend this for the second period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, no, we did not extend beyond the December 31 date. We feel very comfortable with our ability to raise deposits. As you can see, we've had a very robust and diversified deposit base, so we didn't see any need to extend beyond the original time of the original program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Louise Pitt with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, guys. Thanks for holding the call this morning. I have a couple of questions, in addition to the ones that have already been asked.</p>
          <p>I'm just wondering whether you could give us your opinion on the proposed language of resolution authority that is in the Dodd bill that is going to the Senate on Monday. In that, I guess there's some confusion as to how creditors or classes of creditors or even individual investors could be treated in the event that this becomes as an issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Louise, it's Eric. To be honest, I really don't think it's appropriate for us to comment on the direction of Congressional legislation. I think that's really Congress's role. They're taking it on, as they should, and that's just going to play out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. An additional one was just on the trajectory of the Citi Holdings runoff. Could you just comment a little bit on your expectations for how quickly that might run off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Louise. It's John Gerspach. As we covered on the Investor call on Monday, obviously, that pace is going to have some ebbs and flows.</p>
          <p>You saw, in the fourth quarter, we reduced the assets by about 71 billion, I think. And now in the first quarter, we're still at a fairly steady pace, but not quite as strong as 27 billion reduction in the first quarter. So we will continue to maintain a steady pace. I think from here on out, somehow that pace is going to be impacted by whether or not we're able to do any large deals.</p>
          <p>And if you look at the components of the assets that are remaining in Citi Holdings, specifically in the Local Consumer Lending category or segment of that, you'll see that what we've got now is some concentrations in student loans, Citi Financial assets, our retail partner cards groups.</p>
          <p>So now it's a little bit about what's the pace of our ability to get some larger deals done, and that's going to be a little bit up to the market, as well as us. So I can't give you any specifics on exactly what the timing is going to be, but we do continue to work, and you will continue to see it decline as we move forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks. Just to clarify from a question earlier, though, you think that the pace of runoff is going to correspond pretty closely with the debt that's running off, that you don't think you'll have to replace, though?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Louise, it's Eric. I think the way to think about that is that the pace of the holdings reductions give us the capacity or put us in a position where we don't need to reissue our maturing debt on a dollar-for-dollar basis, right?</p>
          <p>We obviously do conservative planning from a treasury standpoint, so there's a range of different speeds of reductions. But even within the band of what we've seen and we think we can expect, we're fairly confident that the reissuance needs are modest, relative to the maturities that are coming through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Bill Droege with John Hancock.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, thanks for taking my question. I was hoping you could speak to parent company liquidity. And specifically, when I look at your regulatory Y-9LP form, it looks like there is a modest shortfall between cash and securities and borrowings due in one year. I'm wondering how you think about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Eric. I'm trying to reference the regulatory report that you're mentioning. Which one is it specifically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's the parent company only for Citigroup, Inc. So when I look at the asset, the balance sheet on the asset side, cash and securities come up a little short against liabilities due within one year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, I see. I think what you're referencing is really the short-term ratio and how we think about that.</p>
          <p>I think what you need to keep in mind is that we, from a legal vehicle perspective, are really organized between the banks on one hand and the combinations of parent company and broker/dealer companies on the other. So think about Citigroup in two large buckets.</p>
          <p>When you think about the bank, I think we've talked about the liquidity structure there. I think when you talk about the parent company and dealer combined, our short-term ratio is well above one year, and I think we've been pretty clear about that in the recent 10-K.</p>
          <p>If there are more specific questions on a particular sub-vehicle, I think, again, I'd encourage you to reach out to Ilene Fiszel Bieler in our Investor Relations area, and we can certainly help you with some of the individual sub-pieces.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from the line of Steve Kolderup with Allstate Insurance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for the call. Most of my questions have largely been answered, but I'm grappling with trying to dimensionalize the impact, and where the movements would occur within the liability structure on this potential short-term ratings issue.</p>
          <p>And then also, if you have any thoughts on what kind of an impact this derivatives legislation would have on your institution, as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Eric, Steve. I think on rating actions, clearly those are driven by both adjustments on any notching that might happen, and we think those are &#x2013; that's one consideration. And then at the same time, the underlying strength of Citi continues to improve. And so really, it's the calculus of those two that are important.</p>
          <p>I think the areas that we plan for and that we are very conscious of are the ones that we talked about before. It's the short-term borrowings, which are quite modest at the group level, and then the financing operation and the broker/dealer.</p>
          <p>And as you remember, there's not only the repo book, which is an important financing vehicle, but there's also a book of reverses that we have some flexibility to reduce. We have trading asset inventory, which has capacity to be reduced. So there's a fair amount of actions that you can imagine we have considered and we have fine tuned and understand exactly how to address under different eventualities.</p>
          <p>At the core, we retain and have put in place quite a bit of long-term debt funding, literally over the last year, since May of last year, in anticipation of any kind of eventualities, whether they are rating ones or whether they are market disruptions. And that's one of the reasons why we're running so liquid.</p>
          <p>I think on the derivatives side, hard to say exactly how the legislation will play out, and so I think it's actually a little premature to comment, to be honest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just to clarify, you mentioned issuing &#x2013; likely needing to issue 15 billion this year, 4 billion structured notes and senior debt. And that's net of the 2 billion of TruPS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct, the 15 would include the TruPS. It includes the structured notes and the balances. Really, the unsecured senior debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Kehoe with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, just two questions, the first question on issuing senior debt. Which currencies are you looking at issuing at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Eric, Mark. The currencies, I think, continue to be, in our mind, similar to those of the past.</p>
          <p>We've built a very broad franchise in dollars and euros. We did some sterling. We've done some of the yen and Asian currencies. And I think our general plans are continuing to return to some of our historic investor bases and issue in those areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And the second question was, in terms of &#x2013; I think one rationale I think I'd like you to get out of the funding hold that may occur if there's a short-term ratings impact would be for the rating agencies to disconnect the short-term from the long-term ratings. Have you pressured them to look at it in that way, to decouple in the sense that &#x2013; particularly for S&amp;P?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, good question. We've certainly asked them that question. Others have certainly asked them that question. But I think clearly that's their work and their analysis, so hard for me to really add more than that. I think it's probably the kind of question you want to talk directly with them about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Kabir Caprihan with J.P. Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Not to beat up this topic a lot, but two more questions on the potential impact of a downgrade. Can you just go over what the <mark type="inaudible" /> goals could be if the long-term rating is downgraded one notch, two notches, and possibly three notches as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's Eric. If you go through our 10-K, I think we go through exactly that question. We go through a one-notch downgrade of the long-term rating. We also describe one notch of the short-term rating at the holding company level. I think each of those are worth about 4 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. I saw that, but I don't think you gave us any disclosure on what happens with a two-notch downgrade. What happens with a two-notch downgrade for the bank and the holding company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, maybe what I would encourage you to do is to speak to Ilene in our Fixed Income Investor Relations, and we can see if that's available.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just to make sure I get something very clear, did I hear you right saying most of your repo books are actually at the bank and not at the holding company or the broker/dealer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I did not say that. Most of the repo book, as you can imagine, is in the dealer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is in the dealer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just to build on John's question before, if you do get even a one-notch downgrade at the holding company, then that wouldn't impact the short-term rating at the broker/dealer itself, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the question is whether the &#x2013; and I think someone asked it as well &#x2013; is whether the long-term and the short-term rating would be decoupled or not, right, that's a question. The question is whether the concern on downgrade is legislation and obviously our continued progress around capital and liquidity, which is pretty substantial. So it's really those factors that come together.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I get that point. And I know there's only so much you can do and the rest is dependent on how S&amp;P will view the ratings criteria. But just assume we get a one-notch short-term downgrade at the holding company, and that would impact the short-term rating at the broker/dealer. I just want to make sure that I get that clear, and that's where most of your repos are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there's a range of scenarios, but the way it technically aligns, you're correct. Any changes at the holding company are also changes at the dealer because they're part of the same change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then what else do you have at the bank level which we should, from a short-term ratings standpoint, that we should be really concerned about? Because in my mind mostly the repos would be the biggest thing to be concerned about, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the bank is in a very different situation, right? If you go back to the page that we showed you around our ratings, right, I think it was page 11, and you go through the second row of that or the second panel of that table, the bank is really A+. So the bank really has some room around its rating on the long-term, even without decoupling, in a way that the short-term is not likely to be or as likely to be impacted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough, I think that's a two-notch downgrade I think, and S&amp;P said that they could do a three-notch, so it would take a huge downgrade at the bank to make that an issue. But I'm just trying to see again what are the moving parts of the bank from a short-term standpoint that we should be concerned about because most of it &#x2013; you said most of these repos are at the holding company and most of the CP is at the holding company. What's at the bank from a short-term standpoint that could be impacted?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, to be honest, it's a pretty unlikely scenario. So maybe it's worth talking about it with our Investor Relations team because I just don't see how it's particularly relevant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks a lot. Just to change topics for a second, I know you addressed this a little bit on the conference call. But given the fact that you were one of the biggest originators of CDOs back in 2006 &#x2013; 2007, could you talk a little bit about whether there has been -was there notice or have you been in touch with the SEC at all? Has the SEC been in touch with you at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As a point, we obviously report material developments in litigation and government investigations in our public filings. And as I said in the Investor call on Monday, it has been widely reported that the SEC, among other regulators, is conducting an industry-wide investigation into a wide range of subprime related issues. And as we have disclosed in our 10-K, we are fully cooperating with these inquiries, and frankly it wouldn't be appropriate for us to comment any further.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that was our final question. I'll now turn today's call back over to Ms. Fiszel Bieler for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, everyone, for joining the call today. If you have any follow-up questions, please don't hesitate to reach out to us in Fixed Income Investor Relations, and we'll talk to you soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>