<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1490581" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>98</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Investor Relations">Michael DeWalt</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Jerry D. Revich</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Caterpillar Financial Services Corp.">Edward J. Rapp</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">David M. Raso</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Andy Alec Kaplowitz</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Henry Kirn</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Vertical Research Partners LLC">Rob C. Wertheimer</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Seth R. Weber</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Ann Duignan</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Douglas R. Oberhelman</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Jamie L. Cook</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Robert W. Baird &amp; Co. Equity Capital Markets">Robert F. McCarthy</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the Caterpillar second quarter 2012 earnings results conference call.  At this time, all lines have been placed on a listen-only mode and we will open the floor for your questions and comments following the presentation.  It is now my pleasure to turn the floor over to your host, Mr. Mike DeWalt.  Sir, the floor is yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and good morning, everyone and welcome to our second quarter earnings call.  I'm Mike DeWalt, the Director of Investor Relations.  And I'm pleased to have our Chairman and CEO, Doug Oberhelman, and group president and CFO Ed Rapp with me on the call today.  Now this call is copyrighted by Caterpillar, Inc. and any use or recording or transmission of any portion of this call without the expressed written consent of Caterpillar is strictly prohibited.  If you would like a copy of today's call transcript, we'll be posting it in the investor section of our Caterpillar.com website, and it will be in the section labeled results webcast.  This morning we will be discussing forward-looking information that involves risks and uncertainties and assumptions that could cause our actual results to differ materially from the forward-looking information.  A discussion of some of those factors that individually or in the aggregate could make actual results differ materially from our projections, that can be found in our cautionary statements under item 1A, risk factors, of our form 10-K filed with the SEC back on February 21 of this year and also in the forward-looking statements language in today's release.  In addition, a reconciliation of non-GAAP measures can also be found in this morning's financial release and that again will be posted on our website at Caterpillar.com.</p>
          <p>Okay.  To start off this morning, I'll do a few bullet points that summarize this morning's release. It was an all-time record sales quarter, in fact, the best in the 87-year history of Caterpillar, and up 22% from the second quarter last year.  A little over 12% of that was organic growth and a little under 10% from our acquisitions.  Sales and revenues rose about 9% sequentially from the first to the second quarters.  It was a great quarter for profit and also an all-time record at $2.54 a share and operating profit was 15% &#x2013; over 15% of sales and revenues.</p>
          <p>We had very good incremental operating profit pull-through at 44% excluding the impact of our acquisitions.  We did, however, make a downward revision of $2 billion to the top end of our sales and revenues outlook range.  About $1 billion was a result of negative currency translation and about $1 billion because of weaker world economic growth than we previously expected.  We did not change the bottom end of the range so that means that sales and revenues at the midpoint are down about $1 billion.  And we increased our full-year, 2012 profit outlook from $9.50 to $9.60 at the middle of the sales and revenues range.</p>
          <p>Okay.  Those were the high-level points.  I'll add a little more color and then Doug and Ed and I will take your questions and I'll start with sales.  Again, sales and revenues up 22%, excluding Bucyrus and MWM acquisitions which we didn't own last year.  Organic growth a little more than 12%.  The largest increase was in the Resource Industry segment which is primarily mining.  Sales were up 68% from a year ago, about 37% from the acquisition of Bucyrus and about 31% organic growth.  Sales were up in all geographic regions, both with and without Bucyrus.</p>
          <p>Our Power Systems segment was up 12% and that was 8% organic growth and about 4% from our acquisition of MWM.  The strongest growth was in North America and the strongest industries were petroleum and rail.  Our Construction Industries segment was up 8% and that increase was essentially all volume with negative currency impacts about offsetting positive price realization.  Construction sales were up in North America, about flat in Europe, Africa and Middle East, and that's where most of the negative currency impacts were.  Latin America was down 3% and Asia Pacific was off 11%.  And of that 11% decline in Asia Pacific, more than all of that was China.</p>
          <p>Speaking of China, over the past quarter, it's been very topical.  What's happening there, what are we doing about it, and when do we think it will get better?  And with most of the sales in China related to construction, this is a good place to address it.  So in terms of what's happening there, the construction equipment industry remains very weak and it really hasn't shown much in the way of signs of improvement yet.  In addition to the weak demand, there's still quite a bit of inventory available on the ground in China.</p>
          <p>Now, while the industry is still pretty weak, it did turn down at about this time last year.  So we're at about the point where the comparables are starting to get easier.  So on a year-over-year basis, the numbers will likely start looking better than the first half of 2012, even though the industry isn't seeing much improvement yet.  So the question is: what are we doing about it?  And the answer is we're actually doing quite a bit.  First, we're working with dealers to actually sell more product.  Over the past couple of months, we put new programs in place to get that done.  And we expect to start seeing results of those programs in the third quarter and expect to get more of the available market.</p>
          <p>Second, we and our dealers are actively addressing inventory.  During the second quarter, Cat dealers in China reduced machine inventories and that's a good thing.  However, with weak end user demand and dealers cutting inventory, it's resulted in a very low level of shipments from us to dealers, and that makes it tougher to reduce inventory.  We've already lowered production in China and expect to reduce it even more in the third quarter.  That along with a higher level of exports from China to other parts of the world should help lower inventory there.  However, because sales volume levels in China haven't begun to improve much, we expect it will take a couple more quarters to get inventory levels in China where we would like them to be.  While we are actively working to get inventory down in China, we are trying to keep a balanced view.</p>
          <p>One of the few certainties in this business is that markets go down, and then markets go back up.  In China, we're encouraged by the recent actions the government has taken to improve economic growth.  They've cut interest rates.  They have lowered bank reserve requirements and we expect they'll increase infrastructure spending later this year.  So we do need to be a little bit careful.  The construction industry in China has a history of turning quickly, and when it does, we do need to be prepared.  We are actively working the plan to lower inventory there, but we don't want to go to the other extreme and take it down to a point below where we would have difficulty reacting when improvement does inevitably come.</p>
          <p>So bottom line, we think there's a good chance that signs of better economic growth in China will start later in 2012 and while that's our view, our 2012 sales and revenues outlook does not rely on any material improvement in China sales this year.</p>
          <p>Okay, that's enough on China, construction and sales.  Let's shift to profit.  And it's a great story to talk about.  It was a great quarter and in fact, again, at $2.54 a share, our best quarter ever, with operating margin just over 15% of sales and revenues.  That was also one of our best performances ever.  Cost control was very good.  Material costs were about flat.  Freight costs were not an issue.  Variable labor productivity more than offset labor cost inflation and period cost control was very good, with period cost increasing at well less than half the rate of the sales increase.  All in all, a very well executed quarter.  However, on the negative side, there was a tax rate.  We increased our estimated annual tax rate from 30% for the full year to 30.5%, mostly related to the geographic mix of where our profits are earned from a tax perspective.  That means that after tax profit in the second quarter was about $24 million lower than it would have been had we not made a change to the estimated tax rate.</p>
          <p>Okay. That's a quick review of the second quarter results.  Let's move on for a moment to the outlook.  Now as a starting point, remember, our previous outlook was a sales and revenues range of $68 billion to $72 billion and profit of about $9.50 at the mid-point of that range.  This morning, we did tighten up the sales and revenues range by lowering the top end from $72 billion to $70 billion.  Now we first introduced that $68 billion to $72 billion range at the end of January with our year-end 2011 financial release, and we held it steady last quarter in April when we released our first quarter.  This morning's $2 billion decline at the top end of the range was a result of two things:  negative currency translation and weaker global economic expectations than we had previously thought.  The currency impact is a result of the stronger U.S. dollar.  It's translation.  Our sales that are denominated in non-U.S. currencies are translating into fewer U.S. dollars, and certainly the most significant negative impact is in the Euro.</p>
          <p>Now, we did not change the bottom end of the range and as a result, the mid-point is down $1 billion.  And at the mid-point of that new range, that $68 billion to $70 billion sales and revenues range, we expect profit to be about $9.60 a share.  That's up a dime from $9.50 a share at the midpoint of the $68 billion to $72 billion sales range that we previously had.  A few points about the outlook.  Profit is higher despite the increase in the estimated annual tax rate.  Operational execution has been very strong and we expect that that will result in better profit despite the tax increase.  Currency, while impacting sales has had little impact on the profit movement from $9.50 to $9.60.</p>
          <p>Our global manufacturing footprint in broad cost base provides an offset to the impacts from sales.  And on that point, I frequently read media commentary about Caterpillar when exchange rates moved and it's frequently off base.  And because of that, I think it's worth making this point one more time.  We work hard over the past 30 years to get a better balance on currency exposure.  And because of that, we are in a much better currency position than we were historically.  Rates can move and do move sales, but when they do, the cost impact is usually in the opposite direction and mitigates the overall profit impact.</p>
          <p>So in summary, we had a great second quarter.  We're a little more cautious at the top end of our sales and revenues outlook and we raised the profit guidance to about $9.60 at the middle of the sales and revenues range.  Another point before we move on to the Q&amp;A and that's the level of uncertainty in the world economy.  It's hard to pick up a newspaper today and not read about troubles in Europe with Greece, Spain and Italy.  There's angst with growth rates in GDP in China, there's concern about political polarization in the U.S. and what will happen at the end of the year with the fiscal and tax cliff. But those are the facts of life that we're all dealing with today, and there's no doubt that they've been a negative for business and consumer confidence.  We see it and we understand that some of these issues like Europe's debt problems, could take a while to fix.  That said, we expect that over the next couple of quarters that some of those clouds will clear a bit and we can start forming a little bit better picture of 2013, and while none of us know at this point what those outcomes will be, we do know that U.S. elections will be over in the fall and we think chances are good there will be a resolution to the fiscal cliff.</p>
          <p>The leadership change in China will also happen later this year and after another quarter or two, we'll get a better sense of the effectiveness of the easing measures the Chinese have already taken and any additional measures they may take to improve growth.  We know that in Brazil, they started easing late in 2011 and we are seeing some improvement in our business there today, and we expect that improvement to continue to unfold as we go through the rest of this year.  We also think that Brazil's preparations for the World Cup and the next Olympics will be positive for them moving forward.</p>
          <p>Bottom line, we believe that some of the uncertainty that's facing the world economy today will at least be a little less cloudy by the time we get to the end of 2012 and as a result of numerous monetary easing actions that have been taken around the world, we're cautiously optimistic that the world economy in 2013 will be better than in 2012.  One last comment and then we'll start the Q&amp;A, and that's a seasonality reminder.  We have numerous vacation shutdowns around the world built into our third quarter.  That's normal.  That happens every year, and as a result the third quarter is usually a weaker seasonally sales quarter.  The fourth quarter is usually a seasonally high quarter for sales.  So for those of you that are trying to model our quarterly results, please take that into consideration.  The third quarter is usually the weaker quarter of the second half.  So that's a review of our results and with that, we are ready to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question today is coming from Jerry Revich.  Please announce your affiliation and then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  It's Goldman Sachs.  Mike, can you touch on how you're thinking about pricing heading into the back half of the year compared to the price realization we saw this quarter and also comment on where you expect to see company and dealer inventories at year end?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  I'll start with pricing.  We've actually done better on pricing through the first half of the year than we expected.  It's really held up pretty well.  You know, earlier in the year, we'd expected that we would get maybe 1% to maybe 1.5% price for the full year. We're at probably between 2.5% and 3% right now through the first half.  We think it will probably go down a little bit in the second half.  That's what's baked into our guidance. We'll probably end up the year somewhere around 2%.  You remember one of the points I mentioned was we're working with dealers, for example, to sell more product in China so there will be some merchandising programs, for example, related to that.  So I think a lot better year than we thought it was going to be even including the economic impacts that you see today. But probably a little less in the second half than the first half.</p>
          <p>In terms of dealer inventory, we did have a little bit of an increase in the second quarter.  More than all of that was mining.  Now when you look at dealer inventory for mining, you have to be a little careful.  It's not a case where dealers are loading up 400-ton trucks on their lot and hoping for a customer. It's a case where we pass title to them and then they have to get it &#x2013; the product to their customer.  They have to get it assembled and commissioned. So usually when our shipments go up like they did in the second quarter versus the first, the pipe line for mining inventory increases a bit, and that's just a function of us shipping more through dealers to customers.</p>
          <p>In terms of our inventory, we did have a bit of an increase, about $800 million in the second quarter, and there were four reasons for that.  One, and I'll start from the smallest to the largest, in transit inventory, that's basically where we sold a product &#x2013; well, I shouldn't say sold.  We have a product that's been shipped, but it's an export.  It's on the high seas essentially and it's destined for a customer but we haven't passed title yet.  When our shipments and exports go up, in transit inventory usually goes up. We had a 9% increase in sales between the first and second quarters and then transit went up a bit.  That's to be expected based on the sales increase.</p>
          <p>About 20% of the increase in the second quarter was components, work in process, aftermarket parts and that's very related to sales. And again, we had a 9% increase in sales from first to second quarter.  20% of the inventory inquiries was from the acquisition of Siwei and Bucyrus.  Siwei is an acquisition and Bucyrus inventory went up in the quarter and again, that's not very surprising.  We have businesses like Solar, like Bucyrus where they have seasonally big fourth quarters.  They build a bit of inventory all year long, they have a big fourth quarter, it usually goes down.  And again, Siwei contributed about $100 million of the increase, not just an acquisition.  About half of the increase was finished goods and more than half of that was in our excavator division in China, and I tried to cover this a little bit in the release this morning.  It's a case where we're cutting production there.  There are more declines that are going to come in the third quarter.  But dealers are cutting inventory there as well and if you start with a slow market and dealers reducing inventory there are a not a lot of shipments going on from our factories to dealers then.  So it's pretty hard to take inventory down.</p>
          <p>Do even with the reduction in production that we had in the third quarter, it wasn't quite enough.  You had to offset the impacts of a really slow market.  So, we're going to take it down a little bit more in the third quarter.  We're exporting a higher percentage of the business in China, outside of China.  So that should help there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jerry, this is Ed.  The thing I would add on Cat inventory looking for the balance of the year, between now and year end, I would be disappointed if we didn't take at least $1 billion out of inventory.  But we're also trying to be very thoughtful in terms of how we manage the full supply chain. If you think about what the supply chain has done and with $32 billion in '09, mid-point of the outlook $69 billion, and if you look at the basic outlook that says there's some drivers out there that says 2013 could be a positive versus 2012.  We want to be very thoughtful about how we take that inventory down. But between now and the end of the year, getting $1 billion out is something we ought to be able to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Appreciate the color. And I'm wondering if you can talk about how much visibility you have in your gas compression business and whether that business can continue to outpace the slowdown we're seeing in U.S. pressure pumping and in electric power.  Can you just touch on which regions are driving the weakness that we saw year to date and what you expect heading into the back half.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah I mean, we don't break our petroleum business out in quite that much detail, but what I would tell you is the largest sort of application segment for our oil and gas business is gas compression.  So contrary to popular belief, it's not drilling and fracing.  It's gas compression.  So the more gas you have, the more wells you drill, the higher consumption of gas goes, the more need that you have for gas compression and so that business is actually doing quite well and looking up.  We do a lot of gas compression with Solar and with Solar, we have very good, long-term visibility.  So I would say oil and gas, your point about fracing is right.  Fracing is slowing down, but gas compression is doing very well.  So, our general view of the oil and gas industry is actually pretty good right now.  Jerry, we're going to have to move on to the next person in line.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Ladies and gentlemen, the next question today is coming from David Raso. Please announce your affiliation and then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, ISI.  I'm just trying to look at the inventory guidance.  Ed, you just mentioned $1 billion dollars coming out ideally by the end of the year.  That would still imply the next couple quarters that inventory will be growing faster than sales year over year.  So just coming off the last five quarters of inventory still growing faster than sales, I'm just trying to, A, just understand why we continue to grow inventories faster than sales; or B, is the answer can everybody kind of have their own macro view.  Are you that confident 2013 is an up year to continue to grow inventory at this rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>David, two things, first of all, on inventory growing fast, if you really look at our guidance in terms of the mid-point of the outlook we have sales in second half slightly up versus first half and so you got a slight increase in sales and a lower inventory level. So you don't have inventory growing at a faster pace than sales. And, then your second point is part of it as well.  As Mike kind of walked around the world and you look at what 2013 could look like versus 2012, I can't imagine with the degree of uncertainty we have in the U.S. today that we don't have greater clarity in 2013.  I can't imagine with the steps that China has taken in terms of monetary policy <mark type="indiscernible" /> (23:39) reserve requirement cuts, you don't see a better 2013 than 2012.  I can't imagine with all the moves that Brazil has taken as well as the coming of the World Cup, the Olympics <mark type="indiscernible" /> (23:51) better than 2012.  So part of our thinking is making sure we're very thoughtful across the supply chain.</p>
          <p>The other one to keep in mind and I think second quarter really demonstrated it, there are also some benefits to the inventory position we have. Our point of use availability, our quality, our delivery performance, our pull-through, were all very, very strong and, and so I do think there's some benefits as to how we worked with our supply base to ramp up, and I think you're seeing it in some of those operating metrics.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I appreciate that math sequentially, but I was speaking about year over year, and the math is you're still planning on inventory growing faster than sales year over year and obviously, it sets up a little more risk on how much retail you need in 2013 to continue to grow your production.  So I guess at the end of the day, obviously, you'll give 2013 top-line guidance, I assume, Mike, you guys will give it in October.  But the way you're handling the CapEx for the rest of the year, essentially no cut.  The way you're guiding the inventory, I guess base case we have to be thinking you're thinking 2013 is an up year.  Otherwise, you would be taking a bigger cut to your inventory and maybe even the CapEx.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And David, that's why we tried to give you some color as to why we saw 2013 being better.  The other one to keep in mind on the CapEx is that in spite of the numbers that we reported today which are an all-time record on both sales and profit, keep in mind that our traditionally strong markets, U.S., Europe and go back in history, even Japan, are in the neighborhood of 40% off prior peaks and at some point in time, those markets are going to turn, and when they turn, we want to be ready, and there's places where we're taking and slowing down some of that CapEx, China being one example, but we're going through it, business by business, industry by industry.  Really looking at what the long-term prospects are going to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And last one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, I'm just going to add one more comment in there on the year over year, that is you almost have to look at it by the type of inventory that we're talking about. We've increased parts inventory, for example, faster than sales.  Part of the reason for that is we're putting additional Bucyrus inventory into the system.  We're doing that to increase delivery performance there.  That's a key part of driving higher part sales and profit out of Bucyrus.  If you look at our actual production inventory, it's performed a lot closer to sales.  If you look at the PDC, that's where we're holding finished inventory on purpose, we call it lane one inventory.  That's up $1 billion dollars or actually a little bit more than $1 billion dollars year over year.  That's very purposeful.  I mean, the problem was a year ago, we didn't have enough capacity in place to get it where we need it.  Now we've added more than $1 billion dollars to PDC inventory on purpose that was all part of the plan, and we've been able to do that really over the last 6 months to 9 months as production has come on stream.  So it's not just a simple: how much did sales go up, how much is inventory going up. And then we also had acquisitions. Roughly half of the FIFO inventory increase is Bucyrus, MWM and Siwei. Just acquisitions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.  I appreciate the color, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question today is coming from Andrew Kaplowitz.  Please announce your affiliation and then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Barclays.  Good morning, guys.  Nice quarter.  If I could ask you about backlog, Mike, I know you've talked about it in the past.  You kind of rue the day when it would go down.  I think we all expected it to go down sequentially here.  But how do you look at the backlog decline in term of mining and with your comments in the release about mining, customers extending investment over the next few years, how is it affecting your business now, and, if mining CapEx is down significantly, can you grow your business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of things.  One, you say how is it affecting our business now?  Well, organic sales were up 31% in mining in the quarter.  If you look at our year-over-year backlog, how are we doing on backlog versus a year ago.  It's up 11% not down.  If you look at the change from the end of the first quarter, I mean, there are a couple of things that are definitely going on there.  One, and this particularly affects construction, we took quite a few products off managed distribution. We've been in a situation for the last couple of years where we just couldn't supply enough and we had dealers on managed distribution for quite a few products.  We've been adding production capability over the last couple of years.  That situation, delivery times have improved a lot, and when that happens, it's almost like clockwork, dealers take, they don't have to be quite so cautious because we can deliver quicker.  That was definitely a factor for construction.  On mining, customers did cut &#x2013; we shipped more than we took in new orders and the backlog did go down.  You almost have to look at it in perspective.  We were getting very large orders really over the past couple of years and we're increasing every quarter.  And it's a function of we've been putting in more capacity to deal with that.  I mean, we wanted for a long time to get the order book for mining to a more reasonable level.  Delivery times for customers to a better level, and that's why we've been putting capacity in place to do that.  That said, there's a lot of uncertainty in the marketplace today.  Customers are, just like my comments in the in the opening, we're all trying to get a better picture in terms of what's going on economically.  Central bankers have done quite a bit, but that takes a while to actually materialize in the economy, and I think people are taking a little bit of a wait-and-see to see how 2013 is going to shape up, and I think orders reflect that.  That said, mining order book is quite long.  We have very good visibility into 2013.  For a lot of big trucks, we're still taking orders into 2014.  So it's not as though all of a sudden the backlog is dried up and we don't have any visibility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful, Mike.  If I could shift gears for a second, I mean, the first half of the year you've done almost 15% margins and the second half of the year, if you look at the implied guidance, you would do much lower margins.  You talked about lower production in China, incentive comp is going up. We see all the things that are in the release but the question I have is is this some conservatism in the guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what I would tell you is this.  Many of the comments that we've actually made here today and were in the release, price realization is probably not going to be quite as strong in the back half of the year.  Seasonally, the fourth quarter is usually a higher cost quarter so those things will certainly impact the second half of the year. But you're right.  First half is execution has been very, very good.  So, I think our outlook is &#x2013; I mean, we raised the outlook today from $9.50 to $9.60 on mid-point of the sales range that went down $1 billion dollars and we're looking at a higher tax rate.  So I think actually the profit story for the rest of the year is pretty positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Appreciate it, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question today is coming from Henry Kirn.  Please announce your affiliation and then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning, guys.  It's UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey Henry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the release you called out the dealer rental inventories as old. How much opportunity is there to refresh the fleet and if we went through a pause do you think the dealers would take the opportunity to start to refresh?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Henry this is Ed.  I think we're already seeing some of that in terms of dealers refreshing those rental fleets. But if you look at it in terms of the total fleet size, it's still below kind of historic levels, historical peaks and on average the age is older. And I think it's not only a view of the rental fleet, but I think it's a pretty good proxy for customer fleets are especially in the developed parts of the world.  In the period of uncertainty, they just delay the decision to make that upgrade to the fleet, that new purchase. And so like I said, as we talk about moving forward, I think at the point in time they get greater clarity, one of them that helps is the fact that we did finally get a passage of a highway bill.  We are starting to see some &#x2013; the bottoming out and improvement in housing.  I think as those issues get a bit clearer, the opportunities for not only rental fleet replenishment but also the upgrade of customer fleets is one of the opportunities that lies ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful.  And could you share your latest thoughts on Cat Financial and your appetite to take risk there, gain share or use it as competitive weapon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know, Henry, Cat Finance has been a competitive weapon since we launched it back in the 1980s.  And the thing we do with Cat Finance is stay very close to home.  It's there to support and pursue the growth of the Caterpillar business.  If you think about the 2008, 2009 financial crisis and how well it performed, I think it shows the benefits of staying very close to home in terms of the way you manage your captive finance company.  I think with the uncertainty you have today in the financial markets, having a captive finance company has become, I think, even a bigger strategic advantage.  I think the other place where we're going to see it play out as a strategic advantage is drive the full integration of Bucyrus is, we'll really be the only full line provider in that mining industry and plus with a captive finance company I think there's a real strategic advantage there.  But we're not going to significantly alter our risk appetite.  We think we managed that part of the company well.  I think you'll see us consistently manage it moving forward. But as you saw with the results, they had a good quarter, they're a great part of the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Henry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question today is coming from Robert Wertheimer.  Please announce your affiliation then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Vertical Research Partners.  Good morning.  I wondered, you mentioned rail was strong in the press release and I wonder if you could break that down into a pre-buy in North America versus I know rail has been booming in mining globally. Is that a business that has gotten up into a solid double-digit profit margin, or is it still lagging?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  A lot of the rail increase that we've seen so far this year has actually been in North America and to your point, a few years from now, there be a move to new emission standards in rail, and I think there is certainly some buying that's going on ahead of that.  We're actually doing a bit better than the industry.  When we acquired EMD, it had lost a lot of its business over the years to GE and thankfully, we're taking some of that back now.  So actually, we're doing pretty well.  In terms of profitability, in general that business is actually doing quite a bit better than when we bought it.  We've got the new factory going in Indiana right now in Muncie.  They have come up on production remarkably well.  We had a good quarter despite the fact that we essentially shifted assembly in the first to the second quarter from Ontario to Indiana.  So they've done a great job.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay great.  And then if I could ask another power systems follow-up, just on electric, one of your competitors had cited some weakness and I know you have some tough comp issues that maybe are fading.  Is it possible for electric power gen to be up for you guys this year, do you have an order book that would support that? Or is it looking a little softer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, a couple of things.  One, if you look at our overall power systems business versus that competitor that we're talking about, thank goodness for rail and thank goodness for oil and gas.  Those are &#x2013; it's good to have a quite varied business.  So we have some end markets that are weaker.  We have some that are stronger and we happen to have a very good balance.  So in total, you saw our sales to end users accelerate.  The three-month moving average from overall from plus 2% to plus 7% in June.  That was a good thing. But I do &#x2013; there are comments about power systems in general, particularly the smaller diesel end of it.  We're definitely seeing that in the marketplace. And so certainly at the smaller end of electric power, it will likely be a negative year.  At the big end and the turbine end, we had some really tough comparables in the first quarter that were with us throughout March and so year over year that part of the business is &#x2013; has been a little, comparably a little pressed because we had such big turbine sales in the quarter a year ago.  But on balance, I would say the bigger stuff is a little better than the small stuff and the competitor that you referred to is probably relatively speaking stronger in the small stuff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep. True. Thanks, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question today is coming from Seth Weber.  Please announce your affiliation then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey good morning.  It's RBC</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Seth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  Back to the mining business, you gave some good color on the truck, trends on the truck side, can you give us &#x2013; can you comment why you're seeing more on the underground side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Underground hard rock or underground coal? Underground hard rock has amongst the longest backlog of all of our products.  You mean underground coal, Bucyrus underground coal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the old DBT business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  That's probably weaker than the rest.  We talked a lot about that, I think in the first quarter where we were seeing some decline there.  We don't &#x2013; we haven't broken out Bucyrus in a lot of detail separately in the outlook, but I think the overall sales for Bucyrus this year are going to be lower than we had originally thought and really for two reasons.  One is underground coal is a bit weaker.  Thankfully, we don't have as much of our business tied up in U.S. underground coal as maybe our largest competitor does, but it's still going to be a bit of a negative and on the flip side of that we have now sold four of the distribution businesses to Cat dealers.  Those are in our numbers now and in our outlook.  So that will probably take a little bit off the top line from Bucyrus as well and that is baked into our outlook as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.  If I could follow up on Europe on the construction equipment business, can you just comment did it accelerate to the downside through the quarter?  Are you seeing trends get weaker there during the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think it's probably fair to say if you just look at Europe, Africa, Middle East roll in numbers, you've seen that monthly get weaker and I think that's certainly been the case in Europe.  Europe has moved from &#x2013; Europe, Africa, Middle East has moved from up to being about flat and it has moved that way throughout the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you think that continues to deteriorate through the year or does that stabilize at a low level here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's, again, we don't provide our outlook in quite that level of detail, but to Ed's point earlier, we have a decent sales outlook forth back half of the year.  We're not looking for a big deterioration.  That said, there are pluses and minuses. We're seeing, for example, better business in Brazil.  That's turning up a bit.  And you also would have seen that in the Latin America numbers move from, I think down 6% to down 3%.  So you are seeing that move a little better and it was actually positive later in the quarter and in fact, our machine retail sales, I'll say this, in June, we report the three-month moving average, but from a monthly perspective, June was the best month we've had since January in terms of month-over-month increase.  It was one of the best months on a volume basis we've ever had.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks very much, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question today is coming from Ann Duignan.  Please announce your affiliation then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.  JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  You know, can we take a step back again and look at U.S. construction.  Doug, you noted on CNBC this morning that you are seeing more broad based recovery in housing starts across the country.  There's pieces out there that the rental channel is secularly going to grow versus kind of contractor ownership.  What are you guys seeing out there right now?  And Doug, when would you anticipate that your contract customers would start to purchase equipment again rather than rent which they usually do at the beginning of a cycle, but as we get into the cycle, they usually prefer to own their own equipment.  What have you guys seen out there?  And what do you think happens over the course of the next year or two?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My comments earlier on broad-based housing recovery is relative.  I mentioned that I was on the West Coast, in California specifically, and I met with several contractors and all of them had for the first time in five years a subdivision underway, and none of them were massive projects like we saw in the 2000s, but it was fairly widespread in that a subdivision here or a subdivision there in different areas of California, I was impressed with that, but from a very, very small base.  I'd heard that elsewhere around the country as well and I think that housing statistics support that as we look at that.  There's no question the rental market, the multifamily is booming, I guess, in some parts, and we will take advantage of that.  I don't really see our contractor base significantly taking up orders based on housing probably until at least next year. If anything happens, it will be the transportation spending and some degree of clarity on that through the highway bill we just saw, suppose the next two and a half year. And I would say that if we see it, when we see it, it will really be spring.  It's too late in this construction season to get much underway.  We'll see it first in the rental market for sure and depending on the prospects of the debt cliff and everything else in this country and how that settles out this winter, that will impact the spring greatly.  So I see a couple of those things coming together that could be positive and if the country blows itself up as some politicians are threatening, I guess it would be negative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough.  And then on the operating side, you noted that material costs were flat in the quarter.  Should we anticipate or why wouldn't we anticipate that material costs, shouldn't they be a tailwind going forward from here, particularly even if pricing weakens from here, but it's still a positive, shouldn't the net be a positive for Caterpillar going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ann.  This is Mike.  You know, even when commodity prices were moving up, the impact on our actual material costs was quite muted.  If you go back in the first quarter, we were up about a percent.  Last year, we weren't up much more than a percent.  So it was, the impacts on us are quite muted and part of that is because we-for a lot of our purchase volume, we agree prices annually.  The majority of our material purchases are not actually commodities. So I think broadly speaking, your sentiment is correct.  Obviously, the portion of our business that is commodity related, the pricing is a little bit easier, but I wouldn't get carried away in terms of order magnitude there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just a real quick follow-up on that one then.  You're looking at taking $1 billion out of inventory by year end.  What would the target be for days on end or inventory turns once we get through all the sales of the <mark type="ph" /> Bucyrus distribution systems (46:25) et cetera?  What should we be looking at a year from now in terms of the right kind of inventory levels for Caterpillar?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ann, if I was going to look out and net out all the acquisitions and all that and look out into 2013 type timeframe, something around a three turns would be a place I'd fall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That would be sort of think of it as FIFO not LIFO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.  I appreciate that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I want to just come in here a little bit on our inventory outlook run rates, et cetera going forward. And I will tell you that we are playing the game here on a world that grows maybe anemically, but grows between now and call it the next 12 months to 24 months.  We are not playing for an implosion.  We are not playing for a drop like we saw in 2008.  The tea leaves that we see based on the monetary conditions that exist right now and the easy money flows should loosen up the economies a year from now.  What we're seeing today is the effects and impact of pretty tight monetary policies a year ago.  These things take time to wind through.  We have only in our dreams arrived at an availability position that we have today where we can concentrate on market share and pricing, which we are doing.</p>
          <p>I am very reluctant to take too bold of a move on inventory in China because we have seen this China show before, many times in the last 25 years.  We've seen it in terms of an absolute stop in demand for excavators and wheel loader probably three times since I've been watching China in my career, maybe four. And within a year, we've seen a recovery, sometimes booming recovery and some just a nice recovery.  We are in a position today where if we miss that and have insufficient inventory with the amount of competition we have there, we'll be out of that game and it will be hard to get into a leadership position that we want.  So we are watching China very carefully.  There's no question we have too much inventory for today's run rate of sales, but again, I am not at all convinced that a year from now or less or a little more we'll see China back on its feet as we have seen so many times in the past. And everybody can argue that this is different and China's changed and maybe it has, but I suspect there will be some amount of recovery.  We'll be in a position where we have availability and we can build <mark type="ph" /> pins (49:26) in our distribution model that will work for us long term.  That is not a dissimilar place where we are with PDCs.  We arguably are a bit heavy everywhere today at the run rates. But we are in a position where we finally have availability that we have built capacity around that we didn't have in the last two recoveries around here.</p>
          <p>And certainly that's been part of our strategy to take market share with availability.  Our quality levels are as good as we've ever seen them.  Our efficiency levels are as good as we've ever seen them and we now have availability in the marketplace.  We're not playing for an implosion.  We're playing for arguable growth, may be anemic, but as I sit here today and we look at 2013 as Ed said, it's almost got to be better on an economic basis, GDP growth and the world, and that's what we're playing for.  So while yes, we are watching inventory and yes, I'm very worried about inventory turnover, we're doing all we can with our supply chain and it is improving.  We don't want to call this the wrong way with too little inventory and I would say get stuck with too much.  It's all hands on all leverage every day with inventory and run rates.  We've got schedules in the third quarter that are very much reduced with maintenance shutdowns, with vacation shutdowns around the world, and we'll manage production to sales that way as well, but inventory levels are important if we believe the world is going to grow, which we do, may be anemically.  I guess that would be my statement around all of that, with is a little lengthy, and I apologize for that, but it is something we're managing.  We're he being very, very cautious and guarded with, both on the upside and the downside when it comes to working capital and specifically inventory.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair point, Doug.  Thanks for the color</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question today is coming from Jamie Cook.  Please announce your affiliation then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.  Good morning, Credit Suisse and nice quarter.  Two questions.  One, you know, Doug, with regard to the economic outlook you just sort of laid out and obviously you guys are a little more constructive on 2013 relative to what your stock is saying, I guess just beyond 2012 and given the environment you just laid out, how do you think about CapEx?  I mean, do we need to state this $4 billion number to meet your targets in an okay macro, but slightly weaker than what you were calling for? And then I guess, how do you think about share repo in that context given where your stock is, given where your stock is? And then I guess my second question is, can you just talk about your comfort level with dealer inventory levels outside of China? And I guess my thought or concern would be, you know, as I talked to dealers and just given the weaker macro and just given your ability to deliver and given the fact that your lead times have come in, do you think the dealers can sit there with less inventory than they had been historically, one, because they're concerned the macro is weaker and two they're not as worried as they were historically that Cat can't deliver, they have actual confidence that Cat will deliver the equipment so they don't need to sit with as much inventory as they've had historically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you have a lot there, Jamie.  Let me take the CapEx one there right off the bat.  We are on track to get close to $4 billion, but I will tell you also that each of our groups, whether it's construction or resource or our aftermarket business are looking at that very carefully.  We significantly, I'd say, delayed some our plans and most of our plans in China for the time being.  As a result of that market to see how that sorts out.  We have an aftermarket distribution business that is very antiquated that needs upgraded and most of the CapEx you can argue is capacity related but I would also equally argue that it's cost reduction related, a la the Victoria, Texas excavator plant, small dozer plant in Georgia that we're expanding, bringing construction back here.  Those are cost reduction activities as well.  Again, we're playing for growth, albeit slight growth, and significant cutback in CapEx would only hinder us in 2014 and 2015.  We may have to do it. As sure as I'm sitting here today, if something happens on a macro scale between now and year end and we have to take actions, we will and we have proven we'll do it. But right now, we're playing for some kind of growth in the next 12 months to 24 months.  That's kind of around the CapEx.  That's around the inventory question.  I think there's no question that dealers are gaining confidence in our ability to supply equipment. And our PDCs are at optimum levels, hopefully that model will work.  They will carry less.  We'll carry more and the chain takes cost out.  That's what we're seeing, but again, depending on if we see growth or not, we'll have to adjust that model.  I forgot what you had in the middle there, Jamie.  Oh, share repurchase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, share re-purchase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  How could I forget that one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Especially at $82.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's dirt cheap at $82.  But having said that, to have a balance sheet today with debt to debt and cap at 40%, a net debt position when we consider our cash and securities and somewhere around 34%, 35% and I want to be sure that as we go forward in this very uncertain world, although I have painted it somewhat rosy with anemic growth, that we have a bulletproof, rock solid balance sheet that we never have to worry about our credit rating or dividend, which I don't think we do.  Share re-purchase is not on our radar screen today. It's the last of our priorities.  I have said before and I think I've said to all of you that I hope in my career, which has a few years to go, I can buy one share back, but right now we have got other priorities and I think we're investing them wisely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay great.  Thanks.  I'll get back in queue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question today is coming from Robert McCarthy.  Please announce your affiliation then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Robert W. Baird.  Good morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jamie basically asked my question, but the other side of the that coin is, with valuations depressed, and recognizing that it certainly has a lot to do with that, how tempted are you to try to take advantage of that and continue what so far has looked like a pretty successful external investment program?  I'm talking about acquisitions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Rob, this is Ed.  We've laid out kind of our cash deployment strategy and I think you're going to see us consistently stay focused on it.  We think the number one is the opportunity for growth.  We've moved aggressively in terms of the acquisition space.  We tried to do it early in the cycle because it's easier to integrate as you work through the cycle.  I think on the acquisition front today our primary focus is what I would describe as slow down, chew and digest.  We feel good about where we're at with the integration of Bucyrus.  It took a lot of work.  We feel good about where we're at in terms of EMD and Mike talked about the operating performance there but there's still more work as well with MWM and Siwei. So I think you are going to see us stay clearly focused on integrating what we have in the acquisition space.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ed, if that's the case, you're not showing any appetite really to try to reduce the absolute level of debt on the balance sheet.  So should we just then expect to see cash continue?  I mean, you're generating significant free cash flow.  Are you just going to watch that accumulate on the balance sheet over the next two to four quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe.  And we'd like to get that debt to cap gross number not the net number down into the low 30s percent.  And I think that that sets us up to have any flexibility we want in a downturn for acquisition or any growth opportunity that comes along.  So I would say that the concentration on the balance sheet while generating cash and making sure our pull-through numbers are at that 25% level is exactly where we would be in the next two years, particularly with the level of uncertainty out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My follow-up has to do with, I guess, disclosure, if that's the right way to characterize it, but we've now anniversaried the Bucyrus acquisition.  Two sub questions.  One, does that mean next quarter you're going to stop providing visibility into its performance as differentiated from the rest of resources? And second, Doug, do you have some plans to maybe quantify the company's progress toward its existing synergy targets when we see you at MINExpo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll handle the first part, how's that.  And probably I'll handle the second part, too.  The first part is, yeah, we'll probably continue to report Bucyrus just as we are throughout the rest of this year.  They are, for example, not in our monthly dealer statistics from a disclosure standpoint and we would plan on doing that, for example, at the beginning of 2013 where you have good comparables.  We'll continue to break it out certainly for the rest of this year. And in terms of MINExpo, we have an outline at this point of what we're thinking about in terms of material to share at MINExpo and since it is MINExpo, there will probably be a little extra emphasis on mining and Bucyrus is a piece of that.  We'll talk about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll put some definition around that and some definition around that just tell you our synergy plan in the business case is ahead of schedule as of today and we'll talk, we'll get into some detail on that in September for sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll look forward to that.  Thanks, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have time for one more question. Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no further questions in the queue at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>All righty.  Well, thank you very much, everyone.  We are happy to report a great quarter and an increase in the outlook.  With that, we'll sign off.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.  This does conclude today's conference call.  You may disconnect your phone lines at this time and have a wonderful day.  Thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>