<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1426685" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-10-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>98</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Investor Relations">Michael DeWalt</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">Stephen E. Volkmann</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Vertical Research Partners LLC">Rob C. Wertheimer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Douglas R. Oberhelman</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Group President &amp; Chief Financial Officer">Edward J. Rapp</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Andy Alec Kaplowitz</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Susquehanna Financial Group LLP">Ted Grace</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Robert W. Baird &amp; Co. Equity Capital Markets">Robert F. McCarthy</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Jerry D. Revich</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Henry Kirn</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">David M. Raso</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Seth R. Weber</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Longbow Research LLC">Eli S. Lustgarten</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (United States)">Jamie L. Cook</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Third Quarter 2011 Earnings Results Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> It is now my pleasure to turn the floor over to your host, Mike DeWalt. Sir, the floor is yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, and good morning, and welcome, everyone, to Caterpillar's Third Quarter Earnings Call. I'm Mike DeWalt, the Director of Investor Relations. I'm pleased to have our Chairman and CEO, Doug Oberhelman; and our group President and CFO, Ed Rapp, with me on the call today.</p>
          <p>This call is copyrighted by Caterpillar, Inc., and any use, recording or transmission of any portion of this call without the express written consent of Caterpillar is strictly prohibited. If you'd like a copy of today's call transcript, we'll be posting it in the Investor section of our caterpillar.com Web site. It'll be in the section labeled Results webcast.</p>
          <p>This morning, we'll be discussing forward-looking information that involved risks, uncertainties and assumptions that could cause our actual results to differ materially from the forward-looking information. A discussion of some of those factors that either individually or in the aggregate we believe could make actual results differ materially from our projections can be found in our cautionary statements under Item 1A, Risk Factors of our Form 10-K filed with the SEC on February 22 of this year, and also, in our forward-looking statements language contained in today's release.</p>
          <p>Okay. This morning I'll start by summarizing our third quarter financial results, the increase in our outlook for 2011 and our preliminary outlook for 2012 sales and revenues.</p>
          <p>Earlier today, we were happy to report a record-breaking third quarter. Sales and revenues were $15.7 billion, and that was an all-time record, the best quarter ever in our history. Now, the quarter did include $1.1 billion in sales and revenues from our recent acquisition of Bucyrus. Excluding Bucyrus, sales and revenues were $14.6 billion, and that was also an all-time record.</p>
          <p>Profit was $1.71 per share in the quarter, and that did include a negative impact of $0.22 a share related to Bucyrus. Excluding Bucyrus, profit was an all-time record at $1.93 per share.</p>
          <p>The $0.22 impact from Bucyrus included acquisition-related expenses of $160 million for the inventory step-up and $122 million of deal-related and integrated costs. Now, the inventory step-up will continue in the fourth quarter and there will be more deal-related costs, but much less in total than the third quarter.</p>
          <p>There's a good summary of the Bucyrus related impacts in our financial release, and it's on page 15. It's in a table in the Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Now one other point on Bucyrus, when you review our financial results by segment, remember that Bucyrus is in Resource Industries, and when you review our sales by geographic region, remember that Bucyrus impacts every region. Now, to help you understand that impact, we've broken out the Bucyrus sales by region in our discussion of Resource Industries on page 10 of the release.</p>
          <p>Because of the size of Bucyrus, to keep the discussion apples-to-apples, we'll compare our third quarter 2011 results excluding Bucyrus with our total third quarter 2010 results. And again, at $14.6 billion, without Bucyrus, it was a record quarter, up 31% from $11.1 billion a year ago. Sales and revenues were up in every geographic region, with North America up 25%; Latin America, 20%; Europe, Africa, Middle East up 41%; and Asia-Pacific up 38%. And again, those exclude Bucyrus.</p>
          <p>Now in terms of the timing of the sales increase and the backlog growth, it was reasonably consistent as we went throughout the quarter. Now, speaking of the order backlog, for all products other than Bucyrus, it rose 11% from the end of the second quarter in June, from about $21.9 billion to $24.4 billion at the end of the third quarter, and it's about 40% higher than it was at the end of the third quarter a year ago. Now, the Bucyrus backlog grew from about $3.5 billion at the time of our acquisition in July to $4.2 billion at the end of September.</p>
          <p>Now moving onto the results, price realization was $129 million, and that's up close to 1% and about as we expected. Manufacturing costs were up $330 million, and of that, period or fixed manufacturing costs were the most significant driver. And the primary reasons for that increase were our volume increase, the investments that we're making in capacity and the increases in our short-term incentive compensation. In addition to the period costs, material and freight were also somewhat higher.</p>
          <p>Now SG&amp;A and R&amp;D costs were up $82 million in the quarter. That's about a 6% increase in costs on our 31% increase in sales. We think that's pretty good cost control and, as a percent of sales, SG&amp;A and R&amp;D declined.</p>
          <p>Currency impacts overall were negative, $160 million to operating profit. It's a positive impact on sales of $356 million, but a negative impact on operating costs of $516 million. The most significant net negatives were from the yen and the British pound. The U.S. dollar was weaker versus both the yen and the pound, and we are sizable net exporters from both Japan and the U.K -</p>
          <p>As you do your analysis of our third quarter results, I'm sure many of you will do the math and calculate incremental operating margin. To help you out with that, we've included a Q&amp;A. It's on page 12 &#x2013; it's number 12 on page 18 of our financial release.</p>
          <p>Now when you calculate incremental margin, your purpose is likely to be to get a data point on our operating performance. We think to make it a reasonable analysis, you need to pull out the impact of acquisitions to make it apples-to-apples, and that's how we've stated our goal for the year. That's excluding the acquisitions of EMD and Bucyrus.</p>
          <p>Excluding the acquisitions, our consolidated incremental operating profit pull-through was 22% in the quarter and 24% year-to-date through September. That 24% year-to-date number is a little lower than our goal, which was 25% for the year and the primary reason for that is negative currency impacts. Excluding currency impacts, incremental operating profit was 30% in the third quarter and is 28% year-to-date.</p>
          <p>Bottom line, we're at 24% year-to-date versus our goal of 25%. That's pretty close and operationally, excluding currency, we're doing even better than our goal. All in all, it was a good quarter for sales and profit. Costs were in good shape. Margins improved. In fact, excluding Bucyrus, our year-to-date operating profit, as a percent of sales, is better than any full-year in more than three decades.</p>
          <p>Cash flow was also a great story. Our Machinery and Engines operating cash flow was over $6.1 billion through the first nine months of the year. That means if we stopped the year at the end of September, it would be an all-time record. The first nine months have been better than any full year in our history. Our debt-to-capital ratio continues to improve, and it dropped to 41.1% at the end of the third quarter. That's down from 42.6% at the end of the second quarter.</p>
          <p>As a reminder, we bought Bucyrus for almost $9 billion, and we did not issue equity to do it. And even with the acquisition, our debt-to-cap ratio is 41.1%, and we had more than $3 billion in cash on the balance sheet at the end of the quarter.</p>
          <p>Okay. That's enough about the quarter. This morning, we also increased our outlook for 2011. All in with Bucyrus, our new 2011 outlook is sales and revenues of about $58 billion, and profit of $6.75 a share. Our previous outlook was a range of $56 billion to $58 billion, with profit of $6.25 to $6.75 a share. Excluding Bucyrus, our new outlook is for sales and revenues of about $56 billion and profit of $7.25.</p>
          <p>Previous outlook was a range of $54 billion to $56 billion, and $6.75 to $7.25 a share. That's a lot of numbers, but I think the easiest way to think about the change in the outlook is this: from the mid-point of our previous guidance, we raised sales and revenues by about $1 billion and the bottom-line by $0.25 a share, both with and without Bucyrus.</p>
          <p>Now as we usually do at this time of year, we've provided a preliminary sales and revenue outlook for next year, 2012. And for 2012, we expect our total sales and revenues to be up 10% to 20% from the outlook for 2011 of $58 billion. Now, that's based on our view that the developed countries of the world will continue to grow in 2012, a little bit better than 2011, but at a slow rate and below their potential.</p>
          <p>In the developing world, we expect overall economic growth at about the same pace as 2011. In the U.S., we still expect continuing poor housing, a little better than this year, but still very weak. We're also not factoring in any new highway bill, but we are encouraged that it seems to be gaining some traction in Washington.</p>
          <p>In summary, we're still predicting improving but slow economic growth. In some of our businesses, that's actually good. For many of our products, we're producing full out and need more time to get more capacity in place. Despite the relatively weak economic growth so far this year in 2011, our order backlog has steadily increased throughout the year. It's at a record level, and that'll help support next year's sales.</p>
          <p>Commodity prices, while off earlier highs, are still at levels that should continue to be favorable for mining investment. We expect that dealers will continue to add to rental fleets to reduce their average machine ages and increase fleet sizes. Users in developed countries still need to catch up on deferred replacements, and we expect construction activity to continue to improve in developing countries, requiring some further fleet expansion.</p>
          <p>We expect that dealers throughout the world will modestly increase machine inventories in 2012 to support the higher sales, and we also expect that sales of engines, turbines, and rail will improve next year. Now, we understand we don't have a crystal ball, and as Doug said in this morning's release, we realize the world faces economic uncertainty and risk, and a key part of our planning process is to make sure we're prepared if this situation turns negative.</p>
          <p>Each of our businesses prepares trough plans, and that's a standard practice here at Cat. We do it every year, and that's to help us to act faster should the need to take action arises.</p>
          <p>Bottom line, our business is improving. The signs that we see lead us to believe that will continue, but we're keeping a close eye on the world economy, and we'll act if we need to.</p>
          <p>Just a couple of more points and then we'll take your questions. The first is, rightfully, we talk a lot about economics and sales and cost and profit, but there are a few other aspects of our business that are also going very well.</p>
          <p>Quality levels continue to improve for almost all of our product groups. We're well into our U.S. Tier 4 and European Stage IIIB product introductions. They're going very well so far and feedback from the field has been very good. Another area of improvement has been <mark type="ph" /> pins (13:09), and while we don't disclose absolute numbers, I will tell you we're gaining. It's been a steady year-over-year improvement each month since early 2010.</p>
          <p>And my final point, employment, our global workforce has continued to increase in the third quarter. And since the beginning of 2010, we've added more than 30,000 people at Caterpillar, and that does not include the acquisitions that we made.</p>
          <p>Okay. That's enough about the quarter. We're ready to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is coming from Steven Volkmann. Please announce your affiliation, then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. It's Jefferies &amp; Co.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm wondering, Mike, if you might be willing to directionally help us think about how incremental margins might proceed into 2012. And you had a number of things that were headwinds this year, things like currency and price cost and some of these comp accruals, and so forth. And it seems like most of those should be a little better next year. But then again, we're later in the cycle with a little bit higher production levels. Just conceptually how do you think about the progression of incremental margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll talk around it a little bit, Steve. We don't have profit guidance for next year but, as you said, there'll be plenty of puts and takes. On the positive side, this year, we've far exceeded our plan for the year. And the result of that is incentive comp is quite a bit higher than at a regular target number, well higher than our outlook. So, that would actually be a fairly sizable tailwind going into next year. Currency, as you said, has been a big negative so far this year and I guess that's &#x2013; we'll see how the currency plays out. Hopefully, it won't be a headwind next year. But we'll just have to wait and see what happens on currency next year.</p>
          <p>There are a couple of headwinds. We're increasing capacity for a lot of our product. We're producing full-out right now. As you've seen us announce over the last 18 months, we have a lot of projects in place, and that does drive some increase in expense. I guess I would wrap all that up and say so far this year, year-to-date, even, including the negative from currency, we've done about 24%, excluding acquisitions. Our goal leading up to 2012, through 2012, our long-term goal has been around 25%. So, certainly that's what we'll &#x2013; that's our goal. But again, we don't have profit guidance for next year. So, it's a little tough to be more explicit then that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, understood. That's exactly what I was looking for. And then, sorry to get into the weeds here, but was there an interest rate swap loss? I</p>
          <p>think you were guiding to something $150 million-ish and I'm just trying to make sure I'm thinking about interest expense right, maybe it's somewhere else?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no. We did have about $150 million of swap losses, but that was in the second quarter. That's behind us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, nothing else going forward, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is coming from Rob Wertheimer. Please announce your affiliation, then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Vertical Research, and good morning, everybody. Your orders were really exceptional, and it looks to me, I know you don't disclose orders, you do backlog, but it looks to me like they ticked upwards pretty significantly in 3Q. Just interesting, given that the uncertainty ticked upwards as well in August. So, can you tell me was there anything, Mike, you mentioned it in your intro comments, but were orders continuing to be strong through the end of the month, not to get too micro?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's a good question. And I don't normally talk about how things progressed through the quarter, but with all the uncertainty we were trying to send a subtle signal there that we had good consistent growth as we went through the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was on purpose.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Somewhat unrelated follow-up in China, I think you mentioned how you have the &#x2013; finally, have capacity to build a little bit of inventory ahead of the selling season. Can you talk about, obviously China, there's a lot of negativity around equipment sales in the market. Is there a point where you start to worry that you need to back off? Or is there enough share gain ahead of you that you can ramp into your full capacity that you've planned?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think if you look at China, and again, we don't disclose market share data, but there's plenty of information that people can pick up. There's no big leaders in China. It's a very &#x2013; it's a very big market, a very fragmented market. We're executing our strategy there. There's room for quite a bit of growth. We've actually done over the last, I don't know, few months, we've done better than the market overall.</p>
          <p>Earlier, we kept saying, time and time again, our sales were limited by production and I think what's happened to us relative to the market over the last few months has proved that out. It's hard to speculate too much about the future. It's a big market. It's a growing market. It's going to need more capacity, not just from us, but from competitors going forward. But there's always ups and downs in the timing. So, I think we're doing okay. We're proceeding with the capacity that we've already announced there, and that fits nicely within our plans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doug Oberhelman here, just another view on China from a couple of different angles. First, our sales to users in the third quarter of '11 were higher than they were in '10. Secondly, the slowdown we have seen in the economy as the Chinese authorities have tried to get a hold of inflation, in my view, is the best thing that could've happened to the construction equipment industry. The levels of investment, the levels of growth that were occurring there before they did that were unsustainable for Caterpillar, for our competitors, for our industry.</p>
          <p>And it would have led to a bubble of really significant proportions, which I think would've been felt around the world. The fact they got a hold of that early, which is no surprise given Chinese history, they have proven they can run that economy. Granted, it's getting bigger, but the fact they got a hold of that and our industry has slowed down is extremely healthy for us in the long term. The good news is our Excavator business, the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (20:53) product there is a world-class product that we can use just about anywhere in the world. So, we have the ability to divert some of that production elsewhere in the world where we can't keep up until we get our other investments up, like in Texas, which we're &#x2013; which we have started our new plant there for the 20 to 30 ton product, and it is underway.</p>
          <p>So right now, it's kind of a sweet spot, in my opinion, because we've saved the future to a great degree by not having that thing boiling out of control and spilling all over. And in fact, I think we'll see the Chinese authorities get a hold of inflation, reflate. Believe it or not, we'll see 9%, I don't know, 8% to 10%, 11% growth, which is wonderful for us and long term really plays to what our strategy is. So, I'm in the camp, loud and clear, supporting the slowdown in China in our industry because long term it helps us. And it adds then, as Mike said &#x2013; referred to, an inventory level in China we wouldn't have been able to produce to until probably '13 or '14.</p>
          <p>So we're at that level today. Our dealers are ready. Our distribution are ready, and we are seeing market share gains, which we like. But as he said, there's no clear leader yet, because it's such a disparate excavator business, and wheel order business. But right now, I'm pretty optimistic with where that market has evolved to, and what I think will be a reasonable growth, certainly at a lower level than 15% to 20% that we were seeing. But, man, 8%, 9%, 10% is great going forward, in my opinion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Doug. Thanks, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is coming from Andrew Kaplowitz. Please announce your affiliation, then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Barclays Capital. Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Andy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>'Morning, Andy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So if I could just ask you about your guidance for 2012 in maybe a different way. Can you talk about the visibility that you have in this guidance, given Caterpillar is getting more aftermarket-focused, it's getting more backlog focused. And so I know there's a lot of macroeconomic uncertainty out there, but it seems like those two things would help you and give you better visibility as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Andy, this is Mike. I think you're right, I mean, particularly with the acquisition of Bucyrus, with the relative strength of mining, which is a more sort of backlog-oriented business than, let's say, construction equipment. And kind of just going back to the earlier comments from today, or from the end of June to the end of September, our backlog, even without Bucyrus, went up 11%. Bucyrus went up a little bit more than that. We're up about 40% versus a year ago on backlog. So, that does help. You mentioned aftermarket, again, we don't break that out separately, but we've had continuing, consistent increases in the aftermarket business, which basically tells you a couple of things.</p>
          <p>On one hand, it tells you that activity levels are holding up because aftermarket is related to activity levels, and that gives you some confidence. And then, I think there's also an impact, particularly in the developed world, where we just have a little bit of an aging fleet, and I think that gives you a little confidence in terms of the need for at least some minimal replacement.</p>
          <p>But yeah, I &#x2013; it's never a sure thing. I mean, as you look forward to next year, there are a myriad of things that could happen, but I think as we sit here right now today, when you look at aftermarket, which is an indicator of activity, if you look at the backlog, which is an indicator of sort of customer confidence I guess, it looks pretty good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Andy, this is Ed. A couple I'd add to that, in terms of looking into next year, would be also we're seeing rental fleet utilization back to levels that are pre-crisis, so it tells you that rental fleet utilization is there. So, that's another thing that kind of gives us some confidence moving forward. The other one is we continue to see good, strong pricing in the used equipment market, which is another sign of good demand moving forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. And, Mike, if I could ask you specifically about Bucyrus for one second, $4.2 billion, if I'm not mistaken, is a record for the company by a wide range, and I know it's part of Caterpillar now. But as we look at that business, just in a few months of being part of Caterpillar, the backlog expanded quite dramatically. Is that the impact of Caterpillar yet? Is that just the strong markets? And maybe you could just update us on integration so far?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, I would say in general, mining his just continued to be very strong, and I would certainly hope that customers are happier that it's with us right now, but it would be hard to look at that and say this one is and this one's not. So, it probably has something to do with being part of Cat, but probably more to do with being just a really good market.</p>
          <p>In terms of the integration -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike's being a little diplomatic on that. I'd say of course, it is.</p>
          <p>[Laughter]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. In terms of how the integration is going along, we've had them for a few months now. I think all the early indications have been very good. But whenever I talk to people on this, I like to temper expectations just a little bit. If you look at the things that are going to make this just a super deal, they involve the dealers. So, we need to get the business, the distribution piece of it moved over to the dealers, and that's going to take a little bit of time. It's a very backlog-oriented business, so what they're selling this quarter is product that they took orders for a year or so ago.</p>
          <p>So we're seeing a nice increase in the order backlog, but it'll take a little while before that actually translates itself into sales. I'm sure somebody will ask, down the road, so I'll just hit this right here right now, in terms of how are we doing in talking with the dealers about selling them distribution businesses. And I guess I would say I think that's going pretty well. We never thought it would be all done in one quarter or even this year. We're focused in the places where the bang is the biggest, it's &#x2013; and with the dealers that have the most opportunity. They're very excited about taking on this business.</p>
          <p>But at this point, we don't really have any deals to announce, and until we do, we'll probably be a little more silent on the specifics around it. So, I think all in all, so far, so good on Bucyrus. We did not change our estimates for this year in terms of the overall impact, and so I would say that's a good thing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is coming from Ted Grace. Please announce your affiliation, then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Susquehanna. Hey, congratulations on a great quarter, guys. The question I was hoping to ask is in regard to the top-line guidance for 2012. And I was just wondering if you might be able to walk through some of the assumptions at a little more granular level. I know you walked through some of the GDP expectations for the U.S. being up 2.5% next year, Europe being no more than 1.5%. And you talked about U.S. public infrastructure markets being constrained, and private non-res improving. But I was just wondering if you could talk about magnitude and timing of public and private non-res in U.S. and Europe, and how you're thinking about various scenarios of austerity in both regions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think, let's, I'll just &#x2013; in terms of granularity, it'll be a little bit difficult. We didn't provide a lot of specific guidance by region or by country or by product. But what I would tell you is if you look at U.S. and Europe, increased construction spending is not the main driver. The main driver for increases in the developed world today, that would be both the U.S. and Europe, is essentially customers just having to replace some machines, kind of post the, in the U.S., 2006, 2007 highs, and in Europe, late 2008 and early 2007 highs. They have really just cut back replacement spending dramatically. And so I think most of the increase that we're going to see in both the U.S. and Europe and, in fact, that we are seeing today, even amid what is terrible construction spending, I mean, look at the housing market. It's terrible. The sales increases, which are quite healthy, are mostly related to replacements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, the 10% to 20% embeds minimal, if any, real underlying growth in the developed markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, in the developing world, there's enough economic growth that fleet sizes are going up, construction spending is going up. So, I think outside the &#x2013; in the developing world, real construction spending should be a positive. In the developed world, it's mostly replacements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Ted. To give you a feel for it, we have &#x2013; we use dealer rental fleets in the U.S. as kind of a proxy of where customer fleets are. And if you look at dealer rental fleets today, they're still at levels down in the area of the last trough, the '02, '03 timeframe, and on average, that equipment is 30% older. And so there's a really good pent-up replacement demand that is yet play out. And it's one of the reasons we're continuing to make some of the investments in capital that we're making.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then a real quick follow-up, Cat Financial in the quarter, you had $125 million (sic) [$126 million] of profits on revenue of 693 (sic) [$668 million], 21% margin. In the second quarter, it was like $172 million on $695 million, 25% margin. I know the earning assets were down about 1.5% sequentially, but could you just walk us through the other dynamics that, on a sequential basis, would've reduced operating profits?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, I think, if you look &#x2013; this is Mike, if you look at Cat Financial, I think their results have been quite consistent. I think in the second quarter, I think they lowered their allowance reserve, and there was a little benefit in there from that. I don't think that was as much in the third quarter. But I think, relatively speaking, their underlying operating performance is pretty similar. It's been actually good. I mean, past dues are improving, down just over 3.5% now. Cat Financial's been doing a pretty darn good job.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Well, best of luck this quarter, guys. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is coming from Robert McCarthy. Please announce your affiliation, then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Robert W. Baird. Morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wanted to ask about the growth in dealer inventory, $1.1 billion at 6 months, now $1.8 billion, doesn't really look like it's on a track to slow down in terms of its growth in the second half of the year relative to the first, which you've been &#x2013; what you've been talking about a quarter ago. I mean, maybe I'm splitting hairs. But it seems to me that there's some benefit being recognized through the development of &#x2013; through development of the lane strategy. So, my question, although a little bit difficult to define, it goes to the flavor of, are you seeing the impact really in terms of control of dealer inventory that you would expect to see at this point? And can we look for a much &#x2013; a much slower rate, and I mean, relative to your own revenue growth? Can we look for a much slower rate of inventory increases in 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Rob. This is Ed. In a months of sales perspective, you're really seeing dealer inventory get back closer to what we would consider kind of a normal months of sales. If you look at the growth in terms of the quarterly move in terms of dealer inventory, I think about 40% of that was related to mining. And that's not inventory. That's just stuff that's in transit being, getting ready, if you would, for the delivery to an end user.</p>
          <p>If you look at the fourth quarter, our view of fourth quarter would be dealer inventory would be in kind of the flat to down slightly-type range. You get toward the end of the year you usually have it. You get some benefits of things like accelerated depreciation, so I think you'll see it trend flat to down slightly for the balance of the year. And then with it normalizing from the months of sales perspective, I think movement going forward, would be in line with the revenue growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my other question goes to EMD's performance. I realize relative to the entire company, it's quite small, but I think you know we're very excited about the longer-term opportunity there. And I was struck by the fact that you had some nice revenue growth, but a decline in earnings in terms of year-on-year comparison, and I wonder if we're seeing some ongoing, call it, restructuring and integration expenses that are constraining profit</p>
          <p>improvement there, or if that's not the case, when should we expect to see a more healthy rate of profit improvement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is Mike. I think one of the things that's going on with EMD right now is they're kind of caught between two worlds. What they're shipping and selling right now is still at a pretty depressed level. Their expectations for '12, '13, '14 are much better. They're worried about capacity. The result of that is they've added a fairly sizable new facility in Muncie, Indiana. They've actually been getting that ready so there's been quite a bit of cost I think-related primarily to Muncie, to a lesser degree some capacity expansion down in Brazil. So, I think it's a case where they're seeing a strengthening order backlog, and they're trying to get capacity in place to do that, and that's costing something right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Call it investment spending, in other words.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And when you were talking about the Bucyrus service center transactions, and when we might see that, were you intending for us to come away not expecting any of those transactions to be announced before the end of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think we'd love to get some of them done this year. All I was trying to leave you with is we never &#x2013; we never intended that they would all be done this year, and we're focusing on the really big ones first. But, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'd love to get a couple of them done this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is coming from Jerry Revich. Please announce your affiliation, then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. It's Goldman Sachs. On your Mining</p>
          <p>Equipment business, Mike, can you say more about incremental manufacturing capacity expansion you're considering? And also, can you give us an update on your progress on purchasing an aftermarket service penetration on the Bucyrus business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Remember, the second part of that question because after I'm done with the first one, I might forget it, so hang onto that. What was the first part again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Any updated thoughts on incremental manufacturing capacity in mining broadly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And my specific question was -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My memory is short this morning. Yeah, we've been &#x2013; I'll use mining trucks a lot as a proxy because mining trucks, large mining trucks, are the biggest opportunity in mining historically for us, at least for the Cat brand. We've fairly dramatically increased production as we've gone throughout the year. Early in this year, we were, I think, I don't remember the month, but at some point in the first quarter, we got back to the '08 peak levels, and we're going to probably end the year something in the range of, at least for large mining trucks, half again as much. And the idea with the mining truck expansion was that by the time we got to early '13, it would have been doubled from that prior level.</p>
          <p>So for mining trucks, there's more to come. There are other parts of mining, which we're also trying to increase. Underground mining, there's a new factory going into Thailand, so there's quite a long backlog right now in underground mining, hard rock mining equipment. So, that'll be good. We're trying to get more production out on large bulldozers, as well. So, I guess what I would tell you is the plans that we have in place we're executing. But particularly on large mining trucks, it's going to be in bulldozers. It'll be tight as we go throughout next year, better than this year, but probably still tight.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Mike, can you relieve the same discussion on the Bucyrus assets, particularly the hydraulic excavators there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the hydraulic excavators, it would be very much the same, as we look at that manufacturing footprint, Jerry. This is Ed. The other one on your question about the product support side, and what we're seeing on Bucyrus, I'd say as got into it, we continue to see a lot of upside opportunity. A big part of capturing that upside opportunity is going to be getting the dealers inserted into this process, because a lot of that replacement part demand, they can &#x2013; they're already set up on the mining sites to be able to execute that, and so it's just a question of getting the flow of the parts through it.</p>
          <p>If you look at another part of capturing the parts side of the business on Bucyrus longer-term, it's the integration of our components into that product, and we're working that hard, but it's got a little bit longer shelf life in terms of getting that done. And then the last thing, we think we could add some good value with our logistics capability in terms of moving those parts around the world. So, going in, we felt one of the real upside opportunities was capturing more of the aftermarket on Bucyrus, and I'd say our early view is that view was correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And, Ed, as you have discussions with your mining customers on their CapEx plans, can you talk about the range of budget increases you expect to see out of them? And can you touch on which regions and commodities you expect to drive orders for your business over that time period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jerry, at this point in time, the indications from the mining companies are they're going to continue to invest. And you've seen it with the public announcements they've made and you've heard it in coal and you've heard in copper and you've heard it in gold. So, it's been pretty broad-based. And at least, at this point in time, the indications, if you really look at the lack of new capacity coming onboard over the last number of years, and you look at the urbanization that's happening and the long-term view of demand, I think the mining companies have decided they're going to invest through this period of uncertainty, and that's definitely helping our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jerry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is coming from Henry Kirn. Please announce your affiliation, then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. It's UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Henry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Henry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm wondering if you could talk about where the remaining supply chain pinch points are most pressing? And have you seen any discernible margin drags coming out of the supply chain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I would describe the supply chains issues right now as in some areas as tight, but manageable. Tires is somewhat tight, but manageable. Steel castings, kind of the same thing, I mentioned before, one of the places where we use a lot of large steel castings is in frames for mining trucks. We've done a good job. Our suppliers have done a good job in ramping up, but it's still pretty tight. Outside of that, I don't &#x2013; I'm not aware of any &#x2013; some specialty steels, here and there, but in general, I think it's &#x2013; I'd describe it as in some areas tight, but manageable and not many sort of system-wide problems that I've heard of.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And with all the headlines on Europe over the last few months, could you talk about how that market trended during the third quarter and maybe some of the demand thoughts that are baked into your guidance for 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, in a lot of ways, Europe is similar to the U.S. The economic indicators have not been most robust, but much of our business in the developed world again, is replacement-oriented. Most of what we sell in the U.S. and Europe, in any given year, is largely for replacements.</p>
          <p>And so that's driving that business. There are sales. We don't break it out separately, but we show Europe, Africa, Middle East and I think, excluding Bucyrus, that whole region was up 41%. Of course, the AME part of it, the Africa, Middle East part, was up more than Europe, but Europe is behaving in a lot of ways similar to the U.S., up on replacements and at some point down the road, it's certainly not in our expectations for '12, but maybe beyond that, these economies will grow more. We'll get some housing starts in commercial construction and then we'll have real growth that will drive the next leg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot. Good quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is coming from David Raso. Please announce your affiliation, then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the profitability for the company, just trying to think through 0'12 a little bit. The last couple of quarters, even if you pull out Bucyrus, the gross margins have been down year-over-year, and it looks like one of the key reasons is price versus manufacturing costs. The last couple of quarters, the price realization's been a lot lower than the drag on manufacturing.</p>
          <p>So can you take us through a little bit the pricing dynamic, and how you're thinking about that relationship? And then I'll have a follow-up kind of related to those manufacturing costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is Mike. And this is certainly no change in direction. We expected that this year would be somewhere in the ballpark of 1% and, in fact, that's roughly what we had in this quarter. We're &#x2013; we're driving the company to get margin improvement and incremental margins like we have this year without doing it on the back of high price. We're trying to drive the Cat business model, modest price increases, let's say, kind of in line with our cost inflation and then drive incrementals through efficiency. And we've done a pretty good job of doing that so far this year.</p>
          <p>I think if you look forward, I don't see us &#x2013; again, we don't have any profit guidance for next year, but what I just described was kind of in essence what Doug's strategy is, and so I don't see that dramatically changing. The price increases that we announced for machines for next year, the vast majority were between 0% and 3%, which is fairly consistent with this year. So, I would say, at least in terms of price, we didn't give you an average total all-in weighted average expectation for next year, but our strategy is modest increases, drive efficiency and get margin through that. And I probably wouldn't see that changing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I appreciate that. So, thinking through Doug's view right now, I'm trying to balance gain share and the aftermarket opportunity and thus, maybe not pushing price as much as in prior years, looking for areas where you can get the gross margins next year up, not down year-over-year, the $330 million this quarter of manufacturing costs that were up, let's pull out the short-term incentive comp, which obviously, when that goes up, that's a the positive thing, right? You want it going up because you're obviously hitting good targets. So, if you pull that out, the $255 million increase, it's about 240, 250 bps of gross margin drag. How much of that is simply raw materials, where obviously, we can try to hedge that out or just see how it plays out on input cost? And how much is that structural fixed cost because of all the capacity expansions? I have to assume they're going to be there again next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Dave, when you're talking gross margin drag, you have to be a little bit careful because we do our analysis on a period and variable basis. So, when you're looking at gross margin, that does include period costs. And so I think when you're looking at our gross margin performance, I think if you were to take out the acquisitions and the impact of currency, you would see our gross margin not being negative, but being actually better year-over-year. So, I think as you look forward, again, our goal on period manufacturing cost is to keep the growth rate in period manufacturing cost, which is was the biggest contributor to the $330 million, to keep it at less than half the rate of sales growth, and if we do that, that helps increase gross margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll follow up with you. I appreciate it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Doug here. On a broader view of this, I think the quarterly and certainly, the year-to-date '11 over '10 and now the outlook that we put out for '11 over '10, are right where we want it to be in terms of our strategic alignment to 2012 and 2015. And we have always said that our goal here are &#x2013; is a 25% pull-through over time, and we've hit that in some quarters and some quarters we haven't, but we're pretty darn close year-to-date 2011 over '10. And that's exactly what we expect going forward.</p>
          <p>In terms of the strategic gearing of the company, we're still going through that. Market share is the driver, balanced with profits that are 25% pull-through with our goal of &#x2013; our goals out in 2015. And I absolutely believe that if you dissect the numbers or not, the third quarter and year-to-date put us right on track for where we want to be and I &#x2013; we're all, as a management team, pretty happy with the progress on that.</p>
          <p>Long ways to go, we've got lots of capital investments to make, but where there are 7 billion people on the planet that want to live like the most developed countries do, and that's driving the needs for a lot of infrastructure, natural resources, and so on, and we are going to be in a position to take advantage of that, and that's part of the balance we make in terms of market share versus profit over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is coming from Seth Weber. Please announce your affiliation, then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Thanks. Good morning. It's RBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Seth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. I just wanted to drill down a little bit. There was a comment in the release about some unfavorable pricing or unfavorable mix in the Construction Equipment business, I guess two parts. Is that a regional issue? I mean, does that reflect some aggressive pricing in China? And I guess should that get better next year if the U.S. and the developed markets start to improve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in terms of construction, overall, I would say both on &#x2013; both in &#x2013; from a product standpoint and a geographic sort of country standpoint, country mix has been through part &#x2013; much of the year, slightly negative and you see that in terms of price. I mean, we don't &#x2013; for the same product at different &#x2013; in different areas of the world, it sells for different price levels, and we have commented on that, I think, throughout the year that, that's been slightly negative.</p>
          <p>From a product standpoint, we've had some pretty healthy increases in the small end of the product line. Other products, like excavators and some of the larger product, we've been fairly supply constrained. So, product mix has been slightly negative. It's not a huge deal, either sort of the geographic mix and impact on price or the product impact on margin. It's been a slight negative, but nothing overall too significant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And then I guess just a clarification. Is the mining business fully booked for 2012 at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When you say fully booked in mining business, I would say for the most part, we're, based on what we see right now, we'll be capacity constrained on most products during the year. But it's hard to say everything all year long. I mean, if you're mining customer, you might need a 320 Excavator to do some clean-up around a pile, so that would be mining, but it's not a mining product, per se. So, for the most part, I think the answer is we're pretty well sold out, but it's probably not 100% on everything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But fair to say you're not getting any requests for delivery push-outs or cancellations or anything like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. It continues to be a very strong business. The customers seem to have quite a bit of conviction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks very much, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is coming from Eli Lustgarten. Please announce your affiliation, then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Longbow Securities. Good morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Eli.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one quick clarification, you talked about inventory levels at dealers being sort of back up to normal months. Is that true around the world? Or seems hard for me to believe that inventory levels are back where dealers would like them to see be at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we didn't exactly say it's where dealers would like to see them. What we said was they're kind of back to a historical average. So, yeah, and it's actually, I looked at the numbers kind of by region, and it's some that maybe are a little over and some that are still maybe a little under. But surprisingly, all four major regions of the world are fairly close to historical averages right now. During the quarter, if you look at dealer inventory, we had more of a gain in inventory in Asia. But in a lot of ways, that's not surprising. Once we had enough supply to more closely match demand, it had been the region that had been the furthest under. So, yeah, I don't &#x2013; it doesn't look like there are any outliers, if you will. I mean, you don't have one region that's 40% higher and one region that's 40% lower. There's some reasonable consistency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And as far as your pricing for 2012, you talk about the 0% to 3%, but you had a second component for IT4 pricing for most machines. And I got to believe that you had a lot of costs in 2011 that were unrecovered and you converted over. So, I mean, are we looking at 2012 with pricing out of flow-through for IT4 being more of a lesser impact from the cost of conversion than we had in 2012 &#x2013; 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, two things, Eli. You bring up a good point. What a customer sees in terms of price is a lot higher than what we're reporting as price realization because you have things like Tier 4, where there's actually added content. And when we look at &#x2013; when we look at like the Tier 4 or Stage IIIB, where the actual content of the product changes, we're netting off the costs. But there was no big windfall, no big drag in 2011. I mean, the price increases on average, I'm sure it varied by model, but overall, Tier 4 has more than recovered its cost this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is coming from Jamie Cook. Please announce your affiliation, then pose your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Most of my questions have been answered. Just, Mike, quickly, anything, I think people are trying to get at this, but unusual as you think about your top-line forecast with regards to mix that we should consider, which could have implications for incremental margins? And then last, last while &#x2013; have you done any &#x2013; last time when we were going into the downturn, you guys were proactive in going out to the dealers and saying you can cancel orders. You know what I mean? Have we done anything in terms of, I guess, scrubbing the backlog, just given the macro uncertainty?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start with the first one on mix. I can't think of anything just off the top of my head here that's way out of line. I think our view as we look into next year is that mining will continue to improve. Construction will continue to improve. It's fairly broad-based. I'm sure, when it's all said and done, there will be some mix impact, but given the level of sales change that we're talking about and the idea that it's actually fairly broad-based, I &#x2013; it'd be hard to see huge mix shifts in that. And in terms of the backlog, when you go back to this point in time in 2008, it was a situation where &#x2013; and actually from here on in 2008, it was a situation where dealers stopped ordering. And it made you question the backlog. And I think we did the right thing by opening up the order book back then to let it be cleared out.</p>
          <p>We don't have that situation now. Dealers are ordering more. I mean, as you go throughout the third quarter, dealers ordered more from us than we sold to them in the third quarter and consistently in the third quarter. So, you never know what's going to happen down the road. We don't have a crystal ball. But it's been pretty good, solid consistent growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I just want to add in here. We get questions almost daily, from our own employees, outsiders, you name it. The situation seems like 2008 all over again. And while it does at a &#x2013; in some cases on a macro level specific to the European banking situation, it bears little resemblance internally at Caterpillar to this time or even going back to mid-2008. You'll recall that when late '08 hit BCP, our Building Construction Products group, and around house &#x2013; homebuilding had been in a trough for over two years at that point in time. And as Mike said, dealers &#x2013; dealer order rates were coming down all through 2008. And that's one of the reasons we said what we said in the fall of 2008 about a recession coming.</p>
          <p>We're not saying that today. I would love to say we see a boom coming, but we don't see that. We see a slow-growth recovery here that should be a lot better than it is, and it's been compounded by some policy missteps around the world in the last few months.</p>
          <p>Having said that, we do not hear anecdotally from customers or dealers that there is less work at this moment than there was a year ago. We heard that all through 2008, as their backlog shriveled and withered away. We do not hear that today. That's one of the reasons we've talked about that in our outlook statement for the rest of 2011. We may hear it tomorrow or we may hear it next month, but right now, it's very dissimilar to this period in 2008, and we're looking for a slow growth recovery, just exactly as we said in the outlook, going on into 2012, which at this moment, looks pretty good for our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All righty.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I'll get back in queue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're at the top of the hour now so we'll stop here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you all for joining us on the call today, and we'll talk to you again in three months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. This does conclude today's conference call. You may disconnect your phone lines at this time, and have a wonderful day. Thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>