<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1250113" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-08-11</date>
    <companies>
      <company>10261</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Warwick Bryan, Executive General Manager, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Ralph Norris, Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">David Craig, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Ben Koo</participant>
      <participant id="4">James Freeman</participant>
      <participant id="5">Richard Wiles</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, everyone, and welcome to today's presentation of the Commonwealth Bank of Australia's Annual Results for the twelve months to 30 June 2009. I'd like to thank you all for coming today to what is probably our last results presentation at the Lightbulb Auditorium.</p>
          <p>Today's presentation will follow our normal format. Firstly, Ralph Norris, our CEO will provide an overview of the result. Then, David Craig, our CFO will provide a more detailed review of the financial and operating performance and then provide an opportunity for questions. And before I get started, can I just repeat the request to turn off mobile phones.</p>
          <p>So I'll now hand over to Ralph. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Warwick, and good morning and welcome to you all. The Commonwealth Bank today has reported a good result in a difficult trading environment. While recent signs have been more encouraging, operating conditions for banks remain challenging, with slowing credit growth, higher loan impairment, and an uncertain economic outlook.</p>
          <p>Against this backdrop, our performance has been pleasing. Perhaps, most importantly, throughout the crisis, we've remained focused on day-to-day business and our strategic agenda. This enabled us to support our customers, as we all navigate these difficult times.</p>
          <p>For the year to 30 June, operating income was up 14% on a comparable basis, a good outcome in any environment. Strong volume growth and tied with market share gains offset the impacts of slowing system credit growth. The Group has maintained a disciplined approach to costs, with underlying costs up just 2.5%, or 4% if one-off items such as high credit card royalty costs are included.</p>
          <p>This has contributed to our improved efficiency across the Group, with the Group's cost to income ratio for its banking businesses now at an impressive 39.7%. While operating performance was strong, higher impairment costs resulted in cash NPAT falling some 7%.</p>
          <p>From a credit quality perspective, key trends remained in line with expectations. Consumer arrears continued to trend broadly higher, but still remained at relatively low levels. Financial credit quality remains generally sound.</p>
          <p>While the first half of the year was characterized by a small number of large, single name impairments, these have not been repeated to any material extent in the second half. Rather, we've seen a more broad-based steady increase in commercial loan impairments consistent with what you would expect to see in a slowing economy.</p>
          <p>Statutory NPAT was down 1%, inclusive of the final after-tax gain of $612 million on the acquisition of Bankwest and St. Andrews. The Group's return on equity remained strong at 15.8%, a good outcome bearing in mind the challenges we faced in the last year.</p>
          <p>In light of the uncertain outlook and as flagged at our March trading update, the Directors consider it prudent to preserve capital and have today confirmed a final dividend for the year of $1.15, which is 25% lower than last year's final dividend. Total dividend payment for the year was $2.28, down 14% on the previous year.</p>
          <p>As I've indicated previously, the Group has maintained a cautious and conservative stance throughout the global financial crisis and the resultant economic slowdown. While recent improvements in certain key indicators provide a more encouraging backdrop, we've continued to pursue a very deliberate action plan with a focus on key priorities, including risk management, capital, funding and liquidity.</p>
          <p>From a risk management perspective, over the last 18 months or so we've taken a number of steps to further strengthen the Group's already strong risk management culture. And I will talk more on this in a moment.</p>
          <p>Our capital position remained strong with a Tier 1 ratio of 8.07%, well above our Board-approved minimum level of 7% and significantly in excess of prudential requirements. On a UK FSA basis, this equates to a Tier 1 ratio of 11%.</p>
          <p>Our funding team has done an outstanding job again this year. We've completed our 2009 financial year funding requirements in March, having successfully funded the significant balance sheet growth and the acquisition of Bankwest and St. Andrews. We've continued to hold high level of liquids at $80 billion as at 30 June.</p>
          <p>CBA has always maintained a strong risk management culture, evidenced by our relatively lower risk portfolio which is more heavily weighted to home lending than to riskier commercial lending, a generally conservative approach to new lending, historically lower loss rates than our competitors, prudent and conservative provisioning, and adherence to risk-aligned key performance indicators, including risk-adjusted returns and profit after capital charge.</p>
          <p>And finally, a strong, experienced risk management team who work closely with the executives in each of our business units to ensure optimal outcomes for the Group and our customers.</p>
          <p>Following my appointment four years ago I initiated an extensive review of our risk functions. This resulted in the introduction of more sophisticated risk methodologies and organizational changes to better align our risk function with the needs of the business.</p>
          <p>Over the past 12 to 18 months, we've taken a number of additional steps to further strengthen our already strong risk culture to ensure the Group is well placed to navigate this downturn in the best possible shape.</p>
          <p>Under the leadership of our Chief Risk Officer, Alden Toevs, we've benchmarked our risk policy framework to international best practice, conducted a number of in-depth and extensive portfolio reviews and stress-tests, further strengthened our lending criteria in selected higher-risk segments, and reviewed and aligned Bankwest's risk procedures to those of the wider Group.</p>
          <p>Over the course of the past 12 months or so, we've also introduced a number of measures to assist our customers through this period, including in the case of our customers impacted by the collapse of Storm Financial, put in place a process to address cases where we have lost responsibility for their current problems; mortgage repayment holidays for the unemployed; the Commonwealth Bank's Small Business Investment Package; and specialist assistance teams at both Bankwest and CBA for customers who find themselves in financial difficulty.</p>
          <p>Two years ago the Group set itself the target of being number one in customer satisfaction by June 2010. Given where we were at the time, it was an ambitious target. However, it was one we firmly believed that was not only achievable but also necessary to deliver long-term sustainable shareholder returns.</p>
          <p>Standing here today, thanks to the concerted efforts of everyone in the organization, we are well and truly on track to achieve this goal. Customer satisfaction in our retail business has improved significantly, to the point where the gap to the top-rated peer has now closed to just 3.1% compared to around 10% just two years ago.</p>
          <p>In business banking, the improvement has been just as strong. Customer satisfaction has grown from around 60% to now stand at 72%, with the gap to the number one rated bank closing from 20% to 5%.</p>
          <p>In Wealth Management, our FirstChoice platform has been rated number one for the last two years running. These gains in customer satisfaction are adding real value to our bottom line, directly contributing to the strong revenue growth we've been able to deliver recently.</p>
          <p>Over the past two years, concurrent with the gains we've made in customer satisfaction, we've increased the average number of products held by each of our customers by more than 15%, outpacing all of our major competitors. Given that we now have 11 million customers, this uplift in products per customer translates into significant revenue benefit opportunities.</p>
          <p>The gains we've made in customer satisfaction have been across all parts of the organization. However, the areas where improvement has been particularly apparent to most Australians is in our retail bank.</p>
          <p>Three years ago it is fair to say our retail bank lagged its main competitors in virtually all key performance metrics &#x2013; from customer satisfaction to staff engagement, to volume growth, to efficiency and productivity.</p>
          <p>Today, our retail bank has been transformed. Over the past three years, Ross McEwan and his team have successfully delivered on an ambitious program, which has made it much easier for our customers to deal with us.</p>
          <p>Measurable achievements include customer complaints continuing to decline, while compliments are increasing significantly. We've grown home loan market share for 26 consecutive months. Our branch channel is now growing consistently above system and home lending.</p>
          <p>The retail bank cost-to-income ratio has improved by 320 basis points to 42.9% over the past year. And then improvements we've seen across the organization are in no small part due to the progress we've made in implementing our technology and operational excellence initiatives.</p>
          <p>The Group continues to make significant improvements to our systems and processes, directly supporting our frontline staff and satisfying our customers. Our Group-wide process excellence program is delivering real improvements in the areas such as loan application processing, where we have achieved a 50% productivity uplift.</p>
          <p>Earlier this year, we also delivered our Finest Online initiative, which has further strengthened our world-class online capabilities by providing customers with integrated access across a range of channels via a single online identity. The success of this initiative was recently recognized by the Asian Banker 2009 Award for Excellence in Internet Banking.</p>
          <p>Core Banking Modernization represents the next key phase in the evolution of our technology capability. It will deliver a step-change improvement in customer service and efficiency levels as well as provide a clear and distinct strategic advantage over coming years.</p>
          <p>Michael Harte, Dave Cohen and their team are making excellent progress and have already delivered real customer capability via the recent launch of three new products &#x2013; our First Home Saver Account, the CFS term deposit account, and our Online Saver &#x2013; all going live on this new Core Banking platform.</p>
          <p>As a result of this early success, we recently decided that we would extend the original scope of the project to include Bankwest, ASB and a number of other extensions to the program, which will add around $150 million to the original budget. However, we remain on schedule to complete the original CBA migration within our four-year timeframe.</p>
          <p>Once completed, this comprehensive overhaul of our core banking systems will see a significant reduction in our cost of doing business and more importantly, it will improve the way we interact with our customers.</p>
          <p>Finally, none of our recent successes would have been possible without our committed and hard working team of people. And so &#x2013; it's pleasing to see that our internal engagement score improved yet again and this year's Gallop score placed the Group at the 80% globally, which is well inside world best practice.</p>
          <p>Moving now to Bankwest and St. Andrew's. The Group continues to pursue a disciplined, profitable growth strategy with focus on the targeted investment and acquisition opportunities which are on strategy, and which offer value and longer term benefits for our shareholders. And Bankwest is an excellent example of such an opportunity as it represents a great Australian business, acquired at a very attractive price of 0.7 times book. Originally, the price was 0.8 times book, but in the wash up that's taken place, that has now reduced to 0.7 times book.</p>
          <p>The integration process has proceeded smoothly with key milestones achieved on schedule. With the CBA-appointed CEO CFO CRO now in place, Bankwest is pursuing a refined growth path for the future, which emphasizes and draws on the unique strengths of both organizations. And I'm pleased to say, Bankwest is performing well. Customer numbers continue to grow strongly, and volume growth in key areas such as household deposits has been very strong.</p>
          <p>Turning to the outlook, the 2009 financial year has been a challenging one and the outlook remains uncertain going into the new year. However, the Australian economy has been more resilient than many had predicted a year ago. And it is pleasing to see that there is some evidence of the beginnings of an economic recovery and improvements in business and consumer confidence, but there are still significant risks on the downside.</p>
          <p>Despite these positive signs, overall credit growth in Australia is slowing and economic conditions will remain challenging for the Group and many of its customers in the coming year. Accordingly, we plan to maintain our conservative business settings for the foreseeable future by maintaining appropriate levels of capital, liquidity and provisioning. The Group will also continue with its prudent approach for the management of credit market and operational risk.</p>
          <p>Having said that, we understand that the worst is not necessarily over for our customers, and, in particular, we expect unemployment to continue to rise, which will make it more difficult for consumers and some business customers. As I indicated earlier, our strong financial position has enabled us to support our customers through the past 12 months and we remain committed to being there for them in the year ahead. While it is clearly a time to be cautious and judicious, the Group's robust financial position has enabled us to maintain the momentum behind our five strategic priorities, and we are well positioned to further strengthen our core businesses over the coming year.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand over to David Craig to run you through the results in a little more detail. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good morning, everybody and thank you very much, Ralph. Pleased to see such a full house here this morning. As you know, in December last year, we bought Bankwest. Because we don't have audited comparative financials for Bankwest for the same period, most of the commentary I'll make today will be about Commonwealth Bank Group compared to the Commonwealth Bank Group as it was, and obviously we are providing all of the incremental information on Bankwest as well.</p>
          <p>As Ralph said in his opening remarks, revenue was up 14% and costs up 4%, and this has driven a very solid operating performance, up 23% on the prior year. Of course, the main part of the story today is about the state of the economy and the consequent impact that's had on our impairment expenses, which have grown significantly to 2.9 billion this year, and that has led to a 5% decline in underlying profit.</p>
          <p>Bankwest delivered a maiden profit for the six months of $113 million and that's led to an overall cash net profit after tax of 4.415 billion down 7% on the corresponding period.</p>
          <p>Statutory profit was down 1%. And of course, the main factor in the cash &#x2013; the non-cash items has been the gain on Bankwest. This gain has been struck after very conservatively assessing the assets that we've bought. To give you an indication of that, the Bankwest accounts at the half year last year had $213 million of provisions in them. In the acquisition accounting, we've established more than $1.5 billion worth of provisions.</p>
          <p>Despite that significant uptick in provisioning, we've still declared a profit before tax of $983 million and that compares to 600 million that was announced at the time of the acquisition.</p>
          <p>And to put that in other context, at the time of the acquisition, we said that we were buying Bankwest at 0.8 times asset value; the final purchase price was 0.7 times asset value.</p>
          <p>Also below the line are the amortization of intangibles, and in particular this period, the deposit book features prominently. There's a significant profit coming through in fair value accounting, and we've put that profit below the line, the $80 million. And as you can see, that's been offset by integration expenses incurred to-date.</p>
          <p>In total, we are expecting integration expenses for this to be about $313 million. And here you can see the phasing that we expect, these will be treated as non-cash items going forward. 112 million pre-tax this year, and as you can see, IT &#x2013; and as you would expect, IT and operational costs are most of those expenses. These integration costs are broadly in line with the 330 million we announced at the time of the acquisition.</p>
          <p>What's pleasing though is as we've worked through the Bankwest position, we've been able to identify more synergies than we expected, with synergies now forecast to be $340 million per year from 2012. And that compares to 220 million that we announced at the time of the acquisition. So we're very pleased with how that acquisition has gone.</p>
          <p>Turning to the normal operating business, and as you can see, strong business contributions across the board. Ross McEwan and his team in retail have really delivered a stellar performance this year with 3.7 billion of operating performance, up 21% on last year. You'll see for the first time that we're splitting out Institutional Banking and Markets from Business and Private Banking, which is the &#x2013; those two were combined in the old Premium Business Services. Ian Saines' team, in Institutional Banking and Markets, 49% up on the prior year. Of course, there are offsetting loan impairment costs there. In business and private banking, up 13% which is a pretty good performance when you consider that business includes margin lending which clearly has shrunk in this economic market.</p>
          <p>And I would think that there'd be many wealth businesses eying the Grahame Petersen's result in Wealth Management enviously &#x2013; yes, down, but not down as much as I suspect was expected. You can see Bankwest made an profit, this is obviously operating performance, 276 million for the half year. And the corporate center even performed well. Treasury was a significant part of that of course with 650 million of operating performance.</p>
          <p>The operating performance, of course, is a function as you drill down to the underlying Jaws and by growing income at a faster rate than expenses across the board, we've been able to deliver a very strong result. As you can see it's pretty consistent story, in Wealth for example despite the markets just dropping through the floor, underlying expenses in Wealth are 4% down, 2% down when you add in St Andrew's business which has been added to that business with 4% underlying.</p>
          <p>So as well as the Group result of 14% income growth and 4% expense growth you can see that Bankwest also has had extremely strong revenue and Jaws.</p>
          <p>If we turn to banking income, up 21%. So below the operating income you can see that the banking piece, in particular, has grown very, very strongly in the revenue stakes. But interestingly the trading income hasn't been a significant feature of that growth. It has contributed 174 million and what we've shown there on the right hand side of the chart is trading income for each of the halves.</p>
          <p>Now the important message here, of course, is trading income is one of those few countercyclical things that we have in our result. As markets get more volatile and markets deteriorate, our customers seek more hedging and so we're able to provide more foreign currency and interest rate hedging, and that increase in volume, you can see there in the second half of last year and the first half of this year. The second half of this year is returning to more normal levels.</p>
          <p>Now, net interest margin for the year was up eight basis points to 210 basis points, but we are providing much more granularity here of information to help you to understand just how many volatile items there are in arriving at Group net interest margin. As you can see we've increased our domestic pricing by about 13 basis points across the board. But this has not gone anywhere near covering the underlying increase in funding costs which have knocked 24 basis points off our margin.</p>
          <p>Now transaction accounts, for example, which are nine basis points, that nine basis point loss reflects the fact that while our transaction accounts cost us nothing, when interest rates come down the amount of the margin that we make on those accounts shrinks significantly and you can see that that's cost us nine basis points. And then of course, the intense competition for deposits and for funding has cost us across the board.</p>
          <p>The mix and liquids are a function firstly of holding more liquid assets at this time of the market which have a lower margin, but also an &#x2013; a deliberate decision to move from riskier but higher margin products into safer products such as home lending, which leads to a decline in net interest margin but, of course, substantially lower impairment costs. Treasury has delivered in these times and of course the replicating portfolio which is our long-term hedge against these types of conditions, has delivered 16 basis points. And I think it's important to understand that while interest rates remain low, this replicating portfolio will continue to deliver a buffer against this low interest market and that would continue through the next three years minimum.</p>
          <p>But as well as that of course we've raised capital during the year and that extra capital creates more interest income. And we've also been positioning our balance sheet to protect against declining markets. This is another countercyclical thing that we've done which has added four basis points. So a complex story within an eight basis point increase for the year. But I thought it would be worth just sharing with you what's happened to the Group's profit across products since the global financial crunch started. So this is comparing the change in profit over two years and looking at that between volume and margin and so forth.</p>
          <p>So the yellow bars show the significant growth in business, in volume of business, particularly obviously in home loans. So home loan, volume up about &#x2013; has added about $500 million to profits. But we haven't fully passed on the cost, the higher cost of funding to our customers and so you can see that blue bar showing that we're down 100 to $150 million on margin in that book and there has also been a modest increase in loan impairment costs as the markets deteriorated.</p>
          <p>It's the same story but far more significant of course in business lending. While we've continued to support our business customers and grown volume there, we've only passed on a small additional increase in margins and that of course is to start pricing in risk. And risk is never better described than by the red bar that shows the increased loan impairment cost in that book over the period, which clearly &#x2013; the margins have gone a little wide to recover.</p>
          <p>Same sort of story in personal lending. And then across in deposits, you can see the significant volume increases, the flight to quality occurred in deposits, that there's been very, very intense price competition in deposits. And you can see significant margin erosion in that business, although the grey bar shows the offsetting hedge of the replicating portfolio that's mitigated some of that margin decline.</p>
          <p>If I turn to costs, you can see that in this period, we've kept our costs very much under control with underlying costs only up 2.5% on the corresponding period. It's pleasing to see in particular that staff expenses have been managed to only 1%. Now, this represents very significant productivity gains for the Group. When you think that our revenue has grown 14%, to be able to maintain staff costs increasing at only 1% suggests very substantial productivity gains.</p>
          <p>It's pleasing though to see that at this time we are still investing in the future. Our overall investment spend internally has increased to 1.1 billion this year. That's up 5% on last year, and of course we've made a number of very important accretive acquisitions during the year.</p>
          <p>Turning now to loan impairment expense and of course the feature last half was the single name exposures, which you see added 39 basis points in the last half. This half is more of a return to trend, with continuing deterioration in the middle market part of the book and 61 basis points added.</p>
          <p>You can see that we've continued the conservative approach of adding a further management overlay of 10 basis points. When we look at that in dollars, our loan impairment expense for the half is down from 1.6 billion last half to 1.3 billion this half. And then we add Bankwest on at a 113 million.</p>
          <p>If we turn to the balance sheet, you can see that in aggregate our balance sheet provisions have increased significantly. We've collected provisions now sitting at 3.2 billion with a $1.3 billion management overlay included in that.</p>
          <p>The Bankwest increase reflects the fact that we have put Bankwest on to the CBA modeling and properly modeled what the collective provision should be there at 463 million. You can see that the consumer provisions are up, but not up materially and the commercial provisions are also up a little bit.</p>
          <p>So those bars on the left hand side give you a bit of a sense of the underlying book. So this is collective provision for what's in the book, but not yet causing problems. Of course, the individually assist provisions have increased to 1.7 billion. And again you can see Bankwest featuring prominently there. The reason that single name exposures have actually declined is because as we get to this part of the cycle a number of those accounts have now been written off.</p>
          <p>As Ralph mentioned, the CBA has a very safe balance sheet. Residential mortgages represent fully 56% of our exposures, which obviously is a very high proportion of our balance sheet. And a far riskier corporate exposures are a much lower relative percentage of our balance sheet. And history would say that this should lead to significantly lower loan losses.</p>
          <p>However, we have continued to maintain very high and conservative provisioning and you can see from these graphs that we're very much at the conservative end of the market compared to our peers and I particularly call out our total provisions to credit risk weighted assets at 182 basis points.</p>
          <p>So let's have a look at credit quality in a little bit more detail. Home loan arrears have continued to trend up as you would expect at this time of the cycle and with unemployment rising. However, it's been pleasing to see that credit card arrears have actually declined a little bit and that's because we've put a very big effort into the collections process, calling our customers to let them know that they're falling behind and fortunately they are responding to those calls.</p>
          <p>We're still very comfortable about the quality of our home loan book. Now, fully 90% of our standard variable rate customers are paying mortgages off in advance. And averagely they are about seven months ahead. And that will give them a big buffer if they ever hit any problems. The average loan-to-value ratio for our home loan book is 40% of current market value. And as you know, we have mortgage insurance where loan-to-value ratios exceed 80%. We've continued to tighten our credit standards throughout the year.</p>
          <p>On the commercial side, 66% of our book is still graded investment grade. And again, in this book we've been tightening credit criteria. We are seeing increasing signs of stress in the middle portion, the corporate portion of our books. So I'd be characterizing that as loans of between 20 and $100 million. Generally speaking, the larger exposure loans, larger clients have been able to access equity markets where they need to. And the small end of our book, the smaller clients, the mums and dad businesses, have generally been pretty conservative in their borrowing and they're in, they're okay as well. But these middle portions that needs, probably needs some equity, but can't quite find it are experiencing some stress. And in particular I'd call out the property sector, the leisure sector, mining services and some areas of retail.</p>
          <p>We've been conducting extensive reviews of our portfolio on an ongoing basis looking for problems and making sure that we've got them covered and that we're working with our clients ahead of time. In the institutional book, we've looked at 654 institutional clients and these are independent reviews done by credit teams independent from those managing the account. That 654 clients represented fully 65% of our non-bank clients in that area. We've also looked at the 1,200 highest risk corporate and SME clients. The whole of that review yielded just two clients that needed to be regraded into troublesome and impaired and a handful of downgrades. So this has given us a lot of confidence that the books are being managed well and the information we're getting is current.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to capital. Of course, with Bankwest's acquisition now finalized we now have a final number for the impact of capital which was 40 basis points. So we really started the period with 8.35% of capital and we finished before interest rate risk in the banking book with 8.33. So we've been able to manage our capital on a pretty flat basis.</p>
          <p>And in particular, you can see that we've been managing pro-cyclicality. Credit &#x2013; well, risk weighted assets have actually declined only one basis point in the period and that's because we've been managing out of higher risk exposures towards lower risk exposures and that's mitigated the impact of an inevitable migration that you see at this time of the cycle.</p>
          <p>As you know we in Australia have &#x2013; are the one regulated entity or regulated country around the world that has interest rate risk in the banking book. And we've continued to take the position of holding hedges against &#x2013; we believe this is a very countercyclical thing to hold hedges against our balance sheet and against declining interest rates. And those hedges and positions have yielded hundreds of millions of dollars of profit to offset the impact of the declining interest rates.</p>
          <p>We could carry some of these positions in our trading book. And if we did that we wouldn't have this capital impact. But if we carried it in our trading book, we would have to mark-to-market that value and we will be getting significant volatility through our profit. We think it's more appropriate to have these hedges amortized over the period that they are covering and in so doing, we know that we have baked into our results going forward further protection against this slow interest rate cycle. But of course that's cost us 26 basis points.</p>
          <p>So our final position for the year is 8.07% and as Ralph mentioned on an FSA equivalent we are right at the top of the class with 11% Tier 1 FSA capital. We announced this morning that we're seeking to raise a minimum of $700 million of Hybrid capital and that will deliver a minimum 25 basis points of Tier 1 capital.</p>
          <p>Turning now to funding and liquidity. As you know it's a feature of our book that we have a very high level of retail funding at 58%. We continue to extend the maturity of our long term funding, which is now sitting at 3.6 years. And as you can see, we've made significant progress in funding. We're now about $10.5 billion into this year's funding task and it's very pleasing to see that with the markets opening up fully one third of all funding that we've done since the guarantees have come in has been unguaranteed funding.</p>
          <p>As Ralph mentioned we're carrying $80 billion of surplus liquids at this time because of the state of the markets.</p>
          <p>So let me just leave you with a few key messages. Ralph spoke extensively about how we've kept focused on our five core strategic initiatives and I am not going to repeat that, but I would particularly point out that we've made a number of important accretive acquisitions during the year.</p>
          <p>We've managed to increase our staff engagement now to the 80th percentile and of course customer satisfaction is improving across the board. And this customer satisfaction combined with these other initiatives has helped to drive our income up significantly with banking income up 21%. At the same time and because of the state of the economy we're carefully managing our costs and those have only increased by 2.5% on an underlying basis. Those two in combination see our Group cost to income ratio dropping to 44.6%, which is a 430 basis point drop in a single year.</p>
          <p>We've maintained a very strong balance sheet with Tier 1 capital above 8% or 11% on an FSA basis, and we've maintained our conservative provisioning with $1.3 billion of management overlay.</p>
          <p>Above all and from my point of view, most importantly, we are delivering for our shareholders with a return on equity of 15.8%. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David. Just before we start questions, just a couple of housekeeping issues. Can you please wait for the microphone before asking the questions, and also identify yourself? At this stage, can we just keep it down to two questions per questioner? I'll come back to you if we have some further time at the end. And I also understand that we may have some media on the line &#x2013; I'd appreciate if they could save their questions until the media conference at 2 o'clock.</p>
          <p>I'll start here and then go to the phone. So John Lott?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi. It's John Lott from UBS. Just a question on the economic overlay &#x2013; you've built that up now to &#x2013; or total overlays, if you want to call it that &#x2013; $1.3 billion in total. And I know in the second half it was another 200 million odd, but in the third quarter that you highlighted it trading up at, it was actually 250. So it was actually a bit of claw back in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Are we now expecting that to peak and start utilizing that economic overlay, given that the economy looks like it's stabilizing. And does that almost imply that we should start seeing the bad and doubtful debt charges improving from here on, given there probably won't need to be further economic overlays built?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, I think it's fair to say we would like to think that that was the case. I think it's still too early to call that at this point. I think it's fair to say that the way we see the situation is that unemployment is still going to continue to rise for a period yet. And certainly, that's going to have impact on consumer books.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-on question, on the S&amp;A book, I think if you look at slide 35 you highlight that the repricing for the business book from the margin perspective is pretty minimal, yet there has been a bit of repricing through risk. Do you expect to see more repricing through risk in that book, in the business banking book, margins expanding in that book going forward, given it was only pretty minimal in the profit impact so far, since the global financial crisis started?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's a fair observation, John and I think at this point we would say that we've repriced around 25% of that book in total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John . James Raymond?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>James Raymond from Deutsche Bank. Just a quick question on the margin, just so we can get an indication of where the spot margin is at the moment and just a bit more detail on the treasury benefit that came through in the second half, it was nine basis points &#x2013; just sort of what was driving that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to take that one, David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we don't give you spot margin but you'll see on slide 32 that the six monthly margin is sitting at 216 basis points, so it is trending up.</p>
          <p>What was the question about treasury?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a bit more detail as to what actually drove that treasury improvement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it was a mixture of two things. It was the profit on position we took to hedge against declining interest rates so that's a position we took without equity on our balance sheet. And the second piece was the increase in equity that we raised and the benefit that came from utilizing that increased equity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is it fair to assume that those are continuing to kick through into the current half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, there will some continuation of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, James. Craig Williams?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Craig Williams from Citi here. The underlying net interest margin I think in the second half was down four basis points. Given the political environment, are you adamant that you must continue to adjust mortgage pricing in order to recover higher funding costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Craig, I don't there's any doubt that we will continue to reprice where necessary. I think it's fair to say that we've got to act on the commercial basis and certainly we've got to do what is right for the business and if and when we need to reprice we will reprice.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And a question for David. I know he likes commenting on the economists' forecast, slide 116 has some credit growth forecasts with an outlook in 2010 and 2011 for &#x2013; well, certainly some strengthening in credit growth. Do you believe that deleveraging has passed in the Australian economy and can Australian banks grow credit growth in excess of deposit growth, which I presume at eight to 10% is being forecast in 2011 on an ongoing basis and maintain AA credit ratings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there's some good questions in all of that. As you say, these are our economists' projections and the good thing about Michael Blythe and his team, who have just been highly awarded, is they were the ones that called that this crunch wouldn't be as tough as people thought, which is pleasing.</p>
          <p>We are certainly confident that we can fund our fair share. We've been able to do that. Our treasury has been very successful internationally and locally in keeping us well funded, and have helped us easily buy Bankwest. So having absorbed something like that, we are pretty confident that we can look after our normal customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben Koo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Ben Koo from Goldman Sachs JBWere. Just going back to that slide on slide 35. When we look at those different businesses, you just alluded to the fact that rates will eventually have to increase. Just wanted to get a bit more color then, on that impairment expense for housing, we've seen &#x2013; that looks like a number of something around $200 million, which is probably equating to about 10 basis points of losses incurred since the credit crisis began, but we haven't actually seen unemployment rise yet.</p>
          <p>So can you give us a sense of when you're looking at the profit trends across those businesses, home loan losses will probably increase as unemployment tends to rise? You're probably expecting business lending, given you had a few one-offs in there that might decrease. And then personal lending, how do you see that just trending over the next two halves?</p>
          <p>And I am just rolling that in with some of the early comments. Some of the other banks are sort of suggesting that they expect bad debts to peak in like the first half of '010 or around that period. Can you just give us a bit of color around your expectations given the macroeconomic outlook?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to talk?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I've received this one. It's very hard to predict the future. This is obviously what's happened in two years, you're absolutely right that we haven't seen very high unemployment yet. But we have seen deteriorating arrears and the arrears is what drives the collective provisioning in housing. It's pleasing to see so far that we haven't seen a lot of specific losses in housing for &#x2013; with our customers we've been able to work things through, but of course the collective provision builds up nonetheless. That, as you've pointed out, is likely to continue to build up because inevitably we're forecasting that unemployment will climb and that's going to drive further, certainly further collective provisions in that book.</p>
          <p>We would hope that on the business lending part of the cycle that we will start to see some improvement, particularly with institutional clients, those very large ones who've now been able to access equity markets. But we remain cautious and concerned about the middle market &#x2013; middle corporate Group. By the way, this business lending is all institutional end business lending and corporates, the whole lot. Personal lending is a pretty small piece; obviously, with the markets coming back we might do some more margin lending. Part of that change there has been less &#x2013; low margin lending and more higher margin credit card lending. So that's led to that movement.</p>
          <p>So as for where the peak is, I think we're sort of sitting and watching and hoping that we're well provisioned and just waiting to see what happens. But we're there ready to help our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gerard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gerard Martin , Royal Bank of Scotland. Apparently a couple of months ago Ralph, you had retired. So I just wanted to get comments from yourself about when you think the job is done at CBA, what succession is, and what sort of timeframe that you're looking at being at CBA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Gerard, I'm glad that &#x2013; thank you for saying that I'd retired. Well, I'm glad to be back here this morning. Unfortunately, somebody obviously didn't give me the message. I'm here to do the job until it's complete, and so I have no fixed date of completion. And certainly at this point, I'm obviously enjoying the role. It's a challenging role. And so there is no appointed date for my retirement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's completion...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would imagine sometime in the distant future I will retire.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what is completion? What do you &#x2013; when is the job done? Is it customer satisfaction, is it...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, customer satisfaction is only one piece, but certainly one of &#x2013; the key factor for me now is to make sure that I leave a very strong team in place with a board capable to able to pick a successor from that team, and also with a business that is well positioned from the point of view of its technology platform, its processes and systems and the like. So I want to make sure that my successor gets a really strong level of momentum from the plateau that the business will be at when I retire.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Gerard. Matt, it's your turn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Matt Davison, Merrill Lynch. Some questions, just on a few of the revenue line items. The CBA lending fees up about 200 million year-on-year -- if you could just talk a little bit more about the divisional drivers there? The colonial GAM fees down 100 million sequentially, just whether there are any specific drivers there?</p>
          <p>And lastly, just on Bankwest, their net interest income up over 100 million on the pcp, yet the balances don't seem to have moved too much, so just wondering how the margins have tracked there and whether that reflects, I guess, a pullback of some of Bankwest's previous aggressive pricing before you took them over?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Three questions there. I think if we &#x2013; Matt, if we look at the situation, first in regard to &#x2013; taking them in the reverse order &#x2013; looking at Bankwest, certainly, there has been an improvement in margin there. They obviously had issues around funding back last year. And so obviously, with Commonwealth Bank becoming the owner, the cost of funding to some extent was able to be reduced. And as a result of that, you have seen an increase in margin.</p>
          <p>As far as GAM is concerned, I think it's fair to say that the economic environment, et cetera, that markets has had in impact on fee income in regard to GAM, and that's reflected obviously in the overall performance of Wealth Management. I would expect that we will see some improvement in that over the period ahead, if you take the view that markets, equity markets, are going to continue to run at these levels or higher.</p>
          <p>Looking at the issue in and around lending fees, we have obviously had a very strong performance in lending from the point of view of home lending, and that's resulted in obviously a good level of income growth there. And certainly there has been, obviously, some higher lending fees in and around the commercial side of the business as well, which reflects the current interest rate environment and fee environment in general. But, obviously, going forward, we are going to have a reduction in fee income, obviously impacted by the changes that have been announced in regard to exception fees, which will have a nine-month impact on the coming financial year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Brian . Just after Brian we'll go to the phones for a moment, then we'll come back into the room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two quick questions, very predictable question, first of all, for David. David, if you've got a microscope and you can have a look on page &#x2013; whatever it is &#x2013; the capital one on page 68. And then if you've got an even better microscope, and you have a look on note 16, by this time you are really squinting &#x2013; you'll see...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you in the PA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So page 68?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Page 68, note 16, bloody small print. Gees, I'm sounding like Jack Tilburn, which is a bit terrifying, but anyway.</p>
          <p>If you have a look there, you'll see that the investment in Colonial, when you take it out of the capital position, we've known about this for a while, is net of $700 million in Hybrid capital and it's also net of $1.7 billion in non-recourse debt that's issued in the Colonial subsidiary &#x2013; which for the life of me, I don't quite understand why the capital is treated that way.</p>
          <p>But can you run us through specifically the future outlook for both those numbers? Because the Hybrid presumably matures at some point in time, which means it effectively, because it's netted out at the moment, that comes straight off your capital base, and also the 1.7 billion. I would just like to get a bit of a flavor on where those numbers go going forward, and if, in fact, they mature, what is the ability to basically refinance? And then I'd like to ask a second question, if I may?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as you know....I know this is your particular pet topic, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it used to be about the full eight billion wasn't --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the good news is that we intend to continue with the treatment that we've got. We've had some refinancing of this in the current year, and we have been able to successfully refinance that. So we expect -- in terms of trend, we expect that to stay there.</p>
          <p>In terms of our view on that treatment, it's important to note that APRA, the rating agencies and ourselves are all consistent in our view and treatment of that capital, and that's been the case for many years. So we remain comfortable with its treatment. We remain comfortable with our capital levels, the stress testing that we do, and so on. And we continue to believe that not only are we treating that appropriately, as everybody else feels, but also that we are well capitalized.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the 700 million Hybrid. When does that mature?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lyn, do you know the answer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to be clear on the four year format. It's refinanced that 50 million that's due in September. We have that loan for 55 million with a two year maturity and almost a 1 billion free maturity. So that's on financing .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fantastic. Just not to labor the point, but if you look at the global financial stability forum talking about shifting to basically simple leverage ratios, and CBA is certainly more leveraged than the peers, are you still comfortable that in the future that they would actually allow that treatment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You said something Lyn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, we have no reason to think that that will change as a result of a leverage ratio coming in. No we don't have any reasons to think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question is going back to a few of the questions we've had today, just on the replicating portfolio &#x2013; fantastic job to harvest the benefit coming through. What I'd like to understand is what drives basically the realization, the quantum of the gain, and what drives the recognition of it back through the P&amp;L?</p>
          <p>I'd always understood it to be falling rates, whereas if you have a look at the environment we're in, it's not just falling rates that are smashing deposit margins, it's also competition. Could we get a feeling on the unwind of that, on a scenario where interest rates go up, stay steady? Could we just get the future profile of the unwind?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It is always very hard to predict, because of course it moves, as you say, with interest rates. It's &#x2013; to protect against a low interest rate environment, not just &#x2013; obviously it particularly comes in when interest rates are falling and continue to fall. The more they fall, of course, the more the rest of our income gets hurt by falling interest rates, and this comes in to protect. But in a low interest environment, if interest rates stayed where they are today &#x2013; and of course I don't think anyone's predicting that that will happen &#x2013; but if they stayed where they are today, then we would have significant future benefits coming from the replicating portfolio in total over five years, but primarily over the next 2.5 years.</p>
          <p>If interest rates go up, then of course we benefit in our main banking business as we get more income, and at the same time, the replicating portfolio delivers less income, because in an increasing environment, that unrealized profit starts to shrink away.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you also have to start to buy future hedges, though? Does it actually go negative, though? Do you have to spend money on it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, we've been spending money on it. In very high rate environment, particularly when interest rates are going up, up, up, it does cost us money. It's an insurance policy. And if you have a look on slide &#x2013; I'm trying to remember where it is &#x2013; so it's actually a graph that gives you a very good example of how we were paying away...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>114.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>114. You can see that at the height of the interest rate rising theme, that orange line on 114 is above the cash rate line, which is the blue line, and so we were paying away. But of course, in this environment, you can see that the orange line is well below. Sorry. The orange line is the cash rate, and the blue line is replicating portfolio.</p>
          <p>So it smoothes the impact of both increases and decreases. But in this sort of environment, of course, it provides a very significant buffer against that low interest rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Brian. Might just go to the phones now. We'll come back in a moment, here. Firstly, Johan from Daiwa Securities in Melbourne.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, everyone. A question on the profit announcement, page 53, about loans past due. If I look at one of the categories, which is other commercial industrial, which obviously moved up quite a fair bit as a result of the Bankwest acquisition, in terms of loans past due, it used to account for about 11% excluding Bankwest, and now it accounts for 20% including Bankwest.</p>
          <p>My first question is how are you managing that portfolio and how are you managing down the loans past due, particularly on a less than 30-day basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, certainly, we've been, Johan, working very hard in our collections area and through our relationship managers to make sure that loans past due are being obviously taken as a priority from the point of view of making sure that the situation doesn't deteriorate.</p>
          <p>Obviously, in some situations, or many situations, you're going to find that the deterioration is going to obviously be somewhat difficult to arrest. But certainly, making sure that we are getting on top of loans and difficult loans early has been, I think, a successful strategy for us over the last year or so.</p>
          <p>You are right to observe that, certainly in regard to the acquisition of Bankwest, that has had a &#x2013; an impact on that past due profile, and certainly there is a lot of work going on at Bankwest in that regard. And certainly our risk team here in Sydney has been providing a lot of support to Bankwest in that regard.</p>
          <p>So a fair observation, and I think it's also indicative of the comment that David made in regard to the fact that in that corporate or commercial area of around 20 to $100 million, we have seen a &#x2013; an increase in past due in that particular sector.</p>
          <p>But overall, I think we &#x2013; well, overall we are comfortable with our provisioning, we are comfortable with the analysis that we've done on the stress test that we've undertaken, and also the rigor that we've attached to the analysis of the at-risk parts of our portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. My second question is about the Wealth Management operations. I saw that you restated the '08 figures. Could we just get a little bit more flavor as to what the restatements relate to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you like to handle that, David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What are you referring to specifically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>To Wealth Management, the income line. So you've got the breakdown in terms of CFS, so you've got common share and other &#x2013; and the figures are I think slightly lower compared to the previously reported FY '08 figures. And that's something that has changed apparently with today's results announcement, so it should be something related to the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What page are you referring to Johan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, unfortunately he is referring to something compared to our last PA. I'll have to come back to you on that, Johan, I don't know the specifics of the reclassification.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Stewart Olfield. Stewart?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ralph, just a question on your saying that overall credit crunch in Australia is expected to slow through 2010. What in your view are the weakest spots there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The weakest spots are generally in the consumer parts of the portfolio. I think that obviously with increasing unemployment, we're going to see, I think, a lower growth rate. And obviously, we're also been seeing a deleveraging taking place in the household sector in general. And so I think that that will have an impact, and I think also as a result of that, we will see probably lesser demand in the smaller end of business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And perhaps I think David, you referred to that middle part of the commercial market being under some stress -- inability to raise equity. Are we likely to see the discipline that was shown by the majors at the top end sort of extended down that far? Or is that a tougher ask?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, no. I think that &#x2013; I mean it's in all our interests to help our customers through difficult times. So I think that we have seen, as you say, rightly say, discipline amongst the banks.</p>
          <p>Obviously in the larger clients it tends to be big bank syndicates, and it's actually quite difficult to be disciplined in a very big bank syndicate. With the smaller clients, it tends to be single bank relationships, and it's much easier to have a direct and useful conversation with our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Stewart. We might take one more question off the phones and then back to the room. Victor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a quick question on funding. If we look at your position currently versus the 12-months ago &#x2013; and that obviously includes Bankwest in there &#x2013; your loans have grown by around 30%. Their deposit growth was broadly similar. But your total funding has only grown by 18%, which suggests that large share of Bankwest acquisition was actually funded in the short-term market. And whilst you pointed out that the overall maturity profile of your term funding has increased, it looks like compositionally, you are funding larger part of your balance sheet in that short term space.</p>
          <p>Would you be able to tell us whether you are comfortable in the medium term with your long term versus short term funding needs? What your expectations are for 2010 funding requirements, and the impact it will have on the margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll ask Lyn Cobley our treasurer, to respond to that, Victor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Victor, our split between short and long term funding across the year hasn't really changed much at all. In fact, we've stayed at around the 45, 55% mark during the course of the year, and that's where we're at now. So it wasn't the case that Bankwest was funded out of short term liabilities, the entire profile has stayed the same.</p>
          <p>And in terms of our funding requirement for the year ahead, and on current forecast, current settings in terms of asset liability growth and the maturities we have, it is going to be around the $38 billion mark. But we are already well ahead of it, having done 10.5 billion even just in the last six weeks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Victor. James Ellis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>James Ellis from Credit Suisse. Just a couple of questions on capital. Specifically in relation to the 26 basis points from the interest rate in the banking book. Presumably that's going to decline over time, but just can you give us a flavor as to the magnitude of the profile?</p>
          <p>And then just secondly, generally on, when you think about a Tier 1 of 8.07, in an environment where a couple of your peers have increased, how much of an influence &#x2013; do you see that is an external benchmark or are you more focused on the internal benchmarks, like your minimum Tier 1 and the risk you're seeing inherent in your own book?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly James, the interest rate in the &#x2013; interest rate risk in the banking book has certainly fluctuated over the last three or fours halves. And you will see that at one point, I think, it was around 50 plus basis points. At the half year we were down to zero, and we're now back at around 20, 26 basis points.</p>
          <p>I would expect that that will come back in, but that depends obviously on interest rate settings going forward. But certainly, as David said, we see that the replicating portfolio has been a very good insurance policy to have in place as far as softening the impact of falling rates.</p>
          <p>Looking at the capital position, obviously we have done a lot of work internally within the organization, looking at where we are from a capital perspective. We have obviously very in-depth discussions with rating agencies.</p>
          <p>We're also obviously talking to APRA. Throughout this whole crisis, APRA has not moved our PCR at all. So our PCR still remains at a what I would regard as quite a low level. We have a mandated Board range, and the minimum on that range is 7%, which is significantly in excess of the PCR as determined by APRA.</p>
          <p>And certainly in all of our discussions with the rating agencies, they have no issue in regard to our capital ratio -- have not made any comments in that regard. They have undertaken, obviously, their own stress testing of our balance sheet and looked at what is the appropriate level of capital. And certainly from where I sit, we've got to be careful that we don't become &#x2013; get to a situation, as John Laker from APRA warned earlier on in the year, that it's a race to raise additional and additional capital, where it's not necessary.</p>
          <p>And so looking at where we are currently provisioned, having undertaken the stress tests, our discussions with rating agencies and where we are in our relationship with APRA in regard to capital and with the fact that we are obviously undertaking the Tier 1 Hybrid, we are comfortable with our capital position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James Freeman?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, James Freeman from Deutsche Bank. Just wanting to ask a question around the strategy. We've heard a lot today just around some of the pressures you're seeing, particularly in the retail franchise -- fees, volume growth, and you've also mentioned the margin. You know, if we have a look at where a lot of the growth for CBA has been coming, and the focus has actually been in the housing segment versus the business segment, which seems to be showing the reverse trends to retail. Just trying to get an idea as to why you keep pushing into the retail space when the returns over the next two to three years look like they'll be bigger actually in business lending, assuming obviously bad debts do reverse as the cycle gets better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James, we're obviously looking at risk adjusted returns, and we're happy with where we are as far as our home loan portfolio is concerned. You will have obviously seen the change that took place earlier on in the year, where we split PBS into two segments. And that is specifically to give much more focus to our business and private banking operations, to, I think, undertake what you are alluding to &#x2013; the fact that we need to be focusing more in that area, and to be growing that business.</p>
          <p>So we are putting a lot of focus and a lot of work under Rena Aruth into that part of our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Has the risk adjusted returns in retail started to slow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously with where we are, with margins on our home loan book, we are in a situation where we could obviously &#x2013; we're still very competitive. I think that the situation there over time will see a situation where the margin position in mortgages will return more to a normalized margin than it is currently.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Richard wiles?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard Wiles from Morgan Stanley. Just wanted to ask a broad question on the revenue outlook for next year. It seems that you're going to have a lot of exception fees, you won't get the recurring benefit of early repayment fees on mortgages, you won't get the Quantus royalty, you could have lot of treasury, lot of trading income, your flag volume growth slowing &#x2013; it all adds up to quite a lot of headwinds for 2010.</p>
          <p>So very simple question is do you think there is a risk that revenue could fall next year? And if you are confident of revenue growth, do you think you will get positive jaws or there is a risk of negative jaws?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, obviously we don't give too much in the way of forward forecasts in regard to revenue and the like, and I'm not going to change that policy today. But I have to say that we are very much concentrating on the fact that we will be budgeting for positive jaws.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Might go back to the phones again. Theus Slim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good set of results. I just have one question on strategy. With the new Chairman coming in, are we going to see a significant shift in the Bank strategy? For example, going more aggressive in terms of looking at institutional banking opportunities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's fair to say, Theus, that the new Chairman has been on Board now for probably around three years, and is obviously well apprised of the current strategy.</p>
          <p>So I don't think you should interpret the fact that we're going to have a new Chairman, that there's going to be any significant change in direction. I think it will be business is usual, and a seamless transition to the new Chairman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Theus. We have time for two more questions. Tim Barkley .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim Barkley at Shaw. Just a question, if I could, about the Hybrid raising. Just in light of APRA and the FSA's comment about the quality of Tier 1 capital, could you just touch on why the choice of a Hybrid raising? In light of the share price strength, in particular, recently, why not just go with the ordinary equity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're light on hybrid &#x2013; I mean we're well under the limit. It's first worth noting that when you start talking about internationally, internationally hybrids can be a much larger chunk of capital. And APRA has always and already had the more conservative view that hybrids should be a lesser portion of capital, 25%. We're well under that 25%, having paid back <mark type="inaudible" /> raising earlier in the year. So we're really just topping up our hybrids towards the 25%.</p>
          <p>I don't think, at this stage, there is any indication that, although, fundamental capital is going to be an important measure, that hybrids will go away totally. And from our point of view, for our shareholders, this is a very cost-effective way of having Tier 1 capital while still maintaining higher return on equity for our shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So David, just to repeat &#x2013; you don't expect APRA to move away from the 25 or reduce it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Last question. Ben?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just following-on from James' question just on the business lending focus and potential of changes there. When you called out the areas that you're a bit concerned about, you mentioned property, leisure, mining services and some areas of retail. What's the Bank's approach to just lending to businesses or your absolute exposure to those segments?</p>
          <p>Are you willing to still grow your exposures or maintain your exposures or are you going to shrink your exposure to those segments? Just given that you've got a lot of clients right now who potentially, I mean &#x2013; things are a little bit tight, but if you take a three cycle view, potentially they're still going to be all right in two years' time. Do you extend further credit to them, or what's the general approach given your focus on business lending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think as far as business lending is concerned, and particularly property and the sectors you mentioned, mining services and leisure, they are areas that are going through probably more pressure through this particular cycle, which is usually the norm.</p>
          <p>Property, we obviously have a limitation in regard to our portfolio appetite for property, and so there has not been an extensive extension of our exposures in property other than the fact that we are obviously supporting the customers who are currently customers of the Bank.</p>
          <p>There has been a lot of opportunity to grow our business exposure into those areas over the last 12 months with a number of other banks, whether they be second-tier banks or offshore banks lowering their exposure to Australian property, and a number of people endeavoring to get further accommodation &#x2013; we have not taken up the opportunity to actually expand into those additional relationships. But we are very mindful of the fact that we need to be making sure that we are supporting those customers who are already in property, mining services and leisure and making sure that we are seeing an appropriate level of leverage. And certainly, I think that's one of the benefits that we've seen in this particular cycle compared to the cycle of the early 90s, is the fact that business are far less leveraged than they were back in those days.</p>
          <p>And also we're seeing a situation where obviously the interest load is not anywhere near as difficult as it was in that period with interest rates running through to 21%, whereas, you know, we are seeing interest rates obviously in this particular cycle reduced quite significantly.</p>
          <p>So all in all, I think that it's a case of obviously working our way through. It's fair to say that there are lot a of good operators in this &#x2013; in all of these sectors. And the fact of the matter is that some of them &#x2013; most of them &#x2013; will survive this particular crisis. There will be some at the margin that won't. And so really it's a case for us to make sure that we're not lending good money after bad. And it's making sure that we are obviously supporting those clients who we see will come through the crisis or the cycle in a whole way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>On that note, I might bring matters to a close. So thank you all very much for attending today and see you in six months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>