<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1529779" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2013 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-02-12</date>
    <companies>
      <company>10261</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive General Manager-Investor Relations">Warwick Bryan</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer, Executive Director &amp; MD">Ian Mark Narev</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO &amp; Group Executive-Financial Services">David Paul Craig</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Jonathan Mott</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (Australia) Ltd.">Jarrod Martin</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Treasurer">Lynette Elizabeth Cobley</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Australia)">James Freeman</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Scott Manning</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Michael Wiblin</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Australia Pty Ltd.">Craig Williams</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley (Australia) Ltd.">Richard E. Wiles</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="CLSA Australia Pty Ltd.">Brian Johnson</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch Equities (Australia) Ltd.">Matthew Davison</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Australia Ltd.">Victor German</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Bell Potter Securities Ltd.">T.S. Lim</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Parker Asset Management Ltd.">Philip Elliott Parker</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the Colonial Theatre for the presentation of the Commonwealth Bank of Australia's results for the six months ending the 31st of December 2012.</p>
          <p>The process this morning will be as we would normally do. So Ian will kick off with an overview of the result; he will then hand over to David, who will give you a bit more detail around the results; and then Ian will finish with an outlook statement and a bit of a summary; and then we'll go to Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>So without further ado, it's all yours, Ian</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Warwick. Good morning, everybody, and thank you again for joining us for the presentation of these results for the period ended on December 2012. In the period, we had statutory net profit after tax of A$3.661 billion, so that's up 1%. The cash NPAT, which as you know adjusts for hedging, IFRS volatility, et cetera, and a couple of one-offs is up 6% on the prior comparative period. The return on equity on a cash basis is 18.1%, and particularly important to see that in the context of the capital number, which both David and I will refer to later, which on a Basel III globally harmonized basis is up 10.6%. So very strong capital underpinning that 18.1% ROE.</p>
          <p>Cash earnings per share up 4%, and dividends per share up 20%, and that growth number obviously inflated by the fact that we have done what we said we would do six months ago, which is adjust the dividend policy to smooth first half and second half dividends.</p>
          <p>Underpinning the results and probably the overriding message for us is just a continued commitment to a very simple long-term strategy, a strategy focused around customers, a strategy focused around productivity, technology investment, and a very thoughtful balance between share and margin. And I'll come back to that shortly.</p>
          <p>But first, just quickly as we do each time, a quick run over the business-by-business results, calling out a couple of the good aspects of the results and a couple of the more challenging aspects on a business-by-business basis.</p>
          <p>Retail banking cash net profit after tax was up 13%, which is a strong result and one that's particularly good in terms of the underlying momentum for a business with new leadership, and it's now about nine months ago since we announced Ross McEwan's departure, and I think the fact that we've seen not only a continuation but acceleration of that momentum is a real credit to the RBS [retail banking services] leadership team and particularly to all the good people at the frontline of the business, who have just continued sticking to the customers and sticking to their jobs.</p>
          <p>As a result, we've got income growth in the retail bank of 5%, expenses at 2%, which should be seen in the context of ongoing amortization of the core banking modernization program. So despite the extra costs of the amortization, expense have been managed to 2% relative to the prior comparative period here.</p>
          <p>Deposit income is a slightly different story. So deposit income is down 11%. You'll be able to see in the materials that the overall market continued to grow pretty strongly; we roughly held market share, but what we're seeing here is an ongoing challenge on deposit margins. You're going to see that across a number of businesses and that's one of the key things in this result. The other thing I would call out here is that particularly strong credit quality and arrears in the home lending book and right across the retail bankers contributed to that profit result.</p>
          <p>Business and private banking is down 4% on the prior comparative period. On the negative side, we're seeing continued challenges in the equities and margin lending business. So despite the fact that the CommSec business continues to hold good market share of online trading and continues to have good yield in terms of yield per contract note, the factors relative to the prior comparative period, equity markets and the overall trading volumes are very subdued. Margin lending remained very, very low, and so we've seen the equities and margin lending business continue to be a growth drag on the business and private banking results.</p>
          <p>On the more positive side, on an average RBA basis, we've got business lending up 3.5% in business and private banking on the prior comparative period and we've seen flat expenses year-on-year, and again I'd call out the fact that business and private banking has absorbed costs of amortization from the core banking modernization program and still maintain completely flat expenses period-on-period.</p>
          <p>Institutional banking and markets had strong operating performance of 15% up year-on-year. Our old friend, the counterparty value adjustment, which we spent a lot of time talking about six months ago, again figures here this time as a positive. So there is an A$82 million turnaround in the counterparty value adjustment relative to the prior comparative period and also a very good strong markets results, which you will have seen. Again here, net interest income down 7% and that is a function primarily of the theme that we're going to keep coming back to about deposit margins and deposit competition.</p>
          <p>Six months ago and certainly 12 months ago when we were talking about the wealth management business, there were a lot of questions that David and I got about: did we like the business; and we said at the time we love the business. It's just the markets haven't been kind to it. Well, in the last six months, the markets were a bit kinder to it. And lo and behold, we've seen really good performance there.</p>
          <p>So cash net profit after tax up 10% underpinned by net flows of A$6.5 billion. So that's the best performance we've had in net flows for five years. Net operating income overall up 10%, so we've seen not only in the Colonial First State platform, but also in the insurance business and strong performance from the global asset management business.</p>
          <p>Expenses were up 9% to prior comparative period in the wealth management business, which as a headline number, I must say is not too exciting. What we need to bear in mind there is a couple of things: number one is there are some additional costs relative to the prior comparative period for the Count acquisition, and in addition what we have seen in this business is an ongoing cost in implementing new regulations, future financial advice and other regulations. So on a more normalized basis, as David will talk about, the cost growth in wealth management is closer to about 3%.</p>
          <p>In both New Zealand and Bankwest, really good operating performance here. So New Zealand's strength and the margin up 10 basis points, continuing work on productivity saw the cost-to-income ratio come down 140 basis points. LIE up a tick at A$14 million. On Bankwest, slightly lower income growth at 2%. Very good ongoing attention to expenses here, so expense is down 3% relative to the prior comparative period.</p>
          <p>The loan impairment expense in Bankwest is up A$48 million. Now that increase is actually quite a big driver of the fact that the Group's loan impairment expense is up 13% relative to the prior comparative period. But the key point here to note is what we've got in brackets here is that actually that gives us 23 basis points on gross loans compared to the Group's own number of about 22%, so &#x2013; to &#x2013; 22 basis points. So this really is the normalized number. And if you look back at 6 basis points and 11 basis points over the prior two halves, it's actually the fact that those numbers were particularly low. This is a number which we expect to be pretty much normal now.</p>
          <p>So coming back to the point that I started on earlier, which is to say the underlying theme here is that we've just continued focusing on a long-term strategy. It starts with the customer. It &#x2013; obviously, underpinning all of this for us is keeping the engagement high of all the people across the Commonwealth Bank Group. And although the survey is done in the first few months of the calendar year, so we haven't had a new one since the last briefing, we have seen ongoing a really good engagement from our people. So right from the board level, executive committee level through the leadership teams, the focus on talent now is a little higher than it ever has been, and we're also seeing our people continue to respond well not only to the strategy but to the fact that we've made commitments to not seeing jobs offshore and not embark on large-scale redundancy programs. So the overall level of commitment and engagement in our people is very good.</p>
          <p>And what that shows up and above all else is not only the financial results but sustained improvements in customer satisfaction. So the message of the Commonwealth Bank Group remains: "Get focused on your customers". We've had the same message for six years and that message has continued to show very good benefits in terms of customer satisfaction.</p>
          <p>So you can see here on both the retail and the business side that the Group is outperforming the peer average in customer satisfaction. When we look at the most recent number on retail in the Roy Morgan survey for December, the gap between us and the number one is now at 40 basis points. So the Commonwealth Bank's own customer satisfaction is at all-time highs. The get to number one is at an all-time low compared to, I think, 12% when we started doing this, and we're just keeping the momentum on keeping our people focused on the customer.</p>
          <p>In the business bank, we've seen the business bank remain at first or first equal across all the different segments and that focus remains right across the business.</p>
          <p>Over the period we've continued to push ahead on our technology advantage and one of the most important things to call out in terms of where we are now is that there was more ongoing success in implementation during the period of the core banking modernization investment and by the time we present our results for the full year that project will now be complete. So we're migrating commercial lending across in March. We're obviously not taking that for granted, it's still a lot of work to do, assuming that goes as planned by the time we next speak that project will be finished. So again something which we've been very focused on right across the Group for six years which we have &#x2013; which we are bringing to completion.</p>
          <p>Very importantly, if you look at the retail bank, after this current half that we're in, so the one that ends in June mixed calendar year for the first time in about four or five years, the net impact of the operating expenditure and the amortization of core year-on-year will start to go down. So that's a really big milestone. But it isn't just about the core banking modernization program. And as we've managed to get that towards the end, we've obviously had more capacity to devote to other investments. I'll particularly call out here the fact that last week we launched the My Wealth program as part of our equities and margin lending business. So that platform is up and in the market. It's had very encouraging signs; I think 30,000 visitors in the last week and people staying for an average of 10 minutes on the site, and that is really a category leading platform in the investment of wealth management area.</p>
          <p>We have had already good experience in our branches with video conferencing. So by the end of June this year, all our 1,000 plus branches will have video conferencing capabilities. So that's each and every one of them. So the ability to deliver to our customers specialist conversations, specialist knowledge in areas like personal lending, wealth management and business banking will be in the branches and we're starting to use those now and getting good results.</p>
          <p>And the Investor Relations app, which hopefully many of you'll be using today shows that the commitment to looking at how we can use technology to improve the business isn't just prevalent in the customer phasing parts of the business, but also our Investor Relations team took upon itself the same challenge and has delivered something which hopefully you'll all find useful today.</p>
          <p>Quite rightly when we have these discussions and we talk about what we're doing with technology, the first question that comes from all of you is, well, are there any benefits in this? I've already shown to some extent how we think the benefits are showing up in the overall operational expenditure performance of the Group, but equally importantly we've seen in the half real progress in an area which we consider to be a core part of our competitive advantage through core banking and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (11:30) transaction accounts. So this is where the benefits of real-time across our consumer and our businesses really show up.</p>
          <p>And you can see here that RBS personal transaction accounts in the period up 13%, balances in RBS up 9%, BPB transaction accounts increased by 8,000 and we continue to have good success in institutional banking and markets with the successful transactional mandates. So the promise and the capability we've got at real-time banking is showing up in a way that customers are appreciating and that's giving us advantage in a very critical part of the Group's strategy.</p>
          <p>The second area of productivity; again, we have said we did not go down the path of big redundancy programs and big cost-cutting programs, but rather we said to you all we're going to take a considered multi-year approach to improving the fundamental processability of the Group. And you can see here four examples in the period of where the benefits of that focus of productivity is showing up. Particularly to call-out here, the top left in the retail branch network, you can see that transactions per the customer service represented about 6% relative to the prior period and sales and converted referrals per customer service specialist up 16%. And to give you an example of what's driving it, branch managers now have the access to an online work force planning tool which are showing them a over a long period of time hour by hour what the traffic is in the branches that they run and that's enabling them to ensure that staffing levels out in the front are high when customer levels peak, and when customer levels are lower, they have fewer people front of house and they've got more people doing this kind of activity. And this is certainly that's done day by day and the customer information is being updated weekly.</p>
          <p>And finally, in terms of strength that we have said on a number of occasions, we need to think for the long term. We won't favor cheaper balance sheet settings that might look good for short period of time, but we're very keen to ensure that our balance sheet is strong for the long term and we can see here that through the period again we've seen all key aspects of this strengthen. So deposit funding up to 63% of total funding, wholesale funding tenor up to 3.7% on a weighted average maturity base of long-term funding and the average issuance here was 5.3 years. And I want to just stop on this 5.3-year point for a minute, because obviously the question of wholesale funding costs is one of the key areas we'll be talking about in this result.</p>
          <p>If you look at the fact that the average issuance of our long-term debtness period was 5.3 years, that means it is replacing debt, which we took on roundabout the end of 2007. Now the real peak of the spike in spot funding costs started around the time of Lehman Brothers in September-October 2008. And what that means is, we've got another few months left where the cost of new funding that we are putting on the book is probably a little bit higher than the cost of funding it is replacing, and as we get towards the end of next year, that stops. So a lot of the debate here has been around is wholesale funding cheaper than it was one or two months ago. The answer absolutely is yes, but in terms of how this impacts funding cost, the right question is, is it cheaper or more expensive than the funding that's replacing?</p>
          <p>In terms of total provisions to credit risk weighted assets, there you can see we remain very well provisioned and David will have more to say about that. And then on liquidity and capital, we've grown liquids again relative to the prior comparative period, so they're up to A$128 billion. And as I said at the start, we've grown the capital very well. So a combination thereof the advanced accreditation of Bankwest, which accounted for about 30 basis points of capital and we talked about that last time around expecting that, and then strong organic growth also from the business.</p>
          <p>So overall a strategy that's continuing to deliver well for us. Our focus is going to continue on those same themes and I'll hand over to David now for a bit more of the detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good morning, everybody. As Ian has said, this particular period has been characterized by two things. Firstly, reducing volatility in international markets; and secondly, a continuation of very low credit growth. So those two things have combined to give us a 5% growth in profit for this period. And as Ian said, that's very much balance of balancing volume growth with margin, and we'll talk more about that.</p>
          <p>On the expense side, expenses at a headline level are up 3%, but there has been very strong initiatives around productivity across the Group and our underlying expenses are up 2%, allowing us to continue to invest in the business. These two have combined to yield an operating performance of 6%, which as you can see also flows through to cash net profit after tax. Loan impairment expense is pretty steady at 22 basis points. I'll talk more about that.</p>
          <p>Just looking at statutory profit, statutory profit was up 1%. The reconciling items between cash net profit after tax and statutory profit are the same as they have been before. So a very much consistent treatment and nothing really to call out there.</p>
          <p>So let's have a look at operating income. Net interest income is up 3% with volume up 4%, but margins down 1% on the corresponding period last year. Other banking income on the corresponding period was up 11%. So trading income is before counterparty valuation adjustment is flat on the last half but up on the corresponding half last year. You'll recall that in August 2011, there was a great deal of turbulence in the market and most banks lost some money at that stage. So we're certainly up on that period but we're flat on the last half. The thing that has turned around is this counterparty valuation adjustment which you'll recall gave us two periods of hit. The last two halves we've had negative counterparty valuation adjustment. This period, the CVA was positive and the turnaround is A$89 million at a Group level. Finally, funds of insurance income up 4% with strong growth in funds under administration, but this has been offset to some degree by higher claims experienced in insurance.</p>
          <p>So let's have a look at Group net interest margin. As you can see the margin is down 2 basis points on this time last year but there has been a bounce up of 4 basis points since June, and that's been the timing particularly of the asset re-pricing on home loans, which has delivered 7 basis points of improvement. But this has been more than offset by 9-basis point decline in funding costs, roughly 50-50 between wholesale and retail.</p>
          <p>The replicating portfolio, which is that hedge we carry against a low-interest rate environment, has kicked in, because interest rates obviously are getting very low, and that's &#x2013; that buffer is about 50% of the drop in interest rates and has contributed two basis points this period. The lower volatility has meant that basis risk is lower and therefore that's contributed 3 basis points and finally, the fact that we're holding higher equity or higher capital, we get to invest that capital, it earns interest and that's kicked interest &#x2013; our net interest margin up by 1 basis point.</p>
          <p>On the productivity front, what I've attempted to do here is carve out the underlying expense growth from the investment that's being going on. And you can see that across the board, the underlying expenses are very much under control.</p>
          <p>In institutional banking and markets, there are two factors that lead to a higher than 3% growth. One is the continuing investment in that business and the second is the fact that structured asset finance where leasing is growing strongly that has a volume related expense attached to it.</p>
          <p>In wealth management, as Ian referred to, of course we have count in for the first time so that's led to an uptick in costs, and as well as that again we're investing significantly in all of the regulatory reform and that's counted for 6% out of the 9% of cost growth in wealth. Bankwest, Ian's already referred to a strong cost performance. And then interestingly, even in the international markets productivity is kicking in. However, as you would expect, we're growing branches, we're growing people, we're growing investments internationally, and that's led to 6% growth across the board. So overall the Group expenses are up 3%, but the underlying expenses are up about 2% before investment.</p>
          <p>Let's have a look at credit quality. Credit quality, as you can see, sitting at 22 basis points, is pretty much consistent with each of the last four halves. Pleasingly, all of the credit measures are looking strong. The top right-hand corner shows you what's happening to consumer arrears across the Group, so this is a consolidated number, and you can see that all of our main product categories, the 90-day arrears continue to decline.</p>
          <p>The bottom right-hand corner graph shows you what's happening on the corporate side and both troublesome and impaired assets are declining. So these declines were improvements in credit quality naturally lead to a rundown in provisioning. In the case of individual provisions against impaired assets, we remain very conservatively provided at 43% coverage. But as you would expect they're running down and particularly you can see Bankwest that legacy book continues to be rundown and sorted out, and so the provisioning against that has declined.</p>
          <p>If you look at the collective provisions, again the improving credit quality on the consumer side, the lower arrears are leading to a lower consumer collective provision. However, you can see that we have maintained and indeed increased our overlay, so the economic overlays have remained intact and as well as that we've set aside some additional overlays this half for known model reviews that are happening in the second half, so you can expect to see that the management overlays will decline in the second half, so it's merely a timing difference, and those will decline, but the underlying collective may go up for the model related issues.</p>
          <p>Let's have a look at some of the business units and start with retail bank, where we have an offset of what's happening on pricing and on growth in higher volume &#x2013; higher margin products offset by the deposit story that Ian was talking about. So you can see that home loan returns were up on the back of the SVR pricing. Pleasingly, we have continued our push into high-profit products such as credit cards and personal loans, we're growing significant above system in this space and that's delivered a 13% growth, but this has been offset obliviously to some extend by the 11% decline in deposit income.</p>
          <p>So that &#x2013; looking at the retail margin on the top right-hand corner, there are two reasons why the margins ticked up this period, one is a mix change as we move more into credit cards and personal loans which have a higher interest rate and of course the other is the impact of the change in home loan pricing.</p>
          <p>Pleasingly, deposits are up 8%, broadly in line with system, but in particular transaction accounts you can see are actually increasing, and Ian talked about the gap to number one for customer satisfaction.</p>
          <p>If we turn to the business side of the story and here it's a case of volume being offset by changes in deposit pricing, so again, volume versus the cost of funds. The story on business in private bank on the top left-hand side is very consistent picture to the ones we've shown for the last couple of halves that is good growth in lending offset by what's happening on the equities and the margin lending business which is a continuing runoff. I am pleased to say that in the month of January, we had pretty strong volumes through equities and margin lending, so you never know that may be the beginning of something.</p>
          <p>The bottom left-hand chart shows you what's happening with institutional banking and markets, so the institutional lending is pretty flat, global markets are up obviously, partly because of the CVA, but if you take the CVA up they're 19% on that poor period in August 2011.</p>
          <p>Turning to the margin though, this is the important story. You can see that margin in business banking is down 13 basis points. And this is purely a deposit story as well as the fact that we're moving into or continuing to move into a very low interest rate environment. But if you think about deposits and the way they work in our business bank, our pricing is based off wholesale prices. Our pricing is based off the 90-day bill rate. So when deposit pricing goes up faster than wholesale pricing we can't recover that difference from our business customers and so that's led to that decline in net interest margin that you're seeing there.</p>
          <p>In wealth management, as Ian said, it's a case of the markets bouncing back and good flows coming as a result. Funds under management in global asset management are up 5% and that's led to a 7% growth in that space. In Colonial First State, again good inflows but you'll recall that 12 months ago I talked about almost the perfect storm of issues hitting Colonial First State. So compared to that time, there has been a bounce back which has seen the uptick of 28%.</p>
          <p>In CommInsure it's a run-off of the legacy portfolio and as I said higher claims experiences led to that result that you can see in front of you, but we are pleased with the net flows which are the highest they have been for the last five years in CFS, very strong performance in Colonial First State level asset management on investment with 75% of the funds outperforming benchmark. And averagely they're outperforming benchmark by 2.7%. So clearly that is helping to attract funds to that business. And as you can see in-force premiums up 15%.</p>
          <p>So let's have a look at funding and liquidity. And again, it's a continuation of the story we have seen before, virtually all of our lending has been funded out of deposit growth. Our deposit ratio is now sitting at 63%. When we look at the wholesale funding A$13 billion at the half, that we've now done A$20 billion of funding as of today's date. So most of this year's funding requirements are already sorted out. And you can see that we continue to hold at strong levels of liquidity substantially above the regulatory minimum.</p>
          <p>Now the interim of course, the interim dividend is something to speak about, because as Ian said, we called out this time in June that we would be changing the dividend policy, just move dividend, we're going to paying out 70% interim dividend, and that's led to a one-off 20% increase in dividend for this period at A$1.64. The capital is very strong, and this is of two things, strong organic capital growth has delivered 40 basis points of growth and on top of that as I've flagged six months ago, we've sought and obtained advanced accreditation for Bankwest, and that's added 30 basis points to capital. So at 10.6%, this is a very strong capital level and it compares to about 8.9% for our global peers. And, of course, as you can see it's up 54% since beginning of the GSC.</p>
          <p>Our APRA Basel III number is 8.1% compared to 7.5% at June. So because the capital is so strong and again as flagged as part of our capital and dividend policy that we announced in June, we have decided that for this half we will neutralize the DRP, so as not to see even more capital coming in the door. This is a decision that we will revisit each and every time we come to declare a dividend.</p>
          <p>So in summary, this is a result that's responding towards the environment, it's a continuing execution on the strategy that we've been talking about &#x2013; very careful management of volume versus margin. In a low credit growth environment, it's critical to watch net interest margin, continuation of the strategy of delivering on productivity with our cost-to-income ratio reducing to 45.1% this period and continuing to maintain conservative balance sheet settings with our deposit ratio at 63%, high liquids and a very strong capital level at 10.6%.</p>
          <p>So these things have combined to deliver a profit of 6% growth, which is 4% earnings per share growth and an ROE of 18.1%.</p>
          <p>I'll now ask Ian to talk about the outlook.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks you, David. For some period, we and others have been characterizing the question of the trajectory of the Australian economy is fundamentally a question of confidence that the fundamentals of the economy is good that there people have been paying a lot of attention understandably to events overseas. And there is no doubt that from the period that we've seen, if we think back to six months ago and certainly 12 months ago, at that time we were talking about a lot of uncertainty regarding Greece, Italy, Spain, et cetera and the long-term future of the European Union, there was concern about the leadership transition in China and what that would mean for China's ongoing growth and there was concern about the U.S. election, the associated political instability in the fiscal cliff, et cetera. And in each of those dimensions over the past six months, we have seen a relative period of calm. So in the U.S. growth is not yet accelerating but the overall signs are generally positive and of course, they're through the election. Likewise, in the China, the leadership transition has gone well and it looks like there is some degree of stability there.</p>
          <p>In Europe, I don't think we're any closer to knowing what the long-term plan is, but certainly there has been less volatility around some of the short-term risks and that has created less volatility in the markets and that has helped the environment in which we're operating. We don't have a crystal ball to say whether those trends will continue into the next six months and 12 months. What we would say is our base case is that the volatility will remain lower and as long as the volatility remains lower for a sustained period of time, we will see a slow and steady rebuilding of confidence in both businesses and consumers in Australia. That's our base case.</p>
          <p>Now, of course as a major financial institution, we need to be cognizant of tail risks and those tail risks still exist, I don't need to list what they are, but the base case is that the confidence will slowly but steadily come back. What we would say as probably the biggest unknown out there is the much longer term is more in the three, four and five-year timeframe which is just with the effects of the efforts by central banks overseas to stabilize the economy by injecting large amounts of liquidity, buying public debt, keeping interest rates low, et cetera. The long-term inflationary effect of those effects are obviously unknown and that's something we're going to need to watch carefully as a long-term trend. So overall the base case is that the volatility should remain lower and we will see a slow and steady rebuilding of confidence but we need to be cognizant of the ongoing tail risks.</p>
          <p>What does that mean for us? Well, either way it means we're going to continue our focus on the long-term strategic priorities which I talked about. So the priorities have shown us that if we continue to focus on that small number of simple priorities, execute consistently, we've seen good revenue growth in the context of a subdued environment, we've seen that the focus on productivity has enabled us to keep expenses tight while still investing A$582 million for the future in this half, we've seen stable credit quality because of long-term conservatism, and then a strong ROE notwithstanding significantly stronger capital position. So those are the impacts in this half and as we look ahead, our view is that same strategy is positioning us well for longer-term growth into the future and that's where our focus will firmly remain.</p>
          <p>And, with that, I'll hand over to you, Warwick, to chair the Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much, Ian. Just the normal ground rules if I could repeat them. Can you please wait for the microphone and provide us with your name before you ask a question. No more than two questions at a time, thanks. And again, I think we have media on the phone, so if they could just hold their questions till the media conference this afternoon. Okay? Jon Mott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. This is Jon Mott from UBS. Got a question just on deposits, if I could? So on slide 43 you've got a good chart that you kind of repeat most periods. Just looking at the funding and liquidity and the movement in deposits, you talked up earlier in the presentation the good growth you've seen in transaction account and both on the retail side and the business side, but I note that the customer deposit growth in the period was A$7 billion. If you go back over the last couple of presentations, first half 2012 that was A$21 billion, the second half 2012 it was A$9 billion and now it's down to A$7 billion. Credit growth is subdued at the moment and you are more positive about the outlook for confidence and a pickup in credit growth, yet deposit growth is slowing. Why is deposit growth slowing and is this something that management's focused on, is improving deposit growth, especially when you are going <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:08) deposits?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So why is deposit growth growing &#x2013; slowing. As you would expect there are couple of answers here. Number one is for quite some time people have been observing higher household savings rates at the expense of other asset classes and certainly we would expect to stop seeing some of that revert to more long-term averages.</p>
          <p>In terms of our own performance, we have continued to do what we have said for some time that we would do is manage the margin volume tradeoff very, very carefully. So our deposits are still roughly funded, lending growth in this period. That by the way is not a strategic intent. That is a function of how the markets have been and the deposits have funded the lending growth. Our view remains that there were two critical aspects for deposits on our balance sheet. Number one is liquidity management. And in that sense they need to be seen as an important source of funds but one of a number of source of funds and we pay equal attention to making sure that the weighted average maturity of our long-term wholesale funding is good and diversified. So that's part A.</p>
          <p>As long as we're happy with those overall levels for liquidity purposes, we then do what we will continue to do is to make sure we're not writing deposits that are eroding value for shareholders. And that's something which we don't announce targets for, A, because for comparative purposes it would not be sensible; and B, it's something which we need to be prepared to look at quite dynamically in this kind of environment and we'll continue to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jonathan, I just &#x2013; Jon, I'd just add two headlines to that. Our deposit growth is very close to system, so it's &#x2013; system has certainly slowed. I think that's partly because we're starting to see some funds start to move back into equities, just starting to see that turn. So close to system, but secondly, at a time when retail funding is substantially more expensive than wholesale funding, we would think it would be very silly to be funding all of our growth and <mark type="ph" />  ceasing (35:10) trying to compete in an incredibly hot retail deposit market and hurting our shareholders by taking more expensive funding when there is cheaper funding available in the wholesale markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon, can you just pass it to Jarrod and then to James behind you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jarrod Martin from Credit Suisse. Question just more so on the funding side of things, and perhaps if you could comment on the funding markets in the last month that appear to have the margins have kept down dramatically and we're seeing anywhere as narrow as 50 basis points and we're not seeing anything that's above &#x2013; 100 basis points above swap now and then how that does lead into the term deposit pricing that's probably more an immediate benefit on margins, and if I could get a comment on that.</p>
          <p>And also just to your comment, Ian, on slide 19, referring to the wholesale funding tenor, and the fact that you're still replacing funding that was done cheaper because it was rolling five years ago, whereas if I look at that chart, really the increase in tenor of funding has only come in the last couple of years. And, in fact, if I go back to 2007 and 2008, the tenor of funding done then would have been closer to the three-year mark, which &#x2013; so I sort of challenge you on the comment that you're rolling funding back in 2007 and whether you're actually through that hump to bit more. And then with the rates that we've seen in the last month, the margin benefit from the funding is actually going to be a lot more positive in the second half than I suppose what you're willing to say at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me break this into three parts. I'll take one, then head to David, and then maybe Lyn you can talk about the funding markets. Can I first take the part of your question which talked about the impact of wholesale funding on term deposits? This links with the answer I said to Jon. From the point of view of how we should manage this business prudently, we look at the overall cost of funding in the external markets, how much of cost to funds through the wholesale funding markets and the kind of funding we want. And that obviously gives us some good benchmark against which to measure the price we should be willing to pay for deposit. And that's the fundamental way in which we look at this.</p>
          <p>Now, the differences that we've got to be aware of here, number one, that we're obviously all cognizant of the fact that balance sheet needs to look a certain way; and number two that we're not the price maker in the market, I mean, we're in a very competitive deposit market. And if we have a different view of the price of deposits than others, then the price of deposits may well be bid up for liquidity management purposes beyond what would be logical relative to the cost of the substitute funding. And that's undoubtedly what's happened in the market at the moment. That's what's impacted the funding choices that we're making, and the question of whether that will change in the near to medium term is probably more a question for my peers and the other banks than for me.</p>
          <p>On the question of the tenor, you might talk about that David, and let me talk about the markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the first comment to make is, Commonwealth Bank has always had longer average tenor than our peers and our tenor for long-term funding has always been over three-and-a-half years Jarrod. If you have a look on slide 82 in the pack and we've tried to put a slide to help explain this.</p>
          <p>So on slide 82, on the right-hand side, there is a chart that shows firstly what's happened to our long-term funding cost since 2006, but particularly the finer black line above there is the cost of five-year debt. And as you can see, that cost although it's come down for the first time really since the beginning of the GSE below the long-term average movement in funding, it's still as of today at a higher rate than it was four-and-half-a-years ago. So as we continue to fund primarily out of longer-term debt and indeed I think the average issuance &#x2013; the average tenor of our funding in this six months was 5.2 years. So as we continue to get debt that's averagely five years in duration, and your rolling off debt that's four or five years old, you're still ticking the thing up. And in fact if you look at this chart, our prediction is that if rates stayed where they were today, of course who knows where they're going to go, even if they stayed where they were today, then it would be about 12 months before we hit the peak of the impact of having all this more expensive debt on our balance sheet and we would expect that peak would be about 5 basis points higher than it is today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The other I'd just say there to finish off on that point before Lyn talks, Jarrod, if our weighted average term of the portfolio was not moving and we issue a new funding at 5.3 years by math it must be replacing funding of the same tenor. So that does &#x2013; the point that it's replacing funding priced at a type &#x2013; certain point in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean I'd just emphasize that point Ian made. Obviously when we get a portfolio average even if it's three years we do have some debt that's longer in tenor than three years and typically we are trying to keep &#x2013; spread out those tenors and <mark type="ph" /> brace (40:08) them, so it makes absolute sense that we're replacing it with long-term debt now. And the markets are exceptionally good at the moment, Jarrod, and certainly we're very &#x2013; exceptionally good in January, when we executed over A$6 billion worth of deals. So what we've seen in that time is spreads were 3 to 50 basis points tighter than three months ago and up to 150 basis points tighter than 12 months ago.</p>
          <p>I've been in this job long enough to know that that doesn't always last. So what we do is we try to take advantage of the conditions when they're good. And we still have some more funding to do this year, so we'll have to see how the markets trail out as other events come up; but our best case is that we're hoping that the conditions still remain neutral for this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. James Freeman from Deutsche Bank. Sorry to follow-on on the same theme of margins. But in terms of the term deposits, we have heard from other banks that in December we started to see a softening in the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:00), improvement in the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:02) softening for customers. Just whether you are seeing the same thing through your book. Is that a tailwind that we should be expecting coming into the second half of the year, just given the average duration of a TD only tends to be around that three to four months part. And also, I just actually wanted to get some clarification on the DRP neutralization. Is it the intention to neutralize 100% of the DRP? In the media release, it suggested there may be some issued in stock, just some triggers around that. If there are any that we need to be aware of?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look at the triggers, the intention is to neutralize 100% of triggers. Just that the media release written by a lawyer just covers the fact that if there was a huge market dislocation, we wouldn't continue &#x2013; thank you, David, we wouldn't continue to neutralize the DRP &#x2013; but the intention is certainly to do 100%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the first question, James, in terms of the term deposit pricing, I'd say, yes, in the last couple of months it's probably come off slightly. The challenge in this area, and it goes to the previous questions as well, is: as we see what the system is going to be doing and as each individual financial institution makes its decision as to the optimal liabilities configuration of its balance sheet, their level of competition in deposits might go up and might go down and it's just not &#x2013; it's not predictable. So I &#x2013; we've certainly seen a slight improvement in the last couple of months and I wouldn't call it a trend and I think what we're going to see as we have these discussions every six months is we're going to see quite different patterns of behavior depending on what we talk about. I think our approach to this is going to remain very consistent with where it is today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Spot holds, spot holds, it is a tailwind...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. If you believe that what we've seen in the last couple of months can be extrapolated to a longer-term trend, then it would improve the numbers that you've seen here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But the deposit market has been incredibly volatile. It's a very competitive market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott Manning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott Manning from JPMorgan. I'd like to ask you the same question that I asked you six months ago. I'm sure you can't remember it, so allow me to refresh you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As long as I can remember the answer, that's the most important.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The question is, basically, do you have a line in the sand on your ROE. And I think we've had a few more data points since I first raised the question. First of all, the ROE is down 100 basis points year-on-year, but it's flat half-on-half. The &#x2013; secondly, we've had Westpac come out and reallocate capital and focus on their Basel III hurdle returns and therefore what they want to get out of their business. And you also reallocated capital within your pre-release of the segmental disclosures as well as with a few changes between business units. So with the context of these net interest margin tailwinds coming through, potentially good cost management on the core, I'd say, and the amortization being under control there, markets recovering, provisioning under control, the question still stands, do you have a line in the sand on the ROE and is it around current levels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I hope I'll repeat the answer I gave six months ago, which is no, but let me give you a bit more context. We value the ROE premium to our peers and we think that that's an important part of how people look at the Commonwealth Bank. And if I think about what we aspire to do in the long term, it's to maintain a good level of premium through our peers in terms of return on equity. What we don't believe here as a management team or, indeed, as a board is that lines in the sand and say it won't go below X or Y in environments like what we've learnt over the four or five years is a good way to manage the business.</p>
          <p>What we believe we should do is have a high degree of accountability to front up to you folks every six months and explain the decisions that we've made. But prospectively saying the line in the sand is 18 or 18.5 or 17 or 16.5 and then having to make suboptimal management decisions so we can do what we said we were going to do 18 months ago just isn't a good way to run the business. And genuinely that's how we think about it here; we do not have a line in the sand even internally that we talk about. We manage to optimize the environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That said, without a doubt, the largest single downward force on ROE has been the fact that we've had to continue to increase capital. What you're seeing today is we're not &#x2013; we have stopped increasing capital. So we have stopped that particular thing, 54% higher capital ratio since the GFC [global financial crisis].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike Wiblin, and then I'll go across to Craig.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike Wiblin from Macquarie. Just on page 30, just looking at investments there, looks like it's come off just a little bit, but I wanted to talk a little bit about sort of longer term, the outlook for investment, just in aggregate, do you think it's going to be lower going forward and what might you be as far as using the cash flow? And does it make sense, I guess, given returns until today, I guess, it looked a bit softer, yeah, growth is pretty slow, yeah, pulling back on the CapEx could provide some relief just on a cash basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The obvious point to start your question is the fact we've still got 24% here on core banking and what happens to that. I'm very comfortable &#x2013; and David is in the management team &#x2013; with the level of investment we have in the business at the moment. And the important thing to bear in mind here is, A, we've got this product <mark type="indiscernible" /> (46:27) which is going to require further investment. We've got a <mark type="ph" /> One CommBank (46:34) initiative about bringing the whole of the Group to our customers, which requires investment.</p>
          <p>And on top of all that, our fundamental view is while we've all been focused on all the important issues of the global financial crisis, technology-enabled competition is on an exponential curve and we must be prepared to invest to maintain our competitive advantage and maintain competitives, and we've put all those things together, I expect the levels of investment will remain very similar to where they are today.</p>
          <p>We won't as a management team look to sort of squirrel away a bit more to boost short-term earnings because these investments are long-term programs. And I think we should be prepared to continue to do that to invest for long-term growth. What you won't see is one single major six-year project that's going to come in to replace core banking modernization and the next six years we do get a bit more period-on period flexibility in the investment profile.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. This is Craig Williams from Citi. It's said that success has many fathers, except it seems that CBA's result in share price. But with low economic and credit growth prevailing and strong profitability, your cash flow generation remains extremely strong. So how do you think about managing the situation optimally, given your stock is trading on two times book and no particular abundance of franking credits available to you at that moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, given that you've got a buy on the stock, you get as many questions as you want today. So that's number one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I had to wait a long time to get it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, the short answer, Craig, is our overall view on this is that we're going to maintain the course of the business very much as we've been managing it. It's important in the last slide that &#x2013; of David's presentation talk about managing the environment and we have had to manage to a more volatile environment. But the core of what we've been doing as a management team for the last five or six years is just focusing on executing the same strategy, and we actually believe that strategy has got a lot more juice left in it.</p>
          <p>I start with the point of simply saying we've got one in every three Australian consumers feels we are their main financial institution; we've got 2.9 products per customer, and we can do a lot better than that. And that's sort of one of the number of data points and there's a lot more that we need to do manage that. So we &#x2013; investors, analysts, et cetera, will all form a view of the stock at any given time and form a view of whether it's good value, not good value, et cetera, and that's something you will all do. We're very much focused just on maintaining the management attention on the long-term themes and just keeping on going.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But your capital is going up; you said today that doesn't need to go up any further essentially and your profitability looks like remaining strong. So you're going to continue to have this <mark type="ph" /> excess (49:26) capital problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And what we've shown with the DRP neutralization, we flagged it six months ago that we do need to repeat every period to take a view on capital and we've taken a view on capital. We had the one-off this time which is the Bankwest advanced accreditations that's 30 basis points. But beyond that as we get to this point every year, we've got be &#x2013; and through the period we've got to be prepared to look at our capital number and actually decide is it optimal for the period, that might lead to a DRP neutralization as it has this time, that may or may not next time, but it's something we do need to be prepared to manage pretty actively. If we are sitting here in six months' time and risk weighted assets growth is really taking off again, that will add a different factor into capital management which we'll have to consider at that time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, and then we'll go the phone, and I'll come back to you Victor back down here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Richard Wiles from Morgan Stanley. Ian you've been a CEO for more than a year now. Investors are increasingly interested in your approach to acquisitions. I'm wondering if you could answer or provide some clarity on a few things. Firstly, would you be prepared to do acquisitions outside of retail banking in wealth management, should the two key areas of strength to Commonwealth Bank? Secondly, would you be prepared to do acquisitions outside of Asia-Pacific and would you be prepared to do acquisitions in developed markets? And finally, would you prepared to sacrifice some of that ROE premiums piece in order to enhance your medium term earnings growth prospects?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And fourthly what you are going to buy? Those are good questions. I think overall the approach that all of us here have from the board through the management team is exactly as we've outlined it right from when I first got this question 18 months ago, which is we've got a very disciplined approach to how value is created through M&amp;A that sets a very high bar. The answer to all of your questions would be yes, if we had a acquisition which followed the principles that we talked about. We talked about consistently for the last 18 months which is we can create more value for all of our shareholders through acquiring it than they could for themselves and that's a key, and that requires adding capability.</p>
          <p>Now, when I cast that over the lens of what you were talking about, it is unlikely that we would look a lot beyond in theory, beyond sort of retail and wealth management, which are things that we know well if we were thinking inorganically. And our focus markets that we've talked about for quite some time, I think the principles behind those are markets where we feel we could add value, whether it's organically or inorganically. So none of that's changed. And the response is still the same as it has been for the last year, which is there are a lot of people who think because of this price to book ratio there is a list of sort of 50 things we're looking at any given day we might be buying one of them, that just simply isn't the case, because the bar that we put for successful M&amp;A is very high, A; and B, because what we've seen here, again, is that by sticking to the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:31) we can still continue to do a pretty good job for our shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I'll just follow up. One could argue that with CBA's track record over the last five or six years you could add value to banks in developed markets. Is that a fair conclusion or would you take the view that it's not an attractive strategic direction for the Commonwealth Bank to take?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've worked really hard on things here, a number of areas that I've talked about. And through sustained multi-year effort we think we've managed to improve the business pretty well. When you talk about adding value to the banks in developed markets, let's say the UK or the U.S., et cetera, too often the debate is here is your price to book, here is their price to book, do the numbers and it's a good acquisition. The way we think about it here is that if you believe, for example, we're good at technology or good at services or something like that, you've got to be prepared to put 50 people on a the plane tomorrow, fly them over to the target, have them work on that target for two to three years to transfer the capability into that institution to create the value for the shareholders. So again that's a really high bar. And we don't sit here and say because we've performed okay, our customer satisfaction is okay and we've done some good technology investments that that makes us a logical buyer of big assets in developed markets, because the other bankers in those markets, other management teams are pretty good. They compete hard and they compete well, and we're going to have a pretty good reason for believing that we could outcompete them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I might go to the phones now. Brian Johnson from CLSA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Congratulations on the great result. Just a few questions, if I may? When I have a look in the profit release, which I've got luxury of doing as I sit in my office, I can see that in the slide pack you talk about how the liquidity position is really strong. But when we have a look on page 24 of the result, we can say that actually the cash in government and the semi-government bonds was reduced from A$44 billion down to A$39.8 billion, which presumably would have had a favorable impact on the NIM. Could you give us a feeling on how much of a favorable impact that was when the cash in government bonds were run down, and what's the outlook for that particular component, the liquidity going forward? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And the second one is perhaps a more important one. I think you've had a lot of questions today about drawing lines in the sand about the ROE, lot of questions about the ROE, but when I have a look at slide 79, in your core franchise, which is home loans, you're losing share. In your other called franchise which is household deposits, you're losing share. Are we getting to the point where you pulled the price lever and compete more aggressively?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer the second question, Brian, and then I'll pass over to David on the liquidity question. Obviously the numbers are the numbers and that they show exactly is what you've seen and obviously got to be careful here, whenever when I talk about pricing. What I will say is that we have come through a period particularly over the last couple of years, whereas we talked about our thoughtful approach to balancing share and margin, margin has not been that attractive. And we have decided &#x2013; yet the best way of creating value for our shareholders is to go easier on the price lever obviously and just manage margin well, while focusing number one on our customers and that's been the story of what you see here in these numbers.</p>
          <p>In environments where margin improves and the whole environment, which we're competing is different that can obviously lead to some different decisions. So again it's an example of not saying, we wouldn't let the market share go below A or go below B, but actually saying, we're constantly making a tradeoff here between what's the right way to correct long-term value for our shareholders and as margin starts improving in some of these areas that could obviously result in a strategy, which would reverse some of the trends that you've highlighted. David, you want to talk about the liquidity point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, I guess it's just two points to make about liquidity, particularly the way you're looking at it, Brian. The first one is that yes, we have reduced our liquidity, our surplus liquidity from where it was say this time last year remember in January last year, the markets were extremely volatile. There was a great deal of caution coming into Christmas, and we had really built up substantial levels of liquidity, really just as a precaution. So compared to this time last year, in aggregate we're holding less liquidity, less surplus liquidity than we did, because we just don't believe the markets are as bad and indeed, the answer you heard from Lyn a little earlier about just how good markets have been in January, would give you that indication. The second comment to make is that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>David, sorry, can I just interrupt there, but wouldn't that suggest if the funding environment is so great, you'd be borrowing more and you'd be holding it in cash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as we &#x2013; as I mentioned in the presentation, we have in fact done A$7 billion of funding in January. So we've done A$13 billion through to December; we've done A$20 billion as of today. So that we are holding more cash today than we were at 31 December, just because of the point you make. But at December, we were sort of sitting where I've indicated which is that the liquidity was lower than it was at the time of great volatility in December, the year before.</p>
          <p>The second comment to make is we're going to be a little cautious about looking at the accounting classification of things that count in liquidity. So when you look on page 24 of the MD&amp;A, that's a reference to what's in statutory reporting for accounting purposes. And so what's classified there and what counts &#x2013; what you'd see as liquid assets can be a little different to what accounted for liquid assets for regulatory purposes, but look I'll just hand it over Lyn to give you a little bit more flavor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Brian, I mean, just a couple of comments. First of all, yes, we have raised a reasonable amount of debt in the first month of this year, month and a half, but remember we've also done A$3.9 billion buyback of government guaranteed debt. So that means we don't have that much excess cash sitting on our books. Secondly, in terms of your question around the composition of liquid assets, you can expect that to be fluid over time. Yes, it will go up and down in terms of our level one assets and at level two or above level one assets. That's still a measure of negotiation with the regulators as to what is the desired composition at the end of the day once the new liquidity rules come in, and we can expect to see more clarity of that during the course of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Did this favorably impact the NIM in this half year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A reduction in the holding of more expensive assets inevitably does have a favorable impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But it wasn't 1 basis point, Brian. I would have called it out if it had been a significant impact on this particular half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Matt Davison from Merrill Lynch. Matt, you there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On costs firstly, if we look year-on-year costs were up 3%, staff are down 2%, and recognizing there is about 1% of extra investments, but, Ian, I'm just interested if you feel like you've really shown the efficiency dividends yet from any of that investment and whether you're at a tipping point where you can really change the dynamics around costs excluding amortization?</p>
          <p>And then second question was just relating to the dividend guidance. The second half you talk about it being slightly down. Depending on your definition of slightly, just interested whether this could say you moved towards the top end of your 70% to 80% payout ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe we can take the second question first. No, it's not settling there. The primary reason we've even made that comment, which is atypical for us is because as David and I were sitting with the board yesterday, what we wanted to be very clear about, particularly for the benefit of our retail investors, is that a 20% hike in the dividends for this half isn't indicative of what they can expect in the second half, because not everybody spends a lot of time studying our dividend policy. And we were worried that that might seem to signal to people who rely on the dividend, and that's a very important shareholder base to us. So it's not signaling anything other than the fact that we really care about those retail investors.</p>
          <p>In terms of expenses, I would characterize what you have seen here as a good heightened awareness of expense management and the very early signs of the efficiency dividend. So because of the way that we have approached productivity, this is really a &#x2013; A, it's continuous improvement; and B, it's one of these things where you really start seeing the benefits kind of two years in. I'm really happy with where we've got to to date. The focus on this from my team is extremely high, and I'd say the benefits of that real engineering are only just at the very start. And what you're seeing here is the start of that. But the lion's share of the story here is just good awareness and good approach to expense management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Victor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Victor German from Nomura. First question on capital position, obviously a big improvement in the half. One of your peers who has, which has very similar capital position of around just over 8%, signaled that they would be more comfortable sitting at about 8.5% given the volatility around dividends on quarterly-on-quarterly basis. Are you able to give us an idea whether you are comfortable at your current level or would you want that capital position to shift up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I think, the fact that we're buying back the dividend should be a black-and-white answer to that question, but we indicated when the capital was sitting at 9.8% that we were pretty comfortable with the capital levels. Now that they're sitting at &#x2013; and, of course, part of that was because we knew we had the 30 basis points coming on the Bankwest advanced accreditation. Now that we're seeing 10.6%, we're extraordinarily comfortable. So I think if &#x2013; you should take the DRP neutralization as a pretty black-and-white answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you. The second question, Ian, to you perhaps. You've obviously made a very big investment in IT over the last number of years and you're saying that you are nearing the end of that program. As Brian highlighted earlier, you are still losing market share in your key retail segment and I understand the tradeoff around margin, et cetera. But does this IT platform that you have now give you a sustainable advantage over your peers, which should provide you with ability to actually maintain or grow above market? And have you been disappointed so far that you were not able to grow at system, given your IT advantage, and when do you think that that can close?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The number one issue here and it comes back to the answer to the previous question is we manage the shareholder value and that's what's driven the volume performance and the relative market share and we're very comfortable with it. Now, we keep looking at that period-on-period relative to what the competitive conditions are in the market and the margin environment. So as per my answer to Brian that that might lead to different views given there's a margin environment, but I certainly have no concerns whatsoever about the market share performance historically as you've seen it today.</p>
          <p>In terms of the technology performance, yeah, I remain even more confident than I was when I joined the Steering Committee, of course, six years ago that this is really industry-leading capability and hard to replicate it at the core of the simplicity in real-time banking. It was interesting, one analyst did a review and saying it takes three seconds longer to log on to the Commonwealth Bank website than it does for some of the peers, and that was a difference of &#x2013; yes, a three seconds and we're thinking yes, but you can actually get your payment done 72 hours earlier on the Commonwealth Bank website, so you're maybe willing to tolerate the three seconds it takes you to log on.</p>
          <p>And those things &#x2013; I mean, this all comes down to whether you believe &#x2013; and there are good debates about this &#x2013; that that kind of real-time capability in payments and the customer configured system actually matter. We do. We think we're seeing the benefits of that starting already and we're going to continue to as our people use it even more and we get <mark type="ph" /> conditional (01:04:46) lending on there, et cetera. And if you believe that, you will understand that it's going to take five or six years for anybody starting today to replicate that fully. You can replicate parts, but not replicate it fully.</p>
          <p>The views of some of our peers are that actually that isn't a source of competitive advantage and they will tell you why they believe that isn't the case, but we stand firmly behind the view that those investments are great long-term investments. And the fact that we are now talking about them, given all the challenges of putting in that capability almost in the past, i.e., not, if we pull it off when we do it but now that it's in, I think that puts us in a great spot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you expect that to deliver market share benefits or just cost benefit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The combination of benefits was always going to be some increased customer preference, some better ability to manage it at margins because, for example, you've got a ability to price down at the individual branch levels instead of 1,022 price points very quickly and some benefits from operating expenditure. And the way in which we would balance those in any given period of time will mirror the overall view that we've got about the attractiveness of the market at the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think we've got to be very careful about just the market share thing, because we can grow market share, we've seen other banks able to grow market share by throwing price, by throwing shareholder value. We can do that at the drop of a hat, but what we're trying to do is balance the interests of our shareholders with the interests of our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say just to tie off that point, because it's an important one and Brian mentioned, I mean we would be crazy as a major institution with our footprint not to look at market share. So I think the question about, say, here is the trend in the numbers, what do you think about, is very legitimate because we need to &#x2013; that's something that we do keep looking at and keep focusing on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>T.S. Lim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>T.S. Lim from Bell. Simple question for you, Ian. On a scale of 1 to 10, how would you rate these results and why?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would rate them at a 6 out of 10 because I'm very happy, but I would never rate anything about &#x2013; above about a 7.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He is a very hard marker.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are there any more questions in the room? Craig, do you want to have &#x2013; you have another question, Craig, because I've got one on the phone. So I'll go to the phone and then I'll come back and if anyone's got any more questions they might have. Brian Johnson is back on the phone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ian, I'd like to pose a hypothetical situation, which definitely will happen in the next sort of while and I'd like to hear what your response is. Okay, you're sitting on the 7:30 report being interviewed. The RBA has just chopped interest rates by 25 basis points; you've chopped them by 20 basis points for the reasons that you've announced here today. During the day, Hockey [Joe Hockey] has come out and said, oh, geez, those banks are bastards and we're going to have an inquiry into the banking system. Wayne Swan has come out, geez, we're going to have one as well. What is your response?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's not a hypothetical, Brian; that's a history lesson, that one is ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I've got to tell you, even as I sit here today, the Greens have already come out and said, "CBA, what a pack of bastards." So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In all seriousness, there are a couple of answers to the question. Number one is, we're a major financial institution and we have to expect the scrutiny. So that's number one. And you won't ever hear us complaining about the fact that there are people who have these views.</p>
          <p>Number two, we need to understand that the fact that they're &#x2013; particularly in economies where people have found it a bit harder <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:08:24) that there are people who look at interest rate movement, don't exactly understand how our liabilities are configured in the balance sheet, because we wouldn't expect them to, are struggling with their mortgage and look at this kind of profit and think it's too much.</p>
          <p>And I completely understand why those people think the way they do and that it's a legitimate observation. Our job, unfortunately, is we've just got to keep focused on the right balance between their needs, deposit holders' needs, and the needs of 800,000 Australians who own the shares directly and 1 million more through funds and realize at any given time, one or more of those groups of stakeholders is going to hate us. And that's just life running a big institution and what I'd like to think will happen, if I'm under that situation, is what's happened before, which is just we'll take the heat and continue to focus on what the right long-term balance would be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, Ian, the second time they chop interest rates and you do it again during the election campaign, will you be having the same conversation or will you just not have cut?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You always in these kinds of roles have a responsibility to front to people who are genuinely asking questions in the public interest and doing it the right way. So we're never going to hide behind this. Obviously, more people want to talk about these sorts of things than we've got time to talk about it, but I don't think this debate is going away anytime soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more questions in the room? Here <mark type="inaudible" /> (1:09:45-1:09:50)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Phil Parker, PAML. Just looking at page 36, I think if you look at the breakdowns, you had 32% of the market share <mark type="ph" /> and high lines (1:10:08) of the whole big four, and that's still 32%. So notwithstanding that you've grown &#x2013; that it's gone from 58% of the total to 77% of the total. Can you just sort of comment &#x2013; so I don't &#x2013; but the market share thing is not really an issue. So could you just say where you think that's going vis-&#xE0;-vis, the brokers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because clearly that who has lost the market share and you're going to work with them from now or what's the story there, because it's a massive increase in a relatively short space of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, if you look at the RBA numbers, I think, for the period ended December, you are definitely starting to see an increase in the activity of the <mark type="ph" /> mid-tier (1:10:36) banks beyond the majors. So that's up and they grew ahead of the average of the major banks, and that supports the view we've said all along, is that this is a competitive market and that what we're seeing now is greater activity.</p>
          <p>In terms of the third-party market, it's still about 38% of our inflows in the mortgage book. Our view fairly as an organization, we've had it consistently for the last five or six years is: there is a proposition that third parties offer customers which is: this is a complicated product; we'll help you sort through the best offering, and we'll do it without charging you; and that proposition is not going away. So we will continue to work with brokers. Obviously, we always like to think that the level of the service people can get through our proprietary offering is going to be so good that they won't want to go there, but the reality is a chunk of people are always going to want to and we need to be prepared to be good in that market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So suppose I can envisage that you'll still maintain that 30%, 32% of the big four. Do you think that 77% of the total markets are now going to come back towards that figure of years ago or is that gone forever?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think &#x2013; I mean, I can't tell you what the number is going to be, but the trajectory of the major banks here of the overall home loan market, if their best case is right, funding conditions are as they were going to be, volatility lower, et cetera, over time you would expect that to start edging back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just a second question, if I may? Do you &#x2013; or probably in the data here, but what's the split between your deposits for the retail world versus the commercial world?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, we've got &#x2013; well, the split of retail deposits is there on page 37. The split between our overall deposits ....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You can see the market share &#x2013; the question is market shares on page 79 of the pack, there is an analysis...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's more a dollar question. What that split is in dollars?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is in overall dollar number. We'll leaf through it and come back to you on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Victor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to ask you &#x2013; I wanted to come back to the previous question and ask on IT platform. To what extent is it scalable and going back to Richard's question on M&amp;A, to what extent are you able to utilize your IT advantage in potential M&amp;A opportunities, and that would be that angle that you can add as an acquirer that the company doesn't have currently.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It is scalable but it's scalable through people. So the real complexity of the core banking program is, A, you've got a whole lot of people who need to be really adept at actually doing the coding; B, you've got to have a really strong capability in actually integrating the new capability with legacy systems; and C, you've got a have a lot of people in the business who know how to exploit the capability. So those parts are all scalable, but they &#x2013; going back to my answer to Richard's question, all revolve around a bunch of people who know how to do it. So we've been very thoughtful over the core banking &#x2013; at the time of the core banking modernization program. Michael and his team have done a very good job on this on codifying everything we do. So when we do a big migration of retail deposit customers from a legacy platform on the SAP, we've got every step of how to test that, how to migrate them, how to follow-up from it very carefully coded, but it's still never going to be a matter of just emailing those instructions to a bunch of people in the new bank and saying, go do this. So the same principle applies, which is you <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:14:30) cadre of very experienced people who you're prepared to lift out of the business without impacting continuity in this business seems to the new institution and work on that for a protracted period of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On that note, we might wind it up now. So thank you, Ian; thank you, David; and thank you, ladies and gentlemen. Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>