<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1364634" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-08</date>
    <companies>
      <company>10261</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Warwick Bryan, Executive General Manager, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Ralph Norris, Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">David Craig, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Jarrod Martin</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Craig Williams</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Ben Koo</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Brian Johnson</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Alden Toevs</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Johan Vanderlugt</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Victor German</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Matthew Davison</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">James Freeman</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Richard Wiles</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Brett Le Mesurier</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">T.S. Lim</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Scott Levine</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="corprep">Lyn Cobley</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and welcome to the Colonial Centre for the presentation today of Commonwealth Bank of Australia's results for the half-year to 31 December 2010. Today's presentation will follow the normal CBA routine, which is Ralph will speak to you quickly, followed by David Craig who'll run you through some more details. At the end of that I'll come back and we'll open up for questions. So, thank you for coming. And welcome, Ralph.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thanks very much, Warwick, and welcome to you all here this morning. The Commonwealth Bank today has reported another sound financial results, which &#x2013; in what remains a challenging environment. Once again, the resurge, I think, is testimony to the consistent, disciplined and effective execution of our strategy highlighted by continued high levels of investment in the business over the past six months. Whilst the operating environment remains a challenging one, we're cautiously optimistic about the outlook for calendar 2011. And we remain confident about the Group's ability to continue to deliver superior returns for our shareholders. Turning now to the result itself. For the six months to 31 December, 2010 cash net profit after-tax was up 13% to $3.335 billion. Return on equity increased by 70 basis points to a healthy 19.2%.</p>
          <p>Cash earnings per share was up 12% to $2.14, and we declared an interim dividend of $1.32 per share, up 10% on the corresponding period. As we flagged earlier in the year, operating performance was flat on the prior corresponding period with revenue growth constrained by subdued system credit growth, elevated funding costs, and intense competition in key markets. The integration of Bankwest continued to progress smoothly and Bankwest and ASB delivered greatly improved results.</p>
          <p>Pleasingly, we've maintained our record of strong cost discipline with cost growth held around CPI once again during this period, notwithstanding the continued high levels of strategic investment.</p>
          <p>I like to take a moment to reflect on this result in the context of the size and scale of this organization. On any measure Commonwealth Bank is a large organization. We have 45,000 staff worldwide, 37,000 of them-based here in Australia. Domestically and overseas, we have 13 million customers and we operate in 12 countries. As of the 31st of December we had total assets of $650 billion. Our cash profit for the six-month period of $3.34 billion equates to a return on assets of around 1%, and this has been a consistent outcome over many years. Our ROI in 2005 was 1.1%, but this group figure is inflated by our fund management operations, which earn income without recourse to the balance sheet. This little return compares to a median ROI of around 7% for the 20 largest Australian companies, excluding banks. Yet, we are a profitable organization, but not excessively so.</p>
          <p>The Group's journey to being number one in customer satisfaction does remain on track. Everyone in the organization is determined to achieve this outcome. And we've come a long way since we launched the strategy in early 2006 and we have more satisfied retail customers than the combined total of two of our major bank competitors. Financial products per customer have increased by over 20% to 2.64, the equal highest of the peer group. In Business Banking, we've made significant progress and are ranked equal first amongst the major banks on customer satisfaction across the total market.</p>
          <p>In Wealth Management, First Choice has now consistently rated number one on satisfaction amongst financial advisors. Clearly, there will be and have been challenges along the way, and we never expected the journey to be a smooth one. The decision to increase the home loan standard variable rate in November last year was one such challenge. While this has clearly had an impact on our customers, this was absolutely the right decision in the context of a sustained elevated funding costs that have been and continued to be faced across the industry.</p>
          <p>We need to manage this business in a sustainable manner, both for our customers and also, for our shareholders. We remain pleased with the significant progress we've made as an organization and are more determined than ever to achieve our goal and vision of being Australia's finest financial services organization through excelling in customer service.</p>
          <p>Our commitment for this strategy is evidenced by the fact that we have consistently invested in the long-term future of this business, notwithstanding the short-term challenges we inevitably face. Once again, in the past six months, we've invested over $0.5 billion in key strategic initiatives. The investment is specifically targeted to progress our strategic agenda for our business banking growth strategy, the revitalization of their branch network, to our core banking modernization program, as well as a range of targeted productivity and growth initiatives. And what is particularly pleasing is that these investments are delivering real productivity improvements across the organization.</p>
          <p>One area of investment, which doesn't get a lot of exposure is that of Asia, where we've been pursuing a considerate, prudent and focused growth strategy over many years. For several years, we've operated the largest foreign network in Indonesia and we hold 20% stakes in two City Commercial Banks in China, the maximum foreign ownership allowed in that country.</p>
          <p>Over the past 12 months, we've continued to make further inroads, including the launch of our BoComm Life joint venture in China in January, and the opening of our Shanghai branch in March, the opening of the first CBA branch in India in August, the acquisition of a 15% shareholding in Vietnam International Bank in September, and the expansion of our existing networks in other countries with a further 10 branches opened in Indonesia and 43 new ATMs installed across Indonesia and Vietnam.</p>
          <p>And just a week ago, we completed the capital injection for the first bank in our County Banking Initiative in China. Our first County Bank is scheduled to open by the end of this month, as Jiyuan Henan in China, and looking forward we will continue our prudent targeted approach to selectively expanding our presence in key markets throughout Asia.</p>
          <p>The Group has made excellent progress during the half year with the continuing rollout of our core banking system. All of our retail customer information, term deposits, savings, and transaction accounts now operate live on the new SAP platform. This represents in excess of 10 million customer accounts, which makes it the largest banking migration in the Australian history.</p>
          <p>The benefits of real-time transactions are already being seen in customer service improvements and I'm receiving many positive comments from our customers on the real-time functionality of our new systems. We'll be hosting a detailed briefing on core banking in March to give you more insight into the capabilities and benefits of this new system. And I'm sure you'll be impressed with what the high levels &#x2013; of the high levels of functionality and flexibility that will be on display.</p>
          <p>As we moved through the upgrade, it became clear that there are more opportunities to add capabilities and functionality over and above what we initially scoped. There are also some areas of added complexity, which pooled together, extend the program by about nine months. We're using the opportunity to ensure the new system is multi-entity enabled, which will make it faster and cheaper to ultimately roll out to offshore banking businesses. And our current estimate of the total cost of the program is $1.1 billion. With the further benefits noted above, the overall business case and net present value remain largely unchanged.</p>
          <p>Finally, before turning to the outlook, I wanted to talk about a few broader issues. The recent floods in Queensland and Victoria have been devastating to the affected communities. And in some cases it may take years to recover from the losses involved. The broader impacts on the Queensland, Victorian and Australian economies are not yet clear, with estimates, however, of up to around 0.5% of total GDP. From the Commonwealth Bank's perspective, I've been extremely pleased with the response of our staff in dealing with the crisis as it impacted our customers in these communities.</p>
          <p>It will obviously take some time to fully assess the impact, but we remain committed to providing every assistance we can to our customers. As a demonstration of this commitment, we recently announced a package of measures to assist those customers affected by this crisis. The package includes a $50 million compassionate assistance fund to CommInsure Home Insurance customers who are not covered under their policy for riverine flood. Over and above this, CommInsure has already made $8 million of ex-gratia payments towards insurance customers in Queensland and Victoria.</p>
          <p>We've also set up a Commonwealth Bank Community Group Flood Assistance Fund of $5 million, which we distributed to not-for-profit community groups who have suffered damage or loss as a result of the floods. These measures are on top of direct cash donations made by the group of approximately $2 million, and we've also collected donations from staff and customers totaling over $44 million to-date.</p>
          <p>Further, we've set aside $1 billion in funding for our business and Agribusiness customers affected by the floods. Customers can seek special funding to renew overdraft facilities or increase limits and will pay no establishment fee, nor will they be charged any interest for the first three months of a loan.</p>
          <p>The Group has assisted many businesses and personal customers through the activation of our new Emergency Assistance Packages and our specialist teams will continue to work with customers on a case-by-case basis to help them overcome the difficulties they face. The Group has a strong tradition of supporting the community through a wide range of charitable donations, sponsorships and other activities, and I'm pleased that they've once again been able to demonstrate this commitment through these measures. It's times like these that financially strong organizations that have the capacity to support communities in need.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the outlook. While the Australian economy continues to perform well, and other advanced economies are showing signs of improvement, the domestic banking industry still faces a number of headwinds. Underlying credit growth does remain subdued with both consumer and corporate confidence fragile. Competition is intense with depositors benefiting from historically high margins, while also &#x2013; funding costs also remain at elevated levels.</p>
          <p>As we enter the 2011 calendar year, the residual impacts of the global financial crisis are still being felt, particularly in the Northern Hemisphere economies and this could weigh on the pace of global economic recovery.</p>
          <p>Elsewhere, the strength in some of the emerging economies is generating inflationary pressures and we've obviously seen that this morning or overnight, with the interest rate news in China.</p>
          <p>The outlook for the domestic economy remains positive, as the resource sector continues to outperform. However, some of our customers operating in other sectors of the economy are finding conditions more challenging.</p>
          <p>Against this backdrop, I'm cautiously optimistic about the outlook for the group for the balance of the 2011 financial year. We're well placed to benefit from the improvement that will come in consumer and corporate confidence, and the increased level of economic activity, which should accompany that recovery.</p>
          <p>Thank you. And I will now pass over to David Craig, who'll go through the finance details in a bit more detail. So, thank you. David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well thank you, Ralph, and good morning, everybody. Nice to see all these familiar faces in the audience again.</p>
          <p>As Ralph as just said, our cash net profit after tax for the period was $3.34 billion, 13% up on the corresponding period last year and 6% up on the last six month performance. Operating income was up 2% on the corresponding period and 5% on six months ago and expenses are very much under control, up just 3% on the prior year and 2% over the last six months. So, that's led to a relatively flat operating performance year-on-year and 7% up on the half year. All of you need to remember there are three more working days in this half, compared to the prior half.</p>
          <p>Of course, there's been a significant turnaround as was expected in impairment expense with a 48% drop year-on-year, although it is slightly up on the half, and the reason for that is that we've taken the conservative stance of setting aside a special management overlay $100 million against the impact of flooding across the country.</p>
          <p>Turning to statutory profit, and again, it's the usual items that appear as reconciliation between cash net profit after-tax and statutory profit. The major item to note here is that there's an almost $400 million turnaround in hedging and AIFRS volatility. This is the marking-to-market of hedges that relate to future trades over our long-term debt, and of course, with the substantial appreciation of the Australian dollar over the last 12 months that led to those mark-to-markets turning around.</p>
          <p>Turning to individual business unit profitability, and as Ralph has said, it's been a very solid performance across the board. Our Retail Bank margins have been impacted as we've been advising by 10 basis points year-on-year downwards, but deposit balances are up 11%, and the cost-to-income ratio in that business is now 39%. So, overall, Retail Bank's operating performance up 2%.</p>
          <p>Institutional Banking and markets has been impacted by two factors this period; the continuing deleveraging of big corporate accounts and a reduction in markets income due to less hedging going on for our customers, both in interest rates and foreign currencies. So, that has seen reduced markets income, but costs in this business are very much under control.</p>
          <p>Business in Private Banking has had another very good result. Our Private Banking revenue up 10%. Our costs again very much under control, up just 3%. Has CommSec in it, as many of you would know, stock broking businesses have been affected by reduced activity in the markets, and so commissions in CommSec are down, but overall, cash net profit after tax in Business and Private Bank is up 15%.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management has had a very strong performance, and particularly the Global Asset Management Business had a very strong performance, and I think this is underwritten by the fact that fully 81% of all of the funds managed are outperforming their benchmark over a five-year period. So, whether you look at one, three, or five years, the performance of those funds is extraordinarily high, and I think that's driving the increase in funds that are being managed there, which in turn is driving income, up 6%, and again, costs very much under control, up just 3%.</p>
          <p>New Zealand has seen a predicted rebound with income up 13%. The main driver here is the shift between fixed rate home loans and variable rate home loans, which has driven margins up, and in turn, a reduction in loan impairment expense. So, cash net profit after-tax is up 58% in New Zealand. And pleasingly, we've also seen a very strong performance from Bankwest, although, of course, it's not immune to the same margin pressures that we're experiencing across the rest of the Bank with its margins down 10 basis points. But costs continuing to decline in that business are down another 3%, and the cost to income ratio is now down to 54%, and is very much on a trajectory heading lower. So, operating performance in that business is up 10%, and its contribution to cash net profit after tax is up over $200 million for the period.</p>
          <p>So, looking at operating income, which year-on-year was up 2%, funds &#x2013; and insurance income was up pretty much in line with the underlying funds under administration, balance is up 5%. Trading income is a bit higher this period for a couple of reasons. Firstly, a change in mix in the treasury income between net interest income and other banking income. This is obviously we're looking at net interest income here. And also, because of appreciation on credit value adjustments on counterparty risk, which is in effect reversal of those countercyclical impacts we saw during the GFC.</p>
          <p>Other banking income is down 3%, and that's because commissions, and this is again mainly CommSec, are down $49 million, or 5%, and lending fees, so this is the exception fees, this is the residual run-off of that as a result of reducing fees for our customers. But, of course, the main story is around net interest income and this is a volume/margin story with volume up 5% and margins down 3%. And I want to spend a little bit of time looking at this volume/margin story.</p>
          <p>Firstly, on the volume side, in the home loan sector, it was clear during last year when margins were extremely compressed that it was sensible not to grow too fast in this market, and in particular, what we did was concentrated on high credit quality in this business, and so the loans that we did advance and we obviously advanced many, were at the high credit end, and then with the interest rate rise, we're now pushing our foot back down on the floor, so to speak, in home loans, and you'll see, I believe, home lending volumes at system in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>In Business Lending, again, Business and Private Bank continuing to surge strongly here with SME lending up 8.8%. Now, we think that's roughly quadruple market growth. We think market growth is 1% to 2% in that space, and so that's a very good performance and we're continuing to gain market share in that segment of the business.</p>
          <p>You can see the decline in institutional banking markets, which I referred to earlier, as big clients are de-leveraging. The Bankwest story is very much an intentional one. We've quite deliberately got out of low credit quality lending in this space, and on an annualized basis, impact our reduction in the targets low credit quality space is well over 20%, but we've grown market share in the stronger credit space in Bankwest. So, overall, you can see that the CBA group is a bit below system. In household deposits, we've grown strongly, and in line with the system at 12.2%. But in business deposits, we quite deliberately didn't grow that system. You can see a system extraordinary high at 20.6%, but there is a lot of hot money moving around in business market and that hot money not only carries with it a requirement to carry offsetting liquid assets, but also it's just either no or negative margin and we're not in the business of profitless growth, so we quite deliberately held back there, and as you'll see a little later, notwithstanding that, we've more than funded our whole growth for the period out of deposits.</p>
          <p>Turning to the margin story, and I think this is a continuation of a trend that we've seen with asset pricing up, obviously, particularly on the back of the home loan increase in November, but funding costs outstripping that on a year-on-year basis. The interesting point here is that at a Group level, New Zealand has contributed 3 basis points improvement in margin, and that is equivalent to 28 basis points in New Zealand. So, that's the effect of people shifting from fixed rate loans to variable rate loans, which has really boosted group NIM for this period. So, overall, our underlying NIM is up 1 basis point on the period, on a six-month period, and then this AIFRS volatility that adds another three.</p>
          <p>Looking at that across the last three periods and at a Group basis, what you're seeing on the top here and I've deliberately called out the impact of AIFRS volatility because, again, this is very much impacted by the way hedging is viewed and ineffective hedges get &#x2013; which were basically swapped, get reclassified out of net interest income into other banking income, and so that artificially boosts the stated net interest income. And so I've deliberately shown you the impact of that, and you can see that the underlying Group NIM, as I mentioned, is up 1 basis point, and interestingly the Australian net interest income is down 2 basis points, and that's across the offsetting impact of New Zealand coming to the rescue this period.</p>
          <p>Turning to costs, and costs really are very much under control. As Ralph pointed out, we've really continued to boost investment in the business and that's added $81 million to our cost base in the period, and when you back that out our underlying costs are up just 1.4% for the period.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the impairment expense story, and by the Group level in the left hand graph you can see that our impairment expense is down from 55 basis points in December to 28 basis points in June and 24 basis points 23:34 in December. And then you can see the 4 basis points of overlay to do with the $100 million that we provided for the floods.</p>
          <p>Looking at the top right hand graph, you can see that consumer provisioning is down from 23 to an underlying 14 and that's probably pretty much back to normal, and in the corporate space from 54 down to 44. So, the trend is continuing. In the case of the corporate book I think it will be a slow runoff of the old problem accounts.</p>
          <p>Turning to the balance sheet, and you can see that the orange bars in the top &#x2013; in the left hand graph are our management overlays and that actually increased in this period from $1.19 billion to $1.21 billion, so that includes, obviously, the $100 million of our flood overlay. But also, we've retained our economic overlays at this stage as well, says we're still consciously optimistic, but we're not yet ready to release those overlays. But the other bars in that graph, the blue, are reducing and that's because the underlying credit quality of the book is improving, and as the credit quality improves the collective provision reduces. You can see from the right hand graph that we remain very much at the most provided end of the market.</p>
          <p>This is a scorecard of how we are going across credit, and I think it tells a pretty clear picture. The top left hand graph is our consumer arrears, and whether you look at CBA or Bankwest, our consumer arrears are trending down across the board.</p>
          <p>The top right hand graph shows you what's happening to our business book, our risk rated portfolios, and this is a graph that shows the ratio between upgrades and downgrades, and you can see where the GFC hit, and you can see much more particularly within the last quarter, upgrades outnumbered downgrades by 1.6 to 1, so very much a turnaround story. And that obviously guides the bottom left hand graph, troublesome exposures, down both in Bankwest and in CBA, and now continues to drop. And the new impaired assets in the bottom right hand graph are also down. As I've explained before, the total impaired assets, which is the last bucket that problem accounts go through, it always takes a long while for insolvencies to work their way through, so it will be a while before we see that reduce dramatically, but nonetheless I think the signs are extremely good that the cycle is improving.</p>
          <p>I mentioned earlier about the deposit funding and here you can see that the $12 billion growth in deposits more than funded the growth in our balance sheet, and indeed we retired $3 billion of wholesale debt during the period. At this stage, we are now 60% deposit funded, up from 56% a year ago.</p>
          <p>Turning to capital, and again, it's a story of strong growth. Tier 1 capital is a very conservative 9.71% under the Australian Basel II APRA measures and that's equivalent to 13.5% on a globally consistent U.K. FSA basis.</p>
          <p>We've also, obviously, been looking at and talking to APRA Basel III, and on a common equity basis, and our common equity on a Basel III fully harmonized basis looks like it ran 9%, which is clearly well up on the 7%. We're continuing our discussions with APRA around how they're going to interpret the capital rules, and so we'll wait and see exactly what the local measure turns out to be.</p>
          <p>So, let me summarize. I think it's been a period of really good progress. Core banking, the rollout of that &#x2013; the fact that 10 million customers have been converted across and that we now have deposits and transactions in real-time, it is an excellent step for this particular period. Profit is up 13%, costs are very much under control, but we are continuing to invest. Funding costs are obviously continuing to rise and that's put pressure on margins, particularly in Australia where the Australian margins are down 2 basis points, but the Group margins are up one as a result of some repricing or re-changing in New Zealand.</p>
          <p>Bankwest has done well. It's recovering strongly and that's seen our underlying impairments, although we've taken a conservative step of setting aside $100 million for the floods. Our capital is extremely strong at 9.71% and our funding is also very strong with 60% deposit funding. So, our balance sheet is in extremely strong position, ready poised for growth when the market turns around. So, it's a quick overview. I'll now ask Warwick to come up and take questions. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David. Just a couple of ground rules, first of all. Can you please wait for the microphone and identify yourself before your question. If initially we could just run with two questions per person, and then I'll come back if we've got some more time. We'll start in the room, and then go to the Web, and the phones. Finally, I understand there's a fair amount of media online. I appreciate if I could leave a few questions for the media conference at two this afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. Jonathan Mott from UBS. Got a question on slide 33, which is the volumes chart now that you put up, and talked about quite briefly. But I wanted to explore that, especially the home loan fundings, which really ticked up in November and December. Now, obviously, that's the same time that you've reprised the mortgage book. So, it looks to me quite unusual to see the volumes to really surge after that and I think you touched on it that you are really focusing on the high quality products, and now I think you've said that you're putting your foot down. So, if you could just elaborate on that what do you mean? Are you actually changing the underwriting standards of your mortgage book from here, where you're sort of going more to the high OBR. Have you changed discount rates, or this is kind of a line in the sand that you're not prepared to lose any more mortgage market here, given one of your competitors has been a little bit more aggressive than you have?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon, it's fair to say that it's all of the above. I think you've pointed the fact that there's obviously quite a lift-off in that last quarter. A lot of that is &#x2013; obviously that's funding, and that means that those applications were processed earlier so they would have been in the first quarter of this financial year that they would have into be in the system, and so we've seen obviously a pick-up on that. There's no doubt that during November we did have a softer level of applications on the back of the theory around a 20 basis points increase in our SBR. But, I'm pleased to say that we had our base month for the calendar 2010 in applications during December, so December was actually surprisingly very strong.</p>
          <p>Now, if we look at the breakdown of the application approvals, the area where we had a significant reduction last year was in the area of first-time buyers. Traditionally, in the past, we've run it around 15% or 16% of our application approvals being in that particular segment. And in fact, that got up as high as 25%, 30% in the early part of 2009 on the back of the Stimulus. If we look at the last year, last year of those approvals, dropped from around 15% to 16% to 10%, and that was on the back of a tougher credit criteria, and certainly, we had looked at a lot of the issues related to the storm situation, which saw us revise some of our lending criteria on the back of that, but not solely because of that, and certainly, with the market obviously getting choppy, I think it was very prudent for us to take a more conservative approach to the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And given that <mark type="inaudible" /> how do you expect your competitors to react to this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that the market is obviously going to continue to be a competitive one. Certainly, we have a number of initiatives obviously for the year ahead, and certainly, I think some of the work that we're doing in core banking is going to assist us here as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jarrod Martin from Credit Suisse. Just on the margin side, again, the 3 basis points from New Zealand or the 20 &#x2013; equal that 28 basis points at the New Zealand level. Could you talk about a bit more of the drivers of that? What proportion of the portfolio moved from fixed to variable that pushed the margins up? How much further that's got to go, or is there a chance that that reverses back, I just want to understand a bit more about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think New Zealand &#x2013; New Zealand has typically been a fixed rate market over the last several years. What we've seen in more recent times is the fact that obviously the OCR in New Zealand has remained low. It's been down at around actually 0.75% and the Reserve Bank has kept it there for well over a year. As a result of that obviously the market is pricing an increase in that forward curve and we got fixed rate loans, and so we're seeing the situation with fixed rate loans, they've started to move up quite significantly as far as their price is concerned. And, variable rate loans have a significantly higher margin historically than they have had in the past, and so we have a situation of the moment where there's been a significant move on new loans and rollover of fixed rate loans. And fixed rate loans, typically in New Zealand have been of a two to three-year duration, and so that means on a 12-month period you're getting around 40% of the book reprising, as well as your new loans coming to the book as well. So, I would expect that over the next half there'll be a further improvement, but nowhere near as dramatic as the improvement we're seeing on this fairly long period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have any sort of numbers around what proportion now are flowing into variable business sector?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It used to be 80:20 and I think it's now 50:50.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can I just push with the second question. They talk about Core Banking Modernization, and the expenses around that. Ross, you're going to hate me for asking this question, but do you, A still sticking to the sub-35% cost-to-income ratio in RBS by the end of the project? Has that been extended out in terms of timeframe, just some of those original metrics that Ross has to deliver?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He has signed in blood, so it's good to remind him of that. But we're looking at that in the 2012-2013 timeframe and certainly, we really want to give you a good opportunity to see exactly what we're doing in that regard and that's why we are scheduling the presentation in March to show you some of the tremendous benefits that are going to flow from this new &#x2013; from what we currently have implemented.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That wasn't a definitive yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, the answer is that's absolutely the target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the question at the end of the day, Jarrod, is when will credit cards just grow, because clearly you can't &#x2013; it's a factor of both things. So, we need some credit growth to support that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Craig?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Craig Williams from Citi. You've achieved a 19.2% ROE, and this resulted historical average credit costs, probably 40% below where you're currently charging off at through the P&amp;L we estimate. So, you've got about $1 billion of overlays on your balance sheet. So, the return on assets is not particularly special as you pointed in your presentation slide at 1%, and therefore, you're gearing in the business is hard to achieve that sort of ROEs. Can you talk about the expectations for gearing in your business given the regulatory challenge, not just Basel III, but also conglomerates and business mix changes you're anticipating over the next few years, and the prospects for Group ROE exceeding 20% within the next couple of years, which I would have thought looks pretty good from here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dave, would you like to handle it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think on the gearing, we're in the same sort of boat as you are. I think Craig, we're not absolutely certain what the final rules will be and we're waiting for those. We feel we're pretty well set in terms of gearing that certainly all that we're hearing so far would suggest that from a capital point of view we're about right. But we have to wait for that to be affirmed. So, I'd accept your point then if the capital is going to stay steady where it is now and with economic climate improving, you would like to think that there might be a slight improvement in return over time as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you just pass it to Ben Koo, just behind you, Craig.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Ben Koo from Goldman Sachs. Just a question actually on slide 58. I think it is &#x2013; it just shows CBA's position versus peers in terms of the products per customer. The two areas, which you'd expect CBA to be quite strong is deposits <mark type="inaudible" /> but mortgages and credit cards, I would have thought given CBA's strength in the retail business that you'd actually be stronger in that versus peers, but you're actually weaker with fewer products per customer versus peers. Is that an area that you want to focus on in terms of getting back to the top of peers products per customer, and if so is there &#x2013; how do you expect to fund that over time given that you've already got very strong deposit share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think the situation comes down to the demographics of our customer base and certainly, we have a more diverse customer base than some of our competitors and particularly in the customers that have less in the way of financial assets. So, that does have a degree of moderating of our number of products, particularly in the mortgage area in our book, so it's really a customer mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So no change to that <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, over time, I mean, as Australians become more affluent, then more people move up into that part of the market. So, we would expect to see that improve over time, but this is something that takes time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I might just go over to the phones, and then come back into the room. Brian Johnson from CLSA. Hey, Brain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Just a quick question. If you have a look on page 47 of the result, you'll see that the new and increased impaired assets coming through were $2.1 billion, which I appreciate is well down than what it was in the second half, which is still very elevated. Can we get a profile of where that very high level of new impaired assets are coming from? So, it's on page 47 not 46 of the actual results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, what I'll do, Brian, is I'll ask our Chief Risk Officer, Alden Toevs, if he would to like to make a comment on that. Alden?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, it's Alden. The location of the impairment in &#x2013; has been more in the IB&amp;M space than in the BPB. So, we continue to see some moderately large credits getting into the final sort of the tail end of their journeys in the sense of migrating from troublesome to impaired, and they're the predominant cause for that. If you look at another chart that David referenced, the upgrade-downgrade chart, you see that &#x2013; and if you look beneath &#x2013; into the credits that would be in BPB space, for example, and the credits that are in the sort of weak, but performing category, you see a very strong improvement in those performance, and so this is really a kind of residual issue from credits from the global financial crisis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And so these are &#x2013; whereas the other banks are calling out problem loans comes through in the smaller, and for CBA, this is just these residual single known corporates that we're seeing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>More of that. Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's all very fine. I'll just add. I mean, this is &#x2013; what we're seeing is the normal cyclical slideshow. In other words, we held collective provisions against these sorts of accounts. As some of them have had problems they may go into specific, which is what you're seeing here, and then may go finally, into impaired. So, the collectives dropped, but the specific provisions increased slightly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I can just push my luck on that. If you look at this time around, we saw a net reduction in the GRCL, aggregate GRCL expected loss deduction, notwithstanding the fact that collective provision was reduced, can you just explain to us why that is, because that's very different to what we've seen from the other banks as their collective provision declines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well that again, is &#x2013; that obviously is another test or another way of measuring the credit quality across the book, so the credit quality across the book as a whole is improving significantly, and that's why the regulatory expected loss is falling, as is the collective provision. So, they are both falling, but their regulatory expected loss is falling a bit faster than their collective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's the first time we've seen the regulator agree with the accountants?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Laughter] That's a good thing. That's a fine thing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We might go to another question on the phone from &#x2013; to Johan from Daiwa in Melbourne.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I've got two questions, please. My first question is around background information that you are providing for the NIM, particularly the move from fixed to variable home loans. You called it as one of the specific drivers for Australia, and if I look at the slide deck, slide 91 -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that was New Zealand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That was New Zealand, not Australia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because I was under the impression that the effect was much stronger in the previous half rather than this half. So, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's for New Zealand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. This is my second question, and, which is about the volatility in your reserves, specifically the foreign currency translation reserves, which sort of helped your ROE improvement as well, and that's referring to page 53 in the profit announcement. I would assume it has a lot to do with the strength of the A-dollar, but are there any sort of changes around the importance of your foreign operations that could be part of this as well, and could we expect further strong volatility in this area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me just clarify this for you. The foreign currency translation reserve, or indeed any IFRS-related balance that moves around is only a part of the story. At the end of the day we have hedges &#x2013; eventually everything that we do is hedged. So, we have hedges against what's happening to the physical assets on balance sheet, so physical assets might go up in value, but the hedge might go down, or vice versa. See you're looking at one side of the picture. That said, obviously, we have foreign operations and to the extent that the Australian dollar has strengthened, then our results from foreign operations have dropped somewhat, because there were fewer Australian dollars than there were this time last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I might get back to the room. Victor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Victor German from Nomura. Just, yeah, two questions from me as well. Firstly on margins, if I remember you saying, David, correctly your margin in the first quarter was slightly down on 2008, which you recorded in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was the retail margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That was the retail margin, right? So is it fair to assume that the group margin was slightly up a similar level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was pretty &#x2013; the group margin was fairly flat, the retail margin &#x2013; again, we had the New Zealand effect happening. The retail margin we reported was down and obviously, the retail margin bounced back in this quarter because of the rate price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Either way it sounds like the second quarter margins was significantly better than first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, if I look at the standard variable rate, the benefit would be around 45 mill, so there is somewhere around 50 to 100 new benefit that you got in second quarter versus first quarter. Can you give us an idea where that benefit is coming from?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well [Laughter] we don't think about it quite the way you do. But clearly, as you say, the 20 basis points &#x2013; I mean, more than half of our balance sheet is home loans, so 20 basis point improvement in balance &#x2013; in half of the balance sheet is a pretty significant uptick, and clearly, that's the main driver. These other things that we've talked about, where we've got timing differences through the period, but basically, particularly New Zealand has been a fairly steady drive-through for the full six months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, so quarter-on-quarter, there were <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
          <p>Okay. And secondly, just on Bankwest, in the previous results you obviously took a $300 million provision below the line, because you have concerns about that business. If we look at this results, their debt charge is actually lower than the rest of the group in terms of ratio. Has anything changed in your mind? Has performance in Bankwest been better than you expected and should we expect that overlay that you've created to unwind over time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we're using the overlay. So far, it's proceeding according to plan. We did a very, very detailed review of the book, and what provision was required for the performing part of the book. And as we worked our way through that so far, it's worked out pretty much in line with what we established. So, I don't think there'll be an unwinding. I think there'll be a usage, but it's going well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Matt Davison from Merrill Lynch. My question was on the 3% cost growth on slide 39. I guess if we dig a little deeper, we see the staff costs were up 150 mill, and the non-staff costs were down nearly 100. Just interested in that trend, and whether we can take that as really symptomatic as CBA starting to reap the benefits of recent investment in the new platforms, and whether that's something that can continue? And I guess on the flip side with the staff costs, I know that the head count was up a bit as well, so what's the outlook heading forward on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Matt, if you look at the cost as far as head count is concerned, I mean, if you go back to January of 2010, we made a decision to increase salaries and income and wages by 2%. We had actually instituted a wage freeze from July 1, 2009, and as a result of the improving performance of the Group, made the decision to actually pay what would have been half of what we would have normally have paid in the &#x2013; as at the beginning of the last calendar year.</p>
          <p>And then we have the standard increase that we've been working too over the last few years at around 3.5% to 4% that came into play from the 1st of July, so therefore, you have a significant increase over and above the previous corresponding period, because one was in a wage-freeze situation, then you have halfway catch-up in the first half, and then the second half, another 4%, and then we obviously had higher levels of bonus payments in the period of July-August of 2010, compared to what we paid in 2009, so that's really the significant reason for the increase in staff costs over that period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But at the same time, as you can see, we've been able cut other costs and I think the other area that has gone up is IT expense, and of course, that has to do with this investment that we've been making, and part of the staff cost increase is also the people involved in doing those investments. So, I think that what you should read from this is we're very focused on trying to have positive draws, so we're focused on being ready for the growth, but at the same time, being cautious about our expense and quite careful about our expense management, and we would expect in this current climate to be continuing to be pretty careful on expense management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's focused.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James, just right behind you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>James Freeman from Deutsche Bank. Ralph, I just wanted ask you about your margin outlook that you've got on page 20. It appears to me your retail margin still is yet to be benefit from the full period of the outer cycle rate hike that you put through, plus you've also got another six months of New Zealand from what I can understand. Just interested why it's not a more bullish margin outlook, given those two businesses are still performing well and represent a very big chunk of CBA's franchise? And just if you could wrap in the institutional margin, how that's performing, that would be great?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, James, I think the issue for us looking forward is that we still had elevated funding costs coming through, as we get a rollover and certainly, we're looking at somewhere around 1.5 basis points a month on average. So, that's probably somewhere around 9 or 10 potentially over the next six-month period. We'll obviously start to see that wind back as the full rollover of that funding book takes place, and obviously, if a moderate cost of funding comes back then that will be advantageous for us. That's why we're being a little cautious in regard to &#x2013; the outlook in that regard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it fair to assume that the margin at the end of the period was greater than the average?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the rough run rate is positive?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the run rate is positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is the peak period of benefit and that we run down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think as far as the IB&amp;M is concerned, there is no doubt that there is pressure coming in on margins again. I mean, the full re-pricing has worked through the book, and now we are seeing a situation where obviously with the lack of growth that was <mark type="inaudible" /> the deals and transactions that are out there are obviously being pretty fiercely competed for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What margins is that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Greater than &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; spot margins greater than average still or are we at a point now where the spot margins on new deals are below the average in the institutional book?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a little difficult. I mean, because there's so little credit cards, it's a little difficult to really say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard Wiles? Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Richard Wiles from Morgan Stanley. I've got a couple of questions about the Retail Bank margin. In previous periods, you've included the waterfall chart similar to the one you got on page 35 for the group. Could you tell us what was the positive impact of asset re-pricing, and what was the negative impact of higher funding costs in the Retail Bank during the half? And could you also comment on whether the movement in the average funding cost was worse at the start of the half than it was at the beginning of the half? In other words, is funding pressure starting to ease in the Retail Bank?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me take those two questions in order, I guess. On page 36, you can see that we are disclosing our retail margin, which you can see dropped to 219 in the second half of 2010. I think we recorded a number of around 215 at September, and it's up to 223 for the six months to December.</p>
          <p>So, obviously, there's been a rebound. The impact on margins of funding costs in the Retail Bank was running at around 2 basis points during the whole 12 months &#x2013; during the whole of the half. So, you can deduce from that some reverse engineer and calculate the impact of the uptick in funding costs, which obviously is 20 basis points across the portfolio, 300 or whatever billion dollars.</p>
          <p>On the question &#x2013; your second question was just about average &#x2013; could you repeat your second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you see average cost of funding is going up more at the start of the half than it was at the end of the half. In other words, is deposit &#x2013; funding pressure starting to ease during the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well the answer is, it's variable. There are two factors here. Firstly, the amount of household debt that's being refinanced, the amount of cheap wholesale debt that's being refinanced is easing. So, it's probably around about 1 basis point going forward, per month of wholesale funding cost hit still coming through. The other half, of course, is 60% of our funding in the Retail Bank is from deposits and that's the big question mark, and deposit pricing moves around. It's a very, very competitive market. It moves from one moment to the next. It's very hard to predict where that's going.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brett?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Brett Le Mesurier from BBY. Question on New Zealand again. The deposit rate for the June half in New Zealand was 5.7%, and fell to 4.98% in the December half. Yet the commentary refers to deposit competition being intense in New Zealand. Could you marry the commentary with the numbers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm looking at my New Zealand Board members. We may have to come back to you on that, Brett.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The gentlemen in the brown jacket behind Brett.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. This is the Japan Bank for International Cooperation. This is a two-parts question. The first question is in regards to the page number 15 on your slides, which is the target expansion in Asia. You obviously look at China as your growth area, and the opening of China County Bank in which you've actually injected capital into it, given that the situation in China predominantly in the credit rating and accounting market is not good. Do you see that there's been a sort of a strong movement in terms of your market share to growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It certainly is not a &#x2013; it's not going to be a significant part of our business in the initial to medium term. It's obviously an opportunity for us over time, and certainly, we have chosen obviously one of the strongest provinces to open our County banking operations. We're doing that in conjunction with our City Commercial Bank partner, Hangzhou, who are taking a 20% share in this initiative, and as part of that, we're obviously working off the back of Hangzhou's computer systems in their business, and at the same time, drawing a lot from their experience in the SME market in China, along with some of the experience that we have obviously learned from our operations in Indonesia, and certainly, the staffing up of our County Bank operation is being done with very seasoned professionals from other strong banks in the Asian market.</p>
          <p>So, at this point, we're taking a very, I think, prudent approach in the way that we're undertaking this particular operation. It does give us the opportunity to go into deposit collection with the sub -branches in other major cities within the Province, and certainly, that will be part of a broader initiative going forward. So, this is early days yet, and certainly, we're going into this with our eyes wide open -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the second question is in regards to the Reserve Bank of Australia. Now, there's been a lot of talk that, I don't know, maybe you could give us a sort of a guidance and outlook on that. There's probably a rights rate increase incoming in the second Q3 or Q4, do you see that as the &#x2013; ?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Whether I see that as &#x2013; well I mean, the point is, it will be what it will be. I think that the point is if inflation continues to run at high levels in the range or above the range, then the Reserve Bank has made it very clear that it would move, but that's the situation, which will prevail when we see it. But obviously, at the moment, we have a situation where there are obviously negative impacts going on in the Australian economy, on the back of what's happened with flooding in Queensland and parts of Victoria, and so that obviously could segment the equation, but I'm not a forecaster. I'm a Chief Executive of the bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you have a look at page 105 of the pack, our Economist, Michael Blythe, has produced his forecast of what he thinks will happen to the cash rate. These are averages in the period, but I that will give you a guidance. He certainly believes that over time the rates were rising.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>T.S. Lim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>T.S. Lim, Southern Cross. I just like to ask, are you happy with your current business mix of the bank? I mean, are there areas where you want to emphasize or de-emphasize to sustain ROE?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, T.S, there is no doubt that we've made it very clear over the last few years that we want to have a higher share of the business banking market, and certainly, when you look at this particular result, you can see that we are gaining traction there. Business and private banking has performed very strongly during the period and that's on the back of a strong performance over the previous 12 months. We'll see a situation where our balance sheet will take a change over time, but it won't be a dramatic change. It will be an evolving change, but certainly we see the fact that we've been underrepresented in that sector of the market and we intend to improve our penetration in that part of the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott Levine from JPMorgan. Just wanted to have a chat about the growth rates in the domestic loan book. If you cast your minds back six months ago, would you've been happy with something like 4.5% growth in the housing book, or is it fair to say maybe you tweaked the dollar a little bit too far and you're reassessing that? And just your comments around the quality of the book, I can see the broker utilization is still around current level, so I would have thought managing the profitability of that book may have seen a bit more focus on the proprietary channel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's fair to say that as I said, at the outset, we did make changes to our credit criteria and certainly, the area where we've had low levels of penetration has been predominantly in the first homebuyer market and I think that given all that's being going on in the marketplace and looking at consumer confidence, and the like that that's probably not been a bad thing to do.</p>
          <p>And so, from my perspective, I think that we were probably a little underdone running into the first quarter of this financial year. I think that you can see from the numbers, and the fundings that have taken place in the second quarter there's been a significant uptick in that regard, and I think that you will see that continue during the next two quarters, but certainly I don't think that it's not a case of reducing our &#x2013; or weakening our criteria. We'll still be very strongly focused on making sure that the credit that we are taking onto the book, it has got the right risk structure to it, and also, at the same time, we're not really interested in taking profitless growth into the book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just your thoughts around the mix between proprietary and broker, do you see any changes there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think there's a very large segment of the market that is attracted to brokers and that will continue to be the case. I mean, what we've had to do over the last few years is to make sure that our ability to originate in our own channels has been significantly improved in-house, because if we go back to 2006 we've seen a significant run-off in our ability to actually originate through our own channels. And I think that the investment that we put in place and being able to obviously facilitate home loans quickly, being able to reduce documentation in branch, the fact that we've now moved to paperless processing, all of those things have made us a much better initiator of home loans through our own channels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. There is no more questions in the room. I've got Brian Johnson back on the phone. Brian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I had two very quick questions, if I may. Number one, Ralph, can I just draw your attention to slide 20 in today's pack, where you're forecasting now for 2011 of system credit growth 4.5% to 6.5%, and if we were to go back six months ago that figure was 7.5% to 9.5%. Can I just get some comments about what has happened to this alleged pipeline of big business lending that everyone is talking about, which never seems to eventuate, but everyone is always saying it's around the corner. And the second one is if I had to look right at the back, on slide 94 this time, that in the last result of the slide 106, you spoke about the net stable funding ratio at the last results could have resulted in $100 billion of additional long-term wholesale funding and I understand that the environment has certainly gotten somewhat better, could we get an updated number on the $100 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. First moving through the credit growth situation, yeah, there's no doubt that our economists had a much stronger view on the growth in the market at the run on to this particular &#x2013; end to this financial year, and there's no doubt that that hasn't come to pass and certainly, there's no doubt that there's a lot of talk amongst corporates about doing things, but I think if you look at the confidence that has been in the market over the last half, business confidence has been down, consumer confidence has been down. We had the impact of an election. We had the issues around new taxes, and the like in the mining sector.</p>
          <p>There's been a lot of things with destabilizing, I think, during the last half, in particular, which I think the businesses really have sat on their hands. So, I don't think that's the fact that the pipeline has evaporated. I think it's a case of the pipeline has been effectively deferred from running through that pipeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So does that imply &#x2013; Ralph, if you to look at it like on business credit, six months ago that figure was 7% to 9%, and now it's 1% to 3%, what does that imply for the FY12 year then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that from the point of view of calendar year, we're looking I think at that 1% to 3%. I would say that the financial year '12, I would be very surprised if we don't see a reasonably strong rebound during FY12. I mean, when we look at the macro levels &#x2013; the economy at the macro level, in terms of trade it's just so positive that at some point it's going to flow through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, on the slide 105 Michael Blythe is forecasting 7 to 9 for business credit next year. Might just ask Lyn Cobley, our Treasurer to respond to your question around net stable funding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The net stable funding ratio, which is not due to come until about 2013, between that, and the liquidity coverage ratio, it's probably going to mean we'll have to fund extra long-term funding of somewhere in the order of over $50 billion, which we will build up over that time. It's very hard to give you exact numbers, because there is an interplay between the amount that's in the liquidity coverage ratio and next stable funding ratio, but that will become more clear over time as we continue to work with that &#x2013; on those proposals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Lyn, can I just confirm, you said 1 January 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No I said 2019 for the next stable fund ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>2019, so, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So we basically got seven years for whatever the period of time is to raise an incremental 50.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's about a 10% uplift in the funding requirement this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, depends on what the funding requirement is this year, but &#x2013; yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you very much. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One last question on the phone, and then we'll wind up. So, Johan, got time for one quick last question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, a quick one, thank you. On the term wholesale funding agenda, you've raised $8 billion in the half, and if I look at your requirements last year, $54 billion, you seem to having a big gap for the second half. What are your expectations regarding wholesale funding, and also, regarding the funding costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've already said that on funding cost, for wholesale we are expecting an incremental roughly one basis point per month, which we think continue to go on for around 12 more months. On the question of the funding task, clearly we are looking at a situation at the moment we're actually repaying wholesale debt, but nonetheless, we are rolling over our existing wholesale debt, in that, in total for the year there is around about $28 billion of debt to roll over, some of which may be repaid, as has happened in the first half. So, we've done around $8.5 billion to-date, and it's just a question of what happens with some consumer deposits as to whether they repay some of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much everyone. We might wind up here. So, thank you for attending today. Thank you, Ralph. Thank you, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>