<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1220026" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-03-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>103</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Howard S. Frank, Vice Chairman and Chief Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">David Bernstein, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Micky Arison, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Steve Kent</participant>
      <participant id="5">David Bernstein</participant>
      <participant id="6">Micky Arison</participant>
      <participant id="7">Howard Frank</participant>
      <participant id="8">Tim Conder</participant>
      <participant id="9">Robin Farley</participant>
      <participant id="10">Assia Georgieva</participant>
      <participant id="11">Steven Wieczynski</participant>
      <participant id="12">Janet Brashear</participant>
      <participant id="13">Simon Mezzanotte</participant>
      <participant id="14">David Leibowitz</participant>
      <participant id="15">Jamie Rollo</participant>
      <participant id="16">Beth Roberts</participant>
      <participant id="17">Nick Thomas</participant>
      <participant id="18">Richard Lyall</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by; welcome to the first quarter earnings call.  During the presentation, all participants will be in a listen-only mode.  Afterwards, we will conduct a question and answer session.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded Tuesday, March 24, 2009.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Howard Frank, Vice Chairman and Chief Operating Officer.  Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone.  This is Howard Frank.  I'm here this morning in Miami with Micky Arison, our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer; David Bernstein, our Chief Financial Officer; and Beth Roberts, our Vice President of Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>I will have some general comments to make, but first I'm going to turn it over to David to provide some of the color on our first quarter of 2009.  David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Howard.  I'll begin the conference call by reading the forward-looking statement.  During this conference call, we will make certain forward-looking statements.  Such forward-looking statements involve known and unknown risks, uncertainties, or other factors which may cause the actual results, performances, or achievements of Carnival to be materially different from any future results, performances, or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements.  For further information, please see Carnival's earnings press release and its filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
          <p>For the first quarter 2009, our earnings per share were $0.33 versus 2008 where it was $0.30 per share.  Achieving higher quarterly earnings in an economic climate like this is a testimony to the fact that we have the best and most experienced brand management teams in the industry.</p>
          <p>The first quarter came in above the midpoint of our December guidance by $0.12 per share.  This was driven by a few things.  Our revenue yields came in toward the better part of the range, declining 5.2% in constant dollars versus our December guidance of down 5 to 7%, which was worth $0.02 per share.  A variety of cost saving measures and timing of certain expenses benefited us to the tune of $0.06 per share as our employee ownership culture, which tends to lead to incredibly tight cost controls, continues to pay dividends.  Lower fuel prices in the first quarter were $0.02 a share and various other items were also worth about $0.02 per share.</p>
          <p>Looking at our first quarter operating results versus the prior year, our capacity increased 2.3% for the first quarter, with the majority of the increase going to our European brands.  The European brands grew 6.2% while our North American brands grew 1.9%.  As I previously mentioned, overall net revenue yields in local currency declined 5.2% in the first quarter versus the prior year.</p>
          <p>Now let's take a look at the two components of net revenue yields.  For net ticket yields, we saw a yield decline of 5% in local currency.  Our North American brands were down 3.9%, driven primarily by declines in other exotic itineraries.  Yields in the Caribbean held up reasonably well for the first quarter compared to the prior year.  Our European brands experienced a 7.8% lower local currency ticket yield on higher capacity, driven by declines in all itineraries.</p>
          <p>For net onboard and other yields, we reported a yield decline of 5.8% in local currency.  We saw declines in all our major brands around the world, a trend which we had anticipated in our previous guidance.  Net onboard yields for spa and bar were actually up in the first quarter versus the prior year, while casino, shore excursions, shops, and photo were down.</p>
          <p>On the cost side, our cruise costs per available berth day excluding fuel and in local currency were up 1.4%, driven by a $26 million increase in dry-dock expense this year versus the prior year.  However, the best measures of cruise costs are on an annualized basis, which I'll touch on in a moment.</p>
          <p>Fuel prices this quarter were down 45%, and this saved us 167 million or $0.21 per share.  Our fuel consumption per ALBD [Average Lower Berth Day] this quarter declined 6.4%, saving us $14 million or $0.02 per share.  As a result of numerous conservation measures, we've been seeing 2 to 3% fuel efficiency per year for a number of years now.  The stepped up focus in this area that resulted from the 2008 higher fuel prices has paid some dividends in the first quarter with a larger decline.  And despite the decline in fuel prices off their peak from last July, we have maintained our stepped up focus.</p>
          <p>Before I turn to the outlook, let me say a few words about liquidity.  At the end of the first quarter, we had $3.7 billion of liquidity.  This included 1.4 billion on our revolvers and 356 million of cash excluding cash on hand as well as 1.9 billion of export credits, two for 2009 and one per year for 2010, 2011, and 2012.</p>
          <p>Since the December conference call, we completed three financings, a $200 million three-year bank term loan, which we drew in February, and the 2011 and 2012 German export credit for our AIDA ships.  All three of these were included in the liquidity numbers I just gave.</p>
          <p>In addition, we're currently working on two new Italian export credits for 2009 worth over $500 million: one for the Costa Pacifica and one for the Seabourn Odyssey.  The banks have signed these agreements and they're fully committed.  However, we're awaiting issuance of the Italian export credit agency's insurance policy, which we expect to occur shortly.  These two new Italian export credits will be included in our liquidity figures after the issuance of the insurance policy.</p>
          <p>Turning to our 2009 outlook, I will skip the net revenue yield outlook as Howard will discuss that in a few moments.  Per cruise costs per available lower berth <mark type="audio gap" /> date, for the full year excluding fuel and in local currency, are projected to be in line with the prior year, up approximately 0.5 percentage point.  During the December conference call, I provided guidance of up 2%.  However, I indicated that while this guidance for controllable expenses was within our long-term target of between flat to one-half of the rate of inflation, we continue to look for opportunities to reduce this increase. Our brand management teams are all working very hard to find ways to reduce costs in this very difficult economic environment.  And while I'm happy to say that we expect another year of essentially flat costs, we will not rest there.  We'll continue to look for more opportunity.</p>
          <p>Based on the current spot price for fuel, fuel prices are projected to be $279 per metric ton for 2009 versus $558 per metric ton in 2008, saving us a total of $902 million.  In addition, the FX rates have moved from an average in 2008 of euro 1.49 and GBP 1.90 to our guidance in 2009 of euro 1.35 and GBP 1.45, and so the stronger dollar will reduce our costs.  In the end, fuel and currency are driving our costs down.  So in current dollars and excluding fuel, our costs are expected to be down 15 to 17%.</p>
          <p>While the FX rate movement reduces our costs, it also reduces our revenues.  And given the FX rates on a year-over-year basis, our profit hit from currency is expected to be about $223 million or $0.28 per share.</p>
          <p>As fuel and currency are big factors affecting our 2009 results, I wanted to once again share with you some current rules of thumb about the impact that exchange rates and fuel prices can have on our 2009 results.  To start with, a 10% change in the price of fuel represents approximately a $90 million or $0.11 per share impact on our P&amp;L.  The impact of 10% has obviously come down along with the price of fuel, while a 10% change in all other currencies relative to the US dollar would impact our P&amp;L by approximately $120 million or $0.15 a share.  Fortunately for us, these items have moved in opposite directions, acting somewhat as a natural hedge of each other.</p>
          <p>At this point, I will turn over the call to Howard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David.  Let me first provide you with some general comments on the outlook.  Given the significant slowdown in the global economy, I think it's fair to say that this has been one of the most challenging booking environments we have ever experienced.</p>
          <p>Despite the slowing economy, as we indicated in the press release, cruise bookings since the start of the year are almost 10% higher year over year for both North American and European cruise businesses, and our Asia and Australia bookings have also been strong.  So the good news is that by using discounted pricing as a stimulant, we were able to create booking demand.  But in order to achieve this strong booking momentum, we have had to take pricing down to levels not seen in recent years.</p>
          <p>For our North American brands, Caribbean itinerary ticket pricing during wave season is running 10 to 15% lower than last year.  And for Alaska and Europe, ticket pricing is 30 to 40% lower than 2008.  For our European brands, the pricing picture is somewhat better.  With a substantial part of the European wave season bookings from Mediterranean and Northern Europe cruises, European brand pricing during wave season is approximately 10% lower than in 2008.</p>
          <p>We are pleased to see that as in past years by stimulating the market with lower ticket pricing, we can produce a strong booking response.  It's for this reason that our business model enables us to continue to fill our ships and produce good levels of profitability and cash flow, even in the most challenging global economic slowdown we have experienced in our lifetimes.  It's during periods like this that the value proposition of our cruises have become even more compelling to the consumer, who is looking to buy quality vacations at the lowest possible prices.</p>
          <p>As a result of selling at these lower ticket prices, for the full year 2009 we have taken our local currency net revenue yield guidance down by approximately 3% to a range now of 10% to 12%, and that's from our previous guidance.  This includes reduced expectations for onboard revenues for the remaining three quarters as a result of the slowdown in consumer spending habits.</p>
          <p>The closer-in booking pattern and the resulting reduced visibility of our bookings make it more difficult to forecast revenue yields.  However, at this juncture, we are approximately two-thirds booked for the remainder of 2009, even with the reduced visibility.  And based on this, we think our current net revenue yield guidance of down 10 to 12% for the year is reasonable.</p>
          <p>We also continue to work on bringing our costs down and have reduced our cost outlook, which excludes fuel cost, to approximately flat from up 2% in previous guidance.  And our EPS guidance for the full year is now in the range of $2.10 a share to $2.30 a share or a midpoint of 2.20 per share, which represents a $0.30 decrease from our previous midpoint guidance of 2.50 per share.  The main driver to the lower per share earnings guidance is of course the lowering of our revenue outlook, which amounts to $0.49 a share.  The lower revenue yield outlook is offset by a lower cost outlook of $0.24 per share, $0.06 of which is reduced fuel cost and $0.18 a reduction for all other costs.  There is also a negative impact of $0.05 per share due to currency movements.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to some color on each of the next three quarters in 2009.  For the second quarter, fleet-wide capacity is up 5.6% year over year, with 4.3% of that in North America and 7% in Europe.  At this juncture, there is not much inventory left to sell, although given the close-in booking pattern somewhat more than a year ago.</p>
          <p>For North American brands in the second quarter, 54% of the capacities in the Caribbean are somewhat higher than the 51% a year ago.  20% capacity is in long and exotic cruises, which is about the same as a year ago.  10% of the capacity is in the Mexican Riviera, down from 13% a year ago, and the balance is in various other itineraries.</p>
          <p>Caribbean and Mexican Riviera pricing is lower than a year ago.  Pricing for long and exotic cruises as well as pricing for shoulder season, European, and Panama Canal cruises are substantially lower.  This is in line with what we have been indicating; that shorter and less expensive Caribbean and Mexican Riviera cruises with lower price points have been relatively stronger than the more expensive longer and exotic cruise programs for the North American brands.</p>
          <p>For the second quarter, European brands are 60% in European itineraries versus 59% a year ago, 30% in long and exotic cruises, up 5% from a year ago and 10% in the Caribbean, down from 16% a year ago.  Occupancy for European brands is running slightly lower than a year ago.  Pricing is modestly lower for the European brand itineraries.  But although pricing is lower, it is substantially better than US brand pricing.</p>
          <p>From an overall standpoint, by the time the second quarter closes, we expect local currency net revenue yields to be lower, in the 8 to 10% range on a year-over-year basis.  North American yield is substantially lower than yields for our European cruises.  Operating costs ex-fuel are expected to be up 4% on a year-over-year basis; and including the lower fuel costs this year, down 7 to 9% on a year-over-year basis.</p>
          <p>Taking these factors together, we are forecasting earnings per share for the second quarter to be in the range of $0.30 to $0.32 a share, down from $0.49 a share in the second quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the third quarter, on a fleet-wide basis, third quarter capacity is up 5.6%, 3.8% in North America and 7.4% Europe.  Our North American brands' third quarter capacity breaks down as follows.  The Caribbean is 36%, about the same as last year.  Alaska is 28% versus 29% a year ago.  Europe is 19% versus 22% a year ago, with the balance in various other itineraries.</p>
          <p>At this point, even with the strong wave season bookings, occupancies are running significantly behind last year.  Caribbean occupancy is lower in the double digit range, with lower pricing in single digits on a year-over-year basis.  Alaska occupancies and pricing are substantially lower in the double digit range.  European itineraries are running behind in the single digit level, but with pricing also substantially lower.  So it's clear that the third quarter is shaping up to be an extremely challenging one for our North American brands with ticket revenues expected to be in the range of 15 to 20% lower on a year-over-year basis.</p>
          <p>European brand itineraries in the summer quarter are substantially in the Mediterranean and Northern Europe itineraries.  At this juncture, Europe brand occupancies are lower year over year, but performing better than occupancy levels in North America.  Pricing for Europe brands are lower year over year, but also performance is simply better than our North &#x2013; US brands.  By the time the third quarter closes, we expect European brand local currency yields to be lower in the 6 to 10% range on a year-over-year basis.</p>
          <p>From an overall standpoint, taking the US and European brands together by the time the third quarter closes, we are estimating that local currency revenue yields will be lower in the mid-teens range on a year-over-year basis.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the fourth quarter, fourth quarter fleet-wide capacity is up 7.6%.  5.7% of that is in North America and 9.5% is in Europe.  Booking information for the fourth quarter is still in its early stages of development, so I caution not to read too much into the information.</p>
          <p>For North American brands, capacity breaks down as follows.  Caribbean is 45%, up slightly from 42% a year ago.  Alaska and Europe are 17% versus 20% a year ago; long and exotic cruises 23% versus 21% a year ago.  While occupancy for North American brands are running behind last year, on a relative basis in the third quarter, fourth quarter occupancies are better on a year-over-year basis with the pricing picture similar to the third quarter.</p>
          <p>For European brands, 78% are in European itineraries and 17% are in long and exotic cruises, both about the same as last year.  Europe brand occupancies are running lower than a year ago with pricing also lower at this juncture, but better than for the North American brands, which is similar to the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Of course it's still early in the booking pattern for the fourth quarter.  We will provide you with an update on the fourth quarter at our next conference call in June.</p>
          <p>And with that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Howard, before we get to questions, I just wanted to make a point about the situation in Alaska.  It should now be very evident to everyone that the initiative that passed a couple of years ago is having a very significant impact on tourism to Alaska.  The growth stopped immediately after the initiative passed.  And today, the $50 tax is a significant price to pay in a situation of a very sensitive consumer environment.</p>
          <p>Recently, one of our competitors announced a reduction in capacity for 2010.  I want to make it clear that we intend to do the same thing in 2010.  I'll venture a guess that the economic losses including job losses in Alaska will be greater than the revenue generated from the taxes imposed.</p>
          <p>The saddest thing is that we've been unable to find anybody willing to deal with the unintended consequences of this ill-conceived initiative and its impact on the Alaskan economy.  The other unintended consequence of the economic impact in Western Canada where Vancouver will be feeling a significant economic impact as well based on the ill-conceived initiative in Alaska.  I just wanted to get that in before we get into questions.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Moira, we're going to turn it over to you for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And our first question comes from the line of Steve Kent with Goldman Sachs.  Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I just have couple.  The first is just what percentage of Q1 cruises are being booked within the quarter?  And in line with that, what are you seeing as you come in for the last-minute pricing?  I know you've been aggressive on that in order to fill the ships.  Is it worse or better as you get closer to departure points?  And have any of the brands made changes in how they're paying travel agents, either reducing rebates or any of those other techniques that have been used in the past?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, on the first part of your question, the percent of bookings in the first quarter, I'm not quite sure what you're asking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What percentage were done within the quarter for the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I see, probably around &#x2013; give or take around 10% for the quarter within the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's hard to say because you have a churning effect of cancellations in bookings.  And so while the net effect may be 10%, it could be greater than that actually.</p>
          <p>As far as travel agents' compensation, I'm not aware of any significant changes during the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But, I mean, to go to the second part of your first question on the last-minute pricing, I don't know exactly how the pricing worked because it goes across 10 different brands.  But I don't think for the last 10% on a year-over-year basis, we've seen a material movement in pricing based on the late bookings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it actually was better than we had anticipated three months ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Tim Conder with Wells Fargo.  Please proceed with your question.  The line of Mr.  Conder is open.  Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you.  Gentlemen, could you comment a little bit?  It sounds like again, you've taken pricing, a hard pricing cut.  And Howard, based on your comments that you do not anticipate any material additional yield erosion given your new guidance for the year, is it fair to say that you're starting to see some stabilization in that 60-day plus pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know that I actually said that I didn't anticipate seeing any further yield erosion.  What I said is we think our yield outlook now is reasonable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I will tell you that because of the close-in booking pattern and the need to stimulate the business by using pricing, it's very difficult to challenge, even being two-thirds booked for the reminder of the year, to read the second part &#x2013; let's say the second half of the third quarter and the fourth quarter.  But I think our yield outlook is quite reasonable.  I think we've actually even attempted to lean towards a more conservative side.  But in this environment, it's very difficult to know.  It really is difficult to know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We get the question about stabilization a lot, and I'm not sure what that means.  What we do know is the pricing that we put in the marketplace improved our booking volumes 10% year over year and that is a positive.  I'm not sure what that means, what stabilization really means.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess maybe another way to ask it, Micky, would be do you see the booking curve &#x2013; and I know it varies widely by brand, but do you see that booking curve of the window starting to stabilize or do you feel that it could shrink a little bit more than where it currently is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the booking curve has stabilized.  I think that that is clear.  Part of it is the seasonality of when you're going into various seasons, but it hasn't moved in, in the past three months.  In fact, it has either stabilized or improved a little bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you think about 10% increase in bookings during wave season versus a 5% or so increase in capacity, we should be improving the booking curve slightly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Slightly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we've had catch-up to do because we lost a lot of ground in the fourth quarter of 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Okay.  And gentlemen, it sounds like &#x2013; and just a clarification here regarding your European sourced passengers.  It sounds like that demand is holding up better in constant currency than the North American demand.  Is that what I heard in your commentary, Howard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay; thank you gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Robin Farley with UBS.  Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  I've got one housekeeping question and then one question about the guidance.  For the housekeeping question, David, I wonder if you could just give a little color on what the two gains were in the quarter.  I know I saw the detail that they weren't split out, but just a little color around the lease and the income tax uncertainty that was unwound.</p>
          <p>And then my question about guidance is, I guess it seems as if the guidance you're giving today is based on your having found a price point that stimulates bookings and the more stable outlook, everyone's favorite word.  I wonder if you could give us any kind of sense of then whether your conviction level about guidance today versus where it was in December and October -- and I think everybody appreciates that you gave guidance in a difficult period in December without having the visibility you would have liked, but just to get a sense of the higher conviction level that you would have around today's guidance versus that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  As far as the two gains are concerned, the increase in the gain in other income and expense, that was related to the unwinding of one of our lease-in/lease-out transactions.  This was a rather complicated deal.  AIG was involved.  AIG put up collateral, and we were able to get all the parties to agree to take the collateral, unwind the AIG deal, unwind the deal, and take the deferred revenue that we had on the books.  Instead of taking it over the next seven or eight years, we took it in the quarter when the deal was unwound.  That was worth about $15 million.</p>
          <p>The second was in the taxes.  We had a couple of audits both at the federal level and at the state level which were completed.  So the reserves that we had on the books just happened to be slightly larger than the overall situation and we took those reserves into income to adjust them accordingly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Was the AIG deal &#x2013; was that related to a specific asset?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was just related to the Triumph lease-in/lease-out deal.  We had three of them in total: Paradise, Triumph, and Elation.  And so this was just one where the parties did agree to terminate and unwind the transaction at this time.  And it was a mutually agreeable deal between all the parties.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Robin, on the question of the guidance and the conviction we have, clearly we have more conviction today than we had back in December when we were just starting the year.  And as I mentioned with two-thirds of the inventory sold at this point, we think we're pretty close to getting it right.  We give a range.  We think within that range, we should be just fine.  But in these uncertain times, certainly the news in the last 10 days has been much more positive.  And if that continues, then we'll be a lot happier.  If the economies continue to deteriorate in the US and Europe and we struggle more, it could change.  So I think there's a lot that can happen in a rather volatile economy that could impact it.  But right now, we think it's very reasonable, very realistic, and something that we should be able to achieve, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you have to remember though that we give the initial guidance before any wave visibility because we do it in December prior to any wave visibility.  So clearly having a few months of wave gives us significantly more visibility than having to make the call before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And with booking momentum running now at least since the beginning of the year 10% ahead year over year, we're certainly feeling a whole lot better about the year than we did back in December.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which is why we narrowed the range from, as Howard mentioned, $0.50 down to $0.20.  So that was the level of increase in our conviction relating to the guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Assia Georgieva with Infinity Research.  Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, a couple questions.  First of all, could you discuss liquidity in 2010 and what your expectations are?  I know it's very difficult to have an operating cash flow estimate at this point, but do you believe you will need to access the capital markets?</p>
          <p>And then going back to I guess, Micky, your comments on Alaska and the stability question, I know you want to avoid that word, but it seems of the various destinations, pricing in Alaska is a lot more volatile throughout wave season.  Do you expect that to reach a bottom soon or is it too early to tell?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, as far as the liquidity is concerned, for 2009 we said a number of times that we don't need to raise any additional debt.  We're expecting to end the year with well over $1 billion of liquidity, and we're in fine shape.</p>
          <p>When you look forward to 2010, baked into our current guidance is cash flow from operations of about $2.8 billion.  Our capacity does go up next year.  And so if you just take a capacity addition, cash flow from operations might be roughly $3 billion.  We also have one export credit currently on the books.  That's about $300 million.  So we've got total available funds for next year potentially of 3.3 billion.  Our CapEx for next year should be about the $3.3 billion and we do have scheduled debt maturities of about 1.2 billion, if you include all the export credits and the scheduled payments under those.  So we do have some financing to do.  We are working on that today, as we speak.  We're not only working on it to cover the scheduled maturities but any potential opportunities that may come our way over time in the next year or so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just make a comment, Assia. Given the cost of raising capital in the debt markets today, that will be the last place we will go to get the money.  We are working on a number of initiatives &#x2013; and David and Josh Weinstein, which we think will be successful.  There's no assurance it will be successful, which will cost us a whole lot less.  And that's the whole idea, not to raise debt that's expensive, but to raise less expensive debt.  We have a number of options and opportunities to do that.  We are working on a number of those alternatives simultaneously and we feel pretty confident we're going to get it done, which will bring our cost of capital down.</p>
          <p>Having said that, if it all fails, we can go to the capital markets to raise the money.  But that would be the last place we'd want to go right now.  It could be that by the time 2010 runs around, we're in much better shape in the capital markets and cost of capital will come down.  But right now, we're working on the basis that that will not happen.  So let's go out and get lower cost capital right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Also during this period where supposedly the bank market was closed, we were able to arrange some bank financing, including this quarter.  So the financing markets have not been closed to us at any time during this period actually.  We've been able to continue to raise funds as needed during this entire period because of the strength of our cash flow and our balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And would you be able to discuss the alternatives that you're talking about, give a couple of examples?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It includes additional export credits, it includes bank financings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a variety of, I'd say we've got a dozen different opportunities that we're looking at and we'll take the best opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding your question on Alaska, I think the way to look at it is that our competitors have reduced capacity.  We will very soon announce a reduction in our capacity in 2010.  That may or may not stabilize the situation for 2010.  If it does, then hopefully yields will come back in 2010.  If it doesn't, we will have to reduce additional capacity in 2011.  It is a supply and demand situation.  It is a very price sensitive market and a variety of costs that the initiative put on makes getting competitive pricing versus other potential vacations and potential cruises other than Alaska just a lot more attractive.  And so capacity will continue to come down until we reach an equilibrium.  Hopefully that will be in 2010; we'll see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It does seem that Europe which also involves the additional cost of airlift and the inconvenience of traveling rather than flying over there rather than driving, but Alaska doesn't seem to hold quite as much of an appeal and that's why it seems that European pricing is holding up quite a bit better relative to Alaska.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are a number of reasons for that.  Part of it is the fact that you have a broader market for the European cruises.  Not only do you have the North American market, but you got UK, you've got Eastern Europe, you've got Russia.  You've got a lot of markets feeding into European market.  The other part of that is a lot of our Alaska sales really are Discover Alaska programs, the programs that take you into the hinterlands, to Denali, and so on.  And those when you put all the tour components into the cruise become more expensive than most European cruises.  And so again in a very price sensitive environment, that becomes a tougher sale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Steve Wieczynski with Stifel Nicolaus.  Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning guys, two questions.  I think the first one, I'm not sure how much color you can give me, but I guess for the last &#x2013; what have you seen over the last two weeks in terms of the booking environment?  I know when you cut your press release a couple weeks ago saying the first week of March, you saw the highest bookings in terms of Carnival brand, I mean have you seen a material uptick and maybe material is not the right word?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean in the last couple of weeks, I think it has been running ahead at the same levels more or less.  It has just been last week was particularly strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It has been very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It has been very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  And then maybe when you look at the competitive environment, Micky, you've talked about before...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I have to repeat, it was very strong volumes against very lousy rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you.  And then when you look at the competitive environment, have you seen the amount of discounting by some of your competitors start to come back down or is it still running at pretty high levels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we've seen a material change, I think everybody's been very aggressive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you think that will eventually catch up in the industry and eventually hurt the industry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think eventually the volumes will be big enough that pricing will start to come back up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean we have historically been through these periods where we've had to take pricing down, perhaps not as dramatically as we've done in 2009.  But once demand starts to pick up, we are able to stress the pricing back up again.  So it is a very dynamic pricing model, and if there is plenty of demand, we're able to move the pricing back up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But again, it is a very price sensitive consumer and every kind of leisure activity today is being discounted heavily.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great; thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Janet Brashear with Sanford Bernstein.  Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  You gave guidance revision on net cruise costs ex-fuel which was positive, going to nearly flat from negative 2% prior.  I'm wondering if you could talk a little bit more about that.  You had said in your last call that you were looking to utilize more shared services.  I'm wondering if that was effective.  And you also said that you were worried about external cost trends increasing, and I'm wondering if that has mitigated or it's just that you're managing around that with other savings activities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The shared service concept, I wouldn't exactly call it shared service, but I would call it shared negotiations, standardized service, a number of things that the various operating companies are doing together in order to reduce costs.  For instance, they renegotiated a crew calling card and that reduced our costs by a couple of million dollars.  They renegotiated to buy butter all from one vendor and that saved us a considerable amount of money.  We're leveraging the shore excursion contracts across the various operating units.  We're leveraging the cash deliveries to the ships and prices there.  So we are looking at a lot of different things, plus we've been renegotiating prices with our vendors, looking for greater efficiencies and fuel containment of some non-strategic projects.  And reduced commodity prices are also helping in a number of instances.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean I think it goes across the board.  There must be 25 or 30 areas where we'll be able to get some cost benefits.  A large part of that is through the supply chain working with us to do that.  So we've been very successful in that matter and we've done it on a coordinated basis.  So it's fair to say that the group executives working together in there with our centralized procurement group have been able to achieve quite a bit of savings.  We've also had savings in fuel consumption as David pointed out in his comments, and we expect that to continue throughout the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Bart Ware.  Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks.  Micky, I just had a question.  In your discussions with the Board, what do you guys think the appropriate return on investment capital is?  Because obviously you guys have brought on a lot of ships, and even excluding fuel, your returns have come down and you're also talking about a higher cost of capital.  I would contend that over the last couple of years given the value you provided vis-&#xE0;-vis land-based vacations, you haven't gotten the yield you should have got.  And obviously we're seeing the price sensitivity today on the downside.  So what are those discussions focused on and what do you think is an appropriate return on capital?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, I'm not sure I agree with the tone or the conclusion of your question.  The reality is I don't know of a leisure company that will perform as well as we will perform this year or have the returns that we will perform.  In fact, most of them won't have any returns at all this year.  So we've always said that we will outperform leisure in a difficult environment.  I think we've proven that time and again, and I think we're going to prove it again this time.</p>
          <p>There's no question that returns are under pressure.  I think they are for every company in leisure and many companies in other businesses as well.  It's clearly something that we've discussed in the Board and it's an issue when you commit additional capital to the business and whether you commit additional capital in the business, we will look over the long term for our traditional returns.  And we'll make those capital decisions based on over the long term believing that we can get our traditional returns.  But we also understand that this is a business that has ups and downs, and we're in a down cycle now.  And we would hope at some point whether it's a year or two or five down the road that we can get back to more traditional returns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And when you say traditional returns, is that low teens?  I mean obviously you can't go back to the &#x2013; or given what the incremental cost of ship builds, it seems that the mid-teens you were at in the old days are not really achievable.  I just want to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know that they're achievable now.  But there's no question that cost of new builds will be coming down just like everything else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's right, I think two things.  I think cost of new builds will stabilize or come down.  And I also think it's &#x2013; our thinking is that as we move beyond the current ship order that while we will not stop ordering ships, the ships that we will order &#x2013; we will order less ships based on the individual performance of these brands in their markets.  And I think it will be &#x2013; so we will narrow the focus on ship orders and order ships in those markets in which we're getting good returns, and we think that ordering a ship will give us an incremental return.</p>
          <p>And just a comment about return on invested capital; we do spend an awful lot of time on that.  But on the other hand, you just can't simply look at next year when you're making these decisions because these are long-term assets.  But we think the model works, and although we're going through a little bit of pain right now, even with that, we're still way outperforming the rest of the leisure business, leisure sector right now.  So we feel pretty good about ourselves.  On the other hand, we'd love to get higher yields and higher returns on our investments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess my final question to be do you think you guys have gotten your fair share of net yield during the up market let's say from post-9/11 through '07 relative to land-based pricing given the value you provided the customer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we ever think we get enough.  So I mean we are always challenged to do that.  But when you're taking in &#x2013; you're also building a business.  If you just look at year by year, it's not a strategic look at the long-term benefits of ordering new ships and building your business and taking &#x2013; and building share, capacity share in each of the markets that we have targeted.  So I think it's a combination of both short-term objectives of trying to maintain your returns and long-term objectives of building your market share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and this last, do you think that given what the cash flows are for your peers, who obviously have a higher weighted average cost of capital and much lower return on invested capital, Micky, do you think we're going to see some capacity withdrawals from the marketplace at an accelerated rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know.  That's a question for our competitors.  I don't know the answer to that.  I do think that clearly some of our competitors are under significant stress and will have to make some tough decisions, but I can't answer that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Simon Mezzanotte with Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.  Please proceed with your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, two questions from me please.  The first one is what is your thinking in terms of occupancy levels and whether using the current TO [Total Occupancy] guidance would allow you to finish on par with last year; and secondly, if you can perhaps put the current booking curve in the context of previous down cycles?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we would anticipate occupancies to be basically stable year over year.  There are always a basis point or two difference year to year depending on how much third and fourths you carry in a given year and mix factors.  But basically, I would say that we would anticipate them being flat year over year.  What was the second?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Current booking curve in the down cycle versus previous down cycles.  Is that it, Simon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Clearly this has been a much more complicated and difficult situation than September 11 for example, where we got a very, very quick bounce back.  Obviously the combination of global recession, of rising unemployment, the credit crunch, the fear factor from the market gyrations, all these things have had significant impact on the consumer, I would say as significant or more significant than we've seen in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We did look at the overall status of our booking compared to prior years, and 2009 where we stand today for the balance of the year is very similar to where we were at in 2004 and 2005.  It's hard when we go back prior to that because prior to the combination, we were a very different company and didn't have all the same brands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Prior to the merger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Prior to the merger in '03.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see.  So are you saying that the number of days that people are currently booking in advance of their holidays is basically in line with 2004 &#x2013; 2005 levels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we're about at those similar levels, where the &#x2013; exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of David Leibowitz with Horizon.  Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  First, Howard and Micky, you're very &#x2013; you're giving us worst-case scenario, or let's hope it's worst-case scenario.  Beyond the dollar weakening again and oil staying low, what else could happen that would give you better results than the range we're now looking at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Clearly a better return of demand; I mean if demand &#x2013; in these cycles where &#x2013; it's really difficult to go back and look at other cycles.  But we have been through periods where there is sort of &#x2013; if the economy started &#x2013; if people have more confidence, as unemployment becomes less of an issue in the minds of people in terms of their jobs, if demand comes back, we will be able &#x2013; and if we keep this pace up of 10 &#x2013; 12% whatever it is of stronger bookings year over year, we will be able to move pricing.  We haven't been able to do that yet.  We're still behind in each of the next three quarters in terms of occupancies versus a year ago.  So it's when that flips, then we have some &#x2013; the dynamic of that is you can then start to tweak pricing up, and that gives us the best operating leverage to be honest with you.  That's really where the opportunity is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second, talking back to Alaska and you have two brands, Holland America and Princess, which have a lot of land-based fixed assets in Alaska.  If you're cutting back on capacity, are we to take that to mean that their land-based activities will also suffer as a consequence?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and that's in our guidance, and that's what I was talking about when I was talking about the economic impact.  Obviously we have a lot of significant infrastructure.  We have significant amount of employment in Alaska and those will suffer, and no question about it.  We will try to mitigate that in every way we can and we've talked to our management about operating itineraries that will mitigate it as much as possible, but no question that the downstream impact will be felt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And with the new builds program, clearly you don't have any new builds at all on board for Princess.  Holland America has I think one more ship coming.  Are these the types of brands that you said are unlikely to get new capacity, and is Alaska part of that reason?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we've not said that at all.  We think Princess as a brand is extremely powerful and has opportunity to grow.  And if we could get the right new building deal and if we can get the right returns, we clearly would love to grow Princess further.  So no, we've never said that.  Clearly Princess is a brand that works globally.  They have a very successful operation in Australia.  They have a very successful operation in the UK.  It is a very, very powerful global brand.  And no, we'd love to be able to grow it.  It's just that when Princess's ships got delivered, it was really the peak of new building prices, and we just try to stay disciplined and wait.  And as those prices come down, clearly we'd love an opportunity to be able to continue to grow Princess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Jamie Rollo with Morgan Stanley.  Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Back in the fourth quarter and now in Q1, you've reported stronger than expected close-in demand and generally better than expected yields.  But you've still gone on to reduce your yield guidance for the out quarters.  I'm just wondering whether that is just natural conservatism, whether it's a mix impact as the summer months are more skewed to the weaker Alaska and European business, or is there something else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think when we talk about stronger than expected close-in demand, it's stronger than we expected.  It's not necessarily &#x2013; yes, it's obviously strong so it's a relative term because we forecast what the close-in business and the yields are going to be like and they're actually coming in better than the way we had forecasted it to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>By the way, it was within the guidance range.  I mean for instance for the fourth quarter in December we &#x2013; I'm sorry for the first quarter in December, we said 5 to 7%.  It turned out to be down 5.2, so it was within the range.  We're only talking about 0.8% here, so it's a very small movement relatively speaking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean I think everything you said is part of it, but I think the biggest part of it is we have more visibility.  We have about two-thirds of the business on the books and we have more that we've been through a significant part of wave and we have more visibility.  And so with the caveat of everything you said in your question, we've come to this conclusion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then on Europe, I think you said that prices are holding up better than some of the US markets.  Could you perhaps touch a little bit on some of the European markets please and why you're looking better when there is much higher capacity growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say on a market-by-market &#x2013; I mean we seem to be holding up quite well in the UK for example and I think our brands are very well positioned, the P&amp;O and Cunard brands for the UK market, even in a challenging economy because a large part of the consumers there that goes on these brands is a more well heeled consumer.  Many are retirees and so on and less affected by concerns about unemployment or of a difficult economy.  I think that's pretty much true in Continental Europe.  I think Costa is performing well; AIDA performing quite well.  Spain continues to be a challenge for us, albeit we only have three ships dedicated to the Spanish market this year.  Spain seems to be suffering more than any of the other countries in Western Europe from an economic standpoint and that continues to be a challenge.  But fortunately for us, we have very little of our business committed to the Spanish market right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>While it's true that our capacity growth rates in Europe are higher, the penetration level continues to be extremely low in Europe.  We are growing very, very powerful brands, with the exception of Spain, as Howard said, we really are seeing this across all of Europe and the UK, and there are lots of reasons.  Part of it I think is that cruises generally in Europe are not purchased with credit, and so the impact is less.  Vacation time is greater, penetration is lower.  It's all those factors I think that is mitigating the impact of the weak economy in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just finally, I'm wondering whether the group, the mix of repeats versus new cruises has actually changed in the last few months.  Have you seen an acceleration in cruise adoption by more value conscious consumers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We looked at the data for the last three months.  We have really not seen a material change in the level of first timers.  But I guess it would &#x2013; a lot of that will depend on how deep we go in pricing on a go-forward basis as the demographic information we have is really only &#x2013; it looks at it in arrears.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, we get this data post departure, so we don't have the data for people booked during this wave period.  I can tell you that anecdotally in talking to some of the brands, we're getting a lot of first-timers to the brands.  And we won't know whether those are first-timers period or basically brand switchers until we get the data after they sail.  But we are getting a significant amount of first-timers to the brand and I think that's based on the pricing that's in the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Nick Thomas with RBS.  Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello there, a couple of quick questions from me.  First of all, the full-year guidance obviously slightly weaker than it was three months ago, although first quarter at the better end.  That change in guidance that we're seeing, is that pretty evenly spread across the remaining three quarters or is it more skewed towards any particular area?  I mean certainly from your narrative, the third quarter sounded to be maybe the weakest of the quarters looking ahead.  Just give a little bit of color on how things have changed over three months on a quarter-by-quarter basis.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, looking at fourth quarter booking volumes and prices at this stage, are you able to compare where we are now for the fourth quarter with where we were three months ago at your last call for the third quarter as an indication of how much better or worse things are looking for the fourth quarter versus the third quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  First of all, we didn't give guidance by quarter on the last call.  But I will say that a big part of the reduction in the guidance from December through March was as a result of the pricing in the back half of the year.  We had in December the least amount of visibility to third and fourth quarter.  We took our best estimate at that point in time.  And as Micky and Howard had indicated before, given everything we've seen, we put forward what we believe is reasonable for that period of time, which mostly, a big chunk of it is third and fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>As far as the bookings for the fourth quarter versus the prior year, where we were versus the prior year in December relatively speaking, we're tracking similarly to the prior year.  For the second quarter, we made up some ground.  In the third quarter, we made up ground.  But the fourth quarter is still about the same behind as it was in the December call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's interesting, the fourth quarter relative to the third quarter, they are very different quarters from a price point standpoint because the third quarter is our strongest, seasonally strongest quarter.  So we get our highest prices in the third quarter, and pricing comes down typically in the fourth quarter.  So they behaved, the booking patterns for the two quarters behaved very differently.</p>
          <p>I think it's fair to say, and generally speaking but I wouldn't make any conclusions from this, that the fourth quarter because of the low &#x2013; we think because of the lower price points is booking somewhat better than third quarter is booking because of the higher price points, relatively speaking.  It is a relative thing.  I don't know if you can glean anything from that at the end of the day except that that's the phenomenon that we see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's just a continuing confirmation of price sensitivity at this point in time.  The third quarter has historically been our highest price quarter.  The fourth is historically our lowest price quarter because of the seasonality of the quarters.  And if you've got a very price sensitive consumer, if they can -- and many people can't move because many people like teachers and others, they can only get vacation in July and August, can't move.  But people who can move, there is a significant price difference to move and because of the price sensitivity, that will happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just as a follow-up, obviously the yield that you've reported in the first quarter and the guidance you've given for the second quarter is clearly better than what's implied for the second half for the reasons you just outlined.  To some extent, would you put that down to an impact of the benefit that you've perhaps seen from bookings and pricing that you would already have had on hand before the economic environment deteriorated from autumn time at last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think there's no question that we had a base of business, particularly in the first, some in the second prior to that September week, where the consumer really got hammered, and that clearly helped the first half versus the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Rick Lyall with John Bristol.  Please proceed with your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys, I have two questions.  First has to do with group bookings and whether or not you've seen any stabilization in either repricing or rebooking of those.  There's been some stigma about corporate travel and profligacy during a period of layoffs.  Have you seen any stabilization of bookings yet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, stabilization is a word I'm really not enjoying.  Group bookings are down.  In a down pricing environment, historically we've always seen group bookings decline.  And it has held up.  As you say, there's also this overriding thing that I think Vegas is feeling more than anybody else but we're getting some of it of a desire of corporations not to travel right now.  So the combination of those things clearly have affected &#x2013; and our yield management people have had to adjust to that and understand that.  But no, group bookings are down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Alaska is obviously an important market for the industry and rather than just surrender that market to I guess ill-advised tax costing by the state, what is the industry doing to fight back?  And part B of the question is if it is impaired to some degree going forward because the state sticks to its head-tax policy, what plans are you considering to develop other markets like Latin America or more presence in Asia where emerging markets have held up relatively better, any thoughts along those lines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think our strategy has been to try to deal with the issue politically in Alaska first.  It is clear to us and legal opinions are clear to us that the initiative and the taxes are unconstitutional and in fact effectively illegal.  We have tried everything we can to find a political solution.  If we don't in the end find a political solution, I assume we will go ahead and litigate the issue, which is a last resort but that's what we will do.  Other than that, we will have to continue to reduce capacity until we find an equilibrium.  I'm hopeful that the reduction in capacity in 2010 will be sufficient that we will find an equilibrium in 2010 and start to see some recovery.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>South America and Asia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're building Asia.  As you know, Costa is putting a second ship into Asia.  There are still plenty of summer deployment.  Deployment in the summer really is not a challenge because there is plenty of demand and plenty of deployment possibilities in the summer.  It's always winter deployment that's the trickiest.  And if all else fails, it's the Caribbean, which &#x2013; there have been a lot of ships coming out of the Caribbean over the last few years.  And right now, the Caribbean could sure use a little bit of a boost in their economy.  So if all else fails, I think you'll see some retrenchment and return of some of the summer deployment to the Caribbean.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good luck in the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have no further questions at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you all for calling in and if there are follow-on questions in details and so on, Beth Roberts will be available today to take your calls.  Have a good day everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude the conference call for today.  We thank you for your participation and ask that you please disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>