<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1201100" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-12-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>103</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Howard S. Frank, Chief Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">David Bernstein, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Richard Lyall</participant>
      <participant id="4">Howard Frank</participant>
      <participant id="5">Micky Arison</participant>
      <participant id="6">Robin Farley</participant>
      <participant id="7">David Bernstein</participant>
      <participant id="8">Beth Roberts</participant>
      <participant id="9">Tim Conder</participant>
      <participant id="10">Steve Kent</participant>
      <participant id="11">Steven Wieczynski</participant>
      <participant id="12">John Jares</participant>
      <participant id="13">Dominique Mielle</participant>
      <participant id="14">Sharon Zackfia</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Carnival Corporation's fourth quarter earnings conference call. During the presentation, all participants will be in a listen-only mode. Afterwards, we will conduct a question and answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded Thursday, December 18, 2008.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Howard Frank, Vice Chairman and COO. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alex. Good morning, everyone. This is Howard Frank, and with me this morning is Micky Arison, Chairman and CEO of Carnival, along with David Bernstein, who is our Chief Financial Officer and Senior VP of Finance, and Beth Roberts, who is our VP of Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>I will turn the call over to David, who will take you through some of the color for the 2008 year and the fourth quarter, and then David will turn it back to me and I'll give you some views on our current outlook for the business going into 2009. David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Howard. I will begin the conference call by reading the forward-looking statement. During this conference call, we will make certain forward-looking statements. Such forward-looking statements involve known and unknown risks, uncertainties, or other factors which may cause the actual results, performances, or achievements of Carnival to be materially different from any future results, performances, or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. For further information, please see Carnival's earnings press release and its filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
          <p>For the fourth quarter, our earnings per share was $0.47, which came in above the midpoint of our September guidance by $0.10 per share. This was driven by lower fuel prices worth $0.06, stronger than expected revenue yields on close-in bookings worth $0.02, and various other items worth $0.02. The gain on the sale of the QE2 was in our previous guidance; however, the stronger dollar versus the sterling increased the gain.</p>
          <p>Looking at our fourth-quarter operating results versus the prior year; our capacity increased 8.1% for the fourth quarter, with the majority of the increase going to our European brands. Our European brands grew over 16%, while our North American brands grew 4.6%. Overall net revenue yields in local currency increased 2% in the fourth quarter versus the prior year.</p>
          <p>Now let's look at the two components of net revenue yields. For net cruise ticket yields, we saw an increase of 3.2% in local currency. Our North American brands were up 4.4%, driven by the Caribbean, Mexico, and other exotic itineraries. Our European brands experienced 1.3% lower local currency ticket yields.</p>
          <p>Given the 21% capacity increase for our European brands this year and the increasing competition from other companies in the European marketplace, we were expecting to see overall flattish yields, which is exactly where we wound up, excluding Ibero. As to Ibero, they did experience soft pricing in the fourth quarter as they did in the third quarter, which resulted from the difficult economic environment in Spain.</p>
          <p>P&amp;O Cruises Australia, with its reconfigured fleet, adding Pacific Dawn in November of '07 and delivering the Pacific Star to Pullmantur's in March of '08 achieved a healthy yield increase for the fourth quarter versus the prior year, which supports our decision to grow the brand by redeploying the Ocean Village ships over the next two years.</p>
          <p>For net onboard and other yields, we reported a yield decline of 1.8% in local currency. However, mix accounts for 0.8% of the decline, as our European brands, which have always had lower onboard spending, are growing faster than our North American brands. We saw yield declines in about half of our brands around the world, a trend which we anticipated in our previous guidance.</p>
          <p>On the cost side, our cruise costs per available lower berth day for the fourth quarter in local currency were essentially flat. Fuel prices this quarter were higher by 24%, costing us an additional $84 million or $0.10 per share. Our continued focus on managing controllable costs allowed us to offset the $84 million of higher fuel costs, which is a tribute to the strength and talent of our brand management teams.</p>
          <p>Excluding fuel and the gain on the sale of the QE2, which was included in other ship operating expenses, cruise cost per available lower berth day were down 1.2%. However, the best measure of cruise cost changes are on an annual basis, and I'll touch on that in a moment.</p>
          <p>Looking back at the full year 2008, our EPS was $2.90, which I recognize was not in the range of the original guidance that we gave one year ago of $3.10 to $3.30 per share. The midpoint of that range, which was 3.20 per share, was based on $486 per metric ton of fuel. If you adjust for the actual price of fuel, the midpoint would be $2.92. Therefore, we missed our guidance by a mere $0.02 per share.</p>
          <p>For 2008, our capacity increased 8.9%. Net revenue yields in constant dollars was up 2.4%. This was slightly below the range of our guidance a year ago. During 2008, we saw pressure on an onboard revenue yield as a result of the ongoing recession and its impact on our guests. As I indicated before, the best measure of cruise cost changes are on an annual basis. For the full year, our cruise cost per available lower berth day in constant dollars was up 7.5%.</p>
          <p>However, excluding fuel, the gain on the sale of the QE2 in the fourth quarter, and the gain in the third quarter from the final insurance settlement related to the damage done to our port facility in Cozumel, cruise costs per available lower berth day were essentially flat. So our controllable expenses, excluding fuel and currency, were essentially flat despite inflationary pressures. This is a great accomplishment. We were able to offset inflation during the year through economies of scale and increased efficiencies.</p>
          <p>However, as I've indicated on previous calls, our long-term track record of flat cruise costs per available berth date, dating back to 1990, is getting harder to maintain in the face of moderate capacity growth. As a result, our goal for future cruise costs per available lower berth day is in the range of flat to one-half the rate of inflation.</p>
          <p>In summary for 2008, we posted solid earnings in an extremely difficult year. The 55% increase in fuel prices was largely offset by a combination of our capacity growth, our yield improvement, and our excellent cost controls.</p>
          <p>Turning to our 2009 outlook, I will skip net revenue yields, as Howard will discuss that in a few moments. For cruise costs per available lower berth date for the full year, excluding fuel and in local currency, our costs are projected to be up 2%. However, half a percentage point is due to the gain recognized in the prior year on the sale of the QE2, which reduced prior-year costs. In addition, another half a percentage point is due to the gain from the final insurance settlement related to the damage done to our port facility in Cozumel, which also reduced prior-year cruise costs. So without these two one-time items, the real underlying increase in cruise costs would be approximately 1%.</p>
          <p>While this guidance for controllable-expense unit costs, excluding fuel and currency, is within our long-term target of unit cost growth between flat to one-half the rate of inflation, we continue to look for opportunities to reduce this increase. I've had numerous discussions with our brand management teams. We're all working very hard to find ways to improve upon the guidance in this very difficult economic environment. I am hopeful that we will have another year of flat costs.</p>
          <p>Based on the spot price of fuel using Monday's closing price, fuel prices for the full year are projected to be 295 per metric ton for 2009 versus $558 per metric ton in 2008, saving us $861 million. In addition, FX rates have moved from an average in 2008 of a euro 1.49 to a GBP of 1.90 to our 2009 guidance of euro 1.38 and sterling <mark type="inaudible" />. So in the end, fuel and currency are driving down our costs. So in current dollars and including fuel, our costs are actually expected to be down 13 to 15%.</p>
          <p>While these movements reduce our costs, given the diversity of our worldwide revenues, 50% of which come from passengers sourced outside the United States, these movements are expected to negatively impact our bottom line. So given these FX rates, our year-over-year profit hit from currency is expected to be 195 million or $0.24 per share.</p>
          <p>As fuel and currency are big factors affecting our 2009 results, I wanted to share with you some current rules of thumb about the impact that these exchange rates and fuel prices have on our 2009 results. To start with, a 10% change in the price of fuel represents a 97 million or $0.12 per share impact on our P&amp;L. A 10% change in fuel has obviously come down along with the price of fuel, while a 10% change in all currencies relative to the U.S. dollar would impact our P&amp;L by about $140 million or $0.17 per share. Fortunately for us, these items have moved in opposite directions, acting somewhat as natural hedges of each other.</p>
          <p>At this point, I will turn the conference call over to Howard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David. Let me &#x2013; some comments on the outlook for 2009. Since we reported to you some six weeks ago, the slowdown in the cruise booking has continued. While bookings for close-in business has been satisfactory, bookings for late spring and summer continue at a slow pace. We have taken pricing lower, and while that has helped to fill the ships on close-in business, it is yet to have much of an impact on late spring and summer booking patterns.</p>
          <p>In this weakened North American economy, bookings for our shorter, value-oriented Caribbean cruises have been stronger than our longer and more expensive European, Alaska, and long and exotic cruises. The good news is that consumers are still taking their vacations, but the vacation decision is for next month rather than next year.</p>
          <p>Looking at our booking patterns, it is also clear that consumers are looking for more value for their vacation dollar. And our shorter, less expensive Caribbean cruise products are performing much better than our premium and luxury longer cruise products.</p>
          <p>So we are seeing a consumer trade-down to value, which plays nicely into our Carnival Cruise Lines brand, and that should help us to perform reasonably well during this economic downturn. While we are hopeful that consumer psychology will change when the new President and his administration take office in January, and as a new fiscal stimulus plan is implemented, there is no real way of knowing if and when that will kick in.</p>
          <p>There is, however, another silver lining in the booking picture, and that is our European brand bookings are holding up considerably better than our U.S. brands. This will be a positive factor in 2009's performance, since much of our brand's new capacity additions in 2009 will be for our European cruise companies. While many Western European markets are also experiencing a recessionary economy, we believe the European consumer, as net savers and with considerably lower credit card and other personal debt, are better able to cope with the weakening economies in their countries. Also as you know, Europeans have far more vacation time, and the European cruise market is far less penetrated than in the U.S. So our strategy of investing in our European cruise brands should be a positive factor in our overall financial performance for the upcoming year. Our European brand capacity in 2009 will increase by 8%, as compared to North American brand capacity, which will increase by 4%.</p>
          <p>As we indicated in the press release, we have reduced local currency net yield guidance range for 2009 from the guidance we provided in late October to a range of negative 6 to negative 10%. Three points of this reduction is due to the elimination of the fuel supplement revenue for 2009, which we announced earlier this month. And we also took our ticket pricing and onboard revenues lower for the year in view of the further deterioration in the economic environment.</p>
          <p>However, given the closer-in booking patterns, revenue yield guidance is more of a challenge for 2009. And consequently, we are using a broader range of guidance than in past years. Fuel prices have come down further, but not enough to offset the revenue lost from eliminating the fuel supplement and the other revenue reductions. And as David indicated, we are still estimating an approximate 2% increase in costs for the year, excluding fuel. Taking all these factors into consideration, we have lowered 2009 earnings guidance to a range of $2.25 to $2.75 per share.</p>
          <p>Turning to our specific ship deliveries in 2009, this spring we take delivery of three ships for our European brands: the AIDAluna for our AIDA brand in Germany; the Costa Luminosa and Costa Pacifica for our Costa brand, the largest cruise company in Europe. And in June, the Seabourn Odyssey, a spectacular new class of ship for Seabourn and the first ship to join the Seabourn fleet in over 15 years, is being delivered. In September the Carnival Dream, a new class of ship for Carnival Cruise Lines, will be delivered. On a fleet-wide basis, this capacity increase will be about 5.5% for the full year.</p>
          <p>Given the continuing challenges to raising debt in the capital markets, I think it's appropriate to make some comments on the company's balance sheet and its liquidity going forward into 2009. In late October, as a result of the extraordinary high cost of raising new debt, the company suspended its dividend, which on an annualized basis will save us approximately $1.3 billion. With this in mind, let me provide you with a brief overview of our cash flows for 2009.</p>
          <p>Using operating cash flow at the midpoint of our earnings range for 2009 &#x2013; now, that is the $2.50 a share &#x2013; we are currently estimating 2009 cash flow of approximately $3.3 billion. In addition, we have committed financing for ship deliveries today of approximately $800 million, for a total of $4.1 billion of incoming funds flow. Against that, we have approximately $3.4 billion of CapEx spending, which covers the five ships I just talked about plus estimated maintenance CapEx for the year. And we have maturing debt of approximately $700 million. So essentially, our cash inflows for the year will be sufficient to fund cash outflow requirements without having to raise any capital in the debt markets.</p>
          <p>The debt markets continue to be very difficult, even for solid investment-grade credits like Carnival, with credit spreads still at historical highs. However, in order to further strengthen our balance sheet, we have recently closed on additional lower-cost bank financings and are working on several new financings, also at lower costs. In addition, as a further liquidity cushion, we have approximately $1.3 billion of cash and availability under our revolving credit facilities going into calendar 2009. Given these uncertain times, we believe our strategy of maintaining a strong balance sheet has positioned us well, and we will continue with this strategy going forward.</p>
          <p>Now let me give you some color on each of the first three quarters of 2009 &#x2013; a little bit more color on the booking patterns. Looking at the first quarter of 2009, fleet-wide first quarter capacity is up 2.6% on an overall basis, 1.9% in North America, 7% in Europe. On a fleet-wide basis right now, as we look at the booking picture, first quarter occupancies and pricing are running behind last year.</p>
          <p>For North American brands in the first quarter, 62% of capacity is in the Caribbean. That's slightly up from 61% a year ago. 12% is in our Mexican Riviera programs, down from 15% last year. And the balance are in various other itineraries, including long and exotic cruises. At this juncture, with a small amount of inventory left to sell, Q1 occupancies and pricing are running behind year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Caribbean and Mexican Riviera pricing is slightly ahead, with occupancies slightly behind. Not unexpectedly, pricing and occupancies for longer and exotic cruises at higher price points are running behind. This is consistent with what we have been saying, that shorter and less expensive Caribbean cruise products are holding up reasonably well as consumers search for good value in their vacation choices.</p>
          <p>Turning to our European brands, their ships are 32% in the Caribbean versus 37% from last year; 24% are in Europe, up a couple of points from 22% last year; 12% in the Orient Pacific area versus 10% the prior year; 12% in world cruises, which is about the same as last year; and 11% in South America, up slightly from 10% last year.</p>
          <p>At this point, Europe brands, with a 7% increase in first quarter capacity, are running slightly behind in occupancy and pricing. However, Costa brand pricing in Q1 is running higher year-over-year, which is a positive sign, as Costa will be taking on significant capacity this year. Costa appears to be performing relatively well despite the softening of the economies in Continental Europe, which is its primary market.</p>
          <p>By the time the first quarter closes, we expect pricing to be lower for North America and Europe brands, and as we indicated in the press release, we are estimating that local currency ticket yields for the first quarter will be 5 to 7% lower than last year's first quarter. Approximately 40% of the lower yields in the first quarter reflects the elimination of the fuel supplement.</p>
          <p>Fuel costs in the first quarter using today's pricing of 295 a ton will result in fuel being lower by 159 million versus last year. However, operating costs are expected to be higher in the first quarter, but we think there is some opportunity to bring these costs lower as the slowing global economy should help to reduce the cost for certain commodity-based products. Taking all of these factors into consideration, we are currently forecasting earnings per share to be in the range of 0.20 to $0.22 for the first quarter versus $0.30 in the first quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the second quarter of 2009, on a fleet-wide basis second quarter capacity is up 6.1%; 4.4% of that is in North America, and 8.3% is in Europe. On an overall basis, second quarter ticket pricing and occupancies are running behind year-over-year as a result of the slowdown in the booking pattern. For North American brands, second quarter capacity breaks down as follows: Caribbean is 54% versus 51% from last year; Mexican Riviera is 10% versus 13% a year ago; with all other itineraries, including the Alaska and Europe shoulder seasons, Panama Canal, long and exotics, each under 10%.</p>
          <p>Caribbean and Mexican Riviera occupancies and pricing are lower year-over-year; occupancy and prices for shoulder Alaska and Europe and long cruises are even more significantly lower. It's clear that North American consumers are holding off making any decisions on cruise vacations until we get into 2009. However, we believe these booking gaps will start to close in the second quarter as we begin the new year.</p>
          <p>Europe brands in the second quarter are 59% in Europe trades, approximately the same as last year; 11% in the Caribbean, down from 16% a year ago; 11% in trans-Atlantics, about the same as last year; the balance in all other itineraries are all under 10%. On an overall basis, Europe brand occupancies are lower than last year, although better than the North American brands. Overall Europe brand local currency pricing is slightly higher than last year.</p>
          <p>Europe itinerary pricing &#x2013; this is for ships that are in Europe for our European brands &#x2013; is running at about the same levels as last year, with lower occupancies at this point. Caribbean pricing is running behind last year, with approximately flat occupancy. Pricing for the various other itineraries are running slightly better than last year at lower occupancies. So as you can see from this, even with the 8% increase in capacity, our European cruise companies seem to be performing better than their North American counterparts.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the third quarter, where our fleet-wide capacity is up 5.6%, 3.8% of the capacity is up in North America, and 7.4% is increased in Europe. Booking information for the third quarter is still in the early stages of development, so I caution not to read too much into the information I'm about to talk about.</p>
          <p>On an overall basis, third quarter occupancy and ticket pricing have fallen significantly behind last year. Although we continue to have positive bookings week after week for the third quarter, the booking levels are lower than last year's levels, further evidence that the North American consumer is deferring their vacation decisions.</p>
          <p>North American brand capacity breaks down as follows: Caribbean is 36%, approximately the same as last year; Alaska was 28%, slightly lower than last year; and Europe is at 19%, down from 22% the prior year; with the balance of North American brand itineraries in the rest of the world. Caribbean itinerary occupancies are down year-over-year, with pricing at approximately the same levels. Alaska and Europe occupancies and pricing are significantly lower year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Turning to Europe, our Europe brands are 96% in Europe itineraries, and at this point in time, Europe brand pricing in the third quarter is running ahead year-over-year, with occupancy significantly behind. From an overall standpoint, the third quarter is shaping up to be quite challenging at this time. However, given the closer-in booking pattern, we expect the picture to improve as we get close to the cruise dates and consumers begin to make their vacation decisions.</p>
          <p>Just anecdotally, let me make a comment about Australia and Asia, since for the first time in our history we will have four ships in Asia and Australia in the third quarter, with two ships operating for the P&amp;O Australia brand and two ships for Costa Asia. Third quarter occupancies on these ships are nicely ahead year-over-year on somewhat lower pricing. So we are starting to see some progress in these developing markets. And later in 2009, we will be moving an Ocean Village ship &#x2013; we previously announced this &#x2013; from the UK to P&amp;O Australia. And the second Ocean Village ship will be moved to Australia in 2010. So we are feeling very strongly that the Australia market is a very good market, and we will be looking to expand our capacity in that market going forward.</p>
          <p>So with those comments from David and myself, I will turn it back to you Alex, for questions. And that's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And our first question comes from the line of Rick Lyall with John W. Bristol. Please proceed with your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys, couple questions. It's obviously a very tentative environment, and the picture's probably changing almost daily. Can you talk about how you could get more conservative if you needed to in the P&amp;L? It seems like you've been pretty aggressive in your cost controls, and I'm wondering how much further flexibility you have? And then, the corollary to that is how could you go &#x2013; or become more aggressive and really take advantage of your better balance sheet, et cetera, if conditions start to improve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me comment about the cost picture a little bit, Rick. I'm not sure it's going to answer your question. But we have been working on a number of opportunities &#x2013; mostly back-of-the-house opportunities &#x2013; in the organization to create more synergies, more shared services in the organization. And we have a number of objectives in 2009 to achieve those opportunities, to achieve those objectives, throughout the organization.</p>
          <p>And I would say there's a very positive view that we will make some progress in there. And I think David's comment and my comment about, we think there may be some more opportunities on the cost side of the business, I think is based on that. There's a very positive view that we can save some money, and we will continue to look for these kinds of opportunities going forward.</p>
          <p>So I think the objective of getting back to a zero cost metric on an ALBD basis going into 2009, I think that's our largest opportunity. But you have to remember we've got these two other factors in here, fuel and currency, which also play a role in the business. And those are things that are very difficult. Obviously we can't control those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The volatility of fuel and currency is unbelievable. I mean, if you took this morning's prices versus Monday's prices, we'd get pretty close to back to the guidance that we had in October. So it's amazing how volatile these markets are. I guess everybody on the call understands that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How about going on offense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What would you like us to do, Rick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a saying, a good defense is your best offense, you know? Obviously from an antitrust point of view, there's not a whole lot that we can do, but like post-September 11 sometimes opportunities avail themselves that you're not expecting, and we'll be diligent about that as time progresses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Have you guys ever seen an environment like this? When I think back to the various wars and 9/11, and this seems to be a very different environment than that. Have you got any relevant experience that you can compare this to and take advantage of?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's different in that September 11, we saw a very quick bounce-back, which although we've seen some improved volume post the election, it has been on deteriorating yields. I guess we had to some degree a similar situation in the build-ups to both Iraq wars, where it was &#x2013; just seemed like the build-up went on forever, and people were put on hold during that build-up. But this is a pretty unique set of circumstances, where people can't get credit and how that affects &#x2013; the consumer may want to do something, but his inability to get credit could affect the decision. So as time goes on, we'll learn more, but baked into our numbers is an overriding concern by all our management teams about how many people are going to be taken out of the market because they just can't get credit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much, and good luck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Robin Farley with UBS. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, yeah, a couple of questions. One is that I just wanted to make sure I heard your comment correctly when you mentioned opportunities like you saw after 9/11. Does that mean you're looking for acquisitions? Is that how we should interpret that comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. What I said was because of antitrust, we can't really do that. But if things continue to deteriorate and opportunities exist similar to what happened &#x2013; I mean, if you remember post-9/11, there was a number of failed cruise companies, and that created a number of opportunities, and some people jumped on them. If you look &#x2013; NCL went into Hawaii because American Classic went out of business, and the Renaissance fleet was broken up and sent around the world to various cruise companies, including ours and Royal Caribbean and Oceania. So stuff happened, and we just have to be aware that stuff may happen again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If it's a challenge for us to get credit at reasonable prices in the marketplace, it will be a challenge for companies with a &#x2013; low quality credit companies in the industry. So clearly &#x2013; you never know what's going to happen, but clearly we are in a unique position having really run a conservative balance sheet over these years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My only point &#x2013; it's not that we're doing anything in an aggressive manner. All I'm saying is that we have to remain diligent to the possible opportunities that might come our way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then also your comments in the release about close-in bookings in Q4 being better than expected, so that must mean some of that was on price, not just on volume, that -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the way to look at that is &#x2013; when I read it myself, it was kind of funny. That's not to give any indication of strength in bookings in the fourth quarter. It's an indication of how conservative we were at the time and how weak we thought bookings might be in the fourth quarter, and has outperformed our expectations. But that's not to say &#x2013; I don't want you to develop any thought that that means that there was strength. That's not the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that's &#x2013; so I was going to ask if there was a trend there that you were seeing into Q1, but it sounds like that's not the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what we are seeing is that volumes in Q1 are strong because the curve has moved in. So we're seeing very strong volumes in Q1 and very weak volumes in Q2 and 3, and we would expect that to roll over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But the Q4 comment sounded like it was price rather than volume. That's what had kind of caught my attention. But I understand your clarification.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's never volume. We always...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's always price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's always price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's always price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So that's helpful. And then last thing is &#x2013; and I know this is looking out a bit far &#x2013; but it was helpful when you walked through your position in '09 in terms of liquidity, committed financings, and CapEx. Can you walk us through a tentative version of that for 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We really haven't given any guidance for 2010. I guess the only thing I can add at this point in time is that our maturities for 2010 are $1 billion. We do currently have one export credit for 2010, which is $350 million, but we don't have any forecast for 2010 or any guidance to work off of.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our CapEx -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our CapEx at '10...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>3.5 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think the situation will probably look pretty similar by the time we get closer to 2010, that we have in 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we are continuing, by the way, to work on a number of export credits. In fact, we're hoping within the next week or two to close on two German export credits, but those are for '11 and '12. And we're also working on some Italian export credits, which we should probably have closed in the next 30 to 60 days. And all of these export credits again will have interest rates at probably below 5% overall, all in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there's also some misunderstanding of how these export credit works. Generally speaking, the export credit is an agency of government guaranteeing a percentage of the overall loan. So that the lending banks have to take into consideration the creditworthiness of the government for one piece of the loan and the creditworthiness of the company for the other piece of the loan. And that varies by government and by loan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But it's one loan, if you understand what I'm saying, because there's been some confusion on that issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And in some cases there's committed &#x2013; the banks have committed to the export credit, as in our case. In other cases, they don't commit to it until later on, even though the export credit facility's out there. They still have to syndicate the loan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For instance, the one that I just mentioned, we're working on Italian export credits that will close in the next 30 to 60 days. That's where we have the government commitment but we're looking to get the banks to sign on the dotted line in the next 30 to 60 days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then it's fully committed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Tim Conder with Wachovia. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Along those same lines, David, could you kind of outline for us &#x2013; I guess if you look at the ships you have delivery in '09, '10, and you were talking a little bit about '11 and '12. Of those, what do you have &#x2013; again, just recap for us the bank groups that are lined up and then the government commitments that are lined up. I mean if you had to look at two columns, what's open and what's confirmed? So I guess that's one question. I know it's a broad question.</p>
          <p>And the second one, Howard, you talked about the booking strength in Europe on a relative basis. Could you give us a little more color by country, say the Spain, Ireland, UK, where there's been a lot of problems versus some of the other areas on the continent?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't you take the first one, David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. As you know, Tim, we've got 17 ships on order. It's five ships in 2009, six in '10, four in '11, and two in '12. At the current moment, including all of the bank commitments fully signed and done, we have three export credits, two for 2009, one for 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So that's the group and the export credit collectively done?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct. The banks have signed, the governments have signed. At this moment, I have government commitment for one more ship in 2009, and I've got an additional ship in '11 and '12. So we've got three additional government commitments; two of the three should be signed within a week, maybe two. Holidays are always difficult times to get everybody to sign.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the last one would be signed in the next 30 to 60 days. So we're talking about three done and three in the hopper, and that doesn't mean we'll stop there. That's just what we're working on right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But also, the way we're presently structured, remember that five of the ships are being built in Italy for Italian flags, so there is no export involved.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the way it's presently structured. Obviously if we wanted to, we could structure it slightly differently, but that's the way it's presently structured.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim, on the relative performance of the European brands by market, I think you almost hit the nail on the head yourself. I think that if you look at Continental Europe, that seems to be &#x2013; let's suppose we're talking here Italy, Germany and France &#x2013; that seems to be performing better. And Spain is still a challenge, there's still a problem. But of course, we only have a few ships in Spain with Ibero. And right now there are &#x2013; two of the ships are in Brazil. So that's not a problem for this winter. It does become a challenge come the springtime, but it's only two ships.</p>
          <p>And if you look at the UK, while the UK is not performing as well as Continental Europe &#x2013; and this is all relative, now &#x2013; it's performing better than the U.S. So it's sort of between the U.S. and Europe. I can't comment about Ireland. I don't know that. Although I'm sure if we get passengers from Ireland, I assume it's very similar to the UK.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. And lastly, Micky, if you could, it was alluded to earlier in the preamble about how you're going to have more difficulty going forward adhering to your cost control, just because there's going to be less capacity growth. Looking at 2012 and beyond, Micky, and you've talked about this for well over a year, almost two years, that it's going to slow. Any general range of percentage capacity growth or any color you can give on that on &#x2013; looking '12 and beyond?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's difficult to say. As David said, we have, what, two ships now for 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And at current capacity growth is, for 2012 for us is about &#x2013; close to 4% already.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it's unlikely that there would be any contracts done unless we believe we can get the kind of returns that we'd expect. And based on the current situation, that's doubtful. So we'll see, we'll see. But right now it's hard to project much higher than what we've got.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, even if returns would be more palatable, would you say &#x2013; ?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we can work out &#x2013; there are clearly brands in our portfolio that could use capacity in 2012. We have, for example, Princess has no ships on order, and clearly it's a brand that we feel very strongly about and would like to see grow. But again, we're not going to do it unless the returns are there. So we have brands that clearly from a strategic and long-term point of view we would like to grow, but we're not going to do it unless the environment is such that we can get reasonable returns for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We also should point out that we still have time to order ships for 2012. I mean, this isn't like something that we have to do tomorrow in order to get the ships in 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And again, we look at these as 30-year assets. If we don't get them in '12 and we get them in '13 or we get them in '14, that's fine. We look at these as very long-term investments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Steve Kent with Goldman Sachs. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Just on the current stuff, can you just talk about trends and cancellations, any price adjustments on already booked cruises? So just to give us a sense on that. And then, Howard, just on this expense structure, you alluded to that you have a program in place to reduce expenses. And I can't help but notice that every hotel, every gaming company, has made massive cutbacks in overhead and in CapEx. And I just wanted to hear if you could give us a dollar amount as to what your expenses are? Would that include travel agent commission cuts, and would it include consolidation of your multiple headquarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all &#x2013; let me answer the last one first. The reality is that we have been a very cost-efficient, high-margin business from day one. We are working diligently to maintain that culture in the company. But we have done it without massive or drastic cuts that negatively impact the business for the long term. A hotel can close a wing and lay off hundreds of workers. We can't close a deck of a ship. And the economic environment doesn't allow you to do that anyway. Laying up ships also, unless the situation is that you've got two ships in the same itinerary at 50% load factor, which doesn't exist, the economics don't work for laying up a ship. So it's just &#x2013; we're not in the hotel business. We're in a very, very different environment and in different business.</p>
          <p>The other part of your questions about travel agent commission, the answer is absolutely not. Times like this, more than ever we need a strong distribution system. And we need folks out there selling the cruise concept, selling our various brands all over the country, hundreds of thousands of them, the more the merrier. And the reality is that we will support that distribution as long as I'm CEO of this company. What was the first part of the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Headquarters, Micky?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. This is Howard. I mean, we've had this discussion before, and our view is that when you have unique brands with different cultures and different &#x2013; in many cases different markets &#x2013; it would be a huge risk to try to go to bring everybody into one place. And quite honestly, when you look at the risk of doing that versus the potential rewards &#x2013; because we have run numbers on it &#x2013; you just can't justify, nor do we think it makes -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Or companies that have that model have lower margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So really what we have been focusing on is more data centers and consolidation of data centers and looking for more shared services, procurement, working together on potential opportunities we have in Alaska. I mean there's just a whole variety of different things that we're doing right now, and we have current organizations &#x2013; we have current committees of all the companies working on these things, and we've made some progress actually in 2008, and then we hope to see a whole lot more progress in 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And when you add all of that up, Howard, how much money is it? Are you keeping track of it for your Board?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, we have internally, we have projections, and we provide the information to the Board, yes. We haven't externally published the information. But clearly, it is a very nice opportunity. Some of that is actually baked into the numbers, the cost numbers for 2009, some of it is not. So I'd hate to give out a number, but it's a nice number. But hopefully we get from the 1% to the flat; that's our charge. And what would 1% be, David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>1% in cruise costs would -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Taking out the --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; be about $65 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Without fuel, it'd be about $55 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So it's in that range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Also you mentioned CapEx. Most of our CapEx of course is fixed, relating to the new-builds. But we do have a portion of the CapEx, which is maintenance CapEx. Since the budget's been put together, we've gone around to all of the operating companies. I've asked them to take another look at that CapEx and to reduce it where it was absolutely possible. So we're doing everything we can to reduce costs, reduce CapEx, and preserve cash.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But again, we're doing it in a way that would be unperceivable to a customer or to a travel agent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On CapEx, have you talked to the shipyards about delaying new deliveries? Seems like everything is negotiable in this environment. We've seen things that we would've never seen, everything from airlines to hotels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know why everybody's focused on delaying deliveries. No, we have not. The reality is that when we want to mitigate growth in a particular market &#x2013; if you look at the majority of the new builds in &#x2013; this spring it's AIDA and Costa, it's all in Europe. And the reality is there's ways to mitigate capacity increases without delaying new-builds. The reality is that in the European theater, we have significantly mitigated the growth next year. We sold the QE2. We delayed the delivery of the Holiday to Ibero Cruceros. We're transferring two of the Ocean Village's ships from the UK market to the Australian market. And Costa is moving one ship from Europe to Asia. So there's ways to mitigate growth in a particular market without delaying new builds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if it ever got to that point, we would &#x2013; you would probably take an older ship out of service rather than delay the new build. You want the new build.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know if you were able to answer the &#x2013; any cancellations or pricing adjustments on already-booked cruises?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cancellations have increased.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The consumer environment is, as everybody knows, difficult.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have seen more of an increase &#x2013; I mean, it varies depending on the brand, but we have seen some increases in cancellations across all brands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And clearly, we've taken that into consideration as we put together the guidance that we gave you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was more than two questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Steve Wieczynski with Stifel Nicolaus. Please proceed with your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning, guys. When you look out to what used to be the important wave season coming up, I mean how subdued do you think that period's going to be? And would you think that the bulk of the summer bookings, as the booking window continues to shrink, is that going to move closer to an April to May kind of time period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I wish we knew. The reality is that baked into our numbers is a concern about the consumer, obviously, for all of '09. And I think we view the condition, I think baked into our numbers it's a deteriorating situation as you go into the year, because obviously the booking pattern for September would have been for second or third quarter. September to now would have been strong for second and third quarter historically. So we don't know.</p>
          <p>We're hopeful there'll be a bounce-back. We predicted a bounce-back after the election. We actually did see that. We did see volumes improve. The five weeks after the election, the volumes improved year-over-year versus the five weeks prior to the election, but unfortunately with deteriorating yield, and that's why we adjusted the numbers. So we're hopeful that it will be a reasonable wave period, but I must say we're all cautious in our outlook because we all read the same newspapers and see what's going on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then the last question, in terms of &#x2013; it's been pretty helpful in the past in terms of onboard spending, in terms of what you're seeing, where you're seeing strength and where you're seeing weakness?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Clearly -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it just across the board?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, overall it's in the same areas that we had talked about before, art auctions, bar, casinos, generally speaking, and as you can imagine we took our onboards down in the guidance for 2009 along with the ticket prices, which is how we got to the 6 to 10% reduction overall that Howard mentioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of John Jares with The Boston Company. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, good morning. Howard, I just had a quick question for you. You indicated you thought the booking gaps would close as time progressed. I'm curious, is that just a result of the shorter booking window, or are there other factors there that you're counting on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, what I'm talking about is the shorter booking windows. I think that Micky mentioned that if you look at first quarter now, which is substantially done &#x2013; I mean, we've got more to book, but you can see booking volumes now in the first quarter week-over-week &#x2013; prior week last year &#x2013; are running ahead. So what happens is that we're getting the bookings late. They're coming in closer to the cruise, but what also happens is that you're not able to sustain the pricing. So we see deterioration in pricing as a result of the closer-in booking pattern.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then one other question is, back in &#x2013; as you mentioned around September 11, there were a fair amount of, I guess I would describe them as weak sisters that went out of business. How much competition is out there that potentially could suffer, maybe be reduced, maybe be eliminated, as a result of the difficult environment we're experiencing now? Is there much left to go?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, I don't think we should comment on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That wouldn't be appropriate, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of <mark type="inaudible" />. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Question, Micky, maybe you can help me. Q4 outperformed your October 31 expectations, even though at the time obviously we were pretty much done with Q4. Is Q1 in 2009 guidance as conservative?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I hope so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll let David answer that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what you have to recognize is that of the $0.10 that we beat guidance, $0.06 was purely due to lower fuel prices. So a lot of the increase was just as a result of the market and the drop in fuel. And as Micky talked before, he had said that a couple of pennies was due to higher-than-expected revenue yields, and these things are very difficult to project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's fair to say that I don't &#x2013; I think the revenue picture probably won't dramatically change from where we think it's going to be in Q1. I don't think &#x2013;  maybe a little bit. But I think from a cost side, Micky already mentioned that from the time &#x2013; we priced out &#x2013; for purposes of the guidance, we priced out on Monday's fuel prices &#x2013; I'm turning to David -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Monday at close.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So that's improved. And if it stays at those levels, clearly there's some opportunity in those two areas from currency standpoint and fuel standpoint to show some improvement in Q1 earnings &#x2013; if they stay at the levels that we have today. So there has been just some improvement in the last few days. But it is a very &#x2013; fuel and currency are moving very dramatically, and it's hard to know three months out what it's going to look like for the period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to the yield, the yield is based on what the yield management people at the brands delivered to their management and they delivered to us. And obviously they are human beings, and they watch CNBC, and they're hearing everything else, and that conservatism is built into a concern over where the consumer's going to be next year. And that's built into the number. And was built into the number in October.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Given that we are still a couple of weeks away from wave season, and I imagine booking volumes at present are probably &#x2013; at some of their lowest for the year, given that people are focused on the holidays rather than on their vacation plans for '09, do you think there could be upside to expectations for Q2 and Q3? Clearly, Q1 is probably over on the revenue side or pretty much over, but how about the more critical Q2 and Q3?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mentioned that when the President takes office and his new administration, and if you assume that they get through a fiscal stimulus plan pretty quickly, which I think they will, I think that could be a very positive factor psychologically, I think, for consumers and Americans. And I think that could benefit the wave season. But you know, it's really hard to know right now because you just can't see it in the numbers we're booking right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One of the reasons we gave a broader range than normal, which was a $0.50 range, is because of the uncertainty that Howard just mentioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think &#x2013; it's always interesting to me, because all during '08, we had a lot of skepticism in the market that we could deliver the revenue in such a weak economic environment. And of course nobody now is focusing on the 2.90 we delivered in 2008. Everybody including yourself is focusing on '09, and that's logical, but the reality is we delivered, despite the economy. And all I can say is that we've outperformed virtually every area of leisure, and we believe we will do it in '09. Now what does that mean? I mean, that &#x2013; it means we will do better than the rest of the industry, but how will the rest of the industry do? And time will only tell. But sometimes you do have to look back to understand and have the confidence in the future. And when you look back, we've always outperformed in tough economic environments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Micky, I'm clearly with you in hoping that you outperform the number you gave us today. So I guess we'll have to wait until wave season and see how bookings continue for '09. Thank you for -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can assure you that the number we're after is the highest possible number that can be achieved, and not whatever we're giving you as guidance. That is not our goal. That is just our number to give you guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What is it the highest possible number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, well, who knows?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tell me what fuel's going to look like and tell me what currency's going to look like, and I'll give you a better sense of -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tell me if banks are going to be lending any money in the first quarter and people going to be able to use their credit cards and buy cars and -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If credit frees up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, yeah, is General Motors going to be in business, and how many more people will be unemployed, and you know. We run cruise companies, we're not economists.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of <mark type="inaudible" />. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Briefly, fuel, have you contracted fuel out further because of the current low price, or are you playing it as close as you normally do?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now we're playing it as close as we normally do. But as we said before, we always look at those options and we continue to look at those options. But as of today, we are taking full advantage of the lower fuel price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I apologize, Micky, for the add-on here. Am I to take that to mean if you're taking full advantage where you normally would contract out for three months you might be contracting out for four or five months now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean full advantage in that the declines you see today will be in our price this weekend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Second question, in terms of the potential tonnage that might be coming onto the market as lesser-heeled competitors were to go by the wayside, if we leave out your major publicly traded competitor, is there any tonnage out there that you would be willing to buy? And if so, which fleets would you give it to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it would be appropriate to answer that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. That's inappropriate, <mark type="inaudible" /> and I don't think we know the answer to that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, is it inappropriate &#x2013; I'm not asking you to identify where the tonnage would come from. All I'm saying is were there to be another Renaissance, were there to be whatever, where tonnage was made available that you would be able to purchase, would you in fact &#x2013; a) is there any tonnage out there you would be willing to buy? And if so, which fleets would it go to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there any tonnage we'd be willing to buy? The answer to that question is yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The question of which fleet would it go to would depend solely on the tonnage, which would be inappropriate to respond to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then absent that then, if there was tonnage available, would you start a new brand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I apologize. I was not trying to put you onto the defensive with that question. It was more -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you were, <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I get accused of many things for many reasons. But when I make a statement that -- it was done with no malice of forethought, it is meant as such.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We know, we know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe you, <mark type="inaudible" />I know that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of <mark type="inaudible" />. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I just had a question regarding deposits on the balance sheet. I was reading in some trade rags that some agents are seeing customers ask for refunds at a much more increased rate than has been historically, even in the face of paying penalties and such. I was wondering what your experience is with refunds of deposits and how you think that may play out in 2009 and if it would be anything meaningful?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Howard had indicated, the refund of deposit is just another way of saying a cancellation, because when somebody makes a booking, they put money down, and if they're canceling, they get their money back. And Howard has indicated cancellations are up, but we have taken that into consideration in our guidance for 2009. So we understand that trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But indeed that is happening, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We see that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So could that &#x2013; I guess when I look at the balance sheet, could that cause a cash flow issue,? Meaning &#x2013; I'm not suggesting this is what happens. But if half the people said, "We want our money, we'd like to cancel," I think there was $2 billion worth of deposit liabilities on the balance sheet. Would we in theory then have to give half of that back and then come up with $1 billion of cash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you're talking -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a rolling number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a rolling number. Remember, most of those people are actually in the next six to eight weeks because -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They are the fully paid people -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fully paid people.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; that make up the majority of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But there is &#x2013; as booking curve moves in that deposit liability account will decline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because you have less people on the books. And it has declined -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, we saw a &#x2013; net of the currency movement, we did see a decline of 3% in 2008. And obviously, in taking a look at that and the cash flow projection that Howard gave for 2009 at the midpoint, we took into account the slower booking curve and perhaps also a decrease in customer deposits there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When Howard went through the liquidity information, clearly that is one key element of the liquidity, which we look at very carefully.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So when forecasting it out, we assume we're going to see more of that, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And some lower deposit liability as a result.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. All righty, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And we have a follow-up question from the line of Rick Lyall with John W. Bristol. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry for the follow-up, guys. But two quick questions. One on group bookings, have you seen any divergence in the behavior of groups versus individuals? I.e., are the groups canceling and then re-booking at lower prices? And then secondarily, I wanted to follow up on the note that talked about your P&amp;I recovery &#x2013; or there was a call for 2006, 2008. And I was surprised at that, because usually P&amp;I guys just adjust their rates prospectively. So what was the nature of that retro call, if you will?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. On the P&amp;I, the way our P&amp;I insurance works &#x2013; and this has been this way for as long as I've been in the cruise industry &#x2013; you pay a certain premium every year, and there are what is called supplemental calls that could potentially come after the fact. Any particular year in P&amp;I stays open for three years before they close the year, because there's a long tail of claims. And so sometimes if the clubs have a very high claim experience &#x2013; or as in what's occurring right now too, is low investment income &#x2013; it could require some additional supplemental calls. And so these calls related back to 2006 and 2008, and we accrued them in the fourth quarter. So it's very typical, nothing unusual.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I understand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This has been the way clubs work forever. Your question about groups is really tough. It appears that the behavior of the groups are quite similar to the behavior of the regular FIT bookings. Maybe slightly less year-over-year decline versus FIT but not significant enough. I mean, if you put it on a graph, the graphs would look pretty similar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Dominique Mielle with Canyon Cap. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I wanted to ask you, as you look at your product line and potentially acquisitions, what is the product that's most attractive to you in terms of price point? Is it the low end, mid-end, luxury line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're really not looking at making, quite honestly, making any acquisitions right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I recognize this is completely hypothetical.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what Micky said was that if ships became available as a result of a competitor having difficulties, we might be interested in acquiring a ship if the price was right depending on and betting on whether it worked for one of our existing products in our fleet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So putting aside acquisition, what is the best return on investment category at this point, given the environment and the fact that consumers pretty much along &#x2013; everywhere are suffering, but maybe some price point is better than others?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now, as Howard said, the contemporary, the lower-cost product is the one that's performing the best, for obvious reasons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But that hopefully is just a temporary phenomenon. So we'll see. But it's very difficult to answer that question. Clearly, if you're looking for margins profitability, McDonald's makes more money than a three-star Michelin Guide restaurant. And historically the cruise industry has worked in a similar way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Sharon Zackfia with William Blair. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. This may be a rather naive question. I'm kind of new to this story. But I'm just curious, since you're seeing some changes in consumer behavior and you mentioned more of an interest in the shorter itineraries and the more value-oriented cruises. Is there any opportunity as you look into 2010 to change the lengths of some cruises or change the itineraries? And then separately, does the current mindset from the consumer change your marketing message at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the marketing message is really brand-specific, and each brand has very different marketing message and makes tweaks and adjustments. You'll be seeing a new Carnival Cruise Lines campaign break very soon, which slightly tweaks the message, but it's still very fun-focused, as Carnival has always been.</p>
          <p>Your first question's a very good one, actually. When you look at, for example, Europe deployment, the premium brands that operate most of their ships in Europe and Alaska in the summertime &#x2013; we've gotten a lot of questions about that. And despite the fact that we see a lot of challenge in those markets for the North American brands, they still are forecasting yields that would be higher even in this difficult environment than moving the ship back to the Caribbean.</p>
          <p>Summer Caribbean is a mass market product, and while our mass-market brands do very well there &#x2013; our mass market brand does very well there &#x2013; the reality is that it would take a lot of deterioration in Europe and Alaska to move those ships back to the Caribbean, because there is a significant premium that those markets receive. Now, that premium will be lower this year than the prior couple of years. But still not low enough to force movement. However, our brands look at this ship by ship every year, but the effect of that will be felt in 2010, not before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Time is running late. If there is one more question, we'll take one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And gentlemen, we have no further questions at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Okay. Well, thank you very much, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I want to wish you all a happy holiday season and a happy and healthy new year, and hopefully a more prosperous new year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Everybody should go out and see "Spamalot." Happy holidays to everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude your conference call for today. We thank you for your participation and ask that you please disconnect your line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>