<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1524516" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-12-20</date>
    <companies>
      <company>69010</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice Chairman &amp; Chief Operating Officer">Howard S. Frank</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Senior Vice President">David Bernstein</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Robin M. Farley</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Micky Meir Arison</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Beth Roberts</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Felicia Hendrix</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Inc. (Broker)">Gregory Robert Badishkanian</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Nick R. Thomas</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Securities International, Inc.">Harry C. Curtis</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="William Blair &amp; Co. LLC">Sharon Zackfia</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Stifel, Nicolaus &amp; Co., Inc.">Steven M. Wieczynski</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Wells Fargo Securities LLC">Tim A. Conder</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Infinity Research">Assia Georgieva</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Steven E. Kent</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="John W. Bristol &amp; Co., Inc. (New York)">Rick Ellis Lyall</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Fourth Quarter 2012 Earnings Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Afterwards, we will conduct a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded, Thursday, December 20, 2012. I would now like to turn the conference over to Howard Frank, Vice Chairman and Chief Operating Officer. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and good afternoon, to everyone. Welcome to the Carnival Corporation conference call. With me this morning is Micky Arison, David Bernstein and Beth Roberts, and we are all here in Miami on the call.</p>
          <p>Let's start the call. I'm going to turn it over to David and he can take you through the fourth quarter and the year 2012. David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Howard. Before I begin, please note that as some of our remarks on this conference call will be forward-looking, I will refer you to the cautionary statement in today's press release. Also, all of my references to revenue and cost metrics will be in local currencies. Therefore, unless otherwise noted, as this is the more useful measure of our business trends.</p>
          <p>Our non-GAAP EPS for the fourth quarter was $0.13. The fourth quarter came in $0.04 above the midpoint of our September guidance despite a $0.02 impact from Hurricane Sandy. The improvement was driven by higher net revenue yields worth $0.05, as pricing on close-in bookings was 1% better than expected &#x2013; a trend similar to last quarter; and lower fuel prices combined with more favorable currency exchange rates positively impacted the results by $0.03. Both of these improvements were partially offset by higher than expected net cruise costs, excluding fuel, costing $0.04 per share.</p>
          <p>Now let's look at our fourth quarter operating results versus the prior year. Our capacity increased 2.7%. The North American brands were up 3.7% while Europe, Australia and Asia brands, or as we call them, our EAA brands, were up 1.2%. Our total net revenue yields decreased 4.5 points in the fourth quarter, but showed sequential improvement versus the third quarter. It should be noted that almost half of the decline in the fourth quarter was driven by Costa. Excluding Costa, net revenue yields decreased 2.4%, driven by a 4% decline in net ticket revenue yields and that was partially offset by a 2% increase in net onboard and other revenue yields.</p>
          <p>With respect to our net ticket yields, the North American brands were down 3.7%, driven by declines in late-season Europe and Alaska while yields in the Caribbean and all other remaining itineraries held up relatively well during the quarter. Excluding Costa, our EAA brands net ticket yields were down slightly less at 3.4%, driven by the European brands, while net ticket yields in Asia were up nicely. For net onboard and other yields, again excluding Costa, the increase was 2% with increases on both sides of the Atlantic and in all major categories of onboard revenue.</p>
          <p>On the cost side, net cruise costs per available lower berth day excluding fuel was down 1% versus the prior year. The decline was less than we expected in our September guidance. As I have said in the past, it's very difficult to estimate the timing of many of our expenses by quarter, and therefore, the better measure of net cruise cost performances is on an annual basis. As a result of our ongoing efforts to reduce fuel usage, our consumption for ALBD declined 4.4% this quarter, thus continuing our multiple-year savings trend. Fuel prices this quarter were up 5% versus the prior year, which cost us $0.04. In summary, the fourth quarter non-GAAP EPS was $0.13. This was lower than 2011 earnings of $0.28 per share, driven primarily by lower operating income at Costa.</p>
          <p>Now looking at the full year 2012. As Mickey stated in the earnings release, this past year has been the most challenging year in our company's history as a result of the Costa Concordia incident. The ship incident had a profound impact on each and every employee of the company, both shore side and shipboard, and has driven all of us to reinforce our commitment to the safety of our guests and crew. We have taken numerous steps to identify lessons learned and best practices. In addition, we have and will continue to implement improvements to our procedures and our training programs. Furthermore, we have improved the structure and organization of our health, environmental, safety and security-related audit functions. Over the next few years, we expect to fully recover from this ship incident and continue to build on our leadership position.</p>
          <p>For 2012, our non-GAAP EPS was $1.88 versus the prior year's $2.42. The decrease was driven by lower net revenue yields costing $0.41, and higher fuel prices combined with unfavorable currency exchange rates costing an additional $0.39. Both of these were partially offset by slightly lower cruise costs, 4% lower fuel consumption, and increased capacity worth $0.25.</p>
          <p>For 2012, our net revenue yields excluding Costa were in line with the prior year. Our North American brands were up slightly, but that was offset by our EAA brands excluding Costa which were down slightly. Our 2012 net revenue yields including Costa declined 2.5%.</p>
          <p>Turning to our cash flow, as Micky indicated in the earnings release, our cash from operations was $3 billion, which was more than enough to fund the net capital investments of $1.8 billion, leaving us with free cash flow of $1.2 billion for 2012. By the end of December, we have will have returned all of this free cash flow to our shareholders via a $0.25 per share regular quarterly dividend, a recently announced special dividend of $0.50 per share, and by repurchasing 3.5 million of our company shares.</p>
          <p>It should be noted that this is the second year in a row that we returned all of our free cash flow to shareholders. In 2011, the dividends paid and shares repurchased totaled $1.1 billion, which represented all of our 2011 free cash flow.</p>
          <p>Now turning to our 2013 outlook. I will skip net revenue yields as Howard will discuss that shortly. As you know, we have an excellent record of cost control. For 2013, our operating companies have done an excellent job identifying ways to reduce forecasted costs. However, there are a few unique items in 2013 that will be difficult to totally overcome which will push our unit costs higher.</p>
          <p>To begin with, we are expecting that Costa will fill their ships in 2013, which will lead to higher food and other unit costs associated with this higher occupancy. Also, as I have previously indicated, our insurance costs will be higher in 2013. Furthermore, we are anticipating a charge from a closed pension plan for certain British officers. Finally, we are investing in new market development initiatives in Japan, China and Australia including deployment decisions not yet announced. These unique factors alone in 2013 will drive up unit costs 2%.</p>
          <p>To complete the cost picture, as you know we have also had some ship incident related costs in 2012, which are not expected to reoccur in 2013 worth about 0.5%. The net effect of these factors is that we are forecasting the full-year cost excluding fuel per ALBD to be up 1% to 2% versus the prior year. Absent these items, we once again expect to offset inflation and keep unit costs essentially flat in 2013. However, even if you include these unique factors, our five-year expected cost trend from 2008 through 2013 will be flat net cruise costs excluding fuel on a unit basis despite inflation.</p>
          <p>Another multiple year trend worth noting is our fuel consumption. As a result of our operating companies' efforts over the years, we expect in 2013 to use 24% less fuel per berth than we did in 2005. This is a substantial energy saving, which clearly reduces our environmental footprint.</p>
          <p>I want to share with you our current rules of thumb about the impact that fuel price changes and currency changes have on our results. To start with, a 10% change in the current price of fuel excluding the impact of fuel derivatives represents a $0.30 per share impact for the full year. Please note that the impact of a 10% change obviously moves along with the price of fuel. Just to be clear, the price of Brent was just under $110 a barrel when we determined our guidance.</p>
          <p>The second rule of thumb relates to our fuel derivative portfolio where the next 10% increase in the price of Brent for the year will not result in any realized gains as the price of Brent would still be within the band of our tolerance. However, the next 10% decrease would result in a $4 million loss.</p>
          <p>For 2013, our protection begins with the price of Brent &#x2013; when the price of Brent goes above $127 per barrel, and we begin to pay on our fuel derivatives when the price of Brent falls below $100 per barrel. With respect to FX movement, a 10% change in all relevant currencies related to the U.S. dollar would impact our P&amp;L by approximately $158 million or $0.20 a share for the full year.</p>
          <p>On a final note, for 2013, at the midpoint of our guidance range, we expect our cash from operations to be $3.3 billion, our capital investment in 2013 is forecasted to be $2 billion which leaves us $1.3 billion of free cash flow that we expect to return to shareholders. This would result in a total return to shareholders of over $3.5 billion in a three-year period from 2011 to 2013.</p>
          <p>At this point, I will turn the call over to Howard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David. Before I move to the outlook, let me begin my comments by framing the 2013 year.</p>
          <p>We have two ships scheduled for delivery in 2013. The first is the 2,200 little berth, AIDAstella, which will be delivered in March to our very successful AIDA brand in the German-speaking market. And the next one will be the new generation Royal Princess with 3,600 lower berths, which will be delivered sometime towards the end of May. These two ships together with three ships delivered during this past year 2012 will drive a 3.6% increase in cruise capacity in 2013.</p>
          <p>For the full year 2013, our cruise programs will be approximately 33% in the Caribbean, 19% in the Mediterranean, 12% in Europe outside of the Mediterranean, 10% in the Australia Asia region, and with the balance in various other itineraries. The largest increase in our cruise programs in 2013 from a percentage standpoint is in the Australia Asia region and in Europe outside of the Mediterranean.</p>
          <p>Our earnings guidance for 2013 has been established within a range of $2.20 to $2.40 or a midpoint of $2.30 per share, about 20% higher than in 2012. Our earnings guidance for 2013 assumes that the U.S. does not go off the fiscal cliff in January and go into an economic recession during 2013. Hopefully, wisdom will prevail in Washington and January will be the start of a solid 2013 wave season.</p>
          <p>In Europe where we have a strong market presence, we anticipate continuing struggling economies during 2013, much as we experienced during 2012. With regard to our strategy to grow our European cruise businesses, let me make a few comments.</p>
          <p>From a longer-term viewpoint, we are committed to maintaining our strong national brands' presence in Europe. We believe European economies will improve over time and our strong European brands' positioning, together with their significant market penetration throughout Europe and the UK, provides us with a significant market advantage. Even during these difficult economic periods in Europe, our European brands continue to provide us with strong profitability and returns on invested capital. And when Europe economies start to grow again, we will have an even stronger competitive advantage.</p>
          <p>In the Asia markets, we are planning a significant increase in our footprint. In April 2013, Princess Cruises will introduce the Sun Princess to the Japanese market, and we have recently established a Carnival Japan sales and reservations office in Tokyo. With the announcement of the Sun Princess Japanese deployment, response from the market in Japan has been very strong and early signs are quite encouraging.</p>
          <p>In Southeast Asia, we are adding a second Costa ship this spring, the Costa Atlantica, doubling our capacity in the market. With the Costa Victoria operating in Asia year-round in 2012 this past year, for the first time Costa achieved profitability in China. In 2013, operating plan forecasts a nice increase in Costa Asia's profitability.</p>
          <p>We believe Asia represents a significant opportunity to grow our cruise business in the future and we are currently looking at expanding our business in these new and emerging markets.</p>
          <p>We recently established our Carnival Asia corporate office in Singapore headed by Pier Foschi who has considerable business experience operating in Asia. We will have further announcements in early 2013 on fleet expansion in Asia beyond 2013.</p>
          <p>In Australia, Carnival Cruise Lines successfully introduced the Carnival Spirit to the market at the end of this past year &#x2013; for the year that we're in, 2012. And the response from the Australian consumer has been very strong. Carnival Spirit will be a year-round ship in the Australian market.</p>
          <p>So to sum it up, we are very encouraged about our business going forward in 2013, and although the struggling economies in Europe are having some impact on our business, we are very confident that the company will achieve solid growth and profitability over the next several years, and at the same time be able to return significant excess cash flow to shareholders in the form of dividends and stock repurchases.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to the booking picture for 2013. During the last 13 weeks, fleet-wide bookings and pricing excluding Costa for the first three quarters of 2013, are at the same levels against the very strong booking volumes we experienced last year. Not surprisingly, Costa's pricing is still running behind last year's pricing, but we expect that to change once we lap January of 2012.</p>
          <p>For our North American brands, during the 13-week period, bookings are running slightly behind with slightly higher pricing. For EAA brands, the bookings excluding Costa are running at higher levels than last year at lower pricing. We are encouraged by the recent North American booking pattern, especially given consumer distraction from the elections and post-election consumer nervousness about the pending fiscal cliff, and the recent pattern excludes some negative impact on bookings from the Northeast resulting from the Hurricane Sandy. So we are hopeful that once the fiscal cliff issue is resolved and we get into January, and the wave season begins, consumers will start to turn their attention getting on with their lives and booking their cruise vacations.</p>
          <p>For the full year, from a revenue yield forecast standpoint, we are forecasting a constant currency increase in yield in the range of 1% to 2%. North American revenue yields are forecasted to come in higher year-over-year, EAA yields are forecasted to be higher when we include Costa, which will have easier comps versus last year, but excluding Costa, EAA yields are forecasted to be lower on a year-over-year basis.</p>
          <p>Given the economic challenges in the European markets in which we operate, the positive yield outlook, which includes of course Costa, demonstrates the resilience of our cruise business in Europe, the underlying strength of the European consumer, and the propensity for Europeans to take their vacations even during these difficult times. And while we would have liked to see even stronger rebound in revenue yields in 2013, the less-than-robust U.S. economy and the struggling European economies will make higher pricing increases difficult to achieve.</p>
          <p>In terms of our earnings guidance for 2013, broadly speaking, our forecasted earnings improvement is expected to come from top line revenue growth of 5% to 6%, which includes a 3.6% fleet-wide capacity increase and a 1% to 2% yield increase which I previously referred to.</p>
          <p>We are also forecasting lower fuel pricing and a 5% improvement in fuel consumption. Net cruise costs other than fuel are expected to increase 1% to 2%, as David mentioned. All of this translates to an earnings per share range of $2.20 to $2.40, or approximately a 20% increase in earnings if you're using the midpoint of $1.88 per share in 2012.</p>
          <p>Turning to the first quarter, a little bit of color. My comments on bookings in each of these next three quarters that I discuss will include Costa's information for both years unless I otherwise indicate. Fleet-wide capacity for the first quarter of 2013 is expected to be 4.2% higher, 3.6% of that is in North America, 5.1% in EAA. At the present time, fleet-wide occupancy of the first quarter are lower than a year ago with pricing slightly lower versus last year. There is very little inventory, however, remaining to be sold in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter for North American brands, they are 65% in the Caribbean, with the balance in various other itineraries. For North American brands taken together, occupancies and pricing are slightly lower year-over-year.</p>
          <p>As previously mentioned, revenue yield comparisons for first quarter of 2013 versus first quarter of 2012 are tougher, given our strong first quarter North American revenue yield performance in 2012, which at this point was up 5% &#x2013; at this point in time. Caribbean pricing is in line with the year ago pricing and all other itineraries taken together is lower than the year ago.</p>
          <p>EAA brands are 24% in Europe. Itineraries up from 19% last year, 18% in the Caribbean down from 22% last year at 18% in South America, about the same as last year. The balance of course is in all other itineraries. On a fleet-wide basis, EAA brand occupancies are behind last year with lower year-over-year pricing.</p>
          <p>On a fleet-wide basis, as we indicated in the press release, revenue yields for the first quarter are forecasted to be 2% to 3% lower than last year. North American revenue yields are expected to be flat to slightly lower and EAA yields will be lower.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the second quarter fleet-wide capacity, which is up 3.2%, 2.3% for North America and 4.6% for EAA brands. At the present time on a fleet-wide basis, local currency pricing is slightly lower than a year ago with occupancies running behind last year, evidencing the continuing close-in booking cycle that we have been experiencing for quite some time. We expect second quarter occupancies and pricing to show gradual year-over-year improvement as we fully cycle through January of 2013.</p>
          <p>North American brands are 53% in the Caribbean in the first quarter versus quarter versus 56% last year with the balance in a variety of other itineraries. For North American brands taken together, pricing is slightly higher at lower occupancies. Caribbean pricing is higher than a year ago; prices for all other North American brand and itineraries taken together are slightly lower than a year ago.</p>
          <p>EAA brands are 59% in Europe, up from 53% last year with the balance in various other trades. EAA brand pricing is lower than last year at lower occupancies. Although occupancy and pricing for the second quarter are behind last year, we do expect to see a catch-up when we fully cycle through the first quarter. Whilst an easier comparison, we do expect to see an improvement in revenue yields for both North America and EAA brands by the time the second quarter closes.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the third quarter. Capacity in the third quarter is expected to increase 3.7%, 4.5% in North America, 2.6% in EAA. Third quarter booking patterns are still in the early stages of development, so I caution not to read too much into this information. On a fleet-wide basis, third quarter occupancies and pricing are behind last year.</p>
          <p>For North American brands, capacity in the third quarter is 38% in the Caribbean, which was about the same as last year; 24% in Alaska and &#x2013; also the same; and 26% in Europe, which is slightly higher than last year. The balance of the itineraries are in various other programs.</p>
          <p>Overall, pricing for North American brands is higher than a year ago at lower occupancies. Pricing for Caribbean and Alaska cruises is higher than last year, while the pricing for European cruises is about at the same levels as last year. EAA brand capacity is 87% in the Europe itineraries, which is slightly lower than last year. EAA pricing is lower than a year ago at lower occupancies.</p>
          <p>As I commented on earlier, it is still early in the booking pattern and much of the third quarter revenue picture will depend on the strength of the 2013 wave season. We are currently forecasting that third quarter revenue yields for North America will be higher.</p>
          <p>EAA will also be higher year-over-year with the yield improvement driven by the easier revenue comparisons for Costa in the third quarter. Excluding Costa, we do expect the EAA revenue yields to decline in the third quarter on a year-over-year basis.</p>
          <p>And with that, Charlene, I will turn it back to you and we'll open it up for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And our first question comes from the line of Robin Farley with UBS. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I guess just trying to understand how much it's &#x2013; that you're being conservative in your guidance versus how challenging the outlook is, because you had talked about this year that Costa's occupancy &#x2013; the Costa brand alone that occupancy has been down around six points. So it seems like even just recovering that occupancy alone for the Costa brand would get to the company-wide yield increase that you guys are talking about across all the brands so I guess I wonder if you can just put some perspective on that, and then I guess how much lower are the other EAA brands ex Costa I guess that's the only thing that would kind of make the companywide be only up as much as Costa's occupancy recovery.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me give you a kind of the broad strokes on it because there's a lot of detail that we probably can't get into on this call, but we're going to have higher yields in North America as I indicated. We're going to have higher yields in Costa and we estimate that perhaps 50% of our yield deterioration in Costa last year will be recovered, and the neighborhood of that will be recovered this year &#x2013; this coming year in 2013. And the rest of Europe outside of Costa will have lower yields.</p>
          <p>So, that's sort of a composite of the three elements that make up the yield picture, and what I've tried to indicate in my comments, Robin, is that in a year in which we do have increased capacity in Europe, especially in Germany where we also had increased capacity in 2012, and given the headwinds in the economies in Europe and the very close-in booking pattern that we're seeing in Europe. In Germany, the UK and in Southern Europe, it's very difficult to forecast yields because it depends on how bookings start to come in in the wave period. Whether we're conservative or we're not conservative, I think it is a forecast based on the best work that our brands can give us right now in these markets, and could we do better, sure; could we do worse, of course. It is early and let's see how it goes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Robin, a couple of points to make is, one, I think we've been consistent in saying that recovery of Costa is not a one-year issue, it's going to be multiple years; and we're forecasting a recovery of about half the yield deterioration, that's one item. Two is it's important to understand that we don't cycle through this until the second quarter because the first quarter was done, and the timing of first quarter in this instant versus competitors is very important because it did happen in the middle of our first quarter when the first quarter was done. So, that's impacting it as well. So, I think those two &#x2013; the combination of those two things significantly answer your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And maybe just one point of clarification, because clearly no one would have expected full recovery at Costa in one year, but it seemed like the occupancy would be something that could come back pretty quickly, given that it came back between &#x2013; from January until the end of this year that &#x2013; therefore that 2013 Costa occupancy would be pretty well recovered even though there would clearly be work to do on the price recovery. Is that occupancy for Costa &#x2013; are you not expecting it to be back to recovering those six percentage points of occupancy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Robin, yes, we are &#x2013; included in the 50% that Howard mentioned is a full occupancy recovery. Costa was very close to normal occupancy in the fourth quarter and we are expecting normal occupancy and full ships for 2013, and that is the full 6% recovery in their occupancy. But as Howard mentioned, given the economy in Europe, they are expecting some price recovery on top of that, but the overall economic situation in Europe is tempering the amount of price recovery they are expecting to get.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Plus I would like to add if you start the first quarter being down in pricing for the Costa brand then the recovery in the back half for the year is a little bit heavier pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Felicia Hendrix with Barclays [Capital]. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, guys. So, Howard, this is also for you just as I'm trying to digest your guidance. I'm going to kind of preface my comments with knowing that &#x2013; with just acknowledging that &#x2013; and you all have seen us just talk about this for many years that talking to travel agents doesn't necessarily always correlate to what you guys are seeing, but a lot of us do it because it's helpful in our research. That being said, our travel agents are implying to us that the 2013 yields in North America are more robust than your guidance would imply. So &#x2013; and then I'm also, on top of that, just lower capacity industry-wide should also help. So, if you add those two together, what you're saying is that North America seems more muted than a lot of us were expecting and I'm just trying to figure out, is this more related to perhaps the fiscal cliff right now, what we're seeing, maybe people are holding back, maybe some Sandy, or are we just totally off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm happy to hear that travel agents are feeling that pricing is going up; I think that's a positive. I mean, I don't know how...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we've also said that. North America pricing is up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, they're saying more than what you're &#x2013; higher than what you're saying.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know how that translates to our outlook because I think there are many factors at play in our yield outlook that travel agents &#x2013; you can't translate from travel agents' comments and/or the new individual data points. And it depends on what they're selling; if they're selling &#x2013; Caribbean looks strong now, so Caribbean business is pretty good. But then there are long cruises, there are Europe, I mean there's a whole variety of things that we look at and when you ask them the question, I'm not quite sure how it's asked, how the details of it is...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> first quarter is not in their mindset.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so it's very &#x2013; but I guess the bottom line is it's hard to know and we see the reports that you guys write in terms of your canvassing of travel agents and we kind of scratch our heads sometimes &#x2013; sometimes it's right on and sometimes we kind of scratch our heads and see it a little bit differently than they do, so it doesn't always correlate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One thing that you've got to keep in mind is that if you look at it on a quarter-by-quarter basis, we gave guidance for the first quarter down 2% to 3% because as Micky said, when the incident happened last year, we were almost done &#x2013; we were halfway through the quarter and the booking was essentially done. And last year, our yields were up quite a bit in the first quarter, so we're going to be down 2% to 3%. Howard had indicated we do expect the second quarter to be up, but when you look at the full year guidance of 1% to 2%, that does imply let's say 2% to 3% yield increase in the back half of the year. So it's possible that what you're getting and the discussion with the travel agents is more relating to those types of prices than it is the first quarter where we're down 2% to 3% from a very strong prior year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, last year in North America, we were up five points in the first quarter and I don't think the travel agents are focused on when you cycle through a quarter; they're just focusing on just general business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What they're doing today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What they're doing today, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's helpful. And then, Howard, something that you said actually gets to the next point of my question, which is can you just kind of give us some color on how things are &#x2013; you said that the Caribbean is strong now, but maybe some longer cruises aren't doing as well. Can you just give us some color so that we can understand the consumer mentality in terms of what things are selling well and what things have more challenges?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just say that our booking pattern in the fall has been strong. When you consider last year, it was extremely strong. But again, until we cycle the event and get into wave season, it just makes it very, very difficult.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and on top of that, we had the elections this year, which always presents a challenge in terms of consumer distraction. And then right after the election, where things start to normalize, we had the issue of the fiscal cliff which continues to nag us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As well as Sandy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So &#x2013; as well as Sandy. But I think &#x2013; I mean, I think we're doing okay. I think bookings, I think if we're seeing challenges from a North America standpoint, it's more on volume in terms of we're running behind &#x2013; although pricing is okay for Europe and Alaska going forward, we're running behind on occupancy. So the question is, is that going to resolve itself during wave season. And there is also the challenge of the higher air costs that we're all dealing with on the longer cruises, so but we're trying to hold price and we think &#x2013; everybody thinks they're going to get there, but it's a long time between now and late spring and summer when these cruises start to occur.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it sounds like your guidance &#x2013; it sounds like your guidance is not trying to anticipate what things might look like once we get past hopefully this fiscal cliff issue and other things, it's what you're kind of seeing now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The guidance is based on what our operating companies are telling me. And then we kind of take a look at it and if we think it &#x2013; we may make some minor tweaks to it, but only minor tweaks to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a couple of things that makes forecasting always challenging at this time of the year. One is the booking curve has clearly moved in, which makes forecasting tougher; and the fact that we have to do this prior to wave also makes it tougher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You could change your fiscal year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we could. We've talked about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the best thing is to resolve the fiscal cliff and we'll all be happier. We have to pay more taxes. Let it happen already; it's painful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I have some more questions but I've taken up enough time. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Felicia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Greg Badishkanian with Citigroup. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. My question is, if you go back to when you had your last earnings call, have things changed meaningfully, like if you were to have given guidance then versus now, would you say that would have been about the same?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't &#x2013; when you say would I have changed guidance, I don't think I know what guidance would have been back three months ago for 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Whoops.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're okay. We're okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's just a coffee cup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say one thing that we have been saying that Northern Europe and the UK have been strong, and in fact in 2012, we had a good year in both Germany and the UK. We're starting to have &#x2013; to see some effect of a weaker economy both in the UK and Germany, which we really didn't see a whole lot in 2012. So if there's anything different, I'd say we're a little bit more concerned. Although those brands are performing well, we are a little bit concerned going forward as the booking curve has tightened in those countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I guess I was just trying to get at, have things gotten a little bit incrementally better or worse since then, and that's helpful. And as you kind of look out to Europe, I know you typically talk about some of the markets that are weaker and stronger, has anything changed over the last month or two in any of the markets to make you a little bit more optimistic or pessimistic? Just maybe point out a market or two that you think has maybe changed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I just did. It's really Germany and the UK where we had a very good 2012. It looks a little bit weaker and the booking curve has moved in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the other hand, I'd just say in Germany we have &#x2013; just in the German market we have a lot of additional capacity coming in, on top of capacity last year. So, there's a big capacity increase and we've got a closer-in booking curve. Germany, you may recall, the German market I think was more profoundly affected than &#x2013; like Italy as a result of last year's &#x2013; last January's event. So, I think that's been a little bit slower to come back, although all the data and consumer research we've recently seen suggests that the German market will come back and that things will &#x2013; that people are feeling much more positive about taking cruises. So, we think that it's still a good market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The other thing that I haven't seen a lot of focus on is some of our competitors have talked about reducing capacity in Europe. But in reality, our two largest competitors together have increased the Northern Europe capacity by over 20% next year. So, the Northern Europe itineraries have tended to be the highest yielding itineraries in the European market, and that capacity increase will be interesting to see how that all plays out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Right. Good. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Nick Thomas with Bank of America. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Thomas, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Charlene, let's move on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Harry Curtis with Nomura Group [Nomura Securities International]. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I've got a quick question. This 1% to 2% is not a particularly satisfying number. And, could you give us your perspective after two years of Arab Spring and Costa, is it disappointing to you? And do you think that some of it is perhaps related to the amount of capacity that has moved into Europe? Does it maybe argue for moving some of the capacity out of Europe? And then the last add-on question is, from the point of view of profitability per berth, how close are you in Asia to maybe shifting some capacity to Asia and lifting your yields and EBITDA per berth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You made three comments, Harry, this is Howard; is the 1% to 2% not -are we not satisfied with it. I think directionally I think we're satisfied with it. Sometimes it's difficult &#x2013; consensus for yields and the investment community don't always match reality &#x2013; or what we see as reality in our particular markets, or even what our competitors are doing. We do have a lot more increase in capacity I think in 2013 than our competitors have; one of those increases will be in the German market. Perhaps that &#x2013; and on top of capacity increases we had last year. So when you look at Europe and Germany, we like the business there. We think it's a great &#x2013; it's an underpenetrated market, it's got great demographics, and even in these very challenging times, we get very good profitability from these brands even if yield's down 1% or 2,% and excellent returns.</p>
          <p>So, we see the strategy as staying in Europe as the right strategy for us, and to continue to penetrate those markets it only strengthens us from a competitive standpoint in the future, which is my earlier comments. I don't think moving ships around because we start to see some weakness in a particular market &#x2013; by the time you move them around and get them to the new market then the old markets come back. So, for us, that's a very short-term solution to what we think is a poor long-term strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I also &#x2013; a couple of things. One is I think you've got to look at the yield improvement after the first quarter, which is higher than the number you stated. Secondly, satisfied? I wouldn't be satisfied if it was five or six. I mean, we always want more obviously; we always push for more. The reality though is that our focus is profitability, our focus is profit per berth. We get overly focused on yield sometimes, and a great example of this is the fact that we're forecasting fuel consumption to be down 5% next year, and to do that we had to make some itinerary adjustments that risk yield. So, we'll trade yield for lower cost and then the yield number looks lower. The example I've used in the past is when we went from six-day transatlantic on Queen Mary to seven, we would be perfectly happy to have gotten 6.5 days of yield versus seven because the reduction in the fuel cost made up for more than the one-day yield. So, it's &#x2013; yield is just part of the equation. The real key is doing everything we can to increase our profit per berth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And as a &#x2013; just a quick. I'm sorry. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was going to say your last &#x2013; you mentioned Asia there at the end and I think both Howard and I alluded to Asia &#x2013; the fact that there will be more announcements relative to Asia going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, as you know, we've opened the Singapore corporate office that Pier Foschi will be heading up for us, and by the end of the first quarter, we should have more deployment announcement in that region.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>From thirty thousand feet...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mario Draghi said earlier in the week that European economy is coming back in the second half of the year, so we're waiting for that to happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>God bless if his crystal ball is accurate. Just one follow-up on Asia. Separating yield growth from cost, how does Asia compare to Europe and North America from both your ability to price up, and also is it just more expensive to operate in Asia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is more expensive to operate. The question you ask is very difficult when you take a mix of all our brands, but if you look at the Carnival cruise line deployment in Australia, yes, their yields are up; if you look at the Princess deployment, it's also positive. So, clearly &#x2013; again, we're going to make deployment decisions hopefully long-term to increase our profit per berth day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But &#x2013; the cost that we're looking at today with a very limited fleet especially in Asia it's not necessarily representative. If we had built a fleet there, we have more ships over there, we'll get some- certainly some shore-side benefits from it, and as infrastructure is created over there to handle the ships there will be some benefits to cost. So, it'll take some time but costs essentially are higher but the yields are good, so we're okay, and we'll just have to be a little bit patient. But we think it's a great market to develop and a great new market for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well that's it for me. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Sharon Zackfia with William Blair [&amp; Company]. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I'm kind of intrigued by the comments you made about the UK and Germany getting somewhat softer, and I think it would probably be helpful to know just roundly what the yields were like for your UK brands and AIDA this year, and what the differential might be going into 2013 and how much that's weighing on your overall yield guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, look, I think we said yields will be down; we're not going to get into it. We don't really, Sharon, discuss yields for individual companies in the group. We just don't think that's a smart thing to do from a competitive standpoint, but from a directional standpoint, they're going to be down. And, we have gotten more into the yield issues in Costa because of the unique circumstances last year, but we're not going to go beyond that, so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess are you seeing stabilization yet in either of the countries, or is it a moving target right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we're seeing is a close-in booking pattern, both in Germany and the UK. And we haven't seen actually that much deterioration in pricing, but the question is, if you don't start to see the business coming in strongly in wave season, you may have to move some pricing down. So, some of this yield guidance we're giving you is really a future &#x2013; to looking at the crystal ball and saying, well, what possibly can happen in the third and fourth quarters here. It's difficult &#x2013; it's more difficult to estimate it today because of the closer in booking pattern.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you remind us what the &#x2013; sorry. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Clearly, the German economy weakened in the second half of the year and all of our capacity increase in Europe next year is in Germany. So, it's not surprising that there'd be some pressure on yields in Germany. On the other hand, the primary brand in Germany is a stellar performer for us, and will be next year as well at slightly lower yields.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I seem to recall the UK has a long booking window. I don't know if that's the same for Germany. Can you remind us how those booking windows compare to the overall average?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The UK had our longest booking window.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But they also sell long cruises. They have a &#x2013; especially in the winter time, they do have a few around-the-world cruises and long cruises.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Five ships going around the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those tend to book way in advance. So the first quarter in the UK looks like it's shaping up pretty well right now. It's really forecasting the second, third and fourth quarter with the closer in booking patterns because the cruises you're selling coming into the spring and summer are shorter duration cruises. It starts to look like the booking patterns in many of the other businesses including our German business, which is shorter cruises.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Steve Wieczynski with Stifel Nicolaus [Capital Markets]. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning, guys. David, I guess this question is probably best for you. I think you said on &#x2013; I want to make sure this is right &#x2013; in terms of the cost assumptions next year, did you say if you striped out that the higher insurance costs and the higher pension costs and the development cost, your cost assumptions are basically flat?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct. And if you take into account the prior year's ship incident cost, we would've been flat year-over-year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then what happened in the fourth quarter in terms of &#x2013; was there one or two things that drove that cost number higher than you guys were expecting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. It was all the way across the board in a number of instances. There wasn't anything specific. As I said before, it's really tough quarter by quarter. I mean, if you remember back in the third quarter we beat the cost guidance and this quarter we were above, so you got to look at the full year on an annual basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on the onboard side of things, those numbers have actually been trending I think a little better than most people had expected, and just maybe how you're thinking about the onboard trend as we move into '13?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, our onboard trend overall around the globe for 2013 is very similar to 2012. 2012 we were up like a little over 2% and our guidance for 2013 is in the similar range with increases in all the major categories. Our operating companies have done a great job with some new initiatives and so we're expecting those to be driven higher as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then last question for, probably for Micky, I guess. In terms of the &#x2013; with the potential changes here in tax law, I mean, how are you guys thinking about deploying your free cash here over the next couple of years back to shareholders? Is it kind of a wait-and-see mentality right now in terms of how you do that, or can you just give us some color on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what we've said over and over is we're going to return free cash flow to shareholders. Until we know what the tax law is going to be, it's hard to really respond. But once we know that, obviously we'll take it to the board and see what &#x2013; if they prefer a different direction or same direction or whatever. But until we see the final package, it's very hard to guess, and so all we've done so far, as you know, is that special dividend at year end and we're waiting to see what happens in January.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Tim Conder with Wells Fargo Securities. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just to revisit your guidance on Europe, you've seen Thomas Cook and TUI basically imply that over the next six months, things are kind of flattish in terms of bookings and pricing. So, again just to summarize, to take that guidance versus what you're saying out of Europe ex-Costa, is it truly just a capacity issue that you're adding capacity in what has been your strongest market in Germany? Is that to boil it down what we can take away as the difference?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One of the ways &#x2013; I don't know enough about how they manage their business at TUI and Thomas Cook, but they can &#x2013; I do know historically they can move capacity up or down in order to generate higher prices. So, it's not always a good analogy to look at what they're doing and how they're faring in the market from a pricing standpoint versus...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Generally...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly, we do have increased capacity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, generally, when they talk about volumes, they talk about absolute volumes. When we talk about it, we're talking about capacity adjusted. I don't believe they do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so, if we just had flat volumes, we'd be in deep concern, especially in Germany where our capacity increases have -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. And then, to revisit I guess some framework on Costa given the two ships that are out of service and then the Concordia on top of that, I think in previous calls you've mentioned that $300 million would be sort of a new normalized run rate as far as profitability in Costa. I just wanted to clarify, are you counting in the new ships that Costa will be taking delivery of? It would seem that, yeah, you lost two ships, you sold one, got rid of one and then the Allegro, what happened there &#x2013; those weren't that profitable &#x2013; I can't say profitable, but had less profitability, higher cost structure clearly than Concordia. But now you're going to be adding two new ships, could that &#x2013; with the new ships, could that new normalized run rate be back closer to the original $400 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, I'm not going to comment on your number; I'm not exactly sure where it came from. But we only have one ship under contract for Costa at the end of 2014, so the profitability would not be seen until 2015. So, I mean, that's all I can say at this point, that we'd expect Costa's profit to be up in 2015, obviously with at least the capacity increases they have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do believe that Costa &#x2013; that over &#x2013; after 2013, we continue to believe that Costa will continue to grow its profitability in 2014 before the new ship is delivered. So, whether it gets back to the numbers that they previously had, that will take a few years. We've always said that that may take a few years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then a final question relating to the return of capital. It appears again that the company is &#x2013; you stated in the past, was going to return the excess free cash flow. With the special dividend this year, has there been any further thought regarding coming up with a formulaic portion of that on a go-forward basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're now deferring to see what comes out of Washington and then we'll make a decision on how we go with that forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Assia Georgieva with Infinity Research. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. A couple of questions. First of all, the good close-in bookings that we have seen both in Q3 and Q4, are you expecting that Q1 is not going to be a repeat of that? We are basically a quarter of the way into the quarter, and I would think you're already there seeing those. Or, you don't see them and therefore, guidance is not including any pickup on shorter or just near-term pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we gave you our best guess for first quarter, which included what we expect the close-in bookings to be. We're typically 85% to 95% done at this point to the first quarter and we're in that range. So, it's very hard to read every last booking. Maybe we get a little better, a little worse, but we gave you our best guess for the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which is what we do every...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And it's fair to... &#x2013; yeah, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's what we do every quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand. But it's safe to assume that you expect a continuation of this trend at least to some extent in Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We built into that forecast good solid bookings for the remaining 10%-odd of the occupancy for the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. Thank you, David. And the second question is, based on all the trouble that Europe is in and the fact that shipyards may be a lot more open to discussions in terms of ship cost, have you looked at any new builds, especially the Carnival brand is not going to have anything any time soon, and Holland America has been without a new build for a while. In 2015, you do have almost 5% capacity coming in, at least based on my figures. So, for 2016-17, is this a good time to actually be speaking to them, or are you holding off and focusing primarily on returning free cash to shareholders?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've committed &#x2013; we've said now for five years that we'll be building two to three ships a year; that's what we're doing. Whether the yards are doing well or not doing well or whether the price is plus or minus 5% or 10%, it's not going to make us build more or less. I mean, we're going to do it when the returns are right, and in a much more conservative way than we've done in the past. We believe that the growth rate in the industry needs to slow, and that's what we are doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, Micky, if I read you correctly, right now you'll be holding off to see how the near-term demand picture, meaning over the next six months to a year develops before you actually commit to anything?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't want to say that it has anything to do with near-term demand, because these are long-term decisions. These are...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>These are three, four years' delivery and then 30-year assets. So, I would say that our strategy hasn't changed. We're talking two to three ships a year. There's nothing imminent. We just recently announced a Carnival Cruise Line new building and a HAL new building, and we have nothing imminent right now, other than what we've recently announced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And for the years you're talking about, 2016, 2017 and beyond, we have plenty of time. So we don't have to make decisions today. We can do that at some point in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Steven Kent [Steve Kent] with Goldman Sachs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we've exhausted just about everything, but just to be fair to you guys, I mean, it does sound like this is really a short-term booking issue in that, given what you're seeing right now, it's hard to really give much guidance beyond what you've provided. So, am I reading that correctly? I think you said it earlier, Howard, just about, this is the time of year you give the 2013 and this is what you're dealing with at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, it certainly is more challenging to give guidance for 2013 because of the closer in booking pattern that we're seeing. So, there's a sort of a wider span of where this could &#x2013; how this could all play out than in past years when we had a longer term &#x2013; we had a longer booking pattern. So, it's more of a challenge. There's more estimating here, and we think we've factored in reasonable estimates, and as I said before, if we do better that'd be great and if we &#x2013; but there are no guarantees; these are just our best estimates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Really three or four weeks into the wave season, you have a better sense of where you're going, so we'll see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have a question from the line of Rich Lyall with John W. Bristol. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. I have two questions. The first is the fuel efficiency. 5% is a good number. I think it's much stronger than a 2% to 3% kind of number you were guiding to over the last several years, and some of that's itinerary driven. How much further do you have on your itinerary runway to realize fuel efficiency versus other operational improvements?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's funny. Because each itinerary is modeled, you make these decisions based on certain price levels of fuel. So, you're willing to give up X amount of yield for Y amount of fuel savings when fuel is at one price and a different decision based on another price, so it's hard to tell. I think our brands were very aggressive this year to get the fuel cost down and took some yield risk to do it, and I'm sure that's baked into their forecast. We firmly supported those decisions and there is some additional risk to it on the yield side, but we believe that profitability wise it's the right decision. To go beyond &#x2013; a lot of these discussions are longer than one year term, and so I believe that we will see significant fuel savings in 2014 as well, but whether it'll reach this kind of level or not, I don't know. Historically, we've been at the 2% to 3% range, a little bit more and &#x2013; anyway, we pushed hard this year and I suspect we will continue to see some savings in 2014.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And new ships, more efficient ships, will drive some of the metric as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Plus retrofitting ships with new technologies are also drive. So, it's a combination of things that are driving the 5%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About half of it has been &#x2013; about half, a little bit more than half next year is itinerary driven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Second question and this is a very long-term question. What do you think the global balance of your capacity should be? How much should be in Asia? How much should be in exotics? How much should be in Europe? How much in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think you really know the answer to that question, because as we all look at the Asian market as a new market and potentially a strong market for us, it's going to take a while to build it and to get the visibility for cruise vacations in those markets. Over time, look, I mean, Asia &#x2013; it should be no different why Asia is any different than Europe than the U.S. So you can see it relative but over the long-term you can see a relative equal balance but it can take a long time to get there. I'm talking about a long time...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is the kind of thing that we're tweaking all the time. We're always working on the margin. I mean, yesterday Carnival Cruise Line announced a ship being moved from the East Coast to the West Coast because of demand cycles in Canaveral versus Long Beach. So, you're looking at this &#x2013; management is looking at the stuff every day and looking towards 2014 and 2015 and where their brands should be relative to where they are now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But with a two-year decision time horizon, as Howard said, this will take time to balance out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And there are no further questions at this time. I'll turn the call back over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you very much for the good questions and the tough questions, and we want to wish &#x2013; take this moment to wish everybody a happy and healthy holiday season and new year and look forward to seeing you. All the best. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, everybody. Happy new year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Happy holidays.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Happy holidays.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude the conference call for today. We thank you for your participation and ask that you please disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>