<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1322171" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-06-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>69010</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Howard S. Frank, Vice Chairman and Chief Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">David Bernstein, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Felicia Hendrix</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Robin Farley</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Rick Lyall</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Micky Arison</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">David Leibowitz</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Assia Georgieva</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Greg Badishkanian</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep">Beth Roberts</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Timothy Conder</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Harry Curtis</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Brian Egger</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Janet Brashear</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Kevin Milota</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Ian Rennardson</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Sharon Zackfia</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker>
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Carnival Corporation Second Quarter Earnings Call. During the presentation all participants will be in a listen-only mode. Afterwards, we'll conduct a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded Tuesday, June 22, 2010. I would now like to turn the conference over to Howard Frank, Vice Chairman and Chief Operating Officer. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sarah. Good morning, everyone. With me here in Miami is David Bernstein, our Chief Financial Officer and Senior VP of Finance; Beth Roberts, our Vice President of Investor Relations; Micky Arison, our Chairman and CEO.</p>
          <p>I'm going to turn the first part of this call over to David and he will take you through the color of -- during the second quarter and talk about costs going forward. David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Howard. I'll begin the conference call by reading the forward-looking statement. During this conference call, we will make certain forward-looking statements. Such forward-looking statements involve known and unknown risks, uncertainties and assumptions which may cause the actual results, performances or achievements of Carnival to be materially different from any future results, performances or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. For further information, please see Carnival's earnings press release and its filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
          <p>For the second quarter, our earnings per share was $0.32. The second quarter came in above the mid-point of our March guidance by $0.04 per share despite a $0.02 impact from the volcanic ash and the Chilean earthquake disruption. Net revenue yields in local currency came in up 2%, at the higher end of our March guidance, which was worth $0.02 per share even with these disruptions which impacted yields by a half a point. In addition, our ongoing cost reductions were better than forecasted and were also worth $0.02 per share.</p>
          <p>Now let's take a look at our second quarter operating results versus the prior year. Our capacity increased 8% for the second quarter of 2010, with the majority of the increase going to our European brands. The European brands grew 13% while our North American brands grew 4%. As I previously mentioned, overall net revenue yields in local currency increased 2% in the second quarter of 2010 versus the prior year.</p>
          <p>Now let's take a look at the two components of net revenue yields. For net ticket yields, we saw a yield increase of 1.6% in local currency. Our North American brands were up 3.8%, driven by increases in Europe, Alaska and other exotic itineraries.</p>
          <p>Our European brands experienced 1.2% lower local currency ticket yields, which were in line with our expectations. Similar to the first quarter, the declines were driven by challenging winter season in the Brazilian market, with significant capacity increases this past winter. If you exclude the five ships that Costa and Ibero had in Brazil in the month of March, the European brands' net ticket revenue yields in local currency was flat.</p>
          <p>We were pleased with this performance given the economic uncertainty and the significantly higher capacity for our continental European brands.</p>
          <p>For net on-board and other revenue yields, we reported a yield increase of 3.1% in local currency. The increase occurred on both sides of the Atlantic. Our North American brands were up 4.6% and our European brands were up 3.2% in local currency. This was clearly better than we had expected in our March guidance. Keep in mind that the second quarter actual is against easy comps, as the second quarter last year was at the low point for on-board and other revenue yields.</p>
          <p>As a result of our second quarter performance, the operating companies have raised their forecast for on-board and other revenue yields slightly through the back half of the year. On the March call, I indicated that excluding a couple of one-time first quarter items, our expectations for the full year was flat given that the first quarter was flat. However, given the increase in the second quarter, our June guidance for the full year, also excluding the same one-time items in the first quarter, is an increase of approximately 1%.</p>
          <p>In summary, we were very encouraged by the 2% increase in net revenue yields in the second quarter, which was the first time we saw positive revenue yields since late 2008. As Howard will discuss later, we expect greater improvements in yields for the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>On the cost side, cruise costs per available lower berth day, excluding fuel and in local currency, were down 4.9% versus the prior year. The decline was driven by fewer dry docks, economies of scale relating to double-digit growth at certain of our brands, benefits from cost reduction programs, a low inflationary environment and the timing of certain SG&amp;A expenses.</p>
          <p>However, the strength of our revenue and cost performance in the second quarter of 2010 were once again masked by rising fuel prices. Fuel prices this quarter were 64% higher than last year, costing us $162 million or $0.20 per share. One final note on cost. As a result of our ongoing efforts to reduce fuel consumption, our fuel consumption per ALBD [available lower berth day] declined 3.3% in the second quarter, continuing our multiple-year savings trend.</p>
          <p>Turning to our 2010 outlook, I will skip the net revenue yield outlook, as Howard will discuss that shortly. On the cost side, net cruise costs per available lower berth day for the third quarter, excluding fuel and in local currency, are projected to be up 1 to 2%. This was driven by a $39 million charge relating to a closed multi-employer pension plan for certain British officers.</p>
          <p>The multi-employer pension plan accounting rules require us to expense required participant contributions to fund plan deficits when the invoices are received. Excluding this charge, net cruise costs per available lower berth day, excluding fuel for the third quarter, would have been projected to be flat to down 1%.</p>
          <p>For the full year, net cruise costs per available lower berth day, excluding fuel and in local currency, are projected to be down 2.5 to 3.5%. The decline is driven by our ongoing cost reductions, the first-quarter gain on the sale of the P&amp;O Cruises' Artemis and lower dry dock costs. Since we first gave guidance for 2010 six months ago, we have taken a full percentage point off our cost guidance. Our ongoing cost reduction programs are yielding more savings than we anticipated in a variety of areas such as insurance, ports and crew travel, just to name a few.</p>
          <p>Based on the current spot price for fuel, fuel prices for the full year are projected to be $495 per metric ton for 2010 versus $363 per metric ton for 2009, costing an additional $440 million or $0.55 per share. So in the end, fuel is driving our costs up and therefore in current dollars and including fuel, our costs are expected to be up 1 to 2%.</p>
          <p>At this point I will turn the call back over to Howard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David. Okay, let me go over the tone of business with you. On a fleet-wide basis, booking volumes and pricing since our last earnings call, that's in the last 13 weeks or so, covering the next three quarters have held up quite well. Even booking volumes for the last six weeks during a significant downturn in global equity markets have held up well, although we have seen reduced booking volumes for certain itineraries, which I will comment on later.</p>
          <p>For our North American brands on slightly lower year-over-year booking volumes for the last 13 weeks, we have experienced double-digit price increases. Keep in mind our comparisons of this year's booking volumes are against a 26% increase in booking volumes for the same period as last year, when we were selling at deeply discounted prices to move our inventory. With respect to bookings by itinerary during the last 13 weeks for North American brands, we have seen strong volumes and pricing for Caribbean programs, which comprise 52% of North American brand capacity over the next three quarters.</p>
          <p>Alaska, which is 11% of our North American capacity, on lower booking volumes has experienced significantly higher year-over-year pricing, and Europe itineraries, which comprise 9% of our capacity, has also experienced lower booking volumes but with significantly higher pricing as well. We have also seen stronger year-over-year pricing for our Mexican Riviera itineraries. For the first time in a while, all of our North American brand itineraries have booked quite well during this 13-week period with good pricing.</p>
          <p>For our European brands during the last 13 weeks, booking volumes for the next three quarters have been quite strong, with moderate year-over-year local -- current pricing improvements. Booking volumes for European itineraries during the 13-week period, which comprise two-thirds of European brand capacity during the next nine months, have been higher and are keeping pace with year-over-year European brand capacity increases. These bookings are showing moderate increases in prices on a local currency basis, which is quite satisfactory considering the large increase in European brand capacity during the next nine months.</p>
          <p>So looking back over the last 13 weeks, it's fair to say that demand for cruises has been solid and we've continued to achieve higher year-over-year price increases. Now, let me talk a little bit about the last six weeks. Beginning in early May, the effect of the volcanic ash issue in the UK and Western Europe did cause nervousness about air travel, particularly for North American consumers taking airline flights across the Atlantic.</p>
          <p>Compounding this was the European sovereign debt crisis and the resultant negative effect it had on global equity markets,</p>
          <p>Indeed, from late April through late May, U.S. equity markets, as we all know, were down about 12% or so. We believe this caused consumers, especially those in North America, to re-think their discretionary travel decisions. But even with these events, fleet-wide bookings for the last six weeks for our cruises over the next three quarters continue to run ahead of last year on a fleet-wide basis, significantly ahead for Europe -- France and just slightly behind for North American brands. And prices for bookings for North America and Europe brands continue to be running nicely higher.</p>
          <p>Looking at bookings over the last six weeks by major trades for North American brands, Caribbean itineraries, which are more than 50% of North American capacity over the next nine months, continue to be strong at higher prices. Bookings for Alaska cruises, however, ran behind the last six-week period but at substantially higher prices.</p>
          <p>But fortunately there is very little Alaskan inventory left to sell. Bookings for North American brand Europe programs were also lower, but there's also not much inventory left to sell in Europe for the reminder of the year.</p>
          <p>Despite the brief slowdown in these trades, we are still expecting significant year-over-year pricing improvement for Alaska and Europe for 2010. We have seen anecdotally over the last couple of weeks that with the recent strength in the equity markets that demand for -- in North America for these trades has started to pick up.</p>
          <p>Interestingly, effect of these external events seems to have been felt more in North America markets than in European markets. Our European brand bookings during the last six-week period have held up extremely well, with significant improvement in booking volumes and solid improvement in year-over-year local currency pricing. This is yet another example of how the European consumer appears to be more resilient to geopolitical and economic events than is their American counterpart. So to sum this all up, despite the events that have occurred around the world over the last six weeks, people are still booking their vacations and our business has held up quite well.</p>
          <p>Now turning to our full-year earnings guidance, as we indicated in the press release we are maintaining earnings guidance of $2.25 to $2.35 a share. Since our first quarter guidance, currency movements, largely the result of a strengthening dollar net of lower forecasted fuel prices for the second half of the year, have caused a 7% per share down draft in our earnings. Offsetting this has been the better than forecasted second quarter earnings of $0.04 and another $0.03 resulting from lower than expected costs in the second half of the year. When we combine these movements, we get back to the same earnings guidance as we provided last March.</p>
          <p>Now let me take you through some of the color of &#x2013; by each of the next -- for each of the next three quarters. For the third quarter, fleet-wide capacity is 6.2% higher than last year, 3.7% in North America, 8% for Europe brands. At this point, with very little inventory left to sell in the quarter, fleet-wide capacity is slightly ahead -- fleet-wide occupancy, I should say, is slightly ahead year-over-year, with local currency pricing well ahead.</p>
          <p>For North American brands during the quarter -- 41% in the Caribbean, 25% in Alaska, 17% in Europe -- overall pricing for North American brands is well ahead of last year with slightly better occupancies. Even pricing for Mexican Riviera cruises out of California, which has been a struggle for us over the last couple of years, is showing nice improvement. We are expecting that third quarter ticket pricing for North American brands to increase in the low double-digit levels by the time the third quarter closes.</p>
          <p>For European brands, they are 97% in European itineraries in the third quarter. Currently, pricing for Europe brands is slightly higher year-over-year, which is a very positive sign given the 8% capacity increase in our European fleet during the quarter. All brands are performing well, although pricing for our Spanish cruise brand, Ibero Cruises, which had a 37% increase in capacity in the quarter, is expected to be lower.</p>
          <p>By the time the quarter closes out, we are expecting European brand pricing to be flattish year-over-year, which is a very good result given the 8% increase in capacity. As I indicated in the press release, or as we indicated in the press release, we are forecasting third quarter fleet-wide revenue yields will increase in the 5 to 6% range on a local currency basis, flat to up slightly on a current dollar basis.</p>
          <p>Costs excluding fuel are expected to be higher by 1 to 2% on a local currency basis largely as a result of the British officer pension fund charge that David referred to earlier. On a local currency basis, costs excluding fuel are expected to be lower in the 2 to 3% range.</p>
          <p>Fuel cost for the third quarter is expected to be higher by $74 million year-over-year or $0.09 a share. And as we indicated in the press release, earnings are forecasted to be in the range of $1.43 to $1.47 for the quarter versus $1.33 per share in the third quarter of 2009. So it's nice to get back to positive earnings improvements on a quarterly basis.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the fourth quarter, wide capacity is up 6.1% in the quarter, 1.7% in North America and 10.6% in Europe. On an overall basis, fourth quarter occupancy is slightly lower, with local currency pricing running nicely higher. North American brands in the fourth quarter are 50% in the Caribbean, with all other itineraries individually below 10%.</p>
          <p>At the present time, pricing is running nicely ahead year-over-year with lower occupancies. Overbooking volumes for the fourth quarter for North American brands continue to be strong, and by the time the quarter closes we are expecting pricing to be nicely higher year-over-year.</p>
          <p>European brands are 73% in Europe in the fourth quarter, with all other itineraries individually under 10%. Europe itinerary pricing on a local currency basis is nicely ahead of last year with slightly better occupancy. Bookings continue to be strong for the fourth quarter, and we are forecasting that by the time the fourth quarter closes Europe brand local currency pricing will be higher year-over-year, which is a very good result considering the10% -- 10-plus percent capacity increase that we have during the quarter.</p>
          <p>On a fleet-wide basis, we expect fourth quarter revenue yields to be up approximately 3% on a local currency basis; that's throughout &#x2013; that's combining Europe and North America. And I should add it's nice to see a positive sign in -- for European pricing, which we haven't had in quite some time, and that's despite the considerable increases we've had in capacity, which has been absorbed quite nicely. And we've been able to expand our markets at the same time in Europe.</p>
          <p>So now I'm going to turn to the first quarter of 2011, where our fleet-wide capacity is going to be up 6.6%, 3.8% for North American brands and 11.7% for European brands. Let me emphasize that the first quarter booking data is still in the early stages of development and is provided to give you a picture of how the quarter is shaping up at the present time. Overall, first quarter pricing is running higher on a year-over-year basis with occupancy running slightly behind. This is a pattern that is similar to the fourth quarter pattern for 2010.</p>
          <p>North American brands are 66% in the Caribbean, 11% in Mexican Riviera cruises and the balance in all other itineraries. Presently, Caribbean pricing is slightly higher on lower occupancies and Mexican Riviera pricing is higher on higher occupancies. Pricing on virtually all other itineraries, mostly longer premium-price cruises, is higher on lower occupancies.</p>
          <p>European brands are 25% in European itineraries, 23% in the Caribbean and 18% in South America with the remaining in various other itineraries. Local currency pricing for Europe and South America cruises is running higher on lower occupancies and pricing for European brand Caribbean cruises is higher on higher occupancies. Overall, pricing in local currency for Europe brand cruises is nicely higher at this time with occupancies, when you combine it all, at the same level as the prior year.</p>
          <p>And that is adjusted for the 11.7% capacity increase we have in the first quarter for Europe. Again, I caution this is an early picture for Q1 of 2011 and not to read too much into this information.</p>
          <p>And with that, Sarah, I'm going to turn it back to you for questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And our first question comes from the line of Felicia Hendrix with Barclays Capital. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi; good morning, guys. Two questions for you. First, Howard, you gave us great color on the third, fourth and first quarter. I just wanted to talk about the fourth quarter for a moment. I was just wondering, at this point of time, are you surprised that the occupancy is lower year-over-year or is that trending how you expected? And how has the booking pace trended through the quarter since the second quarter has closed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We've been running this lower occupancy, and actually been pacing lower. I think principally what's happening is that there &#x2013; the yield -- it varies by brand, but the yield management people are working on getting stronger pricing for the quarter. They are less concerned about the lower occupancies. The booking pace has been good for the fourth quarter, as I indicated. So they're pretty confident that they're going to get to the yield numbers that I gave and they feel pretty good about the situation. I think there was a little bit of a hiccup, I would call it, for a period of time back in May. And I think the pace has now picked up again, and I think they're feeling pretty comfortable as they go forward for the fourth quarter. But we were running behind in the fourth quarter really -- as I can recall, I think throughout the year and we've never really picked -- pressed to pick up the pace because we're really focusing on getting better pricing. And that seems to be happening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's good. And then just on -- turning to the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One more comment, I should add that booking pace has picked up for the fourth quarter without having to give away any price. So we've been able to -- it's been a successful strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. And then just on onboard spend. I was just wondering has there been any impact since the end of the quarter given the macroenvironment, and what has been the most recent onboard trends that you've seen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll let David talk to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Since the end of the quarter, Felicia -- here at corporate we don't get all the detailed reports by voyage, by brand. And so we don't -- the latest information I have is as of the end of May for the second quarter. Overall, essentially all of the categories except for casino was up in the second quarter. And we are expecting that trend to continue throughout the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's helpful. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Robin Farley with UBS. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I just wanted to clarify your guidance. You talked about onboard revenues coming in a little bit up for the year, which is better than the flat that you had talked about previously. But your total yield guidance is unchanged. So I guess just want to clarify: should we think about the implied guidance on ticket prices being the same increase as what you had previously expected or is it slightly lower? In other words, is it enough to be a rounding error or is there an implied less of an increase in ticket price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Robin; it's really just a rounding era. And remember when you give guidance in a range of 2 to 3%, you can go up by 0.1 or 0.2 and you don't necessarily change your whole -- your range. So it really is just rounding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Just wanted to clarify that. And then also on the pension charge you're talking about in Q3. Just to clarify: that's in your full-year EPS guidance today but was not in there previously, right? In other words ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no; that has always been in our EPS guidance since December.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It may have changed by a million or two, but it's been there since the beginning. We expected it all along.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Rick Lyall with John W. Bristol. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. I have a couple questions. Post-Katrina, the Gulf and Florida pretty much stopped booking. And I'm wondering what the trends have been in the Gulf in terms of domestic demand, and same kind of question in Southern Europe. Have you seen any material impact in demand for either of those two regions, given some of the events that have transpired?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rick, I'm not sure I understand your Southern Europe question other than, fortunately, we don't carry a lot of Greek passengers. The Gulf cruises have been virtually unaffected by the spill. We are operating and passengers are not even aware of it. The ships are navigating around it. There may be a slight increase in fuel consumption because we have to navigate around what may be the worst areas, but the ships are being inspected every time they return to the U.S. We haven't had to clean a hull once yet. We've seen no slowdown in booking pattern.</p>
          <p>Clearly, we're offering an outstanding vacation option for people in that region, and one that they don't have to concern themselves with the spill during their vacation. We are, in an attempt to try to help the region, we are encouraging on Carnival's Web site people stay a day or two before or after the cruise in the region to try to kind of stimulate tourism in the region, but from our point of view it hasn't affected business at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Southern Europe I was thinking about Italy. We know Spain has been weak, but I was wondering about Italy, Greece, et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean, in terms of those markets we -- they have been fine. They have been solid all the way through. We haven't seen any discernible change in demand in continental Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Remember, we took a delivery of an AIDA ship this winter. We took delivery of a Costa ship this winter right after two ships last spring for Costa, and we've absorbed that capacity with no deterioration in yields. So Europe is performing, I would say, fantastically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So last question for David. Given the very, very low bond yields available today, any thoughts about refinancing debt early or moving anything around with the current spreads?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rick, we always look at that. But fortunately for us, we have a significant number. I think right now we have seven export credits available to us going forward that are at even lower yields and lower interest rates than most bonds. So we are in very good shape. We don't have any financing needs, but we do consistently look at that on an ongoing basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much. Good job, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of David Leibowitz with Horizon. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The advanced bookings on the balance sheet show that they're up 25% year-over-year. And the question is how much of that is pricing, how much of that is going further out on the calendar, and how much of that is the additional capacity that has come on stream this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you asked the question, David, David Bernstein is going through his book now to see if he can give you some direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think you're looking at year-end versus...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It depends on what you're measuring against.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What are you measuring against, David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Year-over-year or --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am using the 3.2 versus the 2.6 that shows up on the balance sheet that was reported today. I apologize; it is year-end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, part of that is seasonality as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's a huge part. Remember, as we get bigger, and this is an important factor that everybody has to understand, as we get bigger and bigger and bigger in our European brands, you become more and more seasonal. And so our advance ticket deposits at the end of the second quarter is always going to be significantly higher than at the end of the year. I think that's just the way the business is going to be. And the reality is, as we grow the European brands, you can expect lower earnings in the first quarter and more earnings in the third quarter. It's just going to be a more seasonal business because the European business is so seasonal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, if you want to compare back to the prior year, it's 3.2 today; it was 2.9 a year ago in May. And we got hurt a little bit on FX rates because the dollar did get stronger. And remember, that was more than offset by the capacity increase. And then of course the big difference was the pricing increase, because the prices that we're getting today for the back half of the year are up considerably versus the prior years. So those are the big swings and it nets to an increase of almost 400 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And my second question has to do with new build and your domestic brands. At what point do the domestic brands get the incremental attention, given how much of their capacity are 20 to 30 years old at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't have any 30-year-old tonnage. I am sorry. The age of our fleet is much younger than you characterize. The only thing I would say is that we have two very large ships on order for Carnival Cruise Lines. We have two very large ships on order for Princess. We have said that going forward, '13 and beyond, that our CapEx will be lower, significantly lower than it's been in recent years. Probably two to three ships a year, and that's what you can anticipate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We also have the Nieuw Amsterdam being delivered for Holland America later on this month.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next week.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And next year at this time a new -- third in a series of a Seabourn ship for the North America &#x2013; principally the North American...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have plenty of capacity coming for the North America brands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think the oldest ship in North America is 1988, 22 years old.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About 20 years old. And we don't have many of those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Assia Georgieva from Infinity Research. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. One question, given that the North American and especially the Carnival brand pricing seems to be driving Q3, could you comment on the present price increase back in March and how far long relative to that figure of up to 5% Jerry has enabled to get pricing to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the way to answer your question is I think that strategy brought forward some business, which is a logical conclusion of that kind of marketing strategy that people would book earlier to take advantage of the lower pricing before the price increase. So I think that worked very well. And as far as I know, all the pricing that was taken at that time has held.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Assia, did you made the comment -- I'm not sure I heard you right -- that the Carnival brand was driving the pricing improvement in the third quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, she did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think relative...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think all brands are -- all North American brands -- all the major North American brands -- Carnival, Holland America, Princess -- their pricing is also nicely up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And previously --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Howard, you are right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But just a clarification.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am sorry that I did say that the Carnival's brand pricing will be actually what will be driving Q3, but what I meant more was that North American brands and especially the Caribbean would be helpful and I think in Q3 you only have, or mostly have Carnival with a little bit of Princess in there. So my expectation had been that the Carnival brand's price increase is a significant factor to Q3 yields and bookings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, as Howard stated, it's pretty much across all our North American brands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean at Carnival &#x2013; Carnival, they're all up, they're all up nicely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Including Carnival and <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You have to remember that, but as we said on the prior call that Europe bookings for the North American brands and Alaska bookings for the North American brands, pricing-wise, was very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Particularly during the wave period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's good to hear that, especially on Alaska, we know the whole fiasco there. So thank you very much for answering, that was my only question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Greg Badishkanian with Citigroup. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. Did you guys notice any pick up in cancellations when the equity markets began to decline in late April, or is it pretty consistent?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty consistent. We didn't see any discernible increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, we tended to see, and Howard, I think, mentioned it in his notes is that our premium North American brands tend to be more sensitive and longer cruises, more premium, luxury-type cruises, tend to be more affected by market volatility in generations. And so in the month of May, we felt some of that. It didn't -- everybody seems to be asking us questions about Europe, but it didn't seem to impact Europe at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Which kind of leads me to a question just on the differences in the consumer in Europe versus North America. When the negative news lines hit and stock market was declining, you see -- saw more of an impact in the North American consumer. Were there any other kind of differences between the two types of consumers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the European consumer is &#x2013; it's a much more stable consumer. It doesn't have a lot of debt, consumer debt, there's not a lot of consumer debt there. There's not a lot of credit card debt. There's strong social systems that support the Europeans. So &#x2013; and the way they -- this whole psychology is that vacations are really right at the top of their list of priorities of how they spend their money. So I think it is a very different consumer and their behavior is different. And I think this is the one way -- another way of seeing how it's manifested. We -- it's really very interesting, especially when you talk about the whole sovereign debt crisis, and we talked to our colleagues in Europe and they're all concerned about it. But they didn't see it affect their business that much, which means that the consumer, the day-to-day consumer, the market doesn't really think that much about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What's interesting is even during this period when the market was falling, the on-board revenue yields were even up more in North America than they were in Europe. I indicated it was up about 4.6%, the North American brands in the second quarter, and 3.2% for the European brands. So despite what was going on, people are still out there spending.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Interesting, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Tim Conder with Wells Fargo. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And again, congrats on great execution, everyone. A couple of -- two questions here. Micky, on the last call you talked about the letters of intent for the two Princess ships, and then you said that those would be finalized very shortly, which they were. And then you said at that point in time that behind that you really had nothing material in discussions in the pipeline. If you could update us on that statement, that's question number one. And then question number two is just kind of looking now to little bit more the North American ECA, the new fuel standards, how do you guys feel about your ability to deal with those as they start to phase in I think the middle of 2012 and the potential impact on your fuel costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am going to take a pass on the first part of your question and kind of defer to my two to three a year starting in '13 and kind of leave it at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. ECA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as ECA is concerned, Tim, we did disclose in our 10-K that for 2012 the impact on our fuel costs would be somewhere in the range of 50 to $70 million, which took into account not only the North American ECA but other rules and regulations around the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean on the ECA issue, I think a large part of those costs are related to sailings in Alaska and to some degree Hawaii; we don't have that much capacity in Hawaii. And we are still working to see if we can get some deferral of the implementation of the ECA in those waters. I don't know if we'll be successful, but it's something we're working on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And I guess --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will be great if we can reduce the effect that David talked about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That was the root of my question is over the year to date here has anything changed where you feel that that cost impact would be lower, and I noticed that recently also Costa announced that a ship that's currently visiting I think the Canadian-New England itineraries will not be returning I think in '11 or '12. So -- but -- so you're working more on the deferral side and anything I guess internal from whether that will be scrubbing technology or change in some potential engine types or anything like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it gets very complicated, but the whole concept of reducing consumption or equivalencies, if you will, of other ways of saving or having less pollution from &#x2013; in the ECA zones, and by the way relative to the St. Lawrence Seaway, we're also working with the Canadian authorities, local Canadian authorities to see if we can get some help in that area. But it gets to be very complicated. But we are working, we are trying to mitigate it to the extent possible, so hopefully what David's given you is the worst-case basis and hopefully it will be less than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think as far as new technologies and things, it's more of a longer term strategy and the shorter term is the deferral and reduce fuel consumption, which we continue to work on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we're still working on the scrubber technology, but that's not -- not with a whole lot of success yet. But I think it's -- still working on it. We're working with a number of companies in the area, as are many of our competitors in the cruise industry, so we're trying to find other solutions to this issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Harry Curtis with Lazard Capital. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Quick question for Micky. When you consider the last two recoveries, what does your experience tell you about how the 2010 recovery is going to be different?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Boy, you know, the world is so different now that the size of our business, the global nature of our business, it's so hard to translate past. I mean, historically we bounced back in two to three years. So it's -- but it's so hard to make the comparison. And if you were to tell me six months ago that I'd have to be -- we'd have to be dealing with volcanoes and earthquakes and oil spills and have to navigate through that in the quarter. I mean, if you look at our risk section, I don't think volcano is in that, and you'd think we'd throw the kitchen sink at it. And somehow we've been able to navigate through that; our guys have done a great job. And all I can say is that we'll recover as quickly as demand will allow us to. And that really depends on a lot of things, but clearly the economy and how the economy does is going to be a factor, just like it's going to be a factor for all leisure businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have any sense of, going back to the prior consumer question, of the condition of the consumer in this recovery again compared to the last two recoveries?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We saw -- the interesting comment we saw from an analyst right after the announcement was that our volumes in the press release we said are slightly up versus last year, and the comment was that last year was a disaster. And I think everybody forgets that we had a huge bounce back in March of last year in volumes. Now that was at much lower prices, but our volumes were extraordinarily strong from March on last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They were up 26%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They were up 26%. And when we said we're up slightly, we were talking volume year-over-year at higher prices. So we took that as a very bullish statement and immediately analysts came out and said it was a negative statement. So it's very interesting. I mean the reality is that the bounce back was very strong, it happened very quickly because if you consider the financial crisis in September, to be bouncing back as strong as we did in March, albeit at much lower prices, I think it was very encouraging sign that the consumer viewed our product as a very, very value-oriented product and one that has great value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the last couple of recoveries you were able to get your pricing back in just over a year. Do you think that it's too aggressive to think that it will come back that quickly this time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you can tell me what the economy is going to do over the next 12 months, I'll tell you, but it's really &#x2013; it's very, very...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You think that it is a little bit different. I mean we've got these really unprecedented levels of unemployment that we're all dealing with in North America. And an economy that's recovering, but not quickly, not dramatically. And I think it's reflected in our -- what we were seeing in the business. And I think it may be a longer haul recovery. And I think that's what we kind of -- our model -- we're modeling on a longer haul basis as we look at our yields and saying this is not all going to come back in a year or two. It may take another year or even more. So I think it's going to be a long haul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One of the things that everybody is talking about is austerity, budget issues, raising taxes, whether it's in the UK or the U.S. And obviously you raise taxes, that's going to have a negative impact on the consumer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think the current administration and even the Congress is taking -- some of these things that they are doing is really -- is going to hurt the consumer, no question about it. And we'll feel that. So that will slow the recovery as well. It is surprising because you think the one thing that they would be working on is jobs and getting more jobs and that you have to pump money in the economy to do that. But that's not what's happening, it's the reverse, they're taking money out of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess what we're saying is -- and I think we said this all along is we are much more -- we are much more susceptible to geopolitical events than our business itself. And all we can say is that the economy is weak, but we will outperform other forms of leisure and I think we've proved that time and time again, but not -- but we will be impacted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And our next question comes from the line of Brian Egger with Affiliated Research. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. It was pretty clear from your previous comments that you've experienced no demand or operational impacts from the oil spill in the Gulf region. And my question is at some point if that situation were to change, do you have any flexibility to change the homeport status of the ships you've got homeported in New Orleans and Mobile, and I think there are two but I don't know if mid season or mid programs that are established if there is any operational flexibility to change itineraries with the base of origin for ships that are homeported in those two ports.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't believe that that should be necessary, even if there is an oil issue that there is a cleaning process, if you go through, to clean the hulls as they come in and out of port. So it would delay our arrivals and departures and we'd have to adjust for that. But as I said, to date we have not had to clean at all, which is a testament to the captains and their ability to maneuver around this thing. And hopefully as we get closer to August this thing will get capped and we can all move on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think, hopefully, everything suggests that the worst is over. They're certainly limiting the amount of oil coming out right now and hopefully by mid-August or even earlier they will have it fully cut off. So I think the worst is over. Brian, I haven't heard your name in a long, long time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah; good to be back. Thanks again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Janet Brashear with Sanford Bernstein. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. You said earlier this quarter that you're discontinuing air transportation bookings. Can you talk a little bit about how significant that is? I know that's a low portion of your business, but what impact that will have and how it might filter through?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We didn't say that. Carnival Cruise Lines changed their air policy not to sell, let's say, air deviations because air is such a small piece of their business. But all the other brands are still -- have made no change and Carnival still sells its traditional fly-away, non-deviated program. So it's a very small piece of our business now. I don't know what the percentage of it is but --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's like 10% in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>10% in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And in fact I think a quarter that Princess implemented their eZAir where you can now book either our standard air program or restricted air at the time of booking for the cruise to make it easier for the consumer. So each brand has got their own strategy that's appropriate for them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Carnival Cruise Lines just eliminated one part of their air program, and that's all that was announced. We didn't announce anything across the board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; thanks for clarifying that. If I could dwell on Europe for just one more second here, although I know we're beating it to a pulp. You said that the demand trend has been great in Europe despite the economic headwinds here. If the economic headwinds continue for another three to six months, is it possible that some of the reaction by the European consumer is just delayed, given booking patterns and what not, and that three, six months from now, if the trend gets no worse but stays the way it is, that that will start to show up in the bookings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You never -- it's hard to predict, but you know, Janet, the European consumer tends to be -- have more ability to consume in these environment. Because they are not as strung out as in North America. They don't have the housing issue that we still continue to have in North America. They don't have the larger mortgages as we have in North America. It's a very different consumer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They're not buying the cruises on credit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So I don't think so. We found over the years that the European consumer is far more resilient than their North American counterparts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're also losing sight of the fact that it's still, despite the growth, an underpenetrated market and still significantly behind North America as far as penetration. And so there is still a lot of growth left.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If we look at the North American consumer in Europe, is there any fear around the Mediterranean bookings? I mean, are the North Americans at all gun shy about economic events in Athens and the potential for riots or anything as they're booking or are they pretty comfortable in the same booking patterns relative to the Mediterranean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't -- we haven't seen any concern. Obviously, if there was an issue in Athens, we would just divert around it. We do not use Athens as a homeport. So we really don't have an issue there. It's not -- it hasn't been a problem. If there was any problem at all, as we said earlier, it was the premium brands saw some hiccup during the severe volatility in May in the markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Kevin Milota with JP Morgan. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I was hoping to speak a little bit more about the forward bookings, and appreciate your commentary on the European consumer. I was hoping you might be able to give us some commentary on what you've seen from the booking curve for the European customer and also domestically for North America. Have you seen a lengthening or shortening in the booking curve and how much inventory you have left to sell for the fourth quarter and first quarter of next year for both regions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the curve is about at the same levels as last year. There is no discernible difference. It kind of moves -- sometimes it moves above the line, sometimes it moves below the line, I don't exactly where it is right now. But it's more or less about the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as what's left to sell, I mean we don't give out the exact booking -- advanced booking percentages, but typically for the next quarter, which in this case would be the third quarter, we're always 85 to 95% booked. Two quarters out, which is the fourth quarter, our historical range is 55 to 75% booked. And for three quarters out, which would be the first quarter, traditionally we are in the range of 30 to 50% booked, and we're still in those historical ranges.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Ian Rennardson with Banc of America. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon. It's Ian Rennardson, Banc of America. Quick question on the dividend. You maintained it at $0.10 I think for this quarter. Things seem to be progressing pretty well. When do you think you might consider a raise in the dividend? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The dividend is a Board decision. The Board of course takes up the dividend at every meeting because they do have to declare it. The Board is well aware of the financial situation with the company as well as the reduced CapEx next year. And I don't want to predict what the Board will say, but they will make an appropriate decision at the right time to change the dividend. So it...</p>
          <p>&lt; Q &#x2013; Ian Rennardson&gt;: It might change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't want to predict what they'll say or what they will decide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Sharon Zackfia with William Blair. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. David, I was hoping you could go over on the net cruise costs the reduction that you had there. How much of that is due to stronger U.S. dollar, and if you could give us a rule of thumb as to what percent of your net cruise costs are in non-U.S. dollar?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, basically we do give the cruise costs out in current dollars. So for instance when I was talking about, like, for the second quarter being down 4.9%, that is in current dollars. I don't have the overall cost in terms of the costs themselves, but typically what we do say is that if the U.S. dollar strengthens or weakens by about 10% versus all currencies, it impacts our bottom line by about $160 million or $0.20 a share. So, since we've got so much of our revenue in foreign currencies as well as costs, there is a -- they are offsetting factors there and the impact is $0.20.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And at this time, I'm showing that there are no further questions from the phone lines. So I'll turn the conference back to our speakers for their continuing presentation or closing remarks. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thank you all very much for your good questions. And as you know, Beth is available to answer calls and provide any more details that you may need that she is able to do after the call. And we look forward to seeing you, everybody soon. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude the conference call for today. We thank you for your participation and ask that you please disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>