<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1407937" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-07-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>648</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Corporate Communications">Brian P. Gill</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman, President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Robert J. Hugin</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Senior Vice President">Jacqualyn A. Fouse</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Matt M. Roden</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co., Inc.">Geoffrey C. Porges</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Geoff C. Meacham</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Mark J. Schoenebaum</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Robert W. Baird &amp; Co. Equity Capital Markets">Chris J. Raymond</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Mizuho Securities USA, Inc.">Gene C. Mack</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Yaron Werber</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Oppenheimer Securities">Bret Holley</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Wells Fargo Advisors LLC">Brian Abrahams</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets LLC">Michael Yee</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Piper Jaffray, Inc.">M. Ian Somaiya</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Gleacher &amp; Co. Securities, Inc.">Ying Huang</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Cowen &amp; Co.">Eric Schmidt</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Rachel L. McMinn</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Lazard Capital Markets LLC">Joel D. Sendek</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">Thomas A. Wei</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Joseph Triartisan LLC">Shiv Singh Kapoor</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst" affiliation="Leerink Swann LLC">Howard Liang</participant>
      <participant id="22" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Sapna R. Srivastava</participant>
      <participant id="23" type="analyst" affiliation="Stifel, Nicolaus &amp; Co., Inc.">Maged S. Shenouda</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and thank you for standing by, and welcome to the Second Quarter 2011 Celgene Corporation Earnings Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>And now I'll turn the program over to Brian Gill, Vice President of Corporate Communications for Celgene. Sir, the floor is yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and good morning, everyone. I would like to welcome you to Celgene's Second Quarter Conference Call.</p>
          <p>The press release reporting our second quarter 2011 financial and operating results was issued earlier this morning and is also available on our corporate website. Our conference call webcast will include a presentation which you can access by going to the Investor Relations section on our website at celgene.com.</p>
          <p>For today's conference call, we have Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, Bob Hugin, and our Chief Financial Officer, Jackie Fouse.</p>
          <p>Before we start, we want to remind that you our discussions during the conference call will include forward-looking statements, which are generally statements that are not historical facts. Forward-looking statements can be identified by the words expect, anticipate, believe, intend, estimate, plans, will, outlook, and similar expressions. Forward-looking statements are based on management's current plans, estimates, assumptions, and projections, and speak only as of the date they are made.</p>
          <p>We undertake no obligation to update any forward-looking statement in light of new information or future events, except as otherwise required by law. Forward-looking statements involve inherent risks and uncertainties, most of which are difficult to predict and are generally beyond our control. Actual results or outcomes may differ materially from those implied by the forward-looking statements as a result of the impact of a number of factors, many of which are discussed in more detail in our annual report on Form 10-K and our other reports filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
          <p>In addition to financial information prepared in accordance with U.S. GAAP, this conference call and presentation also contains non-GAAP financial measures that we believe provide investors and management with supplemental information relating to operating performance and trends that facilitate comparisons between periods and with respect to projected information. These non-GAAP measures should be considered in addition to, but not as a substitute for, the information prepared in accordance with U.S. GAAP.</p>
          <p>We typically include certain GAAP items that management does not believe affect our basic operations and that do not meet the GAAP definition of unusual or non-recurring items. Other companies may define these measures in different ways. Further information relevant to the interpretation of non-GAAP financial measures and reconciliations of these non-GAAP financial measures to the most comparable GAAP measures may be found on Celgene's website at celgene.com in the Investor Relations section.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Bob Hugin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Brian, and thank you, everyone, for joining us this morning.</p>
          <p>It was an exceptional quarter for Celgene. Our teams continued to deliver excellent commercial and financial results, while advancing our regulatory, clinical, and research programs, all designed to produce sustained long-term growth and value creation. During the quarter, we made important progress on all of our key strategic initiatives.</p>
          <p>Jackie will outline our financial and operating results. As you'll see, we're performing well on all major metrics. In the second quarter, we strengthened and expanded the global reach of our hematology and oncology franchises, advanced our development pipeline of 25 Phase III and pivotal clinical trials, and progressed our robust early pipeline of nearly 20 compounds in pre-clinical and clinical development. All of these are designed to sustain industry-leading growth well into the future. Our operating momentum is strong.</p>
          <p>Both our hematology and oncology franchises produced excellent commercial results in the quarter. Our cancer therapies were further enhanced by the data from more than 300 abstracts presented at major medical meetings over the past few months. Specific to REVLIMID, new clinical results in lymphoma and prostate cancer will help us accelerate our development programs. In myeloma, multiple studies demonstrated the exceptional benefit risk value proposition of REVLIMID, highlighted by the overall survival data from the CALGB study presented at the international myeloma workshop in Paris.</p>
          <p>Based on these significant results and comprehensive safety analyses specific to the low reported incidence of second primary malignancies, our clinical and regulatory teams have made significant progress towards bringing the Article 20 procedure to resolution and on executing our newly diagnosed multiple myeloma filing strategy. We're also working hard to further increase the value of our myeloma franchise by accelerating our clinical program and regulatory strategy for pomalidomide.</p>
          <p>Significant progress was achieved in our oncology franchise during the quarter. With growing ABRAXANE revenue and important new data at ASCO and other major medical meetings, we're creating commercial momentum in metastasized breast cancer and are generating data that will help drive this indication in the future. New and promising data has also been presented in both melanoma and pancreatic cancer. Importantly, our near-term drivers are planned filing for non-small-cell lung cancer in the U.S. later this year.</p>
          <p>We're also making excellent progress in our inflammation and immunology franchise, highlighted by the rapid accrual of our pivotal apremilast trials in psoriatic arthritis and psoriasis. These trials are now more than 50% accrued, with completion anticipated before year-end. With pivotal data likely to be presented beginning in less than a year, 2012 will be an exciting year for apremilast.</p>
          <p>Our research and translational medicine strategies continue to progress and are focused on long-term value creation. In just the past few months, we initiated our first clinical study with CC-115 and submitted the IND for CC-122, two promising novel anti-cancer agents discovered in our lab in San Diego.</p>
          <p>At Celgene, we remain focused on our objective of delivering value to our shareholders through operational excellence in all aspects of our business, and delivering on our goal of addressing the unmet medical needs of patients through innovative research. We're strategically positioned for sustained high growth and value creation in the months and years to come.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn the call over to Jackie to review our results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bob. Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us on the call today.</p>
          <p>Momentum continues to be strong for Celgene in 2011, and the team delivered an outstanding second quarter in all aspects. Second quarter revenue growth was excellent on a year-over-year basis, up 38%, as well as sequentially up 6%. As we will see in a moment, year-over-year product revenue growth was even stronger, at 40%. This growth drove non-GAAP operating profit that rose 33% and earnings per share that rose 29%.</p>
          <p>Excellent performance was achieved on all of our commercial metrics, including share and duration gains in all regions, continued expansion of market access, and efficiency in operating expenses. I'll cover our revenues by product and give you more color on expenses in a moment.</p>
          <p>We generated a strong performance, while continuing our commitment to invest for the future and while maintaining a strong balance sheet, even as we returned funds to shareholders via share buy-backs. Bob will cover more about our progress on the clinical and regulatory fronts in his coming remarks.</p>
          <p>Turning to our income statement, second quarter non-GAAP revenues grew 38% year-over-year, fueled by an excellent result from REVLIMID. The product continues to gain share in regions around the world, and duration of treatment trends remain on an upward trajectory. VIDAZA revenues are increasing rapidly outside the U.S., and in the U.S., we have not yet seen a generic azacytidine entrant. Momentum in ABRAXANE was outstanding in the quarter, as our commercial efforts in the U.S. have started to bear fruit and as launches of the product are underway outside the U.S.</p>
          <p>Regarding the impact of FX on revenues, as a reminder, we hedge revenues to the extent of our net exposure. Thus, this is reflected in the revenue line. That net impact for the year-over-year comparison was minimal.</p>
          <p>We maintained strong sequential growth quarter-to-quarter in 2011, coming out of the strong finish to 2010 where that fourth quarter also included our first quarter of ABRAXANE sales. Q2 2011 total revenue sequential growth was 6%, and sequential product revenue growth was an even more impressive 7.6%, driven by REVLIMID global sequential growth of 7.8%. ABRAXANE grew sequentially almost 28%, and ISTODAX sequential growth was over 21%.</p>
          <p>This revenue growth drove an operating profit increase of 33% for the second quarter of 2011 over the second quarter 2010, and non-GAAP EPS in the second quarter grew by 29%, to $0.89.</p>
          <p>Year-over-year R&amp;D expense for the quarter was up 52%, driven by progress on our late-stage clinical trials, as we reached the peak enrollment periods on many of those  The quarter also included a $7 million milestone payment to Acceleron under our collaboration agreement with them; full absorption of ABRAXANE R&amp;D, which we did not have in the second quarter 2010; and some costs associated with the work required to manage the second primary malignancy issues in the Article 20 regulatory procedure.</p>
          <p>Year-over-year SG&amp;A expense for the quarter increased 39%, as it included Abraxis integration costs, the impact of expenses for eight major medical meetings versus two in 2010 in the quarter, some costs associated with the work on the second primary malignancy issues, and a negative impact from foreign exchange. Without the impact of foreign exchange, SG&amp;A expense would have grown slower than revenue and would have been flat sequentially. I will cover our updated full-year outlook for expenses when I cover the new guidance in a moment.</p>
          <p>Looking at key individual product results, REVLIMID had a great quarter, with $795 million of sales, a year-over-year increase of 35% and a sequential increase of 7.8%. This growth includes the negative impact of the donut hole change that took effect as of January 1, 2011.</p>
          <p>The dollar impact of the donut hole in the second quarter was somewhat lower than it was in the first quarter. The dollar impact of the donut hole will be even lower in the second half of this year. I will cover the overall impact of healthcare reform in a coming slide.</p>
          <p>Revenue growth continued to be fueled by the multiple drivers of increased share, increased duration of treatment, and geographic expansions. VIDAZA net product sales grew 23% on a year-over-year basis, driven by international growth, and were slightly down sequentially. First quarter sales benefited from some pipeline fill in Japan as we launched there.</p>
          <p>The product lost exclusivity in the U.S. on May 19, and though we do not know what the timing of generic competition to VIDAZA will be, our future revenues in that market will decline upon such entry. We have not seen that entrant so far in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Momentum is building in ABRAXANE, and we are very pleased with its sales for the quarter at $95 million. The integration of the former Abraxis commercial infrastructure into Celgene is essentially complete in the U.S., and the product is launching internationally. There was a modest incremental benefit to the quarter from pipeline fill in some international markets. We expect to see continued success for ABRAXANE in metastatic breast cancer through the second half of this year and beyond.</p>
          <p>Regarding the geographic breakdown of REVLIMID, U.S. sales grew 30% year-over-year and almost 10% sequentially. International sales grew 43% year-over-year and approximately 5.5% sequentially.</p>
          <p>Regarding the expected full-year 2011 impact of all aspects of healthcare reform, we now forecast the total impact on revenues, including the donut hole change, to fall in the range of $70 million to $80 million, $10 million less than our original estimate of $80 million to $90 million. Particularly driven by the donut hole, a larger share of this impact has been incurred in the first half of the year. We now estimate the impact of the donut hole to be about $30 million for the full year, and we incurred about 75% of that cost in the first half of the year, around $23 million for all products.</p>
          <p>Turning to the key line items of our P&amp;L, our non-GAAP product gross margin was 93.2% for the quarter, consistent with the first quarter of this year and running slightly favorable to our guidance. On a year-over-year basis, that margin improved by 80 basis points, reflecting product mix.</p>
          <p>On the expense side, in the quarter, R&amp;D increased somewhat as a percentage of revenue, partly due to the $7 million Acceleron milestone payment and some of the other costs I mentioned earlier, but also because we are hitting the peak enrollment periods for many of our late-stage trials. We expect full-year R&amp;D dollars to be in line with our original dollar guidance of $1.2 billion and slightly lower as a percentage of revenues, as you see in our updated guidance, at around 26%.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A expense posted modest sequential growth of 1.6% over the first quarter but was up 39% for the year-over-year period, as the current quarter includes costs associated with the ongoing integration of Abraxis, a higher than usual number of medical meetings in the quarter, and costs related to the management of the second primary malignancy issue, as well as the foreign exchange impact I mentioned earlier. We now expect these expenses to come in for the full year at closer to $1 billion versus our previous guidance of $950 million, partly driven by launch expenses for ISTODAX in the U.S. and higher than expected contributions to patient assistance programs. Expressed as a percentage of revenue, at about 22%, they will be almost 150 basis points lower than 2010.</p>
          <p>Our effective tax rate for the second quarter was 19%, an increase versus the comparable period one year ago. We now expect the full-year rate to be a bit higher, at 19% to 19.5%, driven by incremental VIDAZA revenue in the U.S. If U.S. VIDAZA revenues continue to exceed our forecasts for the remainder of the year, this will affect our revenue mix and will drive an increase in the effective tax rate for this year. That is considered in our updated guidance. Such an impact would not be sustained after 2011.</p>
          <p>We see leverage in our P&amp;L that is driving an expansion in our operating profit margin year-over-year. We are producing this result while investing in R&amp;D spend that is impacted by our 25 late-stage clinical trials and while absorbing and integrating the Abraxis business into the Celgene portfolio.</p>
          <p>Our strong profit performance is driving strong cash flow generation, and our operations produced $736 million in the first half of this year. We continue to return capital to shareholders in the form of share repurchases, while investing for the long-term growth of our business. We bought back about $689 million of stock in the first six months of 2011, and our cash position remains relatively constant. As of today, we have approximately $800 million remaining under our existing repurchase authorization.</p>
          <p>Turning to our updated 2011 financial outlook, we have updated our full-year revenue and earnings guidance to reflect several factors. First, we expect continued strong growth from our hematology franchise, as share and duration gains as well as geographic expansion are all driving revenue.</p>
          <p>Second, though we expect sales of VIDAZA in the U.S. to eventually be negatively impacted upon entry of a generic competitor, the timing for that entry is later than we originally anticipated. Second quarter VIDAZA sales benefited incrementally from this situation, and we are benefiting from it so far in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Finally, several expense items were more heavily weighted to the first half of the year, and we will see most of this year's P&amp;L leverage in the second half of the year, particularly in SG&amp;A expense.</p>
          <p>We now expect full-year REVLIMID net product sales to reach $3.15 billion to $3.25 billion, and total non-GAAP revenue to be in a range of $4.6 billion to $4.7 billion. Mostly driven by higher revenues, we have increased our full-year guidance for earnings per share to $3.45 to $3.55 range. We widened the forecasted EPS range to take into consideration the uncertain timing of generic competition to VIDAZA.</p>
          <p>Our dollar guidance for non-GAAP R&amp;D expense has not changed, though its percentage of revenue falls as a result of the increase in revenues. And I already mentioned the modest changes to our expectations for full-year SG&amp;A expense and the tax rate.</p>
          <p>So, to summarize, the Celgene team again delivered an outstanding result during the second quarter of 2011, producing strong growth in the overall top and bottom lines as well as by key products. Our performance is sustainable and robust because it is fueled by multiple value drivers. We are performing well across all major metrics and maintain our position of excellent financial strength and flexibility. We will continue to deliver strong performance for all of our stakeholders and invest appropriately to sustain the strong trajectory of industry-leading profitable growth for many years into the future.</p>
          <p>For more on our broader strategy and accomplishments, I'll now turn the call over to Bob. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jackie.</p>
          <p>As you've heard, it was quite a quarter. I'd like to take a few minutes to share my perspective, and let me start with REVLIMID. REVLIMID sales continue to be strong, with 35% year-over-year growth. In the United States, REVLIMID has approximately 50% of the overall myeloma market, up two points versus last quarter; and 52% share in second line, also up two points versus the first quarter of the year. Increasing duration of treatment is a continuing indicator of effective chronic disease control and a valuable growth driver.</p>
          <p>International sales grew 43% year-over-year. Line 2 share in the four major European markets, where second line is reimbursed, is approximately 50%, up from 46% in the first quarter. Line 3 in the five major markets is approximately 42%. After one full year of commercialization in Japan, we are pleased that the overall market share for REVLIMID in multiple myeloma is about 22%, an excellent beginning to our launch, in spite of the tragic events of early 2011.</p>
          <p>We continue to expand our global reach for REVLIMID through regulatory and reimbursement approvals in emerging markets also. The clinical potential of REVLIMID in other areas is being recognized. Of note, emerging data on REVLIMID was highlighted at the International Conference on Malignant Lymphoma in Switzerland. And based on these data, REVLIMID was granted reimbursement in mantle-cell and diffuse large B-cell lymphoma in Italy. Across all metrics, it was an excellent quarter for REVLIMID, with strong momentum.</p>
          <p>VIDAZA sales grew 23% year-over-year, driven primarily by strong performance in Europe, Asia-Pacific, and Japan. Following the first quarter approval by the health technology assessment agency NICE, VIDAZA sales have grown dramatically in the United Kingdom, increasing 48% quarter over quarter. Additionally, our teams in Australia and Canada are producing strong sales in their first few quarters since launch. Despite the loss of orphan drug exclusively for VIDAZA in the United States, no generic has entered the market, as Jackie reported, and our quarter-over-quarter sales remain steady. With the approval of ISTODAX in peripheral T-cell lymphoma, our sales force now has the added responsibility of launching ISTODAX for this new indication in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Expanding our oncology franchise is an important objective. ABRAXANE sales grew by 28% quarter-over-quarter, to $95 million. Following the completion of the commercial team integration and the repositioning of ABRAXANE, sales in the United States grew 15%. In Europe, ABRAXANE is being launched in the four major markets and will continue to launch on a country-by-country basis in the second half of 2011 and 2012. We believe that the development of ABRAXANE in all stages of breast cancer, non-small-cell lung cancer, pancreatic, metastatic melanoma, and multiple other indications offer significant high-growth opportunities for our oncology franchise.</p>
          <p>Critical data is the lifeblood of hematology-oncology franchises. The past several months were significant for the number of major medical meetings where Celgene's compounds were highlighted. In hematology, the presentation of updated data from the CALGB, IFM, and MM-015 newly diagnosed multiple myeloma studies confirmed a 50% to 60% improvement in progression-free survival, high overall response rates, and now an overall survival benefit in the CALGB post-transplant maintenance study. This significant overall survival benefit and the ongoing analyses of the reports of second primary malignancies advanced the global myeloma community's understanding of the benefit/risk of profile of REVLIMID in myeloma.</p>
          <p>In lymphoma, compelling REVLIMID Phase II data were presented at the International Conference on Malignant Lymphoma for patients with untreated diffuse large D-cell, mantle-cell, and follicular lymphoma. Updated data on the combination of REVLIMID with rituximab, or R-squared, in previously untreated follicular lymphoma demonstrated a 98% overall response rate, with an 85% complete response rate. And for patients followed for 24 months, progression-free survival was 83%. These data are the basis for the recently announced Phase III GELA study evaluating the combination of REVLIMID plus rituximab for patients with newly diagnosed follicular lymphoma. We expect this very important study to start later this year.</p>
          <p>As many of you are aware, in June we received accelerated approval for ISTODAX for the treatment of peripheral T-cell lymphoma in patients who have received at least one prior therapy. Our U.S. sales force has just completed product training to support the U.S. commercial launch.</p>
          <p>In oncology, the full data analysis from our ABRAXANE Phase III trial in non-small-cell lung cancer were presented at ASCO in June and at the International Association for the Study of Lung Cancer meeting in July; in the final data, a significant improvement in overall response rate of 33% for the combination of ABRAXANE plus carboplatin versus 25% for the paclitaxel carboplatin arm. A subset analysis demonstrated that patients 70 years and older achieved almost a doubling of overall survival, to almost 20 months versus approximately 10 months. Additional prospective studies of ABRAXANE in non-small-cell lung cancer are being evaluated to follow up on clinical outcome based on histology and age. We're on schedule to file our sNDA with the FDA by the end of this year and are reviewing our filing options for other international markets.</p>
          <p>Also presented at ASCO were encouraging data from a randomized Phase II study evaluating the combination of ABRAXANE, Avastin, and carboplatin in melanoma, which reported one-year survival rates of nearly 60%, with an estimated median survival of nearly 14 months. Additionally, Phase II data presented at ASCO on the combination of REVLIMID, Avastin, and docetaxel in first-line castrate-resistant prostate cancer showed more than 86% of patients achieved a 50% reduction of PSA or better. Celgene's REVLIMID Phase III MAINSAIL study with docetaxel is rapidly recruiting patients and is expected to complete enrollment this quarter.</p>
          <p>We have multiple near-term regulatory growth drivers. The highest priorities of our clinical and regulatory teams are on the resolution of the Article 20 procedure and our REVLIMID filing for newly diagnosed multiple myeloma and maintenance therapy with the EMA. We're working on our responses to the 120-day and the Article 20 questions in parallel, and we remain on track, with the newly-diagnosed multiple myeloma regulatory strategy targeted for the first quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>At the completion of the Article 20 procedure, we plan to file for MDS deletion 5q in Europe. Separately, we're optimistic on Swiss regulatory approval for REVLIMID in the MDS deletion 5q indication late this year.</p>
          <p>We continue to advance our global regulatory strategy for pomalidomide in relapsed/refractory multiple myeloma and myelofibrosis. Given the increasing pool of patients who have very limited treatment options in the relapsed myeloma setting, there's broad-based participation in the clinical development of pomalidomide. Importantly, our international Phase III study in 15 countries is open and accruing. Additionally, we expect the final data from our Phase II pomalidomide MM-002 study to be presented at the upcoming ASH meeting in December. We continue to have active discussions with the regulatory agencies, and as soon as we're able to provide you with an update on the filing strategy, we will.</p>
          <p>We're also making outstanding progress advancing our clinical programs, with key milestones throughout the remainder of this year and 2012. Data from REVLIMID and pomalidomide myeloma studies will be presented late this year, and with additional data throughout 2012. New pivotal trials in lymphoma and leukemias will open, while others will complete accrual, and the first Phase III trial of REVLIMID in the solid tumor indication will, again, complete enrollment this quarter. We'll continue to update you on the status of our promising pivotal ABRAXANE trial in pancreatic cancer.</p>
          <p>Our immunology and inflammation franchise is making significant progress, with full enrollment of six Phase III apremilast studies expected by year-end. And we'll advance our novel cellular therapy PDA-001 in three Phase II studies, which we expect will also complete enrollment by year-end, with proof-of-concept results in 2012. These high-value clinical programs, with breakthrough potential, are the result of a sustained focused investment in R&amp;D.</p>
          <p>We're executing on our strategy, delivering strong operational and financial results, expanding our global reach, and advancing our regulatory, clinical, and research programs by driving operational excellence in all functions. We are delivering in the here-and-now and building a tremendous future for Celgene and our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much for joining us today. And, Operator, will you please open the line for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first questioner in queue is Matt Roden with UBS. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks so much for taking the question, and congrats on a very nice quarter. So firstly, on the day-120 questions on the newly diagnosed myeloma filing, is there anything in those questions that would change your confidence one way or another in terms of the outcome of the filing? And then secondly, more of a longer-term strategic question as it relates to operating leverage, Jackie, you've indicated that, near-term, more of the leverage is going to come from the SG&amp;A side, but I think you guys have something like 10 Phase III trials, reading out over the next two years, so with that in mind, longer-term, do you see some potential to have a little bit of leverage coming from the R&amp;D side as well? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, Matt &#x2013; it's Bob &#x2013; on the 120-day questions and the Article 20, just to cover that, there are no questions there that we think are not expected. They're very much in line with what we've expected, and we're working very focused and expeditiously to ensure we give the complete, comprehensive answers, and we're very confident in our ability to do so. So I wouldn't say there's anything that we're not expecting, and we're moving very aggressively to complete it as quickly as we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Matt. Just on the operating leverage question, so yes, you see the leverage coming through in SG&amp;A, and I think I've spoken before about my expectations for that over time, where I think percentages of revenue is going to trend down into the teens, and you see that coming through this year already with about a 150-basis-point move. On the R&amp;D side, you're absolutely right. We have a long a lot of late-stage trials reaching peak enrollment periods. We are going to continue to invest appropriately in R&amp;D. Given the platform that we have today, I would expect to potentially see some leverage from that over time, and as I think I've highlighted when we've spoken about our 2015 long-term very high-level guidance, what we've assumed there is that R&amp;D stays flat at about 25% of revenues and we're still driving EPS growth, even with that assumption, in the mid-20% range. So I think that's a conservative assumption, and you see how we're doing with it this year, even with everything that we've got going on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Geoff Porges with Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. And just related to this operating leverage question, Jackie, it looks as though, in the second half, your guidance is that, at least on a current basis, that revenue growth will slow down to something around 20% but that you'll deliver EPS growth in the second half substantially above that revenue growth, so two questions. One, is that a correct interpretation of the guidance? And secondly, if indeed revenue growth is sustained at the growth that you saw in the first half of the year, which was closer to 40%, should we anticipate that the EPS growth in the second half will be at your guidance &#x2013; which will therefore match revenue growth &#x2013; or will the incremental operating income flow through to higher EPS? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, your interpretation of the numbers is accurate. I think you can triangulate them and come at them in a few different ways and you get more or less the same answer. So included in our revenue guidance for the second half of the year is an assumption around an eventual entrant generic competition to VIDAZA, so one has to keep that in mind when one thinks about the growth rate in the second half of the year. The comp obviously also gets harder and harder as we continue to see VIDAZA grow in revenues. So you can think about the revenue guidance that way.</p>
          <p>With respect to expenses, particularly in SG&amp;A, for all the reasons that I mentioned in my prepared remarks, we had much more of certain expenses loaded into the first half of the year, and those will not repeat in the second half of the year. So you've got my commitment to see that leverage in the second half of the year, and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The whole team's commitment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The whole team's commitment. And just when we look at R&amp;D as a percent of revenues, we don't make our investment decisions that way, as everyone knows, but we are tracking very nicely to that $1.2 billion. So if revenues continue to exceed expectations, then obviously that percent of revenues come down so when you think about straightforward P&amp;L leverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Terrific. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Geoff Meacham with JPMorgan. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Thanks for taking the question. A question on pomalidomide. I'm just curious what the gating factor for a filing decision is. Is it more data? Have you guys met with FDA already? Is the conversation a little different in Europe with respect to filing? And then just a quick follow-up, REVLIMID, when you look at OUS geography, maybe just would be helpful if you guys put some of these emerging markets in the bigger context of what the opportunity could be just in the core myeloma indications &#x2013; for example, in China, Brazil, things like that. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, first on pomalidomide, as we mentioned in the earlier discussion, the <mark type="ph" /> MM-02 (36:38) data, the updated and really complete data will be presented at ASH this year. So with any type of potential for any kind of accelerated regulatory approval, you'd need to have that data completely analyzed and available for any kind of discussion. So that was our first priority to ensure that, and any type of accelerated opportunity for pomalidomide would be in discussions like, you say, in the U.S., and we're engaging in continuous discussions with regulatory agencies, as you'd expect.</p>
          <p>So as that data &#x2013; the complete analysis is available, any potential opportunity will become clear. Once it is clear, what the strategy will be in timelines, we will be as transparent as we can when that's clear, and we're hopeful that's not in the &#x2013; that we'll make progress on that, but the belt-and-suspenders baseline guidance is based on Phase III trials, and that's why we're accelerating the development of the Phase III trial in Europe. And so in Europe, you should definitely consider that as the baseline strategy, though, obviously if we're successful in any market, try and export that success to all other markets.</p>
          <p>And then on REVLIMID specifically, I think you could point out two important markets over time that we don't yet have either regulatory or reimbursement approval, China and Brazil. And China is an attractive market over time for us. We're completing the important bridging studies done in China. It's also an important accrual center for MM-020 study. So those are markets we're focused on. We're optimistic in the next sort of 18 to 24 months we could see them beginning to have an impact on revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Mark Schoenebaum with ISI Group. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Congratulations on a great quarter. I just had a question back on REVLIMID. Is the &#x2013; or sorry, on the EMA regulatory process. Is getting the Article 20 issue resolved gating in any way to the label expansions? And once the label is expanded, should our expectations be that you'll get a maintenance claim in a post-transplant setting as well as the first-line setting in non-transplant patients, or should we be assuming that you get just one of those two? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. Yeah, I think a couple questions there. First on the review, it is important for us to get the Article 120 issues resolved because that's fundamental to &#x2013; and just not &#x2013; we wouldn't expect to get any label expansion until the Article 20 is resolved. And that's why we're so focused on making sure that we have the comprehensive, complete analysis, and our team has really the investment and done a great job to ensure that we have that well positioned and the strategy being well executed there. And we're moving along on the right course there. They're technically not linked, but in essence you need to have the Article 120 done before you can have an expectation of a complete review of any of the indications.</p>
          <p>And any label expansion is going be based on the data that's filed, and our expectation is that we will have a rigorous discussion around both the maintenance post-transplant based on the IFM and the CALGB study and on an induction or initial treatment under MM-015, based on the population within that data, that would support a label expansion. So the regulatory review in the end will determine what the outcome is on the label &#x2013; good, bad, or indifferent &#x2013; but it is our intention to expeditiously get the Article 20 done, get the 120-day questions resolved, and pursue that kind of dialogue on both the newly diagnosed label expansion and the maintenance study, and the regulatory process will resolve that in the coming months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Chris Raymond with Robert Baird. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks. Just wanted to make sure I understand completely, I don't think we saw on the slides absolute U.S. and ex-U.S. numbers &#x2013; you typically have given that in the past &#x2013; but you did give sequential growth, so can I just confirm, was the U.S. number $460 million and the ex-U.S. number $336 million? And then I have a follow-up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, hi, Chris. Yes, we did have on the slide the breakdown between U.S. and international REVLIMID product sales. The U.S. number for the quarter is $458 million. The international number for the quarter is $337 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>$337 million. Great. Okay. Thanks. And the follow-up is on ABRAXANE. You're kind of struck by the strong showing this quarter, especially we were expecting some generic Taxotere pressure, at least through this quarter. So maybe can you give a little bit more color about what's going on there in terms of the upside and market share dynamics, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. As we mentioned, we're very focused on making sure that as we expand into oncology, we do this effectively. And we feel very good about the integration, the quality of team that we have put together on the sales side and the marketing side and market access, et cetera. So we're very focused on execution, which is certainly important to us expanding the revenue in the metastatic breast situation.</p>
          <p>There are a number of other factors that are both positives and headwinds in the sense that when you have the generic Taxotere, that certainly is a headwind that we experienced in the first quarter, and there was inventory issues in the first quarter. The second quarter, we probably got a little bit of a benefit from the fact that there's been some shortages of generic anti-cancer chemotherapy drugs. So for the most part, I think we're working our way through the generic Taxotere. That's something that's going to affect us this quarter, in the third quarter, and will gradually dissipate. So I think there's a number of positive and negative factors.</p>
          <p>We're focused on what we control, is building a market share in the approved indication, and we're very pleased with the progress that we're making about building a very comprehensive development plan in lung cancer where, again, we're hopeful we'll be able to actually promote on that in 2012. And we fully accrued the Phase III. It may not be a pivotal study in melanoma, but we're seeing good traction there in terms of accelerating our program there.</p>
          <p>And, as everyone knows, we're very focused on pancreatic. We expanded that trial to 800-plus patients to ensure that when we get the result there, we get a definitive answer. So we're working hard to build a very comprehensive focus on ABRAXANE, both on commercial execution and regulatory and clinical programs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Gene Mack with Mizuho Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the question. I wonder if I could just follow up on ABRAXANE and get a sense of how gross margins might be impacted as sales increase or as that product becomes a little bit more of the sales mix. And then could we also get an update on what the status is of oral formulation of VIDAZA is, and then just a breakout of maybe what REVLIMID sales were in Japan? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Gene, it's Jackie. Let me start with the ABRAXANE question. So the cost of goods on ABRAXANE is a little bit higher than it is on our hematology products. So from an overall standpoint of its impact on the mix, all other things being equal, it would tend to be a little bit negative for the portfolio from a mix standpoint. However, the hematology products are growing so nicely and weigh so heavily in that mix that they contribute very positively. And what we see with ABRAXANE is 10, 20 basis points here or there that would push maybe that number up, but the momentum for the cost of goods is very much on a downward trajectory, so the net impact is still positive. And you see, then, that we're running 20 basis points ahead of our guidance.</p>
          <p>So I'm not at all concerned that momentum in ABRAXANE is going to have a negative impact on the cost of goods. I'm very happy to see the momentum in ABRAXANE. And when you think out for the long term with other products that should be coming into the revenue mix in the not-too-distant future &#x2013; products like pomalidomide, other indications in the future for REVLIMID &#x2013; that's a very good thing from a cost of goods standpoint.</p>
          <p>Then I think your next question was oral &#x2013; update on oral <mark type="ph" /> azacytidine (46:32)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (46:33), yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we're very encouraged by what we're seeing in terms of the activity, and the tremendous interest in really having an oral epigenetic therapy that can be dosed on an ongoing basis to really have a positive impact, especially in combination therapy. So we've made great progress on the formulation, and we're accelerating that development program as quickly as we can because we think, in a number of indications, this is going be a very attractive opportunity for us.</p>
          <p>And then on &#x2013; I think the other question was on Japan. We don't specifically break out Japan. And I'd say there are some very positives in Japan like we've always talked about, the ideal nature of REVLIMID fitting that marketplace, and we're on track with where we'd hoped we'd be, so we haven't seen any dramatic impact on the events in the first quarter, but we're always sensitive to what the future might bring.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. I think you probably saw on the slide that we did give you an overall share number for REVLIMID in Japan at 22% total, all lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Yaron Werber with Citi. Your question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks so much for taking my question, and also congrats on the good quarter. So two questions. First, just help us understand a little bit REVLIMID in the U.S., and what exactly are you waiting in order to file the first line and maintenance filing? Are you waiting for the IFM survival cut? Is that what it is? And then I have a follow-on as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the first thing that we are doing is resolving the SPM and the Article 20 process because I don't think any regulatory agency is going to say, I'm going to ignore that, even though I don't see that, we don't use melphalan in this country in a very significant way, and it's very clear to us what the risk/benefit is. They're going to want to see that. So we want to make sure the Article 20 process comes to a resolution. And we keep all regulatory agencies all over the world updated on that.</p>
          <p>So we want to do that. And then we'll have the maximum updated, most mature data in both MM-015 and in the maintenance studies. And it is our objective to submit both MM-015 and the maintenance studies CALGB and IFM in the U.S. once we get the completed Article 20 and a resolution of the whole package of the maturity of the data.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, secondly, when we look sequentially quarter-over-quarter OUS, the growth was &#x2013; at 5.5%, it was around $19 million or $18 million. Can you quantify how much of that is Europe versus the rest of the world outside of Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yaron, the one thing that I would say about Europe is you do have some impact, specifically in the French market, with REVLIMID with what's going on there, which I think is to be expected, given everything that's gone on around the SPM issues and the IFM trial and the environment there in France.</p>
          <p>So it's a big market for us in Europe. So the European growth for the whole portfolio was very good, but it would have been even better if France had performed in line with what we would expect under a more usual market situation. So I think that's probably the best way to think about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Bret Holley with Oppenheimer. Your question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks for taking the questions, and then I'll add my congratulations. I guess my question is kind of a follow-up to the last question. I guess you said that you had very rapid share gains in Europe in line 2/3 REVLIMID use, and I'm wondering what's driving that phenomenon, given the fact that the newest data obviously is focused on frontline maintenance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there are a couple of positive factors affecting it. One, you have other therapies moving more to first-line, so you have a positive impact by using more novel therapies in frontline, which will give REVLIMID even a stronger position in second and third-line.</p>
          <p>And I think the whole idea &#x2013; the whole paradigm of continuous therapy continues to be validated in medical meetings throughout the period. So I think there's very positive data that really improves the old messaging around continuous therapy and the dynamic of using innovative therapy as early as possible leads to longer duration and more effective patient treatment. So that's positive.</p>
          <p>The one offset that we have to &#x2013; that everyone needs to keep in mind is that in the second half of 2010, and even in the second quarter of 2010, you saw price decreases in Spain and you had Germany's price decrease in the third quarter of last year. So we're offsetting those and continuing to grow in spite of those, so that's a very encouraging sign.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Brian Abrahams with Wells Fargo. Your question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for taking my question, and congrats on the strong quarter. Can you talk us through potential outcomes with respect to the impact of the Article 20 review on your existing label for REVLIMID in Europe and how that might affect the size of your current reimbursable population there? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our analysis of &#x2013; and all the work that we've done for months really, we believe, strongly validates the benefit/risk value proposition of REVLIMID, and we would not anticipate any impact on the opportunity that REVLIMID has on the existing label or, in longer-term, in broadening the label in many, many different ways &#x2013; in myeloma and in many diseases and indications outside of myeloma.</p>
          <p>So we have not seen anything that would give us any reason to reconsider our outlook in myeloma or in other indications. So that's very clear with what we've seen. Now, we obviously have to just continue to make sure that information is presented effectively and communicated to regulatory agencies around the world.</p>
          <p>So there isn't anything that would change our optimism, our investment in broadening and strengthening the REVLIMID franchise by diseases, within myeloma globally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Michael Yee with RBC Capital Markets. Your line is now open. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Great, thanks. Congrats on the great quarter. Just a follow-up on the Article 20, is there actually a clock in terms of responding to the 120-day questions? Have you actually filed? Is there a gating timeline along that? And do you expect to resolve that around the end of summer, early fall? And at what point, if any, does it impact staying the course for the newly diagnosed EMA filing? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, as we mentioned earlier, the Article 20 and the 120-day questions are separate phenomenon, though are being worked on in parallel, but you're not going to see a complete review of any regulatory package until the Article 20 procedure is completed.</p>
          <p>And there are not specific timelines related to the Article 20. But I can assure you that we are working expeditiously to ensure that any and all questions are very rapidly and effectively answered. And obviously, you have a little bit of a summer issue in terms of August, et cetera, in terms of review of our responses and discussions.</p>
          <p>But it is moving along I think very appropriately. We do not feel there's any issues of it not being handled expeditiously. We're working very closely with the regulators, and we think it's a very appropriate timing of how things are going. And we feel very good, again, to reiterate on the analysis that we've done, which is a very comprehensive analysis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Ian Somaiya with Piper Jaffray. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I had a couple of questions. First on VIDAZA, Jackie, you mentioned that there's no generic entrant. I was wondering if you can confirm whether there's been a generic filing in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Unrelated, but question on VIDAZA, is the trial that you announced &#x2013; the start of the REVLIMID VIDAZA trial in AML, just curious why you would pursue a trial when there's the potential for a generic entry at some point. And then I had one last question, if you don't mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we don't have any access to any information regarding any other regulatory filings, outside of the ones that Celgene does, than anybody else would, so I couldn't give you any more assistance on that.</p>
          <p>And I think that we have a number of strategies around VIDAZA oral azacytidine and REVLIMID in a number of indications. And we think REVLIMID will be significantly enhanced in AML, whether it's used with a generic VIDAZA, a branded VIDAZA, or oral azacytidine.</p>
          <p>So we will explore the combinations that we think have the most patient impact, and we think that combination is going to have a big impact on AML patients. And we'll certainly benefit directly from REVLIMID, potentially VIDAZA, and over time potentially oral azacitidine. And outside the United States, it also will have significant value to us both with VIDAZA and REVLIMID.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just the last question was on maybe a follow-up to Matt's earlier question on the R&amp;D spend. Just tracking the 25 Phase III trials that are ongoing, it looks like about 9 read out to finish in 2012, about 14 or 15 by the end of 2013. Is there potential for a scenario where R&amp;D spend on an absolute basis could be either flat or down? I know you have historically spoken to R&amp;D declining as a percent of sales, but just curious from the standpoint of absolute dollar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think that one of the things that we have tried to do &#x2013; and obviously we will evolve our processes appropriately over time, but historically, and where we are today is we look at the value proposition and does that investment justify another dollar or not.</p>
          <p>And so there absolutely is the potential for a absolute dollar decline in R&amp;D, but I'm not predicting that. I'm hopeful that the pipeline will accelerate, other opportunities will come along. But we set no standard that we must invest in this or we cannot have a decline in it, and if it's appropriate to have a decline based on the opportunities we have, we will not spend the money without, we believe, the proper value proposition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Ying Huang with Gleacher &amp; Co. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for taking my questions here. So can you give us an update on the FDA safety review process for REVLIMID, and then is that a factor why you're delaying the filing in the front line? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to make it clear, we work very appropriately to ensure that every regulatory agency around the world is fully kept informed of any discussions with any other regulatory authority in terms of data filing. And there is nothing specific in any market that is different than just let's resolve the Article 20 process so then we'll disseminate that information. And we'll disseminate it as we &#x2013; once we provide it to one agency, we provide it to another.</p>
          <p>So there's nothing in the U.S. that is different than what we're trying to do. And once we resolve the Article 20 process, we'll move expeditiously all around the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Eric Schmidt with Cowen &amp; Co. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my questions. Just as a follow-up to that safety review question, when might we see some resolution, and do you expect any updates to the label to be made after that safety review?</p>
          <p>And then, second, just to maybe try and kill the questions around the Article 20 resolution, do you think, Bob, that you're still on track for, say, a standard 15-ish-month approval process in Europe, given that you filed back in January of this year for the expanded label?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, on the Article 20, and in general this whole area, I just want to re-emphasize again that we have done incredibly comprehensive, detailed, substantive review of all available data on REVLIMID and do not believe that there's any issue out there that will prevent us from fully capitalizing on the potential of REVLIMID within myeloma and with every other indication that we pursue as a potential for REVLIMID.</p>
          <p>So there's nothing new that we're aware of that would have a deleterious effect on any type of regulatory, clinical, commercial opportunity for REVLIMID.</p>
          <p>That being said, we've got to finish the Article 20 process. We think it's moving expeditiously. There's not a specific date for that review, but we're doing everything, and we don't sense in our regulatory discussions any type of issue that is not in a very constructive, engaged process of achieving this review and completing it. And when that's completed, then we'll be able to have the rigorous review about the MM-015 and the IFM and the CALGB.</p>
          <p>So specifically the timeline there, there's nothing that we're aware of that would change the timelines that we've targeted, but we have to get through the Article 20 process, we have to go through the regulatory process, and then in the end, the timeline and the actual label will be what it will be. But we're not aware of any data that should have any fundamental change to our ability in any of the areas that we're focused on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Rachel McMinn with Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, two questions. Just one on capital deployment &#x2013; Jackie, I think you've talked about $2 billion in cash being a comfort zone on the balance sheet, so as your cash flow continues to be really strong, should we expect you to continue to augment your buy-back program, or how are you thinking about M&amp;A?</p>
          <p>And then &#x2013; sorry for this, but just on the U.S. and EU filing, I guess what are the chances, or do you think there's any reason at this point based on the questions that you have from EMA that you would need to supplement your filing with the 020 data? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer the second one first. There are not any questions that we're aware of that would change our view on filing additional data or waiting for additional data. We have to go through the review process, and the label will reflect what's in the data submissions, but we don't have any plans today to add to the filing of MM-015, IFM, and CALGB.</p>
          <p>That being said, all along, MM-020 is an incredibly important study because it really does challenge any type of Melphalan initial therapy, and that 1,600-patient study, as you know, finished accruing last year. And so we're going to see data in the hopefully not-too-distant future that we think has the potential to really be a definitive answer. So assuming we get the regulatory review of MM-015, IFM, and CALGB &#x2013; all around the world; we're not going to wait anywhere for the MM-020 data &#x2013; but once we have the MM-020 data and if it's as positive as we hope it'll be, we'll obviously look to augment those filings and those labels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Rachel, and to your question on capital deployment, we're going to continue to manage the capital structure dynamically. You'll see that from us just on an ongoing basis. So I think what you've seen us do in the first half of the year is somewhat representative of how I would think about the second half of the year, as long as we don't have some kind of a major M&amp;A transaction.</p>
          <p>As you know, on those, we look at them, again, based on the value proposition and the strategic importance for Celgene, and we'll do those as appropriate. But if we do not have that kind of a capital need in any given year, we are generating very strong cash flow, and we're going to use that to dynamically manage our capital structure. So that will be something that you'll just see evolve on a quarter-to-quarter basis.</p>
          <p>I've said it before. I'll say it again. We don't need to build up huge amounts of cash in our balance sheet, and we're not going to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Joel Sendek with Lazard Capital Markets. Your question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks a lot. I have a question on ABRAXANE. Can you help us understand how soon you could get the approval in lung cancer, and are you specifically going after a label in the over-70 population? And have you had discussions with the FDA about that in particular yet? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Specifically to the non-small-cell lung application, we're obviously pulling that together, and we'll get that submitted as quickly as possible because we do expect a standard 10-month review, so the sooner we get that done, the quicker the ability for us to do that.</p>
          <p>And then we're looking at other opportunities. Clearly, our nearest-term targets are both melanoma and pancreatic as the &#x2013; even though we've got other targets that we think have the potential for both clinical and regulatory progress &#x2013; ovarian and bladder &#x2013; but clearly the next two are going to be the pancreatic and melanoma.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Thomas Wei with Jefferies &amp; Co. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I was wondering, another follow-up on the potential label that you might get in Europe. When you say the label will reflect the data that you've got so far, is there any indication from the questions or your interactions with the EMA that they would look at the data from the MM-015 and somehow draw the conclusion that REVLIMID is not offering any benefit as part of induction, and that in the transplant-ineligible population it should only get a label for maintenance-only? Is that even possible to draw that conclusion scientifically without an arm that contains MP followed by REV maintenance?</p>
          <p>And then just a second question on any plans that you're aware of being developed by cooperative groups to look at the question of a fixed duration of REVLIMID maintenance versus continuous REVLIMID maintenance through progression. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, obviously, any regulatory outcome is possible, and certainly a maintenance label is a possible outcome because the IFM data and the CALGB data are part of the filing. So, regardless of MM-015, which is the base part of the filing, we do have the IFM and CALGB in there. So having a maintenance expansion in the label based on the European filing is a very possible outcome.</p>
          <p>I think that the analysis in review of the MM-015 data may look at populations within that prior-to-transplant by age or other stuff that could have an effect on the actual upfront newly diagnosed label, but that will be part of the regulatory review. And so far, from what we've seen, it's going be the kind of normal regulatory review that you would expect that would go through all of these issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Shiv Kapoor with Morgan Joseph. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question, and congratulation on your quarter. Most of my questions have been answered, but I wanted to find what kind of exposure you might have to Southern Europe and what kind of changes you've made, if any, to your bad debt expense from that area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just &#x2013; I just want to make sure, before we answer that question, that we just fill in one of the previous questions a little bit about the studies that will look at fixed duration of maintenance therapy versus continuous maintenance therapy with REVLIMID post-transplant.</p>
          <p>Obviously, the data that we're looking at, we analyze all the subsets of the existing data, and so far what we seem to see is that continuous therapy seems to have the greatest potential for patient benefit. But it is a good question, and there are studies being planned and looked at that will look at 18 months, two years of REV treatment versus continuous in the post-transplant setting.</p>
          <p>So I think, over time, over the next five, six years, you will see data that will come out to help answer that. But initially we think, as we look at the people, examine this data, it's very possible that the conclusion will be that in certain populations, you may want to limit, but for the largest percentage of the population, you'll want to have continuous therapy.</p>
          <p>So <mark type="ph" /> let me go to (1:09:01) this question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thanks. So just on the Southern European exposure, a market that's gotten particular attention being Greece, we use a distributor in Greece so we have minimal, minimal exposure there, and all of that is current on &#x2013; if you look at Spain, Italy, Portugal, those countries, the company's always been quite diligent at how it manages those receivables, and we continue to do that. So if you look at our days sales outstanding by country &#x2013; which you don't have visibility to &#x2013; but you would find that for those countries, obviously, they are a bit longer than they are for countries like France and Germany and the others, but they are lower than the benchmarks for the typical payment terms in those countries. So we manage the exposure very closely, and we are diligent about staying on top of that. Our relative exposures are quite modest actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Howard Liang with Leerink Swann. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Have you seen a positive impact since the second quarter after the CLGB overall survival data, and are you able to communicate or highlight the data to physicians?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the impact of that data is and will be quite positive. Clearly, the timing of the data &#x2013; there hasn't been much time, and we really don't have internal resource or research that would indicate what the impact is. Over time, we'll have third-party research and we'll be able to do better analysis. I really can't give you much of what the near-term impact has been. And the communication of it, obviously, the most value to the marketplace will be peer-reviewed publication of the data. That's something that the scientific community is working on, and that will be a big advantage to us when it's peer-reviewed published.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next questioner in queue is Sapna Srivastava with Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for taking my questions. I have just a couple of quick clarifications. One on VIDAZA, could you help us understand what's the exposure to ex-U.S. and to U.S. sales? And secondly, just with the debt ceiling debate, do you have any comments on dual eligibles, and is there any concern that that may come to fruition this time versus healthcare reform? And that's basically it. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Sapna. So just on your VIDAZA question, obviously the growth is mostly outside of the U.S. So the product is doing extremely well, and what we start to see is, in terms of the overall global sales for VIDAZA, it will be shifting closer and closer to &#x2013; more and more in favor of international, and that will be significantly accelerated when we see a generic entrant in the U.S., and that's quite obvious to everybody I think. So if we look at the numbers for Q2, the split is roughly 50/50, and again, as we said, the overall global growth of 23% is driven by international.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on dual eligibles, though, we expect if something were to happen, it would have a modest impact on us. But I think if you looked at The Wall Street Journal on Tuesday, I believe it was, there were a number of op-eds and editorials about the importance of &#x2013; the value of what Medicare Part D has done to senior citizens and to lowering costs of prescription drugs and the impact on the healthcare system, et cetera. So there's very strong support for the value of Part D. And we do not anticipate &#x2013; though deficit reduction is a very important issue, we do not think that part D will be part of that deficit reduction here in the near term. And we think the compelling value of Medicare Part D, it'll retain its position for a long time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next questioner in queue is Maged Shenouda with Stifel, Nicolaus. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Hi. Congratulations on the quarter's result. Can you just discuss your current thinking about smoldering myeloma development with REVLIMID? It was absent from your prepared comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good. I appreciate your raising that, Maged. Certainly it wasn't absent for any messaging point of view. We think that if you saw survival data from a high-risk smoldering population, it was very, very intriguing, very important for us because if you can really &#x2013; we're going to explore this aggressive in the clinical and regulatory arena, and that the ability to identify those patients that will clearly have a survival advantage in that population is an untapped market for us and to position REVLIMID very nicely in all segments of myeloma.</p>
          <p>So I would not read anything into our comments. It was just that there hasn't been any new data since the last time. We are working with clinical programs, and we're working, both in the U.S., where their studies are open, and Europe to expand our knowledge on this. And hopefully the data will continue to show what the very encouraging initial data has shown. So it is something of high priority to us, and please don't read anything into to the absence in this one quarter's comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next questioner in queue is Ian Somaiya with Piper Jaffray. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, just a follow-up on apremilast. Given the data we are expecting next year, I was just curious if one of those two scenarios plays out where apremilast is equivalent to the methotrexates of the world or the other scenario being it's equivalent to many of the biologics, what is the market opportunity under those scenarios, and if you can provide some comments related to it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think if you look at the control Phase II data, it's very encouraging what you saw, especially about when you go from 20 milligrams twice a day to 30 milligrams twice a day, the increase  in efficacy was very little change, and the very encouraging side effect profile. So that's obviously why we're doing these Phase III trials. And as a reminder, we're doing Phase III trials in psoriatic arthritis, in psoriasis. We're doing a very large Phase IIb in rheumatoid arthritis that is to completed accrual here in the very, very near term, and we see data on that as early as the first half of next year or middle of next year, to see what we can do in that indication.</p>
          <p>Plus I think we mentioned that we're expecting at ACR to have our first data from ankylosing spondylitis, and based on that data which we've already seen, we've had regulatory discussions around the world about the Phase III program for ankylosing spondylitis. So when that data comes out and we finish those discussions, I wouldn't be surprised for us to see us, again, moving to Phase III there.  So obviously the positioning of apremilast based on the data is going to be very important. But if the data comes out where we think it will come out based on the benefit, the activity versus the side effect profile, this has a high, high market opportunity to be used pre-biologics, a very safe oral therapy, likely to be less expense than biologics, to use it for a sustained period of time. So, again, we've got to have the Phase III data, but all of the indications we're pursuing are multi &#x2013; certainly more than $1 billion an opportunity for each of those indications.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next questioner in queue is Gene Mack with Mizuho Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My question was answered. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There is another questioner, Maged Shenouda with Stifel, Nicolaus. Your question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Follow up &#x2013; can you discuss your unit growth trends for ex-U.S. REVLIMID figures for second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I will, but let me just make some general comments. Now, we don't, I think, give you that specific breakdown, but you can think about what we have told you, particularly with respect to Europe and the price evolution environment there where every year for that basket of countries we get some form of price decline. You can also triangulate your thoughts back to our market share numbers that we give you on some of the slides, and make some inferences about unit growth, because we're growing very nicely despite price decreases that we see every year on that portfolio of countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Geoff Porges from Bernstein, your question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much for letting me jump in with another question. You're being very generous with your time. One thing we haven't discussed is duration. In the past, you've suggested that duration was increasing in the U.S. by about one month a year and that you're also seeing increases in Europe. You've given us some perspective on penetration and share, but could you talk a little bit about whether that duration trend is continuing or even accelerating with the maintenance data?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Geoff, I would say that the data that we have most recently looked at is a continuation of that trend that you outlined, and I think that is continuing in the markets generally. And I hate to be obtuse about it. It's just that it really is not in our interests from the kind of discussions we have with payers, et cetera &#x2013; and competitors in the field &#x2013; that it's not something we think is appropriate for us to share the specific data. But there isn't any change at all in the very positive momentum in trends we're seeing in duration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, everybody. I think that we don't have any more questions in the queue. We appreciate you spending the time with us on the call today, and we look forward to speaking with you soon. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude today's program. Thank you for your participation, and have a wonderful day. Attendees, you may disconnect at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>