<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1243966" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>648</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">David Gryska, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Sol J. Barer, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Robert J. Hugin, President and Chief Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jim Birchenough</participant>
      <participant id="5">Mark Schoenebaum</participant>
      <participant id="6">Ian Somaiya</participant>
      <participant id="7">Geoffrey Meacham</participant>
      <participant id="8">Yaron Werber</participant>
      <participant id="9">Eun Yang</participant>
      <participant id="10">Charles Duncan</participant>
      <participant id="11">Geoffrey Porges</participant>
      <participant id="12">Maged Shenouda</participant>
      <participant id="13">Sapna Srivastava</participant>
      <participant id="14">Aaron Reames</participant>
      <participant id="15">John Sonnier</participant>
      <participant id="16">Brian Abrahams</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Matt and I'll be your conference operator today. At this time, I would like to welcome everyone to the Celgene Second Quarter Conference Call. This call is being recorded. Celgene would like you to know there are slides that are accompanying this webcast. They are available at the Investor Relations section of the Celgene website, www.celgene.com.</p>
          <p>I'd like now to turn the call over to David Gryska, Chief Financial Officer. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. And thank you for joining us today. I am Dave Gryska, Celgene's Chief Financial Officer, and I would like to welcome you to Celgene's second quarter 2009 conference call. With me are Celgene's Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, Sol Barer and President and Chief Operating Officer, Bob Hugin.</p>
          <p>The press release reporting our second quarter financial operating results was issued earlier this morning, and is also available on our corporate website. In addition, today's conference call webcast will include a power point presentation, which you can access by going to the Investor Relations section of our website at celgene.com. Sol will begin our call today with a strategic perspective on 2009. I will then review our second quarter results and Bob will wrap up by discussing our operational and commercial results for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Before we start, we want to remind you that certain statements made during this conference call may be forward-looking statements within the meaning of Section 27A of the Securities Act of 1933 and within the meaning of Section 21E of the Securities Act of 1934.</p>
          <p>Certain forward-looking statements, which involve known and unknown risks, delays, uncertainties and other factors not under our control may cause our actual results, performance or achievements to be materially different from the results, performance or other expectations implied by these forward-looking statements. These factors include the results of current or pending clinical trials, research and development activities, our products failing to demonstrate efficacy or an acceptable safety profile, actions by the FDA, EMEA and/or other U.S., international regulatory bodies; the financial condition of suppliers, including their solvency and ability to supply product and other factors detailed in our filings with the Securities &amp; Exchange Commission, such as our Form 10-K, 10-Q and 8-K reports or referred to in the press release issued this morning.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll turn the call over to our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, Dr. Sol Barer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone and thank you for joining us today. We're quite pleased to announce that the second quarter was exceptional for Celgene. We advanced our global clinical regulatory research and commercial initiatives, which support continued robust growth and further position us to successfully achieve our short and long-term corporate and financial objectives. I'll briefly review our results then highlight some key recent items.</p>
          <p>For the quarter, we reported record non-GAAP total revenue of $626 million, and record non-GAAP net income of $216 million or $0.46 earnings per diluted share. This represents an increase of more than 24% year-over-year. This significant growth supports our focus to effectively and efficiently execute our long-term plan to drive global, clinical, regulatory and commercial momentum.</p>
          <p>I'm particularly pleased to see REVLIMID revenue grow this quarter to $397 million, a 10% quarter-over-quarter and 22% year-over-year increase. This growth is global in scope and reflects increasing patient demand driven by market share and duration increases. It also reflects the unique clinical characteristics of this drug, evidenced by the continued flow of important data in myeloma and other indications.</p>
          <p>I'll turn now to a very significant event that occurred this past Monday, the first interim analysis of our newly diagnosed myeloma trial MM-015. Personally speaking, I have to say I was quite surprised and quite impressed that at the first interim analysis after a relatively short follow-up period, the Independent Data Monitoring Committee notified Celgene that the pre-specified efficacy analysis comparing melphalan prednisone, REVLIMID followed by continuous REVLIMID to melphalan prednisone followed by placebo demonstrated a highly statistically significant improvement in the primary efficacy end point of progression-free survival. This difference crossed the O'Brien-Fleming boundary for superiority. In addition, there were no safety concerns reported by the Independent Data Monitoring Committee.</p>
          <p>This is clearly an exciting development. Yet it is still early with much to do as we gather and evaluate the data and speak to regulatory authorities around the world. We anticipate this data to be presented at the American Society of Hematology meeting and look forward to discussing the results further at that time.</p>
          <p>We also continue to expand our drugs globally, with REVLIMID approvals in Eastern Europe and Latin America, our NDA filing in Japan, and reimbursement approvals for VIDAZA and Thalidomide in Europe. We have become a truly international company, offering three major therapies to hematology patients that impact survival.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn to our pipeline, the future of our company. We are in the fortunate position of having a robust, deep and differentiable pipeline with tremendous global potential. We continue to invest in our future by advancing promising compounds in hematology, oncology and inflammation.</p>
          <p>As a result, over the next several quarters, we expect to report clinical trial data on more Celgene compounds than ever before, including our anti-inflammatory franchise which encompasses among other drug candidates Apremilast and our stem cells and our hematology, oncology franchise encompassing Pomalidomide, Amrubicin, the active inhibitor 8011 and others.</p>
          <p>The results of these trials are expected to lead to important pivotal studies such as Pomalidomide in critical blood cancers, our stem cells in Crohn's Disease and other severe conditions and Apremilast in debilitating inflammatory conditions. Focusing on Apremilast, during the quarter we announced initial data from a Phase II randomized controlled study of Apremilast in psoriatic arthritis showing promising activity with an encouraging safety and tolerability profile. These Phase II results reinforce the significant potential of this novel oral therapy in a range of inflammatory conditions, and, indeed, of our entire inflammatory franchise.</p>
          <p>Turning to our financial status, as is clear from our statements, we are one of the strongest companies in our industry. Cash flow is very positive, our COGS are among the lowest in the industry, and our tax rate is one of the lowest in our industry. We are quite leveragable globally, and all this continued to improve in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Finally I'd like to review our guidance, based on recent developments and current global trends. We are reaffirming our top and bottom line 2009 guidance and targeting REVLIMID revenue of approximately $1.65 billion, a growth of approximately 25% from the previous year, making REVLIMID one of the fastest growing oncology products to date.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, I can truly say I've never been more optimistic about our company and the role we play in delivering critical therapies to patients around the world. Our global opportunities, our opportunities with our unique commercial products in label expansions to new indications, our opportunities with our deep and promising pipeline in our two franchises, our financial strength and leveragability and our exciting earlier-stage research opportunities make us a uniquely strong and potentially preeminent biopharmaceutical company.</p>
          <p>Correspondingly, we expect the second half of the year to yield multiple commercial, clinical and regulatory catalysts to drive our performance and help us achieve our near and long-term goals.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to turn the call over to Dave Gryska who will provide more detail about our financial performance for the quarter and our outlook for the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Sol. Now I'll take you through the financial results. Non-GAAP total revenue for the second quarter 2009 was a record $626 million, a 10% increase versus the second quarter 2008. As you know, in March 2009, we concluded our agreement with GlaxoSmithKline related to sales of ALKERAN. If I exclude ALKERAN, non-GAAP total revenue increased 14% as compared to the second quarter last year.</p>
          <p>For the six months ended June 30, 2009, non-GAAP total revenue was a record 1.227 billion, a 19% increase versus the same period in 2009. Again, if I exclude ALKERAN, non-GAAP total revenue would have increased 21%.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP diluted earnings per share for the quarter was $0.46 as compared to $0.37 during the second quarter of 2008, an increase of 24%. Total non-GAAP net product sales increased 596 million for the second quarter, up 11% from $538 million in the year ago quarter. This is an increase of 4% over the first quarter of 2009. If I exclude ALKERAN non-GAAP net product sales would have increased 8%.</p>
          <p>REVLIMID net product sales were $397 million, an increase of 22% over the second quarter of 2008 and a 10% increase over the first quarter of 2009. Turning to VIDAZA, net product sales for the quarter were $92 million, an increase of 54% from the year-ago quarter, and a 22% increase over the first quarter of 2009. The launch of VIDAZA in Europe is progressing well. The drug was launched in Spain and several other countries during the second quarter, and we expect to complete the launch of VIDAZA in Italy and France by the end of 2009.</p>
          <p>THALOMID net sales were $105 million for the quarter, down 20% as compared to the year ago quarter and down 8% over the first quarter. The launch of THALOMID in Europe is on track, however, the price of THALOMID is much lower in Europe versus the U.S., therefore, the impact of increasing volumes in Europe will not offset the decreasing volumes in the U.S.</p>
          <p>For the second quarter of 2009, sales of REVLIMID in the U.S. were 244 million, and international sales were 153 million, representing an increase of 6% and 16% respectively on a sequential quarter basis. REVLIMID international sales represented 38% of total REVLIMID sales for the six months ended June 30th, 2009.</p>
          <p>Our non-GAAP product gross margin for the second quarter was 92% compared to 89% during the first quarter. We are forecasting a 92% gross margin for the full year. The gross margins have improved due to a higher percentage of REVLIMID and international VIDAZA sales, which have higher margins, and the discontinuation of lower margin ALKERAN. Our sales returns and allowances as a percent of total sales continue to decline as compared to last year.</p>
          <p>As of June 30, the total returns allowance balance was 9 million, compared to 13 million at the end of the first quarter because sales returns allowances are primarily related to U.S. THALOMID sales; we expect U.S. THALOMID's volumes to decrease, and accordingly, our sales returns and reserves are expected to further decline.</p>
          <p>Our inventory on the balance sheet decreased 20 million as compared to the prior quarter. The decline in inventory was primarily due to a decrease in ALKERAN inventory due to the conclusion of the ALKERAN agreement as well as a decrease in the FOCALIN inventory. Our inventory consists of approximately one-third of finished goods and the remainder work in process raw materials. We expect inventory to be in the 80 to $90 million range for the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>We ended the second quarter of 2009 with 354 million in accounts receivable, which represents a $14 million increase as compared to the prior quarter. The days sales outstanding or DSO increased from 50 to 51 days during the quarter due to increased sales in Europe. The collection process tends to take longer in Europe than in the U.S. As we continue to gain further penetration of our products throughout Europe, we expect our accounts receivable and DSO to increase.</p>
          <p>Turning to expenses for the second quarter, non-GAAP R&amp;D expense was 169 million as compared to 167 million for the first quarter of 2009. For the remainder of the year, we expect R&amp;D expenses will stay at this level as we continue to initiate and accrue multiple late-stage clinical trials in the areas such as NHL, CLL, inflammation and small cell lung cancer. Therefore, we expect R&amp;D expenses to be in the range of 680 to $690 million for the year.</p>
          <p>Our non-GAAP selling, general and administrative expenses were 157 million during the second quarter, as compared to 157 million during the first quarter of 2009. We expect 2009 SG&amp;A expense to be in the range of 615 to $620 million for the year.</p>
          <p>Turning to taxes, our year-to-date non-GAAP tax rate was 23.1%. We continue to anticipate improvement in the tax rate for the last six months of 2009, and are forecasting a tax rate of approximately 22% for the year.</p>
          <p>As you are aware, we hedge our balance sheet, foreign currency exposures, inter-company foreign currency transactions and exposure related to certain euro based revenue and expense. For the remainder of 2009, we are hedging approximately 80% of our euro net earnings exposure over a rolling 18-month period. The impact of foreign currency on top line revenue on a sequential quarter basis was immaterial. In addition, during the second quarter, we realized approximately 5 million in hedging and revaluation gains, which is included in other income. Our hedging activity is incorporated into our overall planning process for the year, and our goal is to neutralize the impact to earnings from FX volatility.</p>
          <p>And now a few words about our balance sheet. We ended the second quarter of 2009 with cash, cash equivalents and marketable securities of 2.5 billion. We continue to invest primarily in high grade U.S. government and government agency securities and money market funds. In addition, we repurchased approximately 2.2 million shares of common stock during the quarter and entered into a $40 million collaboration with GlobeImmune.</p>
          <p>In summary, the overall fundamentals of our business and financial position have never been stronger. We have some of the best operating leverage, gross margin, tax rate and cash flow in our industry. We continue to expect non-GAAP total revenue to be at the lower end of the range of 2.6 to 2.7 billion; additionally, non-GAAP diluted earnings per share is expected to be at the lower end of the range of $2.05 to $2.10. We are updating REVLIMID product sales guidance to approximately 1.650 billion.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn the call over to our President and Chief Operating Officer, Bob Hugin, who will expand on our global, commercial, clinical and regulatory plans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dave. Good morning. Across markets our team effectively executed our plan, producing strong results. Our products performed well, generating significant top and bottom line growth despite continuing challenging economic conditions. In addition to delivering on our financial targets, major progress was achieved in advancing key corporate initiatives that will drive sustained growth and build long-term value. Sol outlined some of these key developments, such as the myeloma filing in Japan, the MM-015 results, the encouraging Apremilast data and others. I'll provide more perspective on the strong commercial performance in the quarter, the progress made on important value drivers and key milestones for the remainder of 2009.</p>
          <p>Before I review the specifics of our quarterly performance, let me add my perspective on the very positive news introduced by Sol and announced in our press release this morning regarding our pivotal trial, MM-015 in newly diagnosed multiple myeloma. It is both exciting and impressive that the MPR followed by continuous REVLIMID arm demonstrated a highly statistically significant improvement in progression free survival versus the MP arm. This pre-specified primary efficacy comparison crossed the O'Brien-Fleming boundary for superiority at the first interim analysis. This result is all the more compelling in light of the relatively small trial size and the high bar for efficacy required in the trial, a pre-specified improvement in PFS of at least 50% for the completed trial with a significantly higher standard for interim analyses. These results further illustrate the potential for sustained disease control which can be achieved by continuous REVLIMID therapy in myeloma. We look forward to discussing the data with regulatory agencies around the world in the coming months and to the presentation of the data at ASH in December.</p>
          <p>Our businesses performed well across geographies, producing substantial product sales growth. The very positive REVLIMID and VIDAZA revenue growth outlined on the slide reflects strong performance in both the U.S. and European markets. As Dave noted, REVLIMID revenue in the United States increased by 6% quarter-over-quarter and by 16% internationally, with international REVLIMID revenue accounting for approximately 38% of total REVLIMID revenue, in line with our expectations of 35 to 40% for the year.</p>
          <p>Though global economic conditions did not materially improve in the second quarter, our results did benefit from operating lessons learned in the challenging first quarter. Second quarter results were also less impacted by the dislocations experienced by patients in January, with the start of new insurance plan years, especially high co-payment plans in Medicare Part D.</p>
          <p>Underlying fundamentals remain strong, with REVLIMID and VIDAZA patient demand growing in both the United States and Europe. U.S. REVLIMID myeloma prescriptions increased by approximately 9% over the prior quarter. Unit growth was very strong internationally, with prescriptions growing by more than 12% over the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Market share is an important measure of performance and future prospects. Meaningful share growth was achieved in all markets during the quarter. 12-month rolling data indicates substantial market share gains in multiple lines of therapy in the U.S., with total REVLIMID share now 31%, and REVLIMID front-line share growing to 30%. Rolling six month data reflects even stronger recent market penetration gains. In Europe, significant market share gains are also being achieved, with second-line growth of approximately 5 percentage points attained this quarter in developed markets.</p>
          <p>Duration remains a key driver of long term REVLIMID revenue growth. Duration in the United States increased to nearly 11 months during the quarter. Duration trends in Europe were also positive for the quarter, with duration estimated at slightly longer than 7 months in developed markets.</p>
          <p>Market share increases, longer duration, international market expansion and enhanced reimbursement and market access are all key revenue growth drivers. During the quarter significant progress was achieved in all of these important categories. We recently announced the REVLIMID filing as a treatment for multiple myeloma in Japan, bringing REVLIMID one step closer to serving the unmet medical needs of myeloma patients in the world's second largest oncology market. This major accomplishment was achieved by a Celgene team led by our clinical, regulatory and commercial group in Tokyo. We expect a regulatory review of approximately one year.</p>
          <p>Of all of the drivers of product sales growth, positive new clinical data has by far and away the greatest long-term impact on oncology products. During the past few months, over 150 abstracts featuring Celgene products have been presented at major medical meetings. With our commitment to fully exploring the potential of our products, we expect a continued flow of clinical data to be presented at upcoming medical meetings, including data from the CALGB and IFM maintenance studies and, of course, MM-015.</p>
          <p>The outlook for continued strong REVLIMID revenue growth remains promising, with multiple key growth drivers. Our discussion and the drivers outlined on the slide highlight several of the future growth opportunities. We're making steady progress in achieving reimbursement in key international markets where regulatory approvals have been granted. Despite government budgets pressured by the global recession, we do expect to begin meaningful reimbursed sales in countries such as the United Kingdom, Canada and Australia late this year.</p>
          <p>The global MDS markets are becoming an increasingly important component of our revenue growth as we seek to capitalize on the unprecedented VIDAZA survival data. VIDAZA global sales increased 54% year-over-year and 22% quarter-over-quarter. In the U.S. VIDAZA is the clear market leader in intermediate to high risk MDS; and in Europe, we made excellent progress executing our commercial plans with second quarter launches in Spain, Austria and Greece.</p>
          <p>Based on our increasing knowledge of VIDAZA's unique biological activity, we're identifying specific indications and drug combinations that merit additional studies. To date there are nearly 60 studies worldwide in various stages of planning and enrollment, evaluating VIDAZA in combination trials with REVLIMID and other new therapies in MDS, AML and other cancers.</p>
          <p>This slide illustrates that our European launch of VIDAZA is well underway. We expect positive reimbursement decisions in all major European markets by year end with the exception of the U.K., where the NICE process will likely extend into 2010. We must continue to successfully penetrate launch markets and increase the awareness of the benefits of active therapy in MDS. Multiple strategies are being employed to effectively communicate the extraordinary survival advantage of VIDAZA treatment. We are making significant progress.</p>
          <p>While REVLIMID and VIDAZA in myeloma and MDS are our principle near term growth drivers, this slide illustrates that these indications are only two components of our overall growth strategy in hematology and oncology. WE made excellent progress in the first half of the year advancing a number of these promising programs including accelerating the accruals of a number of key trials and initiating several regulatory track studies. The next few slides will illustrate the progress achieved in advancing these programs. We hope that you find it useful to review the status of our most important clinical trials, which comprise our major development programs.</p>
          <p>The exciting news regarding MM-015 highlights the continued upside potential of REVLIMID in multiple myeloma. We have a comprehensive program to fully explore REVLIMID's opportunity in the up-front myeloma setting. The trials on this slide are designed to enroll upwards of 4,000 newly diagnosed multiple myeloma patients. These trials are being conducted to clearly establish REVLIMID-based regimens as the standard of care for all patient segments of newly diagnosed myeloma.</p>
          <p>When the MM-015 data is presented, it will be the third REVLIMID Phase III study in newly diagnosed myeloma to demonstrate overwhelming superiority. The Phase III evidence supporting REVLIMID as the standard of care for all patient segments continues to grow.</p>
          <p>Several Phase III studies are also examining the benefits of extended continuous REVLIMID therapy, with new data beginning to be reported as early as this year's ASH meeting. During the quarter, the 514 patient CALGB maintenance study completed enrollment. We're also studying REVLIMID in smoldering myeloma to evaluate if the early onset of the disease can be delayed.</p>
          <p>Additional clinical research in myelodysplastic syndromes has the potential to broaden the usefulness of our products. We have important studies enrolling in a wide range of MDS patients from lower risk MDS to those patients with disease transforming to acute myeloid leukemia. We're exploring numerous combinations to produce the maximum patient benefit. We do expect that the initial analysis of the data from our Phase III MDS-004 study to be presented at ASH. We're exploring a number of additional important indications that offer exceptional growth potential for REVLIMID.</p>
          <p>Our chronic lymphocytic leukemia clinical development program has the objective of establishing REVLIMID as a standard of care for the treatment of multiple patient segments. During the second quarter, we initiated CLL-008, a global Phase III SPA approved study of REVLIMID versus chlorambucil in previously untreated elderly patients. This is the first registration quality trial examining the therapeutic benefit specifically for elderly CLL patients. Additional new data from our extensive clinical program may begin to emerge as early as this year's December ASH meeting.</p>
          <p>As with our CLL development strategy, our lymphoma development plan is exploring REVLIMID's potential in a range of patient subtypes within lymphoma. Our program is targeted to establish REVLIMID as a standard of care for the treatment of relapsed/refractory aggressive lymphomas and to establish REVLIMID as a standard of care for patients with diffuse large B-cell lymphoma who respond to first line R-CHOP treatment.</p>
          <p>The Phase III GELA Trial in diffuse large B-cell lymphoma initiated enrollment this past quarter. Our special protocol assessment Phase III trial comparing our third-generation anthracycline, Amrubicin versus topotecan in second line small cell lung cancer is accruing rapidly with enrollment of 620 patients expected to be completed either late this year or early next year.</p>
          <p>We expect Amrubicin's final data from Phase II studies in relapsed/refractory small cell lung cancer to be reported in oral sessions at the International Association for the Study of Lung Cancer conference in San Francisco next week.</p>
          <p>Our next IMiD, Pomalidomide, is enrolling 212 relapsed/refractory myeloma patients in a multicenter controlled Phase II trial. Additional data on Pomalidomide is expected at this year's ASH meeting also.</p>
          <p>ACE-011, our Activin inhibitor being developed in collaboration with our partner Acceleron, is completing a Phase II trial in myeloma patients with bone lesions. Also the FDA recently accepted the IND filing for a Phase II study in chemotherapy induced anemia breast cancer patients. This trial is expected to commence in the next month or two.</p>
          <p>We're also very pleased to report the dosing of our first cohort of Crohn's Disease patients with PDA-001, our proprietary placental stem cell product, has been completed. The trial is expected to finish before year end; and assuming appropriate safety profile we will commence a broad clinical development program based on encouraging preclinical evidence in a number of additional indications.</p>
          <p>Our inflammation clinical program has gained significant traction during the past several quarters. On June 15, we announced the positive top line data from a randomized controlled Phase II study of Apremilast in psoriatic arthritis. This encouraging data is expected to be presented at the American College of Rheumatology Conference in October.</p>
          <p>Having now demonstrated meaningful clinical activity in two Phase II placebo-controlled trials, one in psoriatic arthritis and one in moderate to severe psoriasis, we're accelerating the development of potential Phase III programs designed to begin in 2010. Additional data is also expected from Apremilast trials in recalcitrant psoriasis and moderate to severe psoriasis over the next few quarters. We're expanding our knowledge of the drug's full potential in dermatological, rheumatological and inflammatory conditions through a wide range of Phase II studies.</p>
          <p>Hopefully, our presentations this morning have provided you with better insight into the results of the first half of the year and the key objectives and programs that are essential to our continued rapid growth. Many of the remaining 2009 key deliverables are listed on this slide. We have exceptional people worldwide, focused on accomplishing these goals and maximizing our 2009 clinical, regulatory and commercial opportunities.</p>
          <p>I hope that you can sense the enthusiasm that we have for our prospects, and the significant momentum of our programs. The excellent operating and financial results achieved during the second quarter accurately reflect our focus on maximizing our near-term potential, while at the same time investing in our future to ensure that we sustain high growth for the long term. We continue to believe that we are &#x2013; we continue to believe that we are strategically positioned to capitalize on our vision of building a preeminent market leading global biopharmaceutical company focused in hematology, oncology and inflammation. We thank you for your interest.</p>
          <p>Operator, we can now open the call for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We will take our first question from Jim Birchenough, Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Congratulations on the strong quarter and the 015 results. Just on the 015, I just want to confirm that the pre-specified interim analysis was focused on the MPR plus maintenance versus MP and not MPR induction alone versus MP, and just wondering, on that second comparison, if you've got interim data on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Sol Barer. Yes, you are correct. It was the melphalan prednisone REVLIMID followed by continuous REVLIMID versus the placebo arm. And the data we have is essentially the data that we talked about, and we're going to be getting a lot more data on this arm and other arms as time goes on, Jim, so. But you are right, that is the regulatory end point with an increase in progression free survival, with obviously a higher hazard ratio for those two arms.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We go next to Mark Schoenebaum, Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, hey, thanks a lot for taking my question. I was wondering, Sol, if you could just comment on, in thinking big picture about the MM-015 results, it sounds like you got a hit on the maintenance arm. And given a profound PFS benefit for a maintenance regimen for REVLIMID in the first line setting, how do you think this trial is actually going to change physician practice, and do you think the trial has got a shot at showing an overall survival benefit, and does it matter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. A great question. First of all, I have to say that this is really great news for patients. The objective of all companies who are doing work in myeloma is to take this almost inevitably fatal disease and turn it into a chronic treated disease. And I think that this trial in REVLIMID has a role in that and that we've taken a step forward with that. I think that an important advantage of this trial will be certainly internationally, especially in Europe, where melphalan and prednisone are more usually used. In the United States, we have very good first line use, based on physicians prescribing from data. That's less the case in Europe. So I would, if the question is where do we see the primary commercial impact, while, of course, it will be helpful to have first line in the United States and so on, I think the primary commercial impact will be overseas, and especially in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We go next to Ian Somaiya, Thomas Weisel Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Congratulations. This is obviously stellar data and gives us a reason to all go to the ASH this year. Just on the 015 data, can you just talk about the stopping criteria? I know Bob, you mentioned that a 50% improvement was required at the end of the trial. What was the requirement at the first interim analysis? And then I just had one follow-up question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Ian, obviously the hazard ratio for the completed trial, as I said, was a 50% improvement; but clearly the interim analysis has a significantly higher bar, and the p-value would need to be 0.0015 and a hazard ratio of 1.825 to produce, to cross the O'Brien-Fleming boundary, so it had to be better than those two parameters to have the Independent Data Monitoring Committee report these results to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just a follow-up, do you know at this point what the average duration was in this trial, or maybe if you can point us to the Phase I and II data, what the average duration was on that trial?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What, as we said, Ian, is we just found out about this clearly, literally a couple of days ago, and there's a limited amount of information that we have, and that we're going to spend the next few months obviously harvesting, analyzing the data, and with that data, speaking to regulatory authorities. So there's really not much more additional information that we can provide, other than the very exciting news with respect to the fact that we crossed the O'Brien-Fleming boundary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We go next to Geoff Meacham, JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys, I also wanted to say congrats on the quarter and the MM-015 data. A couple of questions here, first, are you crossing patients over in the study in MM-015? And the second question is, why do you think from a commercial perspective there's a delta between the U.S. and international duration of therapy for REVLIMID? And would you expect this to reach parity in the near term? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think, two questions. The first one, I think the, any kind of crossover is really not relevant in this study in the sense that the control arm of melphalan and prednisone has reached the nine cycles before this event. So the course of the trial will just continue on with the normal progression of it following it. So there isn't any need for any type of activity in that regard.</p>
          <p>And on the second question, would you repeat that, Geoff?</p>
          <p>Sorry, the duration question. Obviously, we launched earlier in the U.S., so we have the opportunity to penetrate the market more significantly. And we continue to see very positive duration trends in the U.S. And in Europe, I think it's earlier in the development and the commercialization of the drug, but also I think the reason the MM-015 data has impact in Europe is we've got to continue to convince people of the value of treating to and through progression. And that's probably one of the most important significances of 015 is to really demonstrate the value and the importance of REVLIMID to really have sustained disease control through continuous treatment. And I think, in Europe, there's more of a pressure to try and treat towards best response, and I think this data will help move us to identifying that many cancers can become chronic therapies if they're continuously treated with the right regimen.</p>
          <p>So this is the first step and you saw in the slides the commitment we have to really producing data to demonstrate the value of sustained disease control through continuous treatment with REVLIMID.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I just had a follow-up on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. So you have in the slide 11 months duration of therapy for the U.S. and that's mostly relapsed/refractory and that's what the data support in relapsed/refractory. Where would you see duration in first line going if you were to speculate just on MM-015? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I am not &#x2013; I wouldn't &#x2013; I don't think it's appropriate for us to speculate. We'll see &#x2013; the trends look good. I do think that, if you notice the markets here that we talk about, we are getting an increasing percentage and the trends in the front-line setting for myeloma with REVLIMID are very encouraging.</p>
          <p>So I do think we're going to over time see that as an increasing component of the revenue model in the U.S. And I think the key strategy for us is to really convince everyone that treatment with REVLIMID as early as possible, for as long as possible is in the patient's best interest, and that ultimately then duration will be a beneficiary of that, if that kind of treatment regimens continue to advance, but I think that it would be speculation and we just don't speculate on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We go next to Yaron Werber, Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How are you doing? Congrats. I have two questions, and just a quick clarification. When &#x2013; just to &#x2013; give us a sense as to how long would it take you to actually crunch this data and be able to talk to the Europeans and then submit it both in the U.S. and in Europe? And then the second question is, just help us understand, you've already filed ECOG and SWOG with FDA, and now you have a hugely positive study. Just help us understand how this would impact the current filing for ECOG and SWOG, which presumably was based on safety. And then just a clarification for Bob. Did you say the p-value was 0.0015 or 0.00015? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So let me start that, and just a clarification. The 0.0015 was the pre-specified statistical boundary that we had to cross in order to have this &#x2013; in order to have the situation we have now. Okay. So that was the O'Brien-Fleming boundary. All right, so that's number one. That's not what we had but that is what we had to cross, and obviously we had significantly better than that.</p>
          <p>In terms of where we're going now is we have not really had a look at the data. We want to get the best, most mature data that we can get, Yaron, and we're going to be doing that over the next several months. We are going to &#x2013; and during that period of time, obviously, and as appropriate, we'll be talking to regulatory agencies around the world so that we'll be better able to give you specific timing at the upcoming ASH meeting in terms of filings. And you are correct. The ECOG/SWOG data set is there. I think that part of what will happen will be that &#x2013; one potential outcome -- and again, there's a bit of speculation here on my part, because we have not talked to the agency regarding the fact that we have essentially three trials here, is to combine those trials in a subsequent filing for first line and continuous use. But that's going to have to really wait until we have those specific conversations with regulatory agencies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We go next to Eun Yang, Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. On the Pomalidomide side, you have a Phase II in myelofibrosis and recently inside had a JAK2 inhibitor and had an SPA for Phase III for that indication. So could you actually comment on what your development strategy for this product in myelofibrosis going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. Was the question, the strategy going forward for this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, with Pomalidomide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay. So Pomalidomide is a very different agent than the JAK2s for example inside for myelofibrosis patients. Obviously, the mechanism is different. The clinical effects are very different. The clinical effects with Pomalidomide are largely from a hematological perspective. JAK2s certainly have some hematological, but do affect spleen size and other organs. So in many ways, they are complementary to each other as opposed to competitive, and I think that's an ideal situation for patients, is you want different mechanisms operating. So what we are doing is we are designing pivotal trials, pivotal trial or trials for Pomalidomide in myelofibrosis. We think that it will offer patients a great potential therapy for a disease which really has a high unmet medical need, and hopefully it will be complementary and patients can benefit from more than one mechanism.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We go next to Charles Duncan, JMP Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. I wanted to, first of all, comment: great execution on the quarter, and congratulations on the data. I had a question for Bob perhaps. As you look out to 2010 and '11, you did a great job laying out the growth strategy for near term. But if you look out over the course of the next couple of years, what can we point to as the top, call it two, three elements of that growth strategy to support the growth expectations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the growth strategy fortunately for us has multiple factors to it. Clearly continued geographic expansion is one of the important ones, as we move into Japan with the announcement of the filing there. That's about a one year review. And then you do expect a period of time in negotiations for price and reimbursement. So whether it be late 2010 or early 2011, we'd begin to see revenues from the second largest oncology market there.</p>
          <p>We've got just recent positive news in some Eastern European countries, including Russia, where we're hopeful in early 2011 we'd get added to the formulary there, where that is an attractive market for indications like myeloma. So we've got upside in some of those geographies. Getting reimbursement in, late this year in Australia, getting Canada on and the U.K. benefiting hopefully late this year from the positive NICE announcement. So clearly one is the general continued international expansion that will roll out 2010 and '11.</p>
          <p>And then we obviously, in all of the markets, we don't think we're anywhere near the market shares that the drug can achieve. In the U.S., we're more advanced. We talk about a 30 plus percent overall market share, and we've talked about long-term before we launched REVLIMID, we thought a 40% overall market share was the right target, and we continue to have that here. That's going to always be more challenging as you get closer and closer to your targeted market share. But we've still got upside in the data that we've talked about today, helps us in that regard in terms of market share, the benefit of REVLIMID.</p>
          <p>And in Europe, clearly it's much earlier, when we talk about where we are with market share, and especially in the front-line setting. Getting the front-line approval in Europe helps to have a much larger patient population and significantly supports the duration argument, as obviously the earlier patients you treat you would expect to have longer duration there.</p>
          <p>So I think the growth drivers for the next couple of years are REVLIMID in myeloma, are both international expansion and improved reimbursement in certain markets where we have approvals, we don't. We have the market share gains, the duration gains and the investment that we have made in clinical trials over the last few years and continue to make, whether it's in -- we went through a number of the trials on the slides today, to really continue a steady flow of new clinical data, which we think will support continued growth; and in the outer years, we expect to have more indications for REVLIMID outside of myeloma and MDS.</p>
          <p>So I think there is a combination of many factors that will be staggered over the course of years. We've got execution we have got to do to maximize the potential and we've got some regulatory and clinical risks that we've got to manage to make sure we can fully maximize to get the peak sales 10 years from now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We go next to Geoffrey Porges, Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much for the question, and also congrats on 015 coming sooner than we thought. Quick items, Bob, you talked about Europe, just wondering if you could tell us what the comparable to the 30% you have in the U.S. is for REV in the major markets in Europe? Secondly, you didn't mention anything about prostate cancer, there was some positive data at ASCO, are you going ahead with that? And then lastly, could you just talk about co-pay reimbursement? There's been a lot of scrutiny about that. And if you had to go to 50% of all Part D co-pays, would that be an incremental cost or a saving for you? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hopefully, I have written down most of those questions, but we may need to reiterate one or two of them. On the market share issue, the U.S. we talked about an overall market share of in the 30 plus% range, and we also talked about market share significant in the upfront setting. And that's a big difference between the U.S. and Europe, where the market shares are in the lower single digits in an up-front setting because of the different market conventions in the U.S. and Europe, where the second-line setting in the developed markets we're getting into the mid-20s and upper-20s market share. So we would expect a higher market share in second line in Europe than we would in the U.S. because of the higher front-line market share that we would expect, and our targets, our internal targets I think are appropriate and I think recognize the convention and the reimbursement and the regulatory issues in the different markets. So I think we've got ambitious targets within the U.S. and around the world, but they do recognize the convention in the markets. And that's why I think Sol said the significance of MM-015 is more valuable to us internationally, because of the way reimbursement and the regulatory approvals impact the product there. So that's one.</p>
          <p>On the co-payment issue, that if we were to have health care reform that would either &#x2013; I don't think it would specifically mandate but would be in our economic interest to provide a 50% reduction for patients that are in the 7.5 times the poverty level and below, when they're in the doughnut hole would be &#x2013; and we don't have to &#x2013; we don't quantify the exact number, because we don't know exactly who is in that economic category, but it is fair to say that today, we support independent third party co-payment foundations that support patients in the doughnut hole and co-payments for up to seven times the poverty level. So the type of resources we're allocating to these third-party co-payments are already significant in regards to that relationship to the potential healthcare reform of the 50%. Clearly we'd lose some revenue, but we'd have an offset on the bottom line.</p>
          <p>And I have to tell you frankly, I wouldn't quantify it, but if we can put some of the pressures on senior citizens and the focus away from co-payments, because they can focus on the clinical benefits, the benefit is clearly to ensure that clinicians and patients get the right therapy for them, not focused on what the deductibles are and the copay. So we do think that kind of reform, that having a 50% reduction in the copay is a cost saving to the healthcare system, because it will come out of our pockets in some ways. But it's important for patients, and it is a long-term benefit for the whole system.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on prostate cancer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Just on that note, thank you for bringing that up, Geoff. This is clearly castrate-resistant prostate cancer, AIPC, the old terminology. We have a trial we'll be starting later this year. It is approximately a thousand patient trial and there are two arms, there's docetaxel prednisone plus REV and then docetaxel prednisone without REV plus a placebo with a primary endpoint of overall survival.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We go next to Maged Shenouda at UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, hi. Also congratulations on the MM-15 (sic) [MM-015] data. My question has to do with health-care reform in the U.S. I know you've been following this closely. Just wondering what your views are of the current developments in Washington, and how you think things will play out this year and what that means for Celgene?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that it's certainly one that gets tremendous coverage, and I think it's people following this closely, as we are. I do think that we hope and our view is we do hope that there is healthcare reform. We do think there is lots of changes that could be made to the system that benefit all parties to the system. And we've got to make sure we've got a sustainable system, so that we can maintain the focus on innovation. And we think our products and products from our industry can be a big part of reducing long-term costs through innovation by dealing with some of the chronic therapies that add so much to healthcare costs in our country. And whether that be, you know, diabetes and all of the, and cancers that can be diagnosed and treated earlier and can have a significant impact on patients.</p>
          <p>I think it's very uncertain. I mean, clearly there's a big concern of tackling the problem right now in such a comprehensive way &#x2013; it is a complex problem. We do think that our industry, the pharmaceutical industry has really been proactive and engaged to be a positive force for change here. It was a little discouraging to hear, I guess, the president felt that the amount that the pharmaceutical industry has offered was a starting point, when in fact, the starting point was much lower and it was very difficult I think for the whole industry to even get close to the kind of numbers that are 80 billion in potential savings to the healthcare system. So I think there is a lot of risk here that people are going to need to come together in the next month or two. Otherwise it could fall apart. And we're hopeful that it won't, but we'll just have to see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to be clear, as we step back, let's always remember what the objectives are. And the objectives truly are to provide the best medical care for citizens of this country as broadly as we can, hopefully everyone, while encouraging innovation. Because it is through innovative therapies and innovative medical approaches that we truly will affect the economics and the quality of healthcare in the country. So this is clearly a very complicated situation, and it is a turbulent situation in the sense that things change very quickly. But we're very confident regarding the fact that, as a company, we focus on patients with serious debilitating diseases, and our primary focus is to develop breakthrough new innovative therapies to help those patients.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We go next to Sapna Srivastava, Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Congratulations. Most of my questions have been answered. And this is probably a little trivial, but just in terms of you lowering REVLIMID guidance, last quarter when everyone expected you to do so, you did not. And I know it's modest, but looking at the macroeconomic factors which are going positively for you now and also the price increase and clearly this data, why do you choose this time point to lower it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that, long-term, we really focus on annual guidance. So we don't like the idea of giving specific product guidance and trying to do it on a quarterly or semi-annual basis. But I think you look at the results, and we are trying to give a sense of where the outcomes are likely to be for the year. I think the minor changes that we might have seen this quarter versus what we could have expected at the end of the first quarter is we've had some minor delays in certain European markets for reimbursement that we were counting on for the third and fourth quarter that are clearly now going to have a potential, bigger impact in the fourth quarter. I don't think there's anything fundamental about whether they will get reimbursement or not in Australia. But clearly Australia is a country that requires cabinet approval for expenditures of $10 million or more, and we're not going to see the approval for reimbursement in the next month or two. It's going to take a little bit longer.</p>
          <p>And I think with the budget pressures in a number of countries, a couple of months' delay is not unexpected as they look to reallocate revenues to support the new products in the different budgets. So I think that we're trying to give just an estimate of where we think the likely outcomes are, and we prefer to keep it an annual focus, but we try to reflect the realities in the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We go next to Aaron Reames, Wells Fargo Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question, and again congratulations on the quarter and the early stop in the 015. I had just a couple minor questions about trial design. In some of the earlier studies with REVLIMID in combination with melphalan and prednisone there is a slightly higher rate of myelosuppression that was seen. I know, in this particular trial, there were some changes and modifications to the protocol to address that earlier on, kind of as a pseudo-prophylaxis. So, I was wondering if you could remind us of the ANC criteria in the protocol around when you would see G-CSF implemented and how that would affect myelosuppression. And also I was wondering if you could just touch upon the differences in the way that the CR will be measured in this particular study versus the way it was measured in the VISTA study?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, I think it's important to recognize that this is a very different study in design than VISTA, both in terms of the number of patients, which I think the VISTA study had almost 700, and this study has 500. This is a more rigorous design in some ways, because it's a randomized, double-blinded study. And the fact that the end point is the progression free survival end point as opposed to the time to progression.</p>
          <p>So there are differences in terms of the studies; and in terms of -- just let me say, broadly in terms of safety, without getting too granular regarding it, because we just don't have the data. But we do know, and it was very explicit from the Independent Data Monitoring Committee, whose primary goal usually is safety, that there were no -- there was explicitly said, there were no safety concerns expressed. So, I think, in terms of getting in more detail and what was the rate of this and that and all these criteria, I think, it would probably be best to wait until we have a full presentation and a data set at ASH so we can answer all of the questions appropriately rather than just react after the last couple of days.</p>
          <p>Okay. So if we could have the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to John Sonnier with William Blair.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the question and congrats on the terrific progress. A couple of questions for Bob. I just want to ask the duration question a bit more broadly, because I still think duration is probably the most underappreciated variable in the REVLIMID calculus. I guess independent of the front line trial and data, you have clinical strategies in maintenance myeloma and lymphoma that are being tested which could have a profound impact on duration. So can you talk a little bit about what the experience has been of patients who have been on REVLIMID way beyond the average? And where do we see duration going realistically over the next couple of years? And separately, we've seen some seasonality, and given that Europe now is kind of a disproportionate amount of your growth, how do we think about Q3?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Just, we'll start with the second part, the seasonality. I do think that there are historical analyses that point out that clearly we see a slowdown in August, especially in Europe. And you have to be very careful as to what conclusions you draw, because July tends to be stronger, and is it underlying fundamental patient demand, or is it a buying-in so people can manage August without having to have issues of supply and less people on staff, on vacations to manage all of the process.</p>
          <p>So I think we would expect to see seasonality consistent with what we have in the prior years, but 2009 is a different year than we've seen. We clearly saw, in January, more significant concerns about new plan years and co-payments so that I think that our signals indicate we shouldn't see anything more significant than we've seen in prior years. But we're carefully watching it every day, and so far, in July, the trends look favorable and in line with what we should expect in the third quarter. But again, it's a good message for people should be aware of that it is not uncommon to see that oncology products especially in Europe in August have seasonality.</p>
          <p>On the duration question, I really think it is, you raise it as an important growth driver for REVLIMID and we certainly agree that. But it is a complicated metric and dynamic, and it is very different in every marketplace and segment of disease. And there are complicated strategies regarding to reimbursement, pricing, all the issues that go into that. And it's, it is very, very important. It's not a simple analysis and it's one that we take very seriously, set the right goals and have a strategy market by market. But I, we do in the big picture agree, it's a critical growth driver for us, it's one we're very focused on, but it is a complex one nevertheless.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to add on top of that, and it's a great question, and part of REVLIMID's uniqueness is from a mechanistic perspective, which translates clinically, is that it does not appear to have dose limiting toxicities from a cumulative perspective. So we really don't know how long patients can continue to be on the drug, and there have been, as you indicated patients on this drug from the early days of treatment of myeloma. So we really don't know the limits of how long patients can be on REVLIMID. We do hope that we can extend patients' lives for a long, long period of time and, indeed, turn this into a chronic disease. And as we learn more about the drug, I think we are going to, as this trial indicates, we will hopefully be able to do that. I think we have time for one more question now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our final question from Brian Abrahams with Oppenheimer &amp; Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. My congrats as well and thanks for taking my question. To what extent do you expect you'll be able to get reimbursement for front line REVLIMID use in Europe from label expansion on the 015 data prior to the 020 study read-out? And can you help us understand how the MPR plus placebo arm of 015 fits into your filing strategy, if at all? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, clearly our discussions are going to be had with the regulatory agencies in Europe, other places around the world, and the U.S. over the next couple of months. But it is our view that, and it's our intention to make sure that everybody understands the value of MM-015 as the significant part of the filing package and would not require additional data from MM-020 to support it. So those are the discussions we're going to have.</p>
          <p>On the other part of the question, which was the pre-specified efficacy analysis in the trial was MPR plus continuous REVLIMID versus MP and so that is going to be the focus of the -- that was the focus of discussion with the regulators in advance of the trial in Europe, and that's the discussions we'll be having over the next couple of months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>And what I'd like to do is, with that, thank everyone for joining us on this call. Obviously this is an important conference call from us from a commercial perspective, as well as from the MM-015 news, it's clearly very positive for this company, but I think even more importantly, it is positive for patients. It is another step towards our making myeloma a chronic disease and hopefully many other diseases.</p>
          <p>So we look forward to seeing many of you at ASH and certainly on the next conference call. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And that does conclude today's Celgene second quarter conference call. Thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>