<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1283980" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-01-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>648</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">David Gryska, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Sol J. Barer, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Robert J. Hugin, President and Chief Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Brian Abrahams</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Geoffrey Meacham</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Steve Harr</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Yaron Werber</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Geoffrey Porges</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Chris Raymond</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Rachel McMinn</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Mark Schoenebaum</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">May-Kin Ho</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Eric Schmidt</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Jim Birchenough</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Celgene Fourth Quarter Earnings Call. I'd like to turn the call over to the CFO of Celgene, Dave Gryska.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Thank you for joining us today. I am Dave Gryska, Celgene's Chief Financial Officer and I'd like to welcome you to Celgene's year-end conference call for 2009.</p>
          <p>With me are Celgene's Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, Sol Barer, and President and Chief Operating Officer, Bob Hugin. The press release reporting our fourth quarter and full year financial operating results was issued earlier this morning and is also available on our corporate website. In addition today's conference call webcast will include a presentation, which you can access by going to Investor Relations section of our website at Celgene.com. Dr. Barer will start the call with an overview of accomplishments and strategic outlook for 2010 and beyond. I'll take you through our financial results for 2009 and our financial outlook for 2010. Then Bob will review our operational and commercial results for 2009 and share with you his perspective on our operational and commercial prospects moving forward.</p>
          <p>Before we start, we want to remind you that our discussions during this conference call will include forward-looking statements. Our actual results, performance or accomplishments could be materially different from those projected by these forward-looking statements. The factors that could cause actual results, performance or achievements to differ from the forward-looking statements are discussed in our filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission, such as our form 10-K, 10Q, and 8-K reports. Given these risks and uncertainties you are cautioned not to place undue reliance on our forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Also our discussions during this call will include certain non-GAAP financial measures. Non-GAAP financial measures provide investors and management with supplemental measures of operating performance and trends that fluctuate comparisons between periods before and after certain items that would not otherwise be apparent on a GAAP basis. Reconciliations of these non-GAAP financial measures to the most comparable GAAP measures are available as part of our earnings release at Celgene's website at Celgene.com in the Investor Relations section. Now I'll turn the call over to our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, Dr. Sol Barer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dave, and good morning, everyone. In many ways 2009 was a transformational year for Celgene. We took major steps towards building a preeminent global biopharmaceutical company and we're pleased to report those accomplishments are not only reflected in the advancement of our therapies for cancer and immunoinflammatory diseases, they are also reflected in our commercial, operational and financial results. We made extraordinary progress across all facets of our business, including continuing to grow as a global company with our therapies available in nearly 70 countries.</p>
          <p>Our products are the global market leaders in their indications. REVLIMID is the global leader in the treatment of multiple myeloma and its share in the marketplace continues to grow. Over the past six months a continuous flow of positive clinical data has been released, demonstrating the breadth of REVLIMID's activity. These studies have shown there is potential for the development of REVLIMID to become the foundation of myeloma therapy from smoldering to salvage as well as in new indications, creating the opportunity for changing treatment paradigms.</p>
          <p>We are also expanding VIDAZA, the global market leader in MDS through market share gains and geographic expansion in Europe and the rest of the world. Importantly, we're making substantial progress in the development of our deep and diversified pipeline by advancing more than 30 clinical programs to address high unmet medical needs in more than 25 serious and debilitating diseases. Some recent highlights include the reporting of positive clinical data in myelofibrosis and myeloma at major medical meetings and in peer review journals for our new hematologic agent, pomalidomide. We plan to enter pivotal clinical trials with pomalidomide this year for both multiple myeloma and myelofibrosis.</p>
          <p>As we expand our Hematology/Oncology franchise we recently added a new and strategic product ISTODAX through the acquisition of Gloucester Pharmaceuticals. Last quarter ISTODAX received FDA approval for the second line treatment of cutaneous T-cell lymphoma and will be our first entry into the important lymphoma market. We look to expand ISTODAX in peripheral T-cell lymphoma and potentially in a number of other diseases while leveraging our current infrastructure.</p>
          <p>Our lead product candidate in our Immune/Inflammatory franchise, apremilast, has made significant clinical progress. Apremilast reached a primary endpoint in two Phase II trials, one in psoriasis and one in psoriatic arthritis. We look forward to starting Phase III registration trials in these indications this year. This is an exciting new area of multi-billion dollar potential for Celgene and we are proud to have developed apremilast in our own laboratories.</p>
          <p>This quarter we plan to announce results from a trial of PDA-001, our cellular therapy in patients with Crohn's Disease and potentially extend this new therapy to other serious diseases with unmet medical need. This will mark the first time this new therapy has been studied in humans. This new area of medicine places Celgene at the forefront of drug development in this area for many years to come.</p>
          <p>So why am I excited about Celgene's future? We have consistently performed in all aspects of our business ranging from science to clinical to manufacturing to commercial to financial, demonstrating we have the entrepreneurial culture and capabilities to continue to grow and sustain a leadership position in our industry. We have made and will continue to make significant investments in our pipeline. We're exploring next generation programs that include small molecules, biologics, cellular therapies and vaccines. We have 20 Phase III and pivotal clinical trials underway fueled by our prolific research and translational efforts towards the objective of ensuring the virtuous cycle of innovation continues to provide results for patients and Celgene stakeholders around the world.</p>
          <p>Our robust pipeline strategically positions us to consistently produce unique therapies to seriously ill patients. We will continue to grow our leading Hematology franchise, which has one of the broadest portfolios of disease-altering therapies for blood cancers, both internally, where we have an excellent track record, and via business development where we continue to demonstrate strategic partnerships and acquisitions. We will continue to expand in ways that will transform treatment paradigms, such as with our IMiD compounds, epigenetic therapeutics, HDAC inhibitors, cytokine inhibitors, kinase inhibitors, activin inhibitor, cellular therapies and more. We are opening the door to a new franchise, our inflammatory business where our current product candidates have the potential to treat millions of people, in addition to our Hematology franchise where we can impact the lives of over 2 million patients worldwide.</p>
          <p>We have the financial resources, the operational excellence, the scientific and clinical capabilities, the geographic breadth and most importantly the excellent people with commitment to make a positive impact on the industry and lead to changing treatment paradigms. We will continue to grow our current products while we acquire and develop new ones.</p>
          <p>We have delivered leading financial results year after year and 2009 was no different. Our innovative and entrepreneurial culture is helping us grow into one of the premiere global biopharmaceutical companies in the world. We are energized by this momentum and look forward to 2010 and beyond. Here to tell you more about our record financial results from 2009 and give you guidance on our 2010 outlook is our Chief Financial Officer, Dave Gryska.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Sol. 2009 was an exceptional year in which Celgene again delivered record operating performance. Despite challenges from the global economic environment, total non-GAAP revenue increased approximately 20% year-over-year to a record 2.7 billion. This increase was driven primarily by exceptional growth from our REVLIMID franchise, the continued growth of VIDAZA in the U.S. and a strong launch of VIDAZA in Europe.</p>
          <p>During the fourth quarter of 2009 total non-GAAP revenue increased approximately 22% year-over-year to $758 million. Non-GAAP net income for the fourth quarter 290 million and non-GAAP diluted earnings per share was $0.62. Non-GAAP net income for 2009 was a record $971 million and non-GAAP diluted earnings per share increased to $2.08. Total non-GAAP net product sales increased to $722 million for the fourth quarter, up 22% from $591 million in the year-ago quarter.</p>
          <p>This is an increase of 9% over the third quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter REVLIMID net product sales were $497 million, an increase of 35% over the fourth quarter of 2008 and an 11% increase over the third quarter of 2009. Full year 2009 REVLIMID net product sales were $1.7 billion, an increase of 29% from 2008 sales of $1.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Turning to VIDAZA, net product sales for the quarter were $117 million, an increase of 68% from the year-ago quarter and a 13% increase over the third quarter of 2009. THALOMID net sales were $108 million for the quarter, down 15% as compared to the year-ago quarter and down 2% over the third quarter.</p>
          <p>For the fourth quarter of 2009 sales of REVLIMID in the U.S. were 291 million and international sales were 206 million, representing an increase of 7% and 17% respectively on a sequential quarterly basis. For the full year 2009 REVLIMID international sales represented 39% of total REVLIMID sales. We expect international sales of REVLIMID to be approximately 45% of total REVLIMID sales for 2010.</p>
          <p>Our non-GAAP gross profit margin for 2009 was approximately 92%. For 2010 we expect an improvement in gross margin of approximately 100 basis points. Now turning to expenses, non-GAAP R&amp;D expense during the fourth quarter was 182 million, slightly higher than R&amp;D expense of 178 million during the third quarter of 2009. Non-GAAP R&amp;D expense was $696 million for 2009. We will continue to strategically invest in our R&amp;D in 2010 as we seek to advance our very deep and promising product pipeline.</p>
          <p>During 2010 our development efforts will evaluate multiple compounds in more than 20 pivotal and Phase III clinical trials. Our key development programs are evaluating REVLIMID in all stages of multiple myeloma as well as pivotal Phase III trials of NHL and CLL. We will also conduct late day trials for apremilast, pomalidomide, amrubicin, ISTODAX, and we will continue to advance other promising compounds in the clinic, including ACE-001, PDA-001 and our kinase inhibitor program. All of these development efforts are expected to contribute to our long-term revenue growth. As a result of our continued commitment to R&amp;D, we expect 2010 R&amp;D expense to increase approximately 20% versus 2009.</p>
          <p>Taking a look at SG&amp;A, non-GAAP selling, general and administrative expenses, they increased to 193 million during the fourth quarter as compared to 172 million during the third quarter of 2009. For 2009 non-GAAP SG&amp;A expenses were $679 million. We expect SG&amp;A expenses in 2010 to increase approximately 5% versus 2009 as we continue our global expansion of REVLIMID and VIDAZA in new markets and in particular REVLIMID in Japan.</p>
          <p>Turning to taxes, our non-GAAP tax rate for 2009 was approximately 21%. We anticipate to reduce the non-GAAP tax rate by approximately 100 basis points for 2010. As you are aware we hedge our balance sheet foreign currency exposures, inner-company foreign currency transactions and exposure related to certain euro-based revenue and expense. The impact of foreign currency on top line revenue on a sequential quarter basis was immaterial. In addition, during the fourth quarter we realized approximately 7 million in hedging and revaluation gains which is included in other income.</p>
          <p>In summary, this was an exceptional year with record revenue and earnings. We ended 2009 with cash and marketable securities of approximately $3 billion. In addition, we repurchased approximately 1.2 million shares of common stock during the quarter. On a year-to-date basis we have repurchased 4.3 million shares. For 2010, we expect our operations to generate approximately 1.2 billion in cash and expect to spend approximately 150 million on capital expenditures.</p>
          <p>Turning to our financial outlook for 2010 we expect total revenue to increase by approximately 20% versus 2009 to a range of 3.2 to 3.3 billion. We expect REVLIMID net product sales will increase approximately 25% year-over-year to a range of 2.1 to 2.2 billion. We also anticipate that non-GAAP diluted earnings per share will increase approximately 25% to a range of $2.55 to $2.60 for 2010.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, our company has never been in a stronger position to execute on the global expansion plan for our Hematology, Oncology and Inflammation franchises. As you can see, we have further improved our operating efficiency and leverage during 2009. Our clinical, regulatory, manufacturing and financial execution, as well as our investment in information technology has delivered one of the best operating margins, gross margins and tax rates in our peer group. We are truly well positioned to achieve our goals in 2010.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn the call over to our President and Chief Operating Officer, Bob Hugin, who will expand on the global, commercial, clinical and regulatory achievements of the year and discuss the key objectives that will lead to continued success in 2010 and beyond.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dave. As you've heard, 2009 was an extraordinarily successful year for Celgene. We achieved or exceeded major corporate objectives across all areas of the company. Dave highlighted the exceptional fourth quarter and full year 2009 financial results. I'll review our most significant accomplishments in 2009 and outline the key drivers and objectives for continued excellent performance in 2010.</p>
          <p>At the beginning of 2009 we identified the strategic initiatives and activities required to deliver outstanding performance. We executed against these imperatives in 2009. Our results this past year are a clear reflection of operational excellence across the globe and across functions. Continued market penetration, market share gains and increased duration for our products drove year-on-year revenue growth. Our international expansion significantly contributed to our operating results with new markets fueling revenue growth during the second half of 2009.</p>
          <p>We're beginning to realize the operating leverage from our investments to build a global franchise, with international markets contributing an increasing percentage of our revenue. In 2009 we advanced multiple late stage clinical programs with 20 pivotal trials now either underway or planned to start in 2010. Our medium term pipeline is also more robust now than it was 12 months ago with several key programs advancing into Phase II this year. Our teams advanced 12 compounds in development and numerous preclinical programs and we expanded important collaborations with our external partners.</p>
          <p>2009 was an exceptional year for Celgene in advancing these key strategic initiatives. In the following slides I will share my perspective of these results in greater detail and describe the key drivers for 2010.</p>
          <p>The results of the fourth quarter were outstanding. Total revenue increased by more than 20% year-over-year, driven by strong REVLIMID and VIDAZA sales. The quarter was also highlighted by significant new data on REVLIMID, apremilast, VIDAZA, THALOMID and pomalidomide. And in December, we announced the strategic acquisition of Gloucester Pharmaceuticals.</p>
          <p>Our commercial team performed well in all geographic territories. Global market penetration, increasing the treatment duration, and international expansion all contributed to the outstanding fourth quarter and full year REVLIMID performance. Total U.S. REVLIMID market share in the multiple myeloma market grew to approximately 37% and in major European markets second-line share increased by more than 35% during the year.</p>
          <p>In the United States duration grew to roughly 11.8 months and in Europe to approximately 7.5 months. Late in the fourth quarter the commercial launch in Australia continued our track record of successfully securing REVLIMID pricing and reimbursement agreements across the globe. Japan is our next major opportunity with a regulatory decision expected mid-year and reimbursement and commercial launch targeted for late this year.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter REVLIMID results provide a strong foundation for 2010. Share gains and earlier lines of therapy across major markets, full year sales in the U.K., Canada, Australia, and Latin America and increasing treatment duration remain the key growth drivers. The recent positive announcement by the U.S. cooperative group CALGB and the French cooperative group IFM regarding Phase III myeloma studies provide additional support for continuous REVLIMID therapy. We expect this important new data to be presented at major medical meetings later this year.</p>
          <p>Our position in the global MDS market has never been stronger. In 2009 our focus was on continued growth in the United States, while executing a best-in-class commercial launch in Europe. VIDAZA global sales increased 68% year-over-year and 13% quarter-over-quarter. In the U.S., VIDAZA is the overwhelming market leader in higher risk MDS, and in Europe we're rapidly establishing a treatment standard for the disease. Following regulatory approvals in 2009, we're seeking VIDAZA reimbursement in Canada, Australia and Latin America.</p>
          <p>The presentation of the data from MDS-004, our controlled study of REVLIMID in Del(5q) MDS at the American Society of Hematology Meeting confirmed a significant clinical benefit of REVLIMID for the treatment of transfusion-dependent low-risk Del(5q) MDS. We are actively developing regulatory strategies for key global markets with the combined MDS-003 and 004 studies.</p>
          <p>Continuing the rapid adoption of VIDAZA in Europe for the treatment of all classifications of MDS and a subset of patients with AML is the most important growth driver in 2010. Our teams are focused on following the successful European launch in other markets. As the recognized standard of care VIDAZA continues to be the subject of intense clinical investigation. We expect and look forward to additional results of single agent and combination studies, including those with REVLIMID at major medical meetings later this year.</p>
          <p>Data presented at the annual American Society of Hematology Meeting has historically been a major catalyst for our products. At the 2009 past meeting a record 218 abstracts and over 50 oral presentations were delivered on Celgene products. Leading investigators and cooperative groups presented significant new REVLIMID data across all stages of myeloma, as Sol mentioned, from smoldering to relapsed refractory. The interim data from the Phase III MM-015 trial highlighted the benefits of continuous REVLIMID therapy by significantly prolonging progression-free survival compared with a fixed course of therapy.</p>
          <p>In patients with high risk smoldering myeloma, early results showed that REVLIMID significantly delayed the time to active disease. REVLIMID is the first treatment to show benefit in this patient population. We expect additional updates of these studies in 2010.</p>
          <p>Building on the preclinical hypothesis of antibody-dependent cellular cytotoxicity, or ADCC, encouraging Phase II data of REVLIMID with Rituxan was presented at ASH. This combination produced high response rates in first line and relapsed/refractory indolent lymphoma, including a 94% complete response rate in untreated follicular lymphoma. Promising data from this combination was also reported in chronic lymphocytic leukemia. In heavily pre-treated CLL patients the overall response rate was 64% with generally manageable side effects. We're optimistic that the data from ASH 2009 will again be a catalyst for our clinical, commercial and regulatory programs.</p>
          <p>Immediately following ASH the two cooperative groups that I mentioned earlier, CALGB and IFM, reported initial data from randomized Phase III studies evaluating REVLIMID compared to placebo in multiple myeloma patients following stem cell transplant. The independent data and safety monitoring boards reported that the trials had met their primary end point of statistically significant improvement in progression free survival. Together with the MM-015 results, the IFM and CALGB trials add to growing body of clinical evidence that continuous REVLIMID therapy significantly prolongs PFS in patients with newly diagnosed myeloma. We will continue to work with these groups as they fully evaluate and present these trial results this year.</p>
          <p>While there is great progress in the treatment of early-stage myeloma, there is a growing pool of patients who have failed all existing therapies. Pomalidomide data at ASH positions this next generation IMiD compound as potentially the most important therapy in development for these patients. In heavily pre-treated patients, including those previously treated with REVLIMID, THALOMID and bortezomib, pomalidomide demonstrated a 50% overall response rate, which is the highest reported rate of all drugs in development for this indication. These responses were durable and side effects were generally manageable. We're actively working with investigators and regulatory authorities to advance our pivotal trials.</p>
          <p>Additional ASH data highlighted pomalidomide's activity in myelofibrosis. Today patients with this debilitating disease rely on blood transfusions to treat chronic refractory anemia. Pomalidomide generated a 25 to 40% response rate with more than 60% of responders achieving durable transfusion independence. Again, side effects were generally manageable. We're rapidly moving pomalidomide into pivotal mode.</p>
          <p>In December we announced the acquisition of Gloucester Pharmaceuticals. This strategic transaction provides Celgene with an entry into the U.S. lymphoma market. We will launch ISTODAX in the second quarter in the United States for the treatment of cutaneous T-cell lymphoma. A pivotal U.S. trial for peripheral t-cell lymphoma is now fully accrued and we're evaluating global regulatory strategies for ISTODAX in CTCL and PTCL.</p>
          <p>Data presented at major medical meetings and published in peer review journals throughout 2009 substantially strengthen the clinical and commercial profile of REVLIMID in myeloma, MDS, lymphoma and CLL. With intellectual property protection through 2026, it is a key corporate objective to fully capitalize on REVLIMID's unique clinical profile. This slide reflects our continued investment in multiple Phase III programs in numerous hematological and oncology indications. As we've passed the four-year mark since the first FDA approval of REVLIMID we would expect as the normal course of their business an abbreviated new drug application filing by a generic manufacturer. We are well prepared to successfully defend our significant intellectual property.</p>
          <p>Beyond REVLIMID the hematology and oncology pipeline continued to strengthen and deepen in 2009. In the fourth quarter we completed the enrollment of the Phase III study of amrubicin in second line small cell lung cancer. This trial compares amrubicin to topotecan, the reference drug in this setting. We expect data to be available sometime late this year.</p>
          <p>Preliminary data reported at ASH on ACE-011, our novel activin inhibitor, in development with our partner Acceleron, showed increases in hemoglobin and improvement in bone lesions in multiple myeloma patients. A Phase II study in chemotherapy-induced anemia in metastatic breast cancer patients is ongoing and other areas of clinical investigation are active.</p>
          <p>Our Inflammation and Immunology franchise gained significant traction in 2009. The franchise is a natural extension of preclinical, clinical and overall research platform and fits well with our specialty focused Hematology/Oncology business. Serious inflammatory and immunologic diseases are also predominantly specialist treated.</p>
          <p>Celgene is indeed fortunate to have several promising programs in the inflammation and immunology field. Let me briefly update you on our lead compounds, including the oral kinase inhibitor, 930, PDA-001, our cellular therapy, and the non-oncology applications of ACE-011. In 2009 we concluded proof of concept trials for CC-930, which demonstrated significant suppression of the kinase JNK in healthy volunteers. Based on these results we plan to initiate a Phase II study in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis later this year. We are optimistic on the therapeutic potential of cellular therapy across multiple indications. Our team made excellent progress in 2009 advancing our proprietary program into the clinic. The treatment phase of the PDA-001 Crohn's Disease trial concluded in September and the six month follow-up will be completed early this year. Our goal for 2010 is to initiate a Phase II study in Crohn's Disease and trials in at least two other diseases.</p>
          <p>In addition to the cancer indications previously discussed we're moving ACE-011 forward in non-oncology indications. Based upon our preclinical and clinical work we plan to study ACE-011 as a potential treatment for chronic kidney disease. With multiple compounds and programs in inflammation and immunology, we see 2010 as an important year to execute on our late stage trials, advance our Phase I and II pipeline and deepen our research initiatives in this area.</p>
          <p>Let me spend a minute sharing my perspective on apremilast. With the completion of two important placebo controlled Phase II trials in 2009 apremilast's potential has become clearer. The data from these trials leads us to aggressively pursue Phase III trials in psoriatic arthritis and psoriasis. Apremilast has shown a unique combination of activity and safety and has the potential to be a meaningful therapy for these conditions. We've studied apremilast in approximately 1,000 patients with psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis. This slide summarizes the results from the Phase II trials. In the psoriatic arthritis 001 study, 44% of patients with moderate to severe psoriatic arthritis achieved an ACR20, the key clinical measure of effectiveness. In the second study psoriasis 005 showed that 41% of patients with moderate to severe plaque-type psoriasis achieved a positive 75 score, in the range of biologic efficacy.</p>
          <p>This level of activity together with the encouraging safety profile is compelling. If a comparable level of activity and safety is demonstrated in the Phase III trial there will be a major opportunity to access at a minimum the 85% of the market held by existing oral therapies.  We'll continue to update you throughout the year as we advance our pivotal programs with apremilast.</p>
          <p>The future of any biopharmaceutical company is only as good as its pipeline, the source of future growth. At Celgene we significantly advanced our Hematologic, Oncology, Inflammation and Immunology pipelines in 2009. Our investment in R&amp;D has led to the broad pipeline of 12 compounds in clinical development that you see here.</p>
          <p>We'll have 20 pivotal clinical trials ongoing in 2010 and we're also advancing 16 preclinical programs in 25 serious and debilitating diseases. We look forward to reviewing the progress and potential of our pipeline with you at our R&amp;D day on March 4 in New York City.</p>
          <p>In summary, 2009 was a great year for Celgene. Our products made an increasingly meaningful difference in the lives of tens of thousands of patients around the world and because of this we produced strong operating results. Our pipeline is more advanced, broader and deeper and our global organization expanded and strengthened. Our talented and dedicated team succeeded at converting 2009 objectives into exceptional accomplishments. The momentum that was built throughout the last year positioned us well to capitalize on the many opportunities outlined on this slide.</p>
          <p>in 2010 we are focused on key drivers of value creation: maximizing REVLIMID's global potential; extending our leadership in MDS; and accelerating the clinical development of our early and late stage pipeline. 2010 will be an exciting year with clinical, regulatory and commercial milestones that have the potential to significantly enhance our short and long-term results.</p>
          <p>We very much look forward to updating you on our progress throughout the year. Thank you. Operator, we can now open the call to questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We'll take our first question today from Brian Abrahams at Oppenheimer and Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks very much for taking my question. I was wondering if you could talk about what the drivers were for the significant increase in SG&amp;A expenses this quarter? I know you've seen seasonal upticks in prior fourth quarters, but maybe you could help us understand what proportion of SG&amp;A expenses this quarter relative to prior quarters was for patient assistance with REVLIMID and then if you could also talk about the inventory changes quarter-over-quarter for REVLIMID. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll address the first question for you, Brian, on the SG&amp;A and then Bob can address the inventory levels of REVLIMID.</p>
          <p>When, for us the fourth quarter has a higher SG&amp;A spend because some of the Congresses that we are involved with such as ASH, so there was a little of an increase there and also there is an increase in our SG&amp;A expenses in the fourth quarter because some of the patient co-pay groups needed some funding. So that is planned and is somewhat typical of the way our SG&amp;A expenses go. If you look in 2008, you will see that there was an increase between Q3 and Q4. Bob, do you want to address the inventory?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure. First just on the inventory front, outside the United States the revenue recognition is closer to what we'd call really a pull-through that really reflects the underlying demand of the marketplace. You don't see much of an impact on inventory outside of the United States in any case in any quarter on our revenue. In the United States we do deal through a limited number of specialty pharmacies, but we do have some inventory and that channel averages generally around two weeks. There was a very modest increase in inventory in the fourth quarter, less than the seasonal increase that we've seen in other fourth quarters generally. So I think a very modest, minor impact in this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Geoff Meacham at JP Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks for taking my question, guys. Question for you on your REVLIMID guidance, I just want to go over the extent that you can some of your assumptions. So have you assumed any impact from dual eligibles and then what trends and duration have you assumed? And then the last part of it is is Japan in the guidance at all? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The guidance tends to be a compilation of multiple different scenarios, some with the upside and some with concerns on the downside. Japan is in the forecast in a very modest way because with the filing of the myeloma application the middle of last year we're hopeful that the middle of this year we'll have approval and then have a number of months to deal with getting the pricing and reimbursement done with the government, et cetera. So we have I'd say generally modest revenue late in the year in Japan.</p>
          <p>In terms of impact on healthcare reform, we have different scenarios that go into the scenarios, some of which do have some negative impact on healthcare reform and some that don't. I wouldn't say that we do anticipate dual eligibles to become treated as Medicaid versus Medicare and Part D this year or really in the foreseeable future, but there are things that may be addressed in healthcare reform that could have a negative impact on us and for those of you and us that follow it closely, it's pretty unclear how that's all going to play out and whether there will be some of those negative impacts coming this year, in the future or ever. One of the key things for us when we think about healthcare reform clearly is the donut hole and that's &#x2013; one of the positive things about the progress of healthcare reform, which has unfortunately been slowed from this one perspective, is that there is recognition I think on all sides of the political landscape, but more importantly the medical community and in the healthcare community generally, that excessive kinds of deductibles and co-pays are not good for patients.</p>
          <p>So one of the side benefits was really there is a recognition we need to close that donut hole as a positive. So I think our guidance is, takes in effect a number of positives that we've talked about, but it also takes in effect some of the concerns that outside the United States the economy, and the economy is generally not very strong in the United States or outside in the developed world and there's continued economic pressure. So though we were successful in 2009 to navigate the pricing and reimbursement issues and we don't &#x2013; we're not aware of specific challenges that are going to happen in 2010 on the pricing and reimbursement front, but we're always cautious that with these kind of economic conditions we could see unexpected things happen too on that pricing and reimbursement front.</p>
          <p>So, bottom line is we think the kind of growth projecting of upwards of 30% with REVLIMID year-over-year and strong VIDAZA growth on a year-by-year basis we think is very robust and there are scenarios where we could potentially do better and there's scenarios that could impact us and we'll have a more challenging outlook. But overall we try and put those together and come up with what we think is a fair base case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Steve Harr at Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Dave, just a quick question because I have a really hard time getting the model towards your EPS guidance without going to the very bottom of your revenue range and putting pretty significant &#x2013; going to the high end of anything that you discussed around OpEx. Is there something around one-times in the operating income or suspension of share buybacks that might be missing or was there something else in there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, during the year, Steve, in 2009 we had approximately $60 million in revaluation and hedging gains and other income and expense which are non-repeatable on a go forward basis because obviously those deal with the fluctuations of foreign currency which we can't repeat. So when you look at that line and also the interest income that line right now has roughly 135 to $140 million in it and we are projecting that for that particular item, investment income and other, which picks up revaluation and hedging gains plus investment income, that's going to be kind of in the 60 to $70 million range right now. So there will be a reduction in that for sure year-over-year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think also, Steve, that one of the key priorities for 2010 for us is to accelerate the 20 pivotal trials that are either underway or planned because when we think about Celgene and the opportunity for value creation and over a period of time in the 2013-15 timeframe we want to be the company that has the highest growth rate out there to justify the premium positioning in the marketplace that we would like to have in 2013, '14 and '15. So I think it is important that our team really focus on the execution, accelerate the accruals and the launch of those trials because that is the opportunity for us to have very differentiated growth for the long term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Yaron Werber at Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks for taking my questions. I have two questions. One, help us understand a little bit, last year the economy completely went downhill in Q1 and so Q1 was a big challenge for you. What are you expecting? I think previously you have been saying kind of Q1 could be down sequentially or flat, kind of what are your thoughts now? And then secondly, can you actually give us, it's for Bob, what were actually the market shares in the U.S. in first line and second line and then the actual market shares for REV again on second and third line in Europe? You kind of gave us just the overall in the U.S., and then just year-over-year growth in Europe. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, on the first quarter versus last year's first quarter, certainly the real angst and the real concern in the Main Street economies globally in the first quarter of last year was more severe than the economic situation that we have today, but it is not a robust economy in any way, shape or form in terms of unemployment and the nervousness in the economy. I think we are as well positioned as we can be. We've learned some lessons as to how to manage that in different markets, including the United States. I think we're generally well positioned. I think we don't have quite the same level of anxiety and it is early in the quarter to be able to have a firm outlook and we're not here to give quarterly guidance. I would say clearly it is our goal to target a growth in REVLIMID and in total revenue for the first quarter over the fourth quarter. So I think the first quarter is still a challenging quarter as new budgets come into play, there are new plan years for patients, you are starting new co-pays, et cetera. So, it is a challenging quarter, especially when economic conditions are not strong.</p>
          <p>I think it is fair to say it is not as challenging as the dire circumstances of last year, but I don't want to paint an very rosy picture, either. I think that is why we are trying to give a very balanced view and the first quarter is always challenging, but we think we'll &#x2013; our target is to do as well as possible.</p>
          <p>On the second <mark type="inaudible" />, the market share, the market share situation continues to be a very positive one. In the front line in the United States from independent third party data that we and other people can get, it appears that physicians continue to prescribe REVLIMID as a leader in the first line myeloma. I think the most recent data that I saw put it around 37% of market share in first line myeloma, and overall increasing in second line also. So positive trends there. Outside the United States the real focus and, for us as it is in the United States, is to build second line share where the labeled indications are and ultimately getting approvals with MM-015 to broaden the label for us so we can actually take an active role in the promotion of front line.</p>
          <p>The trends are positive also. We had basically a seven percentage point increase in the main part of Europe over the course of last year in second line and good increases in third line. So I think overall the tone continues to be positive. The trend is positive there and frankly our ambitions are going to be higher than they would have been a year or two as to where we think ultimately REVLIMID will top out in market shares in myelomas around the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Geoff Porges at Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much for taking the question. Bob just to follow-up on that a little bit on that, could you give us a sense of the distribution of your REVLIMID revenue between myeloma and MDS and then just a rough gauge as to what proportion right now is being used in first line and maintenance? I'm sure you have some insight into that and just related to that, do you think THAL use is going to continue to decline or do you think that it will reach a plateau with increased use in the third line setting? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do get, through our system in the United States, the percentage of prescriptions by indication and we have not seen a big change in those scripts over time. It's approximately 85% for myeloma, about 10% for MDS and then lymphoma is the next and then leukemia is after that. But around 95% for myeloma and MDS. We do not get any further granularity as to which line of therapy and if it is maintenance. We are trying to cull that out and so we understand what the upside potential is, that if we were able to get reimbursement and access and active usage of REVLIMID as continuous therapy following stem cell transplant, which I think is generally the one segment in the United States and other markets around the world where we have not had a significant market share because the paradigm there is do stem cell transplant, watch the patient until you see a relapse and then treat aggressively with REVLIMID or potentially other therapies. So I think there is a good upside there.</p>
          <p>So in terms of percentage of our revenue from one part of, whether it's fourth line, third line or second line, we don't have that data. We do make internal estimates, but that is all they are, internal estimates. And related to THALOMID, I think people have different views on it. I happen to be of the view that it continues to be an important therapy in myeloma and that, I think over time we'll see that patients who progress through different stages of myeloma will look at THALOMID more in the third, fourth, 5th line type of therapy. So I think it's going to continue to have a place in there. I would say what we're very excited about is hopefully accelerating the development of pomalidomide. For that pool of patients that really ultimately eventually, we hope it is a long time before they go through REVLIMID, THAL, <mark type="inaudible" />, but use pomalidomide. That could be, based on the data we have seen, one of the most beneficial aspects for myeloma patients in the next few years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Chris Raymond at Robert W. Baird.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the question. Just, I know people have asked around this question, but I'm not sure if I heard the answer that I'm looking for. You guys have shown some really nice duration trends quarter-on-quarter and can you maybe at least directionally delineate how much of that is being driven by earlier lines of therapy versus sort of inter-therapy, inter-line increases, that is are you seeing in front line an increased duration or should we maybe think of some of that as also being driven by maintenance use? If you could just sort of generally delineate that growth that would be great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris, we definitely share your perspective, this is a very important issue when it comes to the growth of REVLIMID and clearly the data that we have been developing through many, many different clinical trials is really designed to produce the evidence that really demonstrates to the physicians, to patients, to payers, the value of continuous therapy. So I think there is a couple of issues here.</p>
          <p>One, I think the trends so far over the last couple years have certainly benefited from an earlier treatment of disease. Healthier patients have clearly the capability of staying on drugs longer and I think REVLIMID myeloma is no exception to that general rule. And so we have benefited from that. Where duration will go, what the opportunity is and sort of the continuous post transplant therapy is unclear. We have different assessments internally here, whether we look at different markets and different individuals or functions that come with different conclusions, but we don't have one specific outlook that we believe from a guidance point of view we would be comfortable discussing publicly because it isn't certain enough from us and we don't have the data to support some of the projections and conjecture that we have as to what the trends will be the next couple of years. But clearly we continue to recognize the value of it and I think you'll see more and more data on this front. We're very hopeful at ASCO, EHA and ASH this year there will be a steady flow of more mature and new data that will really make it so clear about how to use REVLIMID and for what period of time and what stages. So I apologize, but we can't give you specific guidance because we are still trying to accumulate the data and the data is going to continue to evolve and we think in a very positive way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Rachel McMinn at Bank of America/Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I'm wondering if you can clarify your regulatory strategy for front line myeloma in Europe and I guess specifically we know that MM-015 is the core data set, but what is the gating factor? Are you looking for an overall survival benefit? Are you looking to include additional studies like CALGB and IFM as part of the package?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rachel, thanks for the question because it is very important. We have a great opportunity outside the United States to get a label in newly-diagnosed myeloma. Our market share there outside the United States is in the, basically middle single digits with opportunity for real growth over the next four or five years and that indication is very important to us. There isn't any change in what the gating factors are for MM-015 as the platform for regulatory approval in Europe.</p>
          <p>It was a trial that was done with scientific advice working group advice and we executed the trial the way they asked for with PFS as the end point. We are in the process now, as you know, with essentially adjudication of all the responses and of the data. We have passed as we mentioned earlier and late last year that we went past the 70% of events. We hope in the next few months, second quarter, to fully get the adjudication of those 70%, put the package together and the second half of the year get that to the EMEA for review and following that we do want to use MM-015 and hopefully the ECOG and SWOG data, the comprehensive package, for approval outside of Europe, all around the world, including the United States. And ultimately when we do get the CALGB and IFM post transplant continuous therapy data with REVLIMID which obviously all the signals are extremely, extremely positive data, we would make those decisions about regulatory implications of that data and add to &#x2013; expand the label with that data.</p>
          <p>But they're not linked and we're going to go forward with the existing strategy. We've had no reason that we're aware of that we would change the strategy. It's just now an execution of getting it done as quickly and accurately, effectively as we can, to get MM-015 with the 70% of events adjudicated, put together and as we have pointed out in our desire to get that trial quickly done it is not an electronic data capture trial. So it is a manual collection of the data. So, but, there isn't anything that we're aware of that should, other than just the execution of it, get us to go forward and execute this regulatory strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Mark Schoenebaum at Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys, thanks a lot for taking the question, I appreciate it. I also wanted to ask about duration. Coming out of ASH, the &#x2013; obviously the MM-015 data were very positive and there was some debate about the meaningfulness of the induction arm, but I thought what was clear, if MM-015 taught anything it taught that if someone, if a physician was going to use REVLIMID in a first line setting it should be used as a treatment until progression. So maybe you can help us, what is &#x2013; why aren't &#x2013; why isn't every U.S. physician today that's using first line REVLIMID using it in the maintenance setting today? What's the pushback you're getting and the corollary to that is is reimbursement completely online in the U.S. for treatment to progression? And then if there is time I was wondering if you could clarify when you were thinking about starting your apremilast Phase III program, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me deal with the first part of the question. In terms of the use in the U.S., obviously we don't have a label. We don't promote first line. Clearly physicians understand the data or they wouldn't be prescribing it in the kind of way they are in first line myeloma, where REVLIMID is the leading therapy in first line myeloma. And we do have an extensive team of people that work to ensure that physician offices and patients have effective support to ensure that they get reimbursement. Reimbursement is never easy and insurance companies, et cetera, are going to always keep the pressure on. But based on the compelling data, a very proactive effort by our team to ensure that payers are very well informed about whether it be NCCN guidelines, compendia listing, but also, most importantly, the quality of the data, the impact on patients. We really have not seen any impact or pushback in a sense of patients not being able to be reimbursed in the United States for continuous therapy in REVLIMID and myeloma. So not to say that there aren't cases and challenges every day and it is a thankless task that people do to ensure that patients have access to the right therapy. But there isn't anything that we're aware of that is a hurdle in the coming time that as we see more and more continuous therapy usage that we think reimbursement in the United States should be a challenge.</p>
          <p>The second part was on apremilast?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Phase III. Yeah, all right. Just in answer to that, we're obviously very excited by that, we think that apremilast has a very significant potential in a number of diseases. The two that we will be going to Phase III with this year in 2010 are psoriatic arthritis and psoriasis. We are discussing the trials as we speak, the design endpoints with the FDA and with the European regulatory authorities. We're also by the way going to proceed with a Phase II trial in rheumatoid arthritis. Right now our anticipation is that we have approximately four trials that would encompass both psoriatic arthritis and psoriasis, get the appropriate patient population, get the appropriate endpoints and make sure that there's regulatory buy-in. The other thing that's important to recognize, and it's a bit of a subtlety, is that our latest results in psoriasis were at the 30 milligram dosing which was obviously very exciting and starts overlapping with the biologic range of activity.</p>
          <p>The previous result in psoriatic arthritis was at 20 milligrams. So there is a significant potential at least to get even better results in a pivotal trial now that we've demonstrated at least in a Phase II placebo-controlled trial that the 30 milligrams can be a potentially better dose, more active, while maintaining the very nice safety profile that it appears to have in Phase II trials. So we'll be looking at 30 milligrams in the pivotal trials and that could give us some upside, as well.</p>
          <p>So in answer to the question, we anticipate four trials, four Phase III trials, psoriatic arthritis and psoriasis, we're in discussion with regulatory authorities, we are finalizing those and we will start a Phase II trial with rheumatoid arthritis this year, as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from May-Kin Ho with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, very clearly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>It looks like May-Kin removed herself from the queue. We'll move to our next question from Eric Schmidt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was going to ask Mark Schoenebaum's question a slightly different way. Do you have any data on the percent of patients who are today not getting REVLIMID in a continuous treatment paradigm? And secondly is there any chance toward the end of this year that you could file for REVLIMID in the post-maintenance &#x2013; sorry the post-transplant setting based upon the IFM and CALGB data?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Eric, important points. We're not aware of circumstances where physicians that want to prescribe to progression or continuous therapy of REVLIMID or patients that are not getting reimbursed in that area. If through scientific and medical exchange we identify patients &#x2013; physicians that may have these concerns we look to bring them in contact with peers and educate them on some of the data if they are interested. But we really think for the most part in the U.S., the paradigm of immunomodulatory therapy of treating to produce more durable responses is something that has gotten pretty good traction.</p>
          <p>I think there is still an opportunity, that there are segments out there that have, of more chemotherapy type thing, hit the patient as hard as possible, give them a break, try and knock the disease down without killing them, and then wait for the disease to come back and then hit it again. So I think there are probably pockets of that. I do think the IFM and CALGB data is very important obviously because it is a segment of the population that is generally not treated globally. And so we think we have a label that already deals with continuous therapy after one prior therapy, but getting that in the label I think has big advantage for us. Obviously no one really has the data yet.</p>
          <p>It was just the fact that the data monitoring board saw the tremendous impact and thought these trials should be unblinded early because clearly the placebo patient was at a significant disadvantage from a hazard ratio and risk perspective than those people treated with REVLIMID following the transplant. So we're very hopeful and if there's anything we can do, whether it's financially or anything, we're going to support those cooperative groups to ensure they get the data as soon as possible and present it at major medical meetings so that we then can get access to the data. And obviously with cooperative groups, you've got to be cautious and really review the quality of the data to ensure that it's going to meet the kind of regulatory scrutiny that would be required. But it certainly is our intention to get what we believe to be incredibly important and promising data into our label globally in one way or another.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take next question from Jim Birchenough -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, I apologize, but we have time for one last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then our last question will come from Jim Birchenough from Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys, so just three questions. One on the post transplant setting, NCCN recommends THAL use right now. Do you have a sense of what percent of post-transplant patients get THAL and do you expect NCCN to pick up REVLIMID maintenance post-transplant? Second question is just on the O15, do you expect the RMP and MP induction arms to separate? When should we see that and if they don't, can you still file? And final question just, you mentioned the ANDA filing to REVLIMID that you expect. Why shouldn't we worry about that? There are companies that trade at much lower multiples where people worry about the ANDA. So maybe give us a strong case for your patents and why you think they are so strong?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, a couple, I think three or four questions here. First I don't think THAL on a post-transplant setting has gotten any real traction in that, and if you think about the profile of a drug that has neuropathy, it is a very difficult situation to use that in a newly diagnosed post-transplant setting where the patient has had a remission and has a high quality of life and concern for the ability to use those therapies later on if you induce neuropathy and sedation and the kind of side effects that can come from drugs have that kind of situation.</p>
          <p>I do think once the data is presented at a major medical meeting, whether it be guidelines, pathways, compendia listing, the National Comprehensive Cancer Network, et cetera, type situations, we'll very expeditiously move to have REVLIMID as an important therapy in those guidelines. Obviously, that's up to them to do that. But we need to help support, get the information in the public domain as quickly as possible, because I think, I certainly believe anybody who is patient focused is, want to ensure those guidelines are going to be <mark type="inaudible" />. As far as MM-015 goes from a regulatory point of view the pre-specified regulatory objectives and endpoints with A versus B or the MPRR versus MP of fixed duration, so we're not aware of any reason why there should be any concern from a regulatory point of view.</p>
          <p>We do, as we look at that data and it gets more mature, we do think there will be good analysis that will come out to give people perspective of A versus B and B versus C and C versus A on a continuing basis. And I think there will be more clarity over time and I think that it will be easier to understand the issues.</p>
          <p>But again in a trial trying to answer multiple endpoints, you sometimes get some information that will be complex to understand. But we don't see a regulatory issue. We do think hopefully in the relatively near term, major medical meetings, we'll see more mature, better analyzed data on MM-015 which will continue to support the important paradigm of continuous REVLIMID treatment. And on the ANDA question with REVLIMID, we are in extensive long-term, on the THAL front and that continues to move quite slowly. So we are very pleased with the way the THAL indication has gone over these past three to four years.</p>
          <p>On REV, it is a very different situation, though. We have composition of matter patent. We've got a dozen patents in the <mark type="inaudible" />, but wide range and also this is a strategy that we have been preparing for for a long time. By the way, we're not aware of any generic filing. Let's be clear about that. If that were to occur, we would make a public notification of that. Never can be 100% guarantee anything, but I can tell you that we think we have the best internal and external support. We have multiple firms. We're prepared, we've got all of the preparation that can be done if this were to happen and we will vigorously defend our property and we feel very confident about what will happen in the end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much for everyone's participation on the call. As we did mention, we will have an R&amp;D day on March 4th in New York City which will be webcast for those of you that don't attend. We have our conference call at the end of March for the first quarter results. We thank you very much for your interest and look forward to continuing to update you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude today's conference. Thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>