<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1232668" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1403</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John Ferren, Vice-President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Gerald T. McCaughey, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">David Williamson, Senior Executive Vice-President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Tom Woods, Senior Executive Vice President and Chief Risk Officer, Risk Management</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Sonia A. Baxendale, Senior Executive Vice-President, President, Retail Markets</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Richard Nesbitt, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, CIBC World Markets</participant>
      <participant id="7">Rob Sedran</participant>
      <participant id="8">Michael Goldberg</participant>
      <participant id="9">Ian de Verteuil</participant>
      <participant id="10">Jim Bantis</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the CIBC Second Quarter Results Conference Call. Please be advised that this call is being recorded. To reduce the audio interference within the board room and over the conference call line, please turn your BlackBerry off for the duration of the meeting.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. John Ferren, Vice President of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, Mr. Ferren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. Thank you for joining us today. This afternoon our management team will discuss CIBC's second-quarter results that were released earlier today. This conference call is being audio webcast and will be archived later this evening on CIBC.com.</p>
          <p>We'll follow the usual format of some prepared remarks from CIBC's senior management team, followed by a question-and-answer period. Before we begin, let me remind you that any individual speaking on behalf of CIBC on today's call may make forward-looking statements that are subject to a variety of risks and uncertainties. Certain material factors or assumptions may be applied, which could cause CIBC's actual results in future periods to differ materially from the conclusions, forecasts or projections in these forward-looking statements. For more information, please refer to the note about forward-looking statements in today's press release.</p>
          <p>With that, let me now turn the meeting over to CIBC's President and Chief Executive Officer, Gerry McCaughey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for joining us. Let me remind you that my comments may contain forward-looking statements and actual results could differ materially. Following my remarks our senior officers will provide an update on their respective areas.</p>
          <p>CIBC reported a net loss for the first quarter of 51 million and a cash loss per share of $0.21. Earnings apart from the items of note, were $1.44. Our reported results for the quarter included mark-to-market losses and valuation adjustments in structured credit and other runoff-book. The bulk of these credit charges occurred early in the quarter. Conditions have improved significantly since then.</p>
          <p>Our reported results also included mark-to-market losses on our normal course existing loan hedges. These are direct, single name loan hedges that offset the risk of individual large corporate loans that we make on a regular basis as part of our ongoing business. In other words, while these improving market trends in the second half of the quarter supported more positive credit expectations in our loan portfolios, they also result in a reversal of previously reported mark-to-market gains on the related direct credit hedges.</p>
          <p>The reduction in previous gains is a positive for future expectations for our loan book. David Williamson will take you through these two items, as well as other items of note that impacted results for the quarter in his remarks. Again, this quarter, our capital position is another good news story. We reported a Tier 1 capital ratio of 11.5% through the end of April, up from 9.8% last quarter.</p>
          <p>Our total capital ratio improved from 14.8% to 15.9%. The further strengthening of our capital ratio was supported by three main items. First, core business performance and management of our existing risk weighted assets in the business. Second, we had issuance of preferred shares in Tier 1 notes.</p>
          <p>And third, very importantly, as mentioned on our previous webcast, CIBC has set aside significant risk weighted assets against our financial guarantor receivables, thus reducing the capital impact of potential future write-downs. This reduces the potential for any losses in future quarters significantly, since we have also set aside, as of now, US$9.5 billion of risk-weighted assets against our structured credit remaining portfolio.</p>
          <p>That is already included in our April 30 Tier 1 ratio. This capital assignment will mitigate the impact of future losses that might occur if market conditions deteriorate. David Williamson will cover this in more detail. In summary, our Tier 1 ratio of 11.5% continues to place CIBC as one of the strongest capitalized banks in North America.</p>
          <p>As well, we have extra capital set aside against our legacy structured credit portfolio, as I just described. Our superior capital strength is prudent for current conditions, but importantly, provides us with the capacity to take advantage of opportunities as market conditions are now improving. These opportunities are now becoming more apparent.</p>
          <p>Turning to our business results, CIBC Retail Markets reported revenue of 2.3 billion, and net income of 390 million. Our results in our retail business are consistent with our strategic posture, which we have discussed previously, which is to balance growth with risk and expenses.</p>
          <p>For the past two years, and particularly in the past year, we have restricted risk in our retail business, as we saw the potential for industry conditions in the economy to become more challenging. In doing so, we have chosen strategically, in key risk areas, to grow our retail business possibly below-market levels, while maintaining a strong risk approach and prudent management of expenses.</p>
          <p>For instance, as you have heard from us many times in the past, we executed our shift from unsecured lending to secured lending in order to mitigate just such circumstances that we see in today's recession. Today, our unsecured loan portfolio is less than half of the size that it was prior to that exercise, and a fraction of the size that it would have been had we grown it at market rate. We believe that bodes well for our performance throughout the duration of this recession, which could possibly be a long one.</p>
          <p>Similarly in our cards business, we have chosen to grow more slowly than our competitors. This is part of the strategic mandate of CIBC. We continue to grow the portfolio in key areas to bring product innovation to our clients and continue to invest heavily in this business in order to ensure that we have best-of-class performance on behalf of our clients. However, whether this means a possible share loss, that is a risk that we're willing to take against our requirements in terms of risk approach. There are areas of the business in terms of credit cards where people are choosing to grow at much faster rates than we are. That is not the choice for CIBC, given that we also believe that the business must be robust in all areas, including our approach to risk.</p>
          <p>We have taken a very careful approach to loan losses in general. This is clear when you look at our coverage ratio relative to gross impaired loans, which is higher than any of our competitors. We believe this is a prudent approach and positions us very well in the current environment and that we are favorably positioned to see the benefit of this approach through the credit cycle. At the same time, we believe that the risk versus growth mandate that we have been executing as part of our retail business strategy will ease as pressure in our structured credit portfolios abate, overall industry conditions improve, and we do see some improvement in unemployment and other economic indicators. To this end, we continue to invest significantly across our retail markets franchise in all operating areas.</p>
          <p>While we are being very, very careful in the area of risk, we are continuing to invest in the business from a viewpoint of our ongoing operations, our branch networks, and improvements in any areas of technologies and customer service that will make CIBC the most robust retail markets franchise in the industry. Our retail distribution network, advisory and product capabilities are an area that we continue to invest in significantly. These investments are supporting our clients and positioning our retail business to take advantage of future growth opportunities, particularly as market conditions and the economy improve. Sonia Baxendale will review initiatives to further enhance our retail business in her remarks.</p>
          <p>In wholesale banking, revenue was $546 million and net income was $200 million, excluding items of note. Following a strong first quarter, this was the best performance for wholesale banking since the third quarter of 2007. The risk controls and core business strategy the business set forward is starting to yield positive results. Our capital markets business built on a strong first quarter performance by reporting its best revenue quarter since Q1 of '07. And corporate and investment banking reported its best result since Q4 of '07. We are continuing to invest in these businesses through key hires, even as we refocus on our core strengths and enhance our risk management activities. These activities are aligned with the bank's strategic imperative of consistent, sustainable performance over the long term. Richard Nesbitt will comment further in his remarks.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we continued to reduce exposures in our structured credit runoff business, completing four transactions that reduced notionals and also future earnings volatility. Work continued at the end of last quarter and into this quarter. As David Williamson will describe, in our losses for Q2, almost $200 million of those losses were attributable to deterioration and possibly the weaker part of our non-residential real estate structured credit portfolio, our CMBS portfolio. As we approached the end of the quarter, we had disposed of a portion of that portfolio, and in this quarter we have disposed of the balance. This balance was disposed of this quarter at a price above the end of last quarter's marks. David Williamson will cover that again.</p>
          <p>In addition, normal amortization reduced the notional amount of our purchase-to-credit protection with financial guarantors by $100 million during the second quarter. David will review our current positions and progress in this area, including the significant capital assignment that remains to cover the potential future losses in his remarks.</p>
          <p>In the area of productivity, we continue to make progress. Total expenses for the second quarter were 1.64 billion, down from 1.79 billion a year ago. This expense level is also better than our baseline target of 1.78 billion. During the quarter, we continued to realize benefits from the alignment of our infrastructure costs to business changes and the current environment as well as general expense discipline.</p>
          <p>In summary, CIBC's core business performance was solid in Q2, given the prevailing economic environment, as well as our cautious risk approach. We had good wholesale momentum, excellent cost discipline. In retail, we continued to invest in our business through branch expansions and expanding our retail product volume. We had a very strong Tier 1 ratio that was significantly higher than last quarter. We had an excellent growth impaired ratio. And we do have, in terms of our overall results, a higher than normal tax rate, which did affect them.</p>
          <p>As we look forward, we are continuing to exercise a very careful risk posture. We do believe as conditions improve that this risk posture will pay off in a faster recovery for CIBC as the economy recovers. And in addition, we will be better positioned to take advantage of future opportunities, given that we are currently over capitalized as a result of our caution about the marketplace, as well as our caution in relation to our structured credit portfolio.</p>
          <p>As the marketplace and the economy hopefully improve and our structured credit portfolio issues ebb, we may be able to put a portion of that capital to work in expanding our businesses in a variety of areas where up until now we have exercised extreme risk control.</p>
          <p>Given this, we believe that we are very well positioned in the current environment and confident that we have the capacity to take advantage of growth opportunities that will arise in the future.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn the meeting over to David Williamson for his financial review. David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Gerry. Good afternoon everyone. My comments also contain forward-looking statements, and I would remind you that actual results could differ materially. I'm going to refer to the slides that are posted on our website, starting with slide number five, which is a summary of our results for the quarter.</p>
          <p>We reported a loss for the quarter of $0.24, or $0.21 on a cash basis. We had several items of note this quarter, listed on the top right of the slide, totaling $1.65 per share. And, therefore, our cash EPS, excluding these items, is $1.44 per share.</p>
          <p>As Gary mentioned, our Tier 1 capital ratio continues to be strong, and at 11.5%, CIBC is one of the strongest capitalized banks in North America. During the quarter, our Tier 1 ratio benefited from the issuance of 1.6 billion of innovative Tier 1 notes, and 525 million of preferred shares.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll summarize each of the items of note briefly. We had losses of 475 million, or $0.85 per share, on the structured credit runoff business. The next few sides will cover this in more detail.</p>
          <p>Next, we had 168 million, or $0.30 per share, relating to the negative impact of the narrowing of credit spreads on our corporate loan hedging program. As credit conditions improved towards the end of the quarter, we reversed some of the gains we have reported over the past several periods. We had valuation charges of $100 million, or $0.17 per share, on positions in our exited and other runoff businesses relating to certain trading and available for sale positions.</p>
          <p>Next, we had 57 million, or $0.15 per share, of tax expense, mainly related to the write-off of future tax assets due to lower future statutory tax rates. We had a provision for credit losses related to the general allowance of 65 million, or $0.11 per share. This was primarily related to large corporate lending and credit cards, driven by the deteriorating economic environment.</p>
          <p>Next is 49 million, or $0.08 per share, of net losses and write-downs on our legacy merchant banking portfolio, which is included in the Wholesale Banking other line of business, as these holdings are managed separately from our core portfolio.</p>
          <p>Finally, we have repatriation activity involving foreign subsidiaries. While this nets to a gain of only $0.01 overall, we've highlighted this item since it involves the netting of a foreign exchange gain of 159 million in revenue against 156 million of income tax expense.</p>
          <p> Including items of note, first quarter results were helped by a higher revenue in our Wholesale Banking businesses. As Gerry noted and Richard will comment on in a moment, this improvement occurred broadly throughout the various businesses within Wholesale Banking, and represents good performance from continuing operations, especially in light of recent efforts to reduce risk within these businesses. We were also helped by continuing expense discipline, but were hurt by higher loan losses, lower retail spreads, and lower treasury revenue.</p>
          <p>The next slide provides a summarized statement of operations on a reported basis, showing a net loss for the quarter of $51 million, driven by the items of note I just walked through.</p>
          <p>Turning now to a summary of structured credit runoff for the quarter. Losses in Q2 totaled 475 million or $0.85 per share, down from 708 million, or $1.27 per share in Q1. The first line shows the credit valuation adjustment in the quarter of $657 million that we took due to continued deterioration in the mark-to-market value of certain underlying assets and the credit quality of financial guarantors.</p>
          <p>Specifically, one area of weakness in our non-USRMM holdings is commercial mortgage-backed securities. Marks and CVA on our CMBS portfolio was approximately 190 million of our total structured credit charges this quarter. Approximately half of our CMBS notionals were sold just prior to the quarter end and the balance post-quarter end, at prices favorable to the April 30 marks. Therefore at this point, the structured credit CMBS portfolio is now fully divested.</p>
          <p>I stated in prior webcasts we have assigned substantial risk weighted assets against our remaining financial guarantor positions, which acts to dampen the impact of CVA charges on our Tier 1 ratio and effectively establishes a capital cushion against our remaining exposures. We had total write-downs of 90 million, or $0.16 per share, from our un-hedged U.S. residential mortgage market and non-U.S. residential mortgage market portfolios.</p>
          <p>The last line on this slide, other runoff of 277 million, includes the benefit from purchased protection on held-to-maturity securities, where the underlying exposure is accrual accounted, but the protection continues to be marked-to-market. A gain on the service note is also included, as this note continues to provide us with protection against the declining value of our U.S. residential mortgage market holdings.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, as Gerry mentioned, we undertook a number of transactions to further reduce our exposure to structured credit. Specifically, we completed four transactions that had the effect of either reducing the size of our remaining structured credit runoff holdings, or reducing the future earnings volatility associated with these positions.</p>
          <p>Specific details of these transactions are included in our press release and if you have any questions, either Ron Lalonde or I will be pleased to adjust them during the Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Slide eight is a summary of our financial guarantor protections purchased against our U.S. residential mortgage market exposure. In U.S. dollars this slide shows that we have 3.1 billion of credit protection from three remaining counter parties, which now has a fair value of 2.7 billion.</p>
          <p>We have taken cumulative credit valuation adjustments of 2.3 billion, and therefore have a remaining net fair value of 449 million, as shown in column D. In addition to this balance, we have a remaining value of 391 million, shown as the difference between columns A and B. This total remaining exposure of 840 million is protected by the investment from Cerebrus, which had a fair value of 276 million at the end of Q2 for a net remaining exposure of under 600 million.</p>
          <p>This represents a maximum Tier 1 capital exposure of 20 basis points, assuming the value of all underlying positions fell to zero and that we have zero recoveries from the financial guarantor. The impact on Tier 1 is reduced to nil if we assume a 10% recovery from financial guarantors, even in the scenario where the value of the underlying positions fall to zero.</p>
          <p>Slide nine outlines the counter party protection provided by financial guarantors where the underlying assets are primarily CLOs and corporate debt that are not related to the U.S. residential mortgage market.</p>
          <p>Looking at the total remaining exposure, as shown at the bottom right of this slide, our net receivable from guarantors was 1.6 billion at April 30, after a cumulative valuation reserve of $2 billion. We had total risk weighted assets against this portfolio already included in our April 30 Tier 1 ratio of approximately $7.9 billion.</p>
          <p>If we had to write-off the entire US1.6 billion, the impact would be approximately 63 basis points. If we recovered 15% of our gross receivables from financial guarantors in this portfolio, the impact on our Tier 1 ratio would be approximately 25 basis points.</p>
          <p>Turning now to our business results, starting with Retail Markets on slide 10. Revenue for Retail Markets this quarter was 2.25 billion, which is down from Q2 of last year. Personal banking revenue of 1.4 billion was down 10 million, or less than 1%, from Q2 of last year.</p>
          <p>While we experienced solid volume growth across most of our key products, lower spreads resulted in a slight decline in revenue. Personal banking spreads were down year-over-year due to the lower interest rate environment and lower prepayment penalty fees, but were helped by wider prime/BA spreads.</p>
          <p>Given the current state of the economy, we continue to be careful in managing our credit quality and rate of growth.</p>
          <p>Turning to business banking. Revenue of 312 million was down 16 million, or 5%, from Q2 of last year due to lower spreads as a result of the lower interest rate environment. This was partially offset by higher volumes in deposits, GICs and mid-market lending.</p>
          <p>Slide 13 highlights the results of our wealth management businesses. Revenue of 297 million was down 83 million or 22% from Q2 of last year. Weaker equity markets have resulted in a decline in asset value-based fee income and lower trading commissions. FirstCaribbean revenue of 204 million was up 82 million, or 67% from Q2 of last year, mainly due to the impact of a weaker Canadian dollar and lower securities losses. Also, Q2 of the prior year included an 8 million loss on the Visa IPO adjustment.</p>
          <p>Other revenue primarily consists of Treasury allocations, which were consistent with Q2 of last year, and were down from unusually high levels in Q1 due to lower gains on sales of available for sale securities.</p>
          <p>Retail Markets' net income was 390 million, down 126 million, or 24% from the prior year. The provision for credit losses was 403 million and is up 194 million from last year. The increase in the provision was driven primarily by higher write-offs in the cards and personal lending portfolios.</p>
          <p>Tom Woods will provide additional details on this topics in his remarks.</p>
          <p>It's worth noting that our provisions in Retail Markets included 39 million related to an increase in the general allowance, an item that the other Canadian banks exclude from their business unit results. Non-interest expenses were down 76 million, or 6% from last year, as we continued to be focused and disciplined in managing our costs.</p>
          <p>Slide 17 shows our net interest margins. On the bottom row, you can see the total Retail Markets net interest margin was up 2 basis points quarter-over-quarter. Excluding the combined impact of FirstCaribbean and Treasury, our core Canadian retail net interest margin was down 5 basis points versus Q1. This is due to spread compression resulting from the impact of declining interest rates on our deposits business, partially offset by the effect of wider prime/BA spreads on our lending businesses.</p>
          <p>Total retail markets' net interest margin was down 41 basis points versus the same quarter last year. Excluding the combined impact of Treasury and FirstCaribbean, our core Canadian retail net interest margin was down 25 basis points. This decrease was due to the same reasons that I outlined for the quarter-over-quarter decline.</p>
          <p>Now turning to Wholesale Banking. Negative revenue of 241 million in Q2 was driven by losses in structured credit runoff. As noted on the slide, revenue adjusted for the impact of structured credit is 229 million. If we were to exclude all of the items of note related to Wholesale Banking, revenue for Q2 was 546 million, up 128 million from the prior quarter on the same basis.</p>
          <p>Looking at the individual lines of business, starting with Capital Markets, our revenue was 318 million, compared with 307 million last quarter. This was driven by higher revenue in fixed income trading and from equity new issues. Corporate and investment banking revenue of 200 million was up 44 million from Q1, driven by the higher revenue in our U.S. real estate finance business and our core merchant banking portfolios.</p>
          <p>Lower M&amp;A and advisory revenue were offset by higher revenue from equity new issues. As Gerry noted, this was the best quarter for Capital Markets and corporate and investment banking since 2007.</p>
          <p>Other revenue was negative 745 million in Q2 and was driven by the items of note related to wholesale banking that I outlined at the beginning of my remarks. Wholesale banking net income was negative 373 million in Q2. If we were to exclude all the items highlighted as items of note relating to wholesale banking, net income for Q2 was 200 million, up 91 million from the prior quarter on the same basis.</p>
          <p>Turning now to our total expenses and our performance versus our target, which is to hold expenses flat relative to annualized fourth quarter 2006 expenses. We have made adjustments as noted on the slide to ensure a reasonable comparison. As you can see, we are far ahead of our objective due to continued expense discipline. Thank you for your attention and at this point I'll turn the call over to Tom Woods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks David. My comments may also contain forward-looking statements and actual results could differ materially. With respect to credit risk on slide 44, specific loan loss provisions were 329 million, or 83 basis points of net loans and acceptances. The quarter-over-quarter growth of 82 million was due to, first, an increase of 32 million in provisions for business loans, and second, an increase of 49 million in provisions for consumer loans, with cards accounting for 28 million of the increase.</p>
          <p>Gross impaired loans increased by 138 million this quarter to 1.26 billion. Increases were primarily related to our US and international portfolios. The coverage ratio of impaired loans by specific allowances remained the same at 62%. And as Gerry said, this is the best ratio amongst the Canadian banks.</p>
          <p>On slide 45, we provided additional information this quarter to make our disclosure more comparable to other banks. The chart breaks out our specific loan loss provision for cards into two parts. One is the net credit losses, consisting of write-offs due to bankruptcies and write-offs of accounts delinquent 180 days or more. And the second component is the change in the specific allowance on the balance sheet, factoring in our view of future expected losses from delinquent accounts.</p>
          <p>Our cards net credit loss rate in Q2 was 5.6%, up from 4.8% last quarter. As we've discussed in our webcasts for the last several quarters, we've deployed several account management initiatives in this area. While controlling the dollar value of losses, this has also constrained outstandings growth, which has a tendency to increase today's loss rate in percentage terms, but will ultimately lead to lower dollar losses. News that could prove to be encouraging, although not a certainty, is that 30 day delinquency rates stabilized during the quarter.</p>
          <p>At the top of slide 46 we provide a comparison of CIBC's net credit loss ratio versus the ratio of the three other banks who provide similar disclosure. At the bottom of slide 46, we've also normalized all four banks' ratios, assuming constant quarterly balance growth starting in Q4 last year. Now these are hypothetical calculations only, but help us compare loan loss rates across banks that have had different rates of growth in outstandings.</p>
          <p>Turning to market risk, slide 47 shows the Q2 distribution of revenue in our trading portfolios. In Q2, all but one trading day, or 98% of the days, had positive revenue, up from 76% last quarter and well up from 53% in Q2 of 2008. The trading revenue here does not include the reductions in mark-to-market value of our structured credit assets, as this analysis is carried out only at each month's end.</p>
          <p>On slide 48, our Tier 1 ratio was 11.49% at April 30, up considerably from the 9.82% at the end of Q1. While structured credit charges reduced our Tier 1 capital in the quarter, this was offset by a reduction in our risk weighted assets. This reduction was primarily due to reduced credit exposures, reflecting the impacts of loan repayments during the quarter and the weaker U.S. dollar at quarter end.</p>
          <p>I will now hand it over to Sonia Baxendale, Head of Retail Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Tom. My remarks may also include forward-looking information and the actual results could differ materially. Personal and business banking performed well in the second quarter, while our wealth management business continued to experience market-driven headwinds.</p>
          <p>Personal and business banking had solid funds managed growth. Funds managed increased 26 billion, or 8.6% year-over-year. Growth has been driven largely by increases in deposits and secured lending balances. Total Retail Markets revenue of 2.3 billion was comparable to Q2 a year ago. However, we did see the impact of the declining interest rate environment, and in particular, equity market volatility. This was most reflected in wealth management, which had revenue declines over the same period a year ago.</p>
          <p>We have been prudently keeping expenses flat in this market environment, while at the same time continuing to invest in both our branch network and our products' capabilities. In terms of our branch network, we opened or expanded 14 new locations in the second quarter in markets that provide long-term, high growth potential.</p>
          <p>You will note from previous calls that these openings are part of our five-year, $70 million branch investment commitment. We also added Sunday banking to 22 more branches across the country, and now have a total of 37 branches offering Sunday banking hours to our clients.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we are continuing to expand our competitive product offering. Over the past quarter, we took a leadership position in advising our clients on the new tax free savings account product, providing them an opportunity to understand how TFSA fits into their overall financial plan.</p>
          <p>We are pleased with this success of our efforts in this area, which is supported by the fact that register-to-deposit market share grew in excess of 300 basis points over the quarter. This past month we also launched a new high interest savings product and early results are extremely positive, within excess of $1.5 billion in just over two weeks. And in a few days we will be re-launching our highly successful checking and credit card promotion to acquire new clients to the bank.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to our lending portfolio. Our $170 billion personal lending portfolio consists of credit cards, lines of credit, loans and mortgages. Today, 86% of our lending portfolio is secured. Mortgages represent 80% of our secured portfolio, of which -- represent 87%, of which 80% are insured. The vast majority via CMHC. The average loan-to-value on this small uninsured portfolio is 60%.</p>
          <p>Real estate secured lines and loans represent the remainder of our secured lending portfolio. Like our mortgage portfolio, average loan-to-value is in the 60% range, with utilization on secured lines at less than 50% of available limits.</p>
          <p>Unsecured lines of credit and credit cards represent 14% of our total lending portfolio, with cards accounting for 8%. In credit cards, we continue to implement account management tactics to address portfolio risk. And as we have previously mentioned, we have slowed our growth in response to the market environment. This quarter cards outstandings were flat to Q1. As a result of the mitigation actions we have taken, our credit card portfolio is well-positioned and is performing as expected at this point in the economic cycle. Further, credit card delinquency rates have been flat over the past three months, while bankruptcy rates have trended higher this quarter.</p>
          <p>Moving forward, we are planning flat to low single digit growth rates as a result of our actions to ensure ongoing high credit quality. While this will impact market share, our cards profitability remain strong.</p>
          <p>In lines of credit and loans this quarter's 3.1% growth is comprised of 3.5% in our secured portfolio with 2.2% growth in our unsecured lending portfolio. Mortgage assets have also increased moderately during this quarter. While mortgage rates are at historical lows, we continue to anticipate flat to low single digit growth rates for the remainder of the year, in line with the overall industry.</p>
          <p>Business banking continued to deliver year-over-year growth, with economic factors beginning to slow the pace of growth in both deposits and loans. While the current economic climate has driven a moderate increase in the number of risk rating downgrades, overall credit quality of the portfolio remains strong with minimal losses expected. We continue to be receptive to new business opportunities.</p>
          <p>In addition, during the second quarter, we introduced plans to implement a revised business banking operating model, which enables us to better align our sales forces, leverage our existing infrastructure, and simplify our processes to better serve and grow our important business client segments.</p>
          <p>In summary, our focus continues to be on mitigating risk in the near term, while investing in our core operations of personal and business banking and wealth management in order to achieve CIBC's overall objective for consistent and sustainable earnings.</p>
          <p>Thank you. I'll now turn over to your Richard Nesbitt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sonia. My comments may also contain forward-looking statements and actual results could differ materially. I will review the quarterly performance for our Wholesale Banking business and provide an update on our business strategy.</p>
          <p>When we introduced our strategy last year, we committed to an aggressive repositioning of our Wholesale Bank. This process is well underway. In 2009, we have focused on areas of strength, and the result has been solid, high-quality earnings for the Wholesale Banking business.</p>
          <p>We have achieved this performance through core client focused activities that are aligned with CIBC's risk appetite and to its objectives of consistent and sustainable earnings. We have a net income after tax target for our continuing businesses of 300 to $500 million annually, using economic capital of $1.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Our earnings targets were carefully chosen to be achievable without reaching beyond our desired risk profile or outside of our core business for returns. In Q2 we saw healthy revenue growth and development of a strong pipeline of client opportunities for the future. This growth, combined with a continued decline in our expense base, generated positive results for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Our capital markets businesses, which is comprised of cash equities, fixed income currencies and distribution and derivatives of strategic risk had another strong quarter. We've made several key personnel additions in order to focus on our client activities. We're also building our capabilities in the electronic delivery of capital markets products. Revenues in these businesses increased over a strong Q1.</p>
          <p>In our cash equities business through the first four months of 2009, we led the industry in equity trading market share by value executed and trades executed on the TSX in calendar 2009. We also saw strong equity new issue activity that boosted our revenues. Our fixed income and global derivatives businesses continued to deliver solid revenues, with strong trading income and new issue activity.</p>
          <p>Our corporate investment banking businesses, which are comprised of investment banking, corporate credit products, US real estate finance, and our core merchant banking, also posted increased revenues over Q1. The changes we made during last quarter to refocus our corporate lending and our investment banking activities are well advanced.</p>
          <p>In investment banking, revenues were flat, with higher fees from equity new issue activity offset by fewer opportunities in our M&amp;A advisory businesses. In corporate credit products, which is an expanded lending capability that we established earlier this year, revenues were higher in Q2. We believe that this capability will be a growing source of consistent, risk controlled revenue for our firm.</p>
          <p>So to conclude, our results in Q2 demonstrate that we are making steady progress towards achievement of the business and financial goals we established last year. During the first two quarters of 2009, net income after-tax for our continuing businesses exceeded $300 million which gives us confidence that we will achieve our annual target of 300 to $500 million. I'll now turn our call back to John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Richard. Operator, I guess we're now ready to take questions on the phone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question is from Robert Sedran from National Bank Financial. You may go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Gerry, I've got a question for you on the capital side. In the context of the mitigation that you get from the risk weighted assets associated with the structured products exposure, the runoff exposure, why is -- doesn't it strike -- or should we think of 11.5 as too high of a ratio, given the risk profile of the rest of the firm? In other words, the structured credit stuff seems to take care of itself, and 11.5 is for what is essentially a retail bank in Canada with a more plain vanilla wholesale bank as well.</p>
          <p>So, I'm curious to hear your thoughts on what the appropriate level of capital is. And then, you've also mentioned a fair bit about -- or you mentioned deployment or opportunities a couple of times. I'm wondering if you could narrow it down just in terms of, are you planning on acquisition opportunities? Are you planning on lending? Which segment are you thinking about? Where do you see the opportunities for deployment of some of this capital?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Rob. I'll try to make sure -- there is a couple of things there and I'll pause after I've answered them and just see if I have covered it. I think in my remarks and you did pick up in my remarks that under normal conditions -- and I did qualify that by saying as our visibility increases in the area of structured credit and our concerns ebb. And we're still trying to be very prudent there because the turnaround in the markets and all the rest of it wasn't that long ago. So we're still -- although our improvements are not all market-driven, we believe that the quality of what's left in our structured credit portfolio is much, much better than what was there two years ago or one year ago or six months ago.</p>
          <p>But the fact of the matter is is that we are trying to monitor what we believe is the crossroads between the quality of our portfolio and our expectations for what stress levels it could withstand, and what the stress that will be thrown at it is in terms of the economic conditions.</p>
          <p>So, what I did try to say in my remarks was that things do appear to be improving. And as things improve and our visibility around our structured credit improves that it is possible and probable that we are very heavily capitalized here. And 11.5 under most circumstances would be deemed to be a very high capital ratio and we would hope to be able to deploy some of that towards opportunities that we are seeing now and we believe we will see in the future.</p>
          <p>So you then ask -- so I think I have said to you that we do see the scenario whereby the statement you made that we would -- and again, it is never an absolute, but on a continuum basis that we would start to work with that thought process of 11.5 is high. In February, the higher the better. Under normal circumstances I think that it would be a very high level to operate at and as the world gets a little bit closer to normal, we would gradually consider easing that level. At the same time, keeping an eye on any internal risks we have and external risks. So as we consider easing those levels, you said where might you put that?</p>
          <p>First of all, I do believe that we have, because of our very strong risk posture and a mandate that has been bank-wide, I do believe that we have constrained the levels of growth in the risk areas of our retail business significantly. As I mentioned earlier on we -- the example that I used was in our area of unsecured loans. We were dissatisfied with the characteristics of risk that were involved there several years ago and we went to a tremendous distance towards reducing the risk there. Not just in reducing levels of growth and culling the portfolio, but we cut it in half, which is reasonably unheard of compared to any of our competitors.</p>
          <p>And we were more than willing, for many quarters, to take losses in share in order to have the right risk posture. We believe that was prudent, because in terms of unsecured lending overall for the bank, we look at our total ratio, combining that with our overall cards business, and given that we have, we believe, the best systems available and the best expertise available in cards, as a total ratio of unsecured lending for our bank, we chose to be less weighted in unsecured loans and to be &#x2013; and to continue to work with our cards business.</p>
          <p>But we have, in the area of cards, also been restraining risk to lower than industry growth rates for a significant period of time. During an economic downturn, as unemployment rates start to turn up, we believe that while it's very important to the economy and the consumers that we continue to support the economy, growing within a difficult environment like we've had today is something that we've continued to do. But we have not sought to grow at industry growth rates, which in cases of certain competitors, have been high single or double-digits.</p>
          <p>In our case, we are continuing to grow, but in low single digits. And that is a very specific choice that is risk mandated. As things improve, with our capital position and the capital buffer that we would have in the event that the economy did have a bounce downwards after an initial period of growth, we would be able to expand the growth capacity of our retail business, we think more so than certain of our competitors, given that we have been quite constrained. However, that is something that is highly dependent upon our view of the ongoing risks in the economy, because our risk posture is, at CIBC, it has been our top priority for several years, and it continues to be that way.</p>
          <p>In the area of looking beyond that, where you asked about -- so there is lots of room when we ease up a bit on our risk, in terms of our ongoing businesses and particularly our retail business to grow at faster rates and that would require some capital. In our other areas that you talked about, I think you were talking about, are you interested in buying institutions?</p>
          <p>Our preference in the marketplace, and it's not exclusive, but we have looked at institutions. But not beyond our normal market scan that we have been doing for the last four years. We've engaged in continuous institutional visits to find out what's going on in the marketplace, in terms of both the U.S. and foreign institutions and to make sure that we are aware of opportunities that are available. And we continue to believe that the opportunities are in buying assets, not institutions at this time.</p>
          <p>And the reason for that is that -- or in asset formation -- and the reason for that is that, where we have the underwriting capability, it's a far more predictable outcome and easier to adjust our risk through the purchase of assets or the extension of asset formation, rather than the purchase of institutions. So the opportunities that we are seeing in the marketplace are -- number one, we do have, as Richard Nesbitt has mentioned earlier on in several of his presentations, we have split off our focus in our wholesale business, in terms of making a completely separate business unit in our large corporate lending from our investment banking business.</p>
          <p>They still work very closely together, however, the large corporate lending business, right now, is an area that CIBC World Markets has been under-weighted in, particularly in certain sectors. It is also an area where there is great need in the Canadian economy for institutions to be flexible. And it is also an area where we have particular interest in moving in certain areas to either acquire assets or engage in asset formation with institutions that we have not previously dealt with.</p>
          <p>The opportunities there are, I think, very robust. There are certain parts of the marketplace that recently have tapered off in terms of the potential for acquisition or formation because -- and this is good news for the economy, because issuance of bonds and equity have picked up dramatically. That is very healthy for the economy. We are very pleased and we are participating in that particular phase right now.</p>
          <p>But we do believe that the banks, and particularly the banks in Canada, are in a very, very unique situation where we are having a secular change in the economy and in the granting of credit at a large corporate level. And that is because foreign institutions by and large are reducing their exposure to the Canadian economy.</p>
          <p>There is also a significantly reduced availability of things like securitization and ability to distribute credit. And what that leaves is basically the larger banks to fill that gap. We believe and have been positioning our self for a significant period time, that at the right moment filling that gap is something that will have not only cyclical but strategic importance on a secular basis for CIBC. We have been spending a fair bit of time and effort in ensuring that we have the right liquidity horizons. We have probably engaged in more term funding, in terms of the off-market term funding capacity that exists, in the last several months than we ever had in the past. We have gone far beyond what we needed to do on a prudential basis.</p>
          <p>And the reason why we have done that is because we do perceive that there is a gap in the marketplace for term funding of assets and granting term funding and it's something that we want to have the capacity to fill. Because at this time the marketplace in Canada, as I say, is unique in that there are significant providers of capacity who are exiting. Conditions are reasonably good in terms of arriving at prices that, while they provide reasonable spreads, are still by historic standards low on a nominal basis. And to take advantage of the fact that low nominal rates at higher spreads is a good balance for both the borrower and lender.</p>
          <p>So the opportunities there, we think, are very robust. And that we tend in that direction, rather than looking at institutional acquisitions. We are not ignoring institutional acquisitions, but we do believe that at this time, it is just a clearer opportunity in terms of asset formation and asset acquisition. And it's also something where there is a much clearer need for us to operate in a market where we are dominant and where most of our core businesses are in Canada, the asset formation and asset acquisition is more of a contribution than institutional acquisition. Does that answer your question, Rob?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it more than answers my question, Gerry. It's certainly a lot to digest at the end of a long day. So I think I'll re-queue. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Michael Goldberg from Desjardins Securities. You may go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. In the first quarter, as we discussed, your treasury revenue was depressed, reducing your total net interest revenue by -- in the order of about $200 million. What happened with treasury revenue in the second quarter? That's my first question. And my second question is, what line was the $159 million of pre-tax repatriation reflected in? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Michael. David Williamson speaking. So on the treasury question. You are right, on the -- a couple of factors to address in -- on treasury revenue, treasury earnings. Last quarter, we signaled that the gains on sales, available-for-sale securities were abnormally high, so that came down this quarter. That affected treasury revenues. Again, as we positioned last quarter saying, that was a likely outcome.</p>
          <p>As far as treasury's impact on net interest margin, the last quarter what we had said was that the &#x2013; what was on the frequently asked questions, was the decline in net interest margins was due to two factors from treasury -- less favorable positioning and higher funding costs. So, Gerry spoke to the funding cost. That's still the same factor.</p>
          <p>The positioning did improve, but was offset, and frankly more than offset by a different factor which was the -- in Q2 the results in treasury were adversely affected by hedge ineffectiveness. So something you are familiar with and something that the rules around hedge effectiveness being tighter over time. But primarily economic hedges -- effective from an economic perspective, but hedging something that's been in an accrual account against something that is marked-to-market. So noise, accounting noise as opposed to economic results, but it was a factor in Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So if I adjust, though, for the hedging effectiveness, what would you say the impact was on treasury revenue? I mean, roughly speaking, with the numbers I have done, it looks like it may have been about $70 million better than the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Aggregate treasury revenues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just the net interest portion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The net interest portion -- no, you shouldn't be seeing that kind of an improvement, Michael. So why don't we hook up after the call and I will take you through it? Because that is not what you should be getting to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the other point that you raised, where the FX a bit would be, so it is in the foreign exchange other than trading. And again, that's a $159 million item.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So if that is the case, then it look -- your FX, other than trading was -- let's see, just a second. Let me get to that page. It wasn't -- okay, so your FX. Hold on a second. Okay so it was -- so that's built in to the 243 million FX revenue this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Ian de Verteuil from BMO Capital Markets. You may go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I have a relatively simple question on page seven of the subpack. If I were to remove all the unusual items that you detailed, it looks like the delim made a couple of hundred million plus in the quarter. I was wondering if Richard could talk to the sustainability of that? I think very much to the direction you've given us in the past was sort of 75 to 100 million a quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ian, it's Richard. So, we set the target late last year because we knew that, given all of the changes that had happened, people were going to be wondering about what is the business going to look like going forward. And so we've constructed the business around the 300 to $500 million target as well. What has happened, of course, is that there has been a significant amount of bond financing and equity financing that has positively affected that number, for this quarter anyway. And I hope it continues.</p>
          <p>And in addition, with the expansion of our lending capabilities, by separating them from the investment banking, we're starting to see very early positive impact from that as well. So I think it's too early for us to reconsider that target, but I think we're in -- we have some good -- what do you call them, tailwinds behind us in the marketplace right now that is making us -- helping us to achieve at least towards the higher end of that target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Am I right? It's sort of -- $220 million of after-tax earnings, if I remove the six items of note?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, about 200.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>200 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Steve General from Merrill Lynch. You may go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. A question for Tom Woods. Tom, you highlighted that managed card loss rates in the quarter, from slide 45, it looks like about, call it maybe 5.8, 5.9%. If I do a simple calculation on a reported basis, I get a loss rate of closer to 7%. So a couple of questions. What accounts for the big difference there? And secondly, should we be more or less concerned or indifferent if the higher loss rate product remains on balance sheet? And I guess just to finish up, should the focus really be done on managed loss rates in the card book? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Steve, it's really just a question of the way the accounting works. We look at it and most businesses look at it based on managed, because ultimately it all flows through back in terms of the consolidation and securitization revenue. The owned calculation, I guess, and I'll look for Brian the expert on this matter to help me here, factors in a much higher percentage of what we call the change in allowance calculation, where the managed, because there is a component of securitization in there, you don't have to from an accounting point of view include the change in the allowance.</p>
          <p>And that's why on the slide we broke it out to be comparable to the other banks. And the way most people look at it is the NCLs, which look only at write-offs and bankruptcies, as opposed to trying to factor in a prediction of what future delinquency rolls into write-offs would be. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Jim Bantis from Credit Suisse. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you. One of your adjusted items is the merchant banking losses, yet they have been recurring now for three consecutive quarters. And I am wondering if you can give us a little bit of color and on how this legacy portfolio is going to perform in the balance of the year, and maybe the size of it, and why you feel this is an nonrecurring item? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's Richard Nesbitt. I'll start and then David can fill in whatever I leave out. So we had a policy of looking -- certainly looking at the portfolio since Q4 of last year in a way that tried to reflect the impairment that was happening in the marketplace. And that's based on the -- there is a lack of liquidity in these positions, and so there was -- there has been a thorough analysis of them to try to approximate the values based on indices and other available data, like the value put on them by the sponsors.</p>
          <p>You notice that from Q4 those losses have declined. They were larger in Q4 than they were in Q1, and they were larger in Q1 than they are in Q2. I like that trend, myself. And they were -- and the positions now represent approximately the legacy merchant bank, about $740 million. So, right now the positions are relatively illiquid. So you really need to see an improved economic environment in order to get determination of what the true value would be in terms of a sale context.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Richard, are the bulk of these losses still unrealized or realized?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, absolutely, the bulk of the -- I would say -- I can't, I think they're all unrealized. They're all unrealized, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And 700 million roughly is what the remaining portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A little over 700 million. About 740 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There are no further questions registered at this time. I'd like to turn the meeting back to Mr. Ferren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you everyone for joining us. I know you've had a long day and if you have any further questions, please contact our Investor Relations group. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>