<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1438141" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-12-01</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1403</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Geoff Weiss</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Gerald T. McCaughey</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Senior Executive VP">Kevin Glass</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Risk Officer &amp; SEVP">Thomas D. Woods</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="National Bank Financial Brokers">Peter Routledge</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="SEVP &amp; Head-Wholesale, International &amp; Technology">Richard W. Nesbitt</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch Canada, Inc.">Steve Theriault</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Canada, Inc.">John Aiken</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior EVP &amp; Head-Retail &amp; Business Banking">J. David Williamson</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="BMO Capital Markets (Canada)">John Reucassel</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="CIBC World Markets, Inc.">Robert Sedran</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Desjardins Securities">Michael Goldberg</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (Canada)">Gabriel Dechaine</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Cormark Securities, Inc.">Darko Mihelic</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Dominion Securities, Inc.">Andr&#xE9;-Philippe Hardy</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="corprep" affiliation="Treasurer &amp; Senior Vice President">Andrew Kriegler</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Administrative Officer &amp; General Counsel">Michael G. Capatides</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital Markets Canada Ltd.">Sumit Malhotra</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="Canaccord Genuity Corp.">Mario C. Mendonca</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst" affiliation="Veritas Investment Research">Ohad Lederer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the CIBC Fourth Quarter Results Conference Call. Please be advised that this call is being recorded. To reduce the audio interference within the boardroom and over the conference call line, please turn your BlackBerry off for the duration of the meeting.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. Geoff Weiss, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thank you for joining us. This morning, CIBC's senior executives will review CIBC's Q4 and fiscal 2011 results that were released earlier this morning. The documents that will be referenced on this call, including CIBC's Q4 News Release, Investor Presentation and Financial Supplement, as well as CIBC's 2011 financial statements and MD&amp;A, can all be found on our Web site at www.cibc.com. In addition, an archive of this audio webcast will be available on our Web site later today and CIBC's full 2011 annual report will be available this coming Monday, December 5.</p>
          <p>This morning's agenda will include opening remarks from Gerry McCaughey, CIBC's President and Chief Executive Officer. Kevin Glass, our Chief Financial Officer, will follow with the financial review and Tom Woods, our Chief Risk Officer, will provide a risk management update. After the presentation there will be a question-and-answer period that will conclude by 9:00 a.m. With us for the question-and-answer period are CIBC's business leaders including Victor Dodig, Group Head, Wealth Management; Richard Nesbitt, Group Head, Wholesale, International and Technology and Operations; and David Williamson, Group Head, Retail and Business Banking, as well as other senior officers.</p>
          <p>At the conclusion of the question-and-answer period, please stay on the line, as Kevin Glass will take a few minutes to highlight some of the main impacts of CIBC's transition to IFRS. Kevin will be joined by Shuaib Shariff, our Chief Accountant. Following Kevin's comments we will reopen the telephone lines and take any questions. This portion of the call will conclude by 9:15 a.m.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, let me remind you that any individual speaking on behalf of CIBC on today's call may make forward-looking statements that are subject to a variety of risks and uncertainties. These statements may include material factors or assumptions that could cause CIBC's actual results in future periods to differ materially. For more information, please refer to the note about forward-looking statements in today's press release.</p>
          <p>With that, let me now turn the meeting over to Gerry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thank you for joining us. Before I begin, let me remind you that my comments may contain forward-looking statements. Today, CIBC reported net income for the fourth quarter of $794 million and cash earnings per share of $1.91. Return on equity for the quarter was 20.6%. Adjusting for items of note, cash earnings were $1.87, up 11% from a year ago.</p>
          <p>For fiscal 2011 overall, CIBC reported net income of $3.1 billion and cash earnings per share of $7.39. Return on equity for the year was 21.3%. These results reflect our first principle and strategic imperative, which is to be a lower risk bank targeting value creation for our shareholders by delivering consistent, sustainable earnings over the long term.</p>
          <p>We achieved these results while strengthening our capital base. We closed fiscal 2011 with a Tier 1 ratio of 14.7%, up from 13.9% in 2010. Our pro forma Basel III common equity ratio is estimated at 8.1%, well in excess of the minimum standard. The strengthening of our capital base in 2011 was done while investing for strategic growth. On August 31, we completed a transaction to acquire a 41% equity interest in American Century Investments. We also increased our quarterly common dividend to $0.90 per share effective October 2011.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, the external environment remains very uncertain. We continue to target our medium term objectives that we have maintained for a number of years including average EPS growth through the cycle of 5% to 10% and return on equity of 20%, while paying out dividends within our target range of 40% to 50%, and maintaining strong capital ratios. As we prepare for the Basel III phase-in which begins in 2013, we will monitor our return on equity target in light of the greater weighting towards common equity that will exist.</p>
          <p>Now turning to our business results. Retail and Business Banking reported net income of $580 million for the fourth quarter of 2011, up 15% from Q4 of last year. Revenue for the quarter was $2.1 billion, up 5% from a year ago, supported by volume growth across many of our retail businesses and higher Treasury revenues. Credit quality in our Retail portfolios continues to be strong. Retail and Business Banking made good progress in 2011. We opened 27 new branches, we launched several new products to enhance the experience for our customers, including new Master Card credit cards, and we were named Best in Mobile Banking Among Banks Globally by Global Finance magazine, recognizing our leadership in this emerging and rapidly growing channel.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, it appears the external headwinds that have negatively impacted industry profitability are likely to continue to be with us in 2012. Interest rates are expected to remain low and growth rates in consumer credit are expected to slow down slightly. Demand for business credit should continue to grow, which will help offset some of these headwinds.</p>
          <p>To further our retail business in 2012 and beyond, we are focused on priorities that build deeper relationships with our clients, improve our sales and service capabilities, and acquire and retain clients where we have opportunities for wider margins and more extensive relationships. David Williamson is here this morning to answer questions about our progress and strategic direction in Retail and Business Banking.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management earnings of $65 million were up 20% from the same quarter last year due to higher assets under management driven by strong growth in long-term net sales and the equity pickup on our stake in American Century Investments.</p>
          <p>Wealth Management delivered a very strong year in 2011. Our transaction with American Century Investments will complement our existing investment capabilities and provide additional growth opportunities. We became the first bank to offer mobile stock trading to Canadian investors over their smartphones, and we delivered record long-term mutual fund net sales growth of 44%, driven by investment performance that consistently ranked among the leaders in Canada.</p>
          <p>Our strong capabilities in Canada and internationally, along with favorable capital and demographic characteristics, make Wealth Management an integral part of our plans for growth at CIBC.</p>
          <p>While the outlook for Wealth Management in the coming year will depend on market and economic conditions abroad, we believe that our history of strong investment performance and opportunities to realize the full value of our partnership with American Century position Wealth Management well for continued strong performance in 2012. Victor Dodig is here this morning to answer questions about our progress and the strategic direction in Wealth Management.</p>
          <p>Wholesale Banking reported net income of $172 million in the fourth quarter. Excluding items of note, net income was $154 million. Our core Wholesale Banking business in Capital Markets and Corporate Investment Banking achieved a very strong results in volatile market conditions.</p>
          <p>During the year, Wholesale Banking continued to deliver excellent service and value to our clients. We grew or maintained market share in our traditional areas of strength in Canada, including equity trading, equity underwriting, mergers and acquisitions, corporate and government debt underwriting and loan syndication. We made significant progress in expanding lending activities in Canada and internationally, which drives ancillary growth in other wholesale banking products and service areas where we have long-standing tradition of expertise. And we continued to invest in innovative technology, offering e-commerce and foreign exchange platforms for our clients to go alongside our industry-leading position in electronic trading of equities.</p>
          <p>The strong performance for Wholesale Banking in 2011 is aligned with our strategic principle of being a lower-risk bank, as evidenced by industry low VaR levels. While the outlook for Wholesale Banking in 2012 will depend on market and economic conditions, we believe that our client-focused, lower risk strategy, along with investments we have made in our business position as well, to continue to deliver risk controlled earnings as we grow with our clients. Richard Nesbitt is here this morning to answer questions regarding our progress and strategic direction in Wholesale Banking.</p>
          <p>In summary, 2011 was a good year for CIBC and our stakeholders in what has been a difficult environment for banks globally. Our progress supports the strategic path we are on and positions us well for the future. Before I close, I would like to take this opportunity to thank our shareholders for their continued support and all of CIBC's 42,000 employees for their ongoing dedication to serving our more than 11 million clients in Canada and around the world. Let me now turn this meeting over to Kevin Glass for his financial review. Kevin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Gerry. I'm going to refer to the slides that are posted on our website, starting with slide five which is a summary of results for the quarter. So we reported strong results this quarter that were helped by volume growth in Retail and Business Banking, higher Wholesale Banking revenue and higher Treasury revenue and hurt by lower spreads in deposits and mortgages. Earnings per share this quarter were $1.89, or $1.91 on a cash basis. As listed on the top right of the slide, we had three items of note this quarter, the positive impact of which nets to $0.04. The first item of note was a net gain of $0.12 per share on the sale of a Merchant Banking investment. The next item was a loss of $0.05 per share related to a loan loss in the exited European Leveraged Finance business, and the last item was a loss related to structured credit run-off, which totaled $0.03 per share. And I'll provide more details on this in a few moments.</p>
          <p>As Gerry mentioned in his remarks, our capital position remains strong and we finished the fourth quarter with a Tier 1 capital ratio of 14.7% and a tangible common equity ratio of 11.4%. We continued to strengthen our capital base and our pro forma Basel III common equity ratio is estimated at 8.1%, which already exceeds the 2019 minimum requirements of 7%. Also earlier this year, OSFI confirmed non-viability contingent capital treatment for $881 million of convertible preferred shares, which provides approximately 50% of the non-common Basel III Tier 1 capital requirements.</p>
          <p>We also remain focused on optimizing our capital structure with just over $1 billion of preferred shares redeemable in 2012. These securities do not have NVCC features and therefore will be phased out under Basel III rules and redeeming them would be accretive to earnings by approximately $0.09 per share on an annualized basis.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide six, which provides a summarized statement of operations on a reported basis, showing net income for the quarter of $794 million, which concludes a very strong year for CIBC overall. Excluding all items of note, net income this quarter was $776 million, up $82 million or 12% from the same quarter last year on the same basis.</p>
          <p>Turning now to our business results, starting with Retail and Business Banking on slide seven. So here, revenue for Retail and Business Banking in the quarter was $2.1 billion, up $100 million, or 5%, from the same quarter last year.</p>
          <p>Personal Banking revenue of $1.6 billion and Business Banking revenue of $357 million were both relatively flat compared to the same quarter last year. On a year-over-year basis, in Personal Banking, we were hurt by lower spreads, but had solid volume growth with growth of $10 billion in funds managed, which was driven by mortgages and deposits market share growth in the BRAS channel where we have stronger client relationships, and in general are able to earn higher net margins.</p>
          <p>In Business Banking, we were hurt by lower spreads attributable to a combination of the current interest rate environment, which effects all banks, as well as ongoing competitive pressures. However, this was offset by volumes, which continued to generate strong growth with year-over-year lending and core deposit balances up 11% and 12%, respectively. And each of these product categories have also gained market share over the past year.</p>
          <p>Other revenue was up $105 million from the same quarter last year, primarily driven by higher treasury allocations. These were higher than normal this quarter and we do not expect them to remain at this level going forward.</p>
          <p>On slide eight, net income this quarter from Retail and Business Banking was $580 million, up $75 million, or 15% from the same quarter of the prior year. Revenue was up $100 million for the reasons previously discussed. The provision for credit losses of $266 million was up $25 million from the same quarter last year as a result of write-offs from the acquired MasterCard portfolio, as expected, and was partially offset by lower bankruptcies and write-offs across other products. Tom Woods will discuss credit quality in his remarks.</p>
          <p>The non-interest expenses were just over $1 billion, up $14 million or 1% from the same quarter last year, and our objective is to continue to maintain this expense discipline going forward.</p>
          <p>Retail net margins were down seven basis points versus the prior quarter primarily due to lower net prepayment fees on mortgages, which have now started to stabilize, as well as the low interest rate impact on deposit revenue, which will persist until short-term rates increase. Total bank margins were up 10 basis points from the prior quarter, primarily due to Treasury-related activities.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide nine, revenue for Wealth Management in the quarter were $396 million, up $18 million or 5% from the same quarter of last year. Wealth Management results reflect solid revenue growth in asset management driven by record net sales of long-term mutual funds and increased assets under management.</p>
          <p>Looking at the results of the specific business lines on the slide, Retail Brokerage revenue of $256 million was flat from the same quarter last year. Lower commissions per trade and new issues volume were offset by increased trading volumes and higher assets under administration.</p>
          <p>Asset Management revenue of $115 million was up $16 million or 16% from the same quarter last year. This was primarily due to solid asset growth, driven by record net sales of long-term mutual funds of $3.4 billion and strong investment performance.</p>
          <p>Slide 10 reflects the net income this quarter from Wealth Management of $65 million, up $11 million or 20% from the same quarter of the prior year. Revenue was up $18 million for the reasons previously discussed, and non-interest expenses of $307 million were up $9 million, or 3% year-over-year, mainly due to higher performance-related compensation.</p>
          <p>Turning to Wholesale Banking, reported revenue this quarter was $557 million, up $103 million or 23% compared to the prior quarter. During the fourth quarter, Capital Markets revenue was steady at $251 million. And while we had lower equity, new issues and fixed income revenue, this was offset by higher foreign exchange and derivatives revenue. In Corporate and Investment Banking, revenue was $334 million, up $102 million or 44% compared to the third quarter of 2011, primarily driven by the Merchant Banking gain previously mentioned as an item of note.</p>
          <p>In the Other segment, revenue of $28 million was up $8 million from the prior quarter, primarily due to higher Treasury allocations. So excluding items of note, Wholesale Banking revenue was $418 million, down $37 million or 8% on the same basis last quarter. We are very pleased with these results, given the challenging market conditions under which we operated.</p>
          <p>The Wholesale Banking reported net income on slide 12 was $172 million this quarter, up $27 million from the prior quarter. Reported revenue was up $103 million from the prior quarter for the reasons previously noted. Credit quality continues to remain strong, with a provision for credit losses of $27 million this quarter compared to $6 million in the prior quarter. And the current quarter includes a $25 million provision related to our exited European leveraged finance portfolio.</p>
          <p>Non-interest expenses were $330 million, up $36 million from the prior quarter, mainly due to higher performance-based compensation and fees associated with our Merchant Banking gain in the quarter. Excluding all items of note, net income for this quarter was $154 million, down $4 million from the prior quarter on the same basis.</p>
          <p>The next slide summarizes our structured credit run-off results. We had a pre-tax loss of $14 million this quarter versus a loss of $18 million last quarter. So starting with row one, the increase in the credit valuation adjustment generated a loss of $34 million. This was driven by an increase in the fair value of purchased credit derivatives due to declines in the underlying value of holdings hedged by financial guarantors. The impact of widening credit spreads also contributed to the loss.</p>
          <p>On row two, we had a gain of $49 million on purchased credit derivatives that are marked to market and hedged loans which are carried at amortized cost. So this is largely a timing issue and there was a gain this quarter due to declines in the market value of the underlying loans.</p>
          <p>On row three, we had a net gain of $19 million resulting from the unwinding of positions. These transactions reduced our notional position by $2.6 billion. For the full year, we have reduced our notionals by $18.5 billion from $48.7 billion, down to $30.2 billion, and subsequent to year end our notional position has been further decreased by $2.2 billion.</p>
          <p>The loss on row four represents the net effect of gains and losses on the reminder of the hedged and unhedged positions, as well as net interest and non-interest expenses.</p>
          <p>So our fourth quarter represented a strong finish to strong financial results in 2011. Full year reported net income of $3.1 billion was up 26% from 2010; and cash earnings per share in 2011, if you exclude all items of note, was $7.51, up 16% compared to 2010. We had solid revenue growth above 3%, excluding items of note. Lower spreads were more than offset by volume growth in our Retail and Business Banking and Wealth Management businesses.</p>
          <p>We were pleased with the strong performance from Wholesale Banking, given the challenging market conditions in which they operated. And as a result of improvements in credit quality, we had better loan-loss performance.</p>
          <p>We maintained our expenses discipline throughout the year and our cash efficiency, or NIX ratio, excluding items of note, was 58.2%, essentially flat compared to the prior year on the same basis. Our capital is strong and we are well positioned for Basel III requirements. This concludes both a very strong year, strong quarter and a very strong year for CIBC. Thanks for your attention and I would now like to turn the meeting over to Tom Woods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kevin. Good morning, everybody. With respect to credit risk on slide 22, specific loan loss provisions this quarter were $257 million versus $232 million in Q3. All of this increase came from a reserve we took against a loan in our European leveraged finance run-off portfolio. Apart from this loan losses in FirstCaribbean were up and losses in Credit Cards were down.</p>
          <p>General loan losses were a recovery of $14 million compared with a $37 million recovery in Q3 where we had a large general reserve release due to a credit card securitization. Gross impaired loans were up $78 million in Q4, mainly due to higher impaireds in the Caribbean. Our Canadian portfolios remained relatively stable and since the end of the quarter, we have restructured one large loan in Canada and reduced impaireds by $25 million.</p>
          <p>On slide 23, our Cards portfolio loss rate in Q4 was 4.6% versus 5% last quarter. Losses were down $13 million versus Q3. Our Cards delinquency rate continued to trend positively quarter-over-quarter.</p>
          <p>With respect to our Canadian Residential Mortgage portfolio on slide 24, we've insured 77% of our managed portfolio and 66% of our own portfolio with over 90% of the insurance being provided by CMHC. The average loan to value of our insured portfolio, based on August home price data, is 49%.</p>
          <p>Slide 25 shows our exposure to the European peripheral countries and countries in North Africa and the Middle East. As you can see, we have no sovereign exposure to these countries and very little non-sovereign direct exposure, less than $50 million net after deducting the collateral we hold. We have under $400 million indirect exposure to corporates in the peripheral countries in our structured credit run-off book, where our interests benefit from significant subordination to our position. But here too, none of this exposure is to peripheral sovereigns.</p>
          <p>On slide 26, our U.S. Real Estate Finance business had $3.4 billion of drawn exposures and $629 million of undrawn. In Q4, we had no loan losses, down from $7 million in Q3. We had $167 million of net impaireds. As discussed in our Q3 webcast, we could see a slightly higher loan loss rate in this business in the next few quarters.</p>
          <p>Our European Leveraged Finance Run-off book had $457 million in drawn exposures and $91 million in undrawns. In Q4 total provisions were $22 million, including the $25 million provision I mentioned earlier. Our U.S. Leveraged Finance Run-off book had $112 million in drawn exposures and $179 million in undrawns. There are provisions of $5 million in Q4 in this portfolio.</p>
          <p>Turning to market risk, slide 28 shows the Q4 distribution of revenue in our trading portfolios. In Q4, we had positive results 80% of the day -- 86% of the days. Our average trading bar was down 26% from Q3 and we continued to maintain a low risk profile, given continued market uncertainty. Our Q1 &#x2013; our Tier 1 ratio was 14.7% at Q4, up from 14.6% at the end of Q3. Our tangible common equity ratio increased to 11.4% from 11% in Q3. Our Tier 1 ratio increase was mainly due to earnings net of dividends and equity issued in our dividend reinvestment plan, partially offset by the regulatory deduction related to our investment in American Century Investments, which closed in the quarter.</p>
          <p>As Gerry and Kevin have both said, CIBC is well-positioned for the Basel III transition. Our pro-forma Basel III common ratio at the end of 2011 was 8.1%, exceeding the Basel III minimum requirement of 7%.</p>
          <p>Back to you, Geoff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Tom. Operator, we'd now be pleased to take questions on the phone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Mr. Weiss. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question is from Peter Routledge from National Bank Financial. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Just notwithstanding a very strong quarter and year, I wanted to just ask some questions about risks in light of the Alltel markets. First, the CLO book, you've got 35% of the notional and European Leveraged loans, and I'm aware that you got pretty good subordination. But if you assume a rather disruptive resolution to the sovereign debt crisis, do you guys have a sense of what a stress loss range would be from that part of the CLO book?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've done &#x2013; Peter, it's Tom. We've done a number of stress tests and the main focus of those is an impact on our various capital ratios. And I don't have the numbers with me right now, but I can tell you that &#x2013; I mean I know the number of our base case stress test, which is a Tier 1 ratio impact of less than 50 basis points. We've also done what we call worst of the worst cases, and I can tell you in this particular book one would have to assume a very, very severe global recession for loan loss, for losses here to be in the territory that anyone would call material, and that's just based on the huge subordination rates &#x2013; levels that we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you've got, there is adequate subordination in the European -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About 38% &#x2013; the European book has about 38% subordination.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, it's Gerry here. The &#x2013; one of the elements of the overall CLO book, which earlier this year we did manage to reduce it significantly across the board, one of the elements that has been of particular interest over the last several years is that the amortization and run-off of this book has been slower because of the credit experience, meaning when you start to get defaults in the book, the way the waterfalls work and the structures work is you actually end up getting paid down more rapidly. So the initial phase of any pickup in defaults across the board in the book would actually have a positive impact, or our modeling says it has a positive impact, because you start to trigger the waterfalls and the paydowns accelerate very rapidly.</p>
          <p>So what would happen, and again this is something that I don't want to belabor because, as Tom said, it would be very surprising circumstances where you actually pierced our senior position, but what would happen is that as you saw the defaults coming, the actual amount of exposure that you had would shrink. So the ability to define a much smaller subset as the portion that you had at risk, in the event of piercing the subordination would be, I think, significant given that this is a very small part of the overall exposure that the bank has.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the tranches are thick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And they get &#x2013; they actually &#x2013; yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah. Okay, and just one other question, perhaps for Richard, on your trading portfolio of public equities, I presume this is in line with the electronic trading business, but the &#x2013; you had a real spike in just on balance sheet public equities from like $5 billion in 2009 to $22 billion roughly at the end of 2011. How do you hedge risk in that book &#x2013; downside risk?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. It's Richard. Yeah, so that would primarily relate to our equity derivatives activities, and those books we've maintained on an almost fully hedged basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you would have a derivative on one side and perhaps a cash equity on the other side, or vice versa.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how about counterparty risk on the derivative side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that &#x2013; so that all goes through our normal risk management process where every counterparty has to have a available credit line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You keep it granular, I guess is the question, like there's not one or two counterparties who are particularly long?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We diversify our portfolio. We have maximums that we'll permit with any particular counterparty.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The following question is from Steve Theriault from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. A couple of questions to start. First, maybe probably for Kevin, and maybe I missed this during the commentary, but how much did American Century add to the Wealth division in Q4? And then for Gerry, it would appear that changes to the Bank Act will force you to clear any acquisitions greater than 10% of assets with the Minister of Finance. So I'd be interested in your thoughts there. Was this is a surprise? What's your initial thoughts and do you think this is a reasonable expectation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Kevin, so with respect to American Century, it &#x2013; we only had American Century in for a couple of months of the quarter. So it didn't make a significant contribution. We don't disclose it separately at this point, but it's strengthened since then. It was a very volatile market, we only had it in for a couple of months of the quarter, but has made a good start and is in line with our business case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Gerry. Could you repeat the Bank Act question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In reading the draft changes to the Bank Act, it looks like there's going to be a provision where Minister Flaherty has to approve large acquisitions, and I think the benchmark was a certain level of assets, which I think was 10%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Well, we actually in the past have always been under the assumption that we would go through our full consultation process including our regulator, and in the event of anything substantial, again the regulator has their processes and I won't speak for them. But on anything that got large I think in the past, the fact that their consultation process might have included finance as part of their process anyway, was not an unreasonable assumption.</p>
          <p>So like &#x2013; the reality here is that Canada tends to be a principles-based system. This rule does reflect the principles that I believe we have been operating under anyway. I believe our principles have been prudent. Rules that reflect principles that are prudent are prudent rules. And therefore, I think that the conclusion of this is it's all part of keeping Canada at the forefront of the financial systems in the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you don't view it as a meaningful change. That's &#x2013; that's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I didn't say that. Far be it from me to comment on changes that people are making. I view it as prudent and an important part of keeping Canada at the forefront of the world's financial systems.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. And one last one, if I might, for Tom Woods, in &#x2013; on slide 25 you provided an update to your dips exposure, certainly a nominal amount overall. But can you give us a little flavor, I'm curious as to the composition of the $240 million of collateral, I guess for Ireland and Italy specifically, given the rest of the countries aren't all that material?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The collateral meets our standard collateral requirements. And with respect to the European exposures, roughly 50% of that would be governments, U.S., Canada; probably 40% would be supranationals, AAA rated; and the balance would be a variety. We, however, have the flexibility with our counterparties, and this is standard industry practice, to change those guidelines. There is no reason for us to change them at the moment, but our counterparties understand that we could go back to them and require different collateral. So that number you see is the collateral that our European counterparties have provided, but it's standard high-quality collateral that applies right across our whole portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's helpful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Following question is from John Aiken from Barclays Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Dave, I wanted to focus on the Retail Banking operations, wanted to detail the margin compressions, if you could give us a sense as to what the breakdown was between the macro environments and the competitive pressures? And secondarily, what you're seeing on mortgages, it does look like your volumes declined sequentially from the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, certainly, John. It's David speaking. So let's start with the NIMs question. There are actually four factors that are coming into play when we're looking at the seven basis point drop in NIM. So the largest driver was the impact of net cost to the bank when a customer breaks their mortgage early. For a good portion of the quarter, the prepayment fees collected from customers were actually lower than the actual breakage cost to the bank. This was largely due to the interest rate environment and should be a factor for the industry as a whole.</p>
          <p>The second issue is one you referred to as, again, an industry one, that's the low interest rate environment and the impact on deposits. And we've discussed in the past couple of quarters and Kevin mentioned in his remarks, how the low interest rate environment's impacting our revenue on our deposit business and this has obviously continued, given the current rate environment.</p>
          <p>And then you mentioned competitive pressures. So on the asset pricing, there are competitive pressures, primarily I'd say on the mortgage books, and that's having an impact on the &#x2013; the spreads of the mortgages that are rolling off are more robust than the mortgages that are being added on to the books currently.</p>
          <p>And then the final factor is one we've also talked about in prior quarters and that's that the Retail business unit spreads are feeling the pressure of paying higher internal liquidity premiums to Treasury. The residual amounts of that net liquidity are then allocated back into Retail, and that's the Other line, and that accounted for some of the uptick in the Retail Other revenue this quarter. But that is not included in the calculation of Retail and Business Banking NIMs. So it shows up in Retail revenue, but does not show up in the NIM calculation. So, John, can you give me your second question again, that was on mortgage volumes, was it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, David, it looks like the mortgage volumes declined sequentially from the third quarter, and just wondering if this was a strategic choice from CIBC in terms of de-emphasizing a channel, or this is another factor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The overall growth rate, I don't think changed too much, but let me talk about a strategy that we do have in play. So growth levels, I think, have tracked along pretty well. They're 0.6% quarter-over-quarter. But to your point, John, so what's &#x2013; what strategy do we have in play. So there is focus on our part on looking at those channels and I think I mentioned this last quarter, those channels that offer enhanced net interest margins, and most importantly where there's the opportunity for deeper client relationships, where those are more prevalent, and that's leading us to focus on our branch channels more so than our broker channels.</p>
          <p>So to your point John, if you look, there's a slide in the materials, I think it's slide 16, where we take our market share information, this quarter we have broken it out just a bit further and it speaks to your point. What you'll see is in our branch and related channels, we're actually growing faster than market, picking up market share, but in some of our other channels where we're seeing a bit more compression, bit more aggressive pricing and where we don't see the same opportunity to build deeper relationships with our customer base, there we're losing market share. So this is probably what picked up your question. You can see the mortgages' overall market share is down, but that's being driven by channels other than branch, where we're actually picking up market share points. And the same thing is going on in deposits as well, where both in deposits and GICs we're emphasizing our branch and related channels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sounds great. Thanks, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome. Thanks, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Following question is from John Reucassel from BMO Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and a question for David Williamson as well. Just if I look at the slide seven in the revenue in the Retail and Business Banking, revenue was pretty flat to down in Personal and Business Banking, and all the growth has come from the Other. So when we look, when we think about forward revenue growth, should we think of it as pretty flat? Yes or no, if that's the case. And then, in that environment can you keep your expense ratios at 51%, which you have, roughly, over the last few years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So a couple of points. First point I'd make is I wouldn't fully exclude the Treasury revenue element of things, just for the reasons I've outlined. Some of the liquidity premiums paid out of the two Personal Banking and Business Banking come back down into the Other line, so I wouldn't fully discount that.</p>
          <p>So putting that aside, the factors that are affecting revenue, couple of elements of it, one we spoke of the deposits side. That's the low interest rate environment, we'll anticipate that to continue. The asset margins, I touched on that as well. We're seeing less pressure on that. We're seeing &#x2013; it's abating on that front, and that does bode better for the future. But I should touch on the volume side because there are some dynamics there that are offsetting to a certain extent, and I touched on it my comments just to John a few moments ago.</p>
          <p>So that's, in the volume growth side. We are seeing strong volume growth. It's up strong quarter-over-quarter and year-over-year. But the offsetting factors at play, we're seeing pretty strong branch growth, but on the broker side we're actually seeing quarter-over-quarter and year-over-year decline. So within volume growth, although it's robust in aggregate, we do have that internal dynamic. So then, looking to the future, so I expect volume growth, as I say, it's robust now, I anticipate it to grow, hopefully it'll build. But there will be that dynamic where you'll see the bulk of it coming from branch and related channels. And we're investing in our channels, we're investing in those related channels too, branches, to try to build upon that growth.</p>
          <p>Asset compression seems to be abating. However, we do have this low interest rate environment. And that's going to be a factor for us and any bank that has a substantial deposit base. So that's more of an industry factor.</p>
          <p>So turning now to your third part of your question, what's that mean for expenses and do we need to track them. So we're focused on building our revenue growth. The environment is such that we do have to keep an eye on expenses. I have make a couple of comments. One is we're investing where we need to. We're investing in branch growth. We're investing in mobile banking as a result of the Global Finance Award, we're being recognized as leading in that space. We'll continue to invest in that space. Irrespective of those investments, which were built into the fourth quarter, I think our fourth quarter year-over-year growth rate is 1.6% in expenses, and that's our best in eight quarters. It's &#x2013; it shows that our expenses are coming down after a period of them being elevated with HST and pensions and such for. So I believe, to draw it to a close, I believe that we're at now an expense level which is maintainable, whilst we still invest in the franchise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you still think that you can get positive operating leverage next year even with the slower loan growth environment &#x2013; or slower top line growth environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think we &#x2013; our operating leverage, now it's getting better each of the last three quarters and I think we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just wanted to make sure. And then last question is, I think it's for Kevin or Gerry, but the repurchase of preferred dividends, did you say that was $0.09 accretive? Did I get that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's right, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Following question is from Robert Sedran from CIBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. Just a question on the pre-funding that was done a couple of quarters ago, I gather it has largely been redeployed and I'm just wondering, and I don't know if this is for Kevin or for Gerry, but how the bank is positioning itself from a liquidity perspective and just a balance sheet perspective, given some of the storm clouds that are out there? And I'm wondering if there has been explicit discussions with OSFI or whether OSFI is guiding the group as well in terms of how to position themselves for the environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Gerry. We always have ongoing discussions with all of our internal and external stakeholders and part of that is informational, to understand or get a feel for where the industry is. And on the topic of &#x2013; on all of these topics, it would be our belief that we would be in a very strong position. And interestingly enough, despite the fact that there is some ebb and flow in terms of the availability of liquidity in the marketplace, overall we have found that liquidity is readily available and there is actually a fair bit of excess liquidity down in the shorter end, but more importantly the term funding markets have been opened in Canadian dollar, Canadian names and also in U.S. dollars for Canadian names in a variety of areas, and we've managed to continue our term funding programs, as have the other Canadian banks, without interruption.</p>
          <p>So conditions actually have been rather favorable in terms of availability. Obviously, prices are more elevated than they might have been earlier in the year, but continue to be reasonable if you look at them through the lens of, say, the '08 period. So I have to say that so far it's been, while I wouldn't exactly put it, smooth sailing, I would say it's been very normal course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does that mean, Gerry, you're comfortable basically running, and assuming that that's going to continue or would you be inclined to a more liquid balance sheet given what's going on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have been running our liquidity profile well above what our targets would be in normal conditions. So we do not feel that there is any need to increase from  these levels. We've been running that way for probably six months, we've been at an elevated level, maybe eight months since the storm clouds started to gather. And we also have our internal targets, that even under normal conditions we run well ahead of what would be industry requirements. And that is reflected in higher costs, but that's baked in now to our ongoing cost profile, so we feel comfortable maintaining this at least for the foreseeable future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Following question is from Michael Goldberg from Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning. My question is about the 10 basis point NIM increase, which I guess is related to the net interest margin on average earning assets. How much of that is related, as you said, to Treasury contribution, and is that sustainable? How does the Treasury impact compare with prior periods?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, it's Kevin. So, just to talk about the 10 basis point increase, that has largely been driven by, on the asset side of our balance sheet. On a quarter-over-quarter basis our average interest earning assets came down about $15 billion. So the good news is we maintained our NII. But as a result of that reduction, that's obviously had a very, very positive impact on our leverage.</p>
          <p>With respect to specific Treasury activities and order of magnitude, it's not going to significantly change that particular number. In the current quarter we did have some securities gains, which are slightly higher than we have had in previous quarters, but again lower than in others. That's just part of our regular Treasury activities. It's a volatile area, perhaps a little higher than we would anticipate going forward, but not a significant impact in terms of our overall NII.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All I'm getting at is the un-matching component of the Treasury contribution. Was that a &#x2013; so I guess what I see is that you're saying that really the 10 basis point improvement in margin is mostly enriched asset mix as you brought your earning assets down during the quarter. But just the impact of un-matching in Treasury, how much of that would have contributed to net interest margin, and is that sustainable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, could you just clarify exactly what you mean by un-matching?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the difference in your net interest revenue between what it was and what it would have been if everything on your balance sheet had been perfectly matched?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that there was no major change to that on a quarter-over-quarter basis. That wouldn't have been a factor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So then what did you mean by the increased contribution from Treasury?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When we look at Treasury, I mean there is &#x2013; in terms of the 10 basis points, what we're referring to is total back. When we look at it on a business unit by business unit perspective, that takes into account actually Treasury income and Treasury costs, because &#x2013; and that takes into account the impact of funds transfer pricing. So as David outlined, he gets charged liquidity premiums by Treasury and the difference between our cost of funding and those liquidity premiums is what would flow through Treasury. So when we refer to Treasury profits being up or down, if that's internal allocation of funds we're talking about. In terms of the 10 basis points, that's an all-bank picture, which wouldn't really impact that particular Treasury comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I have one other question. How much of the $314 million variable comp in the quarter was related to your Merchant Banking gain? And typically I look at variable comp in relation to your brokerage underwriting and trading revenue overall, it's been quite high &#x2013; I know that it relates to other parts of the bank also, but what should I be looking for going forward in terms of trying to model your variable comps?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the percentages this quarter, Michael, are actually more or less in line with the previous quarter. But in answer to your first part of the question, that was about $21 million odd that we'd have applied relating to that gain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The following question is from Gabriel Dechaine from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Could you tell me if there is a CVA gain in the trading number? Sorry if I missed this. Are you reiterating your commitment to redeeming those pressed in 2012? And could you quantify &#x2013; actually, I'll save that one for the IFRS discussion. But the portfolio mix impact on your Canadian Retail NIM, can you give us a sense for how much of the mortgage book is turning over on a normal basis, not refinancing activity, but how should we expect that to affect your NIM in the coming year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe -- okay let me take the first part on the CVA and may have to ask you to repeat some of those questions because it was a long list.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So CVA didn't have a material impact on our trading for the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The second one I asked was you did recommit to the $1 billion dollars of preferred share redemption in 2012. And then my last question was really about the -- to better understand how your mortgage book is going to roll over in 2012 and how that's going to be translating into lower NIM, because if we've got a combination of slower asset growth and ongoing spread pressures, it's not looking pretty?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah on the -- it's Gerry here. On the pref shares, as you know, the Basel III regime, which comes in Jan 1 of '13, does not give effect to our preferred shares that we have in the same fashion as they were of value under Basel II. As a result of that, a redemption of our preferred shares that have redemption features in them coming up next year would lead to a $0.09 accretion. In the normal course roughly on schedule with those redemption dates, so if you're wondering which ones we would be looking at first, it's all according to the first redemption dates, and there is, I think, one in February and the next two are later on in the year. So our normal course review would bring these up for redemption and as I've said in the past, it's subject to our normal consultation process but we do have an expectation that, given that these securities no longer have value to our balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>... that we would be looking at redeeming them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. My question is more on the environment the way it is, there's no change in, the way you're looking at it today, there is no change in your plans really?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have a change in my thinking, but I would always add that before we would pull the plug we would look at the environment and engage in our normal consultation with our board and other stakeholders. So &#x2013; however, at this time conditions that existed where we were looking at these and have indicated we're looking at redeeming them, the conditions have not changed in a fashion that would lead us to change our view on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then I'll pick up on your question on the broker NIMS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mortgage...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the mortgage NIMS. I'm going to touch on the broker branch element in answering that. So our overall mortgage book is about $140 odd billion, $143 billion to $145 billion. So it's coming off at a rate, let's say a third, just roughly. So you're right, there is a lot of repricing of and refreshing of that book over time. As in any given year, there is $40 billion to $50 billion of mortgages that are being renewed.</p>
          <p>So couple of comments I'd make regarding NIMS. One is that there has been aggressive pricing. We're seeing that pressure abate somewhat. I think I mentioned that in an earlier comment. So we're seeing that abate, so we'll see how that plays out over the next little while. Then the second element is what I touched on before which, I think an important one for us, which is our balance between branch and related channels and broker and related channels. There what we're doing is we do see better net interest margins in the branch and related channels and hence focus there. And what we're actually doing in the broker channel now is we're thinking about what we consider to be appropriate NIMs or appropriate pricing and what that is causing is in certain places we're pricing slightly higher than the market, and that should help our NIMs. It should get us, help get those NIMs closer to branch NIMs. It also is the cause as to why you're seeing our volumes come off in that channel, and hence the reference to our market share where we're up in branch and down in the broker channel.</p>
          <p>So I don't know exactly what it means for NIMs going forward. Obviously, you're exactly right. The book does refresh at a fast pace. The level of pricing pressure seems to abating and we're trying to pick our channels with net interest margins in mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. That's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Gerry here. Just on a point of clarification, which I think everybody understood, but the preferreds when we refer to the $0.09 accretion, we are talking about the accretion once one has redeemed them all on a look-forward annualized basis. I think everybody understood that, but that's not a 2012 number. The number in 2012 would be as per the phase-in given the redemption dates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The following question is from Darko Mihelic from Cormark Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Just one point of clarification first on American Century, is that &#x2013; could you just tell me what line item, where the equity accounted earnings are coming in on the line item?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now, it's not a material item, Darko, it would just be included in our Other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And I guess my second question is related to the big decline in the average earning assets quarter-over-quarter. Can you just walk me through what the decline was related to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. So let me just go back to some of our discussions we've had earlier in the year. So in the first half of the year, we had a significant increase in our liquid assets on the balance sheet, that was driven by a couple of factors. First of all, market conditions gave us the opportunity to take some short-term funding at very good rates and we took advantage of that and placed these in liquid assets. And then earlier in the year we'd accelerated our funding program just to prefund our requirements. So that's what happened at the beginning of the year and that significantly increased our balances.</p>
          <p>And in the latter part of the year we've seen a big decrease because, first of all, we've reduced the usage of the balance sheet for these short-term borrowing opportunities. We just got out of that program to a large extent. So it doesn't have a big bottom-line impact, but obviously it significantly reduces our asset. And then we've also, some of the prefunding, we've not redeployed those funds into higher yielding assets. So that's really &#x2013; those are the dynamics that have driven the movement in the assets over the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. And my last question is for David Williamson. David, it's long been known that the brokerage channel in mortgages generally comes with lower NIMs. And CIBC's, through FirstLine, has long been the first &#x2013; the largest bank in the broker channel. So what has changed? And I guess on a go-forward basis what makes you think that through the Retail Bank branch that &#x2013; a channel that historically CIBC hasn't really been that strong in terms of mortgage originations, why would &#x2013; what's changing now that's going to make you a stronger player in branch originations in mortgages. I guess that's the question that I have in terms of the Retail strategy, what has changed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would start with &#x2013; I'll hand it over to David in a second, it's Gerry here. But I would start with the all-bank strategy and our view of the environment going forward. You've heard me in a number of forums talk about the world of tomorrow and there are a number of components to that, one of which is the Basel III regime, which is coming in, and the differences in terms of how one foots elements like the balance sheet, which is now far more common equity oriented as opposed to preferred shares and other capital.</p>
          <p>And therefore, we have, over the course of the last year, spent a lot of time on looking at efficiency of balance sheet, value of volumes versus NIMs, what drives volumes versus NIMs, i.e., deeper client relationship, investment in the business and all the things David will talk to you about, and concluded that we are going to be targeting businesses that &#x2013; and client activities that, as much as possible, occupy both sides of the balance sheet. To only occupy one side of the balance sheet with a very narrow NIM product that does not have any attraction to the other side of the balance sheet and no margin, it's just a net &#x2013; the other side is just used on a wholesale funding basis, is of diminishing value in any event, but of faster diminishing value in the world of Basel III. That's part one and that relates to all activities throughout all of CIBC that tend to be low NIM and high balance sheet usage, particularly where they only generate one part of the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>The second part of this is that the macro environment also is changing in terms of our view of the overall configuration of the marketplace in Canada. You've heard David talk about the fact that, and many other forecasters have talked about the fact that there is an expectation of a slowing in loan growth at the consumer level. And we believe that that makes it even more important that one target the higher value-add relationships that occupy, on a population basis, both sides of the balance sheet. In addition to that, the level of indebtedness and the actual size of the mortgage marketplace in Canada unto itself is a macroeconomic factor that leads us to believe that reduced volume in terms of our participation at a higher NIM is something that is prudent from a macroeconomic viewpoint.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn it over to David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it was a pretty comprehensive answer. So let me, Darko, just pick up on one of the elements of what Gerry spoke of, because there is a few prongs to what we're going to be doing in Retail over the next while. But one of those prongs is to focus on building deeper relationship with our clients, which implies a shift towards more of a client view of our operations from the current more product-oriented view. So along with a number of other related changes, one focus that generates is to try to build and develop a client base that's consistent with that objective of having deeper relationships.</p>
          <p>Well, what do I mean by deeper? We're in relationship with our clients where it's more of a multi-product kind of view, has what Gerry spoke of, it's both sides of the balance sheet, brings in the deposit element to it, but it also results in a more sticky, enduring kind of relationship. It's less velocity as far as the client base goes and frankly also it's more of a fulfilling relationship from a client perspective. The client satisfaction stats just show a correlation between depth of the relationship and contentment with that relationship with the bank, all of which is driving us from less product view, more a client view.</p>
          <p>So then when you start to go into FirstLine and the channels, we look at what can be done in our branch and related channels as far as depth of relationship and then what can be done in the broker channel as far as depth of relationship. And we are taking certain steps right now to test how that relationship could develop and whether it could be made to be a deeper relationship.</p>
          <p>And then the final point I'd make is just NIMs in the broker space I think have been particularly, you've asked what's changed, one thing that has changed, in addition to Gerry's comments, is that the pricing in that channel has gotten much more aggressive. And that's something that, rather than us just following that trend, what we've been doing is saying, some of those prices in the variable in particular, just don't make sense to us. So we've not priced with the market, we've priced in some cases substantively above the market and we're still seeing volumes anyway, but obviously at a markedly different level. So those prices change, if not weekly, quite frequently, but we're not just matching prices in that channel anymore. If they get to a place that we think is not appropriate we won't follow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much. I think I understand the dynamics of why you're making the changes. I just thought to myself, I didn't think that CIBC's branch was well-positioned for the change. I mean, some of your competitors have large sales forces that actually can compete well against brokers and can originate a lot of product and can create that strong client relationship. I wasn't aware that CIBC had changed much at the branch level to do in fact what you're actually aiming to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we look actually in the market share, we've picked up market share in mortgages quarter-over-quarter and for a while now, we've been picking it up in the branch relative to those other competitor branch channels. So we are picking up share in that space. To your point, Darko, there is more we can do. We've started the branch build. We have been adding to our mobile mortgage advisors. We have been focusing on other channel improvements. There is more we can do. But we're already underway and some of the evidence is we are picking up market share points. So we're competing fairly well in the branch Channel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Darko.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Following question is from Andr&#xE9; Hardy from RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. First question I have is for Tom Woods. The slide that shows the exposure to the birth rate, do have the numbers on what it would look like for the eurozone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there is a slide, 36 in the SFI. I believe it's 36, let me just go there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Slide number 36 in the supplementary package?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And this is a slide that's dictated by Basel II, and it's a bit of an arcane slide, but it's the best way to see what each of the banks' exposure is. But I have to caution you, if you're not familiar with this slide, the $15.6 billion exposure, the bottom two numbers, the off-balance sheet $5.05 billion, that's essentially indemnities out of our CIBC Mellon business, on a 100% basis, where in fact we're re-indemnified by Mellon. And the OTC Derivatives is before collateral. So the real exposure, I would say, the way you would tend to think of it, is that first number, the $5 billion, and that consists of bank corporate loan exposure and Treasury exposure to non-peripheral sovereign debt. Okay, and the balance of that, or the majority of that would be the latter category. Our corporate loan exposure is about $1 billion. Our bank exposure is about $1 billion. As of October 31, it was about $1.5 billion, and the remainder of that $5 billion, or roughly $3 billion, would be high-quality European non-peripheral sovereign Treasury liquid securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful. I was actually asking about the eurozone specifically, so presumably in that $5 billion, a fair bit of it is in the UK?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes it is. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's helpful. The second question I had was for Gerry. Gerry, you brought up liquidity and how you're running well ahead of targets and industry standards. Are you running ahead of the 2015 standards for liquidity coverage as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the 2015 standards are not yet completely finalized and I'd like to turn it over to Andrew Kriegler from our Treasury Department to give you a little more &#x2013; shed a little more light on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. We haven't disclosed the bank's position on the liquidity coverage ratio, which I think is the standard to which you're referring, and I don't believe generally that other institutions have either. Having said that, I can tell you that we have a good sense of where we think that standard is going to play out. It's not been finalized. And we do have some monitoring of it. So we continue to feel very comfortable with our liquidity position and are mindful of where the standards are going to go. We have maintained a fairly conservative posture and expect to continue to do so going forward, particularly given these market conditions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now is it fair to say that as a bank that's smaller in capital markets and has now a lot of long-term funding, you're probably fairly comfortable relative to peers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's a reasonable statement. We're fairly comfortable with our position. Obviously it's not always easy to tell what's inside other institutions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then last quick one. I know it's always tough to comment on court cases and legal matters, but can you at least comment on the expected timing of a resolution with the CRA on the matter related to Enron?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Mike Capatides, the General Counsel. We really cannot, in the sense that is in the hands of the CRA and we're awaiting the latest ruling from CRA on a motion we filed to strike &#x2013; I'm sorry, from the court on a motion that we filed to strike CRA's answer. But in terms of timing, we really can't predict.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Following question is from Sumit Malhotra from Macquarie Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, a couple of hopefully quick questions on credit for Tom Woods. Firstly on your gross impaired loan slide, it looked like you had a decent sized increase coming from the Commercial Real Estate book. Obviously &#x2013; first off, I apologize if you talked about it in your prepared remarks in relation to your U.S. portfolio, but was hoping for some color there. And along with that, credit card trends look like there &#x2013; or your loss rate looks like it's at the lowest level we've seen since early 2008. With employment situation in Canada somewhat choppier in recent months, wanted to get some comments from you in regards to the outlook on how much potential improvement remains in the credit card portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks Sumit. On the U.S. Commercial Real Estate, we did have a relatively small number of new impaireds in the quarter and I've been guiding in my comments for the last couple of quarters that we might have a slight uptick. We had a pretty low loan loss quarter this quarter, in Q4, but some of the new impaireds that have come in were sort of just one side of the line, so we impaired them. I don't think it's going to be a severe change in 2012, but the next couple of quarters we could have higher loan losses than you've seen, nothing dramatic, I don't expect at the moment.</p>
          <p>In the card space, the comment I made was delinquencies continued to trend positively. I should caution you in the SFI, the supplementary package delinquencies, they look quite a bit better and my guidance was they're somewhat better because of the postal strike impact in the previous quarter that caused an uptick. I would say that we would expect credit card losses in 2012 unless -- with the economy and unemployment continuing where it is, to be slightly better. Okay, I would think wholesale should be probably slightly worse and First Caribbean probably about the same. So overall, probably about the same, but cards would be the one area where I'd see some marginal improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So your specific provision ratio this quarter is roughly 45 basis points, which I think is in line with your long-term average. So based on those comments, fair to say you think we're close to flattening out here in terms of the potential benefit that the bank has gotten from falling loan losses in the last two years, there's not too much left here, would be the base case scenario.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. You really do have to look at it in buckets. I think the very strong performance we've had in the Wholesale side &#x2013; I mean if that continues, then you're going to see continuing improvement next year. I don't think it's realistic to think it can continue. I think cards will get a little better. So it really turns on whether we'll see a continuing lower than normal provisioning in the corporate space, and the guidance I just gave you presumes that that's going to come back a bit, come off a bit. But if it doesn't, then we'll see better loan losses still again next year. I'm just not expecting that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I would now like to turn the meeting back over to Mr. Weiss.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Operator. I would now like to pass it over to Kevin Glass to provide a brief update on IFRS. At the conclusion of his comments, we will open the line for a few questions. Kevin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Geoff. And joining me today is Shuaib Shariff, our Chief Accountant. And so thanks for everyone who's stayed with us.</p>
          <p>So slide 32 summarizes our IFRS disclosure to-date and what you can expect over the next few months. So first, the notes to CIBC's annual financial statements released earlier today contain the November 1, 2010 IFRS opening balance sheet and the reconciliation to Canadian GAAP, which I will walk through in a moment. In late January, we plan on issuing a news release to explain the impact of IFRS on our 2011 financial results, as well as a restated Q4 '11 supplemental financial information package presented under IFRS. And then we'll effectively go live with IFRS reporting with our first quarter 2012 results to be released on March 8, 2012.</p>
          <p>So slide 33 shows a summarized November 1, 2010 IFRS opening balance sheet and the reconciliation to Canadian GAAP. So before we review the opening balance sheet, I do want to discuss some of the more significant elections that we applied under IFRS. So the most important of these is a fresh start for post-retirement benefits where we elected to charge unamortized pension plan actuarial losses through retained earnings.</p>
          <p>The November 1, 2010 impact of this is about a $1.1 billion after tax charge to retained earnings, and this will obviously also reduce Tier 1 capital, which I'll discuss in a bit more detail later. This election will however have a positive impact to the P&amp;L in 2011 and onwards. We also chose the fresh start election for the foreign currency translation account. This election will not impact operating P&amp;L and is also capital neutral, as the $575 million after tax charge to retained earnings is offset by credits to AOCI and both are included in Tier 1 capital. There are a number of gross ups to the balance sheet, as well as a number of re-classifications, and I am only going to highlight some of the material differences here but the full opening balance sheet and reconciliation can be found in note 32 of our 2011 financial statements.</p>
          <p>So first you will see the large $50 billion increase in mortgages as $30 billion of securitized and sold mortgages come back onto our balance sheet and $20 billion of MBS inventory, which was previously classified as fair value option securities, is now included in mortgages. And the associated funding liabilities are shown as secured borrowing which is a new line item on our balance sheet. Similarly you will also see an increase of $3.8 billion for credit cards, as our two credit card securitization vehicles are now consolidated on the balance sheet with the associated liabilities reported under secured borrowings.</p>
          <p>Other notable differences include the election to equity accounts for joint ventures under IFRS that were previously proportionally consolidated under Canadian GAAP. And this had the effect of reducing gross assets and liabilities by $2.2 billion.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 34, while less material in the balance sheet impact, there are number of items that will affect the 2011 IFRS income statement. So the first is the fresh start election for pensions that I mentioned earlier, and this will increase net income after tax by approximately $80 million in 2011, and this is mainly because we have no actuarial losses to amortize through the compensation expense line, since as I noted before, they've been charged to the opening IFRS retained earnings.</p>
          <p>And then second, we took a goodwill impairment charge of approximately $200 million under IFRS with respect to our FirstCaribbean subsidiary, whereas there was no impairment under Canadian GAAP. And the goodwill testing under IFRS is different than Canadian GAAP in that IFRS uses a single impairment test while Canadian GAAP is based on a two-step test. And this is, obviously it's a non-cash item, and again it's capital neutral. Its goodwill is already deducted from Tier 1 capital.</p>
          <p>And then finally, there is a one-time charge of approximately $65 million, after tax, due to market moves on certain derivative hedge positions before they were fully designated as accounting hedges under IFRS. The hedges relate to our mortgage and funding liability balances, which are both accounted for as amortized cost under IFRS.</p>
          <p>And the several other items listed at the bottom of the slide that effectively net out to a minimal income statement impact will simply change the geography of where items are reported on the income statement. So as a result of securitized assets coming back on the balance sheet, we can expect higher net interest income and loan loss provisions, offset by lower securitization fee income. The impact of these changes are relatively neutral to P&amp;L on an annual basis.</p>
          <p>The transitional IFRS impact to our regulatory capital is a $1.4 billion reduction to Basel II Tier 1 capital, or approximately 110 basis points at November 1, 2011. But this transitional relief afforded OSFI, which will allow us to phase this $1.3 billion impact -- will allow us to phase in about $1.3 billion of this impact over time. Some of it's in the first year and then about half of it over five quarters.</p>
          <p>So CIBC's capital position remains strong. And it's important to note that the Basel III pro forma common equity ratios that we have been communicating to the market already account for the effect of IFRS. As I've said it earlier, our pro forma common equity ratio under Basel III is estimated to be 8.1% on November 1, 2011, which is well in excess of the current minimum requirement.</p>
          <p>The conversion to IFRS has obviously been a significant undertaking for us, but I'm pleased to report that we're well positioned for a successful transition from Canadian GAAP to IFRS. So at this point, let me turn the call back to the operator for any questions that you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question is from Gabriel Dechaine from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a clarification, what do you mean by your guidance on Basel III, the 8.1% already reflects IFRS, did I misunderstand that or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean, all I was saying is that effectively Basel III looks through different accounting constructs. So the fact that we've had a retained earnings adjustment under IFRS in no way impacts our Basel III ratios.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the 110 basis of reduction, it won't be 7.9% next quarter, is that what you are saying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now that is the Basel II impact, so under Basel II it will have a 110 basis point impact, but has no impact on the Basel III ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Following question is from Michael Goldberg from Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Couple of questions, first of all will you have a separate line item for net interest revenue from securitized assets or is that going to be buried right in your total net interest revenue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, that will be included in net interest revenue. So there is no separate disclosure for that under IFRS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And secondly, I guess among the points that Gerry and David were making about the strategy regarding broker originated mortgages, is there any visibility that you can see to, a way to originate mortgages that can still qualify for gain on sale accounting, so that they would not have to go on the balance sheet? Is there any mechanism at all that you can foresee for that possibility?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, I mean there are ways to do it, but it would be very difficult to actually achieve that accounting and certainly wouldn't be a focus for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The following question is from Mario Mendonca from Canaccord Genuity. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I actually want to focus on, if I may, the disclosure on, in Europe. Is &#x2013; are we missing anything -- this is for Tom obviously, are we missing anything on the trading book, is that captured in the third column?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just pull that out again, Mario. I thought we were onto IFRS, so let me just...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I just &#x2013; I queued up for something before and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sure the answer is no, but I want to be sure I &#x2013; you're back on page 36, are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe so, I'm going there as well. Yeah, it's 36.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So give me your question again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, are we missing anything here? The exposure seems rather modest. And I don't suspect there is something on the trading book that hasn't been disclosed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, absolutely not. The OTC derivatives, I mean that's a very arcane methodology, in fact our real mark-to-market after collateral exposure is in the low hundreds of millions of dollars, but we're required to in effect show you the aggregate mark-to-market before collateral. So it's very modest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, sorry, going, what &#x2013; the page I was actually referring to is page 25 of your presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about this. Sorry to make you go back and forth. See the $258 million there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does that, the third column, derivative, mark-to-market receivables, what I suspect that you've captured any kind of trading exposure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, yeah. Absolutely. And that slide is just the peripheral countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, right, no, I understand that. And so we're really not missing anything at all then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not on the peripheral, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we're not missing anything at all in Europe. In fact, the two slides together show you way more than is &#x2013; anyone would view as our economic exposure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I got it. And if I could just move to Kevin for a moment here, the summary you gave us of how things have evolved over the last &#x2013; over the year in terms of liquidities and pre-funding, that was a helpful summary. What I'd like to understand is why the bank felt it was appropriate in the second half of the year to take those liquidities down? I don't believe your peers have necessarily.</p>
          <p>And I suspect that the cost was still very favorable in the second half of the year, as favorable in the second half as it was in the first half. Maybe you could correct me on that. What was the logic in taking that down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it's just more our conservative balance sheet management. So when we weighed up what the potential bottom line impact was relative to what the balance sheet impact was, our feeling was that it was just more prudent to bring those balances down, both sides of the balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What risks were you trying to take off by taking the balances down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it's just a more volatile market, so to the extent you have an inflated balance sheet, it's just conservative in running with a smaller balance sheet. And also, as we &#x2013; obviously as we move towards IFRS, we just wanted to make sure that we had appropriate ratios in place, and so it's &#x2013; was more just an ongoing management approach.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just to be clear, it was interest-rate risk then that you thought was appropriate to take down a little, because it's not credit because there's not &#x2013; there wasn't really any credit risk in that book. So I am just trying to get a handle on was it interest rate risk then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Gerry here. The reality of it is is that strategically we are targeting balance sheet efficiency as you heard me talk about earlier on, and for a variety of reasons, some of which were funding-related, and ran their course, when you prefund three months in advance, or four months in advance, or five months in advance, as time passes, your ability to bring down your balance sheet while maintaining your liquidity is something that &#x2013; or increasing your liquidity, is something that is not indicative of a change in posture. It's the passage of time. And we had indicated at the time that we had done some prefunding and that with the passage of time our balance sheet would come down. This was discussed when the balance sheet went up. We laid out the game plan and this is exactly in sync with what we discussed at the time. So there is not much mystery to this. I'm happy to continue to try to answer or shed more light on it. But it is something that was, I think, pretty clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Following question is from Ohad Lederer from Veritas. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just back on the IFRS, has the bank talked about its asset to capital multiple on an IFRS basis with this new balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not something that we disclose on an ongoing basis, but I think that from the perspective of our asset to capital ratio it does have an impact. But as a result of the transitional relief that we get over five quarters, it has very little impact at this point. It would increase from about 16 times to 18.6 times, but then that gets brought right down again as a result of the transitional relief.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So at the end of the transitional relief period, when it's fully phased in, how close to Gerry's world of tomorrow concept, how close does the bank get to where that is fully a part of the bank's day in and day out reality?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean I think looking at our assets to capital multiple, if that's the question, do we look at it. We look at it all the time, right? So it's one of the things we certainly focus on. And I think that in terms of where we're at right now, we're in good shape. In terms of our transition to IFRS, we're in good shape. And if you &#x2013; certainly if you take the transitional relief into account, by the time that runs out we'll have another couple of years of earnings growth under our belt. So we will have created more wealth from that perspective. So right now we're comfortable with our ratios.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All that having been said, it's Gerry again, when I discuss the world of tomorrow and the activities that CIBC is engaged in in terms of how we see it important to change strategic positioning, we are engaged in a series of activities that will very specifically drive convergence with some of the targets that Kevin had indicated that we would land on down the road.</p>
          <p>He had talked about one way you can converge on that through your earnings, the other way is through how you have arranged your life in terms of your targeted asset mix and your asset base. And there are some very significant changes for us in here and reality of it is is that we are no longer targeting a number two position in mortgages. We are targeting a number four position in mortgages and that, I think, will give you a little bit of clarity as to how serious we are and how important we think these strategic moves are.</p>
          <p>We also believe that by targeting a number four rather than number two, we will optimize CIBC's picture, both in terms of its service to its clients, because the NIM configuration here will allow a larger reinvestment in our business from a client viewpoint, and also we think that it does match the macro environment in terms of regulatory change as well as what we believe is a prudent posture, leverage wise and looking at the next few years in terms of how we see the future of the overall housing market and formation in this area. So there are a number of ways that one can adapt to a new environment, and one can adapt and put up with it, or they can engage in strategic change. It is our choice to engage in strategic change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There are no further questions registered. I'd like to turn the meeting back over to Mr. Weiss.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you for joining us this morning. Please contact Investor Relations with any follow-up questions. And on behalf of the team at CIBC, I'd like to wish everyone listening this morning a very happy and safe holiday season, a successful year in 2012. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's conference call. Please disconnect your lines, and thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>