<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1135140" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-02-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1403</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John Ferren, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Gerald T. McCaughey, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Tom Woods, Senior Executive Vice-President and Chief Risk Officer, Treasury and Risk Management</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Sonia A. Baxendale, Senior Executive Vice-President, CIBC Retail Markets</participant>
      <participant id="5">Brad Smith</participant>
      <participant id="6">Tom Woods</participant>
      <participant id="7">Michael Goldberg</participant>
      <participant id="8">Ron Lalonde</participant>
      <participant id="9">Mario Mendonca</participant>
      <participant id="10">Andr&#xE9;-Philippe Hardy</participant>
      <participant id="11">Ian de Verteuil</participant>
      <participant id="12">Sumit Malhotra</participant>
      <participant id="13">Sonia Baxendale</participant>
      <participant id="14">Rob Sedran</participant>
      <participant id="15">Gerald McCaughey</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon ladies and gentlemen.  Welcome to the CIBC First Quarter Results Conference call.  Please be advised that this call is being recorded.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. John Ferren, Vice President, Investor Relations.  Please go ahead Mr. Ferren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Good afternoon and thank you everyone for joining us this afternoon.  The purpose of our call is to discuss our Q1 results which we released earlier today.  The call is being audio webcast and will be archived later this evening on cibc.com.  In addition to the Q1 materials posted on our website, CIBC held its annual general meeting this morning in Toronto and the management presentations from that meeting are available on our website as well.</p>
          <p>This afternoon CIBC's senior management team will deliver some prepared remarks and will be available for a question-and-answer period following.  Before we begin, let me remind you as usual that any individuals speaking on behalf of CIBC on today's call may make forward-looking statements that are subject to a variety of risks and uncertainties.  Certain material factors or assumptions may be applied which could cause CIBC's actual results in future periods to differ materially from the conclusions, forecasts or projections in these forward-looking statements.  For more information, please refer to the note about forward-looking statements in today's press release.  With that, let me now turn the meeting over to CIBC's President and Chief Executive Officer, Gerry McCaughey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and thank you for joining us.  Before I begin again let me remind you that my comments may contain forward-looking statements and actual results could differ materially.  This afternoon I will review CIBC's first quarter results and comment on the actions we have taken to position CIBC for future performance and growth.  Following my remarks, our Chief Risk Officer, Tom Woods will provide the financial and risk review.  Sonia Baxendale will then cover retail markets performance in the first quarter.  Our new Chief Financial Officer, David Williamson is in the room and will provide the financial review beginning next quarter.  Richard Nesbitt, who officially joins CIBC tomorrow, will provide the World Markets review beginning next quarter.</p>
          <p>Let me start with our results.  This morning CIBC reported a net loss for the first quarter of $1.46 billion and a net loss per share of $4.36.  Our Tier 1 ratio at quarter end was 11.4%.  Our core businesses delivered solid results this quarter but obviously our overall results were significantly reduced by charges related to CIBC's exposure to the US subprime residential mortgage market.  Specifically, CIBC recorded valuation adjustments against purchased credit protection from financial guarantors of 1.96 billion after tax as well as write-downs on CDOs and RMBSs of 316 million after tax.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share apart from those charges and other items noted in our press release were $2.02.  This result reflects solid operating performance despite tougher market conditions than a year ago.  Retail markets reported net income of 657 million, up 15% from the first quarter of 2007.  Revenue growth, expense discipline and good credit quality contributed to this result.  Retail Markets revenue of 2.37 billion was up 4% from a year ago.  Volume growth, higher treasury revenue and the FirstCaribbean acquisition offset in part by spread compression and lower brokerage revenue contributed to our overall retail revenue growth.</p>
          <p>World Markets reported a net loss of 2.16 billion for the quarter.  This result includes the 2.28 billion after tax of counterparty credit reserves and structured credit write-downs.  It also includes gains on credit hedges and expenses related to the sale of our US investment banking operation.</p>
          <p>Apart from these items, good performance from the gain in investment banking was partially offset by lower US real estate finance and merchant banking revenue.</p>
          <p>In summary, while many of our businesses performed well this quarter, our overall results are disappointing.  We have to see a strategic imperative to deliver consistent and sustainable performance over the long-term.  With respect to risk, our goal is to take risks that are consistent with our strategy and appropriate for a bank of our size.  Our losses related to US subprime mortgages do not support that objective.  As a result, let me now update you on a number of steps we have taken to reinforce our strategy.</p>
          <p>Our first actions were taken several months ago.  First, we restricted our structured credit business where our US subprime exposures were originated and are winding down this business.  We also put on some hedges where the cost and risk was appropriate.  And we continue to examine opportunities to exit positions within a very illiquid market.  And we suspended our share buy-back while we focused on building our capital during the second half of 2007.</p>
          <p>On a broader basis we have recently undertaken several strategic initiatives to position CIBC for strength over the mid to long term.  The first area of focus is to reduce the risk in our business mix.  Specifically, we have exited businesses that do not offer the kind of solid and sustainable returns our strategy demands.  In November we announced the sale of our US domestic investment banking business to Oppenheimer.  This transaction closed in early January as planned.  In December we announced the exit of our European leveraged finance business.  While this business performed reasonably well in 2007, it's underwrite to distribute model makes it difficult to deliver consistent performance through the cycle.  However the outcome is a more targeted and lower risk range of wholesale businesses that are aligned with our strategy and where we have a competitive advantage in the market place.</p>
          <p>Our second area of focus is to strengthen our senior management capabilities.  To that end, we announced some changes to our senior executive team in early January.  Tom Woods has taken on the position of Chief Risk Officer.  Tom is a 30 year veteran who understands our risk profile and who is committed to our strategy for consistent and sustainable growth.  Tom's focus will be to strengthen our overall risk management practices and procedures as well as adding talent to our team.  Succeeding Tom in the Chief Financial Officer role is David Williamson.  David has broad financial experience as CFO and has worked extensively with banks in Europe, UK and Canada in the area of risk management.  He has also been CEO of two Canadian public companies.  Richard Nesbitt joins CIBC as the Head of World Markets.  Richard has spent many years in the securities industry and is a strong supporter of our plans to refocus and strengthen our core World Markets business.  In addition to these senior management changes, we have made changes at other levels of the organization to advance our objective of delivering consistent and sustainable performance.</p>
          <p>Third area of focus is strengthening our capital position to provide a cushion against deteriorating market conditions.  As part of this plan we completed a $2.9 billion common equity raise in January, through a 1.5 billion private placement and 1.4 billion public offering.  Our capital rate is aligned with our previous stated intention to place additional emphasis on building capital strength in 2008.  CIBC reported a Tier 1 ratio of 11.4% at January 31, up from 9.7% at the end of October.  The growth in our Tier 1 ratio was supported by our capital raise, ongoing earnings and management of our risk weighted assets as well as favorable impact of Basel II.</p>
          <p>Our strong capital position provides a cushion in an environment that remains volatile and unpredictable. As long as this is the case, balance sheet strength will remain our most important priority.  In summary I want to reiterate that CIBC strategy of consistent and sustainable performance has not changed.  The strong performance of most of our core businesses over the past two years is evidence that our strategy is a good one.  At the same time our recent set back is proof that we have more work to do to ensure that all of our businesses reflect our strategic risk posture, particularly in portions of World Markets.</p>
          <p>This alignment is critical when faced with a sudden and fear trend in the credit cycle as we've experience over the past nine months.  We want our entire risk activities to be consistent with the progress we've made so far and the benefits that that has created for the bank.  I'm confident that the actions we have taken to reinforce this strategy will position the bank for long term performance.  Over the course of 2008, we will focus on remediation and management of the areas that are of concern today while investing in both our core, Retail and World Markets franchises for future performance and growth. Thank you, and I will now turn the meeting over to Tom Woods.  Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Gerry and good afternoon everybody.  My comments contain forward-looking statements as well and actual results could differ materially.  I'm going to refer to the slides that were on our web site.  Starting with Slide 5 which is our usual one-page summary of the quarter.</p>
          <p>In the top right, you can see the items of note which when applied to the loss per share, produced the 2.02 that Gerry referred to.  The bottom left, Tier 1 capital ratio 11.4.  I'll get into the makeup of how that went up from 9.7 at the end of Q4.  And in the bottom right, some of the main points why the numbers were helped, volume growth in cards and mortgages, better expenses and the flip side, lower merchant banking, lower capital markets and just slightly higher loan losses.  So those are the main points.</p>
          <p>Slide 11 is a summary of the write-downs for the first two months of Q1 that we announced in our press release January 14.  The second column shows the additional write-downs we've taken in January.  The $292 million number opposite ACA, reflects the additional deterioration in value that the exposure underlying the ACA protection has suffered.  The $624 million number opposite other monolines, reflects the change in our accounting methodology for taking counter-party credit reserves against the other monoline insurers.  The new methodology draws more on credit derivative spreads in the secondary market and produces reserves much higher than if we continued to apply the previous methodology which relies more on historic defaults and loss rates by credit rating.  We concluded we needed to make this change because the high degree of uncertainty regarding the future of several of these counterparties made us less comfortable relying strictly on historic default rates.</p>
          <p>Slide 12 shows our US real estate exposure that is not hedged with counterparties.  This is updated from table 2 in our January 14 press release and reflects the 13 million of additional write-downs in January.</p>
          <p>Slide 13 is a summary of our US real estate exposure that is hedged with monoline insurers.  This shows that we have US 7.91 billion of exposure, an underlying value of 2.9 billion and therefore, monoline insurer protection by subtraction of 5 billion.  To date, we've taken reserves of 2.8 billion, leaving remaining exposure of 5.1 billion.  In the extreme event that all the underlying subprime exposure went to zero and all of monoline insurers went bankrupt.</p>
          <p>In the event market conditions and the value of these assets deteriorated further, in other words to the extent the line beside the asterisk in the middle of the slide moved up or to the extent monoline insurer financial health deteriorated further we'd have to take additional reserves.</p>
          <p>Slide 14, is a sensitivity analysis akin to the one that we showed in the January 14th press release showing the affect on tier 1 ratio to additional hypothetical losses.  I should note that it was done pro forma Jan 31 and therefore is conservative because it does not reflect the inclusion of any earnings beyond the first quarter.  If the calculations were done as of the end of the second quarter for example, and assuming the same level of operating earnings as we had in Q1 the Tier 1 capital ratio shown would each be 14 basis points higher.</p>
          <p>Slide 15.  Looking at the business results now.  First in retail markets, revenue was 2.4 billion, up 4.3% from Q1 last year.  Ex FirstCaribbean which we began to consolidate in Q1 last year, revenue was up 1.9%.</p>
          <p>Turning to each of the individual retail market lines of business.  First on slide 17, in personal and small business banking, revenue was 544 million in the quarter, up 5% versus Q1 last year.  Deposit balances were up 5% from a year ago.  Revenue in Q2 is expected to be down somewhat due to two less days and slightly lower spreads.</p>
          <p>Slide 19.  Retail brokerage revenue was 276 million, down 9% from Q1 last year, driven mainly by lower trading volumes and new issues currently offset by higher annuitized revenue.  February is off to a better start and if markets regain a reasonable degree of stability, Q2 revenue should be up somewhat versus Q1.</p>
          <p>Slide 20.  Cards revenue of 423 million was up 3.2% from a year ago with higher loan and purchase volumes offset narrower spreads.  Loan balances were up 13% from a year ago, the highest in eight quarters.  We expect industry growth this year of 10 to 12% in balances and we expect to maintain our market share.  Purchase volume growth was 7.7%, the highest year-on-year growth in five years.  We expect slightly lower cards revenue in Q2 due to regular seasonal declines in balances and two fewer days.</p>
          <p>Slide 21.  Mortgages and personal lending was 319 million down 16% from Q1 last year mainly due to the tighter prime-BA spread and the lower unsecured lending balances.  Residential balances continue to show strong growth up 12% from a year ago.  Industry pricing was reasonably disciplined in the fixed rate side but remains very competitive in variable rate mortgages.  Personal and small lending balances were up just under 1% on the year but spreads were well down due in part to mix and tighter prime-BA spreads.</p>
          <p>The outlook for Q2 in mortgages and personal lending is for moderately higher revenues driven by higher balances.</p>
          <p>Slide 24 shows Retail Markets net income 657 million up 15% from a year ago or 16% excluding FirstCaribbean.  Revenue was up 4.3% or 1.9 ex FirstCaribbean, as I have just reviewed. And expenses were flat as the additional expenses from the FirstCaribbean consolidation offset lower performance driven retail brokerage payouts.  Loan losses were up 5% which was mainly volume driven, so net income up 15% on the year.</p>
          <p>Turning to our second business group, CIBC World Markets, slide 25.  Negative revenue reflects the 2.28 billion ACA reserve, the 626 million in reserves against other monolines and the 471 million in write-downs to our un-hedged position as I noted earlier.  It also includes 70 million in charges or negative revenue in connection with the sale of some of our businesses in the US Oppenheimer, as we indicated last quarter, as well as positive mark-to-market revenue of 171 million on a credit derivative portfolio.</p>
          <p>The individual lines in business, and I am starting with capital markets, slide 27, revenue excluding write-downs and credit derivative gains was a 165 million versus 214 in Q4, excluding these items.  Revenue in the debt businesses was down from Q4 due to mainly to the effect of credit spread widening on many of our positions more than offsetting strong foreign exchange revenue.  Equity structured products revenue was down as much higher volatilities increased hedging costs in our equity linked note business and new origination here was down as well.  Many of our proprietary trading strategies under performed in a market characterized by declining equity values and widening credit spreads.  Canadian agency equities, however, had another good quarter and US equities was down due in part because Q1 includes only two months of revenue prior to the divestiture of Oppenheimer.  So far in Q2, capital markets were ahead of the pre-write down Q1 run rate and with markets continuing as they are today we should report higher revenue here than in Q1.</p>
          <p>Slide 28, Investment Banking and credit products, revenue of 283 million was up 43 million from Q4.  This included a 128 million in mark-to-market gains on the corporate loans hedges and strong performance from our Canadian and European investment banking businesses.  M&amp;A in Canada continued to be strong but was down marginally from a very strong Q4.  Equity new issues were up from a slower than normal Q4.  Contributions from the US was down as here again we had less than a full quarter of contribution for the divestiture.  The current outlook for investment banking and credit products for Q2 is for lower revenue.  Even after adjusting for the gains on credit derivatives in Q1 and the US divestiture because of a reduced pipeline for new issue equity and M&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Slide 29, Merchant Banking results were well down from a strong Q4 with revenue of 9 million due to fewer divestitures and lower distributions from third party funds.  We had gains and distributions of 42 million offset in part by write-downs in funding costs of 35 million.  The opportunities for financial sponsors to obtain debt financing on attractive terms is much reduced now.  And as a result we are not anticipating a significantly higher run rate here for the balance of the year.</p>
          <p>Slide 30, World Markets net income excluding the write-downs was 113 million.  And excluding the costs incurred with the sale of some of our US businesses to Oppenheimer and other restructurings and the gains on the credit derivatives, was 52 million versus 205 million in Q4.  Revenue excluding these items was down 132 million from Q4.  Expenses excluding costs related to the sale to Oppenheimer, other restructuring and litigation reversals were down 9 million versus Q4 and loan losses were a positive 17 million versus a recovery in Q4.</p>
          <p>Let me turn now to our risk management slide, slide 53, credit risks.  Specific loan loss provisions were 171 million in the first quarter, 40 basis points of net loans and acceptances.  The 37 million increase in specific provisions versus Q4 was due to a $29 million increase in World Markets and an $8 million increase in Retail Markets.  World Markets specific provision was 11 million in the quarter.  The loss is mainly due to a single loan, however the provision from this particular loan was offset by revenue related gains on the hedges in our credit derivative portfolio.  Recoveries in the large corporate portfolio were down from Q4 '07.  Retail Markets specific provision was 160 million in the quarter.  Provisions in the small business and commercial portfolios were up versus the prior quarter largely due to lower recovery and reversal levels.  And in the current portfolio, provisions were up as were volumes.</p>
          <p>Net impaired loans increased 360 million at the end of Q1 in line with the same quarter a year ago.  The increase in the previous quarter is mainly due to one loan in the World Markets portfolio as well as seasonality and a return to more normal levels from the unusually low levels last quarter in the consumer portfolios.</p>
          <p>Slide 54, market risk.  This slide shows the Q1 distribution of trading revenue as we do every quarter. 47% of the days were positive, down from 54% last quarter and well down from the 2007 average of 75% positive trading days.  Trading revenue here does not include the reductions in the mark-to-market value of our structured credit assets as this analysis is carried only at month end.</p>
          <p>Slide 55.  Tier 1 ratio, as Gerry said, was 11.4%.  That's up 1.7% compared to the prior quarter.  Here you can see the makeup of that increase.  Basel II contributed 71 basis points to the increase and the $2.9 billion common equity issue we did in January net of the losses and dividends in the quarter contributed a further 97 basis points.  I'll now hand it over to Sonia Baxendale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Tom.  My remarks may also include forward-looking statements and actual results could differ materially.  Retail Markets revenue increased 2.2% quarter-over-quarter and 1.9% year-over-year excluding the previously announced VISA IPO gains and FirstCaribbean.  Our industry leading credit card business continued to have strong growth.  Credit card outstandings grew 13% year-over-year or 2% quarter-over-quarter.  As I shared last quarter, this level of performance was last experienced in fiscal 2001 and reflects the continued success of our launch of Aerogold mileage multiplier and our no fee Platinum Card.</p>
          <p>We experienced strong growth in acquisition of new accounts and continued strong retention rate of existing accounts.  Portfolio credit quality has remained strong as our loan loss rates decreased year-over-year.  In addition neither delinquency or bankruptcy rates have deteriorated.  Our mortgage business continued to perform at industry growth rates.  Both new mortgage originations and balances grew 13% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>In lending, we are starting to see moderate improvement as the result of initiatives to improve acquisition and account management.  Our total lending balances were up slightly quarter-over-quarter and year-over-year with market share flat quarter-over-quarter after numerous quarters of decline due to our previously discussed changes to unsecured credit processes.</p>
          <p>In the highly competitive deposit and GIC markets, we continued to grow balances.  Personal deposit balances grew 2.2% quarter-over-quarter and GICs 2.3%.  We maintain our plans to increase our marketing investment in this area to grow existing client balances and attract new clients.  Despite the volatility in global equity and fixed income markets, mutual funds started the fiscal year with 730 million in net sales driven by short-term funds.  These results placed us in third position overall in industry net sales, up from thirteenth position in 2007, and increasing our market share by 17 basis points over the previous quarter.  The launch of new income-oriented product solutions, the addition of proven investment manager talent to our team, and the expansion of our wholesaling team will be key to our continued growth.</p>
          <p>In distribution, we continue to make progress in our strategy to improve clients' accessibility in all of our channels.  40 of our planned 70 new branch builds are currently in progress with opening schedules for this year and next.  Chinese speaking clients can now access any of CIBC's 3800 automated bank machines all across Canada in their own language.  And the Sunday opening pilot at six branches in Toronto and Vancouver are receiving extremely positive feedback from both employees and clients and we are currently evaluating additional locations.  In December, commercial banking joined Retail Markets.  This new structure will enable us to strengthen the partnership between our personal, small business, and commercial banking team and position us for increased growth in an important market segment.  In Retail Markets overall, our focus will continue to be on leveraging our core strength in delivering strong advisory solutions to our clients, delivering a consistent client experience, and offering competitive products.  I'll now turn back to John Ferren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Sonia.  So Operator, I think we're ready to take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />  The first question will be from Brad Smith of Blackmont Capital.  Please, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.  Yes, my question just relates to the non-subprime monoline hedges, which I believe saw a slight increase in their carried amount during the quarter.  I was just wondering, in view of the continuing uncertainty with respect to the monolines, if it was possible to get some sense for sizing in terms of the aggregate notional covered by these monoline hedges. Hoping to get some sense for the distribution of the counterparty credit ratings in a similar fashion to the distribution that you've provided us on the subprime bucket. And then I was also curious if we could get some commentary on the composition of the underlying credit that has been underwritten in that non-subprime bucket. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Brad, it's Tom. Yeah, I know you and a few others have raised this before. We haven't provided that granularity, I don't know that any North American bank has. We'll take a look at that. I can tell you, as I've told, as I gave you before, I mean at this stage with consistent corporate loans as well as CLOs. And if you follow this to the market they are trading in the low 90s for the most part &#x2013; some of them mid 90s. The numbers are a part of our overall CDS exposure, which we do disclose. And we give the mark to market, which I don't know that anyone else discloses and that's I know is helpful to you. So we'll take a look at whether we should provide additional granularity, but we have not done that as yet, nor has anyone else disclosed as I know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, can I just ask a follow up on that. If you have a receivable of 855, I can't recall if you've taken any valuation adjustment against that, I don't think that you have. Is that to imply that the counterparties that are in your subprime bucket are different or that that 855 is not to any of those counterparties that you have adjusted in the subprime valuation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah Brad, well they are different. I mean as we disclosed, there is 10 of them. We have also disclosed the largest one is quite small of that eight, I think it's in the 200s, so it's quite a disperse group. Indeed, however, the valuation adjustment of 624 we took in the quarter was split. I don't know that we disclosed this, but it's not something I'm uncomfortable disclosing. That 624 is split 516 to the other monoline subprime and 108 to the other monoline non-subprime. Okay, so we have taken a VA, I think I'm right in saying that, am I? Yes. On that to 885, so 885 is the mark, but we've haircut that using the same model approach, but in that it case, applies to a much more disperse group of monolines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, and just lastly, you mentioned that you were using credit spreads guide for these adjustments. And I was just wondering, do all the counterparties have credit spreads or how do you deal with it when they don't?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not all of them do, some are private.  We've, well, let me back up a sec because I'm glad you asked this, this is an important point.  And just for those of you that I know are particularly interested in this, I'll just give you a bit of background here.  Our understanding in working with our external auditors, Ernst and Young, is that given the dramatic blow out in spreads in this space, and the obviously continuing uncertainty about this space, relying on historic default rates as I said in my comments, didn't make sense.  We were very comfortable with that at Q4, the world has changed. And we understand that many of the other international banks are looking very hard at this.  Now their quarter end lags ours, so time will tell.  But based on the information we have from our auditors, this is the right thing to do and as I said in my comments, it results in a greater evaluation adjustment. We haven't strictly relied on credit default spreads.  We've looked at a number of models and we've sort of triangulated. But the credit default spread market or method is the method that's the most dominant in this.</p>
          <p>In the case of a couple of the monolines which are private, we have used a proxy.  But for the most part, we had enough public or enough that had public spread to make this method supportable and have integrity. And you know, it will be the method that we will likely use going forward, until such time as this space reverts back, if it does, to what we've seen in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, that's very helpful, thank you, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question will be from Michael Goldberg of Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, I've got a few questions. The first one is, just from your slide number 5, and you note in there, among the noted items, significant tax related items, what are those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike, it's Tom.  The main one, and this is a bit complex, but I think you'll grasp it. With the large charge or reserve we had this quarter, we were able to carry back those negative NIBT for tax books purposes in prior quarters when the tax rate was higher, okay. So we got a net P&amp;L pick up because we were able to reduce our taxable income when the tax rate was higher. So we have treated that as an unusual item and therefore adjusted our earnings, in other words, brought them down from what they would otherwise be because our tax rate is lower than it would be in the normal course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then turning to slide 48. You show, looking at the right line, loss on sale of some US businesses and restructuring of $108 million pre-tax.  And you talk about a gain on the disposal of the US investment banking business.  You had indicated that that gain would be in the order of $35 million. You also mentioned I think some 70 million of charges related to the sale.  Can you help to put those &#x2013; the 35, the 70 and the 108 together, what else is in there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well the 108 has the 70 in there, okay.  The difference between 108 and 70 is, well, let me back up a step.  The 70 is negative revenue, the 38 is expense.  We combined the two into the 108 there, one's a revenue item, and one's an expense item, okay?  The 35 million, let me just go back and see if I can dig up my notes here, in fact, Michael, let me come back to you on that one.  I have it here somewhere, but rather than hold the group up, I'll come back to you on that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and my last question is just if you could give us some comments about your prognosis for the monolines, particularly with respect to some of the ideas that have been floated about the banks investing in them, particularly banks that have exposure for the monolines.  It seems to me that that's boot straps?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's Ron Lalonde, I was going to comment on that.  I actually think it's premature to speculate as to what the outcome of the monolines will be and we are relying for the most part on the same information that you have access to.  So it's difficult to judge where that will end up.  We're certainly monitoring the situation very closely and participating where we're able to participate, but I wouldn't want to speculate as to where these restructurings go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, the next question will be from Greg Boland of West Base Capital, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. I had a quick question of the 624 valuation adjustments. I guess if I just look at the delta between this and your January, early January press release, it appears that there's been a negative variance on Ambac of $293 million. And I guess if I want to sort of break down the 624 valuation adjustment I would assume that roughly half of it would have been a result of the negative variance on Ambac. If I look at number one in your break down of the USRMM related counterparties, that notional amount of 2.6 billion. I presume given the rating and the size that, that would have to be SCA whose obligations are trading $0.85 on the dollar. So is it fair to assume that 624 is predominantly an adjustment for Ambac, roughly half for Ambac and half for an adjustment of that other large A minus rated counterparty?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Greg, it's Tom. We've given lots of disclosure on this. I am not inclined to give granularity by monoline. In fact, we have as we said in our disclosure confidentiality agreements with each of our monoline counterparties. Now we've disclosed the ratings and those ratings, obviously, have changed quite a bit from Q4, so it probably doesn't take much to figure out that, but I can't really get info name by name. I mean you can draw your own conclusions given the transparency we've now provided and given the fact that spreads are quite public. But I can't really go any further than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just a couple of quick follow-ups then, on the non-subprime counterparties, I guess you have said that you are somehow incorporating CDS spreads into the derivation of the value of the, the fair value of the derivative contracts. I guess that would imply that since there is credit risk in all them, that all of the non-subprime counterparties must be pay-as-you-go monolines and you're not receiving any collateral with respect to those <mark type="audio gap" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sorry, go ahead...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, if not all, substantially all, because otherwise the credit risk would be deminimus if you had real time...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well just to be clear. I mean we've got as every bank does lots of exposure to credit derivatives with collateral posting banks, insurance companies, and monolines.  What we're talking about here in the 885 is just the monolines, okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to the former, because they are providing collateral.  I mean, there may be an unusual case where there's a deminimus amount of VA taken.  But in the monoline space, you're right.  I mean it's that space that we're taking the VAs.  And we're now taking it on a basis that relies primarily on CDS spreads in the market as the input to the accounting calculation in the same way as we're doing it for the monoline protection on subprime because both are receivables, the underlying are dramatically different.  But it's the receivable that we're treating in a consistent fashion in both cases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  And just a final question on the non-RMBS collateral being primarily loan related products.  The whole loan LCDX is trading in the low 90s.  My understanding is the majority of your exposure is through super senior tranches or tranches that have some degree of subordination that would be in excess of 20 or 30%.  Just sort of with the mark-to-market seems a little high given those trenches.  I wasn't aware that those tranches were trading at $0.96 on the dollar.  I thought they would have been trading a little deeper than that.  Where do you get the mark-to-market on these given that probably a lot of this is vispoke?  Do you have individual quotes?  Or are you using the LCDX as a proxy?  Or is this just mark to model, or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we're getting quotes where we can.  In other cases, in the vispoke situations we are interpolating using proxies.  And as to your subordination comment, I mean it sounds as if you're quite familiar with this space.  I mean it really varies on the investment grade side, obviously the subordination is lower and could be as low as 15%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What do you think your &#x2013; what's your weighted average subordination?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that's not something we've gotten into.  But these are conventional market deals.  So in that we haven't gone beyond a mark-to-market, it's sort of academic to get into what a hypothetical subordination weighted average is.  But this is a mix of marketed deals.  Investment grade deals would have probably 15 to 30%, 15 to 25, and the CLOs would have &#x2013; what, Jeff, 20 to...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>20 to 40.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>20 to 40.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  And what's the logic for not being more granular on the non-subprime monoline counterparties, if you've given that granularity on the sub-prime side already?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as I said to Brad right at the beginning, I mean it's an entirely different space.  It's a question of where do you stop.  We've tried to provide as much as transparency as we can and or should.  If this continues to be something that people feel they need to properly assess us. I mean I would have thought the mark-to-market is what you need.  There's no other bank that's providing this that I'm aware of, but it's something we'll continue to look at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  I guess and also I've stated before in person, I think the overhang of the uncertainty does affect your cost to capital because people always assume the worst and probably there   it's a pretty decent sum</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think you'd agree though Greg I mean this space is dramatically different than the real estate space.  So I mean certainly in my discussions with analysts and investors, while it's become a point of interest. I don't know that it's quite a point of interest as the way you've characterized in terms of effecting our cost.  But we'll take your feedback and I appreciate that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks a lot for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question will be from Mario Mendonca of Genuity Capital.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.  Tom, there is some disclosure the bank has provided on, it relates to $6.5 billion in total return swaps with embedded put options and that number has gone down from 6.5 to 2 billion from the end of October to now.  I guess that ties in with comments you made about taking some assets on the books at par from third party structured vehicles.  What I'm trying to understand is what assets are you taking on and is this just part of the disclosure you've already provided or is this incremental?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, Mario, it's Tom.  It's already in the, I mean there's some RMBS in there and there's some non-RMBS and the RMBS component is included in the 7.9.  This was used or these vehicles were used strictly as funding vehicles originally.  In one case, it appeared as if there would be challenges in that vehicle with funding so we decided let's just take it on our books and we took I think that piece was 2 billion.  We've taken it all on.  The other 4.5 billion was funding satisfactorily but it wasn't clear that it could continue funding.  So for certainty on our part, we took it on our books.  Because we had total return swaps originally and now we have the hard assets, we're in no different a position on that side of the trade.  We have credit derivative protection on the other side.  In some cases with monolines and other cases with collateral posting FI's.  So there's no difference at all from a risk point of view, it's only incremental funding that is the difference.  But just for greater certainty, we took it on our books.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The 2 billion you just referred to, you were referring to subprime number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's a mix.  That's 6.5 and I don't have the numbers handy.  It is a mix.  Some of it's, it's a number of assets.  Some of it is subprime and some of it is not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The reason I'm confused is you said its part of the 7.9; the 7.9 is subprime.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, okay.  Let me take a step back.  A component of the 6.5 is subprime and that component is part of the 7.9 in so far as there are monoline counterparties opposite it if you follow me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I do now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Now the other thing, I'm afraid that I have and I think others have spoken with inappropriate authority about the notional value tied to that original 750 million because I've written on several occasions that that's in excess of $20 billion.  And when I've done that I did that with confidence because that's what I understood from the bank specifically.  So in not answering Brad's question, have I been mistaken in referring to $20 billion plus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well as I said, that amount is embedded in the some 85 billion of total CDS.  Okay?  I'm not quite sure when you say you've obtained this information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll be very clear.  The banks confirmed it, so I'm just not sure why, that's what I heard from the bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well why don't you and I talk afterwards.  We have not published that number.  There's nothing particularly sensitive about it I mean as I said to both Brad and Greg, we're trying to follow consistent disclosure policies here.  This paper as I was saying to Greg and as I think he agreed, depending on the quality of the paper, is trading in low to mid 90's.  You can do your own calculations.  We're just cautious about being consistent in our disclosure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If it's trading in the low to mid 90's though, Tom that would imply a far greater mark than $888 million though, applied to the notional that I just referred to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, some of it's trading there.  It's not all trading there.  It's a mix of CLO, corporate loan and there's a tiny amount of CMBS, a tiny amount.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.  This one doesn't come from me.  This comes from a client.  So I'll just prefix with that.  This person wants to know why this wasn't disclosed in detail prior to the issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why, what wasn't disclosed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The 20 billion plus notional hedge of monolines prior to the bank issuing $2 billion of equity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mario as I've just said, we disclosed, we're the only bank that I'm aware of in a space that's fairly commoditized to disclose the mark-to-market. Now you know and I know and we've been around long enough to know that at the margin there will always be a desire for yet further discloser. I've taken the point from you and from Greg and from Brad, that this is helpful information, we will think about it. In terms of materiality it's embedded in the 85 billion of CDS we've given the mark-to-market and market participants know where these things are trading at. I can't imagine that anyone would think that's a particularly material number. You and others have written it with estimates that are actually very close to one another. So, I mean I can give you more information on that. What we are trying to do is be fairly consistent with the amount of disclosure we provide, and we've taken some comfort that we've given more disclosure on this point than others. So, I'm happy to have the discussion with you further, but we are very comfortable with the extent of our disclosure on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, I think the bar for disclosure gets higher and higher as the charges get higher and higher, I think that's the point this investor is trying to make, but I appreciate your comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, no, I appreciate that point and I would be happy to talk further with you or your investor client, Mario.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question will be from Andre Hardy of RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Again going back to the non-residential mortgage hedges and I suspect that the Q4 mark-to-market or fair value was very small otherwise we would have had disclosure. Then we got disclosure of a 750 million mark, January, sorry, end of December and then 885. Now what's interesting is the LCDX index would have gone from 250 roughly in terms of spreads, October 31st to 300 as of December 31st and now 400. So can you help me understand and maybe I made an incorrect assumption assuming that this was close to zero October 31st. But it seems like a small move in spreads had a much larger impact on the fair value of these hedges then did 100 basis point increase in January?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, yes Andre, because this is a mix of different assets you can't just extrapolate based on the CDX and I don't know what else I can say other than we've got a diverse amount of exposures here. We've got pricing from market sources on them. Obviously ones that are CDX directly related would follow the pattern that you've referred to, but in the same way that our RMBS portfolio doesn't match with the ABX and indeed the hedges we've put on, you know you see volatility quarter-to-quarter on that. So directionally what you are seeing is consistent and I tell you as I'm sure you know that in February that the CDX is increased again. So we haven't done the February month end but if we were to do it today that 885 would be well up and we will do it at the end of Q2. But there is not a direct correlation because this is a diversified amount of corporate bespoke and CDX and CLO for that matter position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and my other question is on asset backed commercial paper, can you update us on what's going on with Great North Trust please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's Ron Lalonde, there are no material development certainly impacting our financial statements there, we remain the swap provider there add we remain well collateralized in that position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that hasn't come back on your books?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it has not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question will be from Ian de Verteuil of BMO Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, page 7 of the press release, so if I look at the value of the derivative contracts and exclude counterparty fix, which obviously I would deduce to be a CA, or is a CA. Beyond, so excluding that there is 2.6 billion of in the money derivative exposure, in the money exposure to the top four monolines. Am I correct in saying that 2.6 is in notional you have written down 516, and that you also have credit hedges of 525 which in theory would operate exactly opposite to how you would book valuation adjustment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, certainly directionally that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is it reasonable to say that there is a billion six of remaining exposure RMBS counterparty exposure to monolines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, give or take Ian I guess, I don't know is that 525, yes, directionally that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The second question page 32 of the sub part. The risk ratings on the derivatives because of Basel II I think you've moved from giving growth and then the net, impact of the master netting, actually allocating it across.  I guess what I'm trying to get here is consistency or a timeline, Tom.  When you look at the risk rated amount of the credit derivatives, if we did them sort of apples-to-apples, would they be up or down from Q3 and Q4?  Do you see what I'm getting at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I see what you're getting at.  I don't have a good answer for you right now, Ian.  Does anybody here have a good answer?  No, I'm getting a lot of nods here Ian, so, heads shaking so let us come back to you on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question will be from Sumit Malhotra of Merrill Lynch.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.  Last quarter we talked a little bit about the real estate finance operations that you have in your US investment bank.  If I look at the loans disclosure you give us, business and government, non-residential mortgages of 5.8 billion, real estate construction just under 4 billion.  Is this essentially &#x2013; how much of this relates to what you have in the US real estate finance portfolio because I think we were told it's not too much of it that stays on the balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Sumit, it's Tom.  I don't know that we've disclosed this before but I'm not uncomfortable just talking a bit about this.  We've got about 1.9 billion in that business on our balance sheet today and we've got no or essentially no CMBS mark-to-market.  We've got &#x2013; and this is a business as most of you know or maybe all of you know is a very successful origination business in the commercial mid-market space.  Generally, typically loans 10 to $20 million that we would put into a conduit with one of the big New York banks.  That market as you know has slowed up considerably.  We did a small transaction this quarter but the outlook for the year is pretty slow.  The fixed rate stuff is fully hedged or as fully hedged as can be for both interest rate and credit rate with the CMBX index.  The floating rate is in an accrual book but it is generally very low loan-to-value ratio so we're not concerned about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, just to make sure we're on the same page here. Those two categories in the loan portfolio that I referenced, real estate related business and government loans just under 10 billion.  So you're saying about 2 billion of that 1.9 I think you said relates to US real estate finance.  The rest is &#x2013; can I take it to be Canadian commercial real estate exposure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'm not with you, Sumit, on a page but I would believe that to be the case, yes.  I'm getting an agreement here, so that's correct.  The rest would be our Canadian small business, commercial banking exposure to the commercial real estate sector.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let's switch over to retail markets for a second.  Tom this might be for you, it might be for Sonia.  Last quarter, we heard about the mortgage in personal lending.  There were some issues with your securitization hedges.  I think you had talked about that number bouncing back in a big way, obviously prime VA didn't move maybe as much as was anticipated.  What's going on with the hedge activity you have there because considering your volume growth it doesn't look like that number moved very much.  It's still well down from the previous quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there is a lot of volatility in that number.  I thought where you were going was on the &#x2013; and maybe this is of some interest to plain vanilla mortgage revenue.  We've really in an effort to help you all understand what the main mortgage business versus the volatility we've moved all of the securitization stuff down into below the line.  So, and that continues to be fairly volatile just because of the nature of the way we have to mark-to-market to sell a swap in these deals and while one might say well why bother if it's providing all that volatility. As you know, the CMBS &#x2013; or CMHC program is very attractive financing.  We attempt to hedge that as best we can but a lot of those hedges still don't meet the test for hedge effectiveness.  We're working to try and improve that but we're just going to have some volatility from an accounting point quarter-to-quarter.  You know as far as the main mortgage business, I know last quarter I did say that we expected that revenue to go up from Q4, it didn't go up, it went to &#x2013; well actually the mortgage component went up a little.  The personal lending component went down, the combined number was down a bit and that's basically due to slightly higher costs of funding, slightly lower pre-payment.  Prime VA was better than it was in Q4 but not as good as we had been anticipating based on how tight it was in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, maybe lastly for Sonia.  Credit cards, wealth management, two historical strengths of CIBC, I am not really seeing that right now.  Credit cards you've been talking for a few quarters now about some of the highest balance activity or activity rates that you've seen but you know is this just a reflection of spreads?  When does this start to affect the revenue line?  I'd say the same thing on wealth management.  You talked about the fund flows but you did reference most of it is money market.  So we're seeing mutual fund revenue essentially flat.  Is this, as long as markets stay weak are we not expecting anything much here or?  I don't see how the conversions mandate can progress until these two big areas for the bank start to move I guess I'd just like to get your thoughts on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well on the, we did have, on credit cards first of all.  We had great growth in our credit card portfolio.  We had revenues up.  The one impact to our credit card portfolio much like the entire market was an increase in our cost of funds.  But I think that was well offset by both the growth in our portfolio as well as the improvements in our loss rate so very comfortable with the growth on that front.  On the mutual fund side certainly given the market as we talked about in mutual funds, we have had some challenges in 2007.  The environment is such that most of the sales industry wide were in money market so that's where we did particularly well.  We've made a number of changes to our products so as the environment improves, we would expect to continue to see improvements in that area.  The other part of the wealth management business that we have not shown the growth that we might have otherwise hoped was on the brokerage side and again, that was market driven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our last question will be from Robert Sedran of National Bank Financial.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.  Good afternoon.  Just Tom, I want to take you back to slide 14 for a second and I'm looking at these ratios and as you mentioned there, a spot in time.  If we go out over the course of the year presumably you could take five or even more billion worth of charges to and still stay above your even target let alone regulatory minimums.  Was the goal of the equity issue largely to insulate you from worst case scenario and do you think you've done that?  And you don't sound terribly concerned about the non-residential side so do you think basically that your balance sheet now is in a position where you're comfortable that you're not going to need any more support even under any kind of a reasonable worst case scenario?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well Rob, I guess what I would say is we've provided, stats by the bond rating, breakdown of our sub-prime exposure, right now a lot of transparency and we can make judgments.  You can make judgments in terms of that.  The fact of the matter is no one really knows where this space is going to settle out.  As I said in my annual meeting presentation this morning, you look at the CIM loss rate imputed by prices in this space that we're basing our marks no, and they're at such extreme levels.  One might be tempted to say that we're at the bottom or very close and it's going to swing back as hedge fund money starts to come in to buy here.  But we're not trying to do that.  We concluded, and Gerry, I don't know whether you want to make any comments.  In January just with the uncertainty, we wanted to have the comfort that, that size of equity issue would bring.  You can see the sensitivity analysis that we provide there but where the market ultimately settles in, you can make your judgments.  We can make our judgments.  What this shows is even at a very extreme case, we still have a very strong capital structure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Gerry here.  One of the things that &#x2013; when we were deciding on the size and whether or not we would do a capital rate, we did weigh up just earning our weight through this issue versus a capital raise.  We concluded that we wanted to do a capital raise for greater certainty so we can have a capital cushion but also be very competitive in the business environment.  And the other element was when we came to &#x2013; after we had decided to do the raise when it came to the size of the raise, we considered the general environment as the important unknown out there.  In terms of our own position, that was only part of the consideration.  Another part of the consideration was the fact that during the month of December, there was a considerable amount of &#x2013; there was really a sea change in terms of a sense of the environment and the fact that we could be in a slower economy this year.  Again, there's many economists out there with many opinions but we decided that we were going to go the route of providing more cushion rather than less.  I know there is a risk that there is a possibility that we may have raised too much capital here and that that would have been dilutive.  But we think that on balance, given the uncertainty in the environment that the size was the right size to raise and to err on the side of caution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  At this time, I'd like to return the meeting back to Mr. John Ferren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks everyone.  If you have any further questions, the investor relations staff will be around for a while tonight.  So thank you and have a good night.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>