<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1312954" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-08-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1564</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John G. Langille, Vice-Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Allan P. Markin, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Steve W. Laut, President</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Peter J. Janson, Senior Vice-President, Horizon Operations</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Douglas A. Proll, Chief Financial Officer and Senior Vice-President of Finance</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">John G. Langille, Vice Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Andrew Fairbanks</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Arjun Murti</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Greg Pardy</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Amir Arif</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">H. Monroe Helm, III</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">John Herrlin</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the Canadian Natural Resources 2010 second quarter results conference call. I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. John Langille, Vice Chairman of Canadian Natural Resources. Please go ahead, Mr. Langille.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Operator, and good morning, everyone. Thank you for attending our conference call. We will discuss our 2010 second quarter results and also update our plans for the balance of 2010. Participating with me today are Allan Markin, our Chairman; Steve Laut, our President; Peter Janson, our Vice President of Horizon Operations; and Doug Proll, our Senior Vice President of Finance.</p>
          <p>Before we start, I would refer you to the comments regarding forward-looking information contained in our press release. I'd also note that all dollar amounts are in Canadian dollars, and production and reserves are both expressed as before royalties, unless otherwise stated.</p>
          <p>Our second quarter cash flow reflects the strong quarter we had, as we achieved over $1.6 billion of cash flow with higher production and very efficient control of our costs. Again our cash flow exceeded our capital expenditures in this quarter, and our CapEx was inflated with a number of acquisitions amounting to approximately $900 million, all closing in this quarter. We are allocating the majority of our capital to oil projects as we go forward.</p>
          <p>Commodity prices for our oil production continued to be volatile, but the average West Texas price remained relatively flat in the second quarter with that realized in the first quarter. However, as expected, the heavy oil differential widened slightly in the quarter to an average of 18% off WTI. Natural gas pricing continues to be challenged, and averaged less than $4 during the quarter. We expect this relative pricing situation to continue during the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>This quarter really shows the tremendous balance in our portfolio of oil assets, with all four types producing at or near 100,000 barrels per day and contributing almost 70% of our total production volumes.</p>
          <p>Light oil from Canada and our international areas averaged 116,000 barrels a day, cold heavy oil from our primary production area and Pelican Lake averaged 131,000 barrels per day. Our thermal heavy oil averaged 96,000 barrels per day, and our heavy oil mined at Horizon, which is sold as high value SCO, averaged 100,000 barrels per day.</p>
          <p>Our natural gas properties, at over 200,000 BOEs, contributed the remaining 30% of our production. So a very, very balanced portfolio. However, our oil sales contributed 86% of our total revenue and oil projects continue to be the preferential reinvestment area.</p>
          <p>Before we turn the call over to Steve for the operating details, I would ask Allan to make some comments. Allan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. Good morning, everyone. I'm not sure if I can add anything from John's great start. But as I've said many times, Canadian Natural's balanced asset base allows us to add value in any business cycle. The efficiency of our operations has allowed us to drop our costs in most sectors of the company and thus, as John mentioned, enhance cash flows.</p>
          <p>Daily production increased 6% quarter-over-quarter. Spending money wisely, and excellent and good operating practices, has allowed higher than expected volumes, especially as, on the primary heavy oil side, record drilling has reaped great returns.</p>
          <p>Primrose thermal volumes achieved record highs. Soon the Kirby thermal project will achieve regulatory approval. Horizon volumes were and are increasing, with some hiccups that more proactive maintenance will solve.</p>
          <p>Light oil internationally continues to achieve strong cash flows, especially at current oil prices. We remain committed to growing value through the drill bit and acquisitions, with efficient, solid operating and financial performance. Over to you, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Al, and good morning, everyone. Canadian Natural is in a very enviable position. Our strong, well-balanced assets combined with our capital discipline, focus on execution and effective operations has again delivered a very strong quarter. And that performance is reflected in the stunning results or outstanding results in four key indicators: production, operating costs, capital costs and free cash flow.</p>
          <p>Production was up 10% over Q2 2009 and 6% over the first quarter of 2010, with oil production up 21% over Q2 2009 and, more importantly, 9% over Q1 2010 driving that overall volume growth. Canadian Natural continues to benefit from the decision to allocate capital towards the oil portion of our portfolio versus our gas portfolio.</p>
          <p>Operating costs are down 13.5% on a BOE basis over Q2 2009 and 10% from Q1 2010. This is driven by a significant decrease in conventional and thermal oil operating costs in Canada, down 17% year-to-date versus 2009, as well as a strong operating quarter at Horizon with operating costs at 32.27 a barrel, near the low-end of our guidance.</p>
          <p>Gas operating costs are also down slightly, which in itself is a very impressive achievement, as we choose to let gas production volumes decline in this low price environment. Capital spending is on track, and in fact we have lowered our capital spending guidance for 2010 by roughly $150 million as we optimize capital spending and capture efficiencies on the Horizon capital program.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow generation is strong, and we are on track to generate between 1.7 and $2.2 billion of free cash flow in 2010.</p>
          <p>It is clear that Canadian Natural's assets are strong and well balanced. We are increasing production, dropping op costs, reducing capital spending and setting Canadian Natural up for significant value growth, while at the same time generating significant free cash flow. Few if any of our peer group is in as strong a position as Canadian Natural is going forward.</p>
          <p>Turning in more detail asset by asset, firstly gas in Canada. Canadian Natural has the largest land base in Western Canada. We dominate the land base and the infrastructure in our core areas. As a result, we are low-cost producer and are able to withstand a prolonged period of low gas prices.</p>
          <p>Our gas land base is very well positioned, with strong assets and teams in conventional, foothills, resource and unconventional plays. Canadian Natural has, over the last four years, been quietly transforming the make-up of our gas portfolio, with 60% of our large gas drilling inventory made up of resource and unconventional play types, with only 27% of the inventory from conventional play types, a fact not well understood by the Street, as we have been historically viewed as a very efficient conventional gas player. Our Montney gas development is one example of our unconventional asset base.</p>
          <p>We have completed our 2010 joint program, with 13 wells drilled. Costs have been excellent, coming in 20% less than expected. Completion and flow-back on these wells has just begun. The first well looks strong, with early rates in excess of 10 million cubic feet a day at 1,000 pounds wellhead pressure, as expected.</p>
          <p>Our plan at Septus is complete. We have to complete the first phase of development this year and bring on 50 million cubic feet a day of gas by yearend. We believe Septus can deliver 200 million cubic feet a day when we elect to bring on future developments in the future.</p>
          <p>Turning to oil in Canada, Canadian Natural has a dominant heavy oil and thermal oil position in Canada. As you've heard me say before, we believe our heavy oil and thermal assets are the hidden gem in our portfolio. Heavy and thermal oil are delivering significant value today and our disciplined cost-effective development program is adding tremendous value in the future, something we believe is not fully appreciated by the Street.</p>
          <p>Our thermal assets alone have 33 billion barrels of oil in place and 5.8 billion recoverable in our defined plan. To put that in perspective, 5.8 billion barrels of thermal oil is essentially the same as the 6 billion barrels recoverable at our world-class Horizon operation, a vast amount of oil that will add tremendous value for all Canadian Natural shareholders.</p>
          <p>Our plan to unlock this value targets adding approximately 285,000 barrels a day of heavy oil production in a very disciplined, step-wise, cost-controlled manner and taking total production facility capacity to 405,000 barrels a day, again, very similar to the 500,000 barrels a day we will achieve at Horizon after Phase V.</p>
          <p>In the second quarter we achieved a very strong thermal production performance, and development progress is been good as expected at Primrose North, East and Wolf Lake. Production will average between 80 and 90,000 barrels a day in 2010. And since this is a cyclic process, we will see peaks and troughs of 60 to over 100,000 barrels a day.</p>
          <p>The second quarter saw production for the most part at the high end of the cycle, with production averaging over 96,000 barrels a day, again, not much different from the 99,000 we delivered at Horizon in Q2.</p>
          <p>The surveillance steaming at Primrose East is going very well and exceeding our expectations. We had expected to average between 16 and 20,000 barrels a day in 2010. However, with performance to date, we expect to average closer to 23,000 barrels a day for 2010 as we slowly return to normal steam operations.</p>
          <p>At Kirby, our next thermal project, we expect to receive regulatory approval this summer. We are making good progress on the detailed engineering design work and developing a more detailed cost estimate, with a target of sanctioning Kirby in Q4 2010.</p>
          <p>As you know, we applied for regulatory approval to build the facility at Kirby to 45,000 barrels a day. As part of our ongoing process for maximizing value, we are currently looking to build the Kirby facility to roughly 40,000 barrels a day of initial capacity. We continue to take a very disciplined approach to the engineering construction of Kirby to ensure effective cost control, with first steam targeted for mid-2013. We expect to sanction the Kirby development in Q4 2010.</p>
          <p>At Pelican Lake, we are on track with our program to convert the field to our highly successful polymer flood. By the end of 2010, we will push the Pelican area under polymer flood to 44% for the total pool. As we continue to convert Pelican to polymer flooding, we expect production to reach a plateau rate of roughly 80,000 barrels a day of low-cost production by 2015, roughly double the 39,000 barrels a day produced in Q2.</p>
          <p>It is clear that Pelican Lake is a world-class pool, with 4 billion barrels in place and roughly 561 million barrels of resource recoverable under polymer flood, a very large pool with very robust development economics. Pelican Lake continues to generate significant value for shareholders and generate some of the highest returns in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Our primary heavy oil program continues to roll along effectively and efficiently. In this commodity and cost environment, primary heavy oil generates top-decile returns on capital in our asset portfolio. Importantly, it also generates the quickest payout and largest cash-on-cash return.</p>
          <p>In the first half, we drilled roughly 188 wells, and we will have a busy second half as we drill 600 primary heavy oil wells for the year, a record number of primary wells for Canadian Natural, roughly 25% more than we drilled in 2009. Our dominant, high quality land base, infrastructure, and effective operations allows us to drill this size of program on a very cost-effective basis, making primary heavy oil one of the best value generators in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Turning to the North Sea, production has been strong and exceeded the top end of our guidance for Q2. As planned, we have started up the drill stream in the Ninian Field, with a plan to drill one producing well, one injection well, and complete three well interventions, as well as undertake some sub-sea work on the T-Block and upgrade facilities in all five platforms in 2010.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter we will be undertaking the majority of the planned turnaround work in our platforms. We are well underway and are tracking to plan. As expected, these turnarounds will impact production, and as reflected in our third quarter guidance and full-year guidance, that remains unchanged.</p>
          <p>In Offshore West Africa, at Olowi and Gabon, we have completed the drilling program on the B Platform, with all wells now on-stream. The earlier production results from Platform B looks much better than Platform C and are in line with our expectations. The jack-up rig moved in late July on to Platform A, and drilling is now underway. Platform A first production is target for Q4 2010. Production at Olowi is expected to peak out in the 12,000 barrel a day range.</p>
          <p>In Cote d'Ivoire, production Baobab and Espoir is stable. The Espoir shutdown in Q2 to install additional compression has been completed, with the duration of the production shutdown less than anticipated. And as a result, Offshore West Africa production was at the top end of our guidance for Q2. Production at Espoir will not be totally ramped up until the new facilities are fully commissioned in September. It's important to note that Offshore West Africa has some of the highest return on capital projects in our portfolio, and along with the North Sea, generates significant free cash flow for Canadian Natural.</p>
          <p>Turning to Horizon, we continue to make good progress driving towards sustained reliability. Overall, we are doing well, and I am very happy with our progress, as we gain confidence in our ability to operate the plant reliability (sic) [reliably], as well as our ability to predict the likelihood of upcoming issues.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding our recent amine reach-in unit issues, our decision to proactively take selected planned outages in May was effective and was reflected in the strong June production volumes. There is no question the operation can and has delivered at or above the 110,000 barrels a day of SCO designed capacity.</p>
          <p>The production by month is as follows: April, 101,000 barrels a day: May, 81,400 barrels a day: June, 117,600 barrels a day; and July, with the amine issue, 93,380 barrels a day. Production has been strong, and we are confident in the capacity of the plant and our ability to effectively run the operation. It is, however, very complex and heat innovative plant, and it appears that it may take some time until we are fully optimized and reliable.</p>
          <p>As an example, we had been running very strong for the month of July. However, a small leak in the amine reach-in unit, a critical component of the sulfur plant, resulted in the unexpected discovery of severe pipe wall thinning due to corrosion. Therefore we took immediate steps to shut down the unit, which necessitated a full plant shutdown on July 30. As a result, production for July ended up being below the guidance issued earlier in the week.</p>
          <p>I will turn it over now to Peter Janson to give you a little more detail on this event and also highlight some of the other successes we've had at Horizon Operations. Peter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Steve, and good morning, everyone. Last week, Horizon experienced a leak in the amine plant in one of the overhead piping circuits. We were unsuccessful in attempting to install an engineered clamp, and the decision was made to begin a controlled shutdown on July 30. Extensive inspection of the equipment upstream and downstream of the leak point identified accelerated corrosion, as Steve had mentioned.</p>
          <p>Investigation into the cause is underway, but we currently suspect high concentrations of ammonia compounds as the cause. Revised operating procedures and corrosion monitoring programs will be in effect upon start-up, and that will prevent recurrence once we come up again.</p>
          <p>Our immediate plan is to install piping replacements this coming weekend, along with some pipe sleeves for the heat exchangers just upstream of the leak. This event will continue to be investigated to ensure we haven't overlooked similar or related applications at Horizon. We expect to be back in production by the middle of next week.</p>
          <p>And during this outage, we have but forward some planned maintenance activities that were planned at the end of August and September such as pigging, screen change in the ore processing plant and shovel maintenance. And this will allow us to minimize production limitations for the balance of August and September.</p>
          <p>The Horizon management team has demonstrated our commitment to sustain both production, with examples such as the improvements in hydro transport and tailing pipeline reliability, where we experienced zero leaks in Q2. And we've reduced the sulfur plant restrictions, thereby achieving a new stream-day record of 131,000 barrels in this past quarter.</p>
          <p>Back to you, Steve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Peter. As you can see, we're on top of the issues, and we're taking all of the necessary steps to set us up for increased reliability and performance going forward. I don't know if you heard it, but Peter did mention that we did hit a record of 131,000 barrels a day stream-day rate. This tells you the capacity of the plant when everything lines up.</p>
          <p>Operating costs for Q2 are very good at $32.27 a barrel, near the bottom end of our guidance. On the sustaining capital side, we are doing very well. We have reduced the sustaining capital for 2010 by $40 million, as we gain a better understanding of the work capacity of our equipment. This is a complex plant and will take some time to fully optimize.</p>
          <p>Going forward, our ops teams believe that they can achieve lower operating costs, not just from higher production levels, but more effective operations. Although we're not there yet, we see many opportunities to further improve performance.</p>
          <p>Horizon is a world-class asset, with over 6 billion barrels of recoverable oil. We have targeted increased production through Phases 2 and 3 to 232,000 barrels a day and future expansions in Phase 4 and 5 to just under 500,000 barrels a day, or 0.5 million barrels a day of light sweet crude, with no declines for 40 years, and virtually no reserve replacement costs.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we continue to complete work on Tranches 2 of our Phase 2/3 expansion. As you can see from our guidance, we have reduced the capital spending on Horizon by roughly 150 million, in part due to reduced capital required in 2010 for Tranche 2.</p>
          <p>Changes in design allowed us to achieve some scope reduction, as well as some lower material costs and construction costs have also been realized in 2010. In addition, we have moved some work into 2011, with the expectation that we will be able to optimize construction execution.</p>
          <p>Our detailed lessons learned from Phase 1 is on track, and we'll incorporate any cost reduction effectiveness measures into future expansions. Along with this work, we will complete significant engineering work on future expansions and prepare a more detailed cost estimate.</p>
          <p>It is our expectation that we will have a more detailed cost estimate around yearend 2010 and a better understanding of any modifications we make to our execution strategy. This work will be completed to give better certainty on costing in various environments.</p>
          <p>Canadian Natural is committed to the expansion of Horizon to 232,000 barrels a day and ultimately just under 500,000 barrels a day of light sweet 34 degree API oil. As always, Canadian Natural is very focused on cost control and creating value for shareholders. And we will be sanctioning the expansion of Horizon, but only when we can be assured that reasonable cost certainty can be achieved.</p>
          <p>It is clear that Canadian Natural is in a very strong and enviable position. Horizon is a world-class asset that is and will continue to add tremendous value to our shareholders. Our thermal heavy oil assets can add value similar in magnitude to Horizon, yet in more manageable sizes, and in my opinion are the hidden gem in our portfolio, and in this low gas price environment, generate even greater value for shareholders. Our light oil assets, both internationally and in Canada, as well as our primary heavy oil assets in Canada, continue to generate strong returns.</p>
          <p>And in this low gas price environment, our strategy of maintaining a well-balanced portfolio, and the fact that we are the low cost producer, will ensure that we will be able to withstand a sustained period of low gas prices.</p>
          <p>Our teams are strong throughout the company, and as Doug will point out, our balance sheet is strong and getting stronger. We have a very flexible capital program, giving Canadian Natural the ability not only to maximize the value of our well-balanced portfolio, but also capture any opportunities that present themselves in this environment.</p>
          <p>Canadian Natural is in a great position. And in today's environment, with our team, our strategy, and our assets, I believe Canadian Natural is better positioned than ever before to generate significant value for shareholders.</p>
          <p>With that, I will turn it over to Doug to update you on our financial position and our prudent financial management. Doug?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Steve, and good morning. The second quarter and first half of 2010 produced a number of financial highlights for Canadian Natural. In the first half, Canadian Natural is very profitable, generating net earnings of $1.5 billion or $1.41 per share. We generated cash flow from operations of 3.1 billion of $2.88 per share. In the same period we incurred capital expenditures of 2.6 billion, resulting in free cash flow of $500 million. As the company continues to generate free cash flow, this excess was applied to debt reduction. At June 30, our long-term debt was 9.3 billion, resulting in a debt to book capitalization ratio of 31% and debt to EBITDA of 1.3 times.</p>
          <p>Our second quarter oil production, as you heard previously, increased to 443,000 barrels per day, and our barrels of equivalent production increased to over 649,000 barrels per day. These increases are spread across a product mix representing five categories of oil production from heavy to light and synthetic crude oil, plus natural gas. This bodes very well as we enter the second half of the year with oil prices exceeding US$80 WTI per barrel and WCS differentials remaining narrow. This is also reflective of our asset diversification across several product lines and geographically. In addition, our product net-backs are very good as we continue to focus on cost control.</p>
          <p>Our commodity hedging program is used to underpin our cash flow for the purposes of securing our capital expenditure program. The outstanding positions are detailed in the financial statements and are posted on our website. For the remainder of 2010, we have 200,000 barrels per day of oil hedged with WTI price collars, with floors ranging from US$60 to $70 per barrel.</p>
          <p>We also have 620,000 GJs per day of natural gas production for the third quarter and 220,000 GJs per day hedged in the fourth quarter, with AECO floors of Canadian $6.00 on 220,000 GJs for the second half of 2010 and 4.50 on 400,000 GJs per day for the third quarter.</p>
          <p>As a final note, on August 3, Standard &amp; Poor's affirmed their reading of Canadian Natural's long-term corporate debt and senior unsecured debt as BBB, however, raised its outlook to Positive from Stable with a view to upgrading the company in the near future. We see this as a positive development confirming our own assessment that our company has repositioned itself for the future in terms of assets and production diversification, its people and the strength they bring to the table, and our balance sheet strength.</p>
          <p>We are positioned to grow profitably through the exploitation of our strong assets and a deep inventory of opportunities and the ability to allocate capital in a very disciplined manner. Thank you and I will return you to John for some closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Doug, Peter and Steve, for an excellent review of our operations. I think you can see that the diversity of our production sources, all developed with very high working interests and efficient systems to control costs, will continue to deliver tremendous value to our shareholders through the rest of this year and for many, many years to come.</p>
          <p>With that, Operator, I would open up the conference call to questions that people may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question is from Andrew Fairbanks from Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, guys. Just had a couple of cost questions for you. First, you ran really well at Horizon in June. I don't know if you have a rough estimate for what the operating costs were, just for the month of June. And then the second question would be outside of Horizon, are there particular areas you think that you can generate the biggest wins in terms of being able to reduce or restrain cost inflation, as that, looks like it's picking up a bit going forward, i.e. would it be drilling efficiency, service company JVs, maintenance programs that are particular areas that you think are worth while to spend a lot of effort on to try and keep costs in line going forward? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, it's Steve here. Thanks for the good question. So operating costs, although we're not fully detailed on June yet, we're in that 29 to 29.50 range a barrel. So looking pretty strong, and as I said earlier and I think probably Peter mentioned as well, we do believe we can do better. And we're going to work on that, although we can't promise that, we believe we've got opportunities to do better.</p>
          <p>As far as costing goes, we do see a little bit of inflation out there as activity picks up. For us, what we see the best thing for us to drop costs, and what's worked very well for us in the past and continues to work for us, is to be better planned. Do more engineering on the capital projects, the more engineering we can do up front, the more flexibility we can have in how we contract construction. As far as drilling and completion work over operations, the better planned and the more I'll say larger programs, we have basically a series of wells strung together that are all very similar, we drive costs down that way. So it's all about planning, it's all about engineering and being prepared and using the best technology.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's great. Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Arjun Murti from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just to somewhat follow up on the cost question, related more to maintenance CapEx. You're still trying to work through things at Horizon, just curious if you have an estimate of what maybe the ongoing maintenance CapEx will be for Phase 1, once thing settle down a bit, maybe on an annual basis? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we look at maintenance capital, there is two parts to that. Part of it's in the operating costs going forward, and we believe we'll be in that say post 2010, in that 30 to $35 a barrel range on operating costs. The other part is in sustaining capital, and we believe we are in the 4 to $5 a barrel range. We're probably a little less than that this year. But as things wear out, that should increase, and that will be lumpy. There will be times when we'll have to buy a bunch of trucks and shovels as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. On the 30 and 35, Steve, does that include the natural gas costs as part of that, or is that just the cash cost ex-net gas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That includes the gas costs as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Including net gas, fantastic. I think Doug gave an update on the hedging program for this year. Just curious on the plans for 2011 and beyond, obviously with Horizon you have a stronger free cash component, you've got a stronger balance sheet. Do you still plan to utilize I guess in particular oil hedging, or would the plan be to be less hedged going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as you know, our hedging policy is 60% for the near 12 months and 40% for the period going out following that, up to 24 months. And I think what you'll see is us continuing on with the near-term hedges. We are reviewing our hedge policies or our hedge program for 2011 at the current time, and I suspect where WTI prices are today, that you will see us engage in further collars into the fall as we move closer to 2011.</p>
          <p>As for periods farther out than the initial then 2012, I think we'll be more conservative on that perspective from a point of putting on hedges. And we'll wait and see how we do with the 2011 budget, as well as the Kirby and Horizon sanctioning and other projects that may come up during that time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Arjun, to add to that is that obviously we have very strong position and a lot of free cash flow. Our need to hedge is not as strong as it was in the past. So our balance sheet is very strong and our cash flow is also very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Greg Pardy from RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. Good morning. Couple of questions, maybe just with Horizon and Tranche 2. So by, once that's completed, I think that was a 5 to 15,000 barrel a day increment. So are we sort of talking 125, 130,000 barrels a day of capacity at Horizon next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think next year that won't happen. Obviously Tranche 2 is not fully done until 2012 and some of it's in 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And a lot of that's reliability, Greg. So the big part of Tranche 2 is the third OPP [Ore Preparation Plant], which will give us higher reliability and less downtime for screen change-outs and issues like that with the OPP. And as we get farther into the mine, you have to truck farther. And so you need that third OPP to ensure you have efficiencies and low operating costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for that. And then, Steve, you've talked quite a bit about Kirby. Could you characterize it a little bit just in terms of the SORs that you'd expect when that settles down? And I don't know whether or not you're prepared to talk about capital intensity at this stage. And then beyond that, I think plans had been with Grouse. You've got another 60,000 coming on potentially in 2014. Any detail around that would be great as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think the SORs overall we look to be in that 3 to 3.4 range at Kirby. And as far as capital intensity goes, I think we're going to wait until we get the detailed cost estimate, but I don't see any surprises coming.</p>
          <p>As far as Grouse, it looks like it will be the next in the hopper, as you say, with 2014 steam-in. We'll continue to evaluate that and look for ways to do that effectively and cost-effectively. But it is next in our sort of conveyor belt or assembly line of projects on the thermal side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, very good. Thanks a lot, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Amir Arif from Stifel. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon, guys. One quick question on the Pelican Lake. I think, Steve, you mentioned that you're going to grow from 40,000 to, was it 80,000 barrels by 2015?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct. 80,000 barrels a day will be the peak or the plateau.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And is that simply as you just keep pushing the polymer flood to other parts of the field?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right. At the end of the year, we'll be 44% of the field under polymer flood. As you know, it takes about 12 to 18 months before you get response and then it ramps up from there. So it will take us to about 2015 until we get most of the pool under polymer flood, and then you're going to have the ramp-up that comes after that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then how long will it plateau before you start getting the decline or fingering or anything coming out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It plateaus for about three to four years and then you come off slowly. I will say, Amir, that's what we expect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But this polymer flood continues to surprise us to the upside. So we could fall off slower, or decline slower, than we expect, but it's too early to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just a question on the maintenance costs at Horizon. I think you touched on this already, but so it's the 3 to 4, or 4 to $5 a barrel that you're thinking on the maintenance? Is that just trucks and shovels, or does that include ongoing maintenance for plant repairs and other stuff as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I will try to be clear here, so we define Horizon costs in three ways. There is the capital cost for projects, ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...there is the day-to-day operating costs, and then the sustaining capital. In that operating costs, there is maintenance where you're replacing equipment, that's to say the tailings pipes that wear out on a normal basis. And then there's sustaining capital to improve like trucks and shovels and other things. So sustaining capital is probably 4 to $5 a barrel, operating costs in that 30 to $35 a barrel, and then capital costs will be what they'll be when we expand. So maintenance capital itself is not defined, or that's not how we define it, we put it in operating costs and sustaining capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anything to add to that, Peter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's bang-on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Monroe Helm from Barrow, Hanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. You made some significant acquisitions so far this year. Can you talk about how the acquisition market is looking now and should we expect some additional capital to go to that area over the rest of this year and the first half of 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as acquisitions go, there seems to be a steady amount of acquisition properties that sort of go floating by here in Western Canada and other parts of the world. As you know, we're focused on acquisitions that would occur in our core areas, so we'll look at anything that's in our core area. And I personally think that they're starting to maybe drop off a bit. But I wouldn't be surprised if there's something that makes sense for us that we can see there are synergies with our operations and that we can drop costs, we will make other property acquisitions within our core areas if they make sense. So it could happen. Hopefully that answers your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks for your comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question is from John Herrlin from Societe Generale. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Following up on what Monroe asked, Steve, you said the properties in your release were complementary. Could you give us a sense of where the gas properties were concentrated that you purchased?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks, John, and good to hear from you again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, all those properties were in the northwest Alberta and Northeast BC, towards the deeper part of the basin, the more resource-oriented part of the basin, although a lot of the properties were conventional gas. And I think when you add them all up, probably about 25% oil and 75% gas. But it's in northwest Alberta and northeast BC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Going forward, should we expect this kind of strategy to be continued in terms of not spending current capital dollars on real drilling activity, given the weakness in gas prices? I mean, you've done this in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think you'll see us maintain that. Our concern is gas prices are weak, maybe we've hit the bottom, we're not sure. But we believe shale gas is real, mainly because we have a lot of it ourselves, so we've got a good feel of the viability. And I guess our concern is if gas prices do strengthen, you may see a flood of gas come on the market and then depress prices again so we have sort of a bit of a cycle. So we're not in any hurry to drill gas properties. We don't need to, to add value. We're very balanced, and we're taking a longer-term approach.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You have no real lease expiration issues on anything?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have ongoing expiries, but it's everything we can manage. And we do drill. A lot of our drilling is towards keeping our land, but it's not a big program, it's only 100 wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay. Last one from me is for Doug. With IFRS coming up, are there any potential charges that we should be aware of or costs associated with the conversion or is it too early?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a little bit early. I mean we are getting closer, and I think we've detailed it in the financial statements. But the one area that we know is going to be a non-cash change in stock-based compensation. And that's basically because we have to set up the stock options on a Black-Scholes basis and account for them from that perspective. So higher initial charge, but over the life of the option, they will be the same.</p>
          <p>All of the stuff that we see right now including a move to cash generating units is all non-cash. And I think we are getting closer and maybe have something more to say in that regard later in the year. But this year, we see things unfolding pretty much as expected.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There are no further questions registered at this time. I would like to turn the meeting back over to Mr. Langille.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Operator, and thank you, everyone for tying into our call today. And of course as usual, if you have any further questions, do not hesitate to call us. And we look forward to a great balance of 2010 and many years to come. With that, thank you very much again for attending our call, and have a good day. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, gentlemen. The conference has now ended. Please disconnect your lines at this time. We thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>