<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1217436" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-08</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1564</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John G. Langille, Vice-Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Allan P. Markin, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Steve W. Laut, President and Chief Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">R&#xE9;al J.H. Doucet, Senior Vice-President, Oil Sands</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Douglas A. Proll, Chief Financial Officer and Senior Vice-President, Finance</participant>
      <participant id="6">Andrew Fairbanks</participant>
      <participant id="7">Arjun Murti</participant>
      <participant id="8">Gil Yang</participant>
      <participant id="9">Peter Ogden</participant>
      <participant id="10">Martin Molyneaux</participant>
      <participant id="11">Mark Polak</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.  Welcome to the Canadian Natural Resources 2009 first quarter results conference call.  I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. John Langille, Vice Chairman of Canadian Natural Resources.  Please go ahead, Mr. Langille.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you operator, and good morning everyone. Thank you for attending this conference call.  We will discuss our first quarter results and our outlook for the balance of 2009 which were covered in a press release issued yesterday.  Participating with me today are Allan Markin, our Chairman; Steve Laut, our President and Chief Operating Officer; R&#xE9;al Doucet, our Senior Vice President of Oil Sands; and Doug Proll, our Senior Vice President of Finance.</p>
          <p>Before we start I would refer you to the comments regarding forward-looking information contained in our press release and also note that all dollar amounts are in Canadian dollars and production and reserves are both expressed as before royalties unless otherwise stated.</p>
          <p>As we had anticipated the first quarter was a challenging quarter as we saw very volatile commodity prices with West Texas Intermediate oil prices covering around US$40 and a continuing lowering of natural gas prices throughout North America.</p>
          <p>However with our hedging position backstopping our cash flow, we achieved cash flow very similar to the fourth quarter of 2008 amounting to over $1.5 billion.  This cash flow exceeded our first quarter CapEx which has not generally been the case in the first quarter of a year.  This reflects our focused discipline when allocating capital expenditures to ensure they are driven by value creation.</p>
          <p>Our operating results were within our guidance with overall BOE production dropping from Q1 of '08 but increasing from Q4 of '08.  These changes of course reflect reductions in natural gas production as we allocate less of our CapEx to those properties.  Steve will give a much more detailed update of our operations, but before Steve begins I would ask Allan to make a few comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks John.  Good morning everyone.  It has been a great start to the year for Canadian Natural, as John mentioned in very difficult times, decent oil regimes and very difficult natural gas regimes.  Obviously the highlight of the first quarter was first production of SCO at Horizon, the first step in value creation from this great asset.</p>
          <p>This was followed shortly by the first shipment of SCO into the sales pipeline, heading slowly towards 110,000 barrels per day.  The ramping up of production at Horizon has been going very well as R&#xE9;al will talk about in further detail later on.</p>
          <p>Internationally first production was achieved at our Olowi Field in Offshore Gabon early in the second quarter.  Congratulations to everyone involved in getting this online, heading towards 20 to 25,000 barrels per day.  Also Baobab, offshore C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire has been reclaimed at over 10,000 barrels a day from our recent re-drilling.</p>
          <p>We had a successful North American conventional winter drilling program that was completed well in advance of spring breakup. Congratulations.  For North American liquids, production for the quarter was as in line with expectations and the economics for crude oil projects remain robust in this commodity price environment.  Steve will get into further detail on our North American conventional assets.</p>
          <p>Natural gas drilling was driven by market conditions and as such we have concentrated our efforts on optimizing existing production, building an inventory of high quality prospects and executing a high-graded drilling program with focus on land expiries and drainage issues.  Not a lot of gas drilling, at three or $4 gas and a difficult fiscal regime in Alberta for gas.</p>
          <p>We continue to focus on efficiencies and execution, maximizing the value in every dollar spent in both crude oil and natural gas.  We need to focus on growth in value, not growth in production in these tough times.  We have always worked together and survived together.  Congratulations to our hard working Board of Directors, management and especially our hardworking employees in all facets, conventional, Western Canadian, North Sea, offshore C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire, West Africa and all the hardworking people at Horizon.</p>
          <p>Everyone everywhere at Canadian Natural just take a moment, pause and pat yourselves on the back for doing it right together with hopefully some fun and lots of integrity.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Al and good morning everyone.  As both John and Al have said, Q1 was a good quarter for Canadian Natural.  It was also a very eventful and important turning point in the evolution of the company with first production in Horizon oil sands mining operations.  It was also a quarter of low commodity prices compared to Q1 2008.</p>
          <p>In these low price periods, Canadian Natural's strong, balanced and diverse asset portfolio combined with our focus on low cost and effective operations has allowed the company to generate substantial free cash flow during this period.  In 2009, each component of our conventional asset base, gas, light oil, heavy and thermal oil will generate free cash flow.  Our assets are strong and we are low cost.</p>
          <p>Our priorities in 2009 remain unchanged:  First, debt repayment; second, capital allocation to maximize our return and to the highest return projects, these would be asset development, acquisitions or share buyback and thirdly, dividends.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter we proactively reduced our capital spending by $800 million.  After the completion of the first quarter, we see no reason to adjust the capital budget any further at this time.  As always, Canadian Natural retains as much flexibility in our capital program as possible, allowing us to be as proactive and prudent in managing the company and ensure we fulfill the priorities of 2009.</p>
          <p>Our conventional production guidance remains unchanged reflecting the strength of our conventional assets.  Let me now briefly update you on each of the assets as well as comment on the cost structure we see today and anticipate in the future.  Starting in Canada with gas, our gas production delivered as expected in Q1 and our small, 72 well drilling program delivered at or above expectations.  However with a very small amount of capital allocated to gas, gas production will decline in 2009 in line with our production guidance.</p>
          <p>We plan to drill approximately 70 gas wells for the remainder of 2009.  These wells are being drilled to offset drainage, conserve land, or are strategic in nature.  With the current gas price and cost environment, it makes no sense to drill any gas wells for any other reason.</p>
          <p>We however are generating significant free cash flow from our gas assets in 2009.  Even in the slow price environment, our gas assets will generate roughly $1 billion in free cash flow.  With the technology developments that have unlocked the potential of shale gas in North America, the gas business has been significantly changed.</p>
          <p>We believe that it's unlikely that you'll see sustained gas prices in the double-digit range that many of our estimators believed less than a year ago.  However, we also believe the current pricing level is not sustainable over the long-term.  Our expectations of gas prices in the long-term are in the six to $8 Canadian AECO range and as price levels drop below the range where we are today, we believe you will see a continuing steady contraction in the North American supply.</p>
          <p>Canadian Natural has the second largest land base in Western Canada, with significant exposure to the unconventional resource base as well.  We dominate the land base and infrastructure in our core areas. As a result, we are a low cost gas producer.  When prices return to the six to $7 range for a sustainable period of time, we will then begin to have a very disciplined capital program to develop our gas assets assuming of course they rank favorably with the rest of the assets in our oil portfolio.</p>
          <p>Canadian Natural's heavy and thermal oil assets in Canada are very strong and will continue to add tremendous value to Canadian Natural shareholders.  Our thermal assets alone have 33 billion barrels of oil in place and 5.6 billion recoverable in our defined plan.  Our plan is to add approximately 300,000 barrels a day of heavy oil production in a very stepwise, disciplined and cost controlled manner.</p>
          <p>Primrose East is our most recent incremental step on the road to 300,000 barrels a day of incremental production. And at our last press release, we stated that we had experienced a setback with a containment event.  Since that time we have completed a significant amount of diagnostic work in the field and analysis of that containment event.  We believe we have identified the event as a wellbore issue with one wellbore.  Our detailed report and analysis has been submitted to the provincial regulators.  And we will work with the ERCB to develop the most prudent way forward to bring Primrose East back into steaming.</p>
          <p>Our report recommends a number of preventative steps and further diagnostic testing including diagnostic steam testing before we bring Primrose East back to full steaming capacity.  We are confident that the issue can and will be resolved and effectively managed going forward with minimal effect on the long-term performance of Primrose East.</p>
          <p>The results from the production pullback have been encouraging and we are confident that the Primrose East will meet and more than likely exceed pre-project expectations, once these operational issues are behind us.  Production guidance has remained unchanged as we accounted for this event in our previous guidance ranges.</p>
          <p>At Kirby our next 45,000 barrel a day of incremental production, we expect to receive regulatory approval this year. Before we kick-off the development, we'll need this regulatory approval as well as the completion of the detailed engineering design work.  As we've said on our last conference call we expect to see capital cost reductions in this commodity price environment, and we also expect to see commodity prices and costs move more in line with each other before we proceed with Kirby.</p>
          <p>At Pelican Lake, we continue with our program to convert the field to polymer flooding.  Currently we have converted roughly 28% of the field to polymer flooding and expect to put another 11% under polymer flood in 2009.  Pelican is a world class pool with 4 billion barrels in place and between 350 and 475 million barrels recoverable.  A very large pool, and we expect to have the entire field on polymer flood by 2016.</p>
          <p>On the positive side we have seen some early indications lately from the field and lab work that our recovery factors that we have seen in the recovery factors, the potential is to go much higher than we currently carry in our reserve estimate.  Additional technical work as well as field performance will be required to prove the degree, if any, the recovery can be expected to increase.  On a 4 billion barrel field every 1% increase in recovery is 40 million barrels; not insignificant.</p>
          <p>Our Primary heavy oil program continues to roll along effectively and efficiently.  In this commodity and cost environment Primary heavy oil generates top decile returns on capital in our asset portfolio.  Importantly it also generates the quickest payout and largest cash-on-cash return.  Although, we do not spend much time talking about our Primary heavy oil business, our dominant high quality land base, infrastructure, and effective operations continue to make this one of the best value generators in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>In the North Sea we have been undertaking very little activity.  We completed one well off the Ninian Central platform which was brought on in the first quarter and although production rates are below expectations it has affirmed the reserve potential of the slumps to the east part of the Ninian forest.</p>
          <p>We're also nearing the zone in our deep depth, high pressure, high temperature gas exploration project.  Canadian Natural operates and will have a 36% working interest in any development if commercial gas is discovered.  Our interest in the exploration well is about 17%.</p>
          <p>In offshore West Africa 2009 has been a busy year so far.  At Baobab we completed the fourth well in our program to convert three to five wells back on stream planned for the one-year window we have with the drilling rig.</p>
          <p>The fourth well P13 came onstream mid-April as expected. P13 is flowing very strongly at about 5000 barrels a day gross with room to open up the well more.  Our original expectation from the Baobab program was to add between 10,000 and 15,000 barrels a day of net production and with the fourth well now onstream we've added roughly 11,000 barrels a day of net production from the Baobab program. A very successful result considering some of the earlier wells in the horizontal sections ended up being much shorter than anticipated.</p>
          <p>At Espoir production has returned to normal levels as the compression issues early in Q1 have been resolved.  And we expect to add additional compression and processing capacity at the Espoir FPSO by the year end, which will increase production and provide better processing reliability.</p>
          <p>At Olowi in Gabon, first oil was achieved in late April from the first well from Platform C, connected to the Olowi FPSO and is flowing at rates of 2000 barrels a day.  The second well was brought on shortly thereafter and today we are in around the 5000 barrel a day range between the two wells.  Additional wells will be completed and brought onstream as we drill and complete the wells on the Platform.</p>
          <p>We have drilled three production wells and a gas injection well from the Platform C.  The results to date have been mixed.  On the upside, the reservoir quality and the amount of net pay in the gas injector is well above expectations.  On the downside, the production wells have encountered the highest water/oil contact expected pre-sanction and more importantly, the reservoir dip is much deeper than expected.</p>
          <p>And while we have over 15 delineation wells in the field to date, it is clear the reservoir has some variability; and at least in the vicinity of Platform C our first platform, the reserves may be less than expected.  It is too early at this point to address the ultimate reserve potential at Olowi and we will monitor well performance and particularly results of the remaining wells on the remaining three platforms yet to be drilled closely to before realizing the reserve potential of Olowi one way or another.  The next platform will be installed later this summer.</p>
          <p>Despite the high cost roles that both Olowi and Baobob development have been undertaking, overall, offshore West Africa continues to provide some of the highest return on capital projects in our portfolio.  Going forward, we will be focused on reducing costs of all developments including the ongoing development of Olowi to be more in line with the current commodity price environment. We expect additional infill drilling and waterflood optimizations programs will take place at Espoir and Baobab once we have detailed plans complete and costs and prices normalize.</p>
          <p>On the cost side overall we are seeing some positive indications that our drive to reduce cost is beginning to pay dividends.</p>
          <p>In Canada in our conventional activities we've been able to get drilling and completion costs on average down to 2005 cost levels.  And in some cases, particularly in our deep gas drilling, which holds the majority of our significant gas potential in CNQ's land base the second largest in Western Canada, well below the 2005 cost levels; anywhere from 10 to 15% depending on the area.</p>
          <p>This reduction in costs has been driven primarily by significant increases in productivity and technical innovation and to a lesser degree by lower service and supply costs.  This is a very impressive result considering that steel prices which on average account for roughly 28% of our drilling costs are up 45% since 2005, and the regulatory cost load, which now account for 6% of our costs are up 35%.</p>
          <p>Going forward we do see tubular steel prices coming back in line with all the other commodity prices, so we should see some more cost reduction.  It is clear that our conventional teams are very strong as technical innovation and productivity are the largest drivers of the cost reduction as we get back to 2005 cost levels.</p>
          <p>Unfortunately for the gas business we are nowhere near 2005 price levels.  And we will need to drive more costs out of business and see commodity prices return to a $6 world before the majority of our gas inventory will be able to compete effectively for capital with our oil projects.</p>
          <p>At Horizon future expansions will need to see even greater cost reductions as the Fort McMurray region continues to lead Western Canada in cost increases and lag in cost reductions.  In productivity alone we believe there is likely a 20 to 30% cost savings achievable.</p>
          <p>In Phase 1 we took many innovative steps to control and reduce cost pressure, most if not all of these steps helped us contain costs.  We are currently undertaking a comprehensive lessons learned process, so that we can capture as many of the efficiency and cost control and reduction approaches as possible to implement in our future tranches.</p>
          <p>The dilemma with all major projects in the Fort McMurray region is the economic viability going forward.  Today, you can likely get some very enticing bids to proceed with construction, all of them on a reimbursable cost plus basis.  However, when certainty and commodity prices return, the players will likely all move to start construction and on a cost plus basis.  The also concern of course is that poor productivity and cost inflation will reignite and we are all back in that same unfavorable position.</p>
          <p>We are very focused on developing enhancements to our strategies and our execution plans to ensure that we will be able to execute the construction of future phases in a cost effective manner.  On a positive side of the story, contractor capacity has increased significantly; something that we use to our advantage with our fly-in/fly-out program on Phase 1 as we're able to bring contractors from across Canada to our site.  This, along with the recent consolidation of operators, should allow for a more orderly and effective scheduling of construction projects and major turnarounds.</p>
          <p>This all sounds good, and it's easy to say, but it will take considerable effort from the industry once more stable commodity prices return to ensure that the industry will not again return to low productivity and minimal focus on cost control that we have seen in the past from everyone; owners, contractors, regulators, and the labor.</p>
          <p>With this in mind, Canadian Natural is proceeding with Tranche 2 of our Phase 2/3 expansion, and we will only proceed and proceed very carefully with Tranches 3 and 4 when we are certain of the following.  Firstly, we can implement all of our lessons learned from Phase 1 to build and enhance our successful Phase 1's execution strategy.</p>
          <p>Two, we see significantly less costs and cost pressures going forward. And thirdly we see a period of more stable commodity prices with a risk bias to the upside versus the downside.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter at Horizon we achieved first synthetic crude oil production, first pipeline shipments, and completed the construction of the distillate hydrotreater on March 23. With the third hydrotreater we are currently running at 75 to 90,000 barrels a day of light, sweet SCO. Of the roughly 62 days since February 28's startup or first production, at the end of April we have been on for 30 days and averaged roughly 38,000 barrels per day &#x2013; stream day -- only 17,000 barrels a day for the calendar day however.  Despite the high costs we were up at both &#x2013; sorry.</p>
          <p>In April, we took a significant outage to ensure we made the necessary adjustments to meet product quality specifications and adjust and repair equipment after the first significant run period.  At this point we are now expecting to run for an extent period of time and slowly ramp up to design capacity to 110,000 barrels a day of SCO.</p>
          <p>The most important factor in our success for 2009 will be uptime or plant reliability.  The major risk to an extended runtime and time required to achieve design capacity will be the ore preparation plant as we experienced some reliability issues with the crushers and associated gearboxes and the hydrogen plant which has also seen a number of premature valve failures that the vendor has addressed.</p>
          <p>What is more important to note at this point is that we have not experienced any design capacity limitations with the major components of the entire Horizon complex.  And although it's early, it appears the hydrotreaters will be able to run above design capacity and provide opportunity for potential de-bottlenecking opportunities.</p>
          <p>With that I will turn it over to R&#xE9;al to describe where we are today and what the remainder of Q2 and 2009 will look like in terms of our production ramp-up.  R&#xE9;al?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Steve.  Yes it is indeed pretty exciting right now at the site since we are continuing our commissioning of the plant.  And we have, like Steve said in April, March and April we have done quite a successful commissioning.  We have so far produced about 1.5 million barrel at this plant.  We have filled the pipeline which was 766,000 barrel and we have between Edmonton and the site right now over 900,000 barrels of inventory ready to be also shipped.</p>
          <p>So, we have gradually brought the production up in stages, as you can imagine, because of a different component of the plant and so on.  Throughout the commissioning right now, we have found about three major issues that we have to deal with and most of them have been dealt with so far.  One, like Steve mentioned the ore preparation plant.  You can imagine that we've built this plant during a period where the supply was in very, very high demand for equipment and we had some less than adequate we think shipments of equipment, some of which, for example, the primary crusher gearboxes.</p>
          <p>The shaft was the wrong metallurgy, which allowed the gearbox or the gear to spin on the shaft and so on.  Two of them have been &#x2013; we have four of those gearbox in operation, two per crusher.  Two of them have been fixed so far and the crusher is in operation.  And the other two are being fixed as we speak right now.  Even though we were able to run the crusher with these kind of deficiencies they definitely brought also their challenges in terms of reliability.</p>
          <p>The second one in the ore preparation plant was the secondary crusher.  The teeth design required modification and the supplier, Krupp, is right now working them out.  However, in the meantime, we have to recycle the oversized material which had a little bit of a cost, because we have to use a loader and trucks to do this.  However, it does not impact the production at this time.  This secondary crusher teeth problem should be solved here in the coming couple of months.</p>
          <p>The second major challenge we have had in the startup of this plant was the hydrogen plant which is a steam methane reformer. Amongst those plants, there is a plant called the pressure swing absorption plant which is a PSA plant. In there, this is where we're separating the hydrogen from the CO2 and the particulate. There is a tremendous amount of valves in operations.  Amongst those, there is 6 inches valve, there is 72 of them spread over 12 beds.  These valves are opening, full open, and fully shutting down within a fraction of a second and as you can imagine, they're controlled by computers and so on.</p>
          <p>We found some scoring in some of the butterfly in the valves and some of stem and so on.  We're still investigating the cause of those.  We have replaced several of them.  Right now, we see a higher reliability of the plant.  We're running about 9, 10 beds out of 12 for the time being; which at full capacity, we need about 10 beds out of 12, but we are recirculating these valves on a higher rate than anticipated so far.</p>
          <p>The third issue that we have on the plant was the tankage management.  As you can imagine starting the plant with no intermediate tankage volume was quite a challenge, since the plant is fully integrated in terms of energy and in terms of material balance.  So for example, we have a DB, diluted bitumen tankage which is an intermediate tankage plant.  We have an intermediate SCO tankage and we have treated tankage.</p>
          <p>So between these three tankage plants, we really have to manage that well.  So when we crank up one unit we have also to crank up all the other unit at the same time. So if one goes down for any reason it stops the overall progress of the commissioning.  So we had those several issues.  Now fortunately most of these issues are behind us, because we have like I said close to 900,000 barrels of intermediate product and final product on site so this is definitely helping us out here balancing the plant's availability and reliability.</p>
          <p>As for the design like Steve mentioned also the hydrotreaters are &#x2013; we see right now that have been brought up to capacity and even more so we know that we do have quite a good capacity in that area.  The cokers have been run so far up to 80% of capacity with no issue.  And we see also that the yield of this plant is as per design and we don't see no problems of cranking it up also to 100% capacity here in the future.</p>
          <p>So as we're going along with this plant right now we're continuing to ramping cautiously.  We're doing it at about five to 10,000 barrels per day, watching and stabilizing every aspect of this plant before we move to the next portion.  So for us definitely the second quarter bring its challenge in keeping the reliability of the plant and gradually cranking it up to its capacity and continuing also to fine-tuning and tweaking this plant as to bring it up to full capacity by year end.</p>
          <p>On this, I will turn it back to you, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks R&#xE9;al.  In summary, Canadian Natural is in a very strong position.  Our assets are strong.  Our balance sheet is strong and getting stronger and we have a very flexible capital program to maximize the value of our low risk, balanced portfolio.  We are proactive in making the tough decisions to not only survive, but prepare to capture the opportunities that will present themselves in this environment.</p>
          <p>Particularly as gas prices have recently fared, with falling through the $3 floor.  As a low cost producer, Canadian Natural has a competitive advantage in today's environment.  Our focus on cost reduction has already resulted in some early wins and we expect to return to our high standards of execution despite the recent setbacks at Primrose East and our startup issues at Horizon.</p>
          <p>And with that, I will turn it over to Doug to update you on our financial position and our prudent financial management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Steve.  In the first quarter of 2009, Canadian Natural generated over $1.5 billion of cash flow from operations or $2.80 per share and 305 million in net earnings.  We incurred 1.26 billion of capital expenditures in line with our cash flows.  This has allowed our financial metrics to continue to improve inside and below our targeted ranges.  Our commitment to cost control, controls capital spending and discipline to the balance sheet as Steve said is again evident in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Our liquid resources remain strong.  At the end of the first quarter, our undrawn bank lines of credit exceeded $1.7 billion.  This liquidity combined with continued debt repayment through the free cash flows continues to strengthen our balance sheet.  Our debt to book capitalization was 41% at quarter end, which is near the midpoint of our targeted range of 35 to 45%.</p>
          <p>Debt to EBITDA is at 1.7 times, at the low end of our targeted range of 1.8 to 2.2 times.  We continue to systematically retire the non-revolving credit facility, which matures in October 2009.  To date, we have reduced the outstanding line to $1.645 billion from the $2.35 billion outstanding at December 31.  It is our intention to retire this facility from an allocation of cash flow from operations, which includes the proceeds from our commodity hedge program.</p>
          <p>Our revolving syndicate credit facilities are in place through June 2012 and our debt maturities are very manageable at less than 500 million per year through 2012.  Our access to the debt capital market is good with strong and stable credit ratings.</p>
          <p>We remain active in our commodity hedge program; 92,000 barrels per day of crude oil puts with a floor of $100 per barrel, in addition to crude oil collars on 25,000 barrels per day with a floor of $70 per barrel and a ceiling of $111.  These positions are in place for the remainder of 2009.</p>
          <p>For natural gas, we have 400,000 GJs per day of AECO natural gas physical sales contracts with an average price of $5.29 per GJ for the period April to December.  And in addition, we have 220,000 GJs per day of AECO natural gas collars with a floor of $6 and a ceiling of $8, for all of 2010.  We continue to monitor this program for expansion opportunities in 2010.  Our commodity hedge book is posted on our website and is presented in the press release.</p>
          <p>And finally, we have declared a quarterly cash dividend of $0.105 payable July 1 continuing the tradition of paying dividends for the ninth consecutive year.</p>
          <p>Canadian Natural continues to grow and diversify with production from conventional oil and natural gas, new production fields in Canada and Offshore West Africa and the now addition of synthetic crude oil volumes from the oil sands, mining and upgrading division.  All of our core areas all or soon will be generating free cash flow.  We continue to grow shareholder value through the prudent management of our world class assets.</p>
          <p>Thank you.  And I will return you to John for some closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Al and Steve, R&#xE9;al and Doug, a great review of where we are and what we're doing.  As you can see Canadian Natural has a suite of assets that I believe is among the best in the independent E&amp;P world and we are continuing the execution of our plans and we look forward to creating additional value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>With that operator, I would like to open up the conference call for questions that people may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Langille.  We'll now take questions from the telephone lines. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  The first question is from Andrew Fairbanks of Banc of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Good morning everybody.  I just was curious how you all are viewing the current asset acquisition opportunities in the market and given your price deck how those stack up against your internal CNQ projects at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew this is Steve Laut here.  Obviously we are starting to see more and more properties brought on to the market.  We're starting to see some reduction in the expectations of the sellers.  And I'd say right now we are fairly close with particularly on the gas side I think you probably buy much cheaper than you can drill for at this point.  On the oil side, we may be getting close but we're not there yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great.  And the areas you're interested in, would those still be in and around your existing operating areas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah pretty much that's what we're looking at mostly within our core areas, I don't think we need to go outside our core areas for any kind of acquisition.  But we would not be averse to doing that if we found a really good deal, but that's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...not high on our list.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question is from Arjun Murti from Goldman Sachs.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  My question is related to the future phases of Horizon.  I think you made some very interesting comments about, productivity alone could get you a 20 to 30% savings and obviously steel and these other things are down.  But you followed that up with the observation that I think is correct that if the oil price comes back and industry activity heats up again, how can one gain confidence that industry overall including CNQ doesn't get back to a less favorable position where the costs re-escalate?</p>
          <p>Is the only solution to that M&amp;A -- we've seen one step here with Suncor merging with Petro-Canada and do you see that as the key to getting to a situation where industry activity doesn't heat up too much? Or what other solutions do you have to gain confidence that you can keep the costs down whenever you think it's time again to go forward with future phases?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a great question.  And we do see a lot of gains on productivity that we can achieve.  I think -- I don't think you need M&amp;A activity to get costs down.  I think it's fairly -- if you look at the players now, a fairly well disciplined group and it's just a matter of organizing ourselves so we that don't compete directly head on head.  These projects can go at the same time, but with segmenting of the timing of them.  So you don't want to have everybody doing civil work at the same time or electrical work all the same time.  You need to stagger the projects even though they are concurrent, they need to be staggered so you've less demand on each of the contractors and labor components.</p>
          <p>For us, one key thing here and I talked about it a little bit in the &#x2013; earlier on here is we had a very, very successful execution strategy in Phase 1.  Our costs were up, but considering what we went through, it was our first time at it.  It's very important for us to go through the lessons learned because we believe that we have some significant enhancements to our strategy that we can achieve.  And obviously I'm not going to share all those with you here today because we think we have some inside track.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there a timeframe by which the lessons learned project will take? Is it six months, nine months, and then after that we might expect some sort of news on what you're thinking about for Phase 2 and 3?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, probably six to nine months to get all the lessons learned completed and its going to take some time to, once you get the lesson, you've got to figure out how you're going to use that and execute going forward.  So we'll take our time and do it right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just one final quick question here. As a follow-up to the acquisition-oriented question, I suddenly heard that the preference or the most logical area is to look at your core areas.  It sounds like on your price deck you're more bullish longer term on oil than natural gas.  You obviously did do a large gas acquisition several years ago of the Anadarko's properties, you sold the inventory from those properties and I know you'll always consider what is the best deal and does it make sense.  But is there a bias towards not doing too large of a gas deal unless it's just a phenomenal deal to keep more of an oil weighting or how should we think about the relative sizing of natural gas going forward as part of CNQ?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Arjun, we don't have --we try not to have a bias on anything.  Our bias is to generate value.  So, we don't go in with a mind saying we're only going to do a deal so big and so in such and such a way.  We're here to generate value for the shareholders and we have a certain core competency and skill set in the company, I think that's very strong.  We have a very strong gas competency, heavy oil thermal and now with Horizon.  We also have offshore capability in the North Sea and offshore West Africa.  So we try to leverage our strengths so that we can add value or see value that our competitors may not see, and that's what we drive to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.   The next question is from Gil Yang of Citigroup.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you comment on Olowi, I think you commented it's too early to tell what the reserve potential is, but could you remind us what the original reserve potential was supposed to be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our original number was about 50 million barrels of recoverable oil out of Olowi.  And right now we're not sure where that will end up.  We've seen some surprises here with the first production wells and the gas injection well.  So if we hadn't drilled the production wells and just the gas injection well we would have had our guys pushing to increase the reserves because of the results there.</p>
          <p>So, the other 15 wells in the pool still align with our original estimates. As we go forward I'm sure we'll see more surprises one way or another.  But it's really we got to get the wells down and see how they perform before we actually start adjusting the reserves. I'm just trying to be as transparent as possible telling you that the contact was higher in these first wells than we expected and the dip was a bit steeper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry so 15 wells looked on target and how many wells were different?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we might be jumping the gun a bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Sticking with West Africa, could you comment on, in terms of new oil, the what kinds of exploration opportunities you have in the context of what Anadarko and Tullow have done nearby in Ghana?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not in Ghana, so I guess you can say we don't follow that.  We have &#x2013; we're in Gabon and C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire.  Gabon, we're pretty much focused on Olowi right now.  In C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire, we do on our lands have some development projects at Acajou and few other smaller pools in around Espoir and Baobab that we can likely tie back.</p>
          <p>There's also infill programs that will happen at Baobab and Espoir as we move forward.  So we're working on that right now, making sure we have basically all the geology and engineering nailed right down before we proceed and see a little better cost and oil price alignment before we proceed.  But as far as the exploration side in that part of it, not a lot.  And "Big E" exploration we do have a "Big E" exploration project in South Africa and it's I would say a very high risk, very high reward.  And likely we're not going to drill that until 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question is from Peter Ogden of National Bank Financial.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning guys.  A quick question on Horizon, you mentioned a production rate of 75 to 90,000, is that an instantaneous rate and have you actually achieved that yet, and is Horizon on today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Horizon is on today, and this morning it was running at 84,000 barrels a day out of the hydrotreaters; out of the cokers we were running about 82,000 barrels a day.  It has been running consistently for roughly the last nine days.  And I would say the average in the last nine days has been around the 75,000 barrel a day range out of the hydrotreaters to the sales tanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent.  And I was wondering if you could elaborate -- you mentioned some spec issues in April and you had to I guess turn down production, is that, does that have to do with the hydrotreaters and is that fixed now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is fixed.  It had nothing to do with the hydrotreaters.  It actually had to do just the way that the operating parameter is in the coker.  We're actually -- because we were starting up and as R&#xE9;al can probably give you a lot more detail.  We were running at lower than design capacity, because a lot of the components are designed for the full 232.  We had some issues with foaming and carrying particulates and not getting the gas/oil backwash to get rid of the particulates out of the stream.  So we ended up getting some particulates in our spec oil.  So we had to basically shut down, get some filtering in place for our spec oil and then just make sure that we got the operating parameters for the rest of the plant nailed down, which we did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent, and a final question just around capital allocation and maybe outside of the acquisition market, heavy oil prices have been extremely strong. And I'm just wondering what your view is on heavy prices and whether you would &#x2013; whether that's sustainable and whether you'd allocate more capital to the heavy oil program at this point, at this stage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we believe that long-term heavy oil prices will be fairly strong.  They're actually very strong right now.  I think those differentials may widen somewhat, but with access to the Gulf of Mexico, our refining complex, I think you'll see that narrow again.</p>
          <p>As far as allocating more capital, as you know, Peter, we are very much a cost control type of company, very focused on low cost.  If we allocate too much more capital to heavy oil, we have some concerns that we may overheat the market and see some cost increases, that we don't want to put too much demand on our contractors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect.  Okay, thanks very much and great quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question is from Martin Molyneaux from FirstEnergy Capital.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My questions have now been answered.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  The next question is from Mark Polak of Scotia Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning guys.  Of the various bump in thermal production in the quarter and I believe at Primrose now you have 120,000 of capacity. Now that you've got a handle on the seepage issues at Primrose East, I'm wondering if you could just give us some color on how you see the ramp up going and when you expect to be up in that 120 range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me Mark.  Right now we are not steaming, so we're just flowing back on the Primrose East pads.  That is nearing, it's starting to dwindle away, decline away.  We do not have approval yet from the ERCB to start steaming and neither do we want to start steaming right now.  We're working very closely with the ERCB, we have a plan.</p>
          <p>We believe we know what is causing the issue and we know how to resolve that.  But obviously on these issues you want to make sure everybody's on site.  Once we get that approval then we'll start diagnostic steaming.  So we're not going to go in and just start steaming full bore.  We'll do it in a stepwise, start out small and then just ramp ourselves up and very carefully monitor the whole situation.</p>
          <p>And particularly the wellbore we believe is the issue.  Before we do that obviously we will repair that wellbore and go forward.  So remember this is a cyclic steam operation here at Primrose East.  So you do hit 120,000 barrels a day capacity, but you're always on a cycle so you come up to 120,000 then you will rotate off, it's like a sine wave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  There are no further questions registered at this time.  I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. Langille.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much operator, and thank you very much for everyone listening in and attending our conference call.  And as usual if you have any further questions do not hesitate to contact us.  Thank you very much.  And have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The conference has now ended.  Please disconnect your lines at this time.  Thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>