<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1269625" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-11-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1564</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John G. Langille, Vice-Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Allan P. Markin, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Steve W. Laut, President and Chief Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">R&#xE9;al J. H. Doucet, Senior Vice President of Oil Sands</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Douglas A. Proll, Chief Financial Officer and Senior Vice-President, Finance</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Arjun Murti</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Greg Pardy</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Andrew Potter</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Peter Ogden</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.  Welcome to the Canadian Natural Resources 2009 Third Quarter Results Conference Call.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. John Langille, Vice Chairman of Canadian Natural Resources.  Please go ahead, Mr. Langille.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, operator, and good morning, everyone.  Thank you for attending this conference call.  We will discuss our third quarter results, our outlook for the balance of 2009 and our capital budget for 2010 which were all covered in a press release issued earlier this morning.</p>
          <p>Participating with me today will be Allan Markin, our Chairman; Steve Laut, our President and Chief Operating Officer; R&#xE9;al Doucet, our Senior Vice President of Oil Sands; and Doug Proll, our Senior Vice President of Finance.</p>
          <p>Before we start, I would refer you to the comments regarding forward-looking information contained in our press release and also note that all dollar amounts are in Canadian dollars and production and reserves are both expressed as before royalties unless otherwise stated.</p>
          <p>The third quarter continued to achieve very meaningful levels of operational cash flow with cash flow exceeding CapEx requirements by $1 billion.  All of our business segments contributed to this free cash flow.  As a result, we have strengthened our balance sheet further.  And in the quarter, as expected, we repaid the remainder of a debt obligation within the due date timeframe and retired that portion of our outstanding debt.</p>
          <p>The business environment for the development and production of our heavy oil assets continues to be very positive with lower than historical levels of price differential and continuing low cost.  We own extensive acreage over the heavy oil areas of Eastern Alberta, Western Saskatchewan which provide excellent recycle ratios and returns.  The business environment for natural gas, on the other hand, continues to be challenging to achieve adequate returns.  And Steve will provide greater detail on our development plans for these parts of our asset portfolios.  And we continue to meet the challenges of ramping up our production levels at our mining project at Horizon, and both Steve and R&#xE9;al will discuss this ramp-up further.</p>
          <p>We have set our 2010 capital expenditure budget at almost $4 billion.  Based on that level of expenditure, we will be able to achieve 7% year-over-year production growth while spending only 60% of our anticipated 2010 cash flow.</p>
          <p>With that, I would like to ask Allan to make a few comments before Steve undertakes the detailed review of our operations.  Allan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.  Good morning.</p>
          <p>It was at this time last year that the world changed in commodity prices, along with the rest of the marketplace, dropped dramatically.  It was at that time we reminded ourselves of the importance adhering to our core values, spending where we need to, maintaining balance and continuing our commitment to low cost.  It was through our core values that we're able to continually create value for our shareholders during the highly volatile business environment of the past year.  As we return to a new normalized state, our effective strategy, proven in all price environments, will continue to pay dividends.  Particularly for the Gas business in Alberta, the physical regime remains punitive at higher gas prices.</p>
          <p>Looking to the third quarter performance, there were some challenges at Horizon that resulted in less than targeted production.  It was a disappointment, especially after a highly successful second quarter.  However, these challenges are very manageable and we've been doing a great job of identifying and mitigating the issues.</p>
          <p>Conventionally, we continue to execute on our conventional assets and look forward to another productive year both in North America and internationally.  Our 2010 budget has been released along with our third quarter results.  Spending is up overall from 2009 as a record primary heavy oil program is rolled out, taking advantage of a strong oil price and favorable heavy oil differential.  In addition, we continue work on the development of Kirby, the next step in our defined thermal growth plan.  Pelican Lake and other enhanced recoveries are also advancing.</p>
          <p>Conversely, natural gas drilling remains challenged as near-term natural gas economics continue to be weak.  2010 spending at Horizon will be focused on tranche 2 of the expansion, working towards reliability, up-time and debottlenecking.</p>
          <p>As always, our long-term objectives have not changed.  The third quarter and our 2010 budget are good examples of that.  We are committed to consistent value creation for our shareholders through capital discipline, efficient capital allocation and a prudent approach to developing our world-class assets.  We have the people, the plan and the assets.</p>
          <p>Steve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Al, and good morning, everyone.</p>
          <p>As both John and Al have said, Q3 was a solid quarter for Canadian Natural.  Oil production was up 17% over third quarter in 2008, driven by a strong production volumes at Baobab and from our heavy oil assets.  And with the exception of Horizon, all areas are within production guidance ranges.  As expected, our offering cost remain low and well within our operating cost guidance for this year, which we lowered in Q2.</p>
          <p>In these periods of commodity price volatility, Canadian Natural's strong, balanced and diverse asset portfolio, combined with our focus on low costs and effective operations, has allowed the company to generate substantial free cash flow.  In 2009, each component of our asset base, gas, light oil, heavy and thermal oil, as well as Horizon, will generate free cash flow, allowing us to significantly pay down debt.  Our assets are strong and we are low cost.</p>
          <p>Let me now briefly update you on each of our assets before I give you a brief update of where we're headed in 2010.  Starting in gas with Canada, our gas production delivered as expected in Q3.  With only 17 gas wells drilled, Q3 production declined as reflected in our Q3 guidance.  For the remainder of 2009, we'll drill another 25 gas wells, bringing the total gas wells for the year to 114.  In comparison, our peak drilling for the gas occurred in 2005 when we drilled just under 900 gas wells.  All gas wells that are being drilled in 2009 are being drilled to offset drainage, conserve land or are strategic in nature.  With the current gas price and cost environment, it makes no sense to drill any gas wells for any other reason.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, oil activity in Canada was very robust and our oil-drilling activity resulted in Canadian Natural being the most active driller in the third quarter in Western Canada, reflecting a strong pricing for oil and the narrow heavy-oil differentials in Q3 and 2009 overall.  On the primary heavy side, we drilled 217 wells in Q3 and will drill another 166 wells in Q4, bringing the total primary heavy oil wells to 494 for 2009.  We have been fairly active as well on our light oil properties, with 10 wells drilled in Q3 and another 24 wells in Q4, for a total of 42 wells in 2009.  At Pelican Lake we drilled 19 wells in Q3 and we'll drill another 19 in Q4, bringing our total to 69 for the year, as we continue to roll out the highly successful Palmer site at Pelican Lake.</p>
          <p>On the thermal side of the business, we drilled 24 wells at Primrose in Q3 and will add 14 more in Q4, bringing the total to 82 for 2009.  Primrose East, our most recent incremental step on the road to 300,000 barrels a day of incremental production. And as you know, we experienced a containment event at Primrose East early in Q1.  In the third quarter, we received regulatory approval for diagnostic steaming to determine the root cause of the containment event.  We are now well into the diagnostic steaming at Primrose East, having completed the first phase of diagnostic steaming and are now into second phase of a multi-phase diagnostic program.</p>
          <p>At this point we have not seen any indications that a containment event will reoccur; however, we're being very cautious, and we'll move forward in a very prudent manner.  It will take us some time to return to full production levels at Primrose East, likely near the end of 2010, as we slowly move through the diagnostic steaming.  And our North Sea production has been steady and within guidance.  On top of the turnaround completed in Union Central in early Q3, we completed a Union cell turnaround in Q3.  Both these plant turnarounds were completed successfully.</p>
          <p>In C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire production at both Baobab and Espoir continue to deliver steady and reliable production volumes well above guidance expectations.  At Olowi and Gabon, production performance has not met expectations on the C Platform, and we're currently pasturing on a B Platform, and expect to have two wells completed in the reservoir before year-end.</p>
          <p>Results from the Platform B wells may affect the overall development plans for Olowi.  It is too early at this point to address the ultimate reserve potential for Olowi, and we will monitor well performance, and particularly results for the remaining wells on the next three platforms yet to be drilled closely before revising the reserve potential at Olowi.</p>
          <p>As far as progress on the overall development at Olowi, all three remaining jacket decks have been installed and we are now pasturing on platform B.  We expect to have the installation vessel back to arrive in the fourth quarter here and complete the hookup of the pipelines and umbilicals between the platforms and the FPSO, with completion scheduled for early 2010.</p>
          <p>At Horizon, our world-class oil sands mining project, we've had a tough August and September in Q3, as well as a tough October.  As you all know we had a very strong production of 92,097 barrels a day in June, and 83,573 barrels a day in July, despite an unexpected wet failure on a wet gas compressor.</p>
          <p>The month of August and September have been difficult with more than expected equipment failures.  Although the equipment failures in the third quarter were numerous, we believe for the most part these type of failures are now behind us.  These failures, which R&#xE9;al will describe more fully in a minute, resulted in a loss of roughly 17,000 barrels a day of average production in the quarter.</p>
          <p>In addition to these failures, we entered a high find section of the mine in early September.  We, of course, need to mine this portion of the second bench in the mine to reach a deeper higher quality bench three portion of the mine.  The high finds section was not a surprise, we knew it was coming.  However, based on the early performance of the bitumen production plant, we had anticipated no material impacts on our ability to achieve productive targets as our bitumen production plant was running well above designed capacities.</p>
          <p>However, the clay content within the finds itself in this portion of the second bench &#x2013; and it is a limited portion &#x2013; has been significantly more difficult to process than first anticipated.  As a result, we lost roughly 6,600 barrels a day of production for the quarter, all that coming in September where we roughly lost 20,000 barrels a day of production.  These issues have continued into October; and although we have taken a number of mitigating actions and we have recovered somewhat in October, they're still likely to dog us until we get to the third bench, when we can effectively blend the climes at the ore dump and return production to our normal target levels.  And we expect to be in the third bench by mid-2010 at the latest.</p>
          <p>Of course, all these issues reflect in our monthly production numbers as follows.  July we had 83,573 barrels.  August was 58,912 barrels.  And September was 58,036 barrels.  And here in October, we recovered somewhat and we're back up to 71,200 barrels a day.</p>
          <p>Now before I get into 2010 budget and the forward plan for each area, I'm going to turn it over to R&#xE9;al to give you more detail on the status of the issues we have faced and what we expect to face in the future, as well as our plans to deal with these issues.  R&#xE9;al?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Steve.  I will divide my presentation into first, the mechanical failures, and the second one is will be the finds and the clays encountered in the ore body.</p>
          <p>On the mechanical failures, we had several short-term mechanical failures, which right now have been solved and I would say the problem is behind us.  The Naphtha recovery unit, we had a pipe connection leak inside of the vessel, which created a steam impingement on the vessel wall.  We had to fix this, so we had to stop the operation, get into the vessel, fix the leak and put it back into business.  The problem has been fixed and the Naphtha recovery unit has been working really well since.  That was several weeks ago and the plant is very reliable today.</p>
          <p>The wet-gas compressor, this is a huge compressor, really, really big into the thousands of horsepower.  It is usually very, very reliable.  However, we had the exciter cable and some diodes that came loose after a few hours of operation.  So we had to change this exchanger, which is an Italian compressor so we had to bring the parts from Italy.  It's been changed.  It's been tested.  It's been put back into operation and has operated now for several weeks without a glitch, and we feel right now that this problem is behind us as well.</p>
          <p>On the hydrogen plant, we have those, what we call PSA valves.  They're 72 valves that are opening and closing within two, three minutes, each continuously.  There was a manufacturing defect, which the stem of the valves were not to spec.  They are some of them oversized, some of them under-sized by 1,000 to one thousand-and-a-half &#x2013; thousand-and-an-inch-size, which creates on a long-term movement of these valves, that they seize in this core.  The valves are getting rebuilt right now one by one, and we have rebuilt several of them, and we have a change also the operational programs of the PSA plant such that when the valves fail now, it does not trigger a whole-plant shut down.</p>
          <p>We have brand new valves on orders.  They have started to arrive here at the beginning of October, and we have started a total replacement of these valves, which will be complete before year-end.  So we'll have all brand new valves and we are checking them all, obviously, to make sure that they are all within specs.  So this problem, by year-end, will be behind us as well.</p>
          <p>We had the secondary crusher, which we were breaking teeth and we were producing over-sized material as a product.  So all the teeth assembly have been re-designed.  The new arrangement also have been tested, and one of the crusher is in operation right now to final testing in the field.  The second crusher is coming up here at mid-November, and will be installed also as it arrives, and we are very confident right now that this problem also is behind us, and we will be totally, fully operational here before &#x2013; well before year-end, as a matter of fact.</p>
          <p>We also have some high wear on our bitumen hydro-transport lines.  And each, as you know each oil preparation plants has one hydro-transport line to bring the material or the slurry, into the extraction plant, and there were &#x2013; we were experiencing high wear, higher than anticipated wear in those lines.  We are adding a third hydro-transport line which will be replacement and a shift over, such that when we are replacing lines and fixing them, we can still operate two out of three for these two plants.  So the third line has been designed, fabricated, and is being installed right now in the field, and this problem also will be behind us at the end of the first quarter of 2010.  We have install these lines and welded them in the field.</p>
          <p>We had also a hydro-treater exchanger leaking.  We have two very sophisticated exchanger, one in the diesel plant, one in the gas oil plant, that are susceptible to leak when the plant gets shut down.  In other words, they go to a time &#x2013; thermal cycle, and the head bolts are leaking.  We have been able to pull one out of there, and we have installed a bypass, and it's working really well.  And in fact, we realized that with the performance that we have out of our hydrogen plant, we don't need this exchanger.  So one of them have been replaced with a bypass, the second one, as soon as we have an opportunity, will be also replaced, but for the time being, we have resorted to have both and it's working perfectly.  So this problem right now is considered behind us as well.</p>
          <p>So those were kind of the mechanical failure or early failure on start-up of the plant that we have experienced and right now we don't see any other major issue with this failure or the mechanical integrity of the plant itself.  We have and we're in the process of completing right now our winterization for this coming winter and we'll be in a very good shape.</p>
          <p>Now talking about the fines in the clay problem, first of all, the fines and the clay were well-defined in our ore body definition and in the fit design as well, so we knew that these fines were there, we knew that there was a clear content with them, and we were positioning the plant design to deal with them.  So our equipment design and the excess capacity of our froth treatment was deemed sufficient to deal with this issue.  We underestimated the difficulty to process this high clay and the more blending that is required to minimize this issue.  Since we are at the beginning of our pit operation, we don't have yet all the blending capability that we will have next year.</p>
          <p>We experienced this high clay on the second bench like Steve said.  Our third bench, however, has a high quality of ore and also much lower fine, and not quite accessible yet until we have of course mined through our second bench.  So the mitigating issue that we're doing right now is we are stockpiling our second bench and in fact we will be stockpiling.  We have started also a month ago to stockpile two and a half million tons of ore which we will trickle in over the next two years on a blend of about 10% ratio to make sure that the plant capability is well-protected.</p>
          <p>We have also tested several chemicals in the separation cell and we have found one that is quite effective actually at separating these clays and fines from the rest of the material.  We have also in the Froth Treatment plant installed additional instrumentation to allow faster plant behavior and formations and corrections versus lab testing.  As you know, like water content &#x2013; for example, fine content and so on, if we can find them and define them as the process goes through, then it's a lot easier to react and mix at a higher performance.</p>
          <p>So the high fine in clay reduces our Froth Treatment capacity. It also affect the intermediate tankage which we call the diluted bitumen tank behavior because there is high water content and because of the clay layer formation in the tank. We have installed three decanters machine to deal with this clay layer in the tank. The decanters are performing really well and we have learned how to keep the diluted bitumen at a high quality to feed the upgrader.  So all in all right now, we believe that we do understand these issues, we have dealt with them and it is just now a matter of a short-term time for us here to get this problem behind us. Thank you, back to you Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Real. One thing I would like to point out before I get into the 2010 budget.  Although the third quarter production and horizon has missed guidance and is a disappointment for everyone involved, it does point out something that is very positive. That being the strength of our team, their ability to identify and troubleshoot problems, and quickly and effectively implement solutions.</p>
          <p>If I had a choice, I would have preferred to remain in the dark about this ability, but we didn't have a choice. The issues we have faced in Q3 have not been trivial. Our ability as a team to effectively deal with the issues while keeping production on and costs down is impressive and bodes well for the future.  Even with the lower production in a mostly fixed cost plant, plus the equipment fires, operating costs were at $38.87 a barrel, trending towards the bottom end of our guidance range. A great result.</p>
          <p>Turning to the 2010 budget, I'll give you an overall view and then a few highlights for each of the assets. Our capital program in 2010 will be $3.9 billion, up 26% from the 2009 capital program. With the increased capital allocations to oil, about 80% of all capital, and particularly primary heavy oil, Pelican Lake, Horizon expansion preparation and enhanced oil recovery in our light oil projects, as well as kicking off the early stages in the first phase of the Septimus/Montney Shell gas development.</p>
          <p>As a result of this capital program and the capital programs in prior years, we will see production grow 7% year-over-year and 17%, entry to exit, generating a 12% increase in cash flow and more importantly, free cash flow in the two to $2.6 billion range. Clearly this reflects the strength of Canadian Natural's assets and the soundness of our strategy. We are growing production and generating substantial free cash flow. We are in a great position.</p>
          <p>In 2010 Canadian Natural will allocate this free cash flow in the following three priorities.  First, pay down debt and further strengthen balance sheet; secondly, allocate capital to additional asset development opportunities, acquisitions or share buybacks; and thirdly, dividends.</p>
          <p>As Doug will address in a few minutes, our balance sheet is strengthened considerably in 2009, and will strengthen even further in 2010.  And with that in mind, and depending on the environment, we would expect a great likelihood that the additional free cash flow in 2010 will be allocated to the second and third priorities more so than we were in 2009.</p>
          <p>Turning in more detail asset by asset, firstly gas in Canada.  As you know Canadian Natural has the largest land base in Western Canada.  Canadian National dominates the land base and infrastructure in our core areas, and as a result, we are a low-cost producer.  Our gas land base is very well positioned with strong assets and teams in conventional, foothills, resource and unconventional plays.</p>
          <p>Canadian Natural's plan in 2010 is not only to preserve, but to strengthen our dominant gas asset base.  We do not see a robust gas price environment in 2010, as we believe there is abundant supply currently available, and we believe supply response may overwhelm any positive gas price pressure.</p>
          <p>In light of this view, in 2010, we will plan to drill only 93 gas wells versus 114 expected for 2009.  As in our 2009 gas program, it is mostly focused on strategic wells, land expiries, and drainage concerns.</p>
          <p>However, in 2010 we'll shift more into the deep type unconventional targets with roughly 55% of the drilling focused in these areas versus 35% in 2009.  The great emphasis to deeper, longer life and more expensive wells will result in a decline in our gas production, effectively bottoming out in Q4 2010, and position us to return to gas growth in 2011.  This is particularly impressive considering we're only drilling 93 gas wells in 2010, compared to 900 gas wells in 2005, when we were growing at 5%.</p>
          <p>This leads us to believe, which I stated earlier, that any positive price increase will likely be met with a significant supply response.  Caution is prudent, and it also reinforces the soundness of our balanced portfolio approach.</p>
          <p>Canadian Natural's heavy and thermal assets in Canada are very strong and will continue to add tremendous value to Canadian Natural's shareholders.  Our thermal assets alone have 33 billion barrels of oil in place and 5.6 billion barrels recoverable in our defined plan.</p>
          <p>Our plan is to add approximately 300,000 barrels a day of heavy oil production in a very stepwise, disciplined and cost controlled manner.  In 2010, we'll continue to execute the defined plan with roughly $500 million allocated to our thermal properties.  Most of this capital is allocated to the continued development of Primrose at Primrose North, East and Wolf Lake.  Production will average between 80 and 90,000 barrels a day in 2010, and since this is a cyclic process, we will see peaks and troughs of between 60 to 100,000 barrels a day.</p>
          <p>At Kirby, our next incremental 45,000 barrel a day production addition, we expect to receive regular approval in 2010.  We'll complete the detailed engineering design work and develop a more detailed cost assessment with a target of sanctioning Kirby in Q4 2010.  We expect to take a very disciplined approach to this engineering and construction at Kirby.  Taking a more measured and somewhat longer approach to achieve effective cost control.  As a result, we'd expect first steam in mid-2013.</p>
          <p>At Pelican Lake, we will in 2010 continue our program to convert the field to our highly successful Polymer Flood.  With roughly $450 million allocated to Pelican, we will push the areas of the field under Polymer Flood from 28% to 40% by the end of 2010.  And as you know, Pelican Lake is a world-class pool with four billion barrels in place and between 350 and 475 million barrels recoverable with the Polymer Flood.  A very large pool with very robust development economics.  Pelican Lake continues to generate significant value for shareholders.</p>
          <p>Our primary heavy oil Program continues to roll along effectively and efficiently.  In this commodity and cost environment, primary heavy oil generates top decile returns on capital in our asset portfolio.  Importantly, it also generates the quickest pay out and largest cash on cash return.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we will drill 600 primary heavy oil wells, a record number of primary wells for Canadian Natural.  Roughly 25% more than we would drill in 2009.  Our dominant, high quality land base, infrastructure and effective operations allow us to drill this size of program on a very cost effective basis, making primary heavy oil one of the best value generators in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Although we don't spend much time talking about our light oil portfolio in Canada, we have been quietly working these assets over the last number of years and the fruits of that work will begin to be executed on in 2010.  We will allocate over $300 million to light oil in Canada, drill over 100 wells, up from the 42 in 2009, initiate the optimization and development of significant enhanced oil recovery projects on our existing light oil pools.  In addition, we will drill 18 wells in 2010 on six new light oil exploration plays that we have been developed in the past couple of years.</p>
          <p>In keeping with light oil, in the North Sea, we'll spend roughly $200 million as we start up one drill string in Ninian in April 2010 and drill two wells and complete three well interventions.  And also take some subsidy work on the T-Block and upgrade facilities on all five platforms.</p>
          <p>In the North Sea, we're also preserving our capability to allocate additional capital to start up a second drill string later in 2010.  In offshore Salbecka, we'll allocate 260 million of capital.  Roughly 200 million will be to complete the development of Olowi in which we will complete the drilling and completion program and bring the remaining wells on-stream over the FPSO.  In addition we'll complete the S4 compression upgrade and progress preparatory work required before we drill our exciting deep water South African BIGI exploration project &#x2013; prospect.</p>
          <p>It's important to note that Offshore West Africa has some of the highest return on capital projects in our portfolio and along with the North Sea, generates significant free cash flow for Canadian Natural.</p>
          <p>Turning to Horizon.  Our world-class asset with over six billion barrels of recoverable oil, we have targeted to increase production to Phases Two to Three to 232,000 barrels a day and further expansions in Phases Four and Five to just under 500,000 barrels a day, or half a million barrels a day of light, sweet crude with no declines for 40 years and virtually no reserve replacement cost.  At Horizon, we will spend 785 million in 2010, up 40% from 2009.  Sustaining capital projects make up about 160 million of this capital or roughly four to $5 a barrel of sustaining capital.  Growth capital will include 435 million for continued work on Tranche 2 of our Phase 2, 3 expansion.  In addition, we'll complete our detailed lessons learned from Phase 1 as we can incorporate any cost reduction or effectiveness measures into future expansions.</p>
          <p>Along with this work, we'll complete significant engineering on future expansions and prepare a more detailed cost estimate for roughly another $100 million.  And in my mind $100 million is significant engineering.  It is our expectation that we'll have a more detailed cost estimate by Q4 2010 and a better understanding of any modifications we may want to make to our execution strategy.  This work will be completed to give us better certainty on costing in various environments.</p>
          <p>Canadian Natural is committed to the expansion of &#x2013; to 232,000 barrels a day and ultimately just under 500,000 barrels a day of light, sweet 34 degree API oil.  As always, Canadian Natural is very focused on cost control and creating value for shareholders.  And we will be sanctioning the expansion of Horizon, but only when we can be assured that reasonable costs and earnings can be achieved.  It's clear that Canadian Natural's in a very, very strong and enviable position.  Horizon is a world-class asset that is and will continue to add tremendous value to shareholders.</p>
          <p>Our Thermal heavy oil assets can add values similar in magnitude to Horizon yet in more manageable sizes and in my opinion are the hidden gem in our portfolio.  And in this low gas price environment, generating even greater value for shareholders.</p>
          <p>Our light oil assets, both internationally and in Canada, as well as our primary heavy oil assets in Canada, continuing to generate strong returns.  And in this low gas price environment, our strategy of maintaining a well-balanced <mark type="audio gap" /> and the fact that we are the low-cost producer, will ensure that we will be able to weather a sustained period of low gas prices.</p>
          <p>Our teams are strong throughout the company, and as Doug will point out, our balance sheet is strong and getting stronger.  Our capital program is very flexible, giving Canadian Natural the ability to not only maximize the value of our well-balanced portfolio, but also capture any opportunities that will present themselves in this environment.  Canadian Natural is strong, and in today's environment, with our team, our strategy, and our assets, I believe Canadian Natural has a clear competitive advantage.  And with that I'll turn it over to Doug to update you on our financial position and our prudent financial management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Steve, and good morning.  The third quarter marked the attainment of several financial goals Canadian Natural has set for itself in 2009.  First, we reduced long-term debt by 2.4 billion to 10.6 billion at the end of the third quarter.  Second, we strengthened our balance sheet, reducing debt-to-book capitalization from 41% at the beginning of the year to 36% at the end of the third quarter.  Today debt-to-book capitalization and debt-to-EBITDA are at the low end or below our internal guidelines of 35 to 45% and 1.8 to 2.8 times respectively.  Third, our liquidity position remains strong, with over $1.2 billion of available bank credit facilities.  Fourth, all of our operating divisions, the Canadian Conventional, Horizon, the North Sea, and Offshore West Africa are now generating positive free cash flow.  And fifth, our capital expenditure plans were implemented with the knowledge that cash flow was secured by our hedging programs in a very volatile commodity price environment.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter we generated $1.5 billion of cash flow from operations or $2.78 a share, and incurred $574 million in capital expenditures.  We also generated $658 million of net earnings, or $1.21 per share.  This capacity to generate cash flow across a diverse and balanced asset base with production from light, medium, heavy and synthetic crude oil and natural gas allows us to prepare our 2010 capital expenditure budget with confidence and puts us in a position to allocate excess cash flow to the highest return projects, new opportunities and further strengthening of our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>In order to ensure that our capital expenditure programs are successfully carried out, we continue to underpin cash flow with an active commodity hedge program in both crude oil and natural gas.  Close to 50% of our first half 2010 production is hedged with callers with a floor averaging over $60 WTI and ceilings of 75, 90 and $105 WTI.</p>
          <p>Second half production is hedged, near 25% of budgeted production.  We also have certain natural gas callers with a floor of $6 aCO for approximately 17% of our production.  Details of these programs are provided in our financial statements, and are also posted on our website.  Thank you.  And I will now return you to John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Steve, R&#xE9;al and Doug for all of your comments.  Consistent with our mission statement in our company, we will always strive to develop our extensive asset base in the most appropriate manner to create value for our shareholders.  And we do that on a consistent basis time after time after time.  With that, Operator, I would now like to open up the conference call to questions that people may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We will now take questions from the telephone lines.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  Our first question's from Arjun Murti of Goldman Sachs.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Steve, I think you mentioned that both Kirby and Horizon, have updated cost estimates around the fourth quarter of 2010.  It sounded like you're more confident that Kirby will be sanctioned.  I think Horizon you left more wiggle room.  I just wanted to make sure I understand the distinction there; maybe you're just further along on the Kirby spending.  And then perhaps the related follow-up would simply be is there some minimum ore price you need to have confidence in relative to the cost estimate to move forward with Horizon?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Arjun, thanks for that question.  I think you got it &#x2013; nailed it pretty much on the head.  We are further along in Kirby in our engineering, so we'll get there sooner, so we have a lot more confidence that we'll be completed and have a good cost estimate.</p>
          <p>Horizon is a much more complex and difficult execution strategy.  We have learned a lot from Phase 1, and there's still a lot to go, and we want to make sure that we have the optimum execution strategy, and the most flexible execution strategy going forward, because as you know, we don't want to get caught here with the higher oil price, and then get trapped in-between.</p>
          <p>And we also &#x2013; we need some regulatory approvals for Horizon to go forward on some of it.  So all in all, we're looking both for Q4 to get the cost estimates, and we will have those.  As far as sanction, I think it's pretty clear that Kirby is very likely to go ahead.  Horizon I think is likely, but we want to make sure we don't be premature and make sure we got it right before we go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it is possible that the costs come in and between continuing to run Phase 1 that you &#x2013; it's not inconceivable that you end up sanctioning Horizon as well at the end of next year?  Or do we &#x2013; should we really think about that as sort of 2011 type event?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would think there's a greater likelihood that it'll be early 2011 than late 2010.  But it all depends what the market is and how quickly we can pull our strategy together.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great.  And if I could just ask one balance sheet question, I believe you said you're within your comfort debt range, 35 to 45% debt-to-cap, and I think there was a second metric as well.  Just curious given the substantial free cash flow and obviously we're just coming off this terrible recession and big downdraft in oil prices, have you given consideration to actually using that free cash flow to have a much stronger balance sheet, perhaps a much lower debt level going forward, especially given that you are looking at some of these big long-lived &#x2013; long lead time type projects?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think that we're &#x2013; one of the focuses of the company is always to strengthen our balance sheet, and we have stretched it from time to time, primarily due to acquisitions in the past, and then we've always brought it back into line.  I think that one of the goals that we have for 2010 is to further strengthen this balance sheet and to further reduce debt levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. That's great.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is from Greg Pardy of RBC Capital Markets.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.  Could you &#x2013; Steve, can you just &#x2013; you touched on your offshore African exploration program.  Could you give a little bit of color on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I assume you're talking about South Africa, Greg?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously you know South Africa is, what we call BIGI exploration project, we've got four very large structures.  They are billion-barrel type in size.  We don't know if they're full of oil or full of water, but they're full of something.  And we have &#x2013; it's in deepwater, it's high current, so it'll be a very difficult and expensive well to drill.  And we're just making sure we got everything lined up before we do drill.  I expect we will drill, but more likely in 2011 before we drill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is from Andrew Potter of UBS Securities.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys.  It seems like you're talking a little bit more about Septimus and the potential development in the Montney.  Could you give us a little bit more background in terms of how many Montney wells you've drilled and what kind of results you've had?  And maybe a little bit in terms of what kind of running room you have at Septimus right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, we have, as you know, a fairly good land position here.  We have over 110 sections.  We have eight wells down now.  Results are very good and getting better.  With each new well we optimize our completion technique and lower the cost, and we get better production results.  So our last well here, it looks very, very strong.  And we're just completing a well now, and the costs there have come in probably 20 or 30% lower than the well we just drilled previously.  So we're learning very quickly.  There's quite a bit of running room.  We will build a 50 million a day plant here in 2010.  We'll monitor it.  I would say there's significant running room here, probably to take this thing maybe up to about 200 million a day, but there's no hurry to do that, particularly in this gas price environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And what &#x2013; just curious on your thoughts &#x2013; I mean what sort of gas price would you need on this development to pursue that 200 million a day development?  And how does that compare versus a conventional opportunity?  Like is this really seeming to be part of a lower cost part of the portfolio, I guess?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is a lower cost portion of our portfolio.  We do have some deep basin gases probably would compete.  The bigger issue for all our gas prospects, even the best ones, is can they compete with our oil prospects?  And that's a difficult thing to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  And one last question, just on the conventional heavy oil side.  If we end up with this period of tight differentials, I mean how quickly or how far can we grow the conventional production base, the conventional heavy oil over the next couple of years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The conventional primary heavy oil is, you drill a lot of wells, you add a lot of production, but they're very short life and they decline quickly.  So the production growth overall is moderate.  I think we can probably take it up to close to 100,000 barrels a day and hold it there.  But it's very difficult to get the big growth there because wells do decline quickly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.  Okay, that's great.  Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  Our next question is from Eli Lapp of Tricadia.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you.  Could you tell me how much is drawn on the credit facility?  And then perhaps sort of as an add-on to that, what your intentions would be with that facility?  Is it to term it out?  Is it just to use the free cash to pay it down, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  We have in place bank revolvers: One for $2.2 billion and another one for 1.5 billion.  They both mature in June of 2012, so we have a good life there.  At the end of September we had about $2.6 billion drawn on the two facilities.  They're revolving facilities, so we can pay them down and draw them back up.  We would like to leave those two facilities in place through their term, and then look at the financial and the credit markets in 2011 and 2012 prior to the maturity to determine what we would do.  But in my estimation we would keep those facilities in place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The one thing that I might add there is that in terms of maturity levels, debt maturity levels, we really only have the CDN $400 million coming due in December of 2010.  So debt retirement is on our mind, but obligatory debt retirement is a ways away.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is from Barbara Betanski of UBS Global Asset.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  I'm just wondering if you could elaborate a little bit on the light exploration &#x2013; light oil exploration play that you referred to, those 18 wells?  And what the potential is there and how much you're spending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Barb.  We have six different plays that we've been working on for a while, and will drill 18 wells on them as we said earlier.  They are in southeast Saskatchewan.  They are also in the Grande Prairie or northwest Alberta region, and a little bit in BC. So these are smaller pools, they're not going to be big, large pools, but they do have &#x2013; generate value, so I would think they range anywhere from maybe a five to 10 well pool up to a 20 well pool.  But they're smaller light oil pools, and in some cases we think we can probably put them under water flooding for increased recovery.  So we're just stepping out and trying to define that in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Our next question is from Peter Ogden of National Bank Financial.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  Just a quick question given the free cash flow you have in 2010.  Kind of maybe some more color on what your thoughts are on the acquisition market right now. And I mean would your overall view on gas prices that you've seen relatively bearish in 2010, does that color your view on gas acquisitions, and then going into 2011 would you buy something to set yourself up for 2011, and what's going to change in the gas market that makes you more bullish in 2011 for the gas markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer the last part of that question first.  I think what will make us more bullish on cash prices in 2011 is if we see a muted supply response.  We believe shale gas is real, tight gas is real, and part of that is because we've got a pretty significant holding here in Canada so we know the cost.  So we feel pretty confident that if prices go up, it won't take long for a strong supply response and it'll bring those prices back down.  So if that supply response is not as what we'd anticipate, then gas prices probably would be stronger than we think in 2011.</p>
          <p>As far as acquisitions, as you know, we're optimistic or opportunistic and we look at anything that's in our core area, and if we can see value and we can add value, then we'll look at those acquisitions.  But we don't ever sort of throw the gauntlet down and say we will do them.  We only &#x2013; we take them if they come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  There are no further questions registered at this time, Mr. Langille.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, operator, and thank you, ladies and gentlemen, for attending this conference call.  And as usual, if you have any further questions, do not hesitate to call us.  Have a good day, and we'll talk to you later.  Bye, bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The conference has now ended.  Please disconnect your lines at this time, and we thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>