<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1293765" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-03-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1564</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John G. Langille, Vice-Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Allan P. Markin, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Steve W. Laut, President</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Lyle G. Stevens, Senior Vice President, Exploitation</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">R&#xE9;al J.H. Doucet, Senior Vice President, Horizon Projects</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Douglas A. Proll, Chief Financial Officer and Senior Vice President, Finance</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Andrew Fairbanks</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Arjun Murti</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Greg Pardy</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">David Wheeler</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Mark Friesen</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Kam Sandhar</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Brian Dutton</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="corprep">Steven Laut</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the Canadian Natural Resources 2009 Fourth Quarter and Year-End Results Conference Call. I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. John Langille, Vice Chairman of Canadian Natural Resources. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator, and good morning, everyone. Thank you for attending our conference call. We will discuss our 2009 results and also update our plans for 2010. Participating with me today are Allan Markin, our Chairman; Steve Laut, our President; Lyle Stevens, our Senior VP of Exploitation, who will discuss reserves; R&#xE9;al Doucet, our Senior Vice President of Oil Sands, who will talk about the progress we're making at Horizon; and Doug Proll, our Senior Vice President of Finance who will discuss our overall financial position.</p>
          <p>Before we start, I would refer you to the comments regarding forward-looking information contained in our press release and also note that all dollar amounts are in Canadian dollars and production and reserves are both expressed as before royalties unless otherwise stated.</p>
          <p>I'll just make some initial comments before I turn the call over to the other participants. I think you can see that reflective of our disciplined allocation of capital over the last several years and the completion of our oil mining project, we can see Canadian Natural evolving into a very large oil-weighted producer with a great amount of economic natural gas production. In the fourth quarter of 2009 our oil production, including synthetic oil, amounted to 64% of production on a volume basis and almost 80% on a revenue basis.</p>
          <p>The last half of 2008 into 2009 saw a weakening in commodity prices. Crude oil prices in the last half of 2009 recovered to the 65 to $75 West Texas range. However, natural gas prices continued to be under pressure throughout the year. We were able to mitigate the resulting decline in our revenues through our very strong hedging strategy for about one half of our oil production.</p>
          <p>As a result of our ability to generate strong cash flow and our disciplined approach to capital expenditures, we have repaid a significant amount of our long-term debt and exited 2009 with a debt to equity ratio of 33%, under the low end of our targeted level. At this time we are also targeting further debt reductions during 2010.</p>
          <p>It appears crude oil pricing will continue to hold at recent levels of 70 to $80 West Texas with accompanying differentials for heavy oil in the low to mid-teens. Natural gas prices continue to be under pressure. Accordingly as Steve discusses our properties and developments you will see a relatively small allocation of capital to natural gas projects and continued emphasis on our oil prospects.</p>
          <p>We have allocated some of our free cash flow with a 43% increase in dividends and potential for a share buy-back. In addition we will be proposing to the shareholders at our upcoming AGM to split our shares on a two-for-one basis.</p>
          <p>Before we turn the call over to Steve, I'd ask Allan to make some comments. Allan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. Good morning. Canadian Natural's defined growth plan continues to deliver value to our shareholders in all economic conditions. 2009 proved to be an unpredictable year for commodity prices as oil remained low through the first half of the year and natural gas prices continued to be unstable. However, with a large inventory of projects and by using our expertise within the company, we were able to deliver another solid year at Canadian Natural.</p>
          <p>Production at Horizon, commencing near the beginning of the year, was a milestone for the company. The amount we have learned during construction and through ramp-up is invaluable and our team continues to apply their knowledge of the plant to ensure reliable production for years to come. We continue to unlock the enormous value of this resource.</p>
          <p>Our conventional business delivered another quarter and full year of strong results. Our industry-leading position in heavy crude oil in Western Canada is allowing us to capture significant value as heavy oil differentials remain favorable. We continue to apply our marketing strategies to the business to make certain we deliver the best return from our assets.</p>
          <p>In our continued effort to generate returns for our shareholders, the Board of Directors has approved a quarterly dividend increase to $0.60 per common share, a 43% increase over '09. The company began paying dividends in 2001 and has subsequently increased the amount every year since, which again shows discipline in our approach and the ability to provide value creation to our shareholders. As 2010 is well underway, we continue to add value for our shareholders. We are always evaluating our assets and look to develop them in the most cost-effective manner to ensure we deliver the best possible returns for many years to come. Our people, plan and assets will deliver.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Al, and good morning, everyone.</p>
          <p>As both John and Al have said, Q4 was a strong quarter for Canadian Natural. Oil production was up 18% over the fourth quarter 2008, driven by strong performance production volumes at Horizon and our heavy oil assets. In Q4 we made good progress at Primrose East and at Horizon we are making good although bumpy progress towards reliable operations and design capacity. It's clear the design and functionality of Horizon is there to deliver at or above nameplate capacity. What we have struggled to achieve over the cold winter months is plant reliability.</p>
          <p>As expected, our operating costs remain low and well within our operating cost guidance for the year which we lowered in Q2. Our capital program in 2010 will be $3.9 billion, up 26% from 2009 capital program, with increased capital allocations to oil, 80% of all capital, and in particular primary heavy oil, Pelican Lake, Horizon expansion preparation and increased enhanced oil recovery projects in our portfolio. As well, we are kicking off the early stages of the first phase at the Septimus, Montney shale gas development.</p>
          <p>As a result of this capital program and capital programs in prior years, we'll see production grow 7% year-over-year and 17% entry to exit, generating a 12% increase in cash flow, and more importantly, free cash flow in the two to $2.6 billion range. Clearly this reflects the strength of Canadian Natural's balanced and diverse asset base, our focus on low-cost, disciplined and effective operations as well as the overall soundness of our strategy. We are growing production and generating substantial free cash flow. We are in a great position.</p>
          <p>In 2010 Canadian Natural will allocate the free cash flow in the following three priorities: pay down debt and further strengthen our balance sheet is ongoing; allocate capital to additional asset-development opportunities and acquisitions, and at this point we have not allocated any additional capital; dividends, as you heard, have increased by 43% today; and share buybacks we have issued a normal pre-course issuer bid. Doug will address both dividend and share buybacks in a few minutes, but before I briefly update you on each of our assets, I'll ask Lyle to give you a brief overview of our year-end reserves. Lyle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Before I start our reserves discussion, I'd like to point out that as in previous years 100% of our reserves are externally evaluated and reviewed by independent qualified evaluators. To better understand our disclosure, I'd like to briefly outline two items that may help as you review our 2009 year-end reserves.</p>
          <p>The first is that as of January 1, 2010 the synthetic crude oil reserves associated with Horizon are now reported with crude oil and natural gas reserves due to changes in the SEC regulations. The second is related to the impact of the SEC pricing upon our reserves. This pricing model averages the prices from the first day of every month in 2009. For 2009 this resulted in a significant decrease in the natural gas prices from the 2008 evaluation and a significant increase in crude oil prices.</p>
          <p>The decrease in natural gas pricing has resulted in the loss of some late-life reserves and also the loss of some reserves associated with undeveloped drilling opportunities. The increase in crude oil prices improves economics, but results in higher calculated royalties for Alberta oil sands projects, and also accelerates payout of these projects. This impacts the net reserves that we report for Horizon, our thermal assets, Pelican Lake and a few of our primary heavy oil assets.</p>
          <p>Now moving onto our results. With the addition of the Horizon synthetic crude oil, our net proved crude oil and NGL reserves now total 3.03 billion barrels, and 4.74 billion barrels for net proved and probable. For natural gas our total net proved reserves are 3.18 Tcf and our net proved and probable reserves are 4.21 Tcf.</p>
          <p>Our 2009 net proved finding and on-stream costs were $19.81 per BOE and $22.64 per BOE for proved and probable. These numbers exclude Horizon reserves and capital. Now that Horizon is on-stream, the company's proved undeveloped reserves total 25% of our total proved reserves, a very low percentage. Revisions due to price for net proved gas resulted in the loss of 337 Bcf. For proved crude oil, including Horizon, revisions due to price resulted in the loss of 326 million barrels.</p>
          <p>Excluding the impact of price revisions that I just mentioned, our finding and on-stream costs would have been very good, $12.28 per BOE for proved reserves and $7.74 per proved and probable reserves. Both numbers exclude Horizon.</p>
          <p>In North American operations, again excluding Horizon, we achieved solid finding and on-stream costs of $12.78 per BOE for net proved reserves and $16.10 per BOE for net proved and probable reserves. Without the price revisions these numbers would have been a very impressive $6.45 per BOE for proved and $5.32 per BOE for proved and probable.</p>
          <p>Internationally, we had positive revisions due to price, but these were largely offset by negative technical revisions. This resulted in no net increase in our international reserves.</p>
          <p>In summary, these results reflect the strength and depth of our asset base. In 2009 even in a challenging price environment we were able to high grade our capital program and direct activity to those assets that provided the best returns and lowest finding costs. I'd now like to return the call back to Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lyle. As you can see, Canadian Natural is in a very strong reserve position and set to deliver strong value growth in the years to come. Turning in more detail, asset by asset, first to gas in Canada. As you know Canadian Natural has the largest land base in western Canada. Canadian Natural dominates the land base and infrastructure in our core areas and as a result we are a low cost producer.</p>
          <p>Our gas land base is well positioned with strong assets and teams in conventional, foothills, resource and unconventional plays. Canadian Natural's plan in 2010 is not only to preserve but to strengthen our dominant gas asset base. Over the last two to three years, Canadian Natural has quietly been transforming the makeup of our dominant land base to the point where today roughly 50% of our gas location inventory is made up of tight, sand or shale gas, unconventional gas plays.</p>
          <p>Unfortunately we do not see a robust gas price environment in 2010 and 2011 does not look much better, as we believe there's an abundant supply of gas currently available and that the supply response may overwhelm any positive gas price pressure that might materialize.</p>
          <p>As a result of this view and the fact that our returns on the oil portion of our portfolio are so much better than gas, we will drill only 93 gas wells in 2010. This limited gas program is mostly focused on strategic wells, land expirees and drainage concerns. However in 2010 we'll continue to shift into the more deep, tight, unconventional targets with roughly 55% of the drilling focused in these areas versus 35% in 2009.</p>
          <p>The greater emphasis to deeper, longer life and more expensive wells will result in the decline of our production, effectively bottoming out in Q4 2010 and position us to return to gas growth in 2011, if we so choose. This is particularly impressive considering we are only drilling 93 gas wells in 2010 compared to 900 gas wells in 2005 when we were growing gas at 5%. This leads us to believe which I stated earlier that any positive price increase will likely be met with a significant supply response.</p>
          <p>It pays to be patient and cautious, a path Canadian Natural has the luxury to pursue because of our balanced asset portfolio and our strong oil assets. And Canadian Natural's heavy and thermal oil assets in Canada are very strong and will continue to add tremendous value for Canadian Natural shareholders. Our thermal assets alone have 33 billion barrels of oil in place with 5.6 billion recoverable in our defined plan. Our plan is to add approximately 300,000 barrels a day of heavy oil production in a very step-wise, disciplined, cost controlled manner.</p>
          <p>In 2010 we'll continue to execute the defined plan with roughly 500 million being allocated to our thermal properties. Most of this capital is allocated to the continued development of Primrose, at Primrose North, East and Wolf Lake. Production will average between 80 to 90,000 barrels a day in 2010 and since this is a cyclic process we will see peaks and troughs of between 60 to 100,000 barrels a day.</p>
          <p>Primrose East is our most recent incremental step on the road to 300,000 barrels a day of incremental production. As is well known, we had a continuing issue at Primrose East in early 2009. Diagnostic steaming is proceeding to plan and we expect to see production average roughly 16,000 to 20,000 barrels in 2010 as we slowly return to normal steaming activities.</p>
          <p>At Kirby, our next incremental 45,000 barrel a day production addition, we expect to receive regulatory approval in 2010. We will complete the detailed engineering design work and develop a more detailed cost estimate with a target of sanctioning Kirby in Q4 2010. We are taking a very disciplined approach to the engineering construction of Kirby to ensure effective cost control with first steaming targeted for mid-2013.</p>
          <p>At Pelican Lake, we continue in 2010 to roll our program to convert the field to our highly successful polymer flood. With roughly $450 million allocated to Pelican, we'll push the area of the field under polymer flood from 28% to 40% by the end of 2010. As you know, Pelican Lake is a world-class pool, with 4 billion barrels in place and between 350 and 475 million barrels recoverable with polymer flood, a very large pool, with very robust development economics. Pelican Lake continues to generate significant value for shareholders.</p>
          <p>Our primary heavy oil program continues to roll along effectively and efficiently, and in this commodity and cost environment, primary heavy oil generates top-decile returns on capital in our asset portfolio. It importantly also generates the quickest payout and largest cash-on-cash return. In 2010 we will drill 600 primary heavy wells, a record number of primary wells for Canadian Natural, roughly 25% more than we drilled in 2009.</p>
          <p>Our dominant high quality land base, infrastructure and effective operations allow us to drill this size of program on a very cost-effective basis, making primary heavy oil one of the best value generators in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>And although we don't spend much time talking about our light oil portfolio in Canada, we have been quietly working these assets over the last number of years. The fruits of that work will begin to be executed this year. We will allocate over $300 million to light oil in Canada, drill over 100 wells, up from 42 in 2009, initiate the authorization and development of significant EOR projects on our existing light oil pools.</p>
          <p>In keeping with light oil, in the North Sea production has been steady. In Q1 we are preparing to start-up one drill string in Ninian in April and drill two wells, complete three well interventions, as well as undertake some subsea work on the T-Block and upgrade facilities in all five platforms. In the North Sea we are also preserving our capability to allocate additional capital by having the ability to start up a second drill string later in 2010.</p>
          <p>In offshore West Africa at Olowi in Gabon we continue to drill off the B Platform and monitor production from the C Platform. As we previously stated in the 2009 results for the C Platform have been well below expectations and may potentially have an impact on reserves. But based on the performance to date on the C Platform, we have now taken $115 million write down. The real results for the B Platform look better at this point than C, and we are currently drilling a fourth well in the platform. The pipelines and umbilicals have been connected from the FPSO to Platform B, and we are currently commissioning the platform with first oil from Platform B expected by the end of April. Although it's too early to tell, we are optimistic that Platform B production will be better than Platform C.</p>
          <p>In C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire we are currently installing the additional compression in Espoir to handle increased associated gas production, and production performance of both Espoir and Baobab in C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire is strong and meeting our expectations. It is important to note that offshore West Africa has some of the highest return on capital projects in our portfolio and along with the North Sea generates significant free cash flow for Canadian Natural.</p>
          <p>Turning to Horizon, we continue to make good progress driving towards sustained reliability. There is no question the operation can and has delivered at or above 110,000 barrels a day of SCO design capacity. We do, however, continue to struggle with maintaining plant reliability as we continue to work out operational kinks, equipment failures and the compounding effect of cold weather in December and January has had on our ability to quickly recover from equipment failures. The production by month is as follows: October, 71,202 barrels a day; November, 97,287 barrels a day; December when we had equipment problems, 42,495 barrels a day. We recovered in January to 72,000 barrels a day; and now in February we're running around 84,200 barrels a day; and looking strong so far in March.</p>
          <p>We have faced many issues, almost all seem to be first-time issues here at Horizon and we are working our way through all these issues and expect at some point in the near future we will see the end of a string of equipment and operational issues.</p>
          <p>I will turn over to R&#xE9;al now to give you a brief account of some of these issues we have faced and what risks we could see that could impact us in 2010. R&#xE9;al?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Steve. Good morning, everyone.</p>
          <p>I will give you just an example of issues we had to deal with, starting with the mine. We had the mine ore body issue which was a combination of high clay content and low blending capabilities since we were operating the mine at the beginning only on two benches. Since August we have accelerated the opening of the third bench which is fully operational now. We have also stockpiled the high clay content ore which we are inserting back into the production about 10% rate. And we have also developed new operating parameters in the froth treatment plant to cope with this combination. All in all right now we have seen great success with this approach and this problem is behind us now.</p>
          <p>Second one is in the ore preparation plant. We have higher wear than anticipated into this plant and the component change-out schedule is coming faster at us than anticipated. So we have to readjust our preventative maintenance.</p>
          <p>Combined with this also was a design change for our secondary crusher which was a first in the oil sand of this kind, and that change right now we have confirmed here over the past two weeks that the design is adequate and this problem now is behind us. Our maintenance schedule has been readjusted as well to cope with the wear that we have on this plant. So this issue also is behind us now.</p>
          <p>Going into the Hydrogen plant, this is the one we had a major issue in December, where we have the forced-draft fan problems. This was due to a start-up problem that we have when we put this plant in operation. That has been fixed also, and it's behind us. In the Hydrogen plant we had also hot tubes in the reformer and we had a couple of leaks, which have been plugged. This problem is behind us as well.</p>
          <p>So is the, if you remember, we've talked about the PSA valves. We had 84 valves that had to be changed in this plant because of bad designs with bad fabrication that started from the suppliers. And we have changed them. We entered into a program with the suppliers to change them. Two weeks ago, they have been all changed out now. The schedule was based on the capability of the supplier to supply these valves. So this problem is behind us now and the Hydrogen plant has been performing really well since, and all these issues are behind us.</p>
          <p>The last one is the coker. We have coking in the furnace which we had to prematurely de-coke, and we also had to change one of the convection sections because it was coked beyond de-coking. So we have enhanced our operational procedure with the help of the licenser. We have also changed our picking sequence. This problem, also, even though not totally behind us yet, will be behind us also by the end of March.</p>
          <p>We also had a heat exchanger that we were operating under lower performance for a while until we received a new one. We did receive the new one here three weeks ago and it has been changed already. The sulfur plant now is performing according to spec. So, all-in-all, right now all of these problems, or the majority of them are behind us. We don't foresee any major issue from now on. However, we want to be cautious about it. We're predicting that throughout the summer we should be back here into high performance at this plant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, R&#xE9;al.</p>
          <p>As you can see, we've faced many issues, but we have very quickly mitigated most of these issues, reflecting the strength and dedication of our operations team. It's important to remember that Horizon is a world-class asset with over six billion barrels of recoverable oil. And we have targeted to increase production through Phases II and III to 232,000 barrels a day and future expansions in Phases IV and V to just under 500,000 barrels a day, or half a million barrels a day of light, sweet crude, with no declines for 40 years and virtually no reserve replacement costs.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we continue to work on Tranche 2 of our Phase 2 and 3 expansion. In addition we are well on our way to completing our detailed lessons learned from Phase 1, so we can incorporate any cost reduction or effect of those measures into future expansions. Along with this work we'll complete significant engineering on future expansions and prepare a more detailed cost estimate. It is our expectation that we will have a more detailed cost estimate by Q4 2010 and a better understanding of any modifications that may make our execution strategy more effective. This work will be completed to give better certainty on costing in various environments.</p>
          <p>Canadian Natural is committed to the expansion of Horizon to 232,000 barrels a day and ultimately just under 500,000 barrels a day of light sweet 34&#xB0;API oil. As always, Canadian Natural is very focused on cost control and creating value for shareholders, and we will be sanctioning the expansion of Horizon but only when we can insure that reasonable cost certainty can be achieved. It is clear that Canadian Natural is in a very strong and enviable position. Horizon is a world-class asset that is and will continue to add tremendous value to shareholders.</p>
          <p>Our thermal heavy oil assets can add value similar to the magnitude of Horizon yet in more manageable sizes and in my opinion, are the hidden gem in our portfolio. And in this low cost gas price environment, generate even greater value for our shareholders. Our light oil assets both internationally and in Canada as well as our primary heavy oil assets in Canada continue to generate strong returns.</p>
          <p>In this low gas price environment our strategy of maintaining a well balanced portfolio and the fact that we are a low cost producer will insure that we can be able to weather a sustained period of low gas prices. Our teams are strong throughout the company and as Doug will point out, our balance sheet is strong and getting stronger. Our capital program is very flexible, giving Canadian Natural the ability not only to maximize the value of our well balanced portfolio, but also capturing any opportunities that will present themselves in this environment. Canadian Natural is in a great position, and in today's environment with our team, our strategy and our assets, I believe Canadian Natural has a clear, competitive advantage.</p>
          <p>With that I'll turn it over to Doug to update you on our strong financial position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Steve, and good morning. Financially 2009 for Canadian Natural will stand out for several reasons. Production of synthetic crude oil from the Horizon Oil Sands Mining and Upgrading operations commenced, established a new product stream further diversifying our oil and natural gas portfolio. All of our operating divisions, North American Conventional, Horizon Oil Sands Mining and Upgrading, the North Sea and Offshore West Africa, are generating positive free cash flow. The balance sheet strength was significantly improved. Long-term debt was reduced by $3.3 billion to 9.7 billion in 2009. Our balance sheet metrics of debt to book capitalization and debt to EBITDA are 33% and 1.4 times respectively.</p>
          <p>A strong cash liquidity position has been maintained over the last several years, and we exited 2009 with $2 billion of available credit under our banking facilities.</p>
          <p>Other financial highlights for 2009 included the generation of over $6 billion of cash flow from operations or $11.24 per share underpinned by our 2009 commodity hedge program and the generation of $3 billion of free cash flow, which was substantially applied to debt.</p>
          <p>We continued to carry on with an active commodity hedge program due to the relative uncertainty of the economic recovery and continued volatility in commodity prices. We have close to 50% of our 2010 first half oil production with collars with a floor exceeding $60 WTI. Second half production is hedged at roughly 25% of budgeted production.</p>
          <p>We also have several natural gas collars in place with a floor of $6 AECO on 17% of our production, as well some are positions on 400,000 GJs per year with a floor of $4.50 AECO. These positions are detailed in the financial statements and are posted on our website.</p>
          <p>As you heard previously, the Board of Directors in assessing the financial and operational strength and maturity of Canadian Natural declared a 43% increase in the quarterly dividend to $0.15 per share. They also proposed that we file a normal course issuer bid for up to 2.5% of the company's issued shares, subject to regulatory acceptance, and finally they proposed a two-for-one subdivision of common shares subject to shareholders' approval in May. We believe that these three events provide top-tier returns to our shareholders, strengthen our commitment to invest in the highest return opportunities and enhance the liquidity of the common shares.</p>
          <p>Thank you, and I will return you to John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, everyone, for your summaries and additional comments. I think you can see that we are all looking forward to execution of our plans throughout the balance of 2010 and into 2011. And with that, operator, I would open up the call to questions that people may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question is from Andrew Fairbanks from Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Good morning, guys. I had two questions for you. First, as you look at the opportunities in your conventional Canadian business, where do you rank out the most economic projects? I mean you mentioned the primary heavy; I don't know if that would be the very best, versus polymer or other light oil projects you might have. I don't know if within your asset base there's anything Cardium-like that may be intriguing that may not be developed this year but might be interesting going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, Steve Laut here. So that's a good question. And I'd say it depends how you want to evaluate the economic parameters. Our primary heavy oil obviously gives us a very quick payout and a great return on capital. Polymer flooding at Pelican Lake also gives us a very good return but obviously the payouts are a little longer and it's a longer-life project. Again, if you look at thermal, again the payouts are a little longer but returns on capital are robust, probably not as robust as primary heavy oil, but again the project life is much longer and more sustainable.</p>
          <p>As far as light oil, we do have, as you know, the second largest &#x2013; or the largest land base in Western Canada and almost by definition we do know we have a lot of these tight oil Cardium-like oil plays that can be unlocked with technology and we are working on some of those. But they're not going to really move the dial for us, but we do have those opportunities. And of course gas obviously in North America is &#x2013; just has a tough time competing with any of the oil projects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Now, that's great, thanks. And then just a small question, would you have a sense for what the Horizon operating cost would have been in November when you were running well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our operating costs in November were $33 a barrel, Canadian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, great. Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The following question is from Arjun Murti from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. First question was just on your upgrader strategy in light of I think what is generally a narrower outlook for light/heavy spreads. I think I'm pretty familiar that with the thermal oil expansions or at least Kirby or the next few, you're no longer planning to go forward with the big upgrader you had mentioned several years ago. But I was wondering how the light/heavy outlook would impact Horizon. We've always assumed that all the future phases of Horizon get the type of big upgraders like you built in Phase I, but I was wondering if you could provide any comments in terms of how the environment might impact upgraders for Horizon in the future. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Arjun, and thanks for that question. It gives me a good chance to talk about my favorite topic. As you know, the light-heavy spreads have narrowed considerably, particularly with the expansion of pipeline capacity of the Gulf Coast and that future capacity that will be there. So as historically the heavy oil differentials have been in that 30 to 45%, averaging about 32%. Pertaining to heavy crude we think that has structurally changed and right now, as you know, Canadian heavy crude differentials are probably in that 10% range, very low. We don't see that as sustainable. We think where probably Canadian heavy crude will move to the historical average that you've seen for Mayan crude in that 22, maybe 24%. So that's where we think we'll be.</p>
          <p>As far as upgraders go in Horizon, we still see that putting an upgrader at Horizon does make sense. A standalone upgrader is difficult and you have to have some very good economic conditions to make it work in the long run. That being said, we do know that heavy oil prices do swing; it's a volatile market and it does make sense to have some sort of hedge or natural hedge by having upgrading capacity.</p>
          <p>When it comes to Horizon itself, the upgrader is in a sense is a special situation. As you know we capture a tremendous amount of heat from the upgrader. We'll also capture CO2 from the upgrader on the Hydrogen plant and I'll talk in a minute why that's important. And the heat integration obviously lowers our costs overall because we use the low grade heat from the upgrader to help in extraction. The other thing is for us to sell bitumen direct versus upgrading means we would have to switch from a naphthenic to a paraffinic process in the extraction plant. That process is the same process that Shell and Exxon will be using at Kearl Lake and obviously it can be done.</p>
          <p>The costs, the capital costs are much higher. And for us to go to that for the next phases, the incremental capital costs versus incremental capital costs of doing an upgrader and capturing that value and the heat make more sense for us to go to a fully integrated, upgrading solution at Horizon. And unless things change that looks likely which way we'll end. Of course, we're evaluating that all the time.</p>
          <p>I'm giving a long-winded answer here, but I want to talk a little bit about the CO2. One of the advantages we have with the Horizon is that we are right now trucking CO2 to Horizon. We'll capture CO2 here in our Tranche 3 of expansion from the Hydrogen plant. That CO2 we mix with our tailings as it's sent up to the tailings pond and we are getting excellent results. We're getting excellent separation at the tailings pond or on the way to the tailings pond and so that we in fact actually have 12 meters of relatively clear water in our tailings pond.</p>
          <p>What this means is that we are now essentially recycling water and we have only used 12% of our utilization of water that we expected out of the river. So in essence on the process side, we're using total recycled water to run the process. That's all due to the fact that our CO2 process in the tailings is working really well. This actually captures the CO2 and sequesters it forever. So it's a great environmental thing, and it reduces the size of the pond as well. So when we go to the next stage, I will look at putting in thickeners on the tailings. That will again allow us to get the water back sooner and be warmer, and reduce our costs as well. So there's an operating cost savings as well. So thanks for the question that allowed me to get on the soap box.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, thank you very much. That's a very thorough and helpful answer. I think I have a very short follow-up, which is on your Primrose East comments and the 16,000 to 20,000 barrels a day I think you said for 2010. How should we think about the timeframe for ramping that back up? Is that progressively over the year or second half? Any thoughts there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we'll slowly increase the steam up as we go through the year. We're being very cautious. The regulator wants us to be cautious, and quite frankly we are bound by what the regulator requests us to do or allows us to do. We think we'll increase the steaming as we go throughout 2010. I would see us probably get back to steaming production levels in 2011 closer to design capacity. But I think that'll be more like mid 2011. But it all depends what happens. We don't &#x2013; as we're still in diagnostic steaming you can't actually predict if, when you're going to have something happen to you. So we've got to go through the process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That makes sense. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The following question is from Greg Pardy from RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. Most of my questions have been answered, but Steve, just rectifying the clay content in the fourth quarter, did that impact Horizon operating costs all that much? Or was it mostly just volume?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It didn't impact the operating costs that much. It might have increased us maybe $0.50 to at the most $0.70 a barrel in fourth quarter. Obviously we're still stockpiling right now, but that will end here once we get the Bench 3 fully opened up and obviously we've got to move that material twice, so it's stockpiled, so there's a cost of moving it back into the process. So it'll have to be done mostly in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The following question is from Dominique Sabia from Interstate Asset Advisors . Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. My question is about cash flow. My question is about cash flow, and I wanted to know about your Horizon project about the future royalties. How soon will you have to pay the higher royalties to the Canadian government for, after you reach full return of your money out? Do you have any idea how far out that would be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is quite a ways out. Right now it all depends on what kind of oil price forecast you use. I think we're looking well into 2020s and maybe into 2030 before it pays out. So obviously the government has changed the way the royalties work so you do pay a higher royalty before payout now, and it's all price based in Alberta. And so the payout is quite a ways away yet and we pay up on the bitumen side of the process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One follow-up question. Will you have forecasts by month for Horizon for the first four months of '10 and will they be on your website?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We won't have forecasts. We have guidance for the year and the quarterly guidance for Horizon, which is on our website by not by month. What we will do is we will publish the production as it becomes available on our website for past months so that people can keep closer track of our production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The following question is from David Wheeler from AllianceBernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Steve, what you might want to do when you publish the monthly production number is that also would be helpful would be to publish a monthly operating cost number for Horizon like you provided for November.</p>
          <p>I've got two questions. Gas production, you mention you've got the option to return to growth after the fourth quarter of 2010. Knowing what you know about service costs, what gas price would it take to return to growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's a two part question, what kind of gas price it would require. It also depends how good our oil projects are because we allocate capital obviously to the highest return projects. So I think even if you had gas prices at $6 an Mcf oil is still a lot better. So you do more gas but oil still looks a lot better. So if you get into that 5.50 to $6 range, I think we would start to look at some of our better gas plays allocating more capital. But, again, it depends on what the oil price is and how we allocate capital relative to each other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as Op costs go, you just about gave our accountants here a heart attack by saying they have to publish Op costs within the same month. It takes a while to get all the costs in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Makes sense. And on that &#x2013; if we had an environment of 5.50, $6 gas and we allocated a bit more to the gas projects, would that give you a flattish growth profile do you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think &#x2013; to be honest with you, as you can tell from our comments, we're not really optimistic that gas prices are going to come back very soon. So it's not something that we are really spending a lot of time planning. Our view is gas prices are going to be fairly low for 2010, and it might be tough to get any kind of price increase for 2011. So at this point in time, it's probably too early for us to sort of speculate what we'd do on the gas side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And can you guys provide &#x2013; you touched on it in your prepared comments, but reserve, negative reserve revisions in the oil sands, either the thermal or Horizon, and you mentioned there was a royalty effect and accelerated path. Can you go through where the reserves came down? Was it on the thermal or Horizon, by how much, and what were the factors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know if we can give you all a complete detailed breakdown, but I think, Lyle, can tell you generally where it came from and what caused each, if you'd like. Lyle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Horizon is very simple and that's actually in our disclosure. So we lost 307 million barrels at Horizon. The other most significant impact was on our thermal operations where we lost 70 million barrels due to pricing. And then at Pelican Lake it's a significantly smaller amount, around 7 million barrels, and even smaller on our primary heavy oil assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And when you say due to pricing, help me out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we end up doing to calculate the impact due to pricing is we take last year's reserves and we run it with this year's prices, and the difference in reserves is called a price revision. So it incorporates shutting off reserves if they become economic, it incorporates changes in the royalties. So for our Horizon and our thermal operations, almost all of the impact is due to changing in the royalties.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, right. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you know, David, the royalties increased, the price increased now with the Alberta royalties. So the higher prices means we have less net reserves to put on our books.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, now I'm with you. Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The following question is from Mark Friesen from Versant Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. A follow-up question with respect to your comments on Horizon, Steve. I was wondering if CNQ has any I guess disputes with the provincial government with respect to the deemed bitumen price and if there's been any hold-back to your royalty payments to the government on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, we don't have any disputes with the Alberta government at this time and we're working well with them, so there's no hold-backs or anything else going on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good. With respect to Pelican, I was wondering if you could go through the impact of the poly flood as it relates to the reserve bookings, expectations for 2010 and going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't actually try to give predictions on what we're going to do for reserve adds in the year going ahead. We do know, and maybe Lyle can expand on this a little bit more on the reserve side of it, but we will be drilling quite a few wells at Pelican Lake. A lot of those are producers and a lot of them are injectors for polymer and as you know, it takes a while before you get a production performance. We would expect that that would convert some of our proven undeveloped reserves at Pelican Lake into proved producing, and it would add also will add more proved undeveloped polymer flood area into our reserve. So I don't know if Lyle can actually make a very good prediction as to what the magnitude of that would be for 2010, but it will be substantial I would think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It does get tough to predict for 2010. Certainly over the past three years that we've been injecting polymer, the performance has continued to improve. In our reserves that are currently booked, the best performing areas are now up to a 27% ultimate recovery factor. And of course there's a full range anywhere from 5% to 27%. And over time with more historical data we are hopeful that that will continue to grow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Mark, to help you out as you know we've got about 28% of the pool under polymer flood today. And we hope by the end of the year we'll have bout 40% under polymer flood. And Lyle's kind of giving the range as we go from primary about 5% and then the very, very best 27%. I think he's saying we can get to 25% if we do well. So it gives you a magnitude of where it could be based on percentage of polymer flood the field will be under this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No, that's a great answer. Thank you. Just wanted to touch on one thing you had mentioned in your prepared remarks. You mentioned something about you have an intention to strengthen your land base surrounding your natural gas position. And then you made several comments with respect to not more aggressively pursuing your natural gas portfolio at present. So I wonder if you could reconcile that thought for me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what you have to look at, Mark, is as you know we are the largest land base holder in Western Canada, and by definition we do have a lot of exposure to every play, including shale gas plays, tight gas plays and unconventional or resource gas plays. What it means by strengthening that means is we are drilling wells to preserve land, and we're drilling strategic wells to prove up some of these plays and ensure that we keep the land we want and to further augment our inventory of gas locations. That's what I meant by strengthening our gas plays or asset base.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any sense of natural gas pricing that you'd want to see before you more aggressively start drilling?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again I think you've got to see $6 and then you've got to see what the oil price is and see what competes. We're going to return &#x2013; allocate the capital to the highest return projects. So if you've got 80 or $90 oil and $6 gas price, gas does have a tough time competing, although some does.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you very much, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The following question is from Kam Sandhar from Peters and Co. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Steve. Two questions. First of all can you just elaborate a little bit more on the price revisions related to gas as to what areas they were in? And then the second question is, you talked about the NCIB that you guys have put in place. Given that you've got two to 2.6 billion in free cash, do you have the intention that you would buy back up to 2.5% in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll answer the second question first and then I'll get Lyle to give you a general overview of where the gas revision is. I think the gas is probably widespread. But on the normal-course issuer bid, as you know it's for 2.5% and that's the maximum we'd go. I think obviously we're going to take a very disciplined approach on how we proceed with buying back shares. And I guess the answer to that is we're going to see what the market conditions are. And we will try to minimize the dilution due to option exercise within the company and probably gain some of that back over the course of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Kam, getting back to your question on gas revisions. The gas revisions that Steve mentioned are widespread across the company. I think that the late-life reserves get cut off; I'd say all across western Canada. We lost a total of 335 Bcf on proved in Canada. Of that 158 Bcf is related to locations, proved undeveloped locations. Those locations are primarily from southern Alberta, and they would be shallow gas wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So just to clarify, that's mostly, is that just because of the slowdown in your drilling activity then, and it doesn't fit into that five-year window?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. It's primarily because at the SEC pricing of 3.79, those wells are uneconomic for us to drill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The following question is from Brian Dutton from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Steve. Just to circle back to the question on the reserve revisions, say for Horizon. Just to clarify, the 307 million barrels, you're talking about on a net basis, would there be any revisions if you were looking at the Horizon reserves on a gross before royalty basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There are no further questions registered. I'd like to turn the meeting back. I do apologize. We have another question from Mark Friesen from Versant Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I was just wondering, how many of the price-driven negative revisions would be back on the books with prices as they are currently?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a hard question. I would think the majority would be on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Lyle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There are no further questions registered. I'd like to turn the meeting back over to Mr. Langille.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, operator. And thank you, everyone, for attending this conference call. As usual, of course, if you have any further questions, do not hesitate to get a hold of anyone in our IR department, and we will look after the answer for you. And have a good day, and we look forward to continuing our progress throughout this year and into 2011. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, gentlemen. This concludes today's conference call. Please disconnect your lines, and thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>