<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1331809" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-11-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1564</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">John G. Langille, Vice-Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Allan P. Markin, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Steve W. Laut, President</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Peter J. Janson, Senior Vice-President, Horizon Operations</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Douglas A. Proll, Chief Financial Officer and Senior Vice-President of Finance</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Andrew Fairbanks</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Joe Citarrella</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Mark Polak</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">George Toriola</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">H. Monroe Helm, III</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Michael Dunn</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Kam Sandhar</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Barbara Betanski</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.  Welcome to the Canadian Natural Resources 2010 Third Quarter Results Conference Call.  I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. John Langille, Vice Chairman of Canadian Natural Resources. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator, and good morning, everyone.  Thank you for attending our conference call.  We will discuss our 2010 third quarter results and also update our operational plans for the remainder of 2010 and into 2011.  Participating with me today are Allan Markin, our Chairman, Steve Laut, our President, Peter Janson, our Vice President of Horizon Operations and Doug Proll, our Senior Vice President of Finance.</p>
          <p>Before we start, I would refer you to the comments regarding forward-looking information contained in our press release.  I'd also note that all dollar amounts are in Canadian dollars, and production and reserves are both expressed as before royalties, unless otherwise stated.</p>
          <p>Again in the third quarter as a result of strong operational results and efficient control over our operating costs, we achieved significant cash flow of over $1.5 billion, well in excess of our capital expenditures.  This is in line with our overall plans for 2010 where we originally budgeted the 2010 year to produce somewhere between $2.5 to $2.8 billion of free cash flow.  We have used this free cash flow to increase the dividends pain in 2010 by 42%, repay some of our debt and strengthen our balance sheet and acquire some strategic assets and institute a share buyback program.  All of the acquisitions have complemented our activities in our core areas and provide opportunities for value creation through reductions in cash operating costs and the assets purchased, synergetic sharing of production facilities and increases in our land bases for future development.  Our developments continue to be primarily focused on oil projects and oil sales contributed 86% of our gross revenue stream.</p>
          <p>Commodity prices continue to follow the trend they have been in for the last several years.  Oil prices are relatively strong and natural gas prices continue to weaken under the adverse over supply situation we find in North America.  In the last month of the third quarter, the discount factor for heavy oil price compared to the West Texas price widened as a result of a number of pipeline outages caused by a ruptured pipe on one of the export pipelines transporting heavy oil out of Canada.  This differential remained high until it was clear that the pipeline was repaired and put back into service.  Upon resumption of pipeline deliveries the differential has fallen back to levels expire to the outage.</p>
          <p>Before we turn the call over to Steve for the operating details, I would ask Allan to make some comments.  Allan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.  Hello and good morning, everyone.  It was at this time last year that we reaffirmed our commitment to our core values, spending where we need to, maintaining balance and continuing to optimize costs and production through safe and effective operations.  And since that time, the company has remained disciplined in its approach to expenditures.  We have maintained a diversified portfolio of assets of crude oil and natural gas and we have demonstrated our ability to adhere to our effective strategy.</p>
          <p>In looking to third quarter performance the company had a well grounded three months, where all of our teams continually worked towards strong operational performance and cost optimization and efficiency.  At Horizon, things are progressing and we continue to find tune operations in the plant in order to reach a state of reliability at the main plate production capacity.  At our thermal operations, we're progressing steadily with our growth plan.  We've expanded the Kirby assets through acquisition growth and we're moving ahead with Kirby Phase 1 after recently receiving Board sanction.</p>
          <p>As we have indicated many times before, our long-term objectives, especially production, have not changed as we remain prudent in our approach.  This year is not different and we will end the year on a positive production and financial note.  Primary heavy oil and natural gas continue to deliver.  We are confident in our execution strategy as we continue to create consistent value for our shareholders.  Steve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Al, and good morning, everyone.  As both Al and John have pointed out Canadian Natural is in a very enviable position.  Our strong, well-balanced assets combined with our capital discipline, focus on execution and effective operations has again delivered a strong quarter even with slightly lower production volumes than expected.  Operating costs are very good with overall operating costs for the first nine months of 2010 down 6% year-over-year on a BOE basis driven by a 17% reduction in oil operating costs in North America and our capital spending is on track.</p>
          <p>This reflects the strength of Canadian Natural's assets and our ability to generate free cash flow.  Based on the current strip pricing, we'd expect to generate between $2.5 and $2.7 billion of free cash flow over what is required to deliver production growth, excluding discretionary property acquisitions.  In the third quarter, we've been able to execute additional opportunistic and strategic acquisitions to strengthen our asset base in the near and long term.  As a result, we expect to allocate $1.5 billion of this $2.5 to $2.7 billion of free cash flow to property acquisitions for 2010, up approximately 500 million from our expectation at the end of Q2.</p>
          <p>Taking into account property acquisitions, we expect to deliver between 1 billion and 1.2 billion of free cash flow in 2010, which will be used to further strengthen our balance sheet.  It is clear that Canadian Natural assets are strong and well balanced.  We're delivering production, dropping operating costs, reducing capital spending and setting Canadian Natural up for significant value growth, while at the same time generating significant free cash flow.  Few, if any, of our peer group is in as strong a position as Canadian Natural is going forward.</p>
          <p>Turning in more detail asset-by-asset, starting with gas in Canada.  As you know Canadian Natural has the largest land base in Western Canada.  Canadian Natural dominates the land base and infrastructure in our core areas, and as a result we're a low cost producer, and are able to withstand what is expected to be a prolonged period of low gas prices.  Our gas land base is very well-positioned with strong assets and teams in conventional foothills, resource and unconventional plays.  Canadian Natural has over the last four years been quietly transforming the makeup of our gas portfolio, with 63% of our very large gas inventory made up of resource and unconventional play types, with only 27% of inventory from conventional play types.</p>
          <p>Our Septus Montney gas development is one example of our unconventional asset base.  We completed our 2010 drilling program with 13 wells drilled.  Costs have been excellent coming in 20% less than expected.  Completions are all done on all the wells now, with costs coming in as expected and flow rates on these wells very strong.  Average initial rates in the first 11 wells are 8 million cubic feet a day at 1,600 pounds wellhead pressure, and are on expectation.</p>
          <p>Our 50 million a day Septus gas plant is nearing completion and we expect to have production ramped up to 50 million a day by the end of the year, on cost and on schedule.  We believe Septus can deliver 200 million cubic feet a day if and when we expect to bring on future development phases.  With the current low prices we have also shut in roughly 35 million a day of gas production in Q3.  This gas will remain shut in until we see prices in the $5 range.</p>
          <p>Turning to oil in Canada, oil production in Canada was down from expectations, driven by a strategic decision to take advantage of an opportunity to optimize our steaming strategy and capture additional value in mid-August.  On our recent pad additions at Primrose, Canadian Natural has drilled with tighter interwell spacing.  We're down to 80 meters versus 190, to capture additional recoverable oil and ultimately high recovery rates.</p>
          <p>After the first steam production cycle it became apparent that we'd achieve a higher degree of interwell communication than expected at the first cycle which was completed in August; this is good news.  This interwell communication has given Canadian Natural the opportunity to adjust our steaming practices to increase overall effectiveness, greater recovery and lower costs in the next cycles.  As a result we have increased the amount of steam injected and as a result the time required to inject these larger steam volumes into late August, September and part of October.  This has caused the production volumes to be less than expected in Q3 as we have essentially continued to steam versus the bringing the wells back on production in the production cycle in late August.  Ultimately, this will result in higher production volumes for Q4.</p>
          <p>Now the production cycle was initiated here in late October and the early results have been better than expected, with significant volumes maxing our plant capacity and more importantly, and unfortunately, maxing out our ability to handle the vast amount of heat coming back at us in these initial stages of flow-back.  As a result, we've curtailed some production in the short term until the amount of heat diminishes as we progress through the production cycle.  Although the flow-back volumes and the amount of heat with these volumes has been difficult to handle initially, it is a very positive indication on the performance of our new pads and our modified steaming strategy.</p>
          <p>I'd also point out this reflects the strength of our thermal, technical, and operational teams, who recognized an opportunity to maximize value and were able to very quickly modify our strategy to capture this opportunity, a strength that is encouraged and highly valued in the Canadian Natural culture.  These strengths will continue to be important as we unlock the huge value in Canadian Natural's dominant heavy oil and thermal oil position in Canada.  As you've heard me say before, we believe our heavy oil and thermal oil assets are the hidden gem in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Heavy and thermal oil are delivering significant value today, and with our disciplined cost-effective development program are adding tremendous value in the future.  Our thermal assets alone have 33 billion barrels of oil in place and 6.2 billion recoverable in our defined plan.  To put this in perspective, 6.2 billion barrels of thermal oil is essentially the same as a 6 billion barrels recoverable at our world-class Horizon operation, a vast amount of oil that will add tremendous value for Canadian Natural shareholders.</p>
          <p>Our plan to unlock this value targets adding 285,000 barrels a day of heavy oil production in a very disciplined, step-wise, cost-controlled manner and taking total production facility capacity to over 400,000 barrels a day, again, very similar to the 500,000 barrels a day we will ultimately achieve at Horizon after Phase 5.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, Canadian Natural strengthened our asset base even further with the acquisition of additional lands adjacent to our Kirby development.  The Kirby acquisition adds 520 million barrels of recoverable oil at a cost of $405 million. And much like Primrose where we've been able to leverage the development of Primrose north and east around our central facilities at Primrose and Wolf Lake, we will leverage the development of these lands around the Central Kirby facilities built on our existing lands and capture significant capital and operating cost synergies.</p>
          <p>At Canadian Natural's original Kirby project, which we now call Kirby Phase 1, we have received all regulatory approvals. In addition, the company has sanctioned the first Phase of Kirby development.  Kirby Phase 1 will be developed with 47 SAGD horizontal well pairs drilled from seven surface pads.  The facility we built capable of generating 118,000 barrels a day of steam, treating 118,000 barrels a day of water and processing 40,000 barrels a day of oil.  Canadian Natural targets the cost of this development of Phase 1 of $1.25 billion and that will cost roughly $31,250 -- barrel a day of capacity.  Dirt work at the site has now been kicked off, with drilling schedule to begin in April 2011 and the first steam unit is expected Q4, 2013.</p>
          <p>It is highly likely that we will debottleneck the Kirby Phase 1 facilities to accommodate the development of a portion of the newly acquired lands and there will be a Kirby Phase 2 in the future.  We are currently working on the optimal way to develop these lands and to leverage our existing development to capture all the development synergies and maximize value.  Although, it's early, we expect Kirby Phase 2 to be in the 30,000 to 60,000 barrel a day range, plus the debottlenecking capacity we will add to Kirby Phase 1.  This will take Kirby ultimate production capacity to the 78,000 to 100,000 barrel a day range, a significant development by any measure.</p>
          <p>At Pelican Lake, we are on track with our program to convert the field to our highly successful polymer flood.  By the end of 2010, we plan to push the Pelican area under polymer flood to 44% of the total pool.  As we continue to convert Pelican to polymer flood, we expect production to reach a plateau of roughly 80,000 barrels a day of low-cost production by 2015, roughly double the 38,000 barrels a day produced in Q3.</p>
          <p>It is clear that Pelican Lake is a world-class pool, with 4 billion barrels in place and roughly 560 million barrels of recoverable resource with polymer flood, a very large pool with very robust development economics.  Pelican Lake continues to generate significant value for shareholders and generate some of the highest returns in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Keeping with the theme of high returns, our primary heavy oil program continues to roll along effectively and efficiently.  And in this commodity and cost environment, primary heavy oil generates top-decile returns on capital in our asset portfolio.  Importantly, it also generates the quickest payout and the largest cash-on-cash return.</p>
          <p>In the three quarters of 2010, we have drilled 497 wells and expect to drill 650 primary heavy oil wells for the year, an additional 50 wells from our expectations at our Q2 press release, and as a record number of primary heavy oil wells for Canadian Natural, roughly 35% more than we drilled in 2009.  Our dominant, high quality land base, infrastructure, and effective operations allow us to drill this size of program on a very cost effective basis, making primary heavy oil one of the best value generators in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Turning to the North Sea, major plan turnarounds were undertaken in Q3, and as expected, production was down in Q3.   All turnarounds are now complete and we're on cost and on schedule.  With the exception of Murchison where we encountered integrity issues with a production header and additional time was taken to replace valves on that header and has pushed the timing to Q4.</p>
          <p>We also had a shutdown in the quarter at Ninian to repair our flare gas system, which reduced production slightly.  Drilling and work over activities have been ongoing at Ninian with safety critical work overs being completed and one water injection well drilled.  Currently we're drilling <mark type="inaudible" /> targeting the <mark type="inaudible" /> zone, as well we will undertake some subsea work on the T-Block.</p>
          <p>In Offshore West Africa at Olowi and Gabon the B platform has been on stream during the third quarter. Although early production results look good, we're seeing rising gas oil ratios and we will be monitoring this very closely.  We're currently drilling on platform A with or first well on stream last week at rates of 2500 barrels a day.  The early production results look good, however Olowi is a very complex field and we'll need to monitor results over time before we can determine that this well will meet expectations.  Production at Olowi is currently 8,000 barrels a day, and is expected to peak out about 12,000 barrels a day when all four platforms are on stream.</p>
          <p>The Cote d'Ivoire production at Baobab and Espoir are both stable.  Espoir gas production has increased by roughly 10 million a day with the additional compression being installed in Q2.  It is important to note that Offshore West Africa has some of the highest return on capital projects in our portfolio, and, along with the North Sea, generates significant free cash flow for Canadian Natural.</p>
          <p>Turning to Horizon, we continue to make good progress, driving towards sustained reliability.  There is no question the operation can and has delivered at or above 110,000 barrels a day of SCO-designed capacity.  Our focus has been and will continue to be on reliability going forward.  The production by month is as follows: July 93,300 barrels a day, August 50,500 barrels a day, September 108,000 barrels a day and October 87,500 barrels a day.  Production has been strong and we're confident in the capacity of the plant and our ability to effectively run the operation.  It is however a very complex and heat integrated plant and it appears as it may take us some time until we are fully optimized and reliable.</p>
          <p>As an example, much like July where we've been running very strong for the month of September and most of October, however it became apparent in October that several maintenance issues needed to be addressed on a proactive basis particularly before the approach of winter.  This activity was not in our 2010 plan.  Therefore an outage was scheduled for October 23 and the entire plant was brought down so we could address all these issues on an effective basis and before the winter season.  The plant has begun to start up procedures this week, with first oil back on as of yesterday.</p>
          <p>I'll turn it over to Peter Janson to give you a more detailed explanation of this planned outage, what type of issues were driving these outages and the level preparedness we are for winter. Peter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Steve, and good morning everyone.  There were three primary objectives in the most recent maintenance outage at Horizon.  Firstly, the dry gas seals on our wet gas compressor began to leak and we did need to replace them.  This was our critical path job going into the outage and we wanted to make sure we had planned and staged all the tools, all the materials and people to minimize our duration.</p>
          <p>Second objective was to include other opportune maintenance within this outage window, so that we can improve our reliability after start up.  Similarly, all this work was also planned and staged prior to the outage.  Scopes of work from the other areas of the plant included a conveyer belt splice, a screen change out in the OPP, cyclone pack renewal and instrumentation installations <mark type="inaudible" />, heat exchanger inspection and repairs, the installation of a new burner in one of our two sulfur units and some pump maintenance.</p>
          <p>The third objective in this outage was to complete the last few scopes of work for winterization, specifically some electric heat tracing and winterization of the OPP equipment.  As you can sense, aside from necessary maintenance, we took this opportunity to enhance some of our equipment reliability and to ensure the plant was ready for winter.</p>
          <p>Just prior to going into this outage, we did experience an exchanger leak in the hydrogen unit, which did have an impact on our absorber performance in that unit.  Maintenance on this exchanger did create a two day extension to the outage, but all other works were generally completed within the window.</p>
          <p>Of concern to us coming out of this shutdown is the peak capacity limit of the pressure swing absorber unit.  Initial indications are that we have lost some unit capacity as a result of contamination from the exchanger leak.  If sustained, this will limit our maximum peak production capacity until December when the adsorbent material can be changed out.  At this point it's difficult to assess the impact but it may reduce capacity by 20,000 to 30,000 barrels a day of capacity.  As we move forward in Horizon, we continue look for improvements to equipment and processes that will enhance our production sustainability.</p>
          <p>Back to you, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Peter. As you can see, we're taking all the necessary steps to set us up for increased liability and performance going forward. As you notice operating costs for Q3 are very good at $34.35 a barrel, about $2 a barrel higher than Q2 which is very impressive considering the lower production in Q3. On the sustaining capital side, we're tracking to or below budget. As I said earlier, this is a complex plant and will take some time to fully optimize. Going forward our ops teams believe that we can achieve lower operating costs not just from higher production levels, but more effective operations. Although we're not there yet, we see many opportunities to further improve performance.</p>
          <p>Horizon is a world class asset with over 6 billion barrels of recoverable oil. We have targeted to increase production through Phases 2 and 3 to 232,000 barrels a day and further expansions in Phases 4 and 5 to just under 500,000 barrels a day, or 0.5 million barrels a day of light sweet crude, with no declines for 40 years and virtually no reserve replacement costs.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we'll continue to complete work on Tranche 2 of our Phase 2/3 expansion and spending-wise we're on track to our budget which we reduced in Q2. Our detailed lessons learned from Phase 1 are nearing completion and remain on track, and we will incorporate any cost reduction effectiveness measures into future expansions. Along with this work, we continue to do engineering work on future expansions and to prepare a more detailed cost estimate. It is our expectation that we'll have a more detailed cost estimate early in 2010 and a better understanding of any modifications we will make to our execution strategy. This work will be completed to give better certainty on costing in various environments.</p>
          <p>Canadian Natural is committed to the expansion of Horizon to 232,000 barrels a day and ultimately just under 500,000 barrels a day of light sweet 34 degree API crude. As always, Canadian Natural is very focused on cost and cost control and creating value for shareholders, and we will be sanctioning the expansion of Horizon but only when we can be assured that reasonable cost certainty is there and our return on capital requirements can be achieved.</p>
          <p>It is clear that Canadian Natural is in a very strong and enviable position. Horizon is a world-class asset that is and will continue to add tremendous value to shareholders. Our thermal heavy oil assets can add value similar to the magnitude to Horizon, yet in more manageable sizes, and in my opinion are the hidden gem in our portfolio, and in this low gas price environment, generate even a greater value for shareholders. Our light oil assets, both internationally and in Canada, as well as our primary heavy oil assets in Canada continue to generate strong returns.</p>
          <p>And in this low gas price environment, our strategy of maintaining a well-balanced portfolio and the fact that we are the low cost producer, will ensure that we will be able to withstand and weather a very sustained period of low gas prices.</p>
          <p>Our teams are strong throughout the company, and as Doug will point out, our balance sheet is strong and getting stronger. We have a very flexible capital program, giving Canadian Natural the ability not only to maximize the value of our well-balanced portfolio, but also capture any opportunities that will present themselves in this environment.</p>
          <p>Canadian Natural is in a great position. And in today's environment, with our team, our strategy, and our assets, I believe Canadian Natural is better positioned than ever before to generate significant value for shareholders.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn it over to Doug to update you on our financial position and our prudent financial management. Doug?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Steve, and good morning. Q3 2010 marked the seventh consecutive quarter of positive free cash flow. During this period, we have applied most of this free cash flow to a reduction of long-term debt which has resulted in a stronger balance sheet where our debt to book capitalization is now at 28% and debt to EBITDA is 1.1 times.</p>
          <p>Additionally, our unused bank lines exceeded $3 billion at September 30th. This increase in balance sheet strength has not gone unnoticed by the rating agencies. Moody's upgraded the company's debt rating to Baa1 from Baa2 in October. This followed the change in Standard &amp; Poor's outlook from stable to positive upon the affirmation of our BBB rating in August and the confirmation of our BBB high rating by DBRS this past spring.</p>
          <p>The third quarter also marked the reactivation of our Normal Course Issuer Bid with the purchase of 2 million common shares. This active share buyback program, together with all four of our business segments generating positive free cash flow, ensures our allocation of capital model is fully functional.</p>
          <p>Our commodity hedging program remains active albeit at lower volumes, which results from our improved balance sheet strength. For the remainder of 2010, we have 150,000 barrels per day of oil hedged with WTI price collars, with floors of US$60 to US$70. For 2011, we have 50,000 barrels per day hedged with a floor of US$70 per barrel. In addition, we have established puts on 100,000 barrels per day with a strike price of $70. For natural gas, we have AECO floors of $6 on 220,000 GJs per day for the fourth quarter of 2010. Details of all of our positions are available in the notes to the financial statements and on our website.</p>
          <p>As a final note, our internal team has made excellent progress in the drive to be IFRS compliant for 2011. Our system changes are virtually complete. Our analysis of and compliance with IFRS accounting policies requiring change from Canadian GAAP standards is also nearing completion and are summarized in our management disclosure and analysis.</p>
          <p>We are therefore comfortable, based on our analysis of standard in place today, to estimate that shareholders' equity as at January 1, 2010 will decrease by less than 4% under IFRS. We do not anticipate any significant differences in reported cash flow from operations. As we move through the remainder of Q4 and into Q1 our focus will be to finalize our analysis and to adopt the new requirements for reporting as required by the CICA and the security bodies in Canada.</p>
          <p>Thank you, I will now return you to John for some closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. As you can see we are following our 2010 plan as we had anticipated last fall. We are in the process of finalizing our 2011 plans which will also establish our targeted 2011 budget. We remain focused and disciplined to ensure we are creating long-term shareholders' value.</p>
          <p>With that, Operator, I would open up the call for questions participants may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now take questions from the telephone line. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question is from Andrew Fairbanks from Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, guys. I was wondering what timeframe are you thinking of now for the decision on the Horizon expansion, will it still be sometime early winter or would you expect that might be drifting into the spring time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Andrew, Steve Laut here. Our timeframe for Horizon is we're looking to have the execution strategy, a more detailed cost estimate I'd say in the first quarter of 2011. And at that time we'll decide how and when we will expand Horizon. So I would expect some news on that in the first quarter of 2011 to the Street.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great thanks. Steve, and I guess a follow up question, I know it sounds kind of prudish to be talking about hedging, and as you move into potentially an expensive Horizon expansion project, how do you think about hedging at this point? You know, are you so large that you wouldn't feel you'd need a great deal of hedging to accommodate the capital spending period for the Horizon expansion? Or would you just go ahead and, kind of as you're doing this year and next, match some degree of hedging to the capital you're going to be spending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Andrew, I think that's a very good question. It actually will be part of our overall execution strategy. We feel we don't have to hedge as much going forward mainly because we have a bigger base to work from now, larger cash flow. Also our execution strategy will have a greater degree of flexibility in it than we had in Phase 1, and we will be taking this in a step-wise approach and we'll probably limit the amount of capital spending per year.</p>
          <p>So that gives us a much more robust project and also I think gives us a larger degree of cost control going forward. And we will detail that more likely as we announce the 2011 budget giving more detail on how we plan to execute Horizon. And that budget I think we'll target to announce it to the Street towards the end of November, early December.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That was super. Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Joe Citarrella from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. In terms of just following up on Horizon here on future phases as we're awaiting more detailed cost estimates, hoping you could offer some early thoughts on how you expect costs to compare to the first phase. I mean, should we be thinking about close to the $88,000 per barrel a day that we had for Phase 1 or anticipating anything meaningfully different here? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Joe, right now we're still in the final stages of it. We're kind of in a unique window right now. And our cost estimates that we've had before may look a little high compared to what we're able to execute in this environment. However, our concern is, once you start announcing projects, that we could get back, the industry as a whole, back into that inflationary period and we would have cost pressures again.</p>
          <p>So all our execution strategy is built around giving us maximum flexibility and the ability to control costs and stop and start as we go forward. As far as 88,000 or 89,000, which you did in Phase I for, I think it would be difficult to achieve that level of cost going forward in expansions. So it would be higher than the 89,000 in Phase 1, just how much higher we haven't nailed down exactly yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And similar lines on Kirby, hoping you'd just provide some additional color there. I mean, you're expanding the whole project to 70,000 to 100,000 per day now and you mentioned capital of about 31,000 for the first phase. Should we be thinking about a lower capital spend for the remainder of the project, given expected synergies? And also any thoughts on timing for production here? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Kirby Phase 1 first steam-in is 2013 and then the oil will come up, it ramps up with SAGD, so it won't be like cyclic where it comes at you right away. So it will take some time, probably in 2014 we'd expect to hit production.</p>
          <p>As far as cost going forward for the expansion of Kirby Phase 2 and the debottlenecking, we would expect to be able to leverage the infrastructure we built here for Kirby Phase 1. And the debottlenecking for sure will give us better cost synergies. So we think it will be lower. At this point in time, we haven't quantified how much lower that will be, but we expect it to trend lower for the future expansions. We'd also expect to see operating costs be a little bit lower with the expansions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's really helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Mark Polak from Scotia Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. Quick question for you, now that you've acquired the Enerplus lands around Kirby, that expansion and debottlenecks, should we think about that sort of pushing out Grouse and all the other projects a little further and sort of coming on in that 2016 timeframe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a good question, Mark. We're still looking at it. What we're planning to do with both Grouse and Birch Mountain East is we're looking now at the possibility of making regulatory applications for both of those in 2011 and trying to put Kirby 2 in there in between. So we're not sure exactly how the schedule will be, but there may be some juggling of schedules. You would think just logically Kirby 2 would probably come before. However, Grouse is looking very good so we may try to do Grouse first or very close together with Kirby 2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But no change to the overall kind of adding 30,000 to 60,000 barrels a day every two to three years, that's still sort of the pace you're comfortable with?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're very comfortable with that pace and we think basically the contracting and construction market can handle that. If you get going too far, you're going to outrun the construction market and outrun the engineering firm's ability to deliver for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then just curious what you're seeing in terms of inflation as you're working through the latter stages of, looking at Horizon here we've seen costs go up on Curl and Suncor mentioned this morning that after a fairly sharp reduction and the slowdown of '08, '09, costs coming up, things getting busy as you look at that pipeline, just curious what you're thinking there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are, Mark, concerned about inflation and about the ability to re-ignite inflation. I will say that on our projects on Tranche 2, we are tracking below our control estimate or our cost estimate at this point in time, and that's one of the reasons why we reduced capital spending in 2010 because of their ability to do the work with less. So, we are seeing our ability to do it for less than we expected. But going forward, it's just I think it's all matter of activity. So, it becomes very difficult to say that going forward you're going to be able to do it for less. But we haven't seen the inflation yet at our site.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from George Toriola from UBS Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and good morning guys. The question is around operating costs in the North Sea. Obviously you had the quarter here you had some other issues, but just looking at that business, where would you expect operating costs to be and what are the drivers you have to the extent that you can bring costs down, what drivers do you have?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The biggest driver in the North Sea for operating costs is production volumes. Mostly operating costs are essentially fixed, so we didn't have as we had in third quarter all the turnarounds, and that's the time to do it when it's in the summer and the water conditions are better. Your production is down and your operating costs go up significantly. So for us, maintaining production volumes is the biggest driver and increasing volumes if we can.</p>
          <p>As you know, we started up a drill string at Ninian this year. Obviously we took a hiatus in 2009. Mainly because of the uncertainty in the global financial market, we wanted to reduce our capital spending. As a result, there's a lot of safety critical work we have to do here in 2010 and 2011 we have to get to before we get to really say some of the juicer production volume adds. So, as we get to that, you'll see production more stable and operating costs stabilize as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And sort of where do you expect that to settle out at, what sort of numbers would you expect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're saying for this year, operating costs are $30 to $31 a barrel. I would expect us to be very close to that 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thanks. And then quickly on Horizon, is it fair to say that as you push Phase I volume towards sort of design capacities here that you're now getting to test some of the pieces of equipment there and that's where you're starting to see some of this reliability issues, is that the fair we look at it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, George, I don't think that's the case actually, when we run at higher volumes we actually run better. When we have offset, when we go down and go back up, that's when we have issues with reliability. Starting the equipment up and pulling it down causes reliability issues. So when we run at designed capacity that's the best time we run; everything runs smooth, it just purrs along.</p>
          <p>So really what we're finding here, to be blunt, the hydrogen exchanger that we had here, was a manufacturing error that occurred and was not detected by their quality control or our quality control. I don't know if you could have detected it actually, and it took this long before it actually generated a leak, so we're still working through some of those issues, what occurred in that 2007, 2008 period when that hyper inflation and every vendor was trying to get as much equipment out the door as possible. And so we still have some of these thing coming back to bite us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it's not really sort of pushing the envelope, but more and more issues from start up, so to speak.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not at all, it's all, Peter, you can say it, when we run at high rates that's when we run best.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In fact, that's where the equipment is designed to run at, and it's the sweet spot is that rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay sounds good. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Monroe Helm from Barrow, Hanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, great results. You've had, I think you said, $1.5 billion worth of acquisition opportunities this year. Can you, I know it's kind of hard for next year to know but because it depends on what comes on the market, but how should we think about how much of your capital will go into acquisitions next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're right, Monroe, that's a very difficult question to answer. As you know we are very opportunistic; we are very, very selective. Every acquisition we made this year has been able to reduce operating costs right out of the shoot as soon as we integrated it into our infrastructure with the exception of Kirby obviously because there is no production there. But every other one, we've been able to lower operating costs. And we have looked at a tremendous number of acquisitions, so we look at everything that comes through our core area that's up for sale and we've been very, very selective. Now what's going to come up for sale in 2011 it's hard to say, I guess it probably depends what the commodity prices are and how other companies react.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And given the comment you made that you think gas prices are going to stay depressed for quite a while to come. Can you kind of give us what are the key things you look for gas acquisitions? Obviously you're going to integrate into your, for bolt-ons you can integrate them in and lower the operating cost. What else would make a gas property attractive from an acquisition standpoint at this point in time, especially in light of the fact that a forward curve doesn't really allow you to lock in what I would consider to be very good rates of return?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, obviously you have to be able to buy it at the rate price and you need to be able to get operating cost synergies right out of the shoot. And hopefully there will be upside in those assets that at some point in the future you'll be able to leverage. And I agree it's difficult and those are some of the key things. We're not going to tell you the whole parameters for us on acquisitions because we want to keep that to ourselves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can you share with us kind of your view on gas prices, how long do you think this oversupply could last? Do you have a good feel or any feel for it that you're willing to share with us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, we, I don't know if we've got a good feel for it or not. But we do know that we believe shale gas production is real. It looks like shale gas reserves are real but I don't think that's for sure yet. And it looks like gas, shale gas might work at $4 an mcf but maybe only in the sweet spots and maybe only in liquid rich. So it's difficult to say but I could see us being here for three to maybe seven years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And one last question, I believe maybe I didn't hear this right. Did you said that excess cash flow that you have this year, free cash flow after CapEx dividends and acquisitions is going to go to reduce debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Mike Dunn from FirstEnergy Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. Just a couple of questions on Kirby and the new property acquisition there. I think you've mentioned sort of an ultimate range of production of between 70,000 and 100,000 barrels a day. Just wondering what some of that uncertainty in that, in the high versus the low end of that is? And I think looking though old Enerplus disclosures, some of those resources were I think in the Wabasca as opposed to the McMurray. So I'm not sure if you can comment on how you view sort of the variety of resource there and also how are you thinking about &#x2013; is co-gen an option for Kirby, what are you thinking about there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the range 70,000 to 100,000 is just our range and what is the optimum plant size to maximize value. And so depending on all your price assumptions, your gas cost assumptions and basically the kind of type curve we use for each of the production wells or pads we expect to drill, you get a different answer. And I would say there's economics to go to a 60,000 barrel a day expansion and there's economics where the life would be shorter and there's economics to 30,000. It's just a matter of what is the optimal NPV. So we got a choice, we know it works at 60, and we know it works to 30, we're just trying to maximize value, that's why I give you the range.</p>
          <p>Now you're right in saying that &#x2013; I don't know about the Wabasca. It is &#x2013; I'm getting some feedback here so I'm hearing some conversation, I'm not sure what that is. But on the Wabasca for Kirby, there is Wabasca, it's a big part of it &#x2013; or not a big part, but a substantial part of the acquisition. And not all Wabasca is created equal. A lot of it has a significant amount of clays in it and when you steam it, basically it locks it up. So Wabasca in general terms has always been deemed to be non SAGD-able. We've done a bunch of work on the Wabasca and particularly in this Wabasca zone around Kirby. And what we acquired here in this acquisition and we are strongly of a belief that it can be SAGDed and it's in our reserves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks guys. And on Co-Gen, Steve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, on the Co-Gen, right now it doesn't look like co-gen makes sense for us. We're not to the scale but maybe when we expand, if we go to that 70,000 or 100,000 barrels a day, we will look at it at that point in time, but right now for Phase I, that's not included.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And do you guys have anything to update us with in regards to progress on negotiations with terms for the Northwest upgrader?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are still in negotiations with the Alberta government. I would say they are going along pretty well. It's obviously a very tough agreement and everybody just wants to make sure that they get it right. So I'd say we're making good progress, but we're not there yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from John Harlan from Societe Generale. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, just some quick ones. With IFRS, can you indicate how you've allocated the charges, like how much is PP&amp;E versus stock options, etcetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, I don't think that we're in a position to discuss those allocations right now. The largest, as you know, would be the stock compensation because there is a change in the way you calculate it to more of a Black-Scholes and away from a cash determination. The other one that's outstanding right now that is giving us a little bit of angst is the ARO event and what rate to use in discounting the factor. And of course there's two rates out there; there's the risk adjusted and the risk free rate. And we're looking for some feedback on those two rates from our advisors on that. So to discuss the allocations between the various areas, I think would be premature.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's fine. One other kind of related question to that though, you give up country pools from a reporting basis, going forward do you think you'll have any sort of different operational reporting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Last one from me, you're seeing a lot of E&amp;Ps in North America return to North America after having explored abroad. You're obviously in the North Sea in West Africa, are you still going to be pursuing more, or are you going to kind of keep the status quo with respect to international E&amp;D?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it turns to, we are in the North Sea as you say in offshore in West Africa. We are very happy with the results we've had in the North Sea and offshore West Africa. It's a significant free cash flow generator for the company. We are open and would look to expand those operations if they are available although it has been very tough to do so here in the last few years. So we're going to stay there and we'll look for opportunities to leverage our expertise into other opportunities if they should show up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Kam Sandhar from Peters and Co. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I have three questions. First one is just wondering if you could give us your steam oil expectations for Kirby? And then the second one is just on where you're at in terms of the sequencing of projects obviously given this acquisition of additional lands at Kirby and whether that changes on the heavy oil side? And then just wondering where you are at in terms of regulatory applications, where those projects and whether you see that being a potential bottleneck?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay. So steam oil ratio, there's a bunch of ways to answer that. As you know on the SAGD, the profile starts out high and then drops down to a lower number as you get lined out and then near the end of the life it tails up again. So we'd expect to probably at the lower end of it to be in that sort of 2.4 SOR but when you take over the whole life of the pad we're probably in that 3 to 3.2 SOR which is very similar to I would say Jackfish and maybe not quite as good as Foster Creek.</p>
          <p>As far as the sequence goes, I kind of alluded to that earlier, right now we're going to stick with our sequence but we are looking at potentially adjusting Kirby 2 to maybe sneak in there or maybe bump somebody back a bit. Regulatory approval, we're going to start the regulatory process in Grouse and Birch Mountain East in 2011, and we'll also look at what we need to do for Kirby 2.</p>
          <p>And is there a bottleneck there? There could be and we've allowed for extra time to get through our process in our plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then one last question, when you allude to obviously your inventory shifting to unconventional gas, Septimus being the one that you're working on in the near term, can you highlight maybe some other areas that you are looking at potentially putting more capital to work in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're looking to put very little capital to work in any of our gas properties, including the unconventional gas. Most of it in 2011, we'll talk more about this when we get to the budget and we get it finalized so I'm being a bit premature. But I would expect most of it would be strategic and land preserving drilling and it'll be a small program. Most of our unconventional as you say is in the Montney in B.C., some in Alberta and farther to the north in B.C. We also have strong plays in the Deep Basin in Northwest Alberta.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our next question is from Barbara Betanski from Addenda Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. Thanks a lot. Just a follow up on the gas, given that you're expecting this weak environment for an extended period, would you expect your gas production overall to continue to decline over the next number of years or have you sort of curbed the decline with the transition to the resource play? And then just, I'm wondering what volume of gas did you acquire this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we expect in 2011 and going forward, unless gas prices increase, we'll preserve our land base, but I would expect to see gas production decline. In our case, we can hold the land and preserve it for when gas prices come back. So it makes no sense, particularly when we have lots and lots of oil projects in the hopper to drill up. So we're not going to drill gas when we don't need to. So you'll see production decline. And we did buy gas, in our acquisitions so far, we've bought about 214 million a day of gas and about 9,000 barrels a day of oil and liquids. And that's sort of the initial rates, obviously they decline as you go through the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. And just another question, actually on Horizon, in terms of when you might plan to significantly ramp up spending on Horizon, Phase 2 and 3 and so I am sort of thinking about that high level of free cash that you're generating currently, would you expect that to be reduced perhaps in 2012 or '13 or can you talk about that right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Barbara we're still working on how the execution strategy is going to portray and how we want to go forward. And we need to get cost certainty assured for Horizon before we go ahead and we also need to ensure that we have our return on capital criteria met. And as you know the costs are high and we need to make sure it's going to work. We don't want to have ourselves caught in a position like we did in Phase 1, where hyperinflation sort of took control of the process. We want to be in control of the process this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. There are no further questions registered at this time. I would like to turn the meeting back over to Mr. Langille.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, operator, and thank you ladies and gentlemen for attending our conference call. And as usual if you have any further questions don't hesitate to contact us. And have a good day everybody. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The conference has now ended. Please disconnect your lines at this time. And we thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>