<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1465974" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-04-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1382</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Robert Noorigian</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Claude Mongeau</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Marketing Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Jean-Jacques Ruest</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice-President">Luc Jobin</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Bill J. Greene</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="TD Securities">Cherilyn Radbourne</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner &amp; Smith, Inc.">Ken Scott Hoexter</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Desjardins Securities">Benoit Poirier</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Wolfe Trahan &amp; Co.">Scott H. Group</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Dominion Securities, Inc.">Walter Spracklin</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Operating Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Keith E. Creel</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Thomas R. Wadewitz</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="BMO Capital Markets (Canada)">Fadi Chamoun</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Chris Wetherbee</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Canaccord Genuity Corp.">David Tyerman</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Dahlman Rose &amp; Co. LLC">Jason H. Seidl</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Susquehanna Financial Group LLP">Matt Troy</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Chris J. Ceraso</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">H. Peter Nesvold</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Brandon Robert Oglenski</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst" affiliation="Cormark Securities, Inc.">Konark Gupta</participant>
      <participant id="22" type="analyst" affiliation="Sterne, Agee &amp; Leach, Inc.">Jeff A. Kauffman</participant>
      <participant id="23" type="analyst" affiliation="Morningstar Research">Keith Schoonmaker</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>All participants, please continue to standby, the meeting will begin momentarily. CN's First Quarter 2012 Financial Results Call will begin shortly.</p>
          <p>I would now like to remind you that today's remarks contain forward-looking statements within the meaning of applicable securities laws. Such statements are based on assumptions that may not materialize and are subject to risks described in CN's First Quarter 2012 Financial Results Press Release and Analyst Presentation documents that can be found on CN's website. As such, actual results could differ materially. Reconciliations for any non-GAAP measures are also posted on CN's website at www.cn.ca. Please stand by, your call will begin shortly.</p>
          <p>Welcome to the CN's First Quarter 2012 Financial Results Conference Call. I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. Robert Noorigian, Vice President of Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. Noorigian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and thank you for joining us for CN's first quarter 2012 financial results. I'd like to remind you about the comments that have already been made regarding forward-looking statements. With us today is Claude Mongeau, President and Chief Executive Officer; Luc Jobin, Executive Vice-President and Chief Financial Officer; Keith Creel, Executive Vice-President and Chief Operating Officer; J.J. Ruest, Executive Vice President and Chief Marketing Officer.</p>
          <p>And we consider that we had a superb quarter and we would really appreciate it when the Q&amp;A starts that if you would try to focus your questions on CN and business related to CN. In order to be fair to all the participants, we'd like to limit your questions to one each.</p>
          <p>With that, it's now my pleasure to introduce Mr. Claude Mongeau, CN's President and Chief Executive Officer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bob, and I'm here in foggy Halifax with the team to cover these results with you. We have our AGM and are very pleased that we will be officially finishing the cycle for 2011 and starting the cycle for 2012 with very, very solid results. Our Q1 results were helped by a milder winter throughout our serving territories, but make no mistake, these results are about strong execution the CN team delivered on all key fronts. Whether it's growth, whether it's efficiency, whether it's safety, our agenda is working and it's showing through in very solid financial results for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Revenues during the quarter were up double digit, about 12% to be exact. J.J. will give you the details. But we're seeing good growth across all of the commodity markets we serve. Our ability to accommodate that growth at the low incremental cost and to balance service and operational excellence also showed through during the quarter. Keith will give you some key metrics along those lines. But our operating ratio at 66.2% is a record operating ratio for a first quarter, and it's a full 2.8% improvement versus last year.</p>
          <p>In terms of earnings, and I'm looking at it here on an adjusted basis, we delivered $1.18, which is up 31% over last year. I'd be remiss if I didn't focus on the weather. Obviously, the fact that we had one extra day also helped; there's perhaps a third of that EPS growth on a year-over-year basis which is due to those factors. But nevertheless, solid, solid first quarter results and Luc will give you all the details including some of our monetization and how we're able to use and deliver very strong free cash flow. So, solid results overall.</p>
          <p>I'll ask the team to give you the details and I'll wrap up at the end. Keith, over to you.</p>
          <p>[065TSM-E Keith Creel]</p>
          <p>Okay, thanks for the comments, Claude. Let me say that while definitely a milder winter in 2011, 2012 first quarter was not without its operational challenges. Regardless, the tenacity and the execution of this operating team produced some pretty solid results. So let's start with a view of the operating metrics that we report quarterly; they always provide a good overview of our productivity and the fluidity of our operation. As you can see on the charts, we produced improvements across the board on all operating metrics. Due to a traffic mix change, our train load was only up 1%. However, train length was up about 3% year-over-year. So regardless of the mix change, we continue to increase the efficiency of our trains.</p>
          <p>All the other metrics, as you see, are up at least 3% relative to last year, which has allowed us to absorb our growth at a lower incremental cost. All a very solid performance by the talented and dedicated railroaders we have on this team. Let's say in the interest of providing a bit more relative first-quarter comparison to proxy, let's compare our performance in the first quarter of 2010, which was a winter similar to this year. We also showed improvements in all of our metrics.</p>
          <p>As you see, the only exceptions in these metrics are in train speed and locomotive productivity. These are two metrics which we have impacted consciously with our efforts to focus squarely on maximizing the throughput of our bulk logistic supply chain. I'll give you a quick example. With the sheer goal of pushing more coal through our supply chain, we're working with our supply chain partners and ports to ensure that we consistently have a train ready to take advantage of our unload windows.</p>
          <p>To make this happen, we've had to dedicate locomotives against our coal trains, which at times requires staging timing queue to unload. In the past, we were very reluctant to do this for two primary reasons; one, it adversely impacted locomotive productivity or car productivity in trains speed; two, we didn't have the type of positive working relationships that are necessary with the terminal operators to secure their commitment to do all they could do to work with us to optimize their piece of the supply chain.</p>
          <p>But today, with our supply chain end-to-end focus and the partnerships we've forged, even though we do have to give a little bit back in terms of the these metrics, overall, it's been excellent for our service and for the bottom line, which is obviously what the true end game is for CN and our supply chain partners.</p>
          <p>Suffice it to say these results show a strategy to provide service excellence, it's working while maintaining operational excellence, becoming a powerful business multiplier, allowing us to grow with our customers and supply chain partners. In fact, some of the growth we're experiencing as a result of this strategy is making our strategic capacity investment decisions crystal clear, which is a great segue to the second slide in your deck.</p>
          <p>To support our operational service excellent mandate, we have to continue to invest surgically to create the capacity to handle our significant growth opportunities efficiently. More specifically, on the BC North territory, we've handled 20% more traffic this year versus last and 27% more versus 2010. We've responded to this growth by running not only more trains but also longer trains, which while it does and has had a negative impact on our train speed due to the current longer trains, they're running in a territory that does not have an optimal siding spacing. It has allowed us to respond at the growth opportunity efficiently.</p>
          <p>So, with that said, what we're focusing on is a plan that we've effectively made in 2010. We're rolling it out. And by the end of third quarter, early into the fourth quarter of this year, we will have seven additional long sidings in service in this quarter, which will increase our capacity to handle longer trains by 50%. This, in turn, will allow us to enjoy our renewed levels of train speed performance with the associated benefits of locomotive and car productivity.</p>
          <p>And at the same time, we continue to invest in our EJ&amp;E property, adding capacity to run more trains efficiently and switch traffic in this critical hub in our system. On the locomotive front, as we've reported previously, we're making strategic investments, purchasing locomotives in advance of demand. This will allow us to leapfrog the need to purchase locomotives during the initial implementation of the new Tier-4 compliant locomotives, which GE and E&amp;D will be producing in 2015 and forward.</p>
          <p>Given the new technology to meet these standards is still being developed, we felt strongly this is a prudent strategy to avoid usual growing pains of adapting new technology, as well as avoiding pricing escalation driven by this technology. To optimize this investment in locomotives, we have pursued a strategy of purchasing part new and part used locomotives. We'll modernize the used locomotives with engine enhancements which will get us additional fuel efficiencies, we'll equip them with DP, we'll add on on-board technologies such as Trip Optimizer and <mark type="ph" /> Mytronics (8:49) as well.</p>
          <p>And on the new front, a new twist to our strategy, or a renewed enhancement to our strategy, we're actually purchasing AC locomotives for these 65 as opposed to DC locomotives where we'll strategically allocate those to fit parts of our network that requires those will convert them with productivity synergies. They're going to provide more <mark type="ph" /> attractive (9:07) effort, more specifically northern BC, optimizing our coal trains and also optimizing the size of our new Canpotex potash unit trains, which will soon be running to the North Shore in Vancouver.</p>
          <p>Finally, we're focused on maintaining solid production relationships based on mutual respect with our labor union leaders and our employees which make this business run day in and day out. Proof of this progress in our area on the Canadian side, two significant agreements we've reached without labor disruption or uncertainty for our employees and customers that were ratified during the first quarter with both our TCRC representative of Locomotive Engineers and USW <mark type="ph" /> mates and (9:46) employees. Both agreements represent a win-win for our company and for our employees, both products of fair but firm negotiations by both the union leadership and management. They're all positive points that allows for a more progressive and productive relationship with our craft employees while we provide certainty for our customers.</p>
          <p>And on the U.S. side, something that's pretty significant for us, we implemented a new agreement with our DMIR, DWP/WC running trains, which provides us much needed operational flexibility to ensure the reliability of our supply chain in not only the iron ore ranges but also our network running through the Superior Corridor, where since our WC and DMIR acquisitions with the absence of this agreement, we've been forced to run these connecting properties as individual railroads. It's obviously had multiple operating inefficiencies.</p>
          <p>So in the interest of time, let me wrap up my comments by emphasizing the fact that our strategy to create and provide the needed flexibility and elements to enable service excellence while protecting our legacy of operational excellence is working. We're consistently demonstrating that we can provide strategic flexibility to our supply chain partners, working together to enable organic growth that we continue to handle at a low incremental cost.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll turn it over to J.J. to add some color to the business level this strategy is enabling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Keith, and good afternoon to everyone. On the revenue side, Q1 2012 was a record first quarter for CN. Revenue was up 13% versus last year. The breakdown is as follow: about 5.5% came from volume, our carload volume went up 5.1% but our revenue ton mile volume was up 6.3%. Same-store price came in a bit more than 4%, slightly better than the prior quarter, consistent with our steady plan to secure sustainable, above inflation increase. 3.3% came from fuel surcharge, mix was overall flat and, finally, we gained 1% from exchange, that is, the Canadian dollar was $1.06 weaker this year.</p>
          <p>Now, looking at our quarter in more detail, all of my comments will be on a FX-adjusted as usual.</p>
          <p>Starting with petrol and chemical, the revenue was up 13% on the back of very strong petroleum growth. New crude oil business accounted for roughly half of our carload growth in that segment. All other petroleum segments were also up, led by refined products. And the chemical and plastics was a combined flat.</p>
          <p>Metals and minerals grew an impressive 29%, after many other quarters have been very strong growth. All segments in the M&amp;M segment has performed superbly. Drilling activities continue to drive record users at Wisconsin's frac sand and drilling pipe, we also have additional sand mine production capacity coming online in Wisconsin.</p>
          <p>Our strong steel volume was driven by our supply chain approach to our customers as well as by a favorable steel market, which is sustained by energy and automotive demand. Forest product, the revenue rose 9%. Lumber and panel traffic in the U.S. both increased 11% from last year. Lumber to Asia and China was up 21% and pulp in boxcar recovered from a soft Asian market in the fourth quarter. The strong export of both lumber and pulp also helped our intermodal overseas business. Paper in boxcar is in circular decline and those shipments were down 16%.</p>
          <p>Automotive revenue was up 11%. North American vehicle sales remain robust, driving gains in our vehicle carload as well also as on our trans-Pacific container import business for parts. This was offset partly by the year-over-year permit closure of the Ford St. Thomas in Ontario and the Ford St. Paul, Minnesota plant.</p>
          <p>Coal revenue, coal revenue was sequentially improved from the fourth quarter of last year and it was up 18% from revenue from the first quarter of last year. At CN, we see a permanent shift in that business from short-haul domestic movement to long-haul export. Therefore, in the first quarter of this year, our carload went down 11% but our total revenue ton-mile volume was up 19% for the quarter, since our average length of haul increased 32%.</p>
          <p>Domestic thermal coal is in circular decline, losing share to abundant, cheap, long-term shale gas supply. At CN, the domestic thermal coal is already less than 2% of our total company revenue. Export, however, is the story. Export is the story for the CN coal franchise, long haul and export of thermal coal and coking coal via Vancouver, Rupert and Convent, Louisiana. In addition, we also handle strong shipment of Canadian oil sand petroleum coke also to export market, in that case, Rupert.</p>
          <p>Now, looking at grain and fertilizer, Canadian grain revenue was up 17% in the quarter on very strong Canadian export of bulk wheat and canola. Our U.S. grain revenue, however, was down 17% on very anemic Gulf export of corn and soybean. Fertilizer revenue was down 29% in a basically very poor North American fertilizer market. I think you will also remember that this winter we did not have any Canpotex spot sales as we did the winter before.</p>
          <p>Going to intermodal, overseas intermodal revenue was up a very strong 21%, our trans-Pacific revenue increased 30%, with volume of our two West Coast gateway outpacing again the trans-Pacific market in overall. Traffic by the Port of Halifax declined due to shipping line service cancellation and to a weaker trans-Atlantic trade. Volume at Port of Montreal was flat for the quarter.</p>
          <p>On the domestic side, domestic intermodal revenue was up 12%. And where we had the most success is with our wholesale partner, where we continued to capitalize on the challenging conditions facing the U.S. trucking industry. Our intra-U.S. volume grew 12% and our cross-broader traffic grew 22% in unit.</p>
          <p>Finally, our non-rail revenue was up 10% in dollar. It was driven by our iron ore vessel and iron ore terminal, as well as by our CNPL <mark type="ph" /> intermodal (16:09) local trucking unit. This was partly offset by some lost revenue related to last year's sales of our Convent coal terminal.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the outlook, if you can join me on page 10, on page 10, I'm sorry. We will continue to grow, growing volume, growing price, growing service innovation and grow by helping our customers and supply chain partners to win in their own market. Starting with intermodal, the outlook is very positive. We will continue to outpace the trans-Pacific trade for import and export. Rupert is starting some new service to Edmonton, Calgary and the Ohio Valley, in that case, with the CSX.</p>
          <p>We have also opened a new lumber export container in the container yard in Vancouver. The U.S. consumer confidence was 70.2 in March, following a sharp rise in January where it was 61.5. We are also taking delivery of new domestic equipment, that is, container, heaters, EcoTherm, chassis, which will enable us to search for the right market opportunity if it does arise.</p>
          <p>On page 11, to look at the bulk outlook. As discussed in our New Orleans Investor Day we are on track to expand our export coal franchise from both existing mine expansion as well as from existing expansion of the four waterfront terminal that we serve. Both are required to succeed in the export market. Cyclical demand for fertilizer will slowly improve from Q1; it will not reach historical peak. Our potash business for Canpotex will start this July 1. There's a huge interest and level of activities toward investment by Chinese-backed consumers of natural resource and to new mine that could be on the CN.</p>
          <p>The U.S. domestic grain business will be steady, but the U.S. export business for grain will remain slow. Canadian grain is coming off a series of back-to-back record quarter, and it should stay strong during the second quarter of this year as well. Finally, outlook for manufacturing on page 12, we will have stable lumber volume from Asian buyer from the province of BC, we will also have sustained year-over-year increase of our lumber to the U.S. market.</p>
          <p>Our Petroleum Metals and the Minerals segment will continue to capitalize on the boom in the shale oil activities. Crude by rail is expected to exceed 20,000 carloads in CN this year versus the 5,000 carloads of last year. We also expect a very strong market in our steel product for the remaining of the year. Chemical, chemical right now looks to be more on the flat side, but we expect positive industrial demand as well as low cost for gas to eventually provide the fundamental support to the sector.</p>
          <p>In closing, Q2 has the making of a growth quarter and same is for the remaining of the year. So far this quarter the leader is our overseas intermodal, minerals, petroleum products and coal exports would also be strong.</p>
          <p>Luc, if you want to take it from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep, thanks very much, J.J. Now, turning to page 14 of the presentation. Let me walk you through the key financial highlights of our quarterly financial performance and, indeed, a good quarter it was.</p>
          <p>Revenues were up 13%, at $2.3 billion. A gradually improving economy and milder winter conditions constituted a favorable backdrop in the quarter compared to last year. J.J. and Keith's teams combined efforts to help us achieve solid volume increases and practically all commodities factors. And once again, several categories performed better than base market conditions. Operating income was $793 million, up 23% versus last year, driven by strong revenue growth and at low incremental costs. Other income was $293 million, up $7 million from last year, as we sold some rail line segments to Toronto's Local Transit Agency in both years. So our net income for the first quarter of 2012 was $775 million, up 16%. And the reported diluted EPS, therefore, was $1.75, up 21%.</p>
          <p>Excluding the gain on sale of the rail line segments, the adjusted diluted EPS for the quarter stood at $1.18, that's up 31% versus 2011. Our operating ratio was 66.2% in the quarter versus 69% last year. This represents an improvement of 2.8 points. This is an all-time record, beating our previous best dating back to the first quarter of 2006, when our operating ratio stood back then at 67.1%.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to operating expenses on the next page. As Keith pointed out, we came through with another solid quarter in terms of operational productivity and customer service. Yet, this performance did not come at the expense of overall cost management. Operating expenses were just over $1.5 billion, up 7% versus last year on a constant-currency basis. Excluding the fuel expense, this was a 4.9% increase.</p>
          <p>Labor and fringe benefit costs were $509 million, 7% higher than last year. This was the result of wage cost inflation of about 3% and a higher head count in the quarter versus last year. Our average head count was at just over 23,000 employees and it was up 3.5% versus last year, while I'll remind you that our GTMs were 7%. Sequentially, however, the average head count was slightly down versus the fourth quarter of 2011. Our manpower dynamics continue to be driven by advanced hiring ahead of attrition to allow for training along with our assessment of future volume growth.</p>
          <p>The fuel expense increased by 13% to $376 million. Higher prices represented 9 points of this increase in the quarter, while the balance of the change was attributable to volume increases for 7%, partly offset by improved fuel efficiency in the tune of 2%. Equipment rent, at $62 million in the quarter were $11 million higher than last year, but essentially flat versus the fourth quarter of 2011. This is the result of increasing our car fleet and intermodal equipment in 2011 to handle the growth and service requirements for the current business levels.</p>
          <p>Casualty and other costs were $77 million, $7 million better than last year as we continue to incur lower expenses and experience lower claims. In terms of free cash flow, on the following page, for the quarter, we generated $48 million operating results and the proceeds received from the sale of rail line segments were $311 million, were offset by higher working capital of $766 million, capital expenditures of $224 million and dividends of $165 million. The higher use of cash attributable to working capital mostly results from a total pension contribution of $553 million made in the quarter. Lower payables were about $150 million and higher inventories and materials and supplies were about $60 million.</p>
          <p>When we compare it to last year, we generated approximately $400 million less free cash flow in the quarter, and this was mostly due to the special voluntary pension contribution totaling $450 million that we have made in the first quarter of this year versus none that were done in last year, in the same quarter last year. Our balance sheet remains strong, with our debt ratio well within our internal guidelines.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me speak to our 2012 outlook. We continue to see a gradual improvement in the North American economy, which should translate into mid-single digit carload growth in 2012. On the pricing front, we are on track with our inflation plus policy. We are clearly encouraged by our first quarter performance. However, given how difficult last year's first quarter was, we will likely have more challenging comparable ahead, since we arguably handled in the first quarter of this year some volume which ended up in the second quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>With this in mind, we are nevertheless now firming up our guidance; so our 2012 annual guidance has us now aiming to deliver a full 10% of EPS growth over the 2011 adjust diluted EPS of $4.84, this, despite our additional pension expense of $100 million. We're also calling for free cash flow to now stand in the order of $950 million, and our capital investment program is set at about $1.8 billion. So, the CN team remains focused and committed to delivering superior results as we continue to unfold our strategic agenda.</p>
          <p>And on this note, I'll turn it back over to you, Claude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you, guys. So I think it's pretty clear, as I said at the outset, that we do have a very solid first quarter performance, but fundamentally this is about an agenda that is delivering results. We've discussed this agenda with you in New Orleans during the fourth quarter. You know about it, you're seeing the proof points coming through in terms of leading the way the industry would grow, being able to accommodate that growth at low incremental costs and continuing on our path of improving efficiency, all the while trying to balance and improve our service offerings so that we can become that trusted partner that helps its customer win in the marketplace, which is the recipe for long-term value creation in the rail industry. The first quarter was solid, the second quarter is starting off on a very solid footing, our results are lining up to help us deliver a very strong year. If the economy stays with us, 2012 should be a banner year.</p>
          <p>And we're looking forward to deliver those results and take your questions at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now take questions from the telephone lines. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from Bill Greene from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there, good afternoon. Claude or Luc, can I ask you to just maybe offer a little bit of color around this guidance? I realize you want to give conservative guidance that you're confident you can do. On the other hand, 30% growth and a beat of this magnitude, it kind of suggests that we've got to have a downward negative revision for the second half, which is not consistent with what you put in the press release or sort of the comments. So what are you worried about? Because I've got to believe that this is very conservative and you'll do much better than this, given the first quarter performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill, I know &#x2013; I'm gratified by your trust. But I think you should take our guidance with &#x2013; for what it is. We have always been a little bit conservative. But we are also telling you that our first quarter, given winter, given an extra day, given stock-based compensation which was very helpful during the quarter, the 30% is outstanding result, but that's not what we would have delivered if not for those factors. If you've got to tweak down a little bit your &#x2013; some of your quarters in the end to get closer to our guidance, that's what I would do if I were you. But we're here to continue to deliver solid results. If we're a little too conservative and do better, that's a good story.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, can I just ask you just on a macro level then, what would you be worried about, what is the conservatism based on? Because based on everything that's in the assumptions here, it's hard to get to your number. Do you see what I mean? I don't know what we're trying to lower, what the reason is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you should take our guidance for what it is, Bill. We are not worried about anything. We see the economy continue to unfold positively. If we can deliver mid-single-digit carload growth, we will deliver a full 10% EPS growth and close to $1 billion of free cash flow, which would be outstanding results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right; fair enough. Thanks. Appreciate the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Cherilyn Radbourne from TD Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, good afternoon. So, it was a strong performance out of your coal franchise this quarter and I think that was perhaps despite Ridley not operating at full capacity. So maybe you can give us some color there and just talk about how you feel the export terminals on your network are positioned in the context of a domestic thermal environment that's challenging.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the domestic terminal will be challenging. Domestic terminal in the U.S. for CN was never necessarily a big revenue driver but typically is fairly big carload driver because a lot of that business was coming to us from <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:14) or the U.P. at the Chicago Interchange. What really drives a lot of dollars is the longer haul. So either PRB coal coming to us via the interchange in Edmonton or via Vancouver. All the PRB coal is going to Rupert, so that's fairly long haul. And Rupert is expanding, has expanded. It has some issues, but it's still &#x2013; it's cranking a whole lot more product than it used to and the future is bright for Ridley.</p>
          <p>The terminal in Vancouver also expanding, making an effort to expand both Westshore and Neptune. And don't forget also our terminal in Convent; when we sold that terminal, we sold it to a very good operator, Cline and Foresight Energy. They're actually running this terminal harder than we did ourselves. And because the domestic market is weakening like it is for everybody else, they have low cost, high Btu coal and they are making effort to sell some of that in Asia and we saw some of that in the first quarter, so Illinois to Convent <mark type="ph" /> at some vessel also (30:9). We're serving terminals and we're serving people who have been focused on export now for a couple of years already. So it's coming together nicely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. That's my one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Cherilyn. You're always very disciplined.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Ken Hoexter from Bank of Montreal Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good afternoon. Thank you. As you look forward to those targets that maybe we could dig a little into your volume expectations and your growth. I know you target to continue to take share. Can you can tell us what's in those expectations as far as the go-forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know what, we want to grow a little bit faster than what the economy would give us. And I think we did that for the last several quarters. It really depends on the rising tide and it doesn't need to much more than half a point to a point better than what we would otherwise receive from the economy to allow us on a longer-term basis to deliver solid results for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>So we're running a little ahead of that at the moment. We have a lot of momentum working for us. There will be quarters where we will run a little light, but on balance, one carload at a time, one unit in intermodal at the time in the markets that J.J. highlighted to you, we're really pursuing a broad range set of initiatives to help us grow share of wallet and help our customers win in the marketplace. And it's actually working because they're rewarding us with more business on an ongoing basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. But you're kind of trending ahead of that. Do you expect to see that slowing dramatically or do you expect &#x2013; or are you saying &#x2013; I just want to understand -- for the pace that you're at in terms of taking share now, do you see that decelerating or even going a little slower or you maintain the current pace? Because, like you noted, you're far above that right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think, as I said a second ago, we are &#x2013; we have a lot of momentum as we speak. So is it going to continue every quarter like this? That would be difficult. But we are certainly of the view that we can continue that for many years to come at the right pace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right; I appreciate that. Thank you, Claude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Benoit Poirier from Desjardins Capitals. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much. When we look at your intermodal growth in the quarter, obviously, pretty solid. But is there any specific explanation behind the strong performance? Is it sustainable? And is it related to the winter issues we had last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Benoit, when we look our -- I think when you look at our intermodal result for the last two years, I think every quarter you see that the business has been fairly strong and it's not a one-time event, it's a fairly solid, steady business plan that we have with steady quality result improvement. And the trans-Pacific trade for all railroad is stronger than the trans-Atlantic trade, and this is where we have put our biggest focus and also had our biggest success , both in Canadian cities and U.S. cities, and expanding our reach to new destination market we didn't have two years ago. I think it's solid. It's a question in the end that the shipping line choose railroad and the bidding owners choose the shipping line and the one that has the better partner providing the better supply chain.</p>
          <p>So, we're not &#x2013; in a way we're competing for the heart of the shipping line, which are our customers. But ultimately, what makes us successful is to win our customers' customers, so that they want to use the sea and port for their delivery. Intermodal is &#x2013; there's no reason for it to really slow down. You might go from market to market, east to west, but we have a solid plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; thanks for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Scott Group from Wolfe Trahan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks. Good afternoon, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Claude, I just wanted to clarify one thing. I think you mentioned to one of the earlier questions that incentive comp or stock-based comp was a benefit in the quarter. Did you quantify that? And was that a benefit because it was low in this quarter or because it was so high a year ago?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Scott, let me pick this up. This is Luc. The stock-based compensation, the benefit in this quarter was to the tune of about $30 million. So we're roughly talking about $0.05 of EPS. And this was really the result of if you look at last year between the &#x2013; in the quarter, the stock price went up by $7 last year, whereas this year it actually went down by a $1. So that's what's producing this favorable variance this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But most of that it sounds like is in the year-ago period. I'm just trying to get a sense of the real run rate we're on just because even if I take out the weather benefit, it feels like, just based on what first quarter normally is as a percent of the year, we're running closer to that $5.75 range for the year relative to the guidance. I just trying to understand what is &#x2013; what's this year and what's last year in terms of the stock-based comp.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As Luc explained to you, the stock-based compensation is the difference between the beginning of quarter and end of quarter stock price. And so last year it went up $7 during the quarter and this year it came down $1 during the first quarter. So the swing of $8 is what drives the $30 million of benefit on a year-over-year basis. But the way it's measured is from beginning to end of quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That makes lot of sense. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Walter Spracklin from RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Good afternoon, everyone. So you did a good job of discussing the sustainability on your volume side and I was wondering if we could switch over to Keith on the operating side. Obviously, another excellent quarter there. Just curious if you could speak to training costs. I know you mentioned at the beginning that you're going to have to train a lot of workers ahead of attrition. Can you update us on what we might see as a headwind and perhaps quantify that from a sustainability standpoint? And also on that sustainability, if you've quantified as well the effects of weather this quarter at all on an EPS level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can tell you now as far as training costs, we're pretty much at a steady state with our attrition. We're well into it now versus last year. And this is going to be sustained where we're at, training locomotive engineers and conductors at the same time I would think looking at our demographics through 2015. So I don't see a lot of change. The only thing I see on head count change relative to running trains would be associated with the level of business. And even with the level of business, a lot we can absorb in our existing train starts. The only part of which we wouldn't be able to, of course, would be bulk train starts and some intermodal train starts. So I think we're at a pretty good run rate now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And in terms of quantifying the weather, was there any effort...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't put an exact number on it. I mean, I'd be taking a hard stab at it, so to speak. So, let me avoid doing that, but let me just say that weather, of course, helped us. It helped us on the revenue side, it helped us on the operating cost side and on a reliability side. But to put a number on it I think would be &#x2013; probably be a little bit reckless.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; thanks. Congratulations on a great quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Tom Wadewitz from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon. Wanted to ask you a little bit more on the cost side. If I look at operating expenses ex-fuel, you were up a little less than 6% in the quarter, and you had obviously stock-based comp. It looks like &#x2013; I don't know if casualty is kind of lower than normal run rate given the weather or how you'd look at that. But what do you think the kind of if you say similar level of volume growth looking forward, what do you think the right run rate is for operating expenses? Is it 1 point higher than that, 2 points higher than that? I guess any thoughts on that would be helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the casualty and other, just to comment on that, I mean, as I provided general guidance on that, it should be in the $75 million to $80 million per quarter. So, I mean, it's just about just about there for the first quarter. Those things tend to be lumpy a little bit though however, so we could have some bouncing up and down in the other quarters.</p>
          <p>Expenses are very well managed. So I think it's really just you're not going to see tremendous variations. The trend is there. The fuel is difficult to anticipate, but I think, as you can see, on the labor side we've got things tightly under control. Of course, the pension headwind is there, that's $100 million for the year. And annual stock-based compensation, again, a little bit volatile, it will be up and down but it should be over the course of the year fairly similar.</p>
          <p>Equipment rents, I made some comments on. And I think $62 million, $65 million is probably not a bad run rate because the equipment is essentially there. And while we're probably going to acquire a little bit more throughout the year, there was a significant change during the course of last year. So that gives you a little bit more color around these -generally these expenses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it was a really the stock-based comp that was probably the biggest thing that we might want to consider looking forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And in the quarter also there was a little bit &#x2013; the fuel lag was actually not very significant, it was only $9 million. But if you look back to last year, that's another component which was important. Last year, this was really a headwind of about close to $30 million. So the difference quarter to quarter last year versus the quarter this year is also contributing probably a couple of pennies favorably to the comparative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You never cease to amaze me, you have these good one questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Fadi Chamoun from BMO Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. So a question on <mark type="ph" /> intermodal (42:07). I want to go back to the &#x2013; you've had a few quarters of good domestic growth. I just wanted to understand little bit. I mean your length of haul is typically longer and your ability to convert from truck is not maybe as good as what you achieve with a U.S. carrier, and yet you're seeing some good number. Can you give us an idea about how much runway you think you have in that specific market and where specifically you are able to be effective?. And the other thing on that IMX as well intermodal, what's the capacity situation now at Prince Rupert?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. So if I start with the first one, I think about 65% roughly in that range is overseas business is coming via ports. So, in that case, you're really looking in most cases at a fairly long haul business, Montreal to Toronto would be the exception. So we in overseas growth what we have, it's we are not really competing with truckers, we're competing with other railroad and other port.</p>
          <p>On the domestic side, that the U.S. market and Canadian market are very different. The U.S. market is &#x2013; the capacity of trucking is tighter because of the regulation there. And our rate of growth for U.S. domestic business as well as cross border is also faster than the Canadian growth. And I think one of the areas that we've exploited and maybe it's not obvious to people, on the intermodal side is we have been selling intermodal harder and harder to our carload customers.</p>
          <p>I wouldn't call this converting boxcar or gondola into container, but I would simply put it in a framework, customers themselves at a time want to use something which is more expensive, call like a truck, to move pulp or steel or whatnot. And when we approach them with the intermodal product, we have more success than we had in the past in selling an over-the-road product to the manufacturing sector. So, I think when you had all this in, there's still a potential for our railroad in intermodal, whether it's domestic or overseas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>His last example, Fadi, that J.J. was referring to is a very good expression of our supply chain approach, that if you're there for the customer on that extra load and you are offerings both a solid carload product and also the intermodal product to flex when we have issues in terms of service or when there is little spike in demand, you can get to that incremental piece of business, that share of wallet that we were not going after before. We are now more focused on and it's paying off on in terms of customer sentiment, but also paying off in terms of a little bit more into little bit more intermodal growth on the domestic side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful. How much of the growth of the domestic would be explained by this carload conversion? I mean, is this a big piece of the growth that you are seeing on the domestic side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't call it huge, but it's something that's steady, that's sustainable. So, for example, on the overseas side, when I made my comment, I did talk about the new lumber transfer facility that we put &#x2013; that we've put in Vancouver. And as you remember, we did the same thing in Prince George about two years ago. So when you have those things, you actually help convert <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:45) into container in those two cases for overseas export business, but the same thing is done also on domestic.</p>
          <p>We move some domestic freight from Vancouver, manufacturing freight to Eastern Canada. In container, same thing to Mexico in some cases during the holiday season. So moving intermodal in manufacturing segment makes a lot of sense, and that's why customers have been using dry van and we said, you know, we have a dry van product long haul, it's called intermodal. The same sales force now is making a much bigger effort than the past to sell that product. Intermodal is not a business unit, it's a service. It could be used by consumer product, automotive, pulp and paper, steel, metal, you name it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Chris Wetherbee from Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. Good afternoon, guys. Just a question, Luc, you mentioned in your wrap-up slide there that maybe you saw a bit of a pull-forward of volumes I think as the comment that you had made from the first quarter, maybe it was due to weather or the favorable operating conditions. Just getting curious if there was specifically any commodity that we should see some of that impact on, was that kind of a thought 2Q and to 1Q? I think that's the way you phrased it. I just wanted to dig into that a little bit, if I could.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, there's probably a little bit in the area of grain and a little bit in terms of how quickly we could get some of our vessel sailings on the Great Lakes. I mean, those with some areas where there has been a little bit of that. Intermodal is also something that was helped by a lot of the favorable weather conditions. So those are some of the areas where you are likely to see a little bit of a pull because of the good weather.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And this order of magnitude, is it something material we should be thinking about or just maybe little bit on the margin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's always difficult to quantify these things. So, as Claude earlier made in his statement, overall, it's not inconceivable that maybe about a third of the growth that we've seen during the course of the quarter may be attributable to a combination of all of these factors. So it's weather, it's Leap Year, or it's volume and expenses coming all together just giving us a little bit of a better first quarter this year versus last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from David Tyerman from Canaccord Genuity. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I guess one concern out that's out there in the market is on Asia and the potential for a slowdown in the China. I was wondering &#x2013; obviously your volumes aren't showing it yet, but I was wondering if you're seeing any kind of leading indicators that that kind of situation could be developing from your conversations with customers, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, our volume <mark type="ph" /> are not showing none (48:48) at this point. In fact, we're still growing, whether it's central oil, thermal coal, coking coal, pulp, lumber, it's holding steady.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, we do hear the same chatters, but J.J. was just for the last week and a half in China. And all the key supply chains that &#x2013; Canada is becoming more and more top-of-mind in China as a source for critical commodities, lumber.</p>
          <p>Clearly, our Canadian lumber producers have broken through and they're now force in that market. And minerals, whether it's coal, whether it's concentrate, there is a tremendous appetite and interest. There's a developing interest in iron ore, for instance, in China. So China might slow down, but I think Canada is well positioned in the world market as a source that the Chinese buyers want to favor. And I think that's going to bode well for CN for many years to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When we say slow down, we mean slower growth, and they're not slowing down very fast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you're not actually seeing anything right now where met coal or things like that are coming under pressure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what we see is that any commodity market goes up and down. And I think the price of met coal, for example, at some point was probably higher than what it could be sustained at. And as you would see in any market, whether it's potash or any other world commodity, it goes up and down. But the price of coal on export is lower for coking coal. But the price of coking coal is also still at a price that the mine make a decent profit, profit enough that it want to produce and sell as much as what they can. So, we're in the business of moving volume, and the price commodity goes up and down, that's does not necessarily reflect itself right away through the volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Jason Seidl from Dahlman Rose. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. On the pricing front, a little bit better than we expected here. Could you guys talk about the strengths that you're seeing on the pricing side, which commodity groups that they're favoring? And also what gives you confidence that you guys are going to be able to maintain that sort of 4% plus pricing going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The pricing is coming from the same area that it was coming last year. It's fairly broad based, some pay a little bit more than some others. We don't necessarily much change on where those pricing come from. And, yes, we did have slightly more this year than last year, so we view that as a positive encouragement that it is sustainable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's a reflection of the quality of our service and the situation in end market. We have always said we will deliver price ahead of inflation in that 3% to 4% range. It's a good thing when it's firming up as we speak and we'll try to keep it sustainable at that level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gentlemen, thank you for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question is from Matt Troy from Susquehanna. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. I was wondering in the broader context of your investment in EJ&amp;E, if you could just give us an update with respect to traffic density flowing through that piece of track and as well as just the strategic fit? You talked about it being more of a chess piece than a checker jump. And was wondering if you could offer some <mark type="ph" /> examples of (52:30) how that property continues to pay dividends?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say from a density standpoint, it's pretty much in line with the growth in business. So, no dramatic changes there. We have not &#x2013; we made a couple shifts over the J trains, we were running through the inner circle, so to speak, of Chicago. We simply cut over to Madison last year, which is helping us in the velocity standpoint. And we continue to invest. Kirk Yard, we're building now in that facility to effectively create a hub that, in the past, you know, we could hub about 1,500 cars a day and bump up against capacity constraints. We're going to a yard that will handle about 2,500.</p>
          <p>So we're in the middle of converting an interchange that normally would have gone through the Belt or other locations with other carriers, taken our interchange there to Kirk Yard, where we can realize some synergies across the network, outlying points where we otherwise would have switched &#x2013; payments we were making to the Belt for traffics charges or to the Harbor for traffics charges. So that's a continuing story that will unfold for us through his year into next year. And then, finally, the last piece of that conversion will be taking a switching operation, switching costs, out of a Markham and shifting that into that same facility at Kirk Yard, as well as our locomotive facility. So that's more to come in the 2013, early 2014 timeframe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. That's my one. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Matt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from the Chris Ceraso form Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. You mentioned your strategy is to bring on volume at a low incremental cost, and it looks like you did a good job at that in the quarter. On my math, it was maybe $0.56 that fell for the bottom line from incremental revenue year-over-year. That's good but it's not that abnormal for a railroad like yourself. So I'm trying to gauge how much help did you really get form the weather? And can we expect to see incremental margins like this going forward or does it go back to 40%, 45%, 50%? What's your feel on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You guys are very demanding and gratifying in your support. There's no question we are able to accommodate the business at low incremental costs. And I think, as Luc explained to you earlier, when you take into account the moving pieces that our less related to the running of the business, pension, the stock-based compensation, fuel lags, these things can move you up or down easily by 10%, 15%.</p>
          <p>So it's tough to use one quarter and make projections. But there's no question during the first quarter, you just look at the metric that Keith explained, we were able to improve operating metrics in terms of efficiency, we were able to grow a little faster on the <mark type="ph" /> rock (55:22) volume side and revenue with good pricing. You do those two things and you deliver very solid results like we just did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just one clarifying point on the pension. There are two different numbers that you've mentioned, the $450 million that you said in the press release, there's $550 million on the cash flow. Is the difference just that the $450 million is voluntary on top of $100 million that's required?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's exactly it. $450 million is the voluntary special contributions that we've made in the quarter. We did two $150 million early in the quarter and then we made another one of $300 million at the back end of the quarter. On top of that, we contributed for current service costs $103 million. So, that's the total of $553 million that you've seen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Peter Nesvold from Jefferies. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. On the labor line, ordinarily you're down roughly $40 million to $60 million sequentially when you go from 1Q to 2Q. Now, I guess this year we had fewer weather-related costs in that line, you had pension going up and you have incentive comp. Is it potentially flattish from 1Q to 2Q? And then just a clarification, maybe that counts as a half question. On the free cash flow, so you took it up. There was nothing in there that talked about gains on sale. Last quarter when you gave the original guidance of $875 million, it did exclude gains on sales. I just wanted to understand if the property gain is included in that upward revision of the free cash flow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The gain on sale of the Gray Line subdivision was proceeds of $311 million. Now, as I mentioned, those proceeds came in and then they quickly left and were reinvested, if you wish, in terms of the pension contribution. So, that really didn't matter into the $875 million, so it wasn't in the $875 million. So it came in on top of it and then, as I said, it ended up leaving the free cash flow because of the special voluntary contributions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on the labor costs, it's typically down $40 million to $60 million from 1Q to 2Q. Is it sort of flattish this year? Is that a reasonable number to think about in the near term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, you've got the trend is the following, I mean, you've got about 3% of wage inflation, you will have head count somewhere &#x2013; at this particular quarter we were up about 3.5. Over the longer term, we are going to be trending a little bit closer to attrition plus 1 or 2 percentage points, depending where volume is going, and we are continuing to hire ahead of attrition so. And then it's down to the pension pressure, which we've quantified at $100 million of additional expense for the year. So those are the factors that are going to drive it. If stock-based compensation doesn't bounce around too much, that's what you've got in store.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Brandon Oglenski from Barclays. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good afternoon, everyone. And I'll keep it quick, I know we have hockey tonight. Just quickly, Keith, looking at the unit cost performance in the quarter, it was pretty solid to us, even with, as you mentioned, locomotive utilization down and train velocity slightly down. So can you maybe just expand on how these new service patterns are impacting those metrics but you're able to more than offset it at a network level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's pretty much that's it. I mean, we're losing a little bit &#x2013; in the West part of the territory, we're a little bit more heavier than other locations. We're gaining with our strategies and our opportunities across the railway. I mean, we consistently review noise, is what I called noise in the system, so to speak. And we strategically invest to eliminate noise and increase capacity and to maintain our velocity on our trains. So what we've lost in BC North, which does have a material impact on the number because the percentage of growth we've had there, we've gained back with investments over the NOD. We're running trains much faster over the NOD than we did last year with those strategic investments.</p>
          <p>We're doing a much better job of controlling velocity and costs in Chicago, with operating strategy, the strategic investment we made with EJ&amp;E. And I can go territory to territory. There's no one silver bullet; it's just a gain here, it's gain there. We've got a very competitive operating group internally. We compete with each other, so to speak. Our success breeds success, and we just don't like effectively give anything back unless we absolutely have to.</p>
          <p>And I think you'll find in the case where we do, which is BC North, we sort of anticipated this two years ago and started this path. And we're two years into a five-year plan that will eliminate that. Now, the next challenge is I want J.J. to give us more business and a more challenging opportunity, and we'll figure out a solution of that as well with this team.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks a lot, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Konark Gupta from Cormark Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys. I'm here for David Newman today. One question would be on the coal side. Your carloads were down 11% in Q1. And so far in Q2, two weeks, it's down 17%. So just talking about domestic thermal, it's weak, PRB stock piles are above normal. Canadian met coal and thermal coal exports are very strong. So can you please comment on your coal RTMs and pricing going forward? And perhaps any impact on PRB coal shipments and Prince Rupert</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, when you look at the CN coal business, looking at the carload is somewhat misleading because our real story is in RTM. So you look at the RTM, you really got a sense where our revenue are heading, while looking to carload you won't get that. The PRB coal and your two questions on PRB, PRB coal is still moving by <mark type="ph" /> rail for (1:01:26) export, mostly to Asia and, obviously, China.</p>
          <p>And the pricing on coal -- I know there's been some question asked in general about whether or not railroad are supporting with better price, meaning lower price, export program. And I know these requests have been made, but we're not on that page. And most of what CN is moving in terms of coal is actually coking coal, coal which was already market was offshore and not domestically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on PRB, you said it's moving via Prince Rupert, obviously, right, but are you seeing any impact of the stockpiles, which are like the other U.S. Class-1 railroad said it's above normal right now, and it's way above normal. Is there any impact of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we're about normal, meaning we had a run rate and we're keeping that run rate &#x2013; there's about a kind of a steady flow that was already in the making, if I understand your question correctly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's important for you to recognize is our so-called utility coal is less than 2% of our revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And because it's a very short haul, it's a lot of carloads, so our volumes in coal in the first quarter and our volumes so far in the second quarter in coal if you measure it by RTM is up on a year-over-year basis. And it's up because our export business, which is longer haul, is doing very well. But if you follow only carloads, you might get a sense that things are coming down. But it's very short-haul on this and 2% of our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; that's very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Jeff Kauffman from Sterne, Agee. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Congratulations, terrific, terrific quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One question for Keith, 23 parts. Keith, you were talking a bit about the longer trains that you run, and you mentioned slower in the west. I know it differs by what class of service and where you're running it, but can you give me an idea, because you're bringing on the DP locomotives now, how far can this go before gravity kicks in? And what's kind of a way for me to think about it? Have you thought about it in terms of every 5% we add to train length should be worth what to operating ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's too many moving parts to be able to do that. I can say that DP certainly has been a significant piece of our success in this area. Effectively, we've invested lot of money over the past eight years, ten years, over $500 million in creating a network &#x2013; our core network with long sidings that are spaced. Without DP we were not able to optimize that. With DP, over the past two years, I mean, for instance first quarter 2010, we had about 260 or 270 DP locomotives, we ran 20 train starts per day with DP, versus this year where we've got about 440 and we ran 60. So, I mean, there's still more room to go, more improvements to be made.</p>
          <p>This is sort of &#x2013; there's not a perfect science to it. The time it really benefits your DP effectively other than controlling train starts is winter operations, maintaining the air pressure through a train. So, this past winter, given that the temperatures were not as extreme as they were last year, we really didn't see the benefit that I think we'll see when winter does come back. So I think there's more to play out in this thing. I can't put a number on it, but I can tell you it's substantial and it will continue to allow us to accept incremental growth, especially in our manifest trains, at a lower incremental cost. So, it's a good story for us; more to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The final question is from Keith Schoonmaker from Morningstar. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. Keith, I think this question is for you. In addition to the DP equipment, let's say the J, the Kirk, those have been quite major. At the Investor Meeting in Chicago a couple of years ago, I think you mentioned maybe even a full percentage point of margin gain from deploying more completely yard management software. What's &#x2013; has that tool been deployed and are there other such big levers still left to pull?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No big levers. That has &#x2013; Smart Yard, which you're talking about, we have deployed that over the preponderance of our system. The major yards are equipped with Smart Yard. The more satellite yards, we've got a modified version that's not quite as robust, but still gives the people that operate those terminals very good planning tools to optimize train connections in our yard <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:05:56), which you see in our metrics. I mean, even with an increased level of business, <mark type="audio gap" /> (1:05:57) cost. Again, no silver bullets. Our big investments, that BC North piece is going to be something we continue to focus on. We'll finish off Chicago and then we'll see where the business is and where the opportunity is from that point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Keith, and thank you for all of you to participate on this call. Again, very solid first quarter. I think we are constructive about the year. If you don't trust us, you can take a little leap of faith and add a couple of percentage if you want to. But stay on us with our guidance and let us over-perform again over the next few quarters and we'll be looking forward to report on those at our upcoming calls. Thank you very much and have a good and safe day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The conference call has now concluded. Please disconnect your lines at this time and we thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>