<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1507885" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1382</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Robert Noorigian</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Claude Mongeau</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Operating Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Keith E. Creel</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Marketing Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Jean-Jacques Ruest</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Luc Jobin</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Chris Wetherbee</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Scotia Capital Markets">Turan Quettawala</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="TD Securities">Cherilyn Radbourne</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Wolfe Trahan &amp; Co.">Scott H. Group</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Bill J. Greene</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Thomas R. Wadewitz</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Desjardins Securities">Benoit Poirier</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Chris J. Ceraso</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Dominion Securities, Inc.">Walter Spracklin</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Susquehanna Financial Group LLP">Matthew Troy</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Dahlman Rose &amp; Co. LLC">Jason H. Seidl</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Veronica Mangione</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Cormark Securities, Inc.">David F. Newman</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the CN Third Quarter 2012 Financial Results Conference Call. I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. Robert Noorigian, Vice President-Investor Relations. Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. Noorigian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thank you for joining us for CN's third quarter 2012 financial results. I'd like to remind you again about the comments that have already been made regarding forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>With us today is Claude Mongeau, our President and Chief Executive Officer; Luc Jobin, our Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer; Mr. Keith Creel, Executive Vice President and Chief Operating Officer; and J.J. Ruest, Executive Vice President and Chief Marketing Officer.</p>
          <p>In order to be fair to all participants, could you please limit your questions to one each. With that, it's now my pleasure to introduce Mr. Claude Mongeau, our President and Chief Executive Officer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bob, and thank you for all of you to be on this call at the end of the day. Let me just go over quickly the highlights and then I'll turn it to the team to give you the key details. But fair to say, we're very pleased with our third quarter performance. It's pretty solid overall. We've had a number of areas where we hit record in terms of our performance. Revenue is one of them, in terms of overall throughput and volume. This is one of our best third quarter ever. Our revenues were up 7% if you take out the impact of exchange and pretty broad based growth across all our business sectors that J.J. will give you the key elements in a minute.</p>
          <p>We were able to accommodate that business at low incremental cost. I'm very pleased with all of our operating metrics continuing to show improvement at the same time as we're continuing to focus and making progress in our core service metrics. So, Keith will give you the highlights, but it comes down to how we were able to accommodate that business at low incremental cost and we're very pleased with the 60.6% operating ratio for the third quarter.</p>
          <p>In terms of earnings, and here this is on an adjusted basis, we delivered C$1.52 per share, that's up 10% on an adjusted basis, very solid performance overall and our free cash flow followed. Year-to-date, we are slightly in excess of C$1 billion of free cash flow and it's the strength of that free cash flow generation and also the solidity of our balance sheet that gave our board the confidence to allow us to start a new share buyback program, which Luc will give you some more detail around in a minute.</p>
          <p>So, overall when you look at it, pretty much all aspects of our agenda are working and operational and service excellence is helping us deliver very strong result. Keith?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Claude. This is indeed a great quarter both from an operation perspective as well as a service perspective as we've moved our service and operational excellence agenda forward, growing our business in concert with our customers and our supply chain partners. To that point, in a few moments, I'm going to provide a bit more color and detail to what we mean when we say operational service excellence as well as how we're tracking the progress in this area.</p>
          <p>But let's start on the operational excellence side of the business line by first looking at our performance and the key productivity metrics that we report on each quarter.</p>
          <p>Train loader GTM's per train mile continue to increase as we take advantage of our ability to safely run longer more environmentally and energy-efficient trains. We're handling 2% more tonnage versus same time last year and 4% over third quarter of 2010. To that point, let me share an exciting development quickly as we continue to innovate on this front with the recent third quarter introduction of what we call a super-coal train, our 224-car long coal train in the B.C. North corridor which were essentially double the size of the trains we were running just three years ago. This train's constant innovation has been made possible through our continued investments in the long sidings of the B.C. North, the acquisition of distributed-power engines and by bringing together the appropriate parties in the supply chain to drive end-to-end efficiency.</p>
          <p>On this point, initial reviews from the port operator in Ridley and our customers have been very positive. More to come on this as we evolve this opportunity, but certainly, a success story in the making when it comes to supply chain collaboration in concert with operational efficiency improvements.</p>
          <p>Efficiency gains continue in our terminals as well with a 5% increase through the number of cars processed per switching hour. This combined with the gains in train productivity between our terminals is allowing us to absorb the growth you mentioned at lower terminal labor cost.</p>
          <p>On the asset side, we're moving cars 8% faster than last year. These gains have been driven by reducing the car spent &#x2013; the time the cars spent in terminals, which we see with terminal dwell down 7% year-over-year. In fact, in September we set a record for car velocity reaching an average of 217 miles per day. These velocity gains have been achieved while handling record volumes. This quarter was our busiest of any third quarter in CN's history averaging over 1.50 billion GTMs per day, up 8% from last year. So, overall, very solid performance on the operational excellence side of the equation. We're rest assured we've not lost any of our passion for driving efficiency, but at the same time, we're making a meaningful difference for our customers and our supply chain partners pushing forward on our service excellence agenda.</p>
          <p>So let's now spend a few moments providing some color to service highlights. Service excellence, it starts with an understanding first of what's important to our customers and our supply chain partners. My team and I have been spending a lot of our time with our marketing team, customers and partners to build relationships within the supply chain based on driving mutually beneficial improvements. What you're looking at are a couple of a key service metrics to provide a quantitative assessment of how our supply chain approach is working.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, we met 96% of unconstrained orders placed by our customers and divided the cars on the day requested 89% of the time. This performance is being pushed by our car management excellence team that we've talked about in the past who now have weekly calls with a large cross section of our customer base covering over 60% of our weekly call orders. As opposed to being car distributors, this team has taken ownership of driving car order fulfillment while at the same time being held accountable for achieving improvements in our car velocity and as you can see, they're delivering on both fronts.</p>
          <p>Another key touch point with our customers is the switch window compliance. When we started this service evolution almost three years ago, we heard from our customers in spades that our hub-to-hub and terminal-to-terminal service was excellent. In fact, the data developed and documented during the service review that we went through here in Canada validated that point. But the reliability of our local switching, pooling or delivering the cars what we call our first mile/last mile, was painful for our customers.</p>
          <p>Understandably, the customers want some level of reasonable predictability and when we're going to show up with their facility delivering pool cars. Some would argue even more crucial, they want to hear from us when we can't deliver so they can plan accordingly. This feedback drove the establishment of new metrics and procedures. We now measure our performance at being the committed switch window, which is the window we developed to the overall design of our operating plan end-to-end. In the third quarter, we were in that window 90% of the time, up 87% last year. We're up from 87% last year.</p>
          <p>More recently, a new process we call iAdvise was launched, which we feel is an industry leading initiative to advice customers of those failures proactively during the daily planning phase of our operation so that they have a chance to react calling an audible with the material and manpower when or if a critical car is not pooled to deliver when it's appropriate.</p>
          <p>Finally, a very powerful game changer for CN in our car supply chain customers is the scheduled grain service. As opposed to our previous weekly view measuring spotting performance to the week, we now measure our performance spotting into grain cars of the day. This approach has allowed CN to schedule our grain shipments from the fields to the ports in ways never possible before by coordinating the empty loading to the online shipments to the port deliveries and eventual export with the goal of maintaining a fluid end-to-end pipeline.</p>
          <p>The trust and dependability we developed established in this robust pipeline has allowed CN to sustain a record of spotting 5,000, in excess of 5,000 cars per week for the last six weeks, which is a record for CN. Previously, we'd only supply 5,000 cars two times in a given grain season and these were not back-to-back weeks. It means to say the supply chain collaborative approach that we embarked on and continue to leverage with our partners is working in spades.</p>
          <p>So in summary, our collective supply chain approach is working. It's allowed us to build momentum in our push for operational service excellence for the mutual benefit of our customers, our partners and our shareholders, all of which is built on a foundation of trust and partnership shaped in large part by commercially driven service level agreements.</p>
          <p>Contrary to what some may currently be saying, we do have a winning recipe to handle the business that J.J. and his team are bringing on stream to the benefit of all our supply chain, customers and partners that are willing to engage with us. So with that said, I'll turn it over to J.J. to provide some color on the business this collaborative approach is bringing to the CN one carload at a time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Keith, and a warm welcome to all of you who are joining us tonight. And I will start &#x2013; first I'll give you in the next few minutes the review of our team, the top line performance in the third quarter and give you after that a sense of what business ahead. The third quarter was solid, solid in term of volume and solid in term of price.</p>
          <p>In summary, the revenue was up 8% as reported. Net of exchange was up 7%. The making of that is the following: volume and mix added together was 5%, volume was 5.5%, mix was negative 0.5%. Same-store price on same-store sales was up about 3.5%, midway in our 3% to 4% range. This is in line with our inflation-plus pricing and slightly lower than our near 4% of recent quarter. I'd like to add a note also that we do not do quality pricing on export coal at CN. The fuel lag &#x2013; the lag on fuel surcharge eroded our revenue by about 0.5%.</p>
          <p>Now, let's go into more detail of the top-line and as usual I will do this on a FX adjusted basis for the revenue. Starting with petroleum and chemical, which revenue was up 14% in the quarter. The story here is quite simple, crude and condensate added an incremental $45 million of revenue in the quarter. Refined petroleum was up $10 million. Sulfur which is related to fertilizer went down $6 million and the remaining economically sensitive chemicals were tend to be steady and flat.</p>
          <p>Metals and minerals revenue was up 5%. The commodities which were over-performing was energy-related product, steel product and shale drilling activities that is, for example, steel that goes in the making of pipeline or making of tank cars or drilling pipe as well as track for the fracking of the drilling activities. Those which were showing negative carloads were mostly steel product and their raw material for the other segment in particular iron ore was down, scrap steel was down so was steel slab. Also underperforming was the non-ferrous or a non-ferrous metal sector by that, I mean copper, nickel and aluminum.</p>
          <p>Forest product revenue was up a slight 2%. It's kind of a two story here one side is housing stock which drove the lumber and the panel business up for CN. Our domestic lumber panel was up 9% for the quarter and the lumber was up 9% as well. However, our Asian lumber export was down 20% and that's mostly related to China. Other notable variants in forest product is paper and paper was down 11% in revenue.</p>
          <p>Automotive revenue was up 9% in the quarter, and that was mostly driven by the offshore import on the two coasts, which in our case is what drove most of our top-line. The revenue coming from our domestic served plant in Michigan and Ontario was fairly muted.</p>
          <p>Very unique to CN, our coal revenue was up 11% in the third quarter. CN is bucking the industry trend as it comes to coal revenue, and here is why we're different. The revenue of our overall met coal business all in was up 12%. The revenue of our thermal coal business all in was up 6%. And the revenue for our pet coal business all in was up 40%.</p>
          <p>To give you a perspective from another angle, our total export, that is a combined export of met coal, thermal coal and pet coal was up 38%. This is a proof that a supply chain initiative that Keith talked about earlier and the effort that we put our partners in the last two years is really paying off in some of our export capabilities at CN.</p>
          <p>Now looking at grain and fertilizer which was up 9%. The fertilizer did very well. It was up 18%. First and foremost, the export potash was up very strong, as a result of CN on boarding the Canpotex new contract which is working very well for us, but also domestically, both potash and fertilizer were also up on the quarter but only single digit.</p>
          <p>U.S. grain was slightly negative because of the drought in the Midwest. We ran out of grain. The Canadian grain was up 11%, and Keith has already talked about our record level of spotting in the last seven weeks exceeding 5,000 work hours per week.</p>
          <p>Going to intermodal, intermodal revenue was up 6% while container unit were up 7% but the RTM was up only 2%. And that's in part because our mix of length of haul is slightly lower this quarter, but also because we improved our intermodal train balance back to the port. In the third quarter, we moved a higher amount of overseas empty container on revenue waybill. The lading tonnage of these empty container being zero, they produce revenue, they produce carload, but they don't produce RTM. But these makes for better round trip yield margin on these train.</p>
          <p>On the West Coast, the business was up 10% in revenue. In our domestic business, we had strong result in both moving retail goods and manufacturing goods. Intermodal is turning out to be an excellent service for our carload customers.</p>
          <p>Now looking at the outlook, and if you want to follow me, I'll start on page 10 with the intermodal one. But before making comment on intermodal, I just want to make two statements on the two commodities at CN which are on secular decline. One is U.S. domestic thermal coal and the other one is North American paper carloads. Both will continue to decline, iPads are not going away, and we will find more cheap &#x2013; cheap gas will become more readily available in the years to come. However, these end products only represent 1.5% and less than 2% of our book of business, respectively. In other words, they are both already quite small. So looking at Intermodal, Intermodal will do very well for us this fourth quarter and next year on the strength of our unique service definition which more and more players in marketplace are starting to understand what we're offering and what we're producing, as well as on expanding selection of destinations sometime in 2013.</p>
          <p>On the international side, we welcome a new transpacific customers in October, and on the domestic side, we successfully secured a large portion of a large U.S. retailer who is entering the Canadian marketplace sometime next year. We view both event as proof point of our strong service offering and service definition.</p>
          <p>On the bulk side, page 11, the following page, the Canadian grain crop is excellent and the carloads are very strong. On the U.S. crop &#x2013; on the U.S. side, the crop hasn't been as good. However, regardless, we're working hard to turn a negative into a positive and with nimble initiative and we'll see how we finish the quarter with U.S. grain. We haven't given up.</p>
          <p>Coal will remain an export story. In the third quarter, we ran at an annualized rate of 8 million ton of export at Convent and at Ridley, we ran at annualized export of 13 million tons. Export products carload would be a bright spot for CN. The market might be a little weak, but for us it's new business on the export side business that we did not have in the fourth quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>On manufacturing, which is a very broad segment, U.S. housing start will drive our long haul lumber and panels through the U.S., as it did in the third quarter, but BC carload to China will be lower or muted. Crude will be a very bright star in the fourth quarter and has been ramping up for CN like in many other railroads quarter-after-quarter. It is conceivable that we may double our crude revenue in 2013 versus 2012.</p>
          <p>On the steel side, anything which is energy-related will be strong. Anything which is not energy-related will probably will be weak. And we predict our carload for iron ore will be down from last year, same thing as the steel product and the same for non-ferrous metals. And the weak story for steel and non-ferrous may actually impact us in the first part of 2013.</p>
          <p>The number of frac sand plant on our line is expanding, that's a Wisconsin story and we're building quite a powerful originating franchise for sand in Wisconsin.</p>
          <p>Now to round this up, talking about price, on same-store price, we will continue to do our inflation plus pricing program that is in the midrange of 3% to 4%. I'd like to maybe note that we applied the Canadian grain cap increase only on October 1 of this year.</p>
          <p>On fuel surcharge, our October and November tariff are already in place and well-known, and we will have a revenue tailwind that we estimate to be about 1% of revenue in the fourth quarter. On the flipside though, in currency we will have a revenue headwind given the Canadian dollar was US$0.98 fourth quarter of last year and so far this year it seems to be heading about at par. That may be a 1% to 2% drag on revenue.</p>
          <p>So wrapping this up, in conclusion, third quarter was a great quarter. We're very proud of our people. We have more initiatives in the pipeline and we have a team to compete and we have the team to really deal with the current economic environment.</p>
          <p>On that Luc, I'll pass it on to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, J.J. Now, let's turn to page 14 of the presentation and I'll walk you through the key financial highlights of our quarterly performance. Revenues were up 8% at C$2.5 billion as well the volume was up in terms of RTMs 7%. In the quarter, however, we did experience a deceleration in RTM growth versus last year. As July was up 11%; August was up 8%, while September came in only at 3% above last year.</p>
          <p>This was really the result of a couple of factors. The first one being that in September, the growth in RTMs was very strong last year, where we had 9%. Secondly, we witnessed weaker growth in the North American and global economic activity affecting some commodity sectors such as iron ore, non-ferrous ores, steel, met coal as well.</p>
          <p>We also saw some lower demand for potash and below average U.S. grain crop. At this point, we expect this weaker economic context to continue through the fourth quarter. In the third quarter, J.J., Keith and their teams' combined efforts to help us achieve solid volume increases in all commodity sectors and once again several categories performed better than base market conditions.</p>
          <p>Operating income was C$985 million, up 5% versus last year driven by strong revenue growth and lower incremental cost. Our operating ratio was 60.6% in the quarter, an increase of 1.3 percentage points versus last year. Last year's operating ratio was more favorable as a result of the substantially lower stock-based compensation expense in that quarter. Other income was C$18 million in the third quarter this year, which is about C$8 million higher than last year, when we exclude the C$60 million-profit on the sale of the IC Rail Marine Terminal in Convent, Louisiana concluded last year.</p>
          <p>Other income relates mostly to small parcel sales and projects relating to passenger rail service. Accounting wise, this category is always difficult to forecast and my sense is that we got a little bit of help this quarter which last year ended up in the fourth quarter. So, our net income for the third quarter of 2012 was C$664 million, up 1%. The reported diluted EPS was C$1.52, up 4%. Removing the impact of the sale of the IC Rail Marine Terminal in 2011, the adjusted diluted EPS of C$1.52 in 2012 represent a 10% increase over last year's third quarter.</p>
          <p>The impact of exchange was C$8 million favorable on net income and C$0.02 of EPS in the quarter as the average Canadian dollar weakened against the U.S. So on a constant currency, excluding fuel lag and without the help of the additional other income in the quarter, our EPS growth would have been just under 10%. These are very strong results given the pension headwind, we're facing and given the modest economic backdrop.</p>
          <p>Now, let's turn to operating expenses on the next page. As Keith pointed out, we came through with another solid quarter in terms of operational productivity and customer service, yet this performance did not come in the expense of overall cost management.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses came in at C$1.5 billion, up 10% versus last year on a constant currency basis. At this point, I'll refer to the changes in constant currency. Labor and fringe benefit costs were C$476 million, an increase of C$78 million or 20% versus last year. Overall, wage cost were up 5%. This was the product of wage inflation up 3%, overtime was up 1% and we had a 1% increase in head count in the quarter versus last year. So, in the third quarter, our average head count of 23,573 employees was up 1%, while the GTMs were up 8%. So, clearly, some very solid operations and a 7% labor productivity gain. The head count dynamics continue to be driven by advanced hiring ahead of attrition to allow for training along with our assessment of future volume growth.</p>
          <p>Fringe benefit cost accounted for about 4 percentage points of the increase, mostly due to higher pension expense as expected and partially offset by some benefit cost adjustments in the quarter. However, the biggest change, over half of the increase in the labor category was due to a higher stock-based compensation expense resulting in 11 percentage points of the unfavorable variance or C$44 million. As our stock price was up modestly through the quarter versus last year, actually, it was down significantly in the third quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Purchased services and material expenses were C$304 million, up 11%. This was mostly a factor of higher activity levels leading to more repairs and maintenance for cars and locomotives. We had as well a higher expenses for contracted services, both in third party non-rail transportation and for various other project work.</p>
          <p>The fuel expense stood at C$369 million, an increase of 4%. Our volume represented 6 percentage points of the increase, but was partially offset by improved fuel efficiency of roughly 2 percentage points. Meanwhile, prices were essentially flat.</p>
          <p>Now turning to free cash flow for the nine months to-date. As Claude indicated, we generated just over a C$1 billion of free cash in the first nine months of the year. This compares to C$1.328 billion last year. The difference versus last year comes from higher net income of about C$205 million and lower tax payments at C$139 million to-date, which is C$184 million less than last year. This was offset by higher working capital mostly resulting from the pension contribution of C$450 million made in the first quarter of this year, while last year, this contribution was made in the fourth quarter. Also our capital expenditures were higher this year by about a C$100 million for the nine months to-date.</p>
          <p>While I'm on the subject on income taxes, I should mention that our 2012 full year cash taxes will settle around C$300 million. But our income tax installments will more than triple next year. As we expect, lower advanced voluntary pension contribution, and so our cash taxes in 2013 will be within one point or so of our effective tax rate, which we estimate will be around 29%.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet remains strong with debt ratios and leverage within our internal guidelines. In the third quarter, we completed our 2011, 2012 share buyback program with 16.7 million shares bought at the average price of C$81 for a total consideration of C$1.350 billion. Finally, let me turn to page 17 and speak to our financial outlook.</p>
          <p>First, I'm pleased to report that the CN board of directors has approved a new stock buyback program consistent with our strong shareholder returns agenda. This new program provides for up to C$1.4 billion to be deployed over the next 12 months for the purpose of buying back our common stocks through a customary normal-course-issuer bid.</p>
          <p>As it relates to 2012's outlook, we see a challenging end to the year, but we are reaffirming our 2012 annual guidance, which has us aiming to deliver up to 15% growth in adjusted diluted EPS over 2011. We also reaffirm our targets of generating approximately C$1 billion in free cash flow and that is after taking into consideration a potential additional voluntary pension contribution of C$250 million to be made between now and the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Given the weak economic context, however, we certainly have our work cut out. And the expectation of reaching the upper hand of our guidance is not a foregone conclusion. You'll recall as well that we'll be lapping in the fourth quarter revenue growth of 12% in 2011, which was an all-time record. And we also had adjusted EPS growth of 20%.</p>
          <p>More specifically for the fourth quarter, you should keep in mind that the timing of other income of the other income category as such that we got last year's fourth quarter upside, which was about C$15 million already in the third quarter this year. Also the favorable income tax adjustments we had in the fourth quarter of last year of about C$0.05 of EPS will turn into headwind as we expect the fourth quarter of this year to be above our year-to-date effective tax rate.</p>
          <p>Now, with respect to 2013, it's still too early to provide a financial outlook. This is especially true given that we maintain a cautious view with regards to the real strength underpinning economic growth prospects. What we do know, however, is that we will unfortunately face a few pension or a few headwinds namely pension and other accounting headwinds. If these combine we'll probably have an effect that could be in the range of about 1.5 point of operating ratio. We expect nevertheless to provide you with annual guidance for 2013 at our fourth quarter earnings call.</p>
          <p>In closing, let me say that we're very pleased with our third quarter results and that 2012 is lining up to be another year of strong performance for CN. We maintain our focus on operational and service excellence to effectively deliver superior returns, no matter what economic conditions we have.</p>
          <p>On this note, back to you Claude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thank you, Guy and just let me wrap it up. This theme of CN Rail holders is obviously very proud of its strong third quarter results. We hit a number of performance record as you heard, but more importantly we are seeing our agenda gaining momentum. We are growing faster in the economy or base markets. We are accommodating that business at low incremental costs and we're generating solid earnings and free cash flow. And that's what it takes to continue to deliver solid shareholder value for 2012 for many years to come after that.</p>
          <p>Before I turn it over to Q&amp;A I have one important announcement to make with some trepidations. After more than 15 years, Bob Noorigian has decided that he's made enough money, and I'm guessing that Shirley wants him on the golf course and his mansion in Florida, so he came to me a few months ago and told me that he would retire at year-end. And so, I asked Bob to give me an indication of who he thought should succeed him and it was not a very long discussion. We decided we would go with Janet Drysdale, which many of you know, Janet was with Bob for almost four years a few years ago and has been continuing to drive value with Luc as of recently in financial planning.</p>
          <p>So, Bob, this is you last third quarter &#x2013; this is your last analyst call and it's very fitting that we're hitting all sorts of record performance. I know you'll be doing a roadshow with Janet over the next couple of months here. She starts only on December 1, so you keep holding the fort for a couple of weeks here. But we will miss you. And I know I speak on behalf of many shareholders and analysts in wishing you the most fulfilling retirement in a couple of months from now, not just yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>It's always good when it's a couple of months. Thank you, Claude. And with that, we'll open it up for any questions we have from the audience. Thank you. It's a great management team, great company and I think there's plenty of growth that we're going to see in the future. Thank you, Claude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question is from Chris Wetherbee of Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. Good afternoon and congratulations, Bob. Looking forward to seeing you in the golf course down in Naples.</p>
          <p>Maybe if I could just ask a quick question kind of on the guidance and the outlook as you think about 2013, I know there's some caution about the strength of the economy. You mentioned a couple of headwinds that you see whether it be from on the expense side. But just want to get a sense about the kind of the revenue opportunity that you see specifically at CN? Obviously, the crude is one that you've highlighted on the release but just maybe give us a sense there., outside of the economy, kind of the things that are working in your favor. It seems like there are a decent amount of opportunities set up for you. So how should we be thinking about that kind of roughly as we look at 2013 preliminarily?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>J.J.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The market that will give us leg next year &#x2013; definitely crude will give us leg. Grain is a good crop on the Canadian side that will carry us till the next &#x2013; following next spring. Housing start is good news. We've been driving the positive U.S. housing starts for a while. The whole thing around energy, so not just crude but also frac sand and intermodal, whether the economy is a little weak or the economy is a little strong, our intermodal performance last two years is we overperformed the economy. So, intermodal, both domestic and overseas, should be plus.</p>
          <p>And again, steel non-ferrous, it's &#x2013; although I can't tell exactly when this will turnaround, these are very cyclical commodities. They will turn around but they may take their time before they turn around. I was in Japan talking to some steel maker a few weeks back and they're not necessarily very optimistic right now. They've kind of written off the fourth quarter and maybe the beginning of 2013.</p>
          <p>But how does that all add up? I think we haven't yet decided what kind of guidance we'll really provide to the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:05) of volume. Again, our objective is to overperform the economy, Canadian economy, U.S. economy and our participation in Asia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as J.J. said, I think we like the portfolio of growth opportunities that we have. Some of them are structural like frac sand and metallurgical coal on the West Coast. Others are really driven by our strategy to improve service and make in-roads in the most service sensitive segments in the market and our flexibility, key supply chain focus is helping us also gain market share against trucks. So, I guess, the best way to think about it, Chris is we don't know where the economy will be and we'll update you in January but we are looking to make our own lunch and grow faster than base markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful. That's what I looked for. I'll keep it at one. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have a question from Turan Quettawala of Scotia Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon and congratulations Bob from our end as well. Just a quick question. I was wondering about your potash business over the next two to three quarters, I understand obviously that you will benefit from the Canpotex contract here. But just, it does seem to be weakening a little bit even domestically and I'm wondering J.J., can you provide a little bit of color there on the domestic potash market? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you. Of course, Turan, we &#x2013; on the export side, whether it's a fourth quarter of this year or first quarter of next year, this is all plus for CN. The potash market in the world may not be as strong as the producer would wish, but it is strong for CN because our base was zero. We had zero export last year, zero products export first quarter. We did benefit during the second &#x2013; the strike at CP in the second quarter so that will be the comparable.</p>
          <p>On the domestic side, we did have gain on the potash side in the third quarter and again, here we could just be as good as our customers or our customers need not be as good as we can be to help them for them.</p>
          <p>So we still basically assume here that the fourth quarter potash domestically for the two big companies that we work with that we will be up year-over-year and the next winter, then we'll see next winter what would happen. I mean, the price of grain is high. There's reason to fertilize because there's a good product out there and time will tell. I think the potash industry is also hopeful. They got lot of investment and a lot of capacity coming on stream.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And as a quick follow-up, is there any change to the Ridley, I guess? It was supposed to be some announce &#x2013; some decision, I guess, by the end of the year on the terminal there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Turan, you're referring to the Canpotex potash terminal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right. So as far as we know, it's definitely a major item on their board meeting in December and in December they will look at that very closely again and might make a decision, positive or negative, I don't know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Turan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Cherilyn Radbourne of TD Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Good afternoon. And let me start by just wishing Bob the very best. Keith presented some very impressive service improvements and yet as we all know, we're facing some service legislation here in Canada that seems to be taking a little bit longer than expected to emerge. So I wonder if you could just tell us what you're hearing in terms of when it may appear and what you think the risk is if we get something that's non-commercial, if I can express it that way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you for that question, Cherilyn. And frankly, Keith was getting miffed here about the reputation for our service being tarnished here in some circle. So, he felt pretty strongly about giving you the real stats so that we can have a good discussion and I think it's important for our shareholders, it's also important to some of the customers and stakeholders and media that might be listening on this call. I mean, the reality is the following. The Rail Service Review was called basically six or seven years ago. That's when the people were asking for Rail Service Review and I said it in many circle, the CN and its agenda to drive change and improve its performance in a way that at times was a bit too fast is a big reason why there was a Rail Service Review in the first place.</p>
          <p>But we are talking about six or seven years ago. And since then, we have clearly stepped up. There's no question at CN and I know it's the same at CP. We are focused on having more customer engagement, we're listening better and we're trying to put ourselves in the shoes of our customers. We have an agenda that's customer-centric. We have made a dramatic change to our first mile, last mile and focus in terms of measurement. We've always been very good hub-to-hub, but now we are focusing as you heard Keith on things like order fulfillment and 96% order fulfillment after car rejection is nothing short of a world-class performance, and the same goals with some of the other metrics.</p>
          <p>But it's more than just these things. It's also supply chain collaboration and new mindset that we're bringing to the table. So from my perspective &#x2013; and I wrote to our customers to discuss this same issue asking them to step back about what's important and where we should go from here. The railroads heard the message. We're stepping up to the plate and I think it's fair to have advocacy, we don't need to agree on everything. But it would be important for the &#x2013; if we want good public policy for the advocacy to be fact-based. Let me be frank, and I won't single out anybody but we had an industry association, the Mining Association, for instance, which is using grain statistics of all commodities to try to make the case that we're failing our customers 50% of the time.</p>
          <p>Well, let me tell you, we're not. We are actually doing a great job for our mining customers, and I know one thing, our shareholders wouldn't know if we were not moving coal for Teck 50% of the time. I think you'd hear about that in the marketplace. The same is true of any other of our customers whether it's Walter Energy or others.</p>
          <p>You have other associations that are out there saying that the &#x2013; in actual fact, they agree that the service has improved. But what we need is a backstop. We need a backstop because somehow the railroad that market power.</p>
          <p>Well, the reality is we compete every day. We compete against other railroads. We compete against trucks and we also compete against the opportunity to have their business for our own benefit. So we want their business. We want to grow and we don't take any of our customers for granted. We want to get better and we want to help them win in the marketplace. So I think it's important and I think the government has to make a very wiseful policy decision here. I think it's important to step back. The reality is there is good service. Can it improve? Absolutely. But we have good service. It's world-class. We have a commercial system that has driven this outcome. We are focused on getting better. And if we want this momentum to continue and the drive for more supply chain collaboration to thrive, I think it's very, very important that the government stays with a commercial agenda.</p>
          <p>Now, I may not succeed and in the end, maybe the government does decide to legislate and if they do, it's probably going to be in the next month or so, Cherilyn. But all I say here is, let's sit back. We have a good thing going. And if the government is going to legislate, then at least they should do so in a balanced way.</p>
          <p>We're asking for only a number of key elements to prevail if there will be regulation. We want mediation before arbitration. That's a fair request. If we don't want arbitration, if we want only a backstop, we should give it a chance by first starting with mediation. Because service legislation goes at the heart of our ability to serve all customers, not just the one that complain, we want the agency, the Canadian Transport Agency itself to be the arbitrator of last result (sic) [resort], not some roster of arbitrators that have very little knowledge of how railroad operate and that's the argument that some of the associations are saying.</p>
          <p>If it's about dealing with the few instances where customers are abusing their market power, if that's the case, then surely these new service regulations and these new arbitration mechanisms should apply only to customers who actually are dependent on one railway or can some show some commercial harm.</p>
          <p>So we don't think regulation is the right way to go, but if we do have regulation, we hope the government will not fall for the advocacy and the anecdotes, that they will follow the advice that I'm providing. And if they do so, we will be able to live with their decision and I hope they make those decisions rather sooner as opposed to later because we have a business to run and there is a good thing going out there at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for that very wholesome answer. That's all for me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have a question from Scott Group of Wolfe Trahan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks. Good afternoon, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So J.J., I had a question for you about housing. So relative to last cycle, the Canadian dollar's a lot stronger. Do you think there is as much demand this time around for Canadian lumber?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Last time the Canadian dollars was the weaker so they were about at par. But the price of lumber is actually pretty good. That's one of the things where you see some diversion of lumber going to Asia to United States if the netback is attractive. So, higher price &#x2013; it's a question of higher price and freight. The freight is at about the same ballpark, plus inflation plus. The price of lumber start to go up before the housing starts have to kick in.</p>
          <p>So now I think for producer in B.C. and Alberta, U.S. housing start is attractive. The producer in Eastern Canada, that is Quebec and New Brunswick, now they may be &#x2013; now this cycle may not be as strong for them, but the CN business when it comes to panel and lumber very much rely on Western Canada.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful. So when we think about your capacity, how much of your center beam or other capacity to handle a rebound in housing, do you still have relative to last cycle? And then should we be thinking that you've been maintaining those cars and there's a lot of leverage to those volumes coming back or do you have to spend some money maintaining and upgrading those cars relative to five or six years ago when you were using them last?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've still got about 2,000 in storage, certainly and the ones that have been in deep storage, we had to take a look at them to make sure that they're in proper order, but we don't expect there'd be any major significant expense there.</p>
          <p>We continue to invest in our physical plant for strategic investments, long siding, improving by expanding the capacity in Prince George which is a major facility that would handle these cars as well as in Winnipeg. So certainly, there's enough latent capacity that we've invested in over the past four or five years that I would not see any issue for a housing start rebound.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, we have leverage and we kept those car for that very reason, for a rebound of the housing starts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you and thanks. Best of luck to you, Bob. Congratulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from William Greene of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, there. Good afternoon. Bob, congrats, best of luck, and Janet, welcome back. Hey, I wanted to ask a question a little bit off beaten path here, but something that's come up a little bit is just the notion of density in Eastern Canada and we've long sort of heard that that's kind of a challenge to margins. Is that true? Is that something that we could see a creative solution that could happen to address margins in Eastern Canada or is that sort of just off the table, not that we should have in mind?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me ask Keith to respond to that. But we have pretty good returns across our entire network and while it is lower density in the east, all the business that we handle is handled through the margins. Keith, do you want to comment on the challenge to keep our costs down in the east given the lower density?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Effectively, it's summarized by doing more with the less. The Eastern region, if you look at all three of our regions, as well as they all do in this downturn over the past couple of years, the east has continued to raise the bar. They've done it through our very strategic initiatives to run long, long trains over the <mark type="ph" /> NLD (46:08). We made some very pinpointing investments to be able to meet long train through strategic locations to allow us to absorb the growth that we have had, although it's been marginal by cutting train starts so to speak. So we controlled our labor costs. We've increased car velocity, train velocity, terminal expense across the board. Jeff and his team are doing a phenomenal job controlling our costs to maintaining better &#x2013; actually improving our margin when it comes to the operating side of things and given level of business we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And a little crude to the east wouldn't hurt, Bill, so we're focused on all levers to make sure our business returns everywhere.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. One more point I can tell you this, these guys are getting so creative and gals in the east. We were just meeting last week in Chicago talking about our pipeline of initiatives next year. We're taking some of that latent capacity and actually doing switching downstream to take additional costs out and increase asset turns more specifically in our automotive fleet which has given us direct savings, have been able to turn more loads, then frees up capacity for the industry, the automotive growth then reduces our car hour costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Tom Wadewitz of JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Yeah. First, congratulations, Bob, you've really been a true professional over the years and it's really been a pleasure working with you, so best wishes to you in retirement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's see, I think this is for Claude, when you look at maybe near-term, I don't know if you want to call it cyclical weakness in some of the commodities, export coal comes to mind. I think that you've talked about significant growth opportunity longer term in B.C. and Northern B.C. Do you see customers in their investment plans responding to some of this near-term weakness? And do you think some of the growth you would expect is at risk? Or is it just kind of a near-term blip and you would still feel quite good about the Northern B.C. opportunity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know what, I feel quite good about the Northern B.C. opportunity. I mean markets are impacting everybody but the export coal that we have out of British Columbia and Alberta is high quality metallurgical coal. It has nothing with the thermal export coal that you see elsewhere across North America.</p>
          <p>So I do think that at the margin, the mines in British Columbia are very competitive even with Australia at the margin and we have a good sailing distance, very efficient port capacity, and our end-to-end supply chain is helping us or is allowing us to help our customers maintain their position in the marketplace. So there might be a little bit of a soft patch here that might delay things a little bit, but I think the metallurgical coal franchise and the opportunity to grow it over the next several years remains intact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you think that you would say that those investment plans are still on track with what you would have seen before?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That's correct, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Tom. And you're right, Bob is the best. We will all miss him dearly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Benoit Poirier of Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much. Best wishes, Bob, for your retirement and welcome back, Janet. Would it be possible to give an update on the level of activity at the Port of Halifax, especially in light of the strike issues at the U.S. ports and the low water levels in Montreal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I could do that. You're right. Benoit, it's J.J. The water level in the St. Lawrence Seaway end of the summer here were low, so the container ship coming to Montreal the last two months or so, if you wish, were light-loaded. So there was less container per ship and some of those &#x2013; some of that business ended up being handled by Halifax, either as export back, as Canadian export out of Montreal tend be heavier. So, the issue is a little more on the return than the import side.</p>
          <p>So, Montreal has been sort of a steady, flat negative partly because of that, and Halifax has seen some benefit. But the way we're selling Halifax, and Keith talked earlier about the density of the network in the east, we're very focused on Halifax, very focused on Montreal. Especially Halifax, it has deep water, has two great terminals. Both of them have &#x2013; especially one of them have great <mark type="ph" /> train (50:52) that could help deal with large vessel and there's a big push right now from CN, the two port authorities and the terminals in both Montreal and Halifax to sell our services in India, in Vietnam and other countries and over time, this will pay off. And not just to serve Canadian cities, but also to serve U.S. Midwest cities it's East Coast with East Coast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for the time, J.J.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Benoit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Chris Ceraso of Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good evening and thanks for everything, Bob. So a question about productivity. Can you give us a rough idea ballpark maybe in terms of percentage points on the operating ratio, how much productivity you strive to achieve each year and what your success rate has been? Has it been 100, 200 basis points productivity? I'm just thinking about that in light of the 150 basis points that you outlined as a headwind for fiscal 2013 from pension and other employee-related costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly, I'll comment and maybe Keith can pick it up from there as well. If you look at this year, I think the team's done an outstanding job because we have effectively been able to offset a good chunk of the pension headwind that we were facing. So, it's not something that is easy to achieve every year. Obviously, next year will be more challenging because we keep looking for opportunities. But, I would say that we strive to try to offset at least half, if we can and more of these types of headwinds, so that's kind of just to give you a sense of direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as far as the challenge of doing it, I mean, day-in and day-out, you reinvent yourselves and as you fix one issue across the board, you're going to identify other opportunities as the pinch point sort of moves. So like I said last week, we spent two days going through this and I walked away feeling even more energized and encouraged by the innovativeness and the ownership that this team is taking refilling that pipeline of opportunities. So certainly, it's no easy task. It's hard work, you got to roll your sleeves up and get at it and operate in a disciplined way and execute, but it's certainly doable. We'll continue to redo it and reinvent ourselves year-after-year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Walter Spracklin of RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. And again as everyone is saying, Bob, congrats on the retirement. I look forward to dealing with you Janet, I'm sure you're on the line. So, my question here is for Claude, I guess. Canadian Pacific has talked a lot about what they &#x2013; been aggressive in terms of what they're going to do, what changes they're going to make, we're going to hear a lot more about it in December. But clearly, you being the main competitor and not one to, I guess, sit back and be reactive on this, I'm sure you're looking at the potential impacts to CN from some of these changes.</p>
          <p>My question is have you seen any changes so far in terms of any changes from your competitor? And when you think about what might happen in the next 12 months, one year, two year, three years out, do you see this as a positive for CN, if they get a little bit more &#x2013; moving a little bit more on pricing or so on or do you see it as neutral or negative? And can you talk to me a bit about again what changes you've seen to-date and what you might see in the future as it impacts CN?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think as I've said before, Walter, I think it's constructive for the rail industry in Canada. You got a pretty competitive bunch here and we're not going to make it easy to catch up. So, if CP gets better, we're going to have to get even better, better faster. And that's exactly what we're doing. We're focusing on our agenda. It's working. And we are I believe making huge strides in regaining our customers hearts in terms of what we do for them. If you forget some of the advocacy in Ottawa, it's paying in additional growth and we are accommodating that business at low incremental costs. So, our agenda of operational excellence and service excellence is carrying to-date and we hope that CP gets better; we hope they are able to price that into the market in a disciplined way with the value of the services they create. And if we all do this, the industry will be better. Canada will be better for it and it's a good story.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And any changes to-date so far that you've noticed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They're working hard to get better and we're seeing evidence that it's working.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Well, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Matt Troy of Susquehanna Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Just a quick question. In terms of just competitive access or potential access to your management &#x2013; middle management ranks, it's a question that often comes up with investors that now that your former CEO is settled at your competitor and the work begins in earnest going forward. Is there a risk? I know one man is not the entire CN management team. But can you just walk us through why you're not concerned or the layers of defense or strategy you've got about retaining the management team? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know what, the best way you retain a team is to have a good agenda that's working and to have fun and to have the right chemistry as a team. And I think we have all of those conditions lined up. There's no question for having a lot of fun driving our agenda and we're getting good feedback from our customers and from our shareholders. I think Hunter has a good strategy undergoing. He and I go way back. I'm not certain at all he will want to come after CN employees. I think he's a man of his word, and I would expect him to focus on driving change at CP without having to poach CN. And if he does poach CN, we have a lot of retention tools and a lot of bench strength.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you. And just to close out, Bob, thanks for the help over the years. Best of luck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Matt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Jason Seidl of Dahlman Rose. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. I guess I'll echo everyone's comments and well wishes to Bob. Bob you've been too professional over the years and the only thing that matched that was your wit; definitely, we're going to miss you at our conferences. You guys mentioned I think on the intermodal side that there's going to be a large retailer coming on. Could you to talk just a little bit about sort of the level that you might see from that and is that going to impact the length of haul?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Without getting into &#x2013; I mean the retailer will start next year, sometime in the first quarter and then we wish them best of luck in their investment opening of their franchise on the Canadian side. And they will tend to be a combination of long haul coming from both coast, mostly the West Coast as well as some product coming from the United States. So I mean it is because of the number of store they're talking about opening, it should be a nice sizeable account on the domestic side. And domestic account that sell a combination of product produced here within North America and product coming from offshore typically Asia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If I can get a clarification question here, J.J. I think you mentioned that there's going to be a revenue tailwind in 4Q due to flow of about 1 percentage points but you said currency could hold you down between 1% and 2%. Did I hear that correctly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right. Last year, the Canadian dollars in the fourth quarter, if I recall well, was about US$0.98. About that, Luc?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And then some &#x2013; it's running on average. I mean it's certainly in the quarter, but it's been running about US$1.01, US$1.02, so it could be of a penny to two pennies, as J.J. pointed out, 1% or 2%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot guys. I appreciate the time as always.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Ken Hoexter of BoA. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys. This is actually Veronica Mangione in for Ken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you having a problem with your phone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I'm having a...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sorry about that. So regarding your recently won intermodal contract from a competitor, can you kind of talk about your underlying process as in was it service price, them not wanting to live through the management turnover and service renewal? Or was it just your work during the strike? And on that point, are there more cases you see following those paths be it in intermodal or other?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would only focus on the one at hand, the one that came to us basically this month. It's very rare that you see a major shipping line that switch from one railroad to another, so you don't see that too often. So, we're extremely pleased that they've decided to come and join us after a decade-plus not working with CN, but working on other railroad. And when you look at those companies, typically not all of them, but most of them, they really &#x2013; they have to go and sell a service in the marketplace. They need a service that fits their own service, as they sell not only in Canada but also in other continent. That name tend to be a service-minded name. Their &#x2013; they need service wintertime, summertime, labor disruption or not, and they really like the supply chain service that we have.</p>
          <p>That is that what most shipping line need and what most shipping line are selling is a good consistent transit time from the time the container gets discharged at the dock to the time it's available to major cities. We all have very fast train service. But, fast train service doesn't mean fast container velocity. The container velocity is from ship discharge to available at the port. And this is where at what Keith was talking about, the whole supply chain mindset, the level of service agreement that we have with the Port of Vancouver, the level of service agreement we have with ESI and other in Deltaport &#x2013; DP World in Vancouver.</p>
          <p>These are really element that matters a whole lot to our shipping line, and I think in the end, that was a compelling offering to them because they think it will help them sell their product, their services in the Canadian marketplace. So that's, I mean, by and large, that was the reason why they may have made the choices that they did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And also just a general follow-up for Keith. I mean, you guys are at 60% operating leisure, this is very broad. But are there any other costs you want to see at this level that you target to reduce and in particular where?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a pretty broad question...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good follow-up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'd say more specifically, there's always operating costs and opportunities. Again, I'd like to get out on the property and just do a couple of visits this summer. It doesn't take long to go to any other major terminals or road operations and different set of eyes and years, you get a couple of guys and gals together that understand operations and blitz the terminal and take a look for opportunities and you see opportunities that you want to reduce cost, time-in, time-out. So certainly, I'm not too concerned about being able to go out and find those opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we need them because we've already signed them up to deal with &#x2013; or close to half of our headwind into next year. So, we'll need some of Keith's magic...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well thanks, Claude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>to deal with the pension and other accounting headwinds. All right, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from David Newman of Cormark Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, congrats Bob and thanks for all your help over the years. Hopefully, you can now throw away your shovels and boots.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Bob, I'll do that. Thank you for the best wishes and you're going to be the last question today. So, we appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. So, my question is, certainly I think the buyback should help in 2013, and you guys have really stepped it up and certainly using your balance sheet. I mean, you had a previous question on density, et cetera. And, I think Claude, you had mentioned on an earlier &#x2013; I think in an earlier conference that you haven't engaged in M&amp;A for a little while and I think Ontario Northland is one that you mentioned. Is there something that you guys might step back into sort of the M&amp;A front once again and reacquire some short lines like I think there has been more interest in that side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know what? There's not many opportunities like that out there. The ONR is the one that appears to be moving towards a potential sale by the Ontario government, but we are always looking for ways to expand our network if we can find one, whether it's short lines or regional lines like the ONR. But while we are ready to act on them as they become available as opportunity, there're not many out there and let's put it this way. It's not plan A and it's certainly not part of what we have in our tool kit to continue to deliver good results between now and year end and into 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Thanks, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Well, thank you, David, you just got under the wire. And if I'm listening to all of you wishing &#x2013; having good wishes for Bob and missing him a little bit, I get a feeling here that you're going to be looking for help to build your model and answer your questions. But fortunately, we have Janet with Paul Butcher that will be ready to standby as of December 1 to help with the transition as Bob moves on to a very, very well-deserved retirement.</p>
          <p>I want say, Bob, you've heard it about 20 times on this call; on a personal note, you've been a trusted advisor of me for basically all my career at CN and throughout I always look forward to get your wise counsel and never worry too much about making sure that our message was well delivered to shareholders. So, for all of that, I thank you and I just only &#x2013; I can only hope that we're going to have a fourth quarter that is another solid quarter with record performance so that we keep the tradition going while you are on the golf course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Claude. I really appreciate it. Like I said, I think it's a great management team, it's a great company, it's been a good run. And because many of you already know Janet, we're going to be visiting a lot of our investors and some of the sell side in the next few weeks here. I appreciate it. No pressure, Janet. It's just when I came to work here the stock on an adjusted basis was $4.50. So, I expect the same from you.</p>
          <p>Bonne chance, Janet. Thank you, Claude. And come see me in Naples sometimes, gentlemen and ladies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and we're looking forward to a strong finish of the year and seeing you all or talking to you all at the year-end in January.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The conference call has now ended. Please disconnect your lines at this time. We thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>