<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1342292" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-10-26</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1382</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Robert Noorigian, Vice President &#x2013; Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Claude Mongeau, President &amp; Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Keith E. Creel, Chief Operating Officer &amp; Executive Vice President</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Jean-Jacques Ruest, Executive Vice President and Chief Marketing Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Luc Jobin, Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Scott Group</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">William Greene</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Jason Seidl</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Cherilyn Radbourne</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">David Newman</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Chris Ceraso</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Walter Spracklin</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Kenneth Hoexter</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Gary Chase</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Benoit Poirier</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Fadi Chamoun</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Jeffrey Kauffman</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the CN Third Quarter 2010 Financial Results Conference Call. I would now like to turn the meeting over to Mr. Robert Noorigian, Vice President, Investor Relations. Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. Noorigian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for joining us for CN's Q3 2010 financial results. I'd like to remind you again about the comments that have already been made regarding forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>With us today are Claude Mongeau, our President and Chief Executive Officer; Luc Jobin, our Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer. This is Keith Creel, Executive Vice President and Chief Operating Officer; and J.J. Ruest, Executive Vice President and Chief Marketing Officer.</p>
          <p>After the presentation, we'll take questions from those of you who are listening on the call. Could you please identify yourself when you're asking the questions, and in order to be fair to everybody that's there, could you please limit yourself to one question with one follow-up.</p>
          <p>It is now my pleasure to introduce Mr. Claude Mongeau, our President and Chief Executive Officer. Claude?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bob. And thank you to all of you for joining us on this call. We're very, very pleased to announce our third quarter results. They are good results.</p>
          <p>We are pleased that we were able to drive significant volume growth and significant top line growth. If I measure it on a constant currency basis, our revenues are up 18%. J.J. will give you the contour of that growth later, but pretty much across the whole book of business we've been making inroads and taking advantage of the economic recovery. But we're also making inroads in terms of our ability to serve our customers and grow faster than what the economy would give us by getting more of their discretionary business, so that solid growth has been accommodated at low incremental cost.</p>
          <p>Keith and his team are doing a wonderful job to handle the business, creating flexibility to improve service, but also maintaining our high level of efficiency and continuing to make progress in terms of productivity, and this is what helped us drive a very good operating ratio. Our third quarter operating ratio was 60.7, which is a 2 point improvement over last year.</p>
          <p>In terms of earnings, solid earnings up 27% on an adjusted basis. Luc will give you some of the details of how we were able to drive this performance, but this is the third quarter in a row where we're able to show leverage and show a solid performance on an earnings standpoint and free cash flow standpoint.</p>
          <p>Year-to-date, we are at $938 million of free cash flow, and that's despite the fact that we have made a contribution, voluntary contribution to our pension plan, which Luc will explain to you in a minute, so clearly from a financial standpoint, very solid results. And I'd like to say just a few words to give you an update on what we're trying to move forward in terms of our strategic agenda, but a particular emphasis on service excellence.</p>
          <p>There was a lot of milestone achieved during the quarter in terms of supply chain collaboration. You may have followed us. We have been able to finalize basically a cross-Canada tour. All of the major Canadian ports now have a supply chain agreement, and I'm also pleased to report that we have service level agreements with all of the key container terminal operators in all of those major ports across Canada.</p>
          <p>We're leveraging the value that comes with those service level agreements in terms of visibility and end-to-end focus one box at the time. We're fixing issues and addressing bottlenecks on an ongoing basis, really daily with the benefit of these score cards that we've put together with our partners.</p>
          <p>And it's really helping us improve our performance in terms of the overseas business. You've seen the result of that over the last several months, but again, the third quarter and J.J. will give you the details, we have very good growth in terms of our overseas business.</p>
          <p>Our end-to-end approach is also showing significant benefit in the bulk side. We've had good performance in terms of our new scheduled grain performance, but also very, very good performance in moving Canadian coal to the west coast in record levels. So we call it our mine-to-ship supply chain approach, and it's clearly paying dividends.</p>
          <p>In the merchandise side, similar story. A couple milestones; we've introduced our new car order process, which gives the flexibility to our customers.</p>
          <p>We're using that flexibility to gain opportunities one car load at a time, whether it's in steel or forest products. We are able to respond quickly, and have higher fulfillment rates, which is helping service to our customers, but importantly is helping CN capture more business, and given that every carload counts, it is helping us having the top line grow a little faster than what the general economy would have given us.</p>
          <p>So all of these service initiatives are core to our strategic agenda. We have said we would be working on those when we met with you at our Analyst Meeting in May or early June, and we are delivering on them one step at a time, and it's a positive story overall.</p>
          <p>With that, I will turn it over, and Keith will give us a rundown on our operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, Claude. Let me start by recognizing and thanking the best operating team in the industry that I'm honored to lead, again, for delivering a strong operating performance this quarter.</p>
          <p>Since Claude laid out our CN 2010 vision three quarters ago, this team continues to leverage our operating model, focusing on delivering meaningful results which we're basing on service innovation, employee engagement, growth absorption and the constant pursuit of safety excellence.</p>
          <p>The financials you're looking at provide a strong case this approach continues to deliver, so let me take a couple of minutes to share a few of the details that we've been up to.</p>
          <p>Speaking to the productivity metrics front that we report on each quarter, we've again achieved gains in virtually every aspect of our operation. To put it in perspective, since the year end 2008, during '09 and '10, we've driven a 20% improvement at CN from a 25 mile an hour railroad to consistently knocking on the doors of a 30 mile an hour railroad.</p>
          <p>We've driven over a 15% improvement in car velocity from 185 miles to 214 miles per day on every car we handle. And the most critical validation point that I want to leave with each of you is to our operating performance this year. Year-to-date we've done all this while maintaining or improving our metrics, absorbing a growth rate of 12% over 2009 volumes, moved on our eco-friendly trains that are safer, longer and heavier.</p>
          <p>This team produces it relentlessly, blocking and tackling day in and day out executing our operating model, and I'm happy to share with J.J. and with the audience that in 2010 we've evolved that same tenacity and focus on improving our customer service and earning additional market share one carload at a time.</p>
          <p>To ensure the success story continues, we have to continue to innovate at CN. We do it by making a small, targeted investment to support our growth in service performance, like the 132 locomotives DP equipped, high horsepower, fuel efficient with the latest technology in 2010.</p>
          <p>We've retrofitted others. We currently have 35% of our locomotives equipped to DP, and we're pushing to 50% by the end of 2011. So you combine that, looking at our marketing forecast six to 12 months out with our attrition, and we'll be in solid shape to handle the business.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned, let me make a couple of points on the DP side. These locomotives continue to allow us to run safer, longer trains, especially as we look forward to the cold winter months that lie ahead in the years ahead.</p>
          <p>They also allow us to further leverage our investments in long sidings, running longer and heavier trains that currently were not possible without these concepts.</p>
          <p>From the car side, we purchased just under 2,000 new rail cars this year to support growth in the iron ore, steel, coal and forest products markets. And in certain cases where we've had periods of excess fleet, we're strategically storing cars to provide recoverability and to improve our ability to respond to spot opportunities like those we converted in the volatile steel market during 2010.</p>
          <p>Another key resource we're carefully managing is our train crew base. We have roughly 6,000 T&amp;E employees at CN over the next five years. Just under half of those will retire. Keep in mind that it takes us six months to recruit and train a new conductor, so it's critical that we get this right.</p>
          <p>We're relying on the volume forecast, and we do so by the resource tool that we deployed earlier this year, Precision Planning Process. We effectively take the forecast, we combine it with attrition on the marketing side, and it puts us where we need to be from a resource standpoint.</p>
          <p>These steps, combined with our tentative labor agreement, will ensure that we're prepared to protect the service. And by the way, I'll comment that I'm excited about that tentative agreement we recently reached with the conductors in Canada.</p>
          <p>It's largely a status quo agreement in nature, but it does provide a mechanism for us to work together on scheduling issues, which we hope ultimately will be good for CN and for our running trades employees on a go-forward basis.</p>
          <p>On the customer front, our daily operating metrics are being rounded out with a suite of customer centric metrics designed to assess performance from our customer's perspective. These measures include switching performance, car supply, traffic left behind, our car return times at our intermodal terminals and aging of our containers at port.</p>
          <p>And finally, as an excellent example of pursuing a more collaborative approach with our employees in partnership with our dispatch offices that are the employees that run our dispatch centers, we're implementing a dispatching excellent initiative. Their mandate is simple: It's to identify ways to drive up train speed, service, performance, doing it through process improvement, collaboration and some targeted investment.</p>
          <p>I trust that gives you a good flavor of some of the key areas of innovation at CN that we're pursuing that will allow us to continue our operating story, and success story that we produced. And with that, I'll turn it over to J.J. to review the top line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, Keith. That's operation excellence. I'd like now for you to join me in looking over overall revenue results on Slide 10, looking first at the year-over-year results Q3 2010 versus Q3 2009.</p>
          <p>The quality results of this year are more than just an economic recovery story. It is time to see the dividend of our new supply chain initiative, which are designed to help our customers grow their business and position CN to handle a greater amount of their traffic.</p>
          <p>Revenue growth for the third quarter was 18% on an FX adjusted basis. To peel that off into each element, 9% of that was rail revenue, RTM, we're up 9%, carload we're up 18%; 3% came from same-store price from our same-store sales. Another 2% came from fuel surcharge and the remaining 4% came from non-rail business and some positive mix.</p>
          <p>On a sequential basis, third quarter versus second quarter of this year, the volume declined by 1% in terms of RTM, but increased 2% in terms of car load.</p>
          <p>Now if you want to join me on the next page, looking at the business by business, again, emphasizing the revenue on an FX adjusted basis. Petroleum and chemical up 14%. The Canadian recovery and chemical production was initially behind that of the U.S., but seems to have caught up.</p>
          <p>Metals and minerals was up a strong 29%, a reflection of our ability to work with our customers. We had strong iron ore volume, and we have truck market share gain in the steel industries. Automotive was also strong at 26% growth, FX adjusted, strong production from the CN served plant, as well as new supply chain focus, for example, ground and inventory dwell time where we track dwell time performance from both the ship discharge, in the case in Halifax, and from the assembly plant release in the plants in Ontario and Michigan. And that to compete against truck light service makes sure business does not leak.</p>
          <p>Forest product was up 8%. There was no real movement in U.S. housing starts, and we do not expect that dial to move very much. However, we have a strong partnership with our forest product customers, as well as our overseas shipping line to capitalize on the China export boom in carload and containers of lumber and pulp.</p>
          <p>Coal revenue was up 31%, another strong performance. We have strong demand for coking coal, ex-Rupert and Vancouver. We have strong demand for export terminal coal, ex-U.S. Gulf, and we have some replenishment of utilities' inventory level in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Grain was up 10%. Canadian grain was up 13% on strong export, mainly of canola and peas, and U.S. grain was up 5%, mainly on strong export of soya bean and corn. Fertilizer was up 9%, mostly on potash. The dealers' inventories are very low out there and the best has yet to come in the fourth quarter for the fertilizer storage.</p>
          <p>Overseas intermodal was up a strong 28% due to a strong west coast import and export trade involving very strong exports starting overseas.</p>
          <p>Domestic intermodal was up 10%, an improvement that came mostly from our direct retail door-to-door product. And again on that, the best has yet to come. Other revenues was up 28% primly due to our Great Lakes fleet and dock operation, which are an integral part of our in-house iron ore supply chain business unit, which has done extremely well in 2010.</p>
          <p>Now let's go to the brief outlook on Page 12. So far this quarter, our carload volume has grown 11%, and we need to keep in mind our comparable from last year is probably to be improving. Remember, last year, the recovery was starting to come over the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>If we look at the three broad segments, first looking at manufacturing, we have additional fleet acquisition that will come in line during the fourth quarter, which will support our ongoing truck market share initiative in steel. We have a continuous focus on serving the shale gas drilling activities, which in our case is mostly in Western Canada, and that will support our shipment of rock, sand and drilling pipe throughout the coming quarter.</p>
          <p>The automotive production level on our line expected to increase by about 10% versus 2009 and keeping with the momentum that we have acquired so far this year, and I think many of you have heard of the good Ford Motors result earlier today and that bodes well. On the bulk side, although the Canadian grain harvest is smaller and late, we see very strong overseas pricing for those crops, which is actually increasing sequentially our orders to the west coast above the third quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>Market for export coal remained very positive. We view our strategic position at the Port of Prince Rupert as being something that will be very useful for us in the mid-term.</p>
          <p>A slow start to this fall fertilizer position in September has actually pushed forward the demand into the fourth quarter of this year. On intermodal, the import fall peak came in early this year. It came actually, started to come in, in May and it started to turn down around the month of September. As imports are slowing down, there's still a very strong push from B.C. export to look for vessel capacity back mostly to China.</p>
          <p>Claude's already mentioned our port supply chain agreement with the ports and that bodes well also for the future. On my side, I've been mostly focused on what I call a glowing box report, which is the daily report that we produce with our terminal partners. Our customers' experience is now a port average well time, customers' experiences relating to their own box. That outside in view of how they view our service is actually what helps us create value for those who actually pay the freight.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, we expect usual fourth quarter sequential slowdown. However, we also expect our bulk business and our internal business to be very strong in the fourth quarter versus 2009, ending off a great year on a strong road.</p>
          <p>So I'll turn this over to my friend, Luc, who will cover the financial side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, J.J. Let me briefly review the financial results for the third quarter. As was mentioned earlier by J.J., the revenues were at $2.1 billion up 15%. And on a constant currency basis, that was actually an improvement of 18% versus last year's same quarter.</p>
          <p>Our operating income and net income were both up 21%, and our adjusted EPS came in at $1.19, which is up 27% versus last year, and on a constant currency that's a full 30% improvement versus 2009.</p>
          <p>Our third quarter operating ratio was 60.7, a 2 point improvement versus last year, and our year-to-date operating ratio now stands at 63.6%, which is a 3.5 point improvement versus last year.</p>
          <p>Turning to Page 15, our operating expenses came in at $1.3 billion, and that's up 15% on a constant currency. We continue to have effective cost management throughout the quarter, as our carloads were up 18% and our RTMs were up 9%.</p>
          <p>Fuel was a significant category where the costs came in at $249 million. That was up 27%. This was mostly due to higher prices, where the WTI was actually $76 during the quarter versus $68 looking back at the same quarter a year ago. We also obviously had higher volumes.</p>
          <p>On the labor and fringe cost, the expenses came in at $437 million. That was up 7%, and this is the result of an increased workforce by approx 2.5%, as we continue to adjust our manpower in line with volume and ahead of attrition.</p>
          <p>In fact, our T&amp;E resources were actually up 5%. We also had some higher wages and benefit costs during the quarter. On the depreciation front, our expenses were $204 million. That was up 8% versus last year. This was mostly due to net asset additions, but we also had an increase in depreciation from the completion of our first phase of a Canadian asset appreciation study.</p>
          <p>Now this study is done every three years, and it's a comprehensive review of every asset category. This year, we're having the benefit of much better asset-specific information, and this first phase covered a portion of our assets and resulted in an annual increase of approximately $20 million going forward in depreciation.</p>
          <p>Phase two will be completed by the end of the first quarter of 2011, and while it's a bit premature, I would say that we do expect the results to have a similar impact as the first phase. So all-in-all, we could see a potential increase in our depreciation from these asset studies to be in the tune of about 50 basis points of operating ratio.</p>
          <p>On the casualty and other cost, the expenses were $91 million, and this was an increase of $40 million versus last year. Now this increase was the result of two factors. The first one is, as some of you may recall, last year we booked a $20 million plus favorable adjustment which resulted from improved experience relating to our U.S. legal claims. In addition this year, we've accrued about $15 million worth of environmental expenses as a result of our ongoing review of these issues.</p>
          <p>Turning over to cash flow. As Claude mentioned earlier, our free cash flow was $938 million, and that was a $280 million plus improvement versus last year.</p>
          <p>This was the result of a very strong operating performance, in addition to the sale of our non-core subdivision in Toronto in the first quarter to the tune of about $170 million and also some lower cash tax installments on the Canadian front, probably for somewhere in the neighborhood of $250 million. This was also partly offset by a voluntary additional pension contribution which we made in the third quarter in the amount of $300 million, and this was intended to improve our plan's funded position.</p>
          <p>Now asset returns remain volatile and quite modest in 2010. However, the discount rate has actually continued to come down, so if you actually just took the discount rate at the end of the year, which is what's going to determine the pension benefit obligation and our future cost, we will ultimately know what will be the liability and the future cost. But just looking at the end of September using the rates that were in place, we can actually see the potential for an increase in our pension expense to the tune of about 50 basis points of operating ratio.</p>
          <p>From the CapEx standpoint, we invested about $824 million in the year-to-date results, and we expect to invest approximately $800 million in the fourth quarter as we continue to prepare our winter program. In fact, we're looking at accelerating the delivery of some of our new high horsepower DP-equipped locomotives to help in this respect.</p>
          <p>Our stock buyback is 75% completed, and so we're up to 11.5 million shares which have been acquired at this point in the year.</p>
          <p>Turning to the 2010 financial outlook. We continue to leverage the recovering economy, and as certainly our third quarter and our year-to-date results indicate. We continue to see a gradual economic recovery unfolding, albeit at a slower pace in the fourth quarter versus obviously the year-to-date performance.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, we reaffirm our 2010 guidance, as we believe that we have the scope to achieve an increase of approximately 25% in our 2010 adjusted diluted EPS over 2009, which was really 324. We also continue to see free cash flow in the range of $1.1 billion, so we're going into the fourth quarter with good momentum, and a good position to finish the year. Also we'll be positioning the company for a solid winter program and a good performance in 2011.</p>
          <p>All of this should translate into some solid shareholder value creation. And with that, I'll turn it back over to you, Claude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, guys. Just to wrap it up, I think we have a solid year in the making, as Luc just explained to you.</p>
          <p>We are taking every bit of advantage of the economic recovery, but this is more than just economic recovery. We are also very much delivering on our strategic agenda, working with our customers. Our supply chain focus is helping us gain market share one carload at a time, and if we continue to do this, I believe that the rail industry has a great future ahead of us with more and more people see the value of railroading in terms of service, see the value of railroading in terms of environmental friendliness and see the value of railroading in terms of cost for their transportation needs.</p>
          <p>So our challenge is to keep the service improving, keep the operational excellence and drive that combination to reward our shareholders over time.</p>
          <p>With that, we'll be happy to take questions from the audience. Operator, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We do have a question from Scott Group with Wolfe Trahan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good afternoon, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Luc, a question for you on the casualty side. I see that it's up a good amount year-over-year up against some tough comps, but if I look at it sequentially, it's down pretty materially from where we were in first and second quarter. Is there anything on the reserve adjustment side or actuarial side that's keeping that number so low? And if not, is this 90 million a good run rate going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'd say the $90 million is not a bad run rate going forward, and I don't necessarily expect anything significant on that front in the fourth quarter, so that's kind of where we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great and then a question for J.J. You talked about some, at least feeling near term -- feeling very good about the bulk side with grain and coal. I was wondering if you think that can continue into 2011? Do you think you might lose some coal volume back to CP, given their new contract with Teck? And then on the grain side, do you think grain can be positive next year given the Canadian crop that's going to be down 10% or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we feel very positive in some of the bulk business for the fourth quarter. Canadian grain is at high price. The crop is smaller and the quality of the crop would only be very well known only come late November, December, but right now the product is moving very well, and we have very strong order, much higher than the third quarter. At some point next year, whether it's first quarter or second quarter, eventually the quality will start to show an impact. Also we feel positive about the fertilizer side, the potash inventory in North America; the wholesalers are low. People are buying when they need it, so I think we'll have a good push start in October, November and then next spring we'll see.</p>
          <p>On the coast side we have a good story. I think Claude mentioned the supply chain story that we have, and our activities in both Rupert and in Vancouver is very busy with a mine that we serve. I think it's natural that Teck and the other railroad had a long-term partnership because of the physical location of those mines in Southern B.C., which obviously we do not serve. And what happened there is maybe something that's very logical.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are there volumes that you expect to lose with Teck as a result of that contract?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think time will tell, but I think that maybe we're getting into a too narrow of a discussion, but time will tell where that will lead us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for the time, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Bill Greene with Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi there, good afternoon. I'm wondering if we can talk just a little bit of clarification on the guidance. So you beat this quarter, but you didn't raise the full year.  So the obvious question is sort of what are you seeing in the fourth quarter that gives you pause that you don't want to raise the full year number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me handle this one. I think we are very well positioned to finish the year on a solid note and at this point in time we didn't feel that changing our guidance was necessary, but as long as the economy holds up and we continue to deliver, we should finish on a strong note. And as Luc said, approximately 25%. You have a little wiggle room around that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If I look at some of the metrics that we showed here on the operating side, it's obvious that you are the most consistent, strongest operator out there, and you've had a lot of success since '08. But recently we have topped out. Does this suggest we're hitting or wall? Or is there a way to get to a new level? Or how do we think about the evolution from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't say that we're hitting a wall. There's still plenty of capacity left in this railroad. I'd just say you're getting to a point where last year with a very less, I guess, less challenged railroad with much fewer boxcars and locomotives running around, we had some astounding -- outstanding metrics. So we're lacking against those metrics.</p>
          <p>There's still more to go. And yes, there's more we can do down the line as we continue to strategically invest in locomotives and make inroads with our unions that we operate and our more collaborative approach that we're pursuing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Claude, that's just sort of, just circling back then, I guess what that says is really the only way you're going to have a big beat from here is really just got to be revenue. There's &#x2013; we've got tougher comps on the operating metrics, and so revenue's really the game. Is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't think it's fair. To be honest, we are leading the industry in terms of volume recovery by a wide margin, so we've been operating in the third quarter and are operating in the fourth quarter at levels approaching 2008. So the fact that we are able to keep the operating metric that we have, despite the volume growth, on a cumulative basis over those two years, it's pretty stellar productivity and efficiency improvement.</p>
          <p>So we've just got to regroup from here, and as we accommodate the volume going forward, with a view to having the right tradeoff between investing in service and flexibility and pushing on the efficiency front, you can see CN driving the top line and being able to accommodate that business at low, incremental cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. That's very helpful. Appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Jason Seidl with Dahlman Rose. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Afternoon, gentlemen. Just getting back to the guidance. What are you using for your continuing ops for nine months in this guidance number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure &#x2013; you mean in terms of EPS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Whatever you &#x2013; this is perhaps a better question to have off line, but whatever we've reported in the first two quarters, plus the 119 that we reported this quarter is what you should use as the first nine months. And as I said, Luc gave you guidance for the full year at approximately 25%, which is basically re-affirming what we have said this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. I'll go back and take that offline then. Claude, you guys have done a lot with the ports and everything else. How should we look at that going forward as a revenue opportunity for CN? And how should we think about modeling that for 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The way you should think about that is this will underscore our ability to grow slightly faster than what the economy would give us. As we discussed when we met in Chicago, the evidence to me, you have to see it on a daily basis. I see the collaboration, for instance, on the west coast between the terminal operators in Vancouver and our operating team is nothing short of a totally new approach. We're monitoring data, and what it takes to come together, terminal and railroad, on a daily basis.</p>
          <p>So we are seeing issues. We have a much quicker recovery. We are able to bring dwell time in terms of the time it takes for containers to stay on the dock down significantly, and more importantly, because we monitor one box at a time, as J.J. mentioned, it's not just averages. It's making sure that we don't leave boxes behind that become reputation killer. And so if you improve consistency and you bring down the averages in terms of supply chain efficiency, eventually you get more traffic. And you only need a few boxes more than what the economy would give you, and you do that consistently over time, it adds up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Claude. Thank you. Luc, real quick. The reported number for the nine months in your press release says diluted 339, but I doubt you guys are going to be guiding to $0.66 for 4Q. So could you help us out and clarify that a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is probably best handled offline, but you have to take out the special gains that we had during the year to get to an adjusted number. So I think if you call Bob, he'll. . .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just call me afterwards.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Will do, Bob. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Cherilyn Radbourne with TD Newcrest. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, and good afternoon. I wondered if you could speak a little bit about your discussions with customers and what they're telling you in terms of their inventory levels as we look forward to 2011, what kind of shape do you think they're in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we get the sense that inventory level obviously is not at peak, that it has depending on the segment, depending on the segment, there has been some rebuilding, partial rebuilding, but there's still a ways to go in terms of &#x2013; but then you get down to commodities. So fertilizer inventories are low. Automotive, I was looking at a dealer's inventory by model type and by automaker. It varies. It's slightly up from where it was. Some automakers are above the average. Some are still fairly low, so I think we &#x2013; there's still room into this run rate of rebuilding inventory  slowly, plus obviously meeting the demand, the market demand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my second question. I just wondered if you could just comment on the collaboration agreements that you've negotiated? And just who's leading that process internally? Have you developed a standard template now? And as you negotiate those agreements, how do you make sure that you protect CN's operating model?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer that one. I think the way we're leading this is in rugby style using a scrum. This is truly operations and marketing getting on the ground. Not just at CN, but when we meet with a terminal operator, for instance, it's down on the dock level. The people who are actually operating the cranes and operating the terminal that we have to come together and agree on what metrics make sense.</p>
          <p>So the answer to your question is it the scrum approach? And by now, we've done it enough that we actually do have a template. And every terminal is a little different, but effectively we're following the template out of the core 10 measures, nine or eight would be the same across terminal. And then we have one or two that would reflect the specificity or some of the special issues that might creep in for one terminal at a time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I may add, we have a similar engagement whether it's a bulk terminal, a container terminal or a break bulk terminal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. That's all my questions. Nice quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Tom Wadewitz with JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good afternoon. It's Michael Wines in for Tom. Just wanted to touch base really quickly on other income. I was kind of surprised that it was so high in the quarter. Was there anything specific driving that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I mean it was inter switching revenue was actually &#x2013; are we talking other income?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Other income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Other income, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We didn't really have anything exceptional versus the last quarter last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But it was significantly higher than first and second quarter. So how should we think about that going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This actually can be &#x2013; it's not a straight projection, so it can be a bit lumpy, but by large, we do expect the number that you had in the first and second quarter to, on average, be about the right level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the best way to think about it is you probably want to average out the volatility, and then take the average and that's probably a good indication of future other income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Makes sense. I was wondering on the head count side, how should we think about &#x2013; I guess on volumes and head count, how should we think about seasonality going into fourth quarter? It looks like from a volume perspective, volumes are typically flattish fourth quarter versus third. So do you think you can get that this year? And what would that mean for head count as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're hiring mostly in line with attrition, and then volume comes into play, but on a sequential basis, the volume between Q3 and Q4 is not going to be a significant movement. So we are &#x2013; it's more what Keith was explaining to you earlier. We are trying to stay ahead of the curve, so we look out to our attrition six months into next year, and because we have to train these people, you have to start getting them on board, and you'll have some of that in Q4.</p>
          <p>So I think the Q3 shape of our workforce adjustment is probably a good indication, more increase in T&amp;E employees where we are hiring basically replacing one to one. And in the other sectors, we are able to get productivity, so the increase is less pronounced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That makes sense. And just on the train starts and train length side, I was just wondering if you could provide the year-over-year change? Because I don't think that was brought up in the operational highlights this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the train start side year-over-year, we've effectively absorbed a 12% increase in business, and only increased train starts by about 4%. What was the second part of the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Train length.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Train length is up in excess, it's about 6%, 5% to 6%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, I appreciate it. Thanks for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from David Newman with Cormark Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just in terms of the pricing, how did the grain reversal factor into your same-store pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Originally grain represented, I think it's what, about 6% of our revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the full year, and that actually has changed, come into effect every year on August 1st and we went from a negative to a positive for this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so there's a bit of a positive swing factor. So that would have been played into those numbers for two of the three months, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, in relation to carload, the rate of grain that we move into the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just overall, I mean are you &#x2013; obviously in the truck competitive sectors that you're in, we're seeing price increases even in things like LTL, et cetera, and you've got the CSA 2010, which is coming in effect for the trucking industry. I mean, do you anticipate that you'll be able to take some price increases on the back of, I guess, price increases that are being taken by the truckers and evolving, I guess, driver shortages?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Most certainly, but I think the trucking industry, the state of the trucking industry, regulation, pricing and regulation you talked about is different between Canada and the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so it'll have some effect, though, for sure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It'll have an effect to the extent that we have an exporter to the U.S. truck market, which has different behavior than the Canadian truck market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you're &#x2013; in terms of your negotiations, you're not seeing anything &#x2013; any sort of more inflation being built into your pricing? So you're sort of sticking with the same-store or sticking with the inflation plus kind of pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're not going to go into specific guidance to what we're going to do next year in terms of price, but the current run rate that we have right now is in line with what we talked about, inflation plus pricing. So you look at inflation, you look at the service that we provide, and the better we are in term of these first mile, last mile in some markets, better we are in terms of these initiatives with forced take holders in other markets, we will leverage that to the extent we can, either price or volume or better mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Chris Ceraso with Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good evening. I actually had a follow-up in a similar vein on pricing and inflation. It does seem like in the quarter that pricing at plus 3 was not able to keep up with inflation. If I look at your labor and fringe and purchased services and materials, they're rising at a faster rate year-over-year on an FX adjusted basis. How do you &#x2013; is that something you expect to continue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just challenge you a little bit on the inflation. In actual fact, the broad inflation is lower than that, and if you exclude the factors like broad based compensation, et cetera, our wage increase is in line with about 3% to 3.5% wage increase when you include benefits. And so our pricing has been generally in that range, both this quarter and in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so the increase above and beyond that is mainly incentive comp?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well it's a higher &#x2013; a larger number for the workforce by 2.5, and then you've got some of the incentive comp on top of that, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But I mean, even if we think about it that way, if that happens quarter after quarter, don't you feel like you're kind of losing some ground with your costs going up faster than your price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe we can think of apples-to-apples. When we measure price, maybe we're measuring it in a fairly pure way. Our same-store price increase is pure price. That is that 90% of the business really has a fuel surcharge. In our price we don't have RCF or other indices which have a fuel component. Pure price is pure price. Fuel is fuel, and when you look at our price, there's really just price. There's not &#x2013; we don't do very much at index pricing. We don't do very much index business, and that's why 90% of our book is business is based on fuel surcharge.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just one clarification. I didn't quite catch the comment from Keith about 6,000 employees. Over what timeframe was that that you expected to hire those people? And was that equal to the number that you thought would leave through attrition?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The 6,000 is the base. So effectively &#x2013; of T&amp;E employees, train and engine employees. So right now we're up 5% year-over-year, so that run rate on a go forward basis we're going to be attriting out for the next four to five years, the demographic model that's constant across the company. So we have to hire them ahead of time, and keep in mind, not just hire the conductor that takes six months to train.</p>
          <p>It's also new engineers that attrite at the same time, and those conductors are replacing engineers as you pull those, promote, and pull them out to do their training for engineer certification. So to a degree you got to manage both sides of it, so 5% is a pretty conservative number. Pretty good job of doing it and making sure that we keep the workforce correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's roughly your attrition rate? And you're going to hire to replace on a one-for-one basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct. Plus, that little advance to make sure we have it ahead of time, and we've got the training done. We've done a quality job of on-boarding the employees.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question from Walter Spracklin with RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Good afternoon, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Walter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the service review panel. The interim report that came out, it seems that they're going to be keeping an eye on the railroad industry, at least on the Canadian side, up until 2013. And, Claude, you've been doing a lot of things now, as you highlighted in the service initiatives front. Just trying to gauge and understand exactly what the initiatives are that you're going to provide? And how they might impact?</p>
          <p>I know this is kind of a follow on to the other question, but is there a risk to the increased levels of service that you're providing your customer, an increased risk to your operating ratio? And if there's not, can you explain to me why wasn't this something that you would have done earlier? Or what is happening now that's allowing you to be able to provide better service without it impacting your bottom line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you have to take this, as we explained it before, in the context of the natural journey that CN has been on. You improve your basic service. You schedule your train operation. You get the hub-to-hub velocity to a leading position. That's what we have done over the last several years. Once you've achieved that, and you continue to have improvement potential in this regard, what's your next opportunity? Well, your next opportunity is to focus on first mile, last mile, to get the switching window compliance, to improve on order fulfillment. You also bring to this a more end-to-end supply chain management approach.</p>
          <p>You reorganize the marketing forces, and you give a slightly different mandate to your operating team to add to their operational focus a few more customer centric measures. And that's the journey we've been on, a journey of constant innovation, pushing the envelope in terms of service and operational excellence. And that's what we &#x2013; that's the journey we're on, and we think we have a great opportunity going forward to not only maintain our operational efficiency, but to improve the product and grow the business with our customers a little bit faster than what the economy would give us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great color, Claude. Thank you. Just moving to, I guess, sort of an administrative question here. I mean, your guidance before I think was around a 29% for tax rate. You've been getting the benefit from a lower tax rate, so that's been helping your bottom line a little bit again this quarter in the 27.5 to 28% range. What do we look at going forward? Is this a 27%, 28% tax rate going forward? Or should we model something higher?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it still continues to be in the 28 to 30% range. We've been at the lower end of that, and we came in on the quarter at 27.6. So going forward, I'd say 28, 29% is probably a good place to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. That's my two questions. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Ken Hoexter with Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good afternoon. If I can just clarify on the outlook just for a second. You said it was based off a 324, so 25% growth gets you to about 405 in earnings, and you've done 312 through the first three quarters. So that gives you a $0.93 fourth quarter with consensus up at $1.07. So I know, Claude, you keep kind of just saying you want to talk about this later, but I just want to understand why the $0.14 below consensus. Is there something going on in the fourth quarter when you compare it to last year's fourth quarter so that it would be a flat quarter relative to the pretty sizable upside we've seen in the first three quarters on a year-over-year basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me put it to you this way. As I said earlier, we have decided not to change our guidance, but we have said that we will achieve a solid end to the year, and that we are guiding to approximately 25%. That has wiggle room, so if you do the straight math, it gives a number that you give, but I think our third quarter results are good, and we expect our fourth quarter to be good. And if the economy stays with us, we should finish the year on a strong note.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I just wanted to clarify that there was nothing that you're looking in the fourth quarter that would cause it to be flat, like any unknown expenses or anything. That's not what you're saying or indicating, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We said quite the reverse, that we see good bulk movement and continued opportunity to accommodate that business with low incremental cost and finish the year on a strong note.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, I appreciate that clarification. Keith, can you just talk a bit about the cars or locomotives still in storage so we can kind of get a concept of maybe the incremental margin potential still on the docket there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we still have just under 200 locomotives in storage, and we still are in the process of acquiring orders that we placed with the locomotive producers. We've got locomotives coming on line fourth quarter of this year, and again, first quarter of next year. So there's still a lot of runway left as we make decisions and business warrants pulling those locomotives and putting them into service.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And cars?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the car side, same thing, same story effectively, lack of a better term. I mean we're up in the 100,000 range as far as cars on line. We still have fleet on the center beam side effectively across the board. There's no fleet really that we have that's constrained right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just lastly, if I could just throw in on the export side. Are you seeing the weak dollar driving any exports? Or can you talk about the currency shifts and how that's kind of altered any of your business flows?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe what we see is, I don't know if it's the weak U.S. dollar or the strong demand from Asia, but out of B.C., whether you're exporting natural resource, bulk natural resource, grain, bulk or container, this is obviously an area of very strong focus for us, as well as an area where the potential is real. If you look at the lumber industry, who's got real tough time in the U.S. partly because of the strong Canadian dollars, they're finding ways to make it up in shipping a lot of product to China mostly via containers. So some of these things are maybe seeing slowly some permanent shift as to where the market for each commodity is going over the long run, and then we'll see how these things play out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks a lot. I appreciate it, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Gary Chase with Barclays Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening, everybody. Two quick ones. Wondered if J.J. could maybe comment a little bit on some of the business that you referenced on the steel side where you're taking some truck competitive business? I wondered if you could give us a little flavor for what the yield dynamics were there and to what extent, if it was material, it might have impacted your yields in that segment during the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think when you look at the yield for M&amp;N, probably the biggest impact was iron ore. Our iron ore business was way up, iron ore short haul and that impacts you sent for RTM. But if you go back to our market share we're getting on steel, that business is profitable. We didn't do this on price. The reason why people weren't using us in the past was not because of the price. It was because of our response time. When you place an order with a trucker, you could get it to your plant within two days.</p>
          <p>The lead time for the trucker to move the product to market is short versus the railroad lead time. So we have to work first and foremost on having our fleet closer in proximity to the steel mill, and two, our willingness on our side to look at our order system so that people can actually try us with short lead time order. And that's what we've done, and that's what's been paying out. We got some strategic location of cars that Keith has near Hamilton, as well as Montreal. So I believe to fulfill short lead or short lead orders with a shorter lead time is what's allowing us to compete with truck. It's just a price game.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So if you cleaned it up on an apples-to-apples basis, it's safe to say it's good as or better than?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And by the way, these don't affect the same-store price because they're new movements. They don't go into filter from same-store activities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I wondered if you guys could maybe broadly comment, maybe for Keith or Luc, but are any of these initiatives creating some cost impact in the near-term that we should think might go away or dissipate over time? When you think about some of these initiatives, like getting cars closer to these customers, is there some sort of spool off cost that we should be thinking about as impacting the results that maybe will dissipate or improve with time? Or you're seeing most of the benefit already?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would not &#x2013; I can tell you now that there are quite lively discussions. J.J. and I are both on the same sheet of music. He understands the critical nature of maintaining our operating model. So in these locations where we strategically store cars, there's not any material cost at all involved. It's effectively putting the cars on track that's adjacent to these facilities, and when the call comes for that last minute order, and provide the flexibility, we'll stop a train. We'll pick the cars up. We'll set them off and the industry jobs that are currently servicing those locations will spot the cars. In the past, we were not that flexible, but with this bottle we have the ability to do that. There's not a lot of cost built into it, so therefore, there wouldn't be any windfall down the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me add. On the terminal agreement that Claude referred earlier, this agreement is a two way agreement. There's things that we want and ask from the terminal operator like seven days operations, which is valuable to our scheduled railroad model, and there's things the terminal asks from us. So this is really not a gift. It's a trade when we create value for them and they help us create value for ourselves on the efficiency side. Historically, the bottom up front was not the most productive for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, guys. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question from Benoit Poirier with Desjardins Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much. Teck recently released their production going forward, and it seems there's a nice support transparency with you with the restart of Quintette. Could you maybe quantify what could be the potential contribution for you? And what is the CapEx implication on this particular opportunity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We too saw that Teck may decide later this year whether or not they will reopen Quintette. Quintette is located where the port of choice would be Rupert where there is capacity. I don't believe that we would have much capital investment, if any. It's something we did in the past, something we'd be happy to do again, and there is capacity at Port of Prince Rupert for more coal. So that would be an upside if Teck makes that decision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, excellent. And maybe my second question is for Keith. You've been talking about the investment on the new locomotives. Could you maybe quantify what we should expect in terms of fuel efficiency going forward in terms of GTMs per U.S. gallon of fuel consumed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, our guidance and our expectation is to finish the year in the 3% area, and that's what we look to on a go-forward basis. And we do that as we effectively we get better at deploying these DP locomotives, and also we're implementing some newer technologies as well with cruise control and with systems that allow us to drive compliance with our horsepower and our throttle knots  limitation that's driving some of those fuel gains. So there's several things in the pipeline that we'll step through that will allow us to maintain that run rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Benoit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Fadi Chamoun with BMO Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good evening. Maybe a different kind of question to Claude and Luc. If I'm looking back at 2009, you had very strong financial metrics, and I'm looking at debt to EBITDA interest coverage. And you reported very strong free cash flow in one of the worst years for the industry in a very long time. So I'm thinking with 2009 sort of in the rearview, looking back at it, wondering whether you feel that maybe you have more room in the capital structure to move more towards debt, and particularly given the low interest rate environment, perhaps increase the buyback and create some shareholder value in the process? And how would you balance this against, I guess, perhaps the opportunity to keep a strong balance sheet for potential M&amp;A in the future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Basically we do have an ongoing stock buyback for the year. As I mentioned earlier, we're in the process of completing it, and so that's out there. Going forward, obviously, we do want to make sure that the business is fully supported in terms of reinvestment. Then we look to increase increasing dividends, and last but not least, share buybacks if there's excess cash.</p>
          <p>We don't necessarily see our ratios as being out of whack. They're a little bit lower than our stated targets, but we're not uncomfortable with where they are now, and we also have to look going forward at the pension situation to make some of these decisions. So we'll be reviewing it on an ongoing basis, and we want to continue delivering excess shareholder value to the extent we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question's from Jeff Kauffman with Sterne Agee. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Congratulations on a very solid quarter. Luc, I just have one question. When I look at the cash flow reconciliation for free cash on Page 16 of your slides, payments for income tax is a reduction of cash flow, about 186 million. Normally when you're growing the way you are, it's a source of cash flow through deferred taxes. Is this a timing issue? And does this reverse in any point in '011 and become more of a driver of cash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's actually going to be opposite. $186 million is the amount that we've actually paid in cash taxes in 2010. Because of the way the Canadian tax structure goes, we are paying lower tax installments in 2010 because it's really on the basis of our 2009 income. And so this will create a headwind as we get into 2011, probably to the tune of some $250 million to $300 million additional cash taxes which will have to be paid.</p>
          <p>So as far as we stand for this particular year, 2010, we expect to be having cash taxes of about 225 million, so there's not &#x2013; this is not going to be a tail wind. I think this is going to be a strong headwind as we get into 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now isn't there some offset because the net income in your cash flow statement would reflect the accrual of taxes at the 27%, 28% rate or no?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the accrual which is actually backed out, and then you put through the actual cash that you pay. So that's why you're seeing 186, but in your 806 you actually have some $344 million of deferred taxes which are backed out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Luc. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that's the end of the questions, and I just would like to thank you again for taking the time in your busy day to listen to our third quarter results. We are pleased with them, and we hope that we will have good fourth quarter results to report in a couple months. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The conference has ended. Please disconnect your lines at this time, and we thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>