<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1303619" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1165</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Clayton Reasor, Vice President, Corporate Affairs</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James J. Mulva, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Douglas Terreson</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Jason Gammel</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Doug Leggate</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Arjun Murti</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Jacques Rousseau</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Paul Cheng</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Mark Gilman</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Neil McMahon</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Edward Westlake</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Blake Fernandez</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Q1 2010 ConocoPhillips Earnings Conference Call. My name is Chris and I will be your operator for today. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. We will conduct a question and answer session towards the end of this conference. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded for replay purposes. I would now like to turn the call over to Mr. Clayton Reasor, Vice President of Corporate Affairs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris, and thanks, everybody for participating in our first quarter conference call. I'm joined by Jim Mulva, our Chairman and CEO, and this morning we'll be discussing the company's first quarter results and status on the strategic initiatives we shared on our March 24 Analyst Day. The summary of key financial and operating results for the quarter will be provided as well as our outlook for the remainder of 2010. As in the past, you can find the presentation materials on the IR section of the ConocoPhillips website and in addition to the presentation material, we plan to use our website to provide information that was part of our quarterly interim update prior to discontinuing its issuance earlier this year.</p>
          <p>Please refer to our Safe Harbor statement in the appendix of this presentation on slide 17. It's a reminder that we will be making forward-looking statements during the presentation and Q&amp;A. Our actual results may differ materially from what we present and also in the appendix are non-GAAP reconciliations footnoted throughout the presentation for your reference.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 2, a summary of our results and highlights for the quarter, you'll see adjusted earnings for the first quarter were 2.2 billion or $1.47 a share which excludes the charges of 110 million for ending our participation in the Yanbu and Shah projects. Cash from operations were $3 billion. Our company's capital efficiency increased as annualized cash return on capital invested improved to 21%. Our E&amp;P production excluding LUKOIL, was 1.83 million BOE per day and in spite of the challenging downstream environment, the competitiveness of our refineries allowed us to run at 88%.</p>
          <p>I'm going to now turn to slide 3. Total earnings for our company were $2.98 billion, up 1.3 billion compared to last year. The majority of our earnings were generated by our Exploration &amp; Production business. Our E&amp;P segment improve by 1.132 billion, primarily due to the increase in crude prices. Compared to first quarter of last year, R&amp;M income fell 209 million. Weaker refining and marketing margins more than offset lower operating costs.</p>
          <p>Our equity earnings for LUKOIL investment were up 379 million compared to the first quarter of 2009. As I mentioned earlier, this quarter we had charges of 110 million for exiting the Shah and Yanbu projects. Adjusting for that you can see this quarter's earnings were $2.208 billion. Total company control of costs were lower by about 40 million year on year, and 110 million sequentially, and if you eliminate the impact of foreign exchange and higher utility and fuel costs.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 4, total company cash flow, you can see the first quarter we generated $3 billion in cash from operations. This included a $979 million negative impact from an increase in working capital. This increase in working capital is driven by the growth and seasonal operational inventory levels and in support of our commercial business consistent with what we've done in the past. We expect a substantial portion of this inventory to be worked off by year end.</p>
          <p>Our capital program totaled $2.480 billion for the quarter in line with our 2010 budget of $11.2 billion. And while debt-to-cap ratio remained flat, our absolute debt level increased slightly due to the increase in working capital I mentioned earlier. We paid $744 million in dividends compared to 696 million paid in the first quarter of 2009. Our first quarter 2010 cash position ended at $855 million.</p>
          <p>Now let's review our total company production for the first quarter on slide 5. As expected, first quarter 2010 E&amp;P production was 1.83 million BOE per day down 5%, or 97,000 BOE per day from the first quarter of 2009. Compared to last quarter, E&amp;P production was virtually flat. Looking at the sources behind the year-over-year decline, 29,000 BOE per day can be attributed to market factors, including production sharing contracts in Indonesia and royalty impacts in Canada.</p>
          <p>Portfolio changes, mainly due to the expropriation of our assets in Ecuador, decreased production by about 9,000 BOE per day and higher planned maintenance primarily in Australia, decreased our production by 3,000 BOE per day. The remaining decrease of 56,000 BOE per day was due to normal field decline primarily in the U.K., lower 48 and Alaska mitigated by new production from Phase 2 of our Bohai Bay project in China and our Foster Creek Christina Lake SAGD developments in Canada.</p>
          <p>Production from FCCL oil properties increased nearly 50% on a net after-royalty basis in the first quarter of 2010 compared to the same period of 2009. The Foster Creek project achieved payout for royalty purposes in the first quarter. It's the industry's largest SAGD project to reach payout to date and is leading the way in implementing innovative technologies that lower operating costs and reduce our impact on the environment.</p>
          <p>In the Bakken shale, we spud 3 wells during March, bringing our 2010 well count to 6. Three of those wells were placed on production in March with each having initial flow rates of approximately 2,000 BOE per day. As we gain experience in this area, drilling productivity continues to improve which we hope to replicate as we increase investments in this region.</p>
          <p>In the Eagle Ford play, we currently have 3 rigs drilling and have completed the drilling phase of 4 horizontal wells this year. The first of these wells were placed on production in late March and flowed at an initial rate of 3.8 million cubic feet of gas and 1,200 barrels a day of condensate. This well and related industry results reinforce the potential of our 240,000 net acre position in the liquid-rich core of this play.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to page 6, unadjusted E&amp;P earnings for the first quarter were $1.832 billion up from 700 million last year. Higher prices and other market impacts contributed 1.5 billion of increased earnings. The increase was partially offset by $104 million due to the impact of lower sales volumes. And operating costs were 23 million higher mainly due to the adverse affects of foreign exchange of about 50 million. Excluding the impact of FX, operating costs were down around 25 to $30 million from a year ago. The $219 million in Other includes $83 million in costs associated with the Shah project exit, increased DDA due to foreign exchange impacts and an increase in export taxes related to our equity affiliates. As stated, when excluding the 83 million charge for the exit of Shah, adjusted earnings are $1.915 billion.</p>
          <p>You can see the realized prices table at the bottom of slide 6. On the right-hand side, you can see realized oil and NGL prices reflect a 78% increase compared to last year and global gas prices increased by approximately 11%. Both U.S. and international earnings improved significantly from the prior year and the lower 48 business unit had solid earnings this year compared to a loss a year ago. Although North American natural gas prices remain challenged, our financial performance in the lower 48 benefited from liquids which represent more than a third of its production.</p>
          <p>Moving onto slide 7 are unit metrics for E&amp;P. You can see our E&amp;P income per BOE was nearly 3 times higher in the first quarter of 2009 reflecting the increase in realized prices. And although we currently lag the largest competitors in our industry on an income per BOE basis, we expect to close this gap as we allocate more of our capital to liquids production.</p>
          <p>Our E&amp;P cash contribution per BOE has been consistently above average compared to our peer group for more than a year. And if prices continue to increase, we expect to outperform our peers on a cash flow per barrel basis due to our large OECD focus portfolio.</p>
          <p>The R&amp;M segment discussion begins on slide 8. Market conditions for R&amp;M were challenging during the quarter and much weaker than the first quarter of 2009. However, we did benefit from wider light heavy crude differentials, better margins on the production of feed stocks used by the chemical industry and improved clean product yields. We were able to increase our U.S. refinery utilization to 88% this quarter from 80% a year ago and 83% sequentially.</p>
          <p>The year-over-year earnings variance was driven primarily by lower global refining and marketing margins. Over 85% of the $213 million reduction in income is related to refining margins. In the U.S., distillate margins have dropped about 40% while internationally distillate margins have fallen 30%. Lower global volumes impacted earnings by 24 million. These volumes were primarily caused by our Wilhelmshaven refinery which was shut down for the entire first quarter as well as planned turnaround activity at both our joint venture refineries, MiRO in Germany and the Melaka refinery in Malaysia.</p>
          <p>The $88 million improvement in operating costs was due primarily to lower turnaround activity and other operating costs. We remain focused on items we can control, including cost management and optimizing our operations. 11 of our 17 refineries are ranked in the top tier of the Solomon Operating Cost peer ranking and this creates competitive cost advantages. 60 million in Other was caused by foreign exchange impacts and includes a $25 million impairment resulting from our decision not to participate in the Yanbu refinery project. Adjusted earnings for R&amp;M were 21 million for the quarter. The table at the bottom of the slide provides U.S. and international earnings as well as realized margins.</p>
          <p>Now let's move to slide 9 which shows year-over-year variances for other segments. Results in our Midstream segment were $77 million, 46 million lower this quarter compared to a year ago. The decrease is primarily due to an $88 million gain on shares issued by a subsidiary of DCP Midstream in the first quarter of 2009, partially offset by improved margins due to higher NGL prices this quarter.</p>
          <p>Our 50% share of CPChem generated $110 million this quarter, 87 million higher than the first quarter of 2009 due to higher ethylene and benzene margins. Finally, LUKOIL's earnings were improved 379 million compared to the same quarter last year, partly as a result of the restatement due to lag reporting.</p>
          <p>As we disclosed on our Analyst Day, beginning in January of 2010, we changed the method we used to determine our equity share of LUKOIL's earnings. Under this new method, the company records our equity share of LUKOIL's actual earnings on a one quarter lag basis, rather than using the earnings estimate for the current quarter. Prior periods have been recast to reflect this change. Corporate expenses were 310 million after tax for the quarter compared to 259 million last year. The increase is primarily due to increased interest expense and foreign currency losses.</p>
          <p>Turning to page 10, our return on capital employed and cash return on capital invested have improved each quarter since the beginning of 2009. This has been primarily driven by better earnings and cash flows resulting from higher commodity prices.</p>
          <p>So that completes my review of the first quarter 2010 earnings. What I'd like to do now is turn to an outlook comment on slide 11 before asking Jim to give us a few of his comments and then opening the phone for Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>So, first I'd like to provide some guidance on operating expectations for the second quarter and the remainder of the year. We'll begin with E&amp;P. Over the next couple of quarters, production is expected to be lower. Areas that will contribute to the decrease includes North American natural gas, Western North Slope and Prudhoe Bay due to seasonal maintenance and normal decline.</p>
          <p>We also have some planned shutdowns being conducted in Norway with Ekofisk and Eldfisk being down between 22 and 26 days. In the UK, Britannia and J-Block will be down 10 to 20 days and in Australia, Bayu-Undan and the Darwin L&amp;G facility will be down close to a month. As we said last quarter and during the analyst meeting, we're targeting 2010 production levels to be flat with 2008, normalizing for the impact of asset dispositions.</p>
          <p>New production is expected to partially offset these declines and will come from our ramp-up of Canadian Oil Sands, Bohai Bay, Australia, North America liquids and Gutter Gas 3.</p>
          <p>Regarding refining, we expect increases in utilization rates, especially internationally due to the restart of our Wilhelmshaven refinery and the completion of turnarounds at both MiRO and Melaka.</p>
          <p>In the United States, capacity is expected to improve given our expectations for higher refining margins. And as for the remainder of the year, we expect average quarterly turnaround costs of about 125 million pre-tax, in line with previously provided guidance.</p>
          <p>We continue to take steps to control costs while ensuring the safety of our employees, integrity of our assets and conducting planned maintenance at all our refineries. In 2009, we exceeded our cost reduction expectation target of 1.4 by reducing costs almost $2 billion and in 2010, we plan to achieve our cost savings of 400 million. At our March 24 Analyst Day, we provided details regarding our plans to enhance returns and outline our asset disposition program.</p>
          <p>We recently announced an agreement to sell our Syncrude interest to Sinopec for $4.650 billion pre-tax. The 2009 production and reserves associated with our interest in Syncrude was 23,000 BOE per day and almost 250 million BOE in reserves. Our expectation for the after-tax proceeds are in excess of $4 billion. This is an early estimate. Could possibly change on the completion of the final transaction. The government approval process is underway in both Canada and China, and we anticipate closing in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Data rooms for our North America asset disposition programs will be opened in the next couple of months. We've selected our financial advisors and expect closing for these packages to start in the second half of 2010. The buyer for our Conoco/Flying J Travel Centers has been selected. We estimate after-tax proceeds to be approximately $350 million. We're still waiting for the Federal Trade Commission's approval and hope to close midyear.</p>
          <p>And we've engaged Citibank as the adviser of our interest in the REX pipeline. We have 25% interest in REX pipeline and marketing efforts are expected to begin in the second quarter with closing of a potential transaction expected by year end 2010. We remain confident that we'll reach our $10 billion target for asset dispositions during 2011.</p>
          <p>Regarding the increase in shareholder distributions, in March we announced a quarterly dividend payment of $ 0.55 per share, a 10% increase over the previous rate. The dividend's payable June 1 to shareholders of record on May 24. And we started selling LUKOIL shares this month in small, open market transactions and commenced purchasing ConocoPhillips shares simultaneously. These amounts and the amount of LUKOIL shares sold and the amount ConocoPhillips bought will be disclosed in the upcoming 10-Q. As stated at the analyst meeting we expect to complete the sale of our half of LUKOIL equity during 2011.</p>
          <p>Moving to exploration, 2009 was a good year with discoveries at Browse basin and the Gulf of Mexico lower tertiary trend, as well as entries into several new areas. While we are constraining capital in some parts of our business, spending in exploration has remained fairly consistent which should strengthen our portfolio for future organic reserve replacement over time. In April, drilling and logging operations were completed on our Laurentian basin wildcat and the well was subsequently plugged and abandoned. The costs of the well incurred through March 31, are included in our first quarter financial results as dry hole expense. A significant amount of data was collected and is being analyzed and no decision has been made regarding any potential future activities in this area.</p>
          <p>Kronos in the Browse basin off the northwest coast of Australia is still drilling toward its planned target depth. Given the extensive coring, testing and analysis that is planned for this well, we are unlikely to have significant updates regarding the overall prospect for several weeks.</p>
          <p>In general, most of ConocoPhillips significant exploration wells will begin during the second half of this year. Some will reach their objectives in the fourth quarter while others will roll into 2011. For example, in the Gulf of Mexico, the Chevron operated Coronado prospect will start early in the third quarter and potentially conclude before year end.</p>
          <p>As mentioned at the analyst meeting, we expect the Tiber appraisal well could also spud prior to year end. In the Caspian, current plans are to spud the Rak More well in the third quarter and achieve TD by year end, and we expect Nursultan to follow some time in the second half of 2011.</p>
          <p>As for our Poland shale play, we expect to spud our initial which well in second quarter and China coalbed methane, we continue to drill and analyze cost in reservoir performance with results interpreted near the end of 2010 or early 2011. With regard to Eagle Ford, we are aggressively pursuing exploration and development opportunities based on the promising results we've encountered to date.</p>
          <p>Our APLNG project is moving forward as planned. APLNG reserves and resources are considered the best in the region and our upstream is making progress daily. Our target is to secure sales agreements to support two 4.5 million metric ton per annum trains. That concludes my comments and I will now ask for Jim for a few closing statements before we open the call for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Clayton, thank you. I appreciate all those who are participating in our conference call this morning. I thought it might be of help to spend a few moments and talk about some of the steps we're taking to create shareholder value and I refer to our March analyst meeting in New York when you heard me indicate that the opportunities set for profitable investments for the large international integrated majors has changed pretty dramatically in the last several years.</p>
          <p>You know, resource access is an issue as is fiscal take and commercial terms. The question for our company is how do we create value for our shareholders in this type of environment given the assets, the resources and the opportunities we already have in our existing portfolio. Our approach is not just to get bigger in upstream volumes but to ensure that we have better than cost of capital returns and not do projects that are at just cost of capital or have limited upside potential. We think the way to create shareholder value for our company is for us to convert our extensive resources into proven reserves and to do this at competitive metrics and while we will grow the absolute volumes in the latter period of our 5 and 10-year period of time of strategic plans, we are stressing to annually increase the procure metrics of reserves in production as we go through this period of time.</p>
          <p>Creating value means more and more focus on improving returns in the portfolio, strengthening the balance sheet with significant increases in distributions to our shareholders in the form of annual increases in dividends and share re-purchases. And we are executing on this plan, and we've seen support from our shareholders and the financial community.</p>
          <p>As Clayton said, we have reached agreement to sell our 9% in Syncrude, and that transaction along with the others that we have told the marketplace that we intend to sell will go a long way toward meeting our $10 billion disposition objective.</p>
          <p>There are very difficult decisions for our company regarding participation in the Yanbu and Shah project, but we believe the decisions that we made were consistent with the execution of our plan. Clayton also said we have commenced sale of a portion of our LUKOIL shares and simultaneously we have started the purchase of ConocoPhillips shares. We're doing this in rather modest amounts and doing this in an appropriate way.</p>
          <p>Capital spending is being constrained to doing our highest return projects while deferring some of the other projects that we may be doing at a later point in time when we can improve the metrics associated with those opportunities. We expect to accomplish our debt and balance sheet objectives really by the end of this year so things are going quite well in that regard. So those are the comments I would like to make, Clayton, and I think it's probably time now we open this up for questions from those participating in our conference call. Clayton?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. So Chris, could you line up for questions for us, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question comes from the line of Doug Terreson of ISI. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, execution on the return enhancement plan has obviously been positive thus far, especially with the recent decisions on Yanbu and Shah, I think underscoring your commitment to higher returns. And on this point, if free cash flow continues to rise by a billion dollars plus per quarter and proceeds from Syncrude and Flying J exceed 4 billion, then the cash position is going to build significantly in Q2 and Q3 of 2010.</p>
          <p>So you've talked about &#x2013; you just mentioned debt and equity reduction as clearly being priorities, and things like the equity reduction component, share re-purchases have already commenced and so could you talk about how you plan to segment the 2? Is debt reduction necessarily more important than equity reduction? How are you guys thinking about that part of the plan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good, thank you. First, what I'd like to say is yes, the cash generation looked quite positive. We're quite pleased with the slow development of the economy around the world and that can be helpful to our businesses. And we're executing on our plan. With respect to our investment opportunities, I would say that there's a likelihood that our capital program would be more than $11 billion, but maybe closer to around $12 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We want to do our very best projects so we might see a little bit of expansion in our capital spending this year, but maybe in the neighborhood of about $1 billion. When we talked about our debt reduction, that will come primarily through some cash flow from operations, but also asset dispositions. We see the debt taking it down into the low $20 billion levels. It could be somewhere between 21, $23 billion, somewhere in there.</p>
          <p>The cost of the debt is certainly very manageable. The debt ratios will be coming down closer toward 20%, so somewhere in the low 20s, we think we've done all we need to do on debt reduction. Don't need to do any more than that. It doesn't have to go to 20 billion, but the low 20s somewhere.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, with the cash coming along, developing quite nicely and funding the capital opportunities in the company, we see annual increases in dividends and we have already increased the dividend this year and so the additional cash will go towards share re-purchase. That's really what the plans are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and Jim one more question on E&amp;P. Norway has always been a significant, steady performer for you guys and on this point, there seems to be a movement on new investment phases which will probably extend the life of that position in a financially attractive way. Could you provide a little color on activities in that area and updated expectations for your position in Norway in E&amp;P?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as you know, we have already rebuilt Ekofisk a second time. We're looking at doing Eldfisk and extending the opportunities of capturing more out of the fields associated with the Ekofisk greater area. It's a field that's already gone for about 40 years and it's going to go for another 40, 50 years, so it's just a great opportunity for us.</p>
          <p>Every time we can capture another 1%, it's in the neighborhood of like a find of about 100 million barrels oil equivalent. That's on a gross basis. We are working our plan so that we are going to be redeveloping and redoing Eldfisk and Ekofisk a great opportunity for us because it has very good returns and the fiscal environment has been very consistent and steady. So we're going to do this another time again in Norway; so we he have really a great presence there and we look forward to 2, 3, 4 more decades in Norway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Jason Gammel of Macquarie. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, guys. I just wanted to ask you about some of the activity onshore in North America. You are seeing very strong liquids production coming out of both your Bakken and Eagle Ford acreage. Jim, you had mentioned there was a potential to expand the capital program a little bit this year. Would that be an area you that might want to pick up activity levels from the current 3 rigs or so that you're running?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, absolutely. When I talk about some expansion in our capital program from 11.2 maybe closer to 12 billion, a lot of that will go toward those types of projects. So we're very pleased with our position that we have, and yes, that would be an area we'd direct more capital towards.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Terrific.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I want to give you some background on that, Jason. Bakken first quarter produced 32,000 a day of oil. Permian, we produced quite a bit of liquid there, that's 31,000 a day. And people are surprised that San Juan actually produces liquids. We have 45,000 a day of NGLs out of San Juan. So those are our core liquid producing areas in the lower 48, with those 3 representing about 70% of our lower 48 liquids production of around &#x2013; I don't know, 150 or 160,000 a day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Terrific. Maybe one more if I could, guys. On Wilhelmshaven, I think you mentioned that it is currently operating &#x2013; is it operating on what you consider normal utilization rates, and have you done anything to lock in margins in Germany at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we had Wilhelmshaven shut down for maintenance and then for market reasons shut down for the whole first quarter and we're looking at the potentially the hyper skimming margins and we look &#x2013; and we have to make these decisions weeks in the past. We felt it was an opportunity for us to start Wilhelmshaven up. We have in the hyper skimming margins backed off pretty dramatically. So I don't think you can expect that we're going to continue to operate Wilhelmshaven in the current market environment.</p>
          <p>It also gives us an opportunity to talk about Wilhelmshaven. Of course this is a decision in front of us. We are evaluating every single alternative with respect to what we should and will do with Wilhelmshaven, and I think you'll hear more from us as we go through this year on Wilhelmshaven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Doug Leggate of Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please proceed</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, fellas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of questions. On the exploration expenditure, Clayton, I think in your prepared remarks you talked a little bit about some of the things you are going to be doing this year. Exploration expenditure fell off a little bit in the U.S. or at least the expense did a little bit. Can you just guide us toward how we should be expecting the split between U.S. and international and maybe a little bit more in the activity levels and what is basically going on in the first quarter in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think guidance remains the same, Doug at $1.3 billion for the year in exploration. I have to get back to you on a U.S./International split but that shouldn't be a problem. I think a lot of our exploration activity is expected during the second half of 2010, and that's &#x2013; that may have been what was behind the kind of coming in below what was &#x2013; what guidance would have suggested.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I guess the only other one I have is kind of an accounting question related to tax. As you shifted your capital toward liquids in the lower 48, it looks like you're getting some tax benefits from mix effects. Can you maybe talk a little bit about &#x2013; last year your run rate was running in the low 50s and if we're going to see a more permanent shift to a lower level of run rate taxes, if you can talk a little bit to that from Q1 and as we go forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Effective tax rate was lower this quarter due to the higher proportion of income from, you know, areas with lower tax jurisdiction so it'd be lower 48 and Canada had earnings improvements so therefore, you saw reduction in the effective tax rates. E&amp;P tax rates fell from 60% in the first quarter of '09 to 51% in the first quarter of '10.</p>
          <p>Does that help? Is that what you're looking for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Is that largely the U.S. mix effects, Clayton?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So we would expect that kind of run rate to continue so long as we continue to see the liquids do well in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess that's right. As long as you're seeing &#x2013; really, I think the impact on the reduction in effective tax rate came from improvement in, you know in liquids prices also. Natural gas prices were slightly higher than they were a year ago so lower 48 just had a much better quarter this quarter than a year ago and I think that was the big reason behind it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Arjun Murti of Goldman Sachs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. You mentioned the APLNG projects progressing. Do you have an update on what the timing might be on signing up the sales contracts there for buyers of the gas?</p>
          <p>And on a related question, do you think it makes sense for, I think it's 3 or 4 projects down there; yours is the largest, but 3 or 4 projects to be combined, or is that for any number of reasons not practical and so they will be sort of forced in to loan developments in that area?</p>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Arjun, thank you. On APLNG we said our objective is this year is to sign MOUs with gas purchasers to take 2 large trains in total, 4.5 million metric tons each train. Get these MOUs signed this year. We're working very hard on this. It's a priority objective of the company because this is so important to the investment and the value creation of APLNG. And we think we're making progress but of course, it remains that we got to demonstrate and get those MOUs signed as we go through this year and just want to make sure that we pass along, as we said, that's our intent, our objective.</p>
          <p>In terms and for competitive reasons, really rather not go into specifically who and how we intend to do this, but we're working and have been for quite some period of time. It would be directed towards, obviously, the Asian markets.</p>
          <p>The 3 or 4 projects in Queensland will obviously &#x2013; there are different kinds of projects in terms of participation by the many different companies. Our view is the way that we really need to be looking at it is collaboration. How can we work together, not necessarily changing ownership or anything like that but how can we collaborate to more efficiently execute our capital spending in the projects as many of us are doing these at the same time as you're aware.</p>
          <p>We can do this with respect to how we gather pipelines from the upstream part, how we can be working in terms of the liquefaction facilities, shipping, all of that. But particularly at Gladstone, how do we build the liquefaction facilities and so we've had discussions with the other participants on other projects. And it's difficult, but on the other hand we know that this make a lot of sense for all of us so as to execute well with respect to capital spending and schedule.</p>
          <p>We know that Queensland and the federal government want to see collaboration, and so we're very open to it. It's difficult to do, but I think you are going to see collaboration, and we're quite willing to do this in a way that, you know, creates value for everyone.</p>
          <p>It's not just the participants of the project but also for the government as well. And they also know that it has impact with respect to availability of labor and the contractors. So it's important to do this well. And so we're very open to collaboration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see, Jim. It sounds like the collaboration is more on coordinating the CapEx and labor as opposed to necessarily reducing the number of actual LNG sites and/or coordinating the gas purchase contracts or the gas sales contracts from your perspective. It's more the labor and CapEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's more collaboration of how we do the capital spend. With respect to coordination on the sale of LNG, I don't think &#x2013; each company will do their own thing. That's what's been happening. In terms of whether there's a possibility of sharing the train or something like that I guess that's possible in collaboration, but that doesn't necessarily change in terms of ownership or participation and what each company may be doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great, and then totally unrelated question, I appreciate the Bakken and Eagle Ford well data in the press release which is nice to see. The 2,000 barrels a day from a well certainly seems like a very solid, if not high, number. Can you comment on whether that's a dual lateral well, or it's certainly a much higher flow rate than I think some other companies are reporting?</p>
          <p>And then to the extent you can say, is that a 30-day initial production rate of 2,000 barrels a day, a single day, or for any other period of time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Arjun, we're going to have to come back to you on that specifically. I know on these wells, I'll just say generically, I think the 4, 5 million cubic feet a day of gas and then liquids, it's somewhere between 1,000 and 2,000 barrels a day. It varies by well, but that's sort of what we've been experiencing in our early wells. We put them down with experience better all the time, completion techniques get better all the time. I think we'll come back to and you tell you how that's done. They're long distance multilateral wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we've talked, we're going to provide more granularity on this part of our business in the future, Arjun. And I appreciate your interest in this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great and we look forward it that. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Jacques Rousseau of RBC. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about that Jacques.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No problem. Good morning. I just wanted to follow up on the share repurchase program. At your analyst meeting there was a slide that pointed towards $6 billion in 2010 and $6 billion in 2011 of buybacks and you know, I assume most of this will happen in the second half of the year as your asset sale program kicks in. My question is, do you think there will be upside to that program given that your asset sale program is off to a pretty good start?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I go back to share re-purchase and the first question that came from Doug Terreson. Our share repurchase is tied to the sale of our 10% of LUKOIL. Let me just say for market purposes, let's say that's around $5 billion. So as we sell our LUKOIL shares in the marketplace and we buy ConocoPhillips shares, there's 5 billion there. But Doug Terreson asked, he said, well, it looks like there's going to be more free cash flow after you fund your capital spending program and your dividends and you already get debt reduction going toward share repurchase, and for illustrative purposes, using consensus numbers when we had our March analyst meeting, it showed that there was in the neighborhood of about $12 billion we said, about 6 billion each year for share repurchase.</p>
          <p>That's kind of the plan. To the extent how that materializes a little bit more, a little bit less, it's going to depend upon not so much, we'll meet our debt objectives and annual increases and dividends. It's going to be does the marketplace develop the commodity prices like we would expect. So the flywheel then would be share repurchase</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Paul Cheng of Barclay's Capital. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A number of quick questions. Clayton, earlier you were talking about the E&amp;P tax rate. I understand how the overall division tax may change because of the stronger result of the U.S. How about in the international? In 2009 you were roughly about in the 67% or so; in the first quarter it was around 59%. I don't think that may be changing between the gas and liquids so is there any particular thing that we should be aware and if that 59% on the international, is a good proxy going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know. I'm going to have to get back to you on that, Paul. I just don't know. Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I presume that on Bakken and Eagle Ford that in terms of, say, what is the per well total resource recovery or the total development cost and more detailed information that we will have to wait until that you can come back to us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We're early days on the development at Eagle Ford. Bakken, we've been there quite a while, but as far as the reserves in each of those areas or the production growth that we expect to see, I would expect us to provide more of that type of information later this year. Just too early to say right now with Eagle Ford with where we are and I think, you know, the development plans around Bakken are coming together. So stay tuned on those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Two other questions. One, Jim, you guys are going to redevelop the Ekofisk, any kind of rough cost estimate, how much is that going to be on that redevelopment on a per-barrel basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'd have to &#x2013; I thought we indicated that at our March analyst meeting. Maybe we didn't. I would assume that the development costs are somewhere probably in the mid-teens. The rates of return are well in excess of cost of capital, and that means rates of return, probably, in excess of mid-teen returns.  So that's what we're really looking at in terms of money to be spent on redoing Eldfisk as well as some of the satellite fields and going and continuing to replacement wells to recover more of Ekofisk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, should we assume the portion would be FID this year so you can book reserves this year or it's going to be a mixed year event?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't have it. I think that's a later period in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not going to be this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I could be wrong on that, but we'll check that out, but something tells me it's not this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Final one. On page 10 on the presentation that you gave the return on capital employed for the last several quarters. Clayton, do you have a rough estimate that between the first quarter 2009 through first quarter 2010 the 5% improvement, how much is related to  market condition?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Most of it is. The majority of the improvement comes from higher oil prices and better gas prices. You know there is some cost reduction, but the majority of the improvement comes from better earnings, from higher prices. Capital employed has moved up a little bit. One of the ways that we're going to improve ROCE is slow down the growth of capital employed. In fact, parts of our business, we're going to see capital employed fall as we invest less than DD&amp;A. The majority between first quarter of '09 and first quarter of '10 is due to commodity price improvements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that's true, but I think also, Clayton, we've done a nice job on managing and constraining our costs. It's quite a challenge as we go forward. As Clayton said, we expect I think about 4, $500 million of lower costs this year than what we actually achieved in all of last year in absolute terms. The challenge is whether it's currency or it's suppliers and contractors, is they're coming at the industry pretty hard and so to hold on, to more than hold on to what we've already accomplished last year is quite a challenge, but that's why we think we're doing pretty well as we've gone so far this year. And that helps with respect to returns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll follow up with you on that one, Paul just to make sure &#x2013; to give you the breakout between the self-help and what came from market help.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Mark Gilman. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Guys, good morning. One operationally oriented question, if I could, and then one relating to Yanbu and Shah. Operationally, any shut-in gas volumes in the U.S. and Canada underlying the first quarter production in either of those areas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a little bit, Mark. There's some stuff that was not brought back on the first quarter due to some severe weather, but it's less than 5 a day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Essentially first quarter gas volumes, both countries, you know, at field capacity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>90, you know, call it- 98%, but I think there's somewhere around 30,000 MCF a day that didn't come back on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So small.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On Shah and Yanbu, can I safely assume that your feasibility studies indicated returns below cost of capital levels, and can you give me any idea where your feasibility study indicated the comparative return between the two, one greater than the other, one less than the other? Any clarification on that would be helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very different projects, and of course, people can argue why there's a cost of capital within one firm or another. As you know, Mark, people can say the cost of capital is technically if you look at cost of debt, whatever is in single digits. Then you can look at what you must provide and have provided to your shareholders and you get into double digits but what is the cost of capital?</p>
          <p>Very different kinds of projects. Have different risks associated with them and even though the numbers may be where one looks higher than the other, they have a different risk/reward profile. So I think it's really for many different reasons, not appropriate for us to get too involved into how we analyze the projects and which one might have been ahead of the other. The important thing is that we worked this very, very hard for several years with both ADNOC and with Saudi Aramco and we did this, always with the best of intentions and we just felt that given the direction of our company it was important for us, these decisions are consistent with emphasizing returns over growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Neil McMahon of Sanford Bernstein. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Neil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's an interesting pronunciation. But anyway, Neil McMahon from Sanford Bernstein. Two things, one basically around the Arctic. The first one is really on the Chukchi Sea well and how contingent is the drilling of this well on rig availability with Shell? Because they were undecided what they were going to drill first between their Beaufort Sea and Chukchi Sea.</p>
          <p>And secondly, just on the Alaskan pipeline, it's obviously an absolutely huge project and sort of needs to get off the ground pretty quickly given the construction timing and with the 2 competing projects with yourself and BP versus sort of Exxon proposal, can you give us an update on that because it seems to have stalled somewhat in recent times?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't I try Chukchi and give Alaska pipeline to Jim. We've had a couple special interest groups bringing some lawsuits up in Alaska and even though the Department of Interior affirmed the 2008 sale in late March, we still have a &#x2013; there's a time for public comment through the early part of May, and then we expect a final court decision around our ability to drill Devil's Paw in late 2010. So we're doing some progression around drilling the exploration well but we don't see that happening before 2012. And then just kind of an add-on Chukchi, in January, we exchanged about 25% working interest on 50 of those leases for some lower tertiary leases in the Gulf of Mexico and some cash consideration. Does that help you with Chukchi? Or is there anything else on that one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's fine. Just getting some timing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah it's 2012 at the earliest and then maybe Jim on Denali.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Neil, good morning. We're with BP in the Denali project. You know, the Alaska gas pipeline, they filed an open season in early April with FERC and that's in an open season and it remains to be seen whether our company we participate and how. Denali, while we anticipate FERC approval to go forward with our open season, we're expecting doing this in July, I believe, of this year and that's going to last for about 90 days or so and we'll simultaneously do the same open season in Canada. And really the decisions for the companies to participate in the open season for the 2 competing projects will be made by our company as we go through the next several months.</p>
          <p>I do expect, though, that the open season for both of the projects would probably have rather conditional participation or acceptances because we really don't know with any certainty what really are not only the commercial but the fiscal rules and regulations associated with the pipelines so this is a process that's going to go for the remainder, a good share of this year and so I think we just wait and see as we go through these months. We'll give you more information as it develops.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Jim, are there any ongoing discussions with Exxon Mobil around this at all, and feasibly, can you have 2 projects coming out of this, or one is eventually going to win?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, first, both projects are going at the same time. Not really discussion between the 2. It's a very upfront competition between Denali and the other competing project. Obviously when executed, it will be 1 project not 2. How that comes together remains to be seen.</p>
          <p>And then the other thing is that we can't underestimate the challenge with respect to the costs. The execution of the project &#x2013; the cost is, I can't recall exactly but it's probably somewhere between 30 and $40 billion. As I said what are the fiscal terms and certainties associated with that and we also, I know, you start a project like this, it's 10, 12 years before first cash flow and you got to be looking out what you think the marketplace is going to look like. And of course, that marketplace has changed pretty dramatically over the last 3 to 5 years. So a lot of really challenging significant decisions need to be made before this type of project goes forward and executed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Ed Westlake of Credit Suisse. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Just on refining and CapEx. You are saying you are evaluating every alternative for Wilhelmshaven. Can you just confirm now that you've walked away from Yanbu that you're not going to turn that into a fully operated refinery by spending money? And then on the U.S. refining, obviously the economic recovery and data was improving, are you seeing any more interest in the potential purchase of your refinery assets? It probably feels a bit early and can you comment a little bit on the progress you're making in terms of the $500 million of organic program to improve downstream returns?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, first on Wilhelmshaven, when I say we'll evaluate all opportunities, obviously, one of the opportunities is to go forward and do a full-scale upgrade of Wilhelmshaven. That's not really a realistic alternative. What we're looking at is all the way from shutdown and writing off to how can we bring in a partner, how we can participate, how we could dispose, but the plan is not consistent with the execution of our plan and emphasis on returns to spend billions of dollars to do a full-scale upgrade.</p>
          <p>In terms of interest in the downstream opportunities for disposition of sale of refineries or assets, well, I think we &#x2013; it looks like &#x2013; not directed to ourselves necessarily, but it looks like some of the assets are being moved or sold from one owner to another owner and that's good to see in the marketplace, but I think it is good to see that the market is recovering some, returns in the downstream and we'd expect that to occur with the strength in the economy, some rationalization of smaller, less sophisticated refineries. It will give us opportunities to move on our portfolio, possibly a little sooner than what we said in our March analyst meeting. So that remains to be seen, but it's encouraging to see what's taking place, and then I think the last was, yeah &#x2013; how are we doing on our $500 million cost reduction program that was outlined in the March Analyst Day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, it was business improvement, I think, is the way Willie characterized it, and that was focused not only on cost reduction. I think there's 100 or a couple hundred million dollars of cost reductions in refining, but it's also looking at how to optimize these facilities. There's some things that we can do within the portfolio. If there are capital avoidance opportunities for us, and I would say those are moving forward. Actually, our operating expenses were down about $100 million sequentially. A big part of that was turnarounds, but I know that Willie and the downstream guys are focusing on trying, looking at every refinery every day on continuous optimization of what they have, and then maybe there are some portfolio things that we can do that would help us as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps one follow-up on healthcare costs just because you have seen obviously a charge taken at Exxon. Where is the status with respect to your own healthcare costs, any adjustments for legislation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It's hard for me to &#x2013; I'm not as well versed in all of how to explain this. But essentially, the either incentive or &#x2013; that was available, we didn't do and so essentially our programs are consistent with the way other companies are changing or adapting to. We did this some time in the past so we don't have charges up front as adopting or adapting or to the new rules.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't expect a significant increase in costs associated with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not for the implementation of the new healthcare proposals. On the other hand, there's no doubt that the cost of healthcare has continued to be a real challenge. I'm not saying that's not a challenge, but the implementation of the new healthcare proposals passed has not resulted in an upfront charge for our company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Blake Fernandez. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning. My question is on the divestiture program. The Syncrude transaction price was quite impressive. I think probably well above what most people were expecting. I'm just curious if that changes your thinking with regard to the $10 billion target. Any thoughts on potentially either increasing that or potentially exposing fewer assets to the market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It doesn't change our objective of $10 billion. Potentially, it could be more; it could be less. We're really thinking about $10 billion. What's good about the 9% sale of Syncrude is, yes, we're quite pleased with the price, but if you look at the metrics of assumptions going forward and oil prices and discount rates, you get to that kind of, to that number.</p>
          <p>What is our objective? Our objective is to define the assets that aren't that strategic to our company that we can sell at a very favorable price that's tax efficient. And to the extent that we do that well, then we minimize the amount of assets that we need to sell and we can retain in the portfolio. And quite frankly what we're trying to do is get the maximum for whatever we sell to minimize the impact in terms of our E&amp;P portfolio.</p>
          <p>Obviously oil assets are more of interest than our natural gas assets. So to the extent that we do each asset disposition well, that takes off the pressure with respect to reaching the $10 billion program of what we ultimately need to be selling. On the other hand, if you look back over the last several years we haven't done too much in the way of dispositions and if you look at the size of our company and portfolio, we should be pruning and doing a couple billion dollars of asset dispositions every year by saying what no longer is that strategic, maybe a little bit more mature that is more valuable to someone else. It's tax efficient and we can sell it and redeploy the funds to upgrade the portfolio is something we should be doing every year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you for the comprehensive answer there, Jim. And then just the final question for me. Clayton, you had mentioned the Eagle Ford and aggressively pursuing that. I just wanted to confirm. I assume that means not only increasing the drilling program there, but also potentially adding to acreage in the area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think that acreage addition makes sense for us at the kinds of prices that we're seeing for acreage. I think my comments on aggressively pursuing around Eagle Ford had more to do with adding a number of rigs and number of wells drilled and the amount of capital and expense we were going to invest in that business. But I don't see our acreage in Eagle Ford increasing, but Jim, I don't know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's the work activity associated with the 240,000 acres that that we should get a really good opportunity to really go after it. That's where we're going to allocate and spend more money. We got into Eagle Ford a couple years ago and purchased and got the acreage at a very reasonable price. We look at the prices now of many of these plays, and frankly, it's hard to show that what people are paying, you can see a reasonable return. Maybe that changes in the future, but our allocation of capital and spend is more to get out of what we already have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the clarification.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That concludes our Q&amp;A session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Why don't I just take a second and close up. Again, thanks, everybody for participating. You'll find this information on our website and certainly, Vladimir and I are available for follow-up questions. Thank you, again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may now disconnect. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>