<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1184758" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-10-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1165</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Gary Russell, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James J. Mulva, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Robert Kessler</participant>
      <participant id="4">James Mulva</participant>
      <participant id="5">Paul Sankey</participant>
      <participant id="6">John Carrig</participant>
      <participant id="7">Sigmund Cornelius</participant>
      <participant id="8">Gary Russell</participant>
      <participant id="9">Paul Cheng</participant>
      <participant id="10">Michael LaMotte</participant>
      <participant id="11">Erik Mielke</participant>
      <participant id="12">Mark Gilman</participant>
      <participant id="13">Neil McMahon</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the ConocoPhillips Third Quarter 2008 Earnings Conference Call. My name is Jen and I will be your coordinator for today. At this time, all participants are in listen-only mode. We will be facilitating a question and answer session towards the end of today's conference. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the presentation over to your host for today's conference, Mr. Gary Russell, General Manager of Investor Relations. Please proceed sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Jen, and welcome to everybody on the call this morning to the third quarter conference call for ConocoPhillips. Joining me today is Jim Mulva, our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer; John Carrig, our President and Chief Operating Officer and Sig Cornelius, our Senior Vice President of Finance and Chief Financial Officer. The slide presentation that Jim Mulva will take you through today is intended to help you with your understanding of our financial and operating performance in the third quarter. And you can find this presentation on our website conocophillips.com.</p>
          <p>If you turn to page two with me now, you'll find our typical cautionary statement. That cautionary statement basically says that we will be making forward-looking statements in our presentation today along with responses to your questions and those forward-looking statements include our current view of expectations. Actual results can differ materially from what those expectations are; you can find those items that might cause expectations to be different than actual results in our SEC filings.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Jim Mulva.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Gary, thank you and good morning. Welcome to our conference call. I am going down right to Page 3 of our presentation, and as we normally do, we'll go through these slides.</p>
          <p>You can see in the third quarter our income was $5.2 billion which is $3.39 a share. We generated 7.5 billion of cash from operations, so our debt-to-capital ratio remained unchanged at 19%. Now in our upstream business we produced 2.17 million BOE a day and that includes 422,000 BOE per day from our LUKOIL investment segment. In downstream, our refinery utilization rate was 87%. That's down from last quarter and it's primarily due to the hurricane impacts.</p>
          <p>We purchased 2.5 billion of our stock in the third quarter and that reduced our average shares outstanding to 1.528 billion shares, 116 million shares lower than the prior quarter average. That's 116 million shares lower than the third quarter 2007 average.  And we are pretty pleased with our strong operating performance when you give consideration to the negative impacts from the Gulf Coast hurricanes in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>So I am moving now on to page 4 of the presentation, total company net income, and you can see that third quarter net income of 5.2 billion was 251 million lower than the prior quarter which was 5.4 billion. And that's shown on the gold bar on the left hand side of the chart. So you move from the left to the right you can see our contribution from asset rationalizations in the third quarter is 129 million higher than the second quarter and then we had prices, margins and other marketing impacts reduced third quarter income 13 million.</p>
          <p>We had lower volumes primarily from LUKOIL and refining marketing segments, and that reduced income 232 million. I'll talk more about this when we go through the individual segments. There were a number of other items that in the aggregate had a negative impact 135 million and that's going to be covered more in subsequent slides.</p>
          <p>So I will now go to the fifth slide, which is total company cash flow and you start on the left, gold bar, you can see that in the third quarter we generated 7.5 billion of cash from operations. It shows you that, along with our cash balance at start of the quarter, 787 million, we had 8.3 billion in cash which is available for use during the third quarter. So you move from left to right in the slide you can see how we used cash which was 4 billion for our capital program, 710 million in dividends; we purchased about 2.5 billion of our shares. We ended cash balance in the quarter of 1.1 billion.</p>
          <p>So I am moving to Slide 6, which is our total company cash flow for the first nine months of the year and you can see the pie chart on the left. Total cash available for the first three quarters was 20.8 billion, of which 19.5 billion or 94% was generated from operations; 1.3 billion or 6% mainly came from a combination of a slight amount at debt increase and proceeds from asset sales. And then if you look at the pie chart on the right you would see how we used the 20.8 billion. We spent 11.2 billion on our capital program. We purchased 7.5 billion of our stock and paid 2.2 billion in dividends.</p>
          <p>Now, I am moving on to Slide 7. Start talking about exploration and production, and as you are aware, we experienced both lower crude oil and natural gas prices in the third quarter. Our realized crude oil price in the third quarter was $112.19 a barrel or $5.82 a barrel lower than the second quarter. Our realized natural gas price was $8.91 per Mcf, and that's $0.96 per Mcf lower the prior quarter. And this is consistent with our previous guidance &#x2013; and as well as in our previous guidance our production volumes were similar to the last quarter and we're going to go through that in the next slide, which is page eight.</p>
          <p>Third quarter production from the E&amp;P segment about 1.75 million BOE a day, which is basically flat from the second quarter, as we progress from the left hand side of the slide to the right. Although our production was basically flat during the third quarter, we had some variances which were positive and some that were down.</p>
          <p>Starting with the red bar on the left, you can see that production was 29,000 BOE a day lower in Alaska, and this is primarily due to planned downtime and seasonality that we experience normally in this time of the year. And further moving to the right, our production in the Lower 48 was down 22,000 BOE a day and that's primarily due to the impact from the hurricanes. Norway, our production was 19,000 BOE a day higher, and that's mainly from the startup of our participation in the Alvheim field. In Russia, production was up 15,000 BOE a day and that's due to the startup of the YK field in the Timan-Pechora area up in Siberia.  In addition, the production in Canada was 13,000 BOE a day higher due to lower planned downtime.</p>
          <p>Now, it's important to note that even though production was higher in the UK due to the startup of the Britannia satellites field, that benefit was offset by planned and non-planned downtime and normal field decline. So when you add to this 1.75 million BOE a day which is our E&amp;P segment and you add the equity share of LUKOIL's production, then our total company production totaled 2.17 million BOE a day in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>I am moving on to Slide 9, talking about E&amp;P net income. Our income in third quarter was 3.9 billion compared to about 4 billion in the second quarter which is shown on the bar on the left. So, you move from the left to the right, contribution from assets sales increased income 126 million and prices and other marketing impacts reduced income 250 million when you compare third quarter to second quarter. Income was also improved 41 million compared to the previous quarter as a result of just the impact of regional mix and divergence of effective tax rates on sales volumes. And then there were other items which improved earnings at 13 million, this includes positive impacts from foreign exchange and production taxes. That's offset partially by higher DD&amp;A and operating costs as well as adjustments in abandonment obligations.</p>
          <p>So, now I am going to move from the upstream to the downstream part of the company on Slide 10. Our global realized marketing margins were higher in the third quarter. In the United States, the realized margin was $3.56 a barrel. Now that's up $2.33 a barrel from the second quarter and internationally $9.90 a barrel which is up $0.85 a barrel compared to the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Now in the U.S., the realized refining margin in the third quarter was $9.03 a barrel. That's $1.26 a barrel lower than the previous quarter. And the benefit from &#x2013; again the benefit from higher clean product yields and improved margin for secondary products, but that was more than offset by the narrowing of the heavy crude oil differentials and inventory impacts related to the decrease in crude and refined product prices. And then in addition, our ability to capture the higher Gulf Coast refining margin was impacted by the downtime in certain of our refineries associated with the hurricanes.</p>
          <p>Now turning to international, our realized refining margin was $11.24 a barrel. Now that's $4.54 a barrel higher than the previous quarter and that's due to reduction in temporary inventory builds and we had better clean product yields. International margins continued to be though negatively impacted by poor hydroskimming margins associated with primarily our Wilhelmshaven refinery.</p>
          <p>The domestic refining crude oil capacity utilization in third quarter was 90%. That's 4% down from the second quarter and that's primarily due to the hurricane impacts. And that impact was approximately 6% and was partially offset by lower turnaround activity. Now in the international crude oil capacity utilization was 75%. That's down from 88% in the prior quarter. That's due to the weak hydroskimming margins continued to impact the utilization at the company's Wilhelmshaven refinery. We didn't run the Wilhelmshaven refinery at all time periods through the third quarter because of the margins. That impacts utilization. So worldwide our refining marketing crude oil capacity utilization rate was 86% compared to 93% the prior quarter.</p>
          <p>I am going to go the next slide page 11 which is downstream net income. Our third quarter income was 849 million, which is 185 million higher than the second quarter which was 664 million. That's reflected in the gold bar on the left hand side of the chart. So you move from the left to the right, you can see that prices, margin, other market impacts improved the income 207 million. And this improvement is primarily attributed to higher global marketing margins. And as previously mentioned, reduced volumes mainly as result of the hurricanes negatively impacted income 128 million. So when compare quarter-to-quarter we did experience lower operating costs mainly due to the reduced turn around activity, and this increased income 77 million. And there were a lot of other items up in aggregate improved income by $29 million.</p>
          <p>Now I'm moving onto page 12, the other segments. For financial reporting, page 12, our estimate of the third quarter earnings from LUKOIL is 438 million. This is lower than the second quarter estimate of 774 million and that primarily due to lower volumes, prices, margin estimates. And the net true-up quarter-to-quarter was a positive 19 million. Now the income from our midstream business was 173 million; that compares to 162 million in the second quarter. It's due primarily to higher margins, marketing activity and offset somewhat by the hurricane impact.</p>
          <p>In the Chemicals segment, our joint venture contributed 46 million in income. That's higher than the prior quarter of 18 million and primarily due to a higher ethylene and polyethylene margins offset somewhat by the impact of the hurricanes. And our emerging businesses contributed 35 million in the third quarter. That compares to 8 million and the second quarter. That reflects primarily the higher spark spreads and foreign exchange impacts. And our corporate cost of 281 million or 95 million higher than the second quarter, primary the result of foreign exchange impact.</p>
          <p>So, now I'm going to move on to our metrics, E&amp;P and downstream on page 13. So, on page 13 it shows E&amp;P income and cash per BOE for the years 2003 through 2007. And by the way, when we show our peer group, what we are really looking at is competition against the five largest publicly traded companies, that's Shell and BP and Total and Chevron and Exxon.</p>
          <p>While we don't have peer data for third quarter obviously for 2008 because we're the first one reporting, when you look at the third quarter we would expect to be competitive on these metrics for E&amp;P, on an income and cash per BOE.</p>
          <p>Now I'm going to go to slide 14. We have the same peer group and looking at the metrics for downstream on an income and cash per barrel, it shows that for the years 2003 through 2007 that we expect to be competitive on both of these metrics as we look at the third quarter results,</p>
          <p>Now I'm going to go to slide 15. Again this shaded area is the same peer group: BP, Shell, Total, Exxon and Chevron. And you can see that it reflects that for return on capital employed that no adjustments are made for purchase accounting. The adjustments made to the peer group reflect purchase accounting for them is attached in Table 3. Our annualized ROCE for the third quarter of 2008 was 18%; that's compared to 17% for the first half.</p>
          <p>And then we'll go to last slide, 16, which is our outlook. We recently announced a plan to create long-term Australasian natural gas business with Origin, focused on coalbed methane production and liquefied natural gas processing and sales, and expect to close this here in the next week or so.</p>
          <p>And then we recently announced the signing of a MoU with KazMunayGas in Kazakhstan and Mubadala from Abu Dhabi to negotiate terms for exploration and production in the "N" Block, the Nursultan block offshore of Kazakhstan.  And this would be under a new subsoil use contract and this is a new major exploration presence for ConocoPhillips in Kazakhstan.</p>
          <p>In downstream, we received our government approval in early September. It's a key permit associated with expansion of the Wood River refinery. It's located at Roxana, Illinois and that's jointly owned by our company and EnCana.</p>
          <p>Then for the fourth quarter we anticipate the company's E&amp;P segment production will be higher in the fourth quarter than the third quarter. We expect our full year 2008 production to be slightly below 1.8 million BOE per day due to the impacts of the higher prices. In the first reporters of the year higher prices and their impact on production sharing volumes and we experienced production loss associated with the hurricanes in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>We expect our exploration expenses to be in the range of $400 million in the fourth quarter. Now in downstream fourth quarter our crude oil capacity utilization rate is expected to be in the mid 90% range; our turnaround costs are expected to be about 75 million before tax. Share repurchases have continued into the fourth quarter. Through the end of October we will have purchased about 8 billion in 2008 under our previously announced program. Stock repurchase levels for the balance of the year will depend on the market conditions that we see and our capital commitments and we are going to update the market in the early to mid part of December on the anticipated level of share repurchase that we expect for the remainder of the fourth quarter. And then along with that announcement we will announce what we have in mind for our 2009 capital program along with anticipated share repurchase plans for 2009.</p>
          <p>So, that completes the prepared remarks, Gary, and so I think we are ready now to take questions and comments from those participating in our conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Jen, go ahead and queue up the questions please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Robert Kessler with Simmons &amp; Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning Jim. I appreciate you are going to give us some more complete update in December in terms of your capital program and share buybacks, but it seems everyday anymore brings new volatility and a lot of shifting opportunities one would think in the balance between buybacks, organic investments and potential M&amp;A. I am curious if you could just give us perhaps some more qualitative comments at this point in terms of how you are thinking about the relative mix between those three buckets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well thank you. When we look at the marketplace, the business environment and the worldwide economy and the political situation, when we look at what we &#x2013; how we are going to manage through this difficult time period and the challenges just outlined, we are looking at not just the remainder of this year in November and December; we are already looking out for all 2009. So we are really looking at this 14 month time period. Obviously we look beyond 2009.</p>
          <p>So what we have done as a company, we are very pleased with adding new opportunities and I will just name a few of them, the Nursultan block that we expect to close later this year, the Shah sour gas large project that we are involved with in Abu Dhabi, and then the Origin joint venture in Australia. So, we have added quite a few new things to our already pretty substantial opportunity list of what we are going to be investing on over the next five years or so.</p>
          <p>So, as we look at this, first and foremost is that we want to maintain a really strong financial balance sheet position with flexibility and credit capability. Second, we want to fund those capital commitments and opportunities that we have as a company. So looking at what we have added and what we were already doing &#x2013; and I am not enumerating all the different things that you are very familiar with &#x2013; we expect that we will most likely have a capital program in 2009 that looks a lot like what we are going to experience in 2008 which is in the neighborhood of say $15 billion.</p>
          <p>And then after always maintaining a strong balance sheet and funding our capital program &#x2013; by the way when we fund our capital program we don't want to ever lose optionality, so there are some things just because of market conditions say drilling programs and all, because of the lower price environment that we see in North America, say Canada and the Lower 48, there are things that we can defer but we don't lose the optionality. So we are making all of this fit. So having maintained a strong balance sheet, funding our capital program through this down cycle, we like the discipline of annual increases in dividends. And then whatever the market gives us over and above all of those things then we will be considering buying our sales back in, because we like price that we see for buying shares in.</p>
          <p>So, that gives you hopefully the color of how we approach looking at things at not just November and December; it's what we look at between now and the end of 2009. And then, the other thing is is that we liked to have the fair degree of flexibility capability. There will be the opportunities to pick up some attractive acreage where we already have strong positions say in Canada and the Lower 48. We are not talking about large amounts, but there may be the opportunities for 1 or 2 or $300 million and we want to do that to really support our basic business not just today, but over the next number of years. So hopefully I've given you the color of how we approach the priority and the sequencing as we look through this challenging environment that we are managing through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Again thanks for the color and I appreciate the preliminary $15 billion number, kind of flat year-on-year. Any thoughts as to what kind of inflation or deflation as the case may be embedded into that figure so far?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we haven't really built it expectations of lower cost. So we are still using pretty strong inflation expectations for 2009 and subsequent periods. But we already &#x2013; we are starting to see the moderation inflation and some cost reduction in some of things that we procure and we are starting to see that there is maybe some softness in the rig rates. So that's not been built into our forecast, so to some extent you might view that as some upside. So that's how we've approached it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Paul Sankey with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jim and good morning guys. Jim, we've seen very weak demand over the past few weeks and I wondered just if you could just make any observations that you've got in that respect. Our concern is that demand is now so weak that we may get to  the point where we are at the cash cost of production for certain producers. Just from your perspective given your position in Alaska, given your position in the North Sea, perhaps also your view of LUKOIL in Russia; could you just talk a little bit about the &#x2013; what you think the cash cost is for you to produce in those regions and also you just referenced there but if you could talk a little bit more about the extent to which those costs will fall as the oil price falls. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, I thought you were headed first towards the downstream and then as the nature of your question it was more on the upstream side, but I am going to use the opportunity to first talk about the downstream. We watch very, very closely what is the cash cost associated with each barrel of production by each of our refineries. So obviously we will constrain production if in the refineries if we are not covering our cash cost; but we monitor this very closely certainly on a day-to-day basis. And at this point in time other than when we talk about Wilhelmshaven where we've cut back because of hydroskimming margins we've seen even though difficult times, we see positive cash margins in the downstream.</p>
          <p>In terms of the demand, obviously the demand is down around the world and you know all the statistics associated with that. In terms of upstream part of the company maybe John Carrig or Sig Cornelius could talk more about it, but we are watching our cash cost very, very closely but even with the levels of oil and gas prices that we see, we continue to see positive generation from all of our production. So I don't know, John, do you have anything &#x2013; or Sig &#x2013; more to comment on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have any specific numbers for you Paul. Jim went over the per barrel metrics and you can see the profitability associated with those as well as the cash costs and you can infer from that what the level of DD&amp;A is. But obviously the three big factors are perhaps for one, is the absolute price of the realized product; two, the tax level; three, the DD&amp;A; and four, the operating costs which were impacted by utility costs as well. And so as prices come down they do come down somewhat, but there are some costs that would be more fixed in nature. We do &#x2013; as Jim indicated there is some softness in rigs and tubular goods and we would hope to see that manifest itself particularly as &#x2013; if there was a extended downturn. But we will plan to provide more granularity on that probably in March but certainly as we progress.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, obviously when we talk about a $15 billion program, I think we go forward into 2009 we will not be as aggressive in our drilling programs in the Lower 48 and Canada. But we're not losing the optionality to ultimately drill those wells. Also we are looking at if we think that we're going to see cost come in &#x2013; lower cost &#x2013; the timing of that, both for the market standpoint, but also the cost of drilling those wells you could say well maybe some deferral makes some sense just from the cost side. So just want you to know how we approach looking at this. I don't know, Sig, if you had something you wanted to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No I really can't add any more than what's already been said by John, so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I guess guys what you are saying is, let's say we're at 70 or somewhat softer today, but around that level your entire portfolio is now cash positive and I guess what you telling me is that the operating costs are falling. Could you give me a sense of what percentage of the cost is the rigs? I mean I'm thinking that labor probably will be pretty sticky in terms of costs; I guess obviously the DD&amp;A for instance, will be sticky, but could you just give me a sense for the sensitivity to the various components?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really. I think maybe we could do that offline, we don't have, I don't have that immediately in front of me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul, what I would suggest take to look at the appendix in the presentation that we made in March at the Analyst meeting. And there is some pretty good information on cost and cash contribution by region and that's a pretty good place to start.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I guess &#x2013; I appreciate that Gary. You guy's disclosure is excellent. It's the sensitivity that we are really struggling with, but I take the point that we won't labor it. Jim, one thing you didn't mention if I could just briefly ask you, management change, you have made some shifts, can you just make any observations about that? And I'll leave it there, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we made changes, obviously I've got number of years to go as Chairman, CEO of the company and for personal reasons we've had several in our management team have decided to not work full time and so we just felt at this point time it made sense to make changes, piecemeal as we go through the next several years, so we put in place &#x2013; we like the idea of having a Chief Operating Officer in John Carrig and if you look at all the changes that we made, people are pretty familiar with having worked together in all of these areas. We think we've put a lot more focus &#x2013; not that we haven't in the past &#x2013; but there is more focus on basic operations of the company and cost discipline and everything and so we are pretty pleased with this, and by having a Chief Operating Officer we even put more focus on this during a period of time like this. And also the importance of relationships and all on projects that we are working on, so we put in place this team and I don't think you are going to see much change. You never know what's going to happen with respect to health issues or whatever, but everyone is healthy and so I don't think you are going to see much change over the next several years. We put it in place at this point in time and it's not piecemeal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Paul Cheng with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, gentlemen, several quick questions. Jim, when we are looking at &#x2013; thank you for giving us the priority of your cash use &#x2013; just want to as a follow-up given the current market condition, should we assume you will be willing to borrow money for share buyback or that that's really not out of the question that you want to live within your means?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you.  You said &#x2013; your last comment is really true.  We want to live within our means, which means, we look at our cash flow and we want to make sure that we are covering our capital program.  And we like as I said, not only dividend, but we like the discipline of annual increases in dividends.  So we start with that basic approach, live within our means.</p>
          <p>Now, we say with our balance sheet, our debt ratio is 20 to 25%.  We kind of like to keep it right in that area, but to the extent that we see less volatility, a little more certainty in terms of the marketplace both in terms of the environment of what we think oil prices and gas price, and crack spreads might look like as we go through the next 12 or 24 months.  And we see that the credit markets become more attractive.  Certainly at this point in time there is not much depth or size, and the cost doesn't make much sense to us to be in the public debt markets. To the extent that we see a more certainty or more probability what we think the environment looks like and the political situation and the credit markets, why then we can consider whether we would be interested in bringing our debt up somewhat to &#x2013; for share repurchase.  But until we see more certainty or probability, I think our concentration is to live within our means which is going to be a strong balance sheet, maintain liquidity, and cash position, and credit capacity; fund our capital program.  We like dividend increases.  And as to the extent that we see a better market price and better credit markets then we would consider taking leverage up and buying our shares.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Jim &#x2013; and given the current stock market and the bond market turmoil, stock market has dropped say by more than 20% in a matter of say weeks, should we assume there is any hit to your pension and correspondingly that you need to increase substantially your pension contribution, cash contribution or is there any hit on the P&amp;L related to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we do have already in mind that we will be putting more money into our pension fund.  And that will all &#x2013; it's already been factored into our operating plans that we are putting in place for 2009.  But it is not materially that different than what we've been doing over the last several years.  And we will update the financial community when we make our normal annual presentation, which I think is in, March?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  It's in March.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>March of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great.  And in the international E&amp;P operation, the effective tax rate is about 4% lower than the second quarter, is that just purely the production mix or there is any special adjustment we should be aware?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's the mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's just the mix?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And in the international, refining margin, I think Jim mentioned that you guys benefited from some inventory changes, can you quantify for us, how big is the benefit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the inventory changes are also a function of the realized cracks.  So, it's hard to, I mean you can segregate those out, but they are &#x2013; I think we have doubled &#x2013; the realized crack basically doubled or went up by $5 from 6 to 11 in the second &#x2013; from the second to the third quarter. Some of that was inventory, some of that the yields.  And it all factors into the margin.  So, clearly, there are certain inventory effects.  But they were largely impacts that were &#x2013; we suffered some in the second quarter and the inventory impacts were basically reversed in the third.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because, I mean, John if we are looking at even your own indicators, seems like the international margin was down sequentially, so it's a bit surprising that how strong it turn out to be, so we assume that the entire increase is really related to the inventory benefit or that is only a small portion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we would characterize it as relatively modest, the marketing margins that were better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, but I am talking about your realization in the refining margin in the international, was up $5 nearly and that if your benchmark indicator based on even your own benchmark indicator is down sequentially, so we are trying to reconcile what's causing this such a great margin realization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Once again, I think from our perspective in relative terms, we felt that the margin in the second quarter wasn't as good as it could be.  That was &#x2013; to some extent impacted offset when the third quarter showed up &#x2013; or the realized margin in the third quarter.  We can try to &#x2013; Gary can try to help you offline if there is more detail, Paul.  But, that's overall how we see it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great.  And final question, Origin, can you give us some kind of production outlook for the next two or three years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, production is going to be rather modest over the next several years, but we are going to update that when we announce &#x2013; well, when we announce doing the transaction, but you will get more of that in March.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Michael LaMotte with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Good morning, gentlemen.  Would you mind sharing with us your thoughts on financing for Origin, I guess, given the short-term nature of the commitment you'll borrow against your existing credit lines, but in light of what's going on in the broader credit markets, I just was curious as to what the long-term financing might look like?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've already essentially arranged all the financing for Origin and so we have the cash on hand.  We have several billion dollars in commercial paper that we use and we have a strong A1/P1 rating and access to the marketplace is good.  And so, we don't like the long-term markets at this point in time.  But as we go into 2009, we probably will take some of that long-term.  And we just think that the markets will settle down.  We have better opportunities.  We just don't want to burden the company with issuing any kind of fixed rate money long-term at interest rates that we think are much higher than we ought to be paying.  And so, it's already arranged.  And so, that's basically what our plan is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then, if we &#x2013; I am hearing from other companies that issuance premiums today are sort of running 50 to 75 basis points just given how locked out the credit markets are, is that about the kind of break that we would be looking to see before you would term some of this out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we don't want to talk about other companies, but a few companies, sizable large companies both in and outside of our industry have done some longer-term public issuance in a neighborhood of 400 basis points over treasuries.  And we would like to see dramatically better spreads than that.  So we just don't like to be paying those kind of &#x2013; those spreads.  Don't think we should.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, agreed.  Jim, on the political front, our Washington analyst team thinks that the Obama camp would like to come after big oil to the tune of about $10 billion to fund alternatives and renewables.  Do you have any thoughts on where we stand with windfall profits or other potential changes in taxes that would impact you next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't have any further thoughts with respect to specifics that you have outlined, but there is little doubt that our industry is going to be really challenged with respect to the public's view towards the income that we are earning and reporting.  Of course, our industry, we are really the primary solution to providing energy in the future.  And so, we think that any increase in taxation takes away from our ability to fund our capital programs and then furthermore, is a direct impact on employment.  I mean, we are the ones that know how to do this.  We are making the investments.  We need to make the investment and it really relates not only to providing energy, but it's jobs.</p>
          <p>And the other things is as we pay &#x2013; we pay &#x2013; already pay taxes that are at a rate double what the rest of industry in the United States do.  That's what the rules are and that's fine.  But on the other hand, any increased taxes is going to result in less investment, less supply, and less jobs.</p>
          <p>And on the other hand, I mean we've seen the market work, $147 oil price was too high.  But the market has adjusted and worked and oil prices and natural gas prices and crack spreads have adjusted, that's how the market works.  And so, we have a real challenge in front of us.  And our challenge is, we understand that the public domain with respect to the volatility in cost of energy.  But we also are working in a political process that doesn't have a great deal of knowledge and understanding of what our industry really does.</p>
          <p>And so, we have to really stand up and talk and make known our point, that increased taxation and regulation is just not the thing to do.  And the other thing is, we have reported our earnings for the third quarter.  You know what the oil and gas price and the cracks spreads are.  The sustainability of earnings that we just reported in third quarter is not going to be $5.2 billion.  It's going to be dramatically less given the metrics that we look at in the market conditions.  So, those are the things that we have to make known in the public domain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I would hope that, as you pointed out with the corrections in those margins and commodity prices as well as the sensitivity to jobs in the current economy that sort of cooler heads would prevail.  But, glad to hear that you are sort of prepared for the worst, it sounds?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I don't know how well prepared, but we are certainly going to make known...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Working to make sure it doesn't happen again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We would certainly solicit your help as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough.  Last question from me on LUKOIL, given the intensity of the credit crisis and sort of market confidence issues in Russia in general and the importance that LUKOIL has had in terms of contributing to volumes and reserves for Conoco the last year, do you have in the event that they run into credit issues or cash issues, do you have the ability to sort of maintain their programs with some sort of credit extension to them or a true-up in terms of increasing interest and share of projects, that kind of the thing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we stay in close communication with LUKOIL and with Vagit Alekperov, and we certainly recognize what's happened in the Russian marketplace and the issues in terms of access to the markets &#x2013; the capital markets.  And, but they have their challenges and they work through them and they know what their operating capital programs are and their financial plans, but there is no discussion or no plans with respect to ConocoPhillips changing our ownership position from 20% LUKOIL and we have no plans to be extending credit or cash advances to LUKOIL.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Erik Mielke with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  I'd like to stay with the theme of LUKOIL and Russia and just ask you about the change to the tax system that we're seeing over there.  Firstly, there is a temporary reduction in the export duty in the fourth quarter, what the impact will be on yield profitability from the YK fields.  And also if you can comment on the extension of the tax reductions to Timan-Pechora, which I think will take effect from next year, whether the YK field would qualify for that tax reduction and then, finally a broader question on Russia given the turmoil and the changes that we are seeing there, whether you are seeing increased opportunities for you to pursue additional projects in partnership with LUKOIL or with others?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  The first question, YK field does qualify for these changes in taxation and the result will be as we ramp up production in 2009, we will see increased profitability return from that production. So that's going to be helpful to us in Russia.</p>
          <p>And second point, you are quite true, is quite true as we see opportunities, of course, we have to work through these and make sure that they are working with LUKOIL and with Gazprom at others that what are those opportunities to invest primarily in the upstream part of the business in Russia -possibly outside of Russia but let's just talk about inside Russia &#x2013; I think there will be more opportunities, because Russian leadership has indicated that they feel that it is important to have international companies not just in the oil and gas business, but international companies in all industry participating and making investments in Russia.  And Russia is wanting to grow and develop their relationships in the world community.  So we do see that there will be some opportunities and &#x2013; but we need to work them very closely and make sure that they meet the objectives of what we would <mark type="inaudible" /> and that they also meet the objectives of whether it's LUKOIL or Gazprom.</p>
          <p>So, during periods of time like this, we do see the opportunities, but you have to really work them well and make sure that you get them sorted out right for the long-term for the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, the sort of opportunities that you are considering with Gazprom, would that be focused on the LNG markets or the domestic market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't think it's probably appropriate for me to get into that.  I did &#x2013; we just a week or two ago met with Alexei Miller, the CEO of Gazprom and we are discussing several of those opportunities, but I don't think it's appropriate to go through what specifically they may be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.  Can I ask on the current trading environment for both crude and for products, given the financial markets and the turbulence that we've seen there, how is that impacting who you trade with and how you do business and what do you think of the prices that we see on the screens?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we watch this very carefully.  What we have seen is that the financial markets seem to have less presence and backing away from being in the trading business, commercial business.  We as a company have a pretty sizable commercial organization, but we don't speculate, take flat price risk or anything.  We just trade around our assets and our volumes.  I mean, we need 3 million barrels a day to run our refineries.  And we have 1.8 million BOE a day of production that we need to sell at competitive prices.</p>
          <p>So, we actually see an opportunity to some extent in the commercial side of the business and we see the financial participants having less of a presence.  So, the commercial organization continues to make contribution both upstream and downstream.  And whatever we earn in trading around our assets and our volumes, we actually allocate that back in higher realized prices both upstream and downstream.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  And the final one from me, on the exploration expense guidance for the fourth quarter, 400 million, somewhat higher than what you have been running recently, any specific projects you want to highlight?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mark Gilman with Benchmark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys, good morning.  I had two things.  First, I was wondering if you could just give a brief update on where things stand vis-&#xE0;-vis an upgrading project at Wilhelmshaven.  Secondly, going back to an objective discussed in March of this year, Jim you commented on an effort underway to essentially rebuild the exploration component of the company's upstream program.  Since that point in time, yes, you've acquired some leases in the Chuck Chi the memorandum of understanding in terms of the "N" block.  But frankly it seems as if the focus has really been a bit more on discovered resource opportunities, namely Abu Dhabi and Origin.  Is the objective vis-&#xE0;-vis the exploration program still very much intact, or is your thinking shifting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  First on Wilhelmshaven, even with the challenging market conditions that we see, we look at our conversion project at Wilhelmshaven, and it really has a good rate of return.  So, we look at, how can we do it even do better, but that is in our capital program going forward.</p>
          <p>In exploration, no change whatsoever; maybe we haven't come out and identified exactly this program, where we are going and how we are adding to it.  But we'll do better and you'll see more of that when you see the March presentation.  But there is no change with respect to our direction and we actually put quite a bit of money during 2008 towards capturing these opportunities and picking up acreage.  So, I don't think we've done as good a job obviously that we could have with respect to yourself Mark or others, so we need to do that better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  If I could just follow-up, that 400 million expense in the fourth quarter, I would assume that that's not drilling activity, but perhaps G&amp;G and/or additional lease amortization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let us come back to you on the details of that because I don't have that right in front of me, but Gary, you can call up Mark on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll call you Mark. I would say its all three components.  It's not heavily oriented towards one or the other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, guys.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Neil McMahon with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.  I got a few questions, maybe to start off with first one on Origin, given what's happened to the market conditions while you were negotiating this deal, paying by our calculations 30% premium above the BG bid on a unit basis for the gas position seems a bit rich and sort of feels like what happened during the Burlington acquisition in terms of timing. Is there any chance to renegotiate this bid given what's happened to the entire energy complex even though Australia has held up reasonably well before you pay the 5 billion up front payment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first there is no real opportunity to renegotiate the transaction that we agreed to do. With respect the premium over and above what you outlined for British Gas, of course there are different assumptions that could be made.  What we see ultimately is four trains of LNG and that was built into &#x2013; factored into our forecast and even though we had some pretty strong inflation assumptions as we went forward over this next number of years, and to the extent that we see some help in terms of inflation constraint, that's going to help with respect to our returns. But no we expect to close the transaction here in the next week or two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, this is maybe a bit flippant a point, but is there not an issue just with the overall strategy going forward, if you continue to put in a higher bid than the next company, that one could argue that you're nearly bidding away any price rise from LNG you may see in the future and you'll never really get that uplift in returns and therefore be competitive with others if you keep doing these sort of deals.  I just thought it was odd for you to go into something you've never done before really and pay a price well in excess of where say the stock was trading at the start of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, we utilized our expectations of prices that were not prices that were in the marketplace at the time we actually agreed and announced the transaction.  So, we were more &#x2013; far more modest assumptions.  Second, I mean this is our business.  We are one of the biggest coalbed methane producers, through our experience in San Juan and other places in the world.  We really know this business well and we know how to do LNG and we are in the markets in LNG in Asia.  So, we really know this well.  And so, that's really how we've approached doing the transaction.  We like the country from a political perspective and we like the markets.</p>
          <p>We certainly understand what's going on at this point in time in the marketplace, but what we are really looking to is delivering LNG starting in 2014, 2015 and subsequent years and we expect the markets for liquefied natural gas to be much stronger than we see today.  So, that's really what we are investing at this point in time is for delivering these projects in 2014, 2015.  So, that's how we've approached it and we used realistic &#x2013; what we felt realistic expectations in what the natural gas price would be in those years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Maybe just moving onto the U.S. gas production, sorry if I missed this one already.  Just looking at the Lower 48 production, can you give us a sense of what &#x2013; from a natural gas point of view, what the drop was as a result of the hurricanes versus natural field decline for your U.S. gas business in the third quarter like both sequentially and year-over-year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we said was about 17,000 barrels a day quarter-to-quarter, was the impact of hurricanes in the Lower 48.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.  So, let's put it in other way.  Did your &#x2013; do you think your onshore natural gas volumes from San Juan and other areas, did they go up or down in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was some impact onshore just simply because some of the processing facilities and pipelines were backed up because of hurricane stoppage.  But the majority of the impact of was certainly offshore, but there was some collateral impact onshore.  I don't know what the onshore number is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, where I am going with all of this.  In the past, you've commented that you've got a very low cost base for U.S. natural gas production, and I for one have been a bit surprised you haven't sort of picked up the drilling activity there, as it's such a good economic base.  Are we still looking at growing or keeping U.S. gas production at least flat going into next year from the onshore developments or can you give us any new guidance given the market conditions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are actually working that right at this point in time and trying to determine just how much do we want to invest in that production.  Do we want to hold it flat, just this what do we want to do, do we want to increase it, let it go down some?  So, we look at what is the return and what are the priorities in the capital program.  And then what is very important to us is we don't want to lose the optionality of ultimately drilling those wells.  So, the plan doesn't change.  It's just at what time do we drill the wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You make good points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the points that you make is what we take into consideration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, because I've just been surprised, if the returns are so good, should this not be the opportunity to even think of a stepping up activity in gas, as you look forward and potentially we've got a tightening supply market into next year if everybody starts cutting CapEx but you guys?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for a $15 billion capital program, we will be cutting back some of our capital program, discretionary capital programs in North America.  But as we said, we don't want to lose the optionality of drilling the wells, but hope the details of that is given the market conditions that we are living with and we don't know exactly what they're going to look like, not only two or three months from now, as we look at 2009 is something that we haven't finalized our position at this point in time now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, as this is all the time we have allotted for Q&amp;A, I will now turn the call back to management for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Jen.  We just again want to thank everybody for participating this morning and a reminder that you can find the material that we went through this morning on our website, conocophillips.com and there will be a transcript of this conference call available later.  Good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we do thank you for your participation in today's conference.  This concludes the presentation and you may now disconnect.  Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>