<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1150282" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-04-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1165</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Gary Russell, General Manager, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James J. Mulva, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Douglas Terreson</participant>
      <participant id="4">James Mulva</participant>
      <participant id="5">Arjun Murti</participant>
      <participant id="6">Michael LaMotte</participant>
      <participant id="7">John Carrig</participant>
      <participant id="8">Paul Sankey</participant>
      <participant id="9">Nicole Decker</participant>
      <participant id="10">Paul Cheng</participant>
      <participant id="11">Mark Gilman</participant>
      <participant id="12">Bernard Picchi</participant>
      <participant id="13">Erik Mielke</participant>
      <participant id="14">Gary Russell</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the ConocoPhillips First Quarter 2008 Earnings Conference Call.  My name is Jen and I will be your coordinator for today.  At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode.  We will be facilitating a question-and-answer session towards the end of today's conference.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the presentation over to Mr. Gary Russell, General Manager of Investor Relations.  Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jen, and good morning to everyone who is participating on the conference call.  We welcome you, we are glad that you are here.  With me today, Jim Mulva, our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, and John Carrig, Executive Vice President of Finance and our CFO are here with me today.  Jim is going to be taking you through a presentation that we believe will help you understand more fully the financial and operating performance of the company during the first quarter of this year.  The presentation, as always, you can find on our website, www.conocophillips.com.</p>
          <p>And if you turn to page 2, our normal cautionary statement basically says that during the presentation this morning and in answering your questions that we will be making forward-looking statements that are based on our current expectations and those expectations could be materially different than actual results.  You can find the items or the issues that might cause those differences in our SEC filings.</p>
          <p>So now I'll turn the call over to Jim Mulva.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Gary, thank you and I appreciate all those who are participating in our conference call.  My comments are going to start on slide number 3.  You see in first quarter net income was 4.1 billion.  We generated 6.6 billion of cash from operations; debt equity ratio is 19%.  During the quarter, as outlined previously, we purchased 2.5 billion of our stock, so if you go back and look back to the first quarter of '07, we have reduced our average shares outstanding by 5.2%, and I have a slide here a little bit later to talk about that.</p>
          <p>Upstream business, we produced 2.25 million BOE a day, that includes 459,000 BOE a day which is our estimate production coming from the LUKOIL investment segment.  On the downstream, our crude processing capacity utilization was 89%, that's down from 95% in the fourth quarter last year.  And during the quarter, we announced a 15% increase in our dividends, so go back to 2002, we have been increasing our dividend at an average annual rate of 15%.</p>
          <p>So I am going on to slide number 4, you see our first quarter net income, 4.14 billion, or $2.62 a share.  That was 230 million less than the fourth quarter last year which is 4.37 billion, shown on the left hand side of the chart.  So, as we move along toward the right from the left hand side of the slide, you can see we had 88 million improvement from results of our asset rationalization program when you go from one quarter to the next.  We had prices, margins and other market impacts help us this quarter to 269 million.  This benefit was more than offset by the impact of lower volumes in both upstream and downstream.  That reduced our first quarter net income by 283 million.</p>
          <p>On the tax impacts, which are mainly the absence of the fourth quarter benefits including a one-time E&amp;P item related to the Canadian tax rate change and then there is another in chemicals, which was related to a capital loss.  These two things reduced net income 436 million when you compare this quarter to the fourth quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Then there were other items that in the aggregate improved first quarter income 130 million.  These included lower comparable cost or impairments or net interest expense, but this was partially offset by the absence of a fourth quarter benefit related to the extinguishment of the Hamaca, that is a Venezuelan Hamaca project financing. So we will discuss these variances in more detail in our subsequent slide.</p>
          <p>So I am going over to page 5 or slide 5 and we will be including this in our future conference calls, because we have been buying quite a bit of shares each quarter now.  And if you look at the chart on the left, you can see that we have reduced our average shares outstanding to 87 million shares, about 5% compared to the first quarter of last year.  Looking at the chart on the right, that reduction in average shares outstanding improved our first quarter earnings by about $0.14 compared to last year.</p>
          <p>I am moving on to slide number 6, total company cash flow.  When you start on the left hand side, you can see that we generated 6.6 billion of cash from operations this quarter.  So with this cash, we funded the capital program of 3.5 billion, paid 730 million in dividends and reduced debt 195 million.  You can see we purchased 2.5 billion of our shares.  We also had 335 million from asset sales and other sources.  That left us a cash balance at the end of the first quarter of 1.4 billion, pretty similar to what we started the quarter with.</p>
          <p>So now I am going on to slide number 7, capital structure of the company.  You can see on the left, our equity grew to 91 billion.  Our debt balance shown in the middle part, slight reduction.  We ended the quarter at $21.5 billion of balance sheet debt.  You can see our debt ratio on the right at 19%.</p>
          <p>So, now I'm moving on to slide number 8.  We can start talking about E&amp;P.  Our worldwide realized crude oil and natural gas prices are higher this quarter than last.  In the first quarter our realized crude oil price was $92.88 a barrel and that's $8.35 a barrel higher, and our realized natural gas price was $8.03 an Mcf.  That's $1.37 per Mcf higher.  Our E&amp;P in production and sales volume were somewhat lower than previous quarter and we are going to talk about that more in the next slide which is slide 9.</p>
          <p>Production in the first quarter from E&amp;P was 1 &#x2013; from our E&amp;P segment was 1.79 million BOE a day consistent with what we gave in our guidance.  This is 41,000 BOE a day lower than the fourth quarter production of 1.84 million BOE a day.  And that's reflected on the gold bar on the left hand side of this chart.  So we move along to the right, production in the lower 48 was down 61,000 BOE a day and that's largely due to the unplanned shutdown of a non-operated natural gas processing facility in the San Juan basin and then also the absence of a one-time NGL volume adjustment that we had in the fourth quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Production in the Timor Sea was up 14,000 BOE a day, and that includes an improvement of 19,000 BOE a day due to the completion of fourth quarter planned maintenance, a 5000 BOE a day reduction due to the impact of production sharing contracts.  Then there was other items that increased first quarter production 6,000 BOE a day as compared to the prior quarter.  Then you add our equity share of LUKOIL production and so that totals 2.25 million BOE a day in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Now I am moving on to slide number 10 about the income of E&amp;P.  Net income in the first quarter was 2.9 billion, compares to 2.6 billion in the fourth quarter last year.  Just start on the left, you can see we had lower gains from our asset sales program.  That reduced our first quarter income 17 million and we had prices and other market impacts improve the income 743 million.  Lower production sales volume reduced income 168 million and we had tax impacts which were discussed earlier, reducing first quarter income 283 million.  So, there are number of other items in aggregate that helped us by $4 million this quarter and they included benefits of lower impairments, lower comparable costs, lower DD&amp;A which was mostly offset by the absence of that fourth quarter benefit from Hamaca project financing.</p>
          <p>I'm moving on now to the downstream, slide number 11.  Our global capacity was 89%.  Now that's down 6% from last quarter.  On our domestic capacity, our utilization was 90% and that's 6% lower than the previous quarter and that is due to higher planned maintenance in our refineries on the East Coast and then we had the non-planned downtime at some of our refineries on the Gulf Coast.</p>
          <p>Now our international utilization was 86%.  That's also 6% lower than last quarter and it's due to weak hydro-skimming margins and then to run reductions at our Wilhelmshaven refinery in Germany.  Now with respect to Wilhelmshaven, for a good share of the first quarter of the hydro-skimming margins were below $2 a barrel which is lower than our cost to operate, and therefore, we made run reductions.  And we saw similar market conditions in several regions in the U.S., and particularly on the Chicago and San Francisco as well as certain parts on the East Coast where refining indicators were below operating cost for some of the time periods during the first quarter.  In spite of these conditions, we chose to optimize our refining operations than to make significant run reductions.</p>
          <p>Our realized worldwide refinery margins were lower this quarter than last.  U.S. margin was 8 a barrel, now that's $3.56 a barrel lower than the fourth quarter.  And the international margin was $6.43 a barrel and that's $0.30 a barrel lower than the fourth quarter.  And then our U.S. realized marketing margins were down $0.25 a barrel.</p>
          <p>Now going to the next slide, the refining marketing net income side, you can see that in the first quarter, our income was $500 million.  That's about $600 million lower than the fourth quarter of 1.12 billion as shown on the left hand side of the chart.  And then as you move from the left to the right, you can see we had the benefit of asset rationalizations in the first quarter; that helped us $105 million.  And, however, prices, margins and other market impacts reduced first quarter a little over $600 million, if you compare quarter to quarter.</p>
          <p>The largest portion of this variance relates to the absence of fourth quarter benefits from our planned crude and refined product inventory reductions.  So during the first quarter of this year, we were building inventories in anticipation of the switchover to summer grade gasoline, and we just routinely do that.  In addition, we had operating problems through most of the first quarter with respect to our FCC at the Humber UK refinery, and that reduced clean product yield and certainly impacted negatively margins and income.  Overall, our volumes in R&amp;M were lower than the fourth quarter and it reduced net income 127 million.  This may be due to lower utilization as I talked earlier, reduction in our ownership of the Borger, Texas refinery from 85 to 65%.  That's consistent with our joint venture agreement with EnCana.  And then there are other items that, in the aggregate, improved income by $21 million and that included lower operating cost, and somewhat offset by higher taxes.</p>
          <p>I'm now going to go on to slide number 13, the other segments.  Our estimate of first quarter equity earnings from LUKOIL is 710 million, slightly higher than last quarter, which was, we estimated 649 million.  It's primarily due to higher estimated realized prices for crude and refined products and to some extent offset by higher export tariffs and extraction taxes.  Now, our earnings reflect that we own 20.6% of LUKOIL.  In the second quarter, we expect our ownership to go back down to 20% and this is a result of LUKOIL's issuance of treasury shares for an acquisition -- they made a purchase of a power company in Russia.</p>
          <p>Income from our Midstream business was 137 million.  That compares to 162 million in the fourth quarter and it's down primarily due to oil realized NGL prices.  And our Chemicals joint venture contributed 52 million, little bit higher than previous quarter after you adjust for this one-time capital loss tax benefit of 65 million in the fourth quarter.  So after the adjustment, the higher income is mainly due to better olefin and polyolefin margins.  And then the emerging businesses contributed 12 million in the first quarter compared to 2 million in the last, reflects primarily improvements in income from our Immingham plant in the United Kingdom.  Its improvement is mainly the result of higher spark spreads, somewhat offset by unplanned downtime.  And then our corporate costs, $117 million.  That's 92 million less in the fourth quarter.  It's primarily lower interest expense and reduced losses from foreign exchange.</p>
          <p>Let me go on to slide 14.  We look at our E&amp;P metrics on a BOE equivalent and we compare that &#x2013; this to prior periods of time.  And then, when we used a peer group in all of our sites like in the past, our peer group is made up of the large international oil companies.  So that's Exxon Mobil, BP, Shell, Chevron, and Total.  Obviously, we don't have the information yet, because they haven't reported in the first quarter of '08.</p>
          <p>So the top of the chart shows income and cash per BOE.  It goes from 2003 all the way through first quarter '08.  The effect of purchase accounting certainly negatively impacts our earnings for BOE, because about everything that we've done in the past in terms of acquisition, mergers, is with purchase accounting.  But you can see that our cash contribution continues to be very competitive as does the income contribution.</p>
          <p>So we go from E&amp;P then to the next slide which is refining and marketing.  And for the same peer group and same time period for comparison, obviously the downstream has been under pressure because of the market conditions.  But we think really we will see that our income and our cash per barrel will continue to be competitive with the peer group.</p>
          <p>So now I am going to move on to slide 16, return on capital employed.  Again the shaded area in the back on this slide represents the high and the low of the peer group that I previously mentioned.  And the bar chart reflects our return on capital employed.  There is no adjustments for purchase accounting, adjustments made to peer group reflect purchase accounting for them.  We always include it as an attachment, Table 3 in the presentation, and then you can see, for the first quarter of '08, our return on capital employed is 15%, so 1% higher than for the annual number of last year of 2007.</p>
          <p>Now I am going to the last slide that I have under outlook and we made a number of announcements and developments in our company.  The first, we are quite pleased to be working with BP on the development construction of the gas pipeline that moves natural gas from Alaska's North Slope through Canada, the lower 48.  Ultimately the pipeline will move 4 billion cubic feet of natural gas to the markets in North America, the lower 48.  We are pleased to be underway with developing this project.</p>
          <p>Then in addition, we were the successful bidder on several prospective leases in Alaska's Chukchi and the Gulf of Mexico recently sailed.  And this is an important step in the development of our exploration portfolio.  And then we look to the second quarter, we expect the company's E&amp;P segment production will be lower than the first quarter and this is a result of seasonal planned maintenance.  But for the full year 2008 production, we expect to be consistent with our operating plan as we outlined at the March New York Analyst Meeting.</p>
          <p>Our second quarter exploration expenses will be about $250 million and the downstream, we expect crude capacity utilization to be in the lower 90% range in the second quarter.  This reflects primarily some planned maintenance at several of our facilities and also taking into consideration potential of ongoing weak hydro-skimming margins at our Wilhelmshaven refinery.</p>
          <p>Our second quarter pre-tax turnaround cost will be about 175 million and we expect our share repurchases in the second quarter will be like the last several quarters, between 2 and $3 billion, which is in line with our plans to compete $10 billion in share repurchases for calendar year 2008.  So that completes our prepared remarks and so now John, Gary and myself will respond to questions and observations that you may have of our performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Jen, I think we are ready for our questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  Our first question comes from Doug Terreson with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.  Congratulations on your record results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Good morning, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the Middle East, the Shah gas project would obviously represent an important and positive development and while you guys have experience on projects of that nature, I was wondering what two to three factors do you feel differentiate ConocoPhillips as it relates reflection on that project then?  And also, while I realize that it's very early, the pass-forward that's ahead of us on development of this project during the next 12 to 24 months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we do have experience in handling sour gas and of course, this is a very attractive project, very large project, technically and challenging for any company and also for ourselves.  We've been very interested in pursuing this project.  Nothing has been formally announced, but we continue to work very closely on all of the aspects of this project with ADNOC.  And so we would expect, hopefully in the next month or so, that we can be making a formal announcement going forward on this really important project for our company.  We think our approach towards this project is pretty innovative both on the technical aspect as well as the commercial aspect.  As I've said, Doug, we've been working on this for actually several years.  And this is really a good important one and hopefully as I said, I am optimistic that we will make a formal announcement on this here in next month or two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I see.  And then also Jim, you guys were successful on almost 100 tracks in the Chukchi Sea and while I realize that you wouldn't be involved if you were not optimistic, my question is how optimistic are you in that area and also, the next step as it relates to drilling and development in Chukchi Sea?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have 10-year leases.  We feel that we really know the area quite well.  This goes all the way back to the historic presence of our sales through ARCO Alaska and of course, we have the benefit of that and the experience.  We think that a lot of the things that we see in the Chukchi is similar to what we see in the North Slope of Alaska even though the 10-year leases we have to get underway pretty quickly.  So we are working really hard, both on the technical side, but also ultimately lining up that we will be doing our drilling as soon as we can.  But we have the infrastructure in Alaska and we are really pretty pleased about this promising area.  And as you know several wells have already been drilled out there, so we know that we are in hydrocarbon province.  So it really fits in really well for us to develop our exploration portfolio.  But it also helps as we continue to look out exploitation of the oil resources we have then, the gas pipeline from Alaska and then Chukchi really hopefully being successful sets us up for many decades to come in Alaska.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  Congratulations again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Arjun Murti with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Jim, I realize the analyst meeting was only about six weeks ago, but even since that time, oil prices have continued to move higher and I think general confidence in the bullish natural gas outlook in the U.S. has improved.  Can you comment on how you are thinking about capital spending over the next year or so?  I think relative to your $15 billion budget, you talked about potentially plus or minus 1 billion, around that.  How you guys think about capital spending now in light of commodity prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Arjun, thank you.  Yes, I mean we see an environment that's pretty surprising to ourselves in terms of -- for a very robust oil and gas prices.  But our capital spend as we look at 2008, 2009 is still going to be around $15 billion.  It may be because of cost pressures or some other unique opportunities, might be up a billion or two.  It may be a billion this year and maybe one or two billion next year, but we are really thinking about 15 or $16 billion.  As we said, the priority is not debt reduction.  We are very satisfied.  I think we've got the right capital structure.  So if we find that we have more cash flow it's not really going to be going towards capital spending, it's going to be going towards more distributions to shareholders in the form of share repurchase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's really helpful.  One follow-up, on your lower 48 gas production, it had been pretty steady between 2.1 and 2.2 Bcf.  Today, it looks it fell a little bit in the first quarter.  Is that natural declines or is it some one-off effects and would come back to a higher level going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it primarily goes back to San Juan gas processing plant that was down, that's -- is a real significant impact to our natural gas production in the lower 48 and it's really the primary reason why we are somewhat less on the total companies BOE production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.  Thanks for reminding me about that.  The last question was just on the elastic gas pipeline.  Can that substantively move forward without Exxon's participation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we -- obviously, it makes a lot of sense for all of us to be a participant, so we continue to work very closely obviously with BP.  But we also work closely in everything that we do with Exxon Mobil so, hopefully in time, I would like to see and would expect and hopefully that all three producers are part of the project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Michael LaMotte with J.P. Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Quick follow-up on the San Juan, is it back up now, is there going to be any impact in the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's back up and running and I don't know &#x2013; I don't think there is any impact in the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then to return to this question of CapEx briefly, help me perhaps understand a little bit better the returns trade-off, if you will, between increasing CapEx on the upstream side and increasing the buyback.  I would imagine with the higher commodity prices that the returns have to be pretty good in the upstream.  Certainly the returns that we are seeing from the independent producers in the lower 48 would suggest that.  How do you all view it?  I mean, clearly excess cash goes to buyback, but if I look at returns of buyback program versus CapEx, what's the thought process there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, we don't give up the optionality of doing any of the drilling in the future.  The question is, when do we want to capture those opportunities?  Do we want to do them today, or do we want to do them a year or two from now?  We like to this one in the share repurchase.  We think the purchase of shares is a very attractive investment opportunity for the company, and then we also want to make sure that we are concerned that the service industry and our own people that we have -- the oversight of doing this really well.  So while you never give up the opportunity, the option of drilling the wells and adding to the production, it's really a timing question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All of those things into consideration and that's why -- we'll drill these wells, but it may not be this month or this year, it may be next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful color.  Thank you.  And then, on the service side in particular, a couple of your peers in the lower 48 have talked about, after several quarters of falling services costs, have talked about stabilization.  Wondering if you're seeing the same thing and if there's an opportunity to perhaps go along in terms of contract duration to try to stave-off any potential re-inflation in service costs over the next few quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's difficult for me because I'm not as close to it as our operating people on the -- what we're seeing on the cost side.  I think there might be in some unique areas a little bit of moderation and escalation or cost.  That's good.  We'd like to see it go quite a bit further, but no, I don't know.  John, do you have anything more to say in there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.  We &#x2013; I mean, where we have -- we tend to look at it where we have long-term utilization needs.  We'll go a little bit longer.  But we do see some moderation, but whether it has an uptick as a result of the recent surge in gas prices remains to be seen.  So we try to manage the cost structure across the board, some long, some short, but by and large we are current with prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And historically, we don't go out and line up long-term rig contracts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Last one for me.  On the downstream, Jim, perhaps you could provide some color on what the biggest differences are in the ethanol impact and the gasoline market this year versus last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, obviously there is more ethanol and that is a substitute for volumes and we see that.  We also see that there is indication of -- some indication of reduced demand -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>-- because of the cost side of it.  So, for these reasons, obviously we do see some impact, particularly on the gasoline side of the business.  As you know, the margins in the crack spreads are very strong on the distillates side of the business, not strong on the gasoline side of the business.  So, you can see that that does have impact with respect to ethanol as a substitute and as well as demand in terms of the cost structure of gasoline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there a notable difference this year in terms of the distribution and logistics around ethanol versus last year at risk of dislocations to gasoline markets and potential spikes here in the second quarter, because --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think so, but maybe we could come back and talk with our people and respond back to you offline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  Thanks so much.  That's it from me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Paul Sankey with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jim.  A follow-up on Alaska, if I could.  I think you talked about $30 billion for that pipeline, could you, to the extent that you possibly can, talk a little bit more about how you get to that number and about the timeframe there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, well, really this is on the basis of old studies several years ago and that's one of the things that we really are working on very hard over these next several years with BP and that is just what is the cost structure going to be, as well as the engineering, the environmental, the permits and working towards open season.  So there is no basis, it's really old numbers, there is no -- we are going to have to do the work to come up with the new basis of what we think is the cost structure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, I was with John Carrig not long ago, and I think he was saying for -- almost from the point of construction starts, it's going to take 10 years to build, is that something that -- are we literally that far away from this thing ever delivering?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not going to dispute what John said in any way, but -- he's sitting right next to me.  But on the other hand, yes, seasonal from the time we are right here we are looking at 10 years, maybe a bit longer than 10 years by the time you go through all the study work and engineering and permitting and then going through with open season and then the construction of the pipeline.  We are looking at 10 plus years.  So we've got to start to now, which is what we've done with BP.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think, Jim, what you are saying is 600 million?  Over what timeframe with BP is that, just on the initial work?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the next year or two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next 2 years plus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  In the past, we talked about Mackenzie Delta coming first.  Could you update us on that pipeline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we continue to work that really closely with partners and with the regional authorities and all.  I'll just say, I am pretty optimistic, I think we are going to see something hopefully happen as we go through 2008 on the Mackenzie Delta pipeline.  And I think Mackenzie Delta will come before Alaska; this makes a lot of sense.  I know it's very important for the partners, it's important for Canada.  But I think sequencing in terms of purchase of steel and use of services through these pipelines, it makes sense for Mackenzie Delta to come first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I understand --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it's further along than the gas pipeline in Alaska.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.  Just a tentative date there?  Are we five years away?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paul, I don't know.  Maybe we could talk to our people and come back to you on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  A very brief one on downstream, you've talked about a guidance for how much utilization you'll have in 2Q.  How much of that is the required turnaround work and how much of that is the voluntary shut downs that you've talked about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In other words, what would you be running at if it was -- if we were in a strong crack environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think everything -- we have quite a bit of planned maintenance as we do in the second quarter.  In terms of what's impacting &#x2013; that impacts our utilization, normally we run 95% or so, some would say in the low 90s we are taking into consideration planned turnaround.  I think really the only facility -- we expect to run everything other than planned turnarounds other than Wilhelmshaven.  What we are really saying is, we are underway with making that a very sophisticated refinery.  But until we do so, that's the one that's going to impact utilization.  It's really Wilhelmshaven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And finally, Jim, is that then shut -- totally shut down Wilhelmshaven, not running....?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no we make run reductions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just the run reduction story, okay.  So we can kind of strip out 50% of Wilhelmshaven's capacity, perhaps, in terms of going <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't know what percent it is, but I mean there are times that we have accelerated turnarounds that have -- I think this past year, we went almost to a full shutdown, but we were doing maintenance.  But normally, we make run reductions.  We don't shut the facility down completely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Nikki Decker with Bear Stearns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the Denali project, I am just curious, have you had discussions yet with the Alaska legislators and what is the status of the AGIA program?  Is that ongoing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we talk with everyone, both the federal government, Canadian authorities and we certainly talk with Governor Palin, her administration, the legislators, everyone up in Alaska.  And, so, the AGIA process continues to go.  But, as the governor indicated, she sees ourselves going forward with BP and hopefully in time with ExxonMobil, the AGIA process has been helpful to move everything along.  So, I give credit to the governor.  But what the governor has said and what we hear from everyone in Alaska, they are very pleased that BP and Exxon are moving out on this gas pipeline.  So, what it really is saying is, there is about -- certainly more, far more certainly that this project is going forward and it's going to be done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So &#x2013; but, there are two proposals on the table right now, the AGIA proposal that I think TransCanada is heading up and your proposal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the governor and the state legislature are going to have to sort through how they handle AGIA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But, what we have announced is BP and ourself, we are going forward with our project.  It's not dependent upon funding from anyone; it's not dependent upon any approval by the state or the legislature.  We're going forward with the project.  And we think, given our history and our knowledge, and given that we are producers, we think we are really the right project to be going forward to see this pipeline come with certainty.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.  And, secondly, operating costs seem to have stabilized this quarter which is somewhat surprising given the higher commodity price environment.  Can you comment on whether that is the case and maybe whether it's a product of the environment or more due to self help?  And, particularly, my observation is in the downstream where I think you made some comment, Jim, on lower operating cost quarter-over-quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what we've been doing is, everywhere we can.  But, let's talk about the downstream.  We are trying to use productivity improvements, efficiency, whatever, to hold our cost structure on an absolute basis constant.  But if you are having some unplanned turnarounds, that gets hard to do on a per unit cost.  But what we are really trying to do, as we outlined in the New York Analyst Meeting, we are trying to hold our absolute cost structure flat as we go through the next several years.</p>
          <p>On the upstream, if you look at our charts and all, it looks like -- certainly it looks like the income and cash flow came to the bottom-line far better in terms of our upstream than in the fourth quarter.  But in the fourth quarter, we had a lot of unusual items.  First quarter this year is really very, very clean, just a few discrete items that you can see and &#x2013; but, it's all of us and our industry.  But certainly in our company a lot of emphasis on, let's make sure we minimize our lost profit opportunities, let's be on top of our cost structure.  But we continue to see push in terms of escalation and foreign locations are not helped by the weakness of the dollar.  But I think we are doing everything we can to constrain our cost and maybe you are starting to see that in the operating results in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, getting back to the downstream, could you provide some detail on the lower operating costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll get back with you, Nikki, I can do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  I appreciate it.  And, just one last one.  Where was the asset sale in the downstream?  Was it domestic or international?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was mainly retail locations domestically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Great.  That's all for me.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Paul Cheng with Lehman Brothers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, gentlemen.  Jim, when we are talking about the Chukchi in Alaska, can you tell us that what kind of drilling program that you have in mind and in terms of the timeframe and how many wells you are going to drill and also I know it's just early day, any color -- rough idea that how big is the structure over there compared to say Puho?  I mean, any kind of estimate or insight you can provide?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, I referred to earlier in our call, I don't know exactly what the drilling program will be.  But give it 10 years, and it takes a lot of time to do things, many years.  We just know that we have to get on underway pretty quickly on the drilling of the first well or two and maybe our people will come out and we can give you some more information on that.  I don't have it readily available to me.</p>
          <p>Now, given obviously we have to have some pretty large structures out there.  Because it's a challenging tough environment, so it will be quite expensive.  So, we expect to see some pretty large accumulations.  Otherwise, we wouldn't be bidding the way we did or within this time &#x2013; 10 year timeframe.  So, I really don't have more that I can pass on than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see.  Okay.  On the Saudi Aramco refinery project, any update there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we continue to work really closely with Saudi Aramco.  I think we are starting to move up towards 20% of engineering completed.  I think in the next few months, you are going to &#x2013; next two or three months, you will hear exactly what we are going to do on Yanbu.  But hopefully, we get to a position ourselves with Saudi Aramco to announce that we are going forward with it.  But it's premature to do that.  But we continue to work technically and commercially really well with them.  But I think you will hear more on this here as we go through this next quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Jim, any update on Sunrise?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sunrise?  No.  I know that Woodside and Shell -- we continue to be exploring all the different opportunities of whether to do that offshore or to do that by way of coming to Darwin or going to East Timor.  We continue to progress that work both technically and commercially.  I'd like to think -- I don't have anything right in front of me, but I'd like to think as we go into the latter part of '08, early '09, that we get to a position that we make a decision on just what we want to do on Sunrise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Two final short questions.  I think this is probably for John.  John, at the end of March on just your production, or your inventory, is underneath or over leaped for the corporation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Production for the first quarter was...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>At the end of the first quarter because -- I mean -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>-- this quarter could be underneath or over or maybe it's coming from residual on last year.  So, I just want to know that at the end of the quarter are we -- from an inventory standpoint are we overleap or underneath at that point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't have the number of barrels on the water for you.  We can try to get back to you on that.  But, overall, sales were less than production for the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We ended last year pretty close in balance.  So, if anything, we are either &#x2013; we are close to right in balance or a little bit less sales than production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we should expect if everything else equal that the second quarter should be a little bit higher sales than the production volume?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Assuming that the end of the second quarter doesn't have --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>-- Barrels on the water that would tip that in the opposite direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  And, John, in your analyst meeting you are very kind to provide what is the full year CapEx expense.  I mean, with the first quarter result out.  Any update on that number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.  I mean, we estimated that the corporate would be $1.2 billion for the year.  So, that's a 100 million a month.  And, we don't see that changing -- that monthly rate changing on average.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Very good.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mark Gilman with Benchmark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, guys, good morning.  A couple things.  Jim, can we assume that really, Alaska gas pipeline project that you and BP have essentially relinquished the conditionality that was in place previously regarding tax and fiscal certainty?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are just going forward with -- we know that at some point in time we're going to have to talk about the fiscal situation as it applies to the gas pipeline, but &#x2013; so, we are not -- nothing is tied to anything in the past.  We know at some point in time, though, once we go through engineering and permitting and all that, we are going to have to sit down with the state and discuss that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's still an open issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's an open issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Secondly, question for John Carrig.  I notice that we've seen a very steep downtrend in pre-tax interest expenses going all the way back toward the very early part of last year.  It's disproportionate with the decline in debt over the same period.  Have you dramatically changed the financial structure, shortened up the maturity curve if you will, to account for that or is something else responsible for it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.  We might be a little bit more short-term oriented versus long-term.  But our fixed to floating ratio is not that dramatically different.  But now the floating rates have been positive and because of the cash performance of the company, we had somewhat more higher interest income during these periods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was focusing on strictly expense, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I was focusing on net expense as well.  But the gross expense &#x2013; no, I don't -- there are other factors that get into that number, but no, we don't -- we haven't changed the financial profile of the company dramatically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, in a way, the off balance sheet, financing and debt is about the same, balance sheet is about the same.  So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it would come into the fixed floating ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But there are other &#x2013; there are tax accruals and other things that get into that interest expense number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, just one other one from me.  I can't help but noticing what's become the rather staggering difference between your equity in earnings of LUKOIL and the cash that would be allocable to your proportionate interest.  I make this observation in the context of LUKOIL's apparent announcement this morning regarding a dividend increase, but it still seems as if their payout ratios are comparatively low.  Are you lobbying at all, Jim, to try to get that payout ratio up, so that you can monetize your interest to a somewhat greater extent from a cash standpoint?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, are we lobbying?  Well, we continue to talk and discuss.  You make a good observation.  Our investment to regain all the earnings aren't paid out; it has a rather low payout.  On the other hand I do see Vagit Alekperov pretty routinely and we talk about the company and of course what they have is a lot of opportunity for investment and they want to continue to fund their investments versus an aggressive payout.  So we talk about it, but I don't think you are going to see dramatic changes in what LUKOIL is doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Bernie Picchi with Wall Street Access.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  Jim, you've sort of alluded to this as your Achilles heel of your worldwide refining system at least in the current environment has been Wilhelmshaven.  Can you discuss where you stand with regard to the equipment upgrading, if anything can be done to sort of accelerate the upgrading of Wilhelmshaven?  And then also two or more years I guess into the acquisition, could you critique that acquisition vis-&#xE0;-vis your expectation for Wilhelmshaven at the time that you entered into the agreement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  We brought Wilhelmshaven and we purchased it with the idea that we are going to immediately start a deep conversion project and I am going to say, I can't recall, about 2006 or -- it was 2006.  But when we looked at the deep conversion project, we felt it was overly complex and quite expensive, so we took the better part of a year, or 15 months, to rethink it and so now we have embarked upon it and proved that we are going forward.  I wish we could do it more quickly than we expect.  I can't recall the exact number, but it's the better part of maybe closer to 5 years than 4 years.  But we want to make sure that when we do the project that we've got this figured out and we get going too aggressive, we don't want to just throw money at trying to make a schedule that ends up increased cost and we don't get the schedule we want.  So we want to be realistic in that regard.</p>
          <p>Now if you look at the acquisition cost and the cost of what it is going to take to do this, there is no doubt in our mind that we -- if &#x2013; even at today's crack spreads and margins, this has been a good investment.  Now we wish that we'd made a sophisticated refinery out of it within three years or two or three years, but we can't do it that quickly.  And when we use modest, normalized crack spreads, whatever you want to say those are, we are looking at a rate of return un-levered in the mid teens.  So, therefore it makes a lot of sense for us to do this project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, very good.  And just a follow up question to the question that John was asking about the operating corporate cost and basically I think, John, what you are saying is that the $170 million corporate item that you are showing for the first quarter is kind of an anomalously low number?  That you would sort of guide us to use something closer to $300 million a quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we think that's probably better.  You should use the 300 a quarter.  Hopefully we can do better than that, but that's what you should use.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Erik Mielke with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning.  Thank you for taking my question.  I have a couple of hopefully quick ones.  Would you mind giving us a quick update on some of the key projects that you are developing in 2008, particularly Britannia satellites and the Timan-Pechora project with YK <mark type="inaudible" /> with LUKOIL?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the YK project, I think we are getting close to the first -- we have the first production or a small amount of production, so that's going right as we scheduled and outlined at the analyst meeting.  What was your other question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brit sats.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brit sats.  Well, we have got quite a schedule in terms of how we are getting ready to bring that on stream and I think we are looking at no difference in what we said production in the &#x2013; John, it's, or, Gary, it's the third quarter, isn't it?  Third quarter of this year is production from Brit Sat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the expectation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So no change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great, thank you.  The LUKOIL number that you reported for 1Q, is that a key number was there a fourth quarter catch-up involved as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was a modest, what we call, true up, but not overall significant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  And on the Shell Fuel that you are negotiating in Abu Dhabi, I know obviously you can't comment on the economics given that you haven't signed anything yet.  Can you perhaps give us some guidance on where you see the economics in the project, gas versus liquid versus sulphur, particularly in light of some of the stories that have been in the industry press?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as we have indicated, we felt that what distinguish our company and how we competed hopefully for this opportunity was a rather unique bid both in terms of technical bid as well as a commercial bid and it's not appropriate.  First, we have not been formally awarded this project and I think for other reasons it is not appropriate at this time for us to get into how that would be done.  But I think, assuming that it goes forward, we are named and for the formal announcement in the next month or two, you could expect here in the next quarter conference call if we follow that schedule, we will talk quite a bit more about the project and what are the drivers and what we see in it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good.  Final one from me is on share buybacks, where you were pretty explicit about if you have additional free cash during the course of 2008, you will be more likely to be handing that back in the form of share buybacks.  Would that be a fourth quarter event?  Would you wait until the end of the year before seeing where the cash flows are?  Could you conceivably accelerate buybacks during Q2 and Q3?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't think that you are going to see it in the second quarter and probably not even in the third quarter; but that's something that's very tactical, we will have to address and see.  What we have really set up for the company is we come out in the fourth quarter in December and we say, okay, we pretty well finished the year. Here is what we expect, or what we are going to approve and go to our board for approval on the capital program for 2009.  And with that, we will be making the announcement on what we see the share repurchase for 2009.  So, we like the idea of doing this on an annual basis.</p>
          <p>Now, we &#x2013; and we recognize that the question came from Arjun Murti, what would happen if you have a little bit more cash, well what would you do?  It's really the timing.  We'll look at our capital program, but if we have more cash for a share repurchase, it's a tactic question of when would we do it.  But we like the idea of making an annual announcement on share repurchase because that is pretty finite.  Instead of saying something for three to five years, we say, here is what we are going to do next year, and then it is pretty clear with discipline that's what we are going to do.  And the market price and the shareholders look at it and say, that's what we expect you to do.  So, that's really the plan of what we will probably do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't disagree with that.  Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>As there are no more questions in queue, I will turn the call back to management for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks, Jen, and we do appreciate everybody's interest and participation on the call this morning.  We remind you that the &#x2013; again the presentation that we went through this morning is available on our website and soon we will also include a transcript of the conference call there as well.  Again the website is conocophillips.com and we appreciate your participation and wish you a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we thank you for your participation in today's conference.  This does conclude the presentation, and you may now disconnect.  Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>