<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1418608" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-10-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>133</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO, Director, EVP &amp; Head-Investor Relations">Richard A. Galanti</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Robert F. Ohmes</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="William Blair &amp; Co. LLC">Mark R. Miller</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Mark Wiltamuth</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">Daniel T. Binder</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Christopher Horvers</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Robert W. Baird &amp; Co. Equity Capital Markets">Peter S. Benedict</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co., Inc.">Colin A. McGranahan</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Northcoast Research Holdings LLC">Chuck E. Cerankosky</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Chuck P. Grom</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Nathan Rich</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Cowen &amp; Co.">Laura A. Champine</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Michael Montani</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Telsey Advisory Group">Joe Isaac Feldman</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Bob Scott Drbul</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Piper Jaffray, Inc.">Sean P. Naughton</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Greg S. Melich</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is <mark type="ph" /> Jarree (0:02) and I'll be your conference operator today. At this time I would like to welcome everyone to the fourth quarter and year-to-date operating results for fiscal year 2011 and September sales conference call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. After the speakers remarks there will be a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator instructions" />.</p>
          <p>Thank you. At this time I would like to turn the call over to the CFO, Mr. Galanti. Sir, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jarree. Good morning to everyone. This morning, of course, we reported our 16-week fourth quarter and 52-week fiscal year 2011 operating results both ended August 28th, as well our 5-week September sales results for the five weeks ended this past Sunday, October 2nd and announced our plans to increase membership fees in the U.S. and Canada effective November 1st for new member signups and January 1st for member renewals.</p>
          <p>I'll start by stating that the discussions we are having will include forward-looking statements within the meaning of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995 and that these statements involve risks and uncertainties that may cause actual events, results and/or performance to differ materially from those indicated by such statements. The risks and uncertainties include but are not limited to those outlined in today's call, as well as other risks identified from time to time in the company's public statements and reports filed with the SEC.</p>
          <p>To begin with, our 16 week fourth quarter operating results. For the quarter, reported earnings came in at $1.08 up 11% from last year's reported EPS of $0.97 and of course the $1.08 figure was a penny or two below First Call estimates. Both fourth quarters included certain items that impacted quarter-over-quarter comparisons.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned on our fiscal '10 fourth quarter earnings call last October 6th, last year's fiscal 2010 Q4 results included a few items that in total benefited last year's reported $0.97 figure by $0.02. While there was no LIFO charge last year in Q4 as well as the whole year, the reported $1.08 this year included a $32 million pre-tax LIFO charge or $0.04 a share hit to earnings.</p>
          <p>Other items that impacted the comparison year-over-year: our foreign country earnings results again benefited from relatively stronger foreign currencies on average as compared to the U.S. dollar. In the fourth quarter FX helped earnings by a little over $25 million pre-tax or a shade under $0.04 a share. That is, assuming FX exchange rates were flat year-over-year our foreign country operating results in Q4 when reported in dollars would have been lower by that amount.</p>
          <p>For the entire year the impact of FX assuming FX rates had remained constant in every country as compared to the dollar year-over-year, was to increase pre-tax earnings by about $63 million pre-tax or $0.10 a share after tax. Again, this calculation simply takes the currency exchange rates for the prior fiscal year and assumes they had remained at those levels throughout the fiscal year.</p>
          <p>I'll also point out later my in comments, pre-opening expenses were higher by $12.6 million or about $0.02 a share after-tax. Higher this year in Q4 versus a year ago given the openings, more openings year-over-year in the quarter.</p>
          <p>For the entire 2011 year, net income came in at a reported $1.462 billion or $3.30 a share compared to $1.303 billion or $2.92 a share in last year's fiscal 2010, so up 12% in dollars and 13% on an earnings per share basis.</p>
          <p>If you have followed our earnings conference calls for all of fiscal 2010, I had pointed out a few items each quarter over the course of the year. Together the pluses and the minuses added up to about a wash in fiscal 2010. This fiscal year, of course, the big impact to earnings in '11 was LIFO hitting the second, third and fourth quarters for $0.01, $0.07 and $0.04 per share respectively, or a total of $0.12 a share for the entire fiscal year. I'll speak more about our outlook for inflation a little bit later in the call.</p>
          <p>In terms of sales for the fourth quarter, as we reported on August 31st, our 16-week reported comparable sales figures showed 12% increase, 10% in the U.S. and 19% internationally. Excluding gas inflation and the impact of FX from the U.S. dollar weakening year-over-year, the plus 10% U.S. reported comp would be plus 6%. The 19% reported international comp would be plus 10% and the 12% total company comp would be plus 7%, so the impact from gas was about 3% while the lift from FX was 2% and that again, was for the fiscal quarter.</p>
          <p>As you will see when I talk about the September numbers, the FX impact was about 1%, so while still the dollar, relatively is weaker versus, on average, all of our &#x2013; the foreign countries where we operate, that impact has diminished. In terms of sales &#x2013; comparable sales for the five weeks of September, 4 of the 5 weeks our comparable sales figures showed a 12% increase with the U.S. coming in at an 11% and international at 14%.</p>
          <p>The 11% reported U.S. comp would be a 7% without a &#x2013; without the nearly 4% impact from gas inflation. And given again the year-over-year U.S. dollar weakness vis-&#xE0;-vis the other currencies in the last month, while that's changed a little bit, for the whole month our reported 14% international comp would have been plus 10% when expressed in U.S. &#x2013; in local currencies.</p>
          <p>Overall, the reported 12% total company comp would have been a plus 8% excluding gas inflation of about 3% and FX as I mentioned of a little over 1%. For the month, our 12% reported comp sales results were a combination of an average transaction increase of 7.5%, and continuing good frequency increases, an average frequency increase of a little over 4%.</p>
          <p>Other topics I'll review with you, our opening activities. We opened a total of 20 net new locations during the fiscal year that just ended: 13 new in the U.S., 3 new in Canada and two new each in Taiwan and Australia. As well we relocated two units in fiscal '11 in San Marcos, California and Chesterfield, Virginia. For 2012 our current expansion plans include 20 net new locations, about half in the U.S. and half outside of the U.S., plus at least one relocation and of course the re-opening of Tamasakai, Japan unit which has been closed since the tragic earthquake of March 11 this past year. We currently operate 592 locations around the world.</p>
          <p>During the first few months of fiscal '12, basically from September through the end of the calendar year, we plan to open seven locations, four in the U.S., one each in Texas, Pennsylvania, Wisconsin and Georgia. We have a relocation planned for Ontario, Canada and two new locations in Japan and that's of course on top of the Tamasakai opening that will happen in early calendar 2012.</p>
          <p>Also this morning I'll review with you our Costco online results, our membership trends and of course the upcoming fee increases in the U.S. and Canada effective the first of next month. Additional discussion about our Q4 operating results of course and our stock repurchase activities during the fiscal quarter.</p>
          <p>Okay on to the discussion of our results. Very briefly, sales, again for the 16 weeks were $27.6 billion, up 17% from last year's $23.6 billion. On a reported comp basis in Q4, sales were up 12% and the 12% again would be plus 7% without FX and gas price inflation. For the quarter, our 12% comp would be an average transaction increase of 8%, an average frequency increase again of a little over 4%.</p>
          <p>Some of you ask about, you know, what is our average sales volume per location? In fiscal '11 the average sales volume company-wide per location was $146 million as compared to $139 million the year before. It is closer to $150 million versus $146 million this year if we exclude Mexico, recognizing our Mexico operations were consolidated for the first time into our numbers during fiscal 2011.</p>
          <p>In terms of sales comparisons by geographic region for both the fourth quarter and September, in the U.S., the strongest comps, both for the quarter and the month of September, were in the Southeast, the Midwest and California, but all regions were fairly good. The 11% reported U.S. comp figure for September, as an example, ranged from a 9% to a 13% among all regions. Internationally in local currencies we continue to do well. In Canada, which is our biggest international component, 9% for the quarter in local currency and plus 10% in September in local currency. The rest of international averaged around 12% in the quarter and 9% for September, so again continuing relatively strong comps there as well.</p>
          <p>In terms of merchandise categories, sales for the quarter, both for the quarter and September, within food &#x2013; I'll do those separately. For the quarter, within food and sundries, comps were positive in the low double digits. Standouts were deli, candy and foods. Sub-departments ranging from &#x2013; throughout the seven or eight sub-departments ranging from a plus 7% to a plus 19%. Our hard line sales showed positive mid-single digits comps. The strongest sub-categories were in the low to high teens. These were tires, sporting goods and lawn and garden offset by a minus mid-single digit in majors, which of course is electronics, which represents about a third of total hard line sales by the way in that category. As you will see in a minute, in September we saw an improvement in that department.</p>
          <p>Within the positive soft line comps which were in the mid to high single digits, great numbers in the small electrics and jewelry both in the 20% plus range. Fresh foods was up about, 12%. All fresh food category sales were fine.</p>
          <p>For the month of September now, food and sundries comps were in the high single-digit range with cooler, deli foods and candy leading the category and as reported in recent methods foods and sundries on a year-over-year basis that's one area as well as fresh foods that continues to experience inflation in the low to mid-single-digit range. And that's based on talking to our buyers.</p>
          <p>Hard lines were positive in the low single-digit range, which is the first time we have seen hard lines positive in a while, led by hardware, sporting goods and tires. Majors as I mentioned which was mid negative, mid singles negative last quarter for the month was positive in the mid-single-digit range with TV sales in units and dollars up for the month.</p>
          <p>Soft lines comps were positive in the mid-single-digit range led by small appliances domestics and jewelry, experiencing softer sales in housewares and media. Media has been that way for a while, needless to say. All departments in our fresh foods categories were positive double digit. Overall fresh foods, again, like food and sundries, experienced inflation in the middle single-digit, low to mid-single-digit range over the past &#x2013; as compared to a year ago. I'll talk in a minute about what we have seen in just the past month and it's mostly in bakery and meat.</p>
          <p>Moving down the line items in the income statement, we'll start with membership fee income. Reported in Q4, membership fee income was $590 million, up 11% or $57 million from last year's $333 million. It was down as a percent of sales by 12 basis points. Again, gas inflation plays havoc on the year-over-year basis points comparison. That minus 12, without gas inflation, would have been a minus 6 and still with strong sales growth we feel the 11% increase in dollars is pretty good. 8%, by the way, if you took out the benefit of FX.</p>
          <p>In terms of membership fees, and renewal rates and loyalty, renewal rates continue at the 89% plus range in the U.S. and Canada and 86% worldwide. Continue to see increasing penetration of the executive membership. In terms of new member sign-ups in Q4, they were dramatically up year-over-year. Up 22% in the fiscal quarter as compared to year ago. In Q4, of course, we had 10 new openings this year. Five of those openings, by the way: two in Australia, two in Taiwan and one Japan, these international ones accounted for much of that huge Q4 spike but even without these five the 22% figure would have still been up 6%, so a pretty good showing for new signups.</p>
          <p>In terms of number of members at Q4 end I'll just give you Q3 end and Q4 end. At Q3 end Gold Star &#x2013; Primary Gold Star was 24.3, at Q4 end, 25.0. Primary business remained at 6.3. Business add-on went from 385 to 4-0. Total 34.4 to 35.3 and including spouse card, 62.6 up to 64. At Q4 end, paid executive memberships were 11.8 million, an increase of nearly half a million, 450,000 or up 4% in the 16-week fourth quarter. That represents about 28,000 a week increase in executive membership penetration.</p>
          <p>The executive members currently represent about a third of our member base and a little over two-thirds of our sales. In terms of renewal rates, as I mentioned, they continued strong in U.S. and Canada which is the core of our business. The business members at Q4 end as of Q4 end were renewing at 93.3%, up from 93.2 at the end of the previous quarter, Gold Star 88.1% versus 88.0% and total 89.1% versus 89.1% due to rounding. Worldwide, it was 85.7% at Q4 end, down slightly from 86%. Again, that's a reflection of all these relatively newer warehouses over the past couple of years and generally a lower renewal rate both overseas as well as given the newness of the concept in some of these markets.</p>
          <p>Renewal rates for Q4 &#x2013; let's see, that's it there. Sorry. I'll spend a minute now talking about the announcement this morning of the pending increase in planned annual membership fees. First, the planned increases relate to our U.S. and Canadian operations. In the U.S. our current annual fee for our individual Gold Star, our business and our business add-on memberships is $50 a year. The annual fee on both the Gold Star and the business members has been at $50 since May of 2006 or a little over five years ago, the annual fee on a business add-on membership increased to $50 earlier this year in order to conform with the two primary memberships and now it, of course, is going to $55 as well. All three of these will be $55 on an annual basis effective November 1st in the warehouse, and effective January 1st with regard to member renewals. January renewals are mailed out near the end of November.</p>
          <p>Also in the U.S. our $100 per year executive membership fee is being increased to $110. This is the first membership fee increase since the inception of the executive membership program in the U.S. in 1997 and a few years after that in Canada. In Canada, the current annual membership fee for both Gold Star and business add-on members was already $50 &#x2013; $55 rather. By the way in Canada we talk Canadian dollars of course, and it was $50 for the primary business member, so it is the $55 &#x2013; is the $50 primary business member that will be raised to conform with the other two, to all be at $55, again effective November 1 in the warehouse and January 1 in terms of renewals.</p>
          <p>And similar to the U.S. member program the current $100 per year executive membership in Canada will also go to the $110 level at this time.</p>
          <p>In all, approximately 22 million members will be impacted by this increase, approximately half of them are executive members and the other half are the various Gold Star, business, and business add-on.</p>
          <p>Please remember that membership fees are accounted for on a deferred basis, for example, approximately 1/12 of the increased fees from our January renewals will be booked in the first month within an additional 1/12 being booked in each of the succeeding 12 months. So increased fees in February renewers, the increase will be booked February to the following January and so on. So the full impact of these increases in terms of how it hits the P&amp;L is essentially a 23 month timeline. That is the last group of members to be billed at the new fees level will be next December with a booking of that $5 or $10 per year increase to accrue over that month and the succeeding 11 months. With regard to executive membership, the 2% reward associated with the executive membership will increase from the current 500 million &#x2013; $500 per year cap up to $750 per year. Based, of course, on eligible purchases. This change we believe and others will help us to maintain our competitive edge.</p>
          <p>Needless to say we feel that the enhanced value of the Costco membership over the past five to ten years far exceeds the modest $5 and $10 increase in the annual membership fee levels and it will continue to allow us to bring our members even greater value on everything we offer. Going down the gross margin line, our reported gross margin in the fourth quarter was lower year-over-year by 34 basis points coming in at 10.54% of sales as compared to a year ago fourth quarter 10.89%.</p>
          <p>Ask you to jot down some line items in three columns. The line items are core merchandise, second line item would be ancillary businesses. Third line item 2% reward. Fourth line item LIFO. Next, quarterly adjustments. And then total. The three columns would be Q3 '11, Q4 '11 and Q4 '11 again without gas inflation, again, the huge volume we do in gas plus the huge 31% increase in prices year-over-year wreaks havoc on all the comparisons on a percentage basis, so we take out gas inflation to show you those numbers on apples to apples basis.</p>
          <p>Going across merchandise core: in Q3 '11 year-over-year it was minus 14 basis points, in Q4 '11 minus 24. Without gas inflation that minus 24 would be plus 2. Ancillary: minus 3, plus 6 and plus 12. 2% reward: plus 3, zero and minus 3. LIFO: minus 24, minus 12 and minus 12. Quarterlies: zero, minus 5 and minus 5, for a total of minus 38, minus 35 and minus 6.</p>
          <p>Mexico, of course, is also again, it was the first time in Q &#x2013; in fiscal '11 and therefore in the fourth quarter as well, it was put into the numbers. If you take Mexico out, it benefited all these numbers by 3 basis points.</p>
          <p>As you can see our overall reported gross margin was lower by 35, that's what we reported, but as was the case each quarter these figures require a little bit of elaboration here, explanation. In the fourth quarter our core merchandise as I mentioned was 24 and the ancillary business gross margins, principally gasoline impacting it, contributed plus six. Our gasoline business and its inflationary price trends during the fourth quarter this year impacts our fourth quarter margin comparison, as I've mentioned to you in the past. The sales penetration of higher margin core business was down 2 percentage points in Q4 year-over-year, whereas the sales penetration of our ancillary businesses, again, mostly impacted by gasoline sales, which is a much lower gross margin business to start with, was up 2 percentage points year-over-year in the quarter.</p>
          <p>So again, the core business: food and sundries, hard lines, soft lines and fresh foods were up slightly year-over-year. Its aggregate gross margin hit was the minus 24.</p>
          <p>LIFO as I mentioned was 12. . We continue to see year-over-year inflation as we did in Q3. Although at a slower rate of impacting Q4 as compared to Q3.</p>
          <p>The minus 5 basis point quarterly amount, that's part of what I mentioned earlier in the call that in last year, we mentioned in the $0.97 figure included about $0.02 of benefits from a couple of items. There were a couple of miscellaneous items that we felt when we reported $0.97 last year that $0.95 was a more appropriate number with a couple of unusual items that actually benefited slightly the margin and SG&amp;A.</p>
          <p>In terms of gross margin outlook, no real margin issues. Our inventories are clean. Very good physical inventories at fiscal year end. We continue to be committed to driving top line sales as we enter the Christmas holiday season and into the new calendar year.</p>
          <p>In terms of inflation outlook, in talking to our buyers, their view is that we continue to see and expect year-over-year inflation with food and sundries, fresh foods and in some non-food areas, although at a slower rate compared to the last six months. I will mention that in September, we did, in terms of looking at our LIFO indices, slight deflation, very slight deflation from the beginning &#x2013; from the beginning of our fiscal year so four weeks earlier, versus the end of September.</p>
          <p>Again versus last year we're still seeing some inflation but in terms of how, what hits the P&amp;L in terms of LIFO, at least for the first four weeks we see essentially flat to very slightly down, slight deflation.</p>
          <p>Moving on to SG&amp;A, our SG&amp;A percentages fourth quarter over fourth quarter were lower or better by 34 basis points coming in at 9.83 this year compared to 10.17 last year. Again, quickly jot down three columns and several line items. The line items are operations, central, stock compensation or equity compensation, quarterly adjustments, total. Going across Q3 '11, Q4 '11 and Q4 '11 without gas inflation. In operations: plus 46 basis points meaning it was lower by 46, Q4 '11 plus 44 and Q4 without gas plus 20. Central: plus or lower by 3, Q4 '11 minus 2 and Q4 without gas minus 5 so higher by 5. Equity: plus 2, plus 2, plus 2. Quarterly: minus 8, minus 10, minus 10 for a total of: plus 46 meaning in Q3 year-over-year we were lower &#x2013; on a reported basis, lower by 43 basis points, and Q4, plus 34 or lower by 34, and without gas inflation, plus 7 or lower by 7.</p>
          <p>Again, Mexico had us a low to mid-single-digit impact on those numbers for the quarter and the year and the quarter with and without gas.</p>
          <p>Again, in terms of editorial, operations were lower or better by 44. Again, a big component of this was due to the 31% increase per gallon for gas, price per gallon for gas during the quarter. Just like with gross margin percentages where it hurt, it correspondingly helped our core SG&amp;A by plus 24. So the 44 would be plus 20 without it. Our central expense was a bit higher year-over-year. Really just a couple of line items things in there on a year-over-year basis that were year-end changes, quarter end, year-end accrual adjustments and what have you, nothing to really speak of.</p>
          <p>Health care costs in the quarter were lower by 2 basis points. U.S. health care costs however were up 14% in the quarter and 12% for the year.</p>
          <p>In terms of the factors that will impact our outlook for expenses and other things in fiscal '12, again, the main items are going to be sales trends, health care, gasoline sales inflation or deflation and of course, and to some extent increasing penetrations of Asia operations which have lower overall SG&amp;A percentages.</p>
          <p>Next on the income statement is pre-opening expense. Pre-opening expenses were up $12.6 million higher or minus 4 basis points to the P&amp;L. $9 million last year in the quarter versus $21.6 million. Last year in Q4 we had &#x2013; in fiscal '10 Q4, we had five openings. This year in Q4, we had 10 net openings but 13 actual openings, so including the two relos and the re-opening of our Makuhari, Japan location.</p>
          <p>In terms of asset impairment and closing costs, in Q4 '10 last year, we had a charge of $3.3 million for the quarter, this year $2.6 million so no real change there. All told operating income in Q4 '11 was up 10.5% year-over-year from $688 million last year to $762 million this year, or an increase of $74 million.</p>
          <p>The bigger percentage increase &#x2013; a little bigger percentage increase if you consider last year's $0.02 that I mentioned that adds to earnings and this year's $0.04 LIFO hit. Below the operating income line, reported interest expense was about the same year-over-year with Q4 '11 coming in at $35.8 million versus $34.7 million last year. These amounts, of course, mainly reflect the interest on our $2 billion debt offering that we did in February of '07.</p>
          <p>I will mention that beginning in mid-March of '12, which is about a month into our fiscal third quarter this coming year, we plan to use existing cash to pay down $900 million principal amount of that $2 billion which was five year maturing debt at an annual pre-tax savings to us, we estimate, of about $44 million pre-tax or $0.06 a share. We get to the $44 million assumption based on all in rate for that five-year fixed rate money of 5.37% and our current return on the $900 million that we'd use of about 44 basis points.</p>
          <p>So that's where we get the $44 million. Again that will start in mid-March of 2012.</p>
          <p>Interest income was higher by $16 million in the quarter, $45.8 million this year versus $29.6 million. Actual interest income, you know, this line is interesting coming out there. Actual interest income was higher by about $8 million, a reflection of not only increased cash but some increased interest earned on increased cash balances outside of the U.S. in some countries.</p>
          <p>The other $8 million is a combination of things. For everything from marking to market FX forward contracts that we use in some foreign countries to the fact that we have &#x2013; a we now consolidate Mexico instead of putting half of its earnings on this line item so taking half out there and spreading it throughout the entire income statement, going from the equity method previously to now consolidated, as well as a couple of other miscellaneous items and so overall, pre-tax earnings were up 13%, $684 million versus $771 million this year.</p>
          <p>Our company's reported tax rate this quarter came in at 35.3%. A little lower than last year's rate of 36.1%.</p>
          <p>A quick run-down of other topics. The balance sheet you should receive, that was received, I'm sorry, in the press release. As well of course like always you will see some other information shortly that will be online.</p>
          <p>Depreciation and amortization was $273 million in the quarter, $855 million for the year. Strong balance sheet, as you guys know. Our AP percent &#x2013; AP as a percent of inventories, on a reported basis it showed that last year in the fourth quarter was 105% and it was declined to 99%. On a merchandise basis so, merchandise accounts payable versus our inventories, it actually went from 89% last year up to 91%. I think a reflection of slight improvement in increased turns and hopefully, good negotiations with our &#x2013; by our buyers.</p>
          <p>Average inventory per warehouse was up $772,000 from $10.441 million per warehouse a year ago as compared to $11.213 million so about 7%. About a third of this increase relates to the stronger year-over-year FX. Food and sundries was up about $165,000. That's partly due to the inflation that we talked about in the past. The balance of the variance is basically spread among departments. Again good inventory showing overall we feel good about how we came out of fiscal year end with very clean inventories and we feel good about our sell-through so far in seasonal items and hopefully we'll have a good season continuing throughout this calendar year.</p>
          <p>In terms of CapEx in fourth quarter it was $472 million. For all of '11 it was $1.290 billion. We would estimate that fiscal '12 CapEx will be in the $1.4 billion to $1.6 billion range with increases from that level expected in fiscal years 2013 and 2014. That's a combination of we would expect increased expansion activity as we have got more in the pipeline. As well as an ongoing increase proportionally of some of the overseas expansion which tends to be a little more expensive in some of these very densely populated major cities.</p>
          <p>In terms of our dividend, in May we increased our quarterly dividend by 17% from 20.5 cents per share per quarter to 24 cents. This $0.96 per share annualized dividend represents a total cost to the company of about $420 million.</p>
          <p>costco.com and costco.ca in Canada in total, sales were up 12% for the year and up almost 15% for the quarter. In terms of expansion I mentioned earlier we currently are planning about 20 for the year skewed towards the end of the fiscal year in spring and summer. Again about &#x2013; of that net 20 about half will be in the U.S. and half in international. As always, subject to a couple slipping one way or the other so one extra in the U.S. and one less or vice versa.</p>
          <p>In fiscal '12 assuming we are at 20 net new units that would be about 3.5% square footage growth. Also, at fiscal year-end some of you asked, total square footage stood at 84,415,000 square feet in our operations. In terms of stock repurchases, we currently have repurchase authorization with the board approval earlier this calendar year to increase the authorizations. We currently have authorization of $3.7 billion.</p>
          <p>As you know, in Q3, as I mentioned we bought, we spent $102 million buying back 1.3 million shares. If I just annualized that $102 million of buying over those 12 weeks, that would be about $440 million. I think if you annualize that 36 weeks, you are approaching a $500 million rate of purchase.</p>
          <p>In Q4 we purchased 3.7 million shares for $294 million. Taking those 16 weeks and annualizing it, you get closer to $1 billion, about $950 million in annualized &#x2013; at annualized rate of purchase during the quarter. Long-term, we continue to be buyers on a regular basis. We're not going to predict up or down where the stock is going to go, but overall we continue, we currently believe in the outlook of the company and clearly we have got enough cash to not only pay for ramped up expansion and increasing dividend but hopefully stock buybacks as well into the future.</p>
          <p>Quick reminder, fiscal '12 is a 53 week fiscal year. The fourth quarter of '12 will consist of 17 weeks this year compared to a 16 week fourth quarter last year.</p>
          <p>And as I mentioned, our supplemental information pack, which includes some of the other useful stats will be posted on the investor relations site later this morning. With that I'll turn it back over it to <mark type="ph" /> Jerree and open it up for Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of Robby Ohmes with Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Hey, Richard, how are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was hoping you could maybe elaborate more on the fee increase sort of, you know, the timing of it. I know it is something that you guys had talked about. But you know, the timing of it this year and also the expected response, if any, from your customers? Do you think you will lose anybody, you know, related to it? And I think also you mentioned something about allowing you to give even better values. You know, is there an anticipated impact over the next two years on what your store level margin structure could look like or the way you are passing on inflation, etcetera, you know, related to taking this membership fee increase? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the timing is simply, we just decided to do it now. We talked about it and just about everybody out there asks about it every quarter. But you know, at least two or three times a year when we're off-campus as a senior management team we talk about it. We have always felt that our membership fees, our membership value is greatly enhanced, we continue to greatly enhance it. Many of you know us well, long enough ago that we use it in a lot of ways and recognizing all monies are fungible but the fact of the matter is we're always going to be competitive with or without this we'll continue to be competitive. This will allow us to continue to be competitive, offer more services and do what we do.</p>
          <p>So you know, we're &#x2013; people ask us about the economy. We're not thrilled about it. We're thrilled that we are performing quite well in terms of shopper frequency and driving sales in the right direction. And we're going to continue to do that. So I'm not trying to be coy, but you guys know who we are. We're going to do what is right to drive our business long-term.</p>
          <p>Now in terms of do we lose members? Recognize this is a, you know, on a primary membership this is 10% increase $5 increase on $50 membership fee that has been $50 for the last 5.5 years. And $10 increase on $100 that has been that way 7 to 11 years, depending on which country.</p>
          <p>And so, this is not a $5 a month increase. It is a relatively small increase. We recognize with the economy is historically we have got a very little fall-off from it. We don't take it lightly. We didn't take it lightly by doing it and when we do it but we recognize that it is part of what we have done historically over 25 years. Doing modest increases in the fee, but every time we have done it we feel, and we take a hard look ourselves, we look at ourselves in the mirror and feel that we have continued to enhance the value of that membership by a lot more than that. And we say that sincerely. Maybe we're fooling ourselves but we don't think so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Miller with William Blair.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Richard. On the net store expansion now expecting 2o for fiscal '12, I think last quarter you commented you thought it would be closer to 25. So I guess I'm curious, is there something that caused Costco to slow it down or I guess something previously unexpected in the marketplace?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, this is probably the one number that we have most poorly predicted every quarter and every year for 15 years. We've got a lot in the pipeline beyond this. Some of the expansion overseas takes longer. All I can tell you is that Craig &#x2013; and Jim and Craig's goal and Jeff Brotman's goal is to get that number up. And you know, again I can't predict what it is going to be. There's other irons in the fire that might tweak that up a little bit. I try to be as realistic as I can going into the year and perhaps each year being even more realistic. But so again, could it tweak up a little bit? It could. My guess is you are going to see, like we did &#x2013; well recently there's again a lot of irons in the fire. I think you are going to see a lot of openings, just past the beginning, the end of this fiscal year into the next year.</p>
          <p>If Jim were sitting here or Craig were sitting here, their goal would get that goal into the 25 to 30 range next year. But I can only tell you what we have got going on right now in terms of what we feel comfortable that we're going to be opening. I can also assure you those three and the real estate people and the operators are working very hard to speed up that process. Because we &#x2013; there's a lot of locations that we want to open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's more unpredictability in terms of some of the timing and zoning particularly in some of these foreign countries. And &#x2013; but I mean, they are favorable to us opening. It is just it is a longer process. And again, there is more iron &#x2013; there are more irons in the fire now which will speed up that process hopefully.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then with half the clubs going outside the U.S. in fiscal '12 I guess I'm trying to integrate that into how we should think about international profitability. It looks like you should be about &#x2013; or now more than 45% of your profits outside the U.S. for all of fiscal '11. I don't know if you can share that exact number. But when do you think we get to more than 50% outside the U.S.? Do you think you get there in fiscal '12? I know FX also is a factor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're including Canada? That number sounds a little high although you have the numbers in front of you, I don't have the details in front of me. I would have to look at it. Clearly, clearly the rate of increase in overseas expansion, and I include in this Canada and other international, and the fact that the dollar has weakened has exacerbated it upward a little bit. My guess is, is that to the extent that that increasing penetration occurred in the last couple of years, it probably still increases but slows down a little bit. Again, I'm just shooting from the hip there though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And finally and then I'll turn it over. The new member sign-up going up 6% outside of the new international club openings, was there any anomalies to that figure or what do you think explains that acceleration? Thanks Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of openings overseas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, the new member signups. I think you said it...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, I'm sorry. In some of these markets like, you know, the area around, in and around Taipei, Taiwan or Tokyo. One where we have been very successful in three Asian countries and starting off pretty darn well in three locations we have in Australia. Particularly in the three Asian countries in the 20 million population cities, if you will, we have memberships per warehouse off the charts in terms of new signups. Even after they have been open for a few years, I think in Japan the number of members per warehouse is double our company average. Darn near double our company average.</p>
          <p>So it has to do &#x2013; it is nice when you have five locations in a city the size of these cities. And there's plenty of opportunity to open more locations and maybe that will come down over time. But there's, the per capita &#x2013; that number of population per warehouse is off the charts over there as well. Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Wiltamuth of Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Richard. Wanted to ask about the inflation pass through on food. Are you having any margin drag from that? Obviously we had the LIFO charge here, but if you take the LIFO out, what's the effect on margins here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, there's a little bit of lag. You know, quite frankly it's us more than anything. You know, if I looked at the detail I would say that you are still impacted in the food court. Because we're not changing the price of the pizza or the hot dog as an example. You are going to see it in bakery for some of the commodity goods there. Even though we have seen some reduction in some of the underlying commodity costs of bakery, it is still not back to where it was. Again, I think a couple of fiscal quarters ago I gave a couple of examples where we're going to hold the price of a 15-pack or whatever of muffins and let the margin dwindled down on it before we take an increase. And we do ultimately.</p>
          <p>So &#x2013; but that's our doing. And I don't think it is a dramatically big change of what we have historically done. It is just we have inflation now. Ultimately you have got to pass the price increases on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on that front we just saw some softening in some of the underlying core commodities with corn cooling off last week. How long does it take for that to really hit your stores before it cycles through the packaged food companies and then gets to you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, keep in mind, as you might expect &#x2013; in my view, you know, a couple years ago when there started to be inflation, actually in mid '08, there was a lot of pent-up demand, if you will on the manufacturing side because retailers had on very light inflation for a number of years. The large retailers, the supermarkets, the Walmart's, the Costco's were able to push back. So some of it will stick because it was catching up from prior stuff.</p>
          <p>Generally, it's all over the board, but generally you will see it in &#x2013; you will see it weekly and monthly in things like beef and pork and poultry. And you will see it in raw materials when we're buying, you know, certain raw materials for our bakery you will see it pretty quick. You are not going to see it all proportional to what you see coming down because they didn't get all of it on the way up. Even when they got it, some of it was, in my view, pent-up demand. Every one of our buyers jobs as manufacturers explain why something was going up, they are out there hitting back saying let's come down now. So we're, I think as good as anybody, in pushing that envelope the other way but it takes some time; anywhere from a few weeks to a few months depending on the categories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One other comment on that as an example. You know, when cotton prices were going way up six, eight, 12 months ago, and I think I mentioned on one of the calls in some cases when you are making three, six, nine month commitments on everything from apparel to towels and things like that, there were some manufacturers, many manufacturers overseas in Asia particularly were basically saying, you've got to commit to quantity and we can't tell you what the price is, because that's how fast the underlying commodity costs of cotton were going up. In some cases &#x2013; we and everybody else, you know, had to eat some of that as cotton prices or other things have come down. But again, we're turning that faster, on average, than other comparable full line retailers in those categories. So do we get hurt? A little bit, but everybody gets hurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Dan Binder with Jefferies &amp; Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Couple of questions. First on the core gross margin, if I'm &#x2013; I think I have it apples-to-apples. It looks like your core was up plus 2 basis points this quarter compared to more substantial gains in recent quarters. I'm just curious if there's anything that leads you to point out to a change in that pace and what we should kind of expect going forward? That was the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question was on the membership, the executive membership with regard to the increase in the rebate. Just curious what the sort of incremental drag is to, you know, that give back to the customer. In other words.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sure there's probably a few members that were exceeding that $500 rebate. So now that you actually have to pay them, what kind of a drag does that bring to the P&amp;L.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Now, I forgot what the first question was.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The core gross margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, yeah, I'm sorry. Again, we don't view it as anything to be concerned about. It's &#x2013; you know, when talking about gas inflation, the other piece of gas is gas gallonage is way up. That's also on a low margin business, you know, eight or so &#x2013; eight or so hundred basis points but increasing penetration of gallonage. There's lots of things, different countries, different penetration. We really as we looked at it in terms of looking at the core, didn't, you know, consider it, it is a little lower than it has been in the last couple of quarters but we'll keep letting you know what it is. Again, we don't read a lot into that as any trend either up or down.</p>
          <p>In terms of the executive membership and the increased reward, it is pretty small. Recognizing that to be at the $500 cap, you are at $25,000 in eligible purchases, eligible purchases meaning everything but gas, alcohol and tobacco. And so, but we're hoping it will grow. It's well under $10 million of impact a year. And we &#x2013; but we hope it would go up because that means it is driving business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and then one final. On the other income line, when we consider that Mexico is not in that number this year, it's up, quite substantially versus where you were in the first three quarters and you mentioned FX contracts. I'm just wondering if there's some bigger items in there that you can identify?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There really aren't. There's a few things that go both ways. FX forward contracts in a given quarter can be, can be plus or minus, you know, $5 million. Usually it is plus or minus a couple million bucks. I think that the, on a year-over-year basis that variation was closer to the five frankly. That's, so that's the biggest chunk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Chris Horvers with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. So Richard, on the LIFO, do you think that based on September's experience that this actually turn out to be a benefit in the fourth quarter if we kind of stay where we are and then can we just run rate that as we think about the experience into next year and the 3Q and perhaps that lift gets better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again, who knows? If I could extrapolate with absolute certainty the first month we would have no &#x2013; it would be flat. Or a very slight amount of credit, who knows? I mean, if you &#x2013; assuming that there &#x2013; in terms of expectations for increases on top of current levels, yeah, the buyers generally view there's not a lot of increases happening right now. In terms of getting price reductions on things, and again LIFO starts with a beginning of this fiscal year on August 29th. So the index for the first four weeks our internal four-week period was just a few basis points under a base of a 100.00. So very slide deflation. Who knows what tomorrow brings?</p>
          <p>To extent from these levels, from August 29 levels of pricing and costing, that we see some, as commodities come down, as we see some price reductions, that would be, that would tend towards a credit. You know, I'm shooting from the hip. But you know, my guess is, is that I would assume right now it is flat and there's no, not a lot of risk it is going to big inflation and not a lot of risk that's deflation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it is not a comparison issue, prices actually have to come down to see the credit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Yes. But in terms of seeing the impact in Q3 and 4 of a LIFO charge that seems to have abated at least at this point. Who knows what tomorrow brings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And obviously we're also sensitive to what's going on with the consumer. Was there anything particularly about the cadence in September that you would call out either positively or negatively?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the thing that continues to surprise us is this continued 4 plus percent frequency number. We certainly appreciate and recognize that gas, gallonage comps for us are strong. Certainly strong relative to the U.S. consumer. And that drives people into our parking lot. We recognize that people are probably eating at home more than they used to. That drives people into our parking lot.</p>
          <p>And I think those are the issues that &#x2013; so we have been somewhat blinded by the fact that we still believe that the economy &#x2013; we know the economies are tough. We're concerned as every one of you are out there every day with the gyrations in the market and the mortgage statistics and the unemployment statistics.</p>
          <p>We are bucking those trends in terms of driving, you know, unit frequency, customer frequency and with a little help from even inflation, dollar increases. So we're working hard to continue to drive that market share. And we think we're doing a pretty good job of it. But if you asked us do we feel good about what's going on out there? No, in terms of the economy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And then &#x2013; and one final quick one, it seems that the FX will probably turn on you in the coming months from a top line perspective and get a bit worse in the spring if we just held today's rates. How does that flow through to the margin structure if it does, if it does turn in the other direction?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It doesn't, it doesn't &#x2013; it doesn't change percentages a lot because it is every line item. To the extent that, you know, our foreign operation is slightly more profitable, bottom line, but those, you are talking about percentages times percentages. I don't think it has a lot of impact on any percentages.</p>
          <p>You know, again like this past year, the three, the reported $3.30 of earnings there was, I think $0.10 in there from that, you know, from just the change in FX. To the extent that we are relatively constant until the spring, and then start to show the other way and again who knows? It could be a slight detriment this year but we don't know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Peter Benedict with Robert Baird.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey Richard, a couple of questions. In the past you have walked us through the, at least qualitatively the gross margin trend within the four main categories. Could you give us a sense of how that flushed out in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I don't have it in front of me. I think hard lines was up. Fresh foods was down a little. And the other two I don't have in front of me, I'm sorry. I know overall it was up two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yeah. Okay. Perfect. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>By the way, one of the things that, you know, Jim has mentioned that you know, less is more. Not from trying to &#x2013; we have always tried to convey, give you a lot of color on things. We're trying to wean me off some of that going forward. Not yet but this &#x2013; and so, you know, we'll continue to try to do that. And still give you the same color on what's going on out there though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's helpful. I mean would you say &#x2013; how would you characterize kind of the mood internally in terms of that core margin line? I mean is the goal still to kind of maintain and increase that or are you more willing to kind of give back some of that now that you have raised the fee?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a definite yes to both of those. You know, the fact of the matter is, we, you know, we do what we do. Really, we don't sit around here being terribly concerned about margin. Keep in mind over the last 10 years, executive membership has hit the margin line for over 100 basis points. Penetration of gasoline, which is easily 700 or 800 basis points lower than the company average margin outside of that, probably eight plus, hundred that's gone from 0% 10 or 12 years ago to 8 or 9 or 10% of sales. 9% of sales. So we have hit the margin hard in a lot of ways and our margins are pretty good. Despite us being competitive out there, we're going to do what's right for the company long-term. We're going to drive sales. We feel very good about our ability to do that. And again, I'm not trying to &#x2013; I am trying to be qualitative because &#x2013; but if you ask us it is our goal to still see pre-tax earnings as a percent of sales improve and get &#x2013; and have a 3 in front of it? Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Fair enough. I may have missed this but any early read on the holiday product? You guys bring your stuff in so early, it'd be interesting to hear. I know September overall was good but how about those holiday seasonal, trim-a-tree, that type of stuff? Any read you are getting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our seasonal sales are good and we brought in stuff in early, we had stuff out there the last week of August, I think, starting to coming in and certainly into mid-September. So we feel good about seasonal merchandise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Colin McGranahan with Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Colin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wanted to focus on the executive active membership fee increase given that you have never had one. Couple questions. One is do you think there's any different there about sensitivity, renewal rates and whatnot?</p>
          <p>Secondly can you give us any sense of the number of competitive members that spend between 2,500 and 2750 because just obviously, I'm playing math. Those are the ones that wouldn't make sense to be an executive member anymore given the $50 to $55 differential?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And thirdly same topic but thirdly in the past you've said executive members spend more and you obviously you've wanted to make more and more members executive. But is there a cart and horse thing there? Do people when they become an executive member actually spend more? Or are people who are spending more naturally became executive members?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well on the last question clearly they spend more when they become executive members. They spend a lot more. I've likened it to a TV commercial I saw a long time ago about two businessmen at a business luncheon and they both reach for their wallet to pay for the bill and one says, "Let me get it, I get rewards." The fact of the matter, affinity programs work. I don't know completely why, but you talk yourself into it. Clearly, being an executive member, they buy more.</p>
          <p>I think also we have gotten better at promoting it and communicating it to the member both at, when they sign up as a new member and as well when they are coming through with a big amount of merchandise and what the register &#x2013; what, you know, what the cashier can do when they swipe the membership card and it can show them that based on their prior year's purchases it would have behooved them to become an executive member. So we do a better job of it.</p>
          <p>In terms of &#x2013; let me take the rationale of why we kept the $100, $100 in each of the last two regular increases. When we first did the $100 executive memberships in the U.S. in 1997, I believe the base membership fee was 40, so it was a $60 deal. At the time that we &#x2013; five or so years later when we went from 40 to 45 in the base, our view was, there's lots of members out there that if you took their prior 12 month eligible purchases that how many of them would be at break even or above at 55, 60 versus $55.</p>
          <p>The view was at the time there were 2 million, 2.5 million members that in theory would benefit based on prior year's purchases. Now if we got 10% of them, we would be happy. Again, I can't tell you if it was 10 or 20 or 15 or 22. It was something in those ranges most likely.</p>
          <p>At the end of the day, we did that again five years ago, five and a half years ago. By the way, what I think has continued to surprise us is the increasing penetration of membership aside from that in each of the years succeeding that delta of having, in theory, another 2 million, 2.5 million members going to that bump break even calculation and how many of those can we get? I think we do a better job overall of getting them.</p>
          <p>I think our view at this point is that the membership fee in the U.S. at executive has been at $100 for 11 years, I believe 7 or 8 years or 6 or 7 years in Canada. It is a nominal increase based on the period of time that we're talking about. And keep in mind, it is &#x2013; the fee relates to the core membership in the case of $100, or the $55 as well as a variety of other services. We have many members that, in our view that if they became an executive member first to take advantage of one of the 20 or so services that we offer. And even then they start buying more because they are executive members.</p>
          <p>So the fact of the matter is, it does create loyalty. We have never taken the increases lightly. We &#x2013; we feel very confident that &#x2013; we always assume you are going to have some conversion delta with regard to somebody saying I'll just become a regular member. Some regular members saying do I really need to be a member? You are talking a very small group. We feel very comfortable about the value of our membership.</p>
          <p>As you know historically, when our membership fee structure has been higher than some of our competitors that's never concerned us from the standpoint that we feel that our membership and the value that we provide our member is a good value. And again, we're not, we didn't do it arrogantly. We did it thoughtfully and what we believe is modestly and we'll go forth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So just to follow up on that is the number still today roughly 2 million to 2.5 million members that would be on the margin mathematically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I haven't looked at it lately because in terms of the break even...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is as good a guess as any. It is not one and it's not five so sure. We have not looked at it that way since five years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you're &#x2013; and then I'll get off the phone. You are not concerned about the risk that as you were closing the differential, you were incentivizing more executive members to then spend more. Now you are widening the differential and you are going to lose some executive members because it mathematically doesn't work and theoretically, as they become off reward members, they would spend less?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. It won't be zero but the fact of the matter is that many of those executive members that were on the cusp in that theoretical equation, spend a lot more today. So many of them have gone up, not down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Fair enough. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Chuck Cerankosky with Northcoast Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone. Richard when you are looking at the two-year store opening total, it sounds like you are saying you want to be conservative in fiscal '12 but we could see some &#x2013; a blip in the first quarter of fiscal '13. Would you be willing to talk about a two-year that it would be fiscal '12 and fiscal '13 store opening number and square footage growth rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you add 12 and '13 together it will clearly be more because our expectation at this point is '13 will have more openings than '12.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So maybe approaching 50 in total?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, I would hope so but I doubt it given the timeline it takes and the efforts. I think, you know, we'll be improved in terms of grading down on a scale but we'll have to wait and see. Again, I don't want to lead you astray. They are working hard to get that up. And there's a lot of irons in the fire. And I would rather, you know, look at it conservatively to start with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you switch into another subject, looking at member attitudes as they are shopping the stores, in comparing third quarter to the fourth quarter sales mix, what are you seeing, what are you noticing in how shoppers are behaving in your clubs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know, we &#x2013; the sales accelerated in September versus the &#x2013; taking out all the noise of FX and gas inflation. I mean, sales accelerated. I mean, we're &#x2013; when we're &#x2013; when we read in the, you know, every day about the doom and gloom with consumer sentiment, we see pretty good stuff at our place but we don't take it lightly. I mean we work hard to have that value out there and you know, it's &#x2013; we feel very fortunate but we're also reminded every day by Jim and now by Jim and Craig that you know, the key is the value proposition and being out there and being show time ready every day and having great stuff. And the one thing I'm very comfortable about is that we're doing a great job merchandising right now and we have got a lot of good things going on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Charles Grom with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. Just to circle back on Dan's question on that quarter on quarter. Again I think everybody is probably pretty surprised, including myself, that it's only up 2 basis points relative to the past couple of quarters. I know you are not concerned about it, but can you dig into at least on fresh foods, why &#x2013; you know, if your comps have been running up high single to low double in that category throughout the quarter that your margins would be down in that category? Just trying to get my hands around why.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know us, we like to drive sales. And also, when there is inflationary pressures on commodity items, we're not going to just take the price of something up the next Thursday afternoon to get back to the margin, we're going to lag a little bit. Certainly with volatile pricing on bakery, meat, food court, that's part of it as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay and then were there any other categories within the four key business segments that was negative or was just fresh foods down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think a couple of them were. I'm sorry I honestly just don't have it in front of me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay, fair enough. I know when you guys report your &#x2013; the 10-K that you will break out the segment margins between the U.S., Canada and International, but just wondering if you had that handy for 2011 now that we have completed the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't. I have it handy but our securities counsel is saying I don't because you can't do it until you publish it to everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and then just on the membership fee, wondering why $110? What was so magical about that number? I know in prior conversations that we have had &#x2013; you have suggested maybe it would be $125 and you would do like a $20 coupon. So I guess, just trying to get a sense for why $110? And looking ahead, when would you look to raise the fee, you know, in Asia and U.K. and Australia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well first of all, I think historically when everybody's ever asked about, if you took the $100 up what would you take it up? And I said, look, who knows? You know, if you say what could you do; you could take to 105. You can take it to 110. I think I probably said you could take it up more than that but then you could give some of it back because that would be a big increase on a percentage basis versus the core. Never was there any giant sensitivity analysis of what should we do here. You know, we priced it based on what we feel. We recognize that some of it relates to the underlying membership which allows you to shop at Costco. Some of it relates to the variety of services that are important and valuable that allow you to, that has allowed the executive &#x2013; afforded the executive member. So I don't want to be too scientific about it. You know, we &#x2013; we're retail merchants and we felt that that was the right price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then outside the U.S., plans to raise it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no currently no plans, but things change. Not tomorrow. 10 years from now, who knows? I say that because right now we focus on what we're doing here, recognizing we're a lot newer in other countries and particularly in Asia with our expansion and we'll go from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Deborah Weinswig with Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Richard. This is Nathan Rich filling in for Deb today. My first question is on the competitive environment. Are you seeing any change in promotional intensity or pricing at either the supermarkets or any of your club competitors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The only thing that has been pointed out to me in the budget meeting is more related to holiday, you know a few holiday items like soda pop before July 4 or before Labor Day. Things that &#x2013; those types of items that supermarkets or Walmart would do the two, three weeks leading up. But overall the answer would be no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then I just wanted to comment, or clarify your comments on inflation. You said that you are seeing inflation in food and sundries and fresh foods in the low to mid-single-digit range. Are you expecting that to moderate kind of as we go through the next quarter or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again, first of all, what we know is what our buyers tell us when we ask them. What we know is when we see the LIFO index as an example. The inventory pool of food and sundries year-over-year for all of last year was up 5% or 6%. Now recognizing not all that translates to the bottom line; some of that causes increased penetration if private label which are at lower prices. So LIFO &#x2013; the LIFO index is not an exact science. It is an exact science in calculating the LIFO index, but it doesn't &#x2013; it's not an exact &#x2013; applicable to what we're seeing everywhere. It is a best guess in that, in using that as a measurement.</p>
          <p>So when I say this &#x2013; on a year-over-year basis, we're still seeing low to mid-single. When asked the buyers when do they see price relief? You know, in our fresh foods area, our senior merchandise, merchants there said they expect relief not for three to six months in some areas simply because of commitments made by the vendor for certain materials or by us.</p>
          <p>But some things we're seeing already. So again I think it is &#x2013; on a year-over-year basis there's still inflation. From prices today, again, in the first four weeks we saw very modest, almost no, but very modest deflation, almost flat. And hopefully though over the next three to six months from the beginning of, as of the beginning of this fiscal year that just started five weeks ago we'll see some modest inflation, but there's no way to know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, and then just my last question. Do you have the private label penetration for the year handy and could you just discuss your long-term target for private label.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't have the exact number in front of me. I don't know if we have gone through every department and calculated it. It's in the low 20s. You know, so you have seen the chart that I think Jim put up a couple of years ago that said the goal and it wasn't defined if it was 5 or 10 years but probably somewhere in there. The goal would be to be in the mid-30s, maybe up as high as 37 with a higher proportion in the food and sundries and health and beauty aids and things like that.</p>
          <p>I think that's a stretch goal. It will keep going in that direction. But there's no timeline. We &#x2013; last fall we started, we introduced a variety of things &#x2013; and these are just examples, of canned goods, both fruits and vegetables. We continue to do that. And so there's a lot of nut items and snack items that we have done of late. And we continue to come up with new things. We had shearling boots the last couple of years and some additional apparel items; men's dress pants, on top of the shirts, and so you know, again I think the trend is that direction.</p>
          <p>We're not committing to exact number other than when asked &#x2013; when Jim talked to the merchants in the different departments over the last year, what are your goals over the next five to 10 years you get up to a number that certainly has a three in front of it if we continue in that direction. But there's no guarantee of how long it takes to get there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Laura Champine of Cowen &amp; Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, just briefly, you mentioned that you are seeing a change in trend in electronics. Is that just lapping the deflationary issues over the past year or is there something really changing in the product cycle there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know. My guess is it is only one month. So let's see what happens next month frankly. It is good that it was &#x2013; had a plus sign in front of it instead of a small minus sign. At the end of the day I'm sure it is a combination of things, including timing of MVMs. If you recall, a couple of years ago, one of the issues in things like big ticket items like TVs and at the time laptops was there were fewer deals out there to be had in terms of the $300 and $400 off contributions from vendors to drive it. Some of that picked up. I think it is a combination of things. I certainly believe that our increased frequency helps. You walk into a Costco, what's the first thing you see &#x2013; these incredible high-definition TVs with cool stuff on them. You know, I'm convinced that the fact that our frequency continues to be high, we &#x2013; you know, if it is in front of you some of the people are going to buy it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Michael Montani with ISI.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey guys this is Mike on for Greg Melich. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard just two quick ones, the first one was on dot-com. Did you mention, and perhaps I had missed it, is dot-com now above $2 billion of sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, a little over.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just on the traffic side, for the U.S. can you help us understand, I think it was about 4% traffic trend on the quarter, but how would that split out for the U.S. versus international?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't break it out, recognizing U.S. is 72% or 73% of our company. So it is going to, even &#x2013; I would guess it is lower because, you know, you have a lot &#x2013; when you have newer warehouses, warehouses that are 0.5, 1.5, 2.5 years old, you are going to drive more frequency. But not meaningfully lower.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so similar. And I guess just last I was going to ask about from the executive membership standpoint can you share what percentage of the executive members today spend enough to reach the 2% off maximum of $500.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't disclose that. I'm not trying to hide it from you. Clearly it is a small percentage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Joe Feldman with Telsey Advisory Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning guys, Joe Feldman here. Quick question, a couple of questions. Again, to go back to the fee increase and the timing of it, Richard. You know, in past calls and discussions with you guys, it seems like you made commentary that you were not likely to raise fees unless you felt the economy was in a better position or a little more stable, or that your core customer could handle it, assuming the economy was more stable. I mean, should we read into the raise today that that's the case? That your view of the world is things are kind of stable and okay going forward, or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that in the past when asked the question, and me being guilty of trying to be helpful &#x2013; you say what are the reasons? One reason would be, I think historically I talked about the fact that we have always been confident on the loyalty of our member, that the fact that our renewal rates are high, the fact that we would be confident to do so. One argument against it would be the economy. By doing it now does not imply that we believe the economy &#x2013; in fact I just recently earlier in the conversation said I would think if you asked senior management around here, the collective view is things aren't getting better fast out there.</p>
          <p>So again there's no &#x2013; I don't think you can put all this in and predict why we did it now versus whenever. This is when we did it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, okay. And then another question, on SG&amp;A, for as terrific a job as you guys do controlling expenses and costs I guess we're a little surprised you didn't get a little more leverage with such a strong comp through the quarter and continues to be strong. And I guess I was wondering, is there anything there? I know in the past you guys have done, you know, been generous towards your employees with giving &#x2013; helping offset some of the health care costs a little more than in the past. Anything that you did this quarter like that, or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I &#x2013; we felt pretty good about SG&amp;A frankly. Given our history of where &#x2013; yeah. I did mention, you remember I mentioned the $0.02 last year, the benefit. It was a combination of benefit. I believe one of those, that quarterly adjustment of 10 basis points. That was part of it as well. The fact of the matter is, is that we &#x2013; again, we choose not to do some things that might help SG&amp;A. There's nothing new that is hurting SG&amp;A more. That's &#x2013; we feel pretty good about it and we &#x2013; I think if you look at it we have actually seen the underlying trends, relatively speaking, improve a little bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks. If I could ask one last question. Kind of back to that whole customer behavior standpoint. Are you guys seeing anything within the customer themselves, like you know, is your core customer, are they trading down to some more of the private label so to speak or are they changing their tender. Are you seeing more people use cash versus credit or the size of the transaction, is it a smaller units per transaction? Things like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, tenders have not changed. The ongoing trend is more debit and credit for years. Those are both big numbers now. And so they still grow but grow slightly but we have seen no trend change in it. You know, the average basket surprisingly is up a little. Inflation helps that a little bit but the average basket is up a little notwithstanding the fact that the frequency is up. Because people are coming in more frequently to buy food and my guess is that you would think it would be down a little bit and it actually is up a little and that makes us feel pretty good right now. And again, I think part of that is driving more people in, that &#x2013; the demographic of our members is a little higher end. I would like to think that some of it is our merchandising. And so all those things help, but in terms of &#x2013; we have a little bit of blinders on because our numbers have been pretty darn good and the frequency has surprised us all, that &#x2013; this compounding of 4% on 4% on 4% now for two or three years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No that's great. Thanks for your help.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of, you know, we would say trade up to private label. But in terms of trading towards private label, there's still increasing penetration. Nothing like we saw, and I know I mentioned back in the first half of calendar '09 right after the financial crisis at the end of calendar '08 we saw a higher rate of increase in private label faster. I think I mentioned back then that over a six month period on the food and sundry side of our business, we thought we saw like a 300 basis point delta in sales penetration in private label. That was unprecedented but we're not seeing anything like that. It is still continuing upward but nothing crazy like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, thanks for the help. Good luck with the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Bob Drbul with Barclays.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Richard. A couple of quick questions. First can you give us the D&amp;A from Q4?</p>
          <p>The second question I have is, can you give us gas gallons in September? I don't know if you gave that out.</p>
          <p>And then the third question that I have is, can you talk about the trends in audio? I think you are cycling the loss of Apple in your stores. Can you talk about the trends there a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Depreciation and amortization for the quarter was $273 million compared to $855 million for the year. And what was the other &#x2013; next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gas gallonage in September. Comp gallons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. 10%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And how about trends in audio? Or &#x2013; are you &#x2013; you are cycling the loss of Apple now. Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have never &#x2013; clearly it's down because it is zero now. The fact of the matter is, is that, you know, our &#x2013; at least in September, our majors was up year-over-year so we're cycling it. And we go forth. I mean, you know, Apple has great products but, you know, we're selling a lot of other things right now. There's not a lot I can say about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One last one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Sean Naughton with Piper Jaffray.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. Just on the &#x2013; another question on the private label for you. Is there a big difference between in international markets the exception &#x2013; you know, the acceptance of the Kirkland brand there versus domestic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is well accepted everywhere. Yeah, we have a lot of products over there. The penetration is lower because there is less, you know, when you say in the U.S. there's more U.S. sourced goods than in other foreign countries but it is very well accepted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Secondly just also on international, you talked about half of the warehouses going international in next year in fiscal '12. Can you talk about &#x2013; are you going to any new markets and when would those potentially be on the horizon if not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's probably no new markets in fiscal -- there will not be any new markets in fiscal '12 through August of '12. Whether it is third &#x2013; most likely in '13 we'll open in one new country in Europe and by '14 two new countries in Europe is our best guess and all of that is subject to change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't we take two more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" /> Your last question is a follow-up from the line of Michael Montani with ISI.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi it is Greg this time from ISI. Richard, the $1.5 billion CapEx or $1.4 billion to $1.6 billion, do we consider that the new normal with around 20 openings? Because that is historically high. I just want to know as we go international is just more expensive or dot-com investment? What keeps it at that level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>International is more expensive. That doesn't account for all of it. What it partly includes is the expectation that it is going to be a busy fall next year right after the fiscal year end. So we have got a lot, again, as I mentioned, we have a lot of irons in the fire. So it is a combination of overseas is more expensive. You know, the assumption is in looking at our own budgets that we'll be committing to land and starting construction on sites that don't hit '12 so &#x2013; but higher amount of that now as compared to a year ago. There's probably an extra $50 million in IT as we are in the process of a three year program which inevitably goes longer of modernizing some things and creating a second data center which we have not had before.</p>
          <p>Got a lot of &#x2013; I mean, it is always a lot of money but not a lot relative to &#x2013; so all those things add up to a little extra.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And secondly on the theory of less is more, if you were to look over all of last year that 5% U.S. comp, what would you say was the traffic versus ticket and the ticket how much of that do you think was really inflation at the end of the day?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think traffic was about 3.5 to 4, probably closer to 4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the rest is, everything else. Inflation was probably the biggest chunk of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Perfect. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But Mike, keep in mind, frequency was up though so that by definition brings your average ticket down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're driving more frequency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. One last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that it? Thank you very much, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>