<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1475878" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-05-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>133</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO, Director &amp; Executive Vice President">Richard A. Galanti</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">LIFO</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Guggenheim Partners Asset Management, Inc.">John Heinbockel</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Chuck P. Grom</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">Daniel T. Binder</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Nathan Rich</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Adrianne T. Shapira</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co. LLC">Colin A. McGranahan</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Robert W. Baird &amp; Co. Equity Capital Markets">Peter S. Benedict</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="William Blair &amp; Co. LLC">Mark R. Miller</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Oppenheimer Securities">Brian Nagel</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Christopher Michael Horvers</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Mark Wiltamuth</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Piper Jaffray, Inc.">Sean P. Naughton</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, my name is Dawn and I will be your conference operator today. At this time I would like to welcome everyone to the third quarter and year to date operating results for FY 2012 conference call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. After the speakers' remarks there will be a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator instructions" /></p>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Richard Galanti you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dawn. Good morning everybody.</p>
          <p>This morning's press release reviews our third quarter operating results for the 12 weeks ended this past May 6. As with every conference call, I'll start by stating that the discussions we're having will include forward-looking statements within the meaning of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve risks and uncertainties that may cause actual events, results and/or performance to differ materially from those indicated by such statements. The risks and uncertainties include but are not limited to those outlined in today's call as well as other risks identified from time to time in the company's public statements and reports filed with the SEC.</p>
          <p>To begin with, for the quarter our earnings per share came in at $0.88, up a little over 20% from last year's third quarter earnings per share of $0.73 and a penny greater than the First Call consensus of $0.87. As was mentioned in this morning's release, this year's third quarter included a pre-tax LIFO charge of $6.5 million, or about a penny a share. Last year's Q3 had a pre-tax LIFO charge of $49 million pre-tax or about $0.07 a share.</p>
          <p>A few other items of note when reviewing the year-over-year comparison, again, our sales results, an 8% overall sales increase and a 5% comp sales increase. The FX impact from earnings of our foreign operations year-over-year, assuming FX rates to have been flat year-over-year, that was a hit to pre-tax earnings of about $8 million or also about a penny a share.</p>
          <p>Also, we had a 9% increase in membership fees that I'll talk about. This increase included a small benefit from last November's fee increase in the U.S. and Canada. Also, about $8 million pre-tax or about a penny a share. Lastly, we had a favorable year-over-year income tax rate comparison, similar to what we saw in Q2.</p>
          <p>In terms of sales for the quarter, reported sales were up 8% total, and on a comp basis up 5%. For the quarter both total sales and comp sales were impacted by gasoline price inflation, which was largely offset by the weakening of foreign currencies on average relative to the U.S. dollar year-over-year. On a comp sales basis, the 5% U.S. comp sales increase in Q3, excluding gas inflation would have been a 4%, and the reported 5% international comp figure assuming flat year-over-year FX rates would have been a plus 8%, if you take those two together, they offset each other and the reported 5% excluding both gas, inflation and FX would have remained at a 5% for the total company on a comp basis.</p>
          <p>Other topics of interest, our opening activities and plans, after opening four new locations in Q1, which ended last November 20, we opened two locations in Q2, both in Japan. In the third quarter we opened a location &#x2013; another location in Japan near Osaka, and also reopened our Tamasakai warehouse in Japan which had been closed since the tragic events of last March 11 in Japan. We also relocated a unit in Ontario, Canada and opened two new units in the third quarter as well in Pharr, Texas and Huntington Beach, California.</p>
          <p>At the end of Q3, our worldwide unit count was 602. All told, that would put our fiscal 2012 expected opening schedule at 16 net new units. The ten we've opened fiscal year to date and 6 more planned by fiscal year end here in the fourth quarter. These total 16 would include 10 in the U.S. and 6 in Asia, one in Korea, one in Taiwan and 4 in Japan. A quarter ago I had indicated we expected the total number for the year to be 17. One has since slipped into early fiscal 2013.</p>
          <p>Also this morning I'll review with you our e-commerce results, our membership results and also a further discussion on margins, SG&amp;A and repurchase activities.</p>
          <p>Again, sales were $21.8 billion, up 8% from last year's $20.2 billion and 5% comp. For the quarter, the 5% reported comp figure was a result of a combination of average transaction increase of 1.7% for the quarter, and average frequency increase of 3.6% for the quarter.</p>
          <p>In terms of sales comparisons by geographic region, in the terms of in the U.S., the Midwest, Northeast and Southeast regions were the strongest. International in local currencies, Canada and Mexico were the strongest with Taiwan and Japan being the weakest, mostly due to the small base of existing units in both of those countries and the cannibalization associated with recent openings over the last year, as well as, a year ago, the very strong post-earthquake business that we experienced in Japan in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>In terms of merchandise categories, for the quarter, within food and sundries we had a comp result in the mid-single digit range, a little below where it had been running in each of the past couple of quarters. All subcategories were positive, ranging from 1% to 11% each among those 7 or 8 subcategories.</p>
          <p>Within hardlines, which was in the low single digits positive, the strongest subcategories were hardware and automotive, with electronics being slightly negative for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Within the high single digit softlines comp, small appliances, domestics and apparel were the strongest performers.</p>
          <p>In fresh foods, all subcategories were all centered around the mid-single digit range and as was the entire category.</p>
          <p>Food and sundries and fresh foods continue to experience inflation on a year-over-year basis, in the low single digit range, but we are seeing a little bit of inflation abatement, if you will, in the past few weeks, in fact some price reductions on some food items like milk, cheese, bacon, butter, coffee, olive oil, flour, etcetera. Still some inflation we see in beef and across many of the nut categories.</p>
          <p>On the non-food side, not much inflation expected going forward right now, although probably a little bit of reduction on the apparel side. That being said, you never know until we get there.</p>
          <p>Moving down the line item, the income statement, membership fees, we reported $479 million &#x2013; $475 million versus $435 million a year ago, so up one basis point or $40 million, and then a year-over-year dollar increase up 9%. As I indicated near the beginning of the call, the U.S. and Canada fee increases that went into effect last November benefited Q3 results by about $8 million. Excluding this fee increase benefit, if you will, as well as a slight negative impact of about $3 million from the FX that I mentioned earlier, in terms of assuming flat FX year-over-year, the 9% dollar increase in total membership fees would have been up 8%.</p>
          <p>In terms of membership, we continue to enjoy strong renewal rates which I'll talk about in a minute, and continue to enjoy increasing sales penetration from &#x2013; and membership penetration from our executive members.</p>
          <p>New member signups in Q3 were quite strong, up 9% on a year-over-year basis. Largely that's due to the strong international openings this past year, in Asia and Australia. In terms of number of members at Q3 end, Gold Star we had 26.4 million, up from 25.9 million 12 weeks earlier.</p>
          <p>Business primary at 6.4, also at 6.4 a quarter ago. Business add-on 3.6 compared to 3.7 a quarter ago. That a lot has to do with people convert to executive member and they go out of the add-on category and become a member. All told, we ended the quarter with 36.4 million member households versus 36.0 million at the end of the second quarter.</p>
          <p>And including spouse cards total cardholders, 66.5, up from 65.7, 12 weeks earlier. At Q3 end, our paid executive members were a little over 12.3 million, and increase of almost 200,000 in the 12-week fiscal quarter, 15,000 new executive members per week, that's a combination of new signups as well as conversions.</p>
          <p>In terms of renewal rates, they continue strong, the trend in the U.S. and Canada have sequentially been up every quarter for the last several quarters. At Q3 end, as of Q3 end, our business renewal rates were at 93.6%, up from 93.5% a quarter ago and up from 93.3% at the end of the fiscal year; Gold Star 88.6%, up from 88.4% and 88.1% at the quarter and fiscal year end, so all told, in the U.S. and Canada, 89.6%, versus 89.4% a quarter ago and 89.1% at the beginning of the fiscal year.</p>
          <p>On a worldwide basis, we're up &#x2013; we're at 86.2%, up from 85.6%, a quarter ago, and 85.7% at the end of the fiscal year.</p>
          <p>So all told trending &#x2013; continuing to trend in good directions, notwithstanding the fee increases that we began in November in the U.S. and Canada.</p>
          <p>As most of you know, the increases, we increased the annual fee for Gold Star and Business and Business add-on, they're all now at $55 in the U.S. and Canada. That was &#x2013; and for Executive Member, it went from $100 to $110. As I mentioned, those were effective November 1st but in terms of size it really was effective January 1st. It was effective November 1st for new signups to the warehouse, but in terms of renewers, the renewers started in January and will continue through this December.</p>
          <p>In all, about 22 million members were impacted &#x2013; or will be impacted by this increase, about half of whom are Executive Members and half of whom are the $55 members.</p>
          <p>In terms of timing of these increases hitting the income statement, please recall that the fees are accounted for on a deferred basis, so really the first big impact to the P&amp;L on that membership fee income line will be in the upcoming fourth quarter and into Q1 and 2 of next year.</p>
          <p>As previously &#x2013; as I previously mentioned on the first and second quarter calls, there was essentially no impact in Q1 to the membership line, about a $1 million pre-tax impact to Q2, and as I mentioned earlier in this call, about $8 million pre-tax in Q3 and again, it will be much more meaningful in Q4 and Qs 1 and 2 of next year. It's essentially a 23-month timeline, as I've talked about before, how we recognize the $5 and $10 increases, starting when they renew, with the receipt, the increase is paid, and then spread out over the next 12 months.</p>
          <p>With regard to Executive Membership, also in conjunction with doing the increases I mentioned earlier, we increased the 2% annual reward from a maximum of $500 a year to a maximum of $750 a year based on eligible purchases. While it's still pretty early to see the complete impact of the renewals &#x2013; renewal rates increase, so far so good and in our judgment, we don't expect any issue here.</p>
          <p>Going down to the gross margin line, margins were up on a reported basis, 5 basis points from a 10.50 to a 10.55. I'll ask you to, as usual, jot down the following four columns and five line items. The line items will be: Merchandising Core; Ancillary; third line item would be 2% Reward; fourth line item will be LIFO and then Total.</p>
          <p>And the four columns there will be two columns for each of Q2 and Q3, the Reported column for Q2 and then the second column would be Without Gas Inflation, we try to show you that, compare things on an apples-to-apples basis; the same thing for Q3, so columns 3 and 4 would be Reported and column 4 Without Gas Inflation.</p>
          <p>Going across, Core Merchandise: in Q2 as you recall, we reported core merchandise margin down 25 basis points. Without gas inflation it was down 16. In Q3 it was down 21 reported and down 14 without gas inflation.</p>
          <p>Ancillary: minus 5 and minus 4 in Q2. And in Q3, plus 7 and plus 8.</p>
          <p>2% reward: minus 2 and minus 3. And the same numbers for Q3, minus 2 and minus 3 again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>plus 2 and plus 2 in Q2. And in Q3, plus 21 and plus 21.</p>
          <p>So all told, in Q2 we reported 30 basis point year-over-year lower margin, without gas inflation, 21 basis points to the negative. In Q3, as I just mentioned, plus 5 reported and without gas inflation, a plus 12.</p>
          <p>Now, mind you the big change there is still the LIFO effect of going from $49 million last year in Q3 to $7 million this year.</p>
          <p>As you can see, our core merchandise was down 21 on reported basis, but the impact of gasoline sales now being almost 12%, about 12% of our sales, up a little bit from last year, that increased penetration caused that number taking that out, it was 14 basis points, minus.</p>
          <p>Within the four merchandising categories of hardlines &#x2013; food and sundries, hardlines, softlines and fresh foods, hardlines was up in margin year-over-year, with the other three categories, food and sundries, softlines and fresh foods down a little bit year-over-year. Ancillary businesses and gross margin as I mentioned were up 7 basis points or 8 excluding gas inflation, mostly a function of higher gasoline gross margins and the higher sales penetration as well. Looking at those two together, we did a little better in Q3 versus Q2.</p>
          <p>The impact from increasing Executive Membership is minus 2 basis points, implying another percentage point of sales penetration going to those Executive Members and their eligible purchases and again of course the big delta here looking at these numbers in this way is the LIFO that I already mentioned.</p>
          <p>Moving on to SG&amp;A, our reported SG&amp;A percentage Q3 over 2 were lower or better by 2 basis points coming in at a 9.84% compared to last year's 9.86%. I think the best way to look at this and explain it is to do the same four columns, reported and then without gas inflation and for both Q2 and Q3. The line items would be: Operations; second line item Central; third line item, stock compensation; fourth &#x2013; actually just those three items and then a total.</p>
          <p>Going across, for operations plus 25, meaning that in Q2 last year our SG&amp;A from operations was lower year-over-year by 25 basis points, so plus means good. And then without gas inflation the plus 25 was plus 18. In Q3, it was plus 10 and plus 4.</p>
          <p>Central, plus 5 and plus 4 in Q2 year-over-year. This year in Q3, versus last year, minus 8 and minus 9. Stock compensation minus 1 and minus 1, and then zero and zero. So all told, in Q2 we reported an improvement of plus 29 basis points year-over-year, or plus 21 without gas inflation. And this year, as I mentioned, plus 2 and then minus 5 without gas inflation.</p>
          <p>So a little editorial here. Just like the gross margin percentage, where increased gasoline sales penetration hurt us, it correspondingly helped the core operations in SG&amp;A by about six basis points such that excluding gas inflation, our core SG&amp;A was lower or better by 4 basis points in the quarter.</p>
          <p>And this is despite increased healthcare and workers' comp costs, which together represented a Q3 year-over-year hit to SG&amp;A in the high single basis points level.</p>
          <p>In Q2, by the way, healthcare and workers' comp and benefits have actually helped the year-over-year comparison.</p>
          <p>Payroll, by the way, within the core business was up about 7% in dollars compared to the 8.2% sales increase. Our central expense was worse or higher year-over-year, by 8 basis points or 9 basis points excluding gas inflation. About half of this negative basis point increase is due to higher IT costs related to a combination of things going on including the modernization of our systems and related activities that we've embarked on of late. This includes, among many other items, the re-platforming of our e-commerce site, as well as our move to a new data center in central Washington.</p>
          <p>Central expenses also impacted a little bit, a couple basis points, by healthcare and benefits as well as a basis point on legal fees, which can go either way.</p>
          <p>Next on the income statement, is preopening expense, $8 million last year in third quarter, and $6 million this year, so $2 million lower. We actually opened 4 units in Q3 this year including Tamasakai, compared to just one last year. No issues, simply the timing of these expenses related to the openings, before, during and after the 12-week third quarter in question.</p>
          <p>In terms of asset impairment and closing costs, last year we had a charge of $1 million, this year we had a similar charge of about $1 million.</p>
          <p>All told, operating income in Q3 was up by $67 million, from $556 million last year to $623 million this year.</p>
          <p>Below the operating income line, reported interest expense was lower year-over-year, with Q3 coming in at $19 million this year versus $27 million last year, so about $8 million lower year-over-year. This mainly reflects the interest expense on our $2 billion debt offering and the fact that on March 15 we paid &#x2013; that offering back in February of '07, on March 15 this last month, a month and a half ago, we paid off $900 million of debt. The anticipated annual pre-tax interest savings given that we were paying off effectively 5.4% debt and foregoing interest income on our cash in the 20 to 50 basis point range, is about $46 million pre-tax per year and that's net pre-tax savings to us.</p>
          <p>Q3, this represented a pre-tax savings of interest expense for about 7 weeks or $7 million. For Q4, which by the way, this is a 53-week fiscal year and therefore a 17-week fiscal fourth quarter, we'll get a pre-tax positive bump of about $15 million. So again, on an annualized basis, given where current cash interest rates are, it's about $46 million a year pre-tax savings to us.</p>
          <p>In terms of interest income and other, that was $13 million better, $18 million this year versus $5 million a year ago. Actual interest income was higher year-over-year by $1 million. The biggest components of the $13 million year-over-year change was related to FX impact on our business. I've discussed with you in the past couple of quarters, internally about $4 million of this benefit or this year-over-year positive change related to gains on FX contracts that we look at internally as efforts as part of our merchandising efforts, but on a book basis, GAAP basis it goes on this line. Also, about $7 million benefit of this change &#x2013; increase related to gains on non-functional currencies held in foreign operations, notably like that in Costco Mexico we hold some of our cash in dollars given that we also procure significant goods from our U.S. operation on behalf of that operation.</p>
          <p>For example, so as the dollar strengthened in these past couple of months, Costco Mexico generated a book gain. Half of that is ours since we own half of the operation, but all of the $7 million goes on this line &#x2013; is recorded on this income statement line with the offset going down below in the non-controlling interest line near the bottom of our income statement. A little convoluted but that's how you report it.</p>
          <p>In terms of income taxes, our company tax rate for the quarter came in it at 34.8% versus 36.1% last year. Our lower effective tax rate is due both to a few discrete Q3 items year-over-year, some of which reduced our Q3 taxes versus last year, and as well, to lower income tax rates in several of the foreign countries where we operate.</p>
          <p>For example, the statutory federal rate in Canada has come down in the last year by nearly 2 percentage points and we've seen similar types of things in a couple of the other countries, so not unlike Q2 where we saw the tax rate come down a little bit year-over-year, we've seen this as well and to the extent that it's related to the changes in the tax rates in these countries, that's, at least for now, a little more permanent. Discrete can go either way.</p>
          <p>Balance sheet, was part of the press release, so we won't go into that detail, other than the fact that the couple of metrics we always talk about, the accounts payable as a percent of inventory, how much of our inventories are being financed with trade payables. What's reported on the balance sheet is all types of payables, not just merchandising but construction payables and things like that. So, on the balance sheet, last year it showed payables as percent of inventories as 106%, and this year 104%, so down a couple percentage points. If you just look at merchandise payables, and inventories, it was 91% last year versus 92% this year, so a little bit of a positive bump there in terms of trade payable financing.</p>
          <p>Average inventory per warehouse last year in the quarter was $11.0 million. This year, $11.7 million, so up $700,000 on average per warehouse. This compares to higher year-over-year per warehouse inventory levels at the end of the second quarter of $1.1 million, and $1 million at the end of Q1, so a little bit reduced from those high levels.</p>
          <p>The $700,000 increase per warehouse in Q3 is really spread among many merchandise categories. Obviously includes also the impact of inflation year-over-year. Our inventories, we believe, we feel are in very good shape.</p>
          <p>CapEx in Q3 we spent $278 million last year, almost the same this year, $268 million, and year to date right at $900 million. Given the expansion we've got going on in Q3 &#x2013; in Q4, rather, as well as some ramped up expansion in the first three or four months of fiscal 2013, starting in September. We expect CapEx during &#x2013; for the fiscal year 2012 to be right in the $1.4 billion range.</p>
          <p>In terms of costco.com, currently that's &#x2013; Costco on line, that's a combination of costco.com in the U.S. and costco.ca in Canada, year to date sales and profits up over last year. Our average ticket continues to be a little down given the nature of the types of products that we sell, but our site traffic continues to grow and was up year to date versus last year and to the quarter.</p>
          <p>Lastly, we are, as I mentioned before, we are re-platforming our dot-com site which should be completed and in operation by the end of the summer. Also, as I mentioned, I think briefly last time I was asked about, we are in the process of getting ready to launch our first two applications for mobile, both an Apple and an Android. Those are expected to be published and available within the next few weeks.</p>
          <p>Next topic, sorry. Expansion, again, for the year we expect to open a total of 17 new units, one of which is a relo [relocation], so a net of 16 new units. On the basis that we started with 592, that's a little under 3% unit growth and about 3% square footage growth. As of Q3 end, our total square footage stood at 85.885 million square feet.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, in terms of plans for CapEx for the year, that includes also a little bit of a ramp-up in the first part of next year. There's plenty in the pipeline next year. We currently have 13 openings planned for the September to December period versus 6 that were actually opened in the comparable four-month period &#x2013; calendar month period in calendar 2011. There's always the possibility that a couple of those may slip, but those are all ongoing projects that are in different stages of site work or real estate planning or construction.</p>
          <p>In terms of common stock repurchases, in Q1 we purchased $173 million worth of stock, Q2, $145 million and Q3 $130 million. So &#x2013; and that would put us at inception to date since the middle of 2005, 113 million shares at an average price of $57.12 a share, or almost $6.5 billion we spent on stock repurchases.</p>
          <p>Lastly, our scheduled fourth quarter earnings release, believe it or not, will be on Thursday, October 11. Again, that's for the 17-week and 53-week quarter and year ending this coming September 2nd.</p>
          <p>With, that I'll open it up to questions with Dawn and I'm going to put you on the speaker phone here, Dawn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of John Heinbockel with Guggenheim Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, a couple of things. On the cost side, the incremental IT expense, I assume that has a finite timetable, and I'm not sure what that is, but what might that be, or is there some ongoing piece of that that will be elevated?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you'll continue to see that &#x2013; first of all, you'll certainly continue to see that over the next year in terms of &#x2013; we have a lot of things going on that have all started in the last year, in the last several months as well. And it's hard to say exactly. We're in the process of putting our budget together for 2013 in detail. But certainly it's not going to go from a few this quarter to nothing next quarter. It will certainly be for the next few quarters. Whether it increases beyond there, we'll have to see. Most of those activities are in place and ongoing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the healthcare, was that &#x2013; is that something strange in there in terms of something that hit, or a change in trend, because the trend had been going very much in the right direction. Or is something temporary in there changing that trajectory?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a little of both. A little bit of a change in trend. Frankly, the biggest issue, mind you, you know, in U.S. &#x2013; and U.S. operations, are roughly 70 &#x2013; low 70% of our company, in terms of sales and what have you. U.S. healthcare costs, and other related health/medical/dental/vision, are higher per employee than in the other countries. Overall, we have &#x2013; hold on one second I'm looking at the numbers here. Yeah, so a, as I mentioned, the trend is higher. The other thing is that &#x2013; this is, just for U.S. health and benefit costs, approaching $1 billion and on this number, every &#x2013; at the end of the quarter you also actuarial look at IBNR, incurred but not reported. In other words, you know based on actuarial history that even though &#x2013; as of that Sunday night of a quarter end close, for example, you have employees and their dependents, spouses and children, who have gone to the doctor or had a procedure done or service done, performed, but it hasn't been reported yet to us or the claim hasn't come in.</p>
          <p>So &#x2013; and you know, I call that the big black box, because it's an actuarial number. That actually benefited Qs 1 and 2 by a few million dollars and hurt Q3 by $4 million, $5 million. So again, getting a little more detail, but that alone was, you know, a few basis points swing year-over-year.</p>
          <p>So I can't &#x2013; I think it's a little of both. Claims have gone up. You have a combination, there is inflation in the mid to high single digit range. You don't have a lot &#x2013; you don't have any kind of abnormal increase in participants. The fact that we have, in the last few years, opened fewer warehouses in the U.S, you don't have as many freebies, what I'll call, new employees that are starting, it's a tough economy, not a lot of employees have left and without opening a lot of new units, you don't have a lot of new employees, in the first 3-6 months, they're not eligible for the first 3-6 months based on their hiring status.</p>
          <p>So it's a combination of all those things, but again, a lot of little things just went negative instead of positive in the quarter. I wouldn't read as much into it beyond that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And then finally, when you think about this inflation or deflation, what is your sense of volume sensitivity to those changes in price, i.e. take dairy and produce as two obvious ones. As the pricing comes down &#x2013; down and I know it's going to vary by category, big category and then subcategory, but maybe think about some of the bigger ones what that does to volume purchases? You know, how much more milk are people going to buy, or certain produce items, or apparel, for example.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know, I think different categories are different. I don't know how much more milk people will drink. I think that on &#x2013; the view on apparel, and I'm shooting from the hip here a little bit. The view on apparel, if it's enough of change to get the KS shirt down a buck, that's real, because people notice that difference.</p>
          <p>Where it impacts us a little bit is on some things where we have always been known, as you guys know, to hold the price and I've mentioned on several of the quarters over the last couple years, where we had huge inflation in cheeses, for example that impacted the profitability in our food court because we held the price on pizza. Well, good news, it's coming down, so we're still holding the price, but we're getting back to perhaps a better margin on &#x2013; you know, I'm giving you a single data point item, but nonetheless a high volume item. Those types of things on some of those food commodity items help us in different ways, other than driving traffic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So all in, less inflation, do you think that is neutral to gross profit dollars? I know there's tons of different moving parts, but neutral to gross profit dollars, is that fair? Versus higher inflation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, given that with higher inflation, we tend to lag a little, because of our nature, I guess given a little less, that's good for us. But I'd be hesitant to know which way directly it is going to go if you add up all the pieces. I guess it can't hurt, and it might help.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Charles Grom with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, Richard. It's been a good 2-3 years now that your traffic has been really strong up over 4% most months, and just wondering when you look ahead, you know, how critical a metric is that for you guys internally when you guys look at the balance, your price investments, over the next couple of years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, we &#x2013; it's hard to answer because we don't &#x2013; we kind of give you the aw-shucks answer here, you know, we're always going to invest in price, but it's not something that we look to do forever. We have always felt that you're &#x2013; we're not going sustain 4% or 5% frequency increases. You know, it's still fluctuating week to week up and down a little bit. I mean up, but how much up? And we're still feeling pretty good about the fact of where it is. I don't necessarily believe that those two things are linked.</p>
          <p>I would say that you know, one of the things that, in my view has happened, as we've enjoyed 5 or so percent &#x2013; 4% to 5% frequency increases now compounding for three years running, in my view and taking gasoline out of it, that people &#x2013; that just &#x2013; the sheer fact that they're coming a little more frequently in our view is fresh foods and if they're doing that, there's still a limit to how many TVs they're going to buy, and that extra shop doesn't get the same percentage of extra non-food discretionary items. So to the extent it comes down a little bit, you have a little bit of offset by the ticket may hopefully go up a little bit.</p>
          <p>I'm talking theory here, who knows? But we feel pretty good about where we are and where we're continuing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just to follow up on the gross profit margin question. With, you know, food costs beginning to fall, and holding retail, I mean how much do you think that helped out you guys here in the &#x2013; in the third quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know exactly, honestly. I still feel very strongly that the margins are the levers that we choose to control rather than what's going on third party in most instances.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just my final question is just on store growth. When you take a multi-year view, you know, the pace of openings has really begun to slow the past few years. You know, in the 15-20 per year range. And it's clearly not a capital constraint given your balance sheet. I'm wondering why you guys don't think you can open up more stores. Is it you need to invest more in the real estate team? Is there site issues? If you could, just flesh that out for us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, one of the reasons I went as far out to tell you &#x2013; mention on the call what we have planned for the fall is to tell that you next year is starting off stronger in terms of number of openings. And part of that is an investment in additional real estate efforts. We have more people landed in different countries. And one of the comments I mentioned, I believe on these calls as well is when people have come out or called us, that Craig has indicated, Craig Jelinek, has indicated, a desire to ramp that up a little bit, but do it within the controls that we have.</p>
          <p>So I think that part of it is the switch from international to domestic, having a high percentage of international. There's been a longer window to get those open, the pipeline has more in it and we'll continue. But I think you'll &#x2013; this sounds like broken record, but you know, I can't go beyond talking about the first four months &#x2013; or the last 4 months of calendar 2012 because it gets a little less exact. But certainly, hopefully, and hopefully that's an indication that we'll see some improvement &#x2013; or increase in that number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Dan Binder with Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I had a couple of questions. First on the gas business, the last couple of months you've had fairly high gas prices but the comp gallons pumped, which we sort of think of as a proxy for traffic at the pumps, seems to have flattened out a little bit. I'm curious what your thoughts are on that.</p>
          <p>The second question was related to membership. I think you said your member growth was being in part largely driven by international. I was wondering if you could just give us what the U.S. comp number growth looks like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the latter question, I don't have that detail in front of me. Clearly, it's a lot less. I mean, generally speaking when we have an open &#x2013; last couple of years when we have not opened a lot of international locations, the number might be a couple percentage points to the minus, or 5 percentage points to the positive, depending upon openings.</p>
          <p>Generally speaking, you know, the fact that our renewal rates improved a little and we're still seeing net increases in our total membership base, you're still getting, you know, we're still maintaining that. But, you know, the big difference is when &#x2013; when we opened Huntington Beach, California and I don't have the specifics, just a week or two ago, and needless to say, we have got a lot of units in the greater L.A. market. So a lot of those members are existing members. We're not getting as many new signups,</p>
          <p>I don't have the exact number of how many signups we had as of opening day but it could be 3,000, it could be 8,000, but it's not 30 and 40,000 or 50,000 like we've had in the last &#x2013; in some of these international openings. When I say as of opening day, it's the signups during the 6 or 8 or 10 weeks prior to opening when we have got the folding tables and the flags and balloons out front so people come by and sign up in advance. The numbers are just chart popping in some of these Asian and Australian countries.</p>
          <p>In terms of gallonage comp, you know, our trends, you know, again, for gosh, 6-8 months ago, we were enjoying some months where the gallonage comps were in the 10% range, 8%-10% range. I believe of late it's been in the 3% range, 4% range. And again, it's how much &#x2013; for how long can we sustain that? The fact that gas prices have actually come down a little bit in most of the country, that, you know, that swing does make some changes to that number.</p>
          <p>I think that, you know, again, I don't think we can sustain 10s. I feel confident we can continue to sustain numbers better than the U.S. economy, the U.S. gasoline sales overall which we've done handily and we'll go from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Then, do you have a number on dot-com sales growth for the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't. We don't give out as much detail on some of the components that we used to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Deborah Weinswig with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Richard this is Nathan Rich filling in for Deb today. If I could start, I wanted to get your thoughts on the macro environment and how you feel about the discretionary side of your business right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know, you look at &#x2013; first of all, in terms of our discretionary business, as I think I mentioned, softlines is up in the high single digits. Hardlines is &#x2013; ex-electronics is in the low single digits, with electronics is a little lower because majors is down a little bit.</p>
          <p>And again, this is one person's view with reading the same things that many of you read. You know, our view is notwithstanding our relative sales strength and member signups and renewal rates, all that stuff, we still think it's pretty fragile out there. We are gratified that we can get people in more frequently than we ever have. We believe fervently that's related not only to the extreme value proposition but to fresh foods and gas. And so those are things that have driven more people in more frequently and if we got you to walk in by the TV or the batteries or patio set or whatever it might be, there's a chance you might buy it.</p>
          <p>So we get a little jaded given our relative success out there. But we're &#x2013; we're not seeing &#x2013; we're not seeing any big risk of a big shoe dropping here but we're also not seeing anything that's driving it in a big way that's sustainable right now. You know, you look at the housing starts and you look at these things, they're improving slightly but it's got a long way to go. So we are &#x2013; the good news for us, I think, is that notwithstanding &#x2013; and this is not a change from our position. We've felt this way for a few years now, there's nothing that's &#x2013; there's not a big engine underneath a lot of this. But it is to our &#x2013; to the credit of what &#x2013; of the activities that &#x2013; you know, monetary policy, and good fortune that we have in the U.S. that things are actually growing a little bit, that's a positive. But it's not like we're not concerned about what's going to happen tomorrow in the economy.</p>
          <p>That being said, given that we have extreme value proposition, that we're in and out of seasons early, we are still throughout this last three years, and continuing, we are aggressive on discretionary items, whether it was patio furniture, which we did well with; apparel, which we are doing well with; patio, we did well with the season behind us, pretty much, but so we can &#x2013; in our view, we can afford to be more aggressive even given those concerns in terms of merchandising.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. And then I also wanted to ask you if you think that you've gotten the benefit in your pharmacies from Walgreens being out of the Express Scripts network and if that's driving traffic to the rest of the club as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A little bit, but I wouldn't say that is something that's &#x2013; that anybody has talked big around here at our budget meetings. I'd have to look at it in more detail, but I can tell you nobody has mentioned that being a big reason why we're getting more frequency. What I hear and what we see is &#x2013; when you have got fresh foods being whatever, 12%, 13%, 14% of sales and growing nicely, when you've got gas driving more people into the parking lot and percentage of those, that's a much bigger impact than some modest improvement in the pharmacy scripts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Adrianne Shapira, with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. You know, Richard, if we could &#x2013; when we look at traffic and ticket, we've seen the ticket has been inching down sequentially the last few quarters. I'm just wondering, is that a function of inflation abating and how we should think about ticket if we see continued abatement across the inflationary line; and would you expect that offset in volume?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, clearly some of it is inflation abating. Some of it is increased penetration of private label. I think that &#x2013; that probably continues a little bit. But again, yeah, I use the silly example of cheese coming down, that doesn't affect the price of our pizza. Because we were, no pun intended, eating that increased cost and having &#x2013; and carrying a lower margin. And I think the same thing can be said for some of the raw material products in bakery. So it's not all &#x2013; it's a combination of some things that help you a little bit and some things that hurt you a little bit on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And you know, I guess the last thing is we're always trying to upscale the item and upsize the item.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. So a follow-on to that, as others are also seeing some of those costs coming down, what are you seeing competitively? Obviously we just saw the quarter that Wal-Mart put out there. They seem very committed to the price investment. It finally seems to be working. What are you seeing competitively as others' cheese prices are coming down? Are they starting to come closer to you? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, just following up on the last question, and my response, the other thing that's impacted that number, at least &#x2013; not year-over-year but from the last quarter or two, gas prices have come down and that's in that average ticket and also FX has impacted it a little bit. So &#x2013; year-over-year on FX.</p>
          <p>Getting to the other question, again, I don't want to sound cavalier about it, but our view is we're always fiercely competitive, we haven't seen &#x2013; on a cross retail, you know, every type of competitor basis, any big changes of how we have to react.</p>
          <p>We are always reacting strongly. You know, certainly there's always going to be items where whether it's Wal-Mart or a supermarket chain or Home Depot or Lowe's for that matter, where we're going to respond and get down &#x2013; and come down in price, but there's other things that are going the other way. One of the things that helps us a little bit is specialty items, whether it's, you know, high end nuts or organic items. As we take some of our penetration in anything from ground beef to fresh turkeys to organic milk, our higher end member, we can: A, show a better savings on those items and there's a little bit more margin protection on those items. So all those &#x2013; again, there's 100 different things that are affecting it up and down. I'm not terribly concerned about what you &#x2013; the question you asked of how that's going to impact us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then lastly, just on the 53rd week, any help you could provide us on line items in terms of how the week impacts gross margin or SG&amp;A?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It really doesn't impact it a lot. Most all things are spread over the extra week. So you have an extra 2% of weeks, if you will, you know, one over 52, but it's not like you get a free week of rent. All that stuff &#x2013; there's a small amount of depreciation benefit. Not enough to move the needle a lot. But the big things like vacation &#x2013; payroll, vacation, health benefits, rent, although we don't have rent on all the 20% of our units that we lease. Utilities, all those things are &#x2013; you have an extra week of those costs in that 53rd week. So it's &#x2013; you know, if one over 52 is the incremental weeks, a shade better than that is what you'll see from that week.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, best of luck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Colin McGranahan with Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I just wanted to follow up first on the competitive question a little bit. You know, I think first quarter we're seeing that Sam's on an ex-gas basis had a little better comp than you did on an ex-gas basis. So just kind of curious what you think they're doing right, or is it just a matter of easier compares, and then have you seen any change out of BJ's since they've exited the public realm?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that they're doing a better job than they were before, is what I hear from our operators, to their credit. You know, they &#x2013; I think they had a little easier comparison, but I'm not going to take that away from them.</p>
          <p>On BJ's side, the only thing we've seen is they're still aggressive on openings. They tend to &#x2013; in my view from &#x2013; again the last few months of budget meetings, there's not a lot of discussion at our budget meetings about pricing, necessarily. But more about they're opening new units and they're tending to open these &#x2013; I forget if they're 75,000 or 85,000 square foot units, so they're continuing to grow.</p>
          <p>Hold on one second.</p>
          <p>Yeah, when we do &#x2013; you know, Bob made a good point. When we do our weekly competitive shops and we see those at our budget meeting by region every four weeks here, in terms of the delta of competitive like items, you know, commodities, Bounty paper towels, Tide detergent, soda pop, Advil, you name it, from our own pricing, versus our competition, we're not seeing any big change in those deltas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's really helpful and actually, a nice lead in to my second question. If you look at the underlying merchandise margin, I think three quarters now, some moderate compression on the underlying merch margin. Next quarter you begin to anniversary a much, much more moderate expansion and then in the November quarter, you actually start hitting anniversary on compression. So how do you think about kind of price investment given that you're not seeing any deltas combined with, you know, traffic that has slowed down a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, it's &#x2013; that &#x2013; I guess I don't want to be too assertive or aggressive here. When we anniversary that &#x2013; you know, the next quarter, you're right will be the fourth quarter of this anniversarying of year-over-year lower core merchandise margins. There's no desire here to drive that in one direction, I mean we have always &#x2013; even during these last few quarters, we've stated we feel good about our ability to generate margin when we need to, and still be very competitive.</p>
          <p>So again, I can't predict what's going to happen in Q1, but certainly your comment is a good one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, final question. You know, obviously we get this on a lagged basis, but segment margins, you know, we've had now a couple quarters in a row where the other international segment margins are down, obviously it's a quarter ago, but you know, what's driving that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think two things. The price investment that we've talked about, and also in a couple of those countries, you know, the cannibalization, you know. That's impacted it as well a little bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, thank you very much, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Peter Benedict with Robert Baird.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Richard. A couple questions. First, just on May. It looks like from your reported sales numbers that maybe perhaps the month got off to a softer start. Just curious as to how you've seen this month flow so far. That's my first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't talk about May until we report May.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then shifting over to the accounting for the extra week, how does that impact the MFI? Will you get an extra week of MFI, or is the accounting different on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you'll get an extra week &#x2013; it's daily. So &#x2013; that extra week, you will get an extra week of membership fees.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just lastly, with Craig now in the CEO spot for 5 months, just speak to maybe, are there any strategic differences that you're hearing, seeing from him versus Jim, whether it be on day-to-day stuff, or even capital allocation? I mean, you have got 13% of the market cap, I think, in net cash right now. Just trying to understand some nuances there with him in charge right now. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Well, I think Craig summed it up best when asked the question, by the way he is in Australia today looking at new sites with Jim, and with Jim Murphy, our head of international. And the &#x2013; you know, Craig said it best, he says his goal is A, not to screw things up. And also he certainly appreciates the culture and what we do.</p>
          <p>The things that he's mentioned and that I've noticed as well, is a desire to get a few more openings done more quickly. Clearly his background of 30-plus years in operations, I think I've talked about the fact that certainly he's focused on some efficiencies in the warehouse. The fact that you know, the 8 or so years he spent in merchandise and handing that baton back to Doug Schutt, who is now in charge of all merchandising, and as Doug's &#x2013; most of his career was spent in merchandising. So I think those are positive things for us.</p>
          <p>Again, I don't expect to see big changes. I expect to, again, growth being one of them. I think he's giving Doug and <mark type="ph" /> Jay Reglin (52:05) under Doug a little bit more leeway to see what they can do with dot-com. Although don't expect giant changes. I mean, the more significant changes to start with are re-platforming and adding a couple apps, but the focus is going to be on hot merchandise at great prices and making sure that we're communicating that to our members.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And anything on the capital allocation front, Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the biggest thing on the capital allocation front is going to be, hopefully, a ramp-up in expansion. And beyond that, you know, we just announced another higher than earnings growth increase, if you will, and looking at history of dividend.</p>
          <p>And we continue to buy stock back. But the core issue of having a lot of cash, as you just said, isn't going to go away overnight. Nor do we feel compelled to do it for the wrong reasons.</p>
          <p>But clearly, we do feel compelled to ramp-up expansion and certainly we're doing that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, terrific, thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Miller with William Blair.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Richard, good morning. Clarification on the renewal rates. I think you said that sequentially in the U.S. and Canada you went up by 20 basis points, and then worldwide you went up by 60 basis points. Did I take that down correctly, and I guess if that is...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's &#x2013; I think it was 50, 85.7% versus 86.2%, and it's worldwide. So that would imply a bigger increase in the &#x2013; in the 20% of our company or 18% of our company, that's non-U.S. and Canada. Mind you, that &#x2013; I mean, if you go back to the beginning of time in the U.S, if we signed up 100 members in year 1, about 70 renewed in year 2, renewed that first time. And in year 2 you also had another 100 signups. In year 3, the 70 &#x2013; that new 100 was 70 in year 3, their first year of renewing but the 70 from year 2 in their second year of renewing was a higher percentage than 70. You know, let's call it in the high 70s maybe. And then of course over time when you've got a lot of mature members in mature locations, we're up to that 89 number in the U.S. and &#x2013; 89-plus number in the U.S. and Canada.</p>
          <p>Given that we've &#x2013; and when you're signing up so many more people in a new market, you're also have even lower than 70% rate, I think it's closer to 60 in that first year overseas. But then we're still getting more. I mean, in Asia I think the average number of members per location is almost double the company average. So we're still adding a lot of people over there, albeit at a &#x2013; not only a lower renewal rate. So that's why you see that number jumping implies that, yes, you're having a bigger improvement overseas, but you started at a lower base overseas, lower renewal rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay, I mean on the same maturity level, then, would you be tracking similar to the U.S. and Canada to adjust for that mix effect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'd say no, because you're starting lower overseas. If we open a new unit here in the United States, it's not that new. I mean certainly people know us even in a new state, which there aren't a lot of those anyway. Whereas, over there, it's been a little bit of a positive frenzy and so you're going to get a lot more people to come in to look see and by definition more of them not renewing in that first year. So &#x2013; but relative to what we've seen over the last several years in those countries, I would say that new units are starting off &#x2013; you know, units that are 2 and 3 years old are trending better than the units that we opened 8 or 9 years ago that were in their first, second and third year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and most of my other questions have been answered but one back on the gross margin. As you have a moderation in input costs, should we think of that possibly flowing through to a little bit better margin and then can you just highlight what extent markdowns played a role in this quarter, if it was significant?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Markdowns weren't an issue at all. Relative &#x2013; you know, year-over-year basis. And the first question I can't answer because I would get shot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well maybe in this period as you saw moderation going through the quarter, did that help you as you progressed through the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm sorry, repeat the &#x2013; first part of the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Some of the food costs are beginning to moderate, take Whole Foods, they saw an increase in their gross margin partly from that, I guess I would think that would start to help you on the food side. So I guess I'm curious if that's happening, and if it's not, why not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, you know, again, I think we're always the first to go down, and we're not &#x2013; frankly, we're not really &#x2013; I don't think we even price shop Whole Foods. So I don't think that's been an impact to us. Again, where we're getting some margin improvement on lower commodity costs are those items where we held the price and as I mentioned in previous quarters, and it's hurt us a little bit.</p>
          <p>The fact that we tend to lag when there's inflation, the fact that there's less inflation is an improvement on that. Again, I think those are &#x2013; that's generally been a little better for us than not, but we're still investing in price. And you know, again, it's not completely scientific. We do what we think we need to do, and we think we're driving our business in the right direction and we're stronger today than we've ever been.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Brian Nagel with Oppenheimer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Most of my questions have been asked. But I did want to just touch on the consumer electronics category. I was looking at your stores, you, like others, have started, I think, to really push into the bigger screen TVs, so I guess first question, is that true? And then with that, what type of consumer response are you seeing to these bigger TV? And Richard, maybe just a comment on any thoughts on what we're seeing out of the manufacturers in the TV categories that are attempting to put a process in place to maybe keep pricing more firm?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, our TV sales actually improved throughout the quarter. We are driving bigger TVs, you're right there. You know, so the average price point of our TVs, I'm, looking just at the last four weeks of the quarter, I've got some &#x2013; a little detail, the sales &#x2013; the average selling price for a TV was about the same as &#x2013; year-over-year, which is &#x2013; even though there's inflation. So it's all about driving the customer towards a little bit higher screens. We're doing 60s and 70s and even 80s out there now as well as the smaller ones.</p>
          <p>And the second question, I'm sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>With some of the manufacturer efforts out there now to try to limit promotional activity in their TV sets, have you guys seen any impact from that or what are your thoughts going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I haven't yet, and what I know is what you know, based on what I think I even read yesterday talking about that. You know, we haven't seen the big promotional stuff like $3oo and $400 off on a TV in our MVMs for a few years. And that went to nothing for a while, and then to something and I'd say it's still something. But not as good as it was a few years ago and not as bad as zero, so not a big change yet. Part of that, I think, is that we've tried to drive the TVs toward the bigger sizes, where there's perhaps a little better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep. And then if I could just &#x2013; a separate question, more of a longer term type question. We've talked for a while about the traffic driving benefits of the fresh food category. As you look at the Costco enterprise now, how much more is there still to come from the benefit of fresh foods as far as maybe expanding the categories, putting it into more centers? For how much longer will this be incremental driver of traffic do you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a hard question to answer. I can tell you that, again, when we attend the monthly budget meetings and the merchants get up and talk, they still are coming up with new stuff.</p>
          <p>I mean, I look at something like bakery, which a few years back, after years and years of great growth, was kind of slowing. Well, guess what? Sue McConnaha, our VP of Bakery Operations and a long time employee of Costco, and her staff, they came up with a lot of new items and what we're doing now in that area is there's a lot of in and out items during the year, whether it's the red velvet cake or the cupcakes, you know, not just having the same old great giant chocolate cake and apple pie and specialty breads, artisan breads. So I think we've, you know, we do what we &#x2013; we do well what we do in terms of being merchants and mixing it up a little bit.</p>
          <p>I think there's still &#x2013; I still feel pretty confident when I hear the presentations from the various merchandising categories, particularly on the fresh food side, that we've got a lot of good things going on, whether it's specialty items, high end commodity items from around the world, organic items, things that separate us from our competition and continue to drive our business in the right direction. The challenge is always going to be on the non-food side, and I think we've &#x2013; you know, again, I look at things like apparel where we've driven more business. You see more presentation out there. We've got good comps on that.</p>
          <p>We're always trying to drive the non-food side because we know we've got you in to get the chicken and the paper towels and how can we get to you buy some more of those things? So it's that ongoing focus for treasure hunt and ongoing focus for specialty items. I feel &#x2013; again, it's a qualitative answer, but we feel pretty good that there's &#x2013; we still have a lot of runway but that's partly because Craig is &#x2013; and Doug are pushing that with the buyers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Christopher Horvers with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Question, most retailers saw a lift from the weather in February and March and then some sort of moderation in April. It doesn't seem to be the case for you, so perhaps you can share your thoughts on whether there was any pull forward and if not, why don't you think that it happened?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob is helping me here with this answer. We don't &#x2013; it did happen, but we haven't really quantified it. It's probably not as big of an impact. Certainly we're in 42 states, so we're across the country. Certainly &#x2013; I mean, what always surprises me, that it could be raining and we're bringing out patio furniture in the end of December, the 26th and all through January it's selling like heck, it's selling well because people &#x2013; it's a great deal and people know if they don't buy it now, they may not get it.</p>
          <p>So I think we're a little bit of an unusual animal as it relates to some of the weather impacts. Even seasonal apparel, we're bringing it in a month or two earlier than typically a traditional retailer in those areas would be. So in my view, we don't see as much of an impact of weather even in a geographically discrete area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you're saying there was a small one &#x2013; there was a small impact, but it was small?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there was a small impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then as you think about last year, I think gas prices peaked in May last year, and started out flat to start the year and maybe up 35% year-over-year, in May. I mean, in retrospect, do you think, is there a number you could put out there and say, you know what, in these months traffic maybe got 100 basis point lift because of the gas, but that seems to be in the rearview mirror now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we know it's hard to say. We know that when gas spikes, it helps our frequency and when gas subsides, it hurts &#x2013; or doesn't help it any more, the frequency. You know, we know that every person that comes to the gas station, about 30% of them do come in to shop that same day. Whether they came to shop or to do gas, who knows? But it's got &#x2013; it's got to be a positive. And I can't tell you more than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Finally, West Coast, it's not been in the &#x2013; the best category for some time. Can you talk about if weather actually had any negative impact there or is there something that you're seeing with the consumer maybe feeling better going out to eat more, so, frequency going down, something like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't &#x2013; I'd be hard pressed to know the exact reasons. I know one of the things was is that California, as an example, was particularly strong comp wise, if I go back, you know, when it was a standout for the first time. So it's coming off of some very strong comparisons from a year earlier. I can't tell you that's the only reason, but certainly that was one of the reasons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't we take two more calls?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Wiltamuth with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Richard. Could you give us the number of Asian stores that are in your pipeline over the next 2-3 years, and when do you think you really start kicking up in the mix of international, in the store openings as you look out in the 5-year period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think if you look at this year, you know, 16 of 10 in U.S. and 6 elsewhere, I would have guessed it was 50-50. I don't have the original budget in front of me. Part of that is they do take longer and when they run into a little snag, it's more than a month little snag. But again, going forward, I would say the trend will go from, you know, 6 out of 16 this year, whatever percentage that is. Six out of 16, 37%. I think it will be 50-50, or close to that next year. And a little &#x2013; you know, close to that, and then higher than that in the year following. And that's based on what's in the pipeline now and the fact that, certainly these countries are less saturated than the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How about the number of them that are going to be Asian stores the next few years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, our activity in those three countries started sooner and so there's more in the pipeline. So sure. But again, I can't predict exactly how quickly. But yes. And as I mentioned, the guys are over in Australia for the last 2 days looking at a bunch of sites. So, you know, I throw that in the pipeline, recognizing there's only three there right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you have three Asian stores in the pipeline right now in total?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. There's three Australian locations...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...that are already open. And I'm sure that will ramp up given that we're looking at a lot of sites, same thing with Asia. There's &#x2013; I was just trying to get to that page, hold on. You know, we end the fiscal year with &#x2013; hold on &#x2013; 30 locations between the three countries. And, you know, my guess is we'll have gone in those three countries from opening 2 or 3 a year in the total a couple years ago, to having opened 8 this fiscal year if all goes as planned. And you know, I would say easily more than 8 over the next couple of years. So you know, the trend is in the right direction, in that regard. But again, they take a little bit longer, too. But we've &#x2013; as I mentioned earlier, we have ramped up our expansion &#x2013; our real estate personnel efforts and so we've got more in the pipeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Shawn Naughton with Piper Jaffray.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. So just following up on one of the economic questions on the consumer, obviously a lot of concern out there, a lot of negative headlines. Have you seen any more exaggerated kind of peaks and valleys in your traffic trends on a week to week basis in Q3 versus Q2? And then just secondly following up on the international side, can you comment on how the U.K. business did in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, what was the second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The U.K. business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well, the first question, the biggest thing in the last few months has been holiday shifts, like Easter, Mother's Day even. Those things shift a week or two weeks and it wreaks havoc with our comparisons of traffic and volume.</p>
          <p>There have been a little bit geographically on weather, but nothing &#x2013; that's usually in one region, where if Southern California had huge rain storms for a few days, that's going to impact a two-week period down there, minus and plus.</p>
          <p>In the U.K., it's come off of &#x2013; you know, it has been &#x2013; it's comps in local currency for a few years have been pretty tough for us. Flat to up a little. And they're up a little better than that right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then I guess following up on that. You talked a little about being on the ground with essentially, some people in Europe over the last 12-18 months. Does what's going on over there change anything with respect to the timing of anything that would potentially be in the pipeline or your thinking around that particular market? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it changes the timeline. If anything, given that we'll be using dollars to convert into different currencies, it's actually a little less expensive. I guess, the question is, a little less expensive because you're also going to &#x2013; you're going to be there, the economy is tough right now.</p>
          <p>If anything, it's making it a little easier for us but I don't think it's speeding anything up for us. And again, as our history has shown, don't expect us to go into any country and have 10 locations in operation two years out. We'll open a unit or two in the first couple of years and go from there and see how it goes. And so we have a lot of patience in that regard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks for taking the questions, best of luck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time there are no further questions, sir. I will now turn the presentation over to you for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>That's it on our side. Bob and Jeff and I are around to answer any additional follow-up questions. Thank you very much, have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's third quarter and year to date operating results for FY 2012 conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>