<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1366750" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call - London</title>
    <date>2011-02-17</date>
    <companies>
      <company>807</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Mattieu Rouot, Senior Vice President, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Henri de Castries, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Denis Duverne, Deputy Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">G&#xE9;rald Harlin, Group Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Mark Pearson, President and Chief Executive Officer, AXA Financial Inc. (United States)</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Farooq Hanif</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Kevin Byrne</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Marc Thiele</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Blair Stewart</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Ralph Hebgen</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Oliver Steel</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Mitchell Todd</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Tony Silverman</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well good afternoon everybody, and welcome to our second session of the day on our 2010 Full Year Earnings. This is meant to be a Q&amp;A session but before moving to questions, AXA's management will come back to our main message and financial performance of the year.  And today will be presenting Henri de Castries, Chairman and CEO of AXA; Denis Duverne, Deputy CEO; G&#xE9;rald Harlin, Group CFO; and  Mark Pearson a member of the Management Committee and CEO of the U.S. Life Operations.  Henri, the floor is yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mattieu, and good afternoon everybody.  And since this is supposed to be a Q&amp;A session I'll go briefly through the slides and I know that most of you were already at the meetings through the phone and through the web this morning.</p>
          <p>First point I want to highlight is, because some people are missing the global picture.  We have built a very strong worldwide position over 25 years.  We are the first -- I mean the largest player worldwide in life insurance.  We are the third of the fourth in P&amp;C with very solid positions in very significant markets and this is making us quite confident that we will build this position further in emerging places even if in certain cases we have started later than others.</p>
          <p>Second point, it's the second time in 10 years that we are weathering a major storm and weathering it without becoming unprofitable or without asking for any support anywhere.  Not that we haven't done mistakes. There are &#x2013; we have done mistakes and where we need to learn our lessons and I think we're learning them.  Second message of this slide is 2010 has been an interesting year because a lot of transformation has been going on.  The &#x2013; basically we have started to reallocate our capital more aggressively, you will see that.  We are also more conscious than before that some of you are let's say nervous or have been nervous with the leverage of the Group and we want to I would say reassure you there and tell you that we're going to have this leverage navigating between borders which we think are very reasonable ones.</p>
          <p>Last message of this slide, we are looking at 2011 with a relatively high degree of confidence because we see two things. We see first the global macro picture improving which should benefit us after a difficult 2010, because of rising long-term interest rates, because of accelerated growth in most of the developed countries, because of better equity markets.  But we also have the, let's say the first fruits of our management actions in Property Casualty, in Life and in Asset Management, which we think we'll start to become visible in 2011.</p>
          <p>Just before going to the details of the results I just want to remind you of what are our key beliefs, what do we think the world is and what do we conclude as far as our business is concerned.  The first very important point is still 80% of the wealth in the world remains in developed markets. There was this sort of fashion until very recently which was always the developed markets is bad, always the emerging markets is good.</p>
          <p>80% of the accumulated wealth is still in the developed and we need to be there and there is growth there even if growth is not universal, even if you have to be more targeted and more segmented.  Of course, the second belief is that growth is going to be higher in emerging markets and there we have to accelerate our presence. But basically 80% of the accumulated wealth in developed, 50% of the flows in emerging.  So yes you have to reposition, think progressively, but it's less cultural than what some people think.  Second point, we still think that diversification is a competitive advantage in our business.  We will speak to that; we think that building global positions diversified geographically is in the long-term a very significant advantage.</p>
          <p>Distribution which is key in our businesses, proprietary is fundamental because it's more resilient because you can have good margins even if the costs are higher. But you also need to build alongside your proprietary distribution, new distribution systems, direct and other things to accelerate your growth; you'll see that this is what we are doing.  Last point I want to insist on: active asset management creates value.  That's why we have the asset managers we have.  So what sort of conclusions to do we draw from that.  We will continue to focus on our core business the way we have done it in the past.  We will keep diversifying the growth from a geographical and from a business standpoint.  We want to keep the multi-distribution, multi-access model.</p>
          <p>We want to have, and this is one of the lessons of the crisis, a more agile capital management or capital allocation.  We are conscious of the fact that we have started to show that in 2010, but we're probably allocating too much capital to certain lines of business or to certain geographies and that it will be better to redeploy it in other lines of business or other geographies.  So it's going to be growth in selective profitable segments in major markets and a larger share of the capital allocated to emerging markets. Last but not &#x2013; well it's not last, it's not least.  We want to have a better balance between financial and insurance risks on the balance sheet and we want to focus on financial strengths; it's a point on leverage and more efficient operations.  If I had to sum that up in three words, it's selectivity for major markets, aggressivity in emerging, and efficiency everywhere.  I think this should be the motto.</p>
          <p>Now if we look at 2010, where I think the results are satisfactory in an environment which has been difficult, we are already showing strong margin improvement in major markets, look at the Life &amp; Savings margins, look at the price increases we've been able to push in the P&amp;C business.  It has worked in 2010; it will continue to work in 2011.  Second point, accelerating the growth in emerging markets, Life &amp; Savings APEs are up 25% in the emerging markets or in the high growth markets with the NBV margin at 38%.  So there it's really combining value and growth.</p>
          <p>In Property Casualty same picture, 1.3 million additional contracts coming from these countries or this distribution model which shows that we're able to combine both.  Where we are 2010 disappointing, clearly asset management because of larger outflows both that are in Bernstein and AXA IM than anticipated because of the issue we had AXA Rosenberg where we've lost half of the assets.  What we can say to that is what we have taken very swift management actions. The investment performance is improving and good in both firms.  So we think over time, this is going to work out and reduce the outflows.  I would even say that at AXA IM, if you take out AXA Rosenberg, we had very significant positive flows last year in the other specialties which have worked well.</p>
          <p>Other elements of confirmation within the Group, organization by business line because this is enabling us to increase the efficiency and deliver on the productivity efforts we have to do.  New CEOs in a large number of business lines -- one of the questions raised sometimes is our management succession at AXA.  I think this demonstrates very clearly that there is very significant management depth. Mark is here today, he was the CEO in Japan; he is now the CEO in the U.S.  He will share with you his thoughts on the U.S. market. It's not the only place where we have changed.  Of course we have a new CEO in Japan, we have a new CEO in France, we have a new CEO in the UK with Paul. So we are able to show that the new generation is coming and say progressively taking over.</p>
          <p>The shifts in capital allocation, you know them, I'm not going to insist upon them. But once the Asian deal will be completed we will have reallocated within one year 15% of the equity of the Group.  They are very few large Groups which have made significant moves in terms of <mark type="inaudible" /> over the last three years. I think we are one of them.  There are people who have attempted to do things; there are a very limited number of people who have succeeded in doing things. I think we have been successful there.  We've also been facing opportunities in other places. The Chinese deal is an important one with ICBC because it's really opening for us the doors of the Chinese market to a much larger scale.  We've been doing some deals in some smaller countries which we think will be very profitable deals for us in the long run.</p>
          <p>I wanted to remind you that once the APH deal will be completed, 50% of the new business value in the Life &amp; Savings side will be coming from Asia, and 30% of it from Southeast Asia which we think is very significant and this should be completed at the end of the year first half.  So what do we see overall?  Increase in the Life &amp; Savings margin, new business margin up four points.  Improvement of the combined ratio current year in P&amp;C even if because of natural catastrophes it's less than we were anticipating at the beginning of the year; it's nevertheless two points and we think it's going to go on.</p>
          <p>And adjusted earnings are up 20% which we think is a good sign, enabling us to propose a 25% increase in the dividend.  The net income would have been up 18% if we hadn't had the UK operation, which of course has affected it.  More important for you because many of you've been asking us questions on cash flow generation, operating free cash flows are up and G&#xE9;rald will share with you our view on 2011.  Group embedded value is up, which we think is also a good sign.  And on the balance sheet side our Solvency ratios are up. We think we're well prepared for Solvency II and the debt gearing is at 28 and you will hear from the Denis that we intent to navigate that between 25 and 30.</p>
          <p>We would like to go down progressively to 25 but I mean we think we have to manage that in a pragmatic way because in bad times it's called leverage, in good times when the risk appetite comes back it's called efficient capital allocation.  So I think we shouldn't be too dogmatic about it especially when the generation of cash flow is enabling us to, I would say, see that we can decrease it progressively.  Denis up to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Henri.  Good afternoon, everyone.  I will not go through each slide of the presentation fortunately because I'd like to give you some time for the discussion.  I'll go directly into the Life section. So page &#x2013; slide 20, just to show that on the Life side in terms of new business, there was clearly a difference between mature markets where we reduced our new business by 5% and increased the margin by four points.  And high growth markets where the margin was stable but we increased new business by 25 points.</p>
          <p>In terms of split of Life business as we now do it between Protection and Health, Savings and Unit-linked.  We see that in this new business, which was down 2%, the biggest decline was on the general account savings whether the decline was 11% because we were mindful of the fact that in a very low interest rate environment we're not making any new business profits.  The protection business was also slightly down because we withdrew a non-profitable cancer product in Japan; that's allowed us to increase our margin from 41% to 47%, so very much a focus on high growth markets and the most profitable business segments.</p>
          <p>The earnings on the Life side were slightly up, this was the combination of the following elements: higher unit-linked assets, so plus 0.4 billion.  Higher investment margin for 0.4 because we increased our margins from 68 basis points to 76 basis points, higher unit-linked assets therefore increased margin on that.  And on the negative side, lower technical margin because in 2009 we had positive one-off in the UK and in 2010 our GMxB margin was significantly negative when it was positive in '09 with a part -- with a sudden back, offsets on the expense side leading to a slightly higher earnings in the Life side.  You'll see that our earnings were flat in Protection, growing in Savings because of the growing investment margin and slightly growing in Unit-linked. You see within that the VA portfolio in the U.S. continued to be profitable but well below the normal profitability.</p>
          <p>Moving to P&amp;C on slide 26, continuation of the trends that we have shown in the previous periods where price increases in personal lines translates into higher revenues by 4% whilst in commercial lines price increases of 2% translate in negative revenue growth of 3%, both because we loss some exposures and because we have lowered some insurance as a reflection of the recession.</p>
          <p>Again on the growth side in P&amp;C, a story which had three prongs. Flat premiums in mature markets, 6% growth in high growth markets, 19% growth in direct. We have a presence in direct in 10 markets; we insure more than 4 million cars we are one of the big direct writers. We're not happy with our current year combined at 105.8. This is a reflection of essentially three factors: we still have start-ups in Poland and in Italy. We had had two markets which were severely hit by the specific situation in Korea where the prices have been blocked by the supervisors, and the UK where we had significant bodily injury results threatening. But we believe that we have a strong position in Direct that we intend to grow.</p>
          <p>On the earnings side for P&amp;C our earnings were essentially flat.  Our current year combined improved by two points to 102.4.  Within that we have 1.7 points of weather events, both the storms in France and Belgium at the beginning of the year and the freeze in the UK at the end of the year.  We had lower prior results developments of 3.3 points versus 5.4 last year translating into a combined ratio of 99.1 against 99 the previous year.  Asset management, the story is simple. Improving asset performance both at AllianceBernstein and AXA IM. And in terms of earnings on page 34 you can see that the earnings were down to 26%, but in 2009 where the one-off tax positive at AllianceBernstein for 62 million.</p>
          <p>In 2010 we have the net provision for the AXA Rosenberg coding error of 66 million.  If we exclude those two elements the underlying trends on the earnings is plus 12. And with that I will hand over to G&#xE9;rald for the balance sheet.  Thank you very much for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.  So here let's start with the shareholders' equity. The shareholders' equity is up from 46 to 49.7 billion, mainly explained by the net income, net of the dividend plus the increasing unrealized capital gains.  You can see on the bottom left that unrealized capital gains increased on both equities and fixed income with equities moving up from 2.7 to 3.1.</p>
          <p>Next is the debt, our debt increased from 13.5 to 15.2 mostly explained by the ForEx effect. The debt gearing moves from 26% to 28% within the 25% to 30% range that had been mentioned before by the Denis.  Interest cover is, moves up from 7.9 to 8.5 mostly due to the higher capital gains that we have realized.</p>
          <p>Moving to the EV, so EV is up from 30.4 to 34.2 with the two main elements, first operating return, a strong operating return of 24% at 7.2 with two main components of total Life 6.1 billion out of the 7.2 and second on the other lines of business corresponding to the net underlying earnings, 1.1 billion for P&amp;C asset management and holding costs including the debt.</p>
          <p>Investment experience, negative minus 2.2 explained by the change in the economic conditions and lower interest rates, wider spreads.  Moving to the new business returns, the new business IRR went up from 10.3 to 10.9 explained by two elements: first it's a lower capital requirement, lower new business strength and driven as well by the improved business mix like in the U.S. as will be explained by Mark later on.  As a whole, we can say that we're quite well on track to deliver on our target of improving the IRR of at least 200 basis points.</p>
          <p>Let's move to the Life free cash flows.  As you can see the Life free cash flows increased from &#x2013; in between '09 and '10 from 0.8 billion to 1.4 billion. It's due to the Life operating &#x2013; it's due to the &#x2013; mostly to the fifth generation <mark type="inaudible" /> but as well as you can see in the middle we decreased the new business strain and capital requirement from new business from 2.5 to 2.2. And you can notice as well that we are expecting to increase it again from 1.4 to 1.7 in 2011.  As a whole that means that almost within two years time, we would have almost doubled the free cash flow from our Life &amp; Savings operations.</p>
          <p>Last, here you have the pattern of undiscounted free cash flows on the left hand side, that's on the inforce business at the end of 2010.  So you can see how it will unwind over time over the next years.  So we concerned with &#x20AC;17 billion for the first five years. On the right hand side you have expected cash flows from the new business.  So expected free cash flow should be boosted by the new business that we'll write, but also as well, actions that in order to improve the inforce book and also to relieve more capital on the existing book of business.</p>
          <p>Now I'll handover to Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much G&#xE9;rald and good afternoon everybody.  I have met many of you in my pervious roles with AXA in Hong Kong and more recently in Japan.  And earlier this month I took over the U.S. business after Kip. And obviously I hope to bring the experience I've had in the high growth markets like Hong Kong and Asia combined with working in very low interest rate environments like Japan, where as you know we also had a VA book, I hope to bring the combination of those two to bring some valuable results in the U.S. These are the two challenges facing us in the U.S.</p>
          <p>I'm particularly proud of my team in Japan. We're able to, quarter four last year, pay a dividend up to the Group of &#x20AC;366 million. That was the first time since AXA owned the business we were able to repatriate cash backup to up to the parent.</p>
          <p>With me this afternoon is Kevin Byrne so having just arrived at the U.S. any easy questions I'll deal with, anything tricky at all is going straight to Kevin. So allow me a little bit of honeymoon on that.  Okay I'll give you my view on how I see the U.S. business and where we are.  You'll know that the U.S. has gone through a significant transformation in its product range, withdrawing products, putting into the market innovative new products.  You can see on the top left hand side the strategy is working and working very quickly. At quarter four 2009, 74% of the regular annuity businesses was coming through Accumulator; that's down to 28% now and the new products, Retirement Cornerstone and the Structured Capital Strategies product are taking up just under 50% there.</p>
          <p>On the Life side we saw growth in the year of 3% in terms of volume.  Our overall sales, we gave up a little bit on top line, 5% down in the year. But if you look on the value side, two things: one the new business margin continues to improve, it's increased from 7.3% to 12.4 in the new.  And that's meant all in all new business value in the year is up 60% and that's a healthy growth.  What's worth noting as well is bottom right hand side you can see that in addition to the new business value growth an increase in Statutory Capital from $4.2 to $4.6 to US$4.8 billion, and these numbers are after payment of a dividend of $370 million in the year.  So yeah bottom line there we can pay dividends and support the growth of statutory capital. For those of you who follow risk-based capital ratios in the U.S., our ratio at the end of the year will be somewhere in north of 400%, up on the year I think it was 370 or so one year ago.</p>
          <p>On the VA attribution just to echo what Denis said earlier, but the conclusion here, a positive contribution in both years on the VA side, 159 million in 2009 and &#x20AC;98 million in 2010.  2010 being lower because of the reserve &#x2013; extra reserves for lower lapses that we notified to the market in November time.</p>
          <p>In terms of we're looking at the high level, the basis risk is probably not an issue for us anymore because of the restructuring of the risks on the liability side.  We do have to watch out for high volatility and keep watch on the lapse rate.</p>
          <p>So looking forward just a couple of things that gives me confidence and encouragement. The new products already account for just under 40% of all sales. So the strategy of going out into the marketplace with new and revised products is working well.  We are managing volatility through AXA Tactical Manager.  We launched that in 2009 and we are just &#x2013; we just put that on to the inforce book as well.</p>
          <p>And looking forward for 2011 it's very much an issue of execution rather than new strategy for the U.S.  And on that side I have to tell you I have been very comforted and confident in the management team we have in the U.S. in place today.  No magic bullets, we have to manage the balance right between getting competitive products, managing our risks, and looking closely at our expense side and it's all about growing -- the value of our business growing our underlying earnings and making sure we'll grow our cash flows as well.</p>
          <p>Thank you, very much.  I'm not sure who I'll hand over to now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Nobody Mark because I don't think I need to conclude. I think we will go &#x2013; thank you &#x2013; I think we will go directly to the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Farooq Hanif from Morgan Stanley.  I'll start with a very easy one. What do you mean by aggressivity in Asia, because there are two problems that I see.  Number one, people don't know what capital position or balance sheet they have because of Solvency II and I know it's getting clearer, but it's still difficult to know how much capital resources you have.  And number two the market asks &#x2013; were desperate for pay back periods to be quick, for cash to be produced.  So investing in growth sometimes it takes time for people to see it. So what do you mean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you for the question.  I mean maybe the word aggressive is too aggressive but I want to mean is one of the criticisms we have heard on AXA is you've been late to be in emerging markets.  The reality is, it has taken us 25 years to build the positions we have in major markets and we could not do everything at the same time.  We have started to become more aggressive in emerging markets into 2005, 2006, okay.  We have done significant &#x2013; and in fact if you look at who has been really doing things over the last three or four years, well not many people. We've done something in Russia.</p>
          <p>We've done something in Mexico.  We've done the deal now with APH, which is in the process of being completed after a lot of, let's say, experiences.  We've also been in new countries.  We are not going to waste money in the emerging countries.  What I see is we are more attentive, we know it's important for us to progressively allocate more capital there.  We are ready to do it, but as usual we will be cautious in the prices we pay.</p>
          <p>To that extent, I think the deal we have in China is a very interesting one with ICBC because it is the only venture they have. It is going of course to require capital, but over time with the development of the business and we think it will be profitable very quickly.  So when I say aggressive what I mean is we are conscious of the fact that we need to increase the exposure of the growth to this market at the price of capital reallocation elsewhere.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>[audio break] [Operator Instructions].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One of the big advantages we had in that market is the equity partnerships we had with our banks partners.  That means we can tap into distribution without really upfront cost and it significantly brings forward the break-even point.  If you look at our Indonesian operation for example, the break-even points there are very attractive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So if this was the easy one, we didn't have a difficult one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> from Morgan Stanley too I'm afraid. Just a quick question on the leverage, you obviously talked about debt having two sides, sometimes good, sometimes bad. What direction are going to be trending in going forward into 2011 and can you give us some sort of indications about what you might be targeting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Behind 2011 I think the &#x2013; if you look at, I mean we have to complete the deals which are going on, like APH, which will have a small impact on the leverage.  Beyond that with the cash flow generation and with the return earnings, the leverage should go down. Do you want to be more specific, Denis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, more specific on what you said on 2011.  We expect the leverage to slightly deteriorate in 2011 because we have to pay for the Asian assets that we still don't own.  So the leverage might go to 20 &#x2013; I mean between &#x2013; it's going to go to 27.5, 28. It might go up 29.5, 30 and it should go down to the 29 at year end and to a lower number each year after 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I want to be clear on the lessons we take from the crisis.  We understand that the leverage has been in your mind of a higher concern that in ours and we want to listen to you.  So long-term, we're going to go down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just quick, maybe a quick follow-up on that.  It's obviously too one of the big issues <mark type="inaudible" /> is that, we'll start looking at quality of insurance capital too increasingly in a mix between Tier 1 and Tier 2 and Tier 3. Have you done any thinking around that about what that means to the fall of leverage you've got on your balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in 72 obviously the first question is going to be the grandfathering of our high debt and for how long this will last, and so that's the question that is currently under discussion.  But that will be part I believe of the -- under this two directive.  So, we should benefit from that.  But then the question is going to be what instruments can be qualified for Tier 1 versus Tier 2 and this is something that we are going to monitor on an ongoing basis.</p>
          <p>The good news is that we have no short term pressure on our balance sheet in terms of renewal of our debt. Maybe G&#xE9;rald wants to be more precise on that.  So, we are under no pressure both because we have some form of grandfathering and because the next, I mean the next renewal of a significant amount, as well the debt, is quite remote in the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> said Denis, is that presently keep in mind that we have 6, more than 6 billion of perpetual Tier 1 debt, so that's a competitive advantage compared to a lot of our peers.  And second, we don't have any renewal of debt and the debt &#x2013; hopefully speaking the 16 billion of debt that we have is more than 6 billion, it's 7 billion debt mature. It's 6 billion Tier 2 and only the rest in senior debt.  And we don't have any debt maturing from an economic point of view. So, that includes of course before three years &#x2013;  so that we don't have any maturity in the short term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of questions.  First one is are you worried that too many people are focusing on risk products at the moment?  You've signaled that you're shifting focus to some extent away from savings onto risk. But a lot of people are doing this and will this lead to margin erosion?  Shall I ask my second question or do you want to answer that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Second question is on the U.S.  Are you being sufficiently aggressive to regain market share?  How worried are you that you're going to lose more market share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first question what I would say, no I'm not that worried on the risk products.  Number of reasons, first I mean to start with margins are generally very high.  But it wouldn't be a sufficient answer because it could erode. Second, there is a vast amount of under-coverage.  If there is one area our clients are under-coveraged, including probably this one, it's risk &#x2013; I mean risk protection.  So and the third point I would make there is we have a significant strength which is our proprietary networks because these are ideal sales for proprietary networks.  One of the issues in fact in periods where markets are very buoyant that it seems easier to sell savings products, because there is an easy story to tell.</p>
          <p>When markets are less buoyant, Protection products are a very good sale. And if I look at what we've been able to do, I mean including last year in the French market on the Protection products, we think there is room for expansion there and even if other players go there I don't think it's negative. On the contrary, there is a point where the awareness and the necessity to be covered increases and it's not necessarily bad for all the players.  Take one example, in the continental market, the increased focus on old age dependency creates a higher interest in the mind of the clients for long-term care products, where they are all under covered.  It's good for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Having said that I wouldn't discount the savings product entirely.  I believe that in Europe, Solvency II puts lot of pressure on those -- on the profitability of those products which creates an opportunity for redesign and repricing which all the markets will have to implement.  So we didn't get out of that market first because there is a need for retirement savings and those products need to be restructured and repriced to be more profitable.</p>
          <p>We started to do that in Europe, in France in particular with our Bonus Euro Plus product that we introduced in December. That's elevated  the proportion of unit-linked sales to 20%, well above the market.  We're on a good trend in terms of volumes and there are ways to restructure the savings products in Europe to make them more Solvency II friendly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark you want to take the question on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah just on the U.S. and I'll hand to Kevin to add any other color to it.  I think first and foremost, I've been really encouraged by the size and the strength of the proprietary network in AXA Equitable, 5,000 strong, very high levels of productivity inside the sales force.  When I talk to the operating guys, they say exactly what Henri has just said, over the past few years up until 2008 very much seduced by the VA story.  But we can see inside the proprietary network a very quick ability to switch. And in fact most of the guys in the sales force came from the traditional life insurance side, this is their roots.</p>
          <p>And so I think it's a real asset in the company that we can have and look to expand and it's really good in times of change because they are our sales force and we can direct them much easier than we can on a third party side.  And in terms of the VA market itself, I mean, really our strategy there is one of going after value. In order to do that we put in more innovative products.  We believe that those products will in a market of rising equity and rising interest rates, provide consumer with more flexibility than the more traditional type of products.  So this is our play in that market and we think it's a good story.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wanted to hear about the wholesale...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, wholesale side, we still have a long way to go in terms of getting on all of the approval lists. So we see some upside there, in particular on our new products, Retirement Cornerstone and the SCS product as well.  How did I do, Kevin, do you want to add anything to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The only thing I would say to that is we're not really targeting market share. We recognize in certain periods that some players will be more aggressive in market share than we will.  We've made lots of progress over the last year on our Retirement Cornerstone. We started out effectively in zero and now it's selling a greater extent than the traditional cumulative product. So we hope that our progress will go into the next year and we are very encouraged by actions this year. Of course we would like a higher level of sales and there are certain platforms we'd like to make more progress and we will continue to work on those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Marc Thiele from UBS.  My first question is on RESO-Garantia, I thought there was a call option when you acquired the company that could be exercised end of 2010 and end of '11. Presumably you haven't exercised it yet but can you remind us regarding the price formula?  Then the second question, on one of the slides I think it says there will be an Investor Day on the 1st of June when you update on initiatives. I mean what do you plan to do, revise already the November targets that you've given for the efficiencies? I mean what should we expect broadly speaking?  And then number three is on the tax rate, will we move back to a normal tax rate in a gradual process or should we pencil in a low tax rate for '11 and then jump back to normal in 2012, or already going back in 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take the first and the last question and let Henri talk about the second one.  So, on the RESO-Garantia you are right Marc we have, we have two call options.  One in 2010, one in 2011 at the formula.  The formula was less attractive in our entry price and we've decided that it was not the right price in 2010.  The upstream remains in existence in 2011 and time will tell whether we exercise the option at that price.  We are happy with development of the business as it currently stands.</p>
          <p>We believe it's the best P&amp;C insurance franchise in Russia.  It's in line with its plans in terms of profitability, slightly below in terms of volume because the price of oil has not evolved as expected when we first entered and the price of oil has a huge bearing on the Russian economy and the sale of new gas which itself is a major trigger for the insurance market.  So nothing more to say on RESO. We are happy with our current investments; time will tell whether we exercise the option and if not we will be a happy minority shareholder of a growing and profitable business in Russia until circumstances change and we find different agreements with the majority shareholders.</p>
          <p>As far as our tax rate is concerned, our tax rates was two points higher in '10 than it was in '09, but it was still benefiting from significant positive one-offs. It's always very difficult in the very beginning of the year to "guesstimate" a tax rate.  We believe that we still should have some positives because we are usually reserving taxes in a conservative way.  On the other side, whereas in the &#x2013; between 2000 and 2007 there was a trend to reduce corporate tax rates around the world.  The trend is rather moving in the other direction right now.  So you should expect that medium term the tax rate should be probably higher than it has been in 2010.  So I mean I would hesitate to give you a guidance but I believe estimating that medium term tax rate 2% -- two points higher would be a reasonable assumption.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as '10 is concerned, we have the details for Life '10 and Life on page 11 and 25 of the appendix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the operating Marc, in the Analyst Meeting in June, ambitious <mark type="inaudible" /> ambitious plan, we do not think we have exhausted on our side the degree of visibility and granularity we want to give to you on the actions, which are I would say supporting these plans, never have we exhausted the question coming from your side.  So we want to give you more visibility on what the developments of the company is going to be for the next five years; don't expect it to be a revolution.  I mean it's going to be an evolution but with some strong components I would say and centered around what I said before, which is selectivity, efficiency and more aggresivity in the places where we think we can capture growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Blair Stewart from BofA/Merrill.  And just one question on the Life free cash flow number of 1.7, looking at the appendix clearly that's a derivative of two items there, the cash flow and the amount of new business investment.  Could you just explain what the thinking is in getting to that 1.7, if it's a &#x2013; the extent to which it's an increase in the cash flow versus a reduction in your new business spend.  And on top of that, if there is a reduction in new business spend, which areas are feeling that the most, and could you have been more aggressive to push the cash flow out even more quickly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe you can go to page 10 of the appendix, and on page 10 of the appendix you will get the answer of, to your &#x2013; to the impact of new business investment here. By new business investment we include the capital for new business as well as the new business trend. And you can see that there are one area where we reduced the new business investment which is the U.S., and in the U.S. it's due to the new products.  We mentioned before retirement cornerstone mentioned by Mark and Kevin and it's less capital intensive.  We have other examples. In the UK, you can see also that we -- the new things we saw the new business, we have less capital intensive business and other examples there.  So that's examples we are working on and we are working almost everywhere in all the entity in order to get it more efficient and to be sure that we invest our capital for new business in an efficient way.</p>
          <p>On the insurance book of business which the other part of your question if I well understood, what we are doing is much more focusing on ways to improve the business that means that soft hand products where the profitability is low, we can change modify the products.  We can in some extreme stop the products and that's what we're doing.  We sold our entities and on a regular way.  So that's why we have the capacity in at least the next year to be quite comfortable in increasing from 1.4, this year sorry, increasing from 1.4 to 1.7 the net cash flow in that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks G&#xE9;rald, that's very useful but the question was more on what went into the planning process for 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What went into the planning process for 2011. So which parts of the, I can see what's happened in 2010, the reduction in the U.S., reduction in the UK. But what's gone into the planning process for 2011? Which markets are not seeing the levels of new business spend as we saw in 2010?  For example why are you committing 600 and odd million in France when the IRRs are low and the paybacks are still relatively high, et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  We -- I won't go into the detail after all the detail on country but just you mentioned France, so in France it's by definition will increase as a percentage of unit-linked.  Unit-linked, we get in France at least an IRR almost of 14%.  So you can see that as we said before, we're 20%. So moving again as a percentage will increase on a relative basis the IRR and this is good news.  And then we have other areas, in the U.S. the improvement in the market means also that the IRR in the U.S. should slightly go up next year, so, and we're working again on all the different countries and all the different products in our planning process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Firstly on &#x2013; under what circumstances does the dividend payout move up to the top of the range of 40% to 50% because I never have seen it anywhere other than 40%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was at 43% in 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh I'm sorry.  My question still stands okay.  Secondly, cash flow after dividend gives you sort of 1 billion and 1 billion and a bit to spend on, changing the balance of the group between the growth markets and the established markets.  And what portion of the underlying earnings would you like from growth markets in five years time and can you achieve that by the reinvestment of organic cash flow in growth markets.  I mean you given the example that you're happy with RESO-Garantia, which I think made a return on investment of 3.8% last year.  One would hope for more than that. And finally, AXA APH what will be the impact on underlying and this year of moving that. Will it be a material factor which we need to think about for 2011 forecast, or is it sort of <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So dividend payouts, I think you are starting to think the way we're thinking about our business.  If we want to increase the proportion of the directed weights of high growth markets we have to invest further in those markets.  We will have to invest further organically; just to give you an example, our JV with ICBC we expect to have a very significant growth, but we also expect to invest 0.5 billion for our share of this business in the next five years given the growth of the business.  So I mean you cannot have high growth in the high growth markets and no investment in the business.  So that's part of the answer.  Therefore you shouldn't expect our payout ratio in terms of dividend to grow to 50% because we believe that we have...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good opportunities to invest in the business.  Now proportion of underlying earnings in high growth markets will probably, something like double in five years organically and....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>These will go first on the underlying earnings....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the impact of....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of APH.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of APH I think is something like a &#x20AC;100 million of earnings in 2011...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On a full year basis and we're not going to have a full year....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but anyway it should be around &#x2013; if you take the 2010, the 2010 contribution of Asia it was 268 and for Australia and New Zealand, 152.  So taking into account the fact that we'll get rid of 54% of Australia and New Zealand and get 100% of Asia that's <mark type="inaudible" /> 100.  In terms of yeah, that's what I can tell you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, going back to the question of how much can we invest and is it enough to be satisfactory for emerging market presence. This is a discussion that occupies our thoughts, occupies the thoughts of our Board.  And if we want to have a higher proportion than the one I've just described, we will have to make more disposals in mature markets to invest more into emerging.  But at the same time as you pointed out when you invest in high growth markets usually you will have high PE for those investments therefore the organic growth is giving us a much better return than making expensive acquisitions. And we'll have to weigh all those factors in our strategy going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to be clear, when you say high growth markets will double in five years, where is it now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's 7%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>7%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello again, Farooq from Morgan Stanley.  I'm looking at slide 18, the margin analysis by business line.  And it's really confusing because the drop in technical margin and you linked those &#x2013; you've got a growth loss, but then your acquisition expenses have gone down. You tell us also that the technical margin is $1 billion over just over $1 billion lower than last year.  How do we navigate this in our forecasts and what do we think is a sustainable level given current conditions, given lack of one-offs. Could you help us with that because it's very difficult to model?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So what I could say is that when you take the technical margin excluding the GMWB hedging losses that are highlighted, we can consider that we are roughly at a level of technical margin which is stable.  So that's &#x2013; and we can go into more detail on this, but you will see on that &#x2013; okay, yes, you go to page 16 that the Life and Savings margin focus and technical margin and you can see that here we split &#x2013; yes, we can get it on the screen.  We have split it into &#x2013; in fact first, the gross mortality and morbidity margin pre-tax, and the second is variable annuity hedging margin.</p>
          <p>And you can see that in 2010 we were at $1.6 billion of gross mortality and morbidity margin.  Explained on the right you have the, you remember that last year in '09 we had the annuity one-off gain in the UK and we had some reclassification in France.  So, 1.6 is a good level; it's a level which we can consider as sustainable.</p>
          <p>Then the second point relates to the gross variable annuity and here it depends on different factors, starting first with the volatility with different elements, but that's another story and we can consider that -- and in your presentation, in Mark's presentation if you go back to it, you will see the different elements of these losses and you will that volatility of course is a significant element and presently volatility is going down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, <mark type="inaudible" /> of it, but also your costs were &#x2013; your DAC was lower as well, your amortization so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but -- you're absolutely, right.  But the net impact as presented before is minus 200 million. So the minus 200 million is the net of your growth cost of minus 808 and DAC  and other elements, taxes and so on.  So on a net basis it's minus 200 and that's why if you want to have a comprehensive view of the contribution of the VA business in the U.S. it was plus 300 million which is I would say is the underlying unit-linked business and minus 200 tax plus 100, 98 to be precise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have a question on the phones.  Let's go ahead with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Jean Dabaque from Cheuvreux.  Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, actually I had a few little questions. First of all I would like to know what is the part of the APs in the risk published. My second question is I well understood that the mortality and morbidity recurring level is 1.6 billion but in the three of four past year it has been navigating between 1 billion to 2 billion.  So can you confirm this 1.6 billion because for our forecasts it is quite important. And I'm sorry to have the last question but could we have an interpretation or read through, through the fact that BNP has reserved its participation into AXA. What are the relationships that you have with the bank, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>G&#xE9;rald, do you want to go ahead with the technical margin thing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes with the technical margin, Jean -- with the technical margin, first yes I confirm what I just said, that means that yes for sure in the past we had plus and minuses.  We've always as much as possible be clear on where it is coming from. And here we consider that 1.6 is a sustainable level and we can expect it. And you will follow-up in June and at the end of the year.  The second question on -- yes what's exactly your question about APs. APs means the future profits part of solvency to discussion and I believe that you're relating to the inclusion of a future premium and the benefit and the profit of the future premium in the recent, in the available financial reporting. It implies....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What was the question exactly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This is precisely my question; if you exclude the risk from future premium even including legally booked future premium, where does it takes us in terms of risk for AXA. I think it's a question also of proportion of single premium and annualized premium that you have in your business mix. I think this is a quite important question for -- given the current discussion with AUP?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But, Jean first of all we had roughly 50% of single premium and 50% of regular premium.  Point number two, keep in mind that the problem of the future profit and the problem of the future premium and what it makes in the risk is not a problem relative to the future investment of our clients.  So, we are not dealing with the traditional Protection products, but it could be a problem for the new investment which are part of the risks and which are already projected in the risk. As far as we are concerned at AXA it's extremely small.  That means that it's 2% to 3% of our VIPs, so it's a clearly a non-issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the question related to BNP, well I think it's a pricing mechanism thing.  The purchase price of the BNP was higher than the price as of the 31st of December.  Our BNP friends are known for their caution. I mean they have taken the reserve and they have at the same time, since the share price has increased significantly since the beginning of the year, a very significant capital gain on it again. As far as the relationship beyond this movement is concerned, we have a very good and a very strong relationship with BNP and nothing is going to change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm Ralph Hebgen from KBW; if you look at slide 17 of the appendix, my question relates to the development of profit by product category.  If you look at the, there was quite a material contribution from the increase in mutual funds.  And I was just wondering whether you could discuss the dynamics behind that and also the, how you see the dynamics evolving from here. Is 100 the new base from which we would have to factor growth, that would be kind?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It mostly concerns today two countries, which are of the U.S. and UK. So that means that it's a capital light activity.  It's a margin activity and it's developing so that's -- you can notice it's a stronger contributor today to pre-tax underlying earnings and it will continue.  So that's a good compliment to say on top of savings products <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And there is another one.....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Also coming from Australia which will disappear, I think another comment that I would like to make on this is that it's very much a function of the evolution of the tax regimes in the various countries.  Gradually a number of countries have removed the tax advantage of the life insurance wrappers, in which case the mutual funds become as attractive or more attractive to the customers.  And we have to adjust to this new environment.</p>
          <p>The way we do it is to more and more offer I would say, solutions like the ones that we're implementing in the UK called Up to the Task which is a fund of funds -- funds of managed assets where we are the fund manager selling to other fund managers.  We've done it in the U.S. now since 1996.  And it's a tradition that we are going to certainly develop to have the flexibility of offering products within a tax wrapper or without a tax wrapper depending on how legislation evolves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oliver Steel at Deutsche Bank.  I just wanted to ask you about the economic capital ratio and I wonder if you could give us a walk through as to how it moved from end '09 to end 2010.  Because I must say I was surprised to see it up on the year.  And then secondly, can you give us some sensitivities around it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>G&#xE9;rald you want to take that question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, what &#x2013; maybe we can go to page 53 and the way I would answer is that as you know...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The appendix, G&#xE9;rald?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the appendix, sorry, that's the appendix.  So you can see the figures that we released moving from 167 to 175 and the coverage ratio is in fact as you know, a ratio which in the numerator is the available time shown resources and in the denominator the economic capital requirements.</p>
          <p>What we have been doing is that first of all as you noticed, the easy is going up so the easy going up means that the available time showed resources figure on going up and at the same time, on the denominator we didn't, we increased only a very small amount our economic capital. How did we --  because it was possible. Normally when you have an increase in equity you are increasing your economic capital by nature. But at the same time what we didn't know that we stated is that reduced the duration as much and we reduced also other elements that we are creating some economic capital. So that explains why.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you reduce the market risk?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We reduce the market risk.  And you can see that we are at the right hand side, we have 52% of market risk and for sure the market risk is the one risk which is the less diversified compared with the others, like life risk and P&amp;C.  So that means that as much as possible we tried to be efficient frontier in terms of investment in order to, as much as possible, increase the investment return without increasing the capital need.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Mitchell Todd from T. Rowe Price.  We've heard some discussion around ambition to the Life business from a product and cash flow standpoint, which would strike me as more medium to long-term. In the near term, can you maybe talk about the levers you're pushing in terms of cash flow generation in the non-life business. There is a number of factors going -- you've offset the price through for 2010, which is obviously going to flow through to 2011.</p>
          <p>We've seen a relatively benign frequency in severity in part for 2010, and we've seen a lower impact from prior year reserve releases, and we're still running at a 99% combined ratio after all of that. It seems that there is a much stronger lever that can be pushed to really take the cash flow up a notch in the near term to a normalized business. What's a number that you're targeting there; can you talk more explicitly on that in terms on what you're looking to do operationally through 2011 to really drive that forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A few comments -- first, I mean don't think that the -- in Life it's necessary only long-term. When Gerald has shown that the free cash flow in Life will double within three years. I don't think this is negligible and once more the organization is focused on using its capital more efficiently.  I think this is going to have effects on the generation of cash flows in Life.  To go back to your question on property casualty and Denis or Gerald will add to what I say.</p>
          <p>First, I mean price increases are a very significant lever and what we can say is that we've been able to push through the price increases we wanted to have with no major losses in terms of portfolio in the various markets where we operate, which we think is a good sign.  Second thing, the level of natural catastrophes in 2010 was slightly lower than in 2009 but higher than what the long term average should be.  We had 1.9 points of natural catastrophes in 2009 which was seen as a very bad year.  In 2010, with the storms in France, with the freeze in the U.K., with the events in Germany and elsewhere we were at 1.7 points. Whereas if you remember 2008 was a year where we were at 0.3 which was probably too low.  So the truth is probably around say 1%, slightly less I don't know, but there is a margin for improvement there because we don't think, I mean even if long-term natural catastrophes have a tendency to go up, we don't think we are at the recurring level of 1.7.</p>
          <p>Next I think the efforts which are done under the leadership of Fran&#xE7;ois Pierson of the global P&amp;C business line to improve the underwriting, to decrease the expenses which has, <mark type="inaudible" /> is going to lead to a decrease of 4 points in the admin ratio over the period of <mark type="inaudible" /> AXA of an impact which should not be underestimated. And what we expect for next year, as we say, this morning in the meeting in Paris is a reduction in the admin expenses of around 0.4 point. What else should we add -- on the -- I would say, what is recurring level of bonus over the years.</p>
          <p>We told you that 2009 was a peak in terms of bonus on previous years released.  We're significantly lower this year but they are still representing something which is not insignificant. Over the long run you should still expect to see us releasing bonus because we are reserving on a conservative way, but it should reverse more to this sort of average long term trend.  So a little bit lower than what we have been releasing this year.  What else would you add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The last factor that I will mention is the issue of claims inflation.  Claims inflation is a big factor in this country; it was quite substantial and 2010.</p>
          <p>Overall across our portfolio we believe that claims inflation was 0.1% in 2010 thanks to the measures that we don't speak a lot about but we continue, which is fighting against claims leakage, fighting against claims fraud, increasing our efforts on claims procurement to move to authorized retailers and negotiate back to the deals with the suppliers.  So all in all, we had a very negligible claims inflation across our portfolio in 2010. We expect it to be slightly higher in 2011, but something between 0.5 and 1%. But we are managing through the claims inflation in a way which allows us to protect the essential parts of the price increases that we are capable of implementing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Tony Silverman, Standard &amp; Poor's Equity Research.  I just wanted to go through the, I think it's slide 17 of the I think on the appendix actually which splits the Life &amp; Savings earnings by product and insurance about 10 billion from Protection and Health has been referred to before; that's obviously much more than Savings.  And there is massive emphasis of the narrative of everybody previously has been talking about, Savings.</p>
          <p>If you could just go back over several years it occupies a large part of the analysis for this industry.  And I was just wondering if you could talk about the geographical spread of the distribution of the Protection and Health product. We probably need to hear a bit more about it; where are they and what are they a bit more?  And the second question was I think I heard a mention of 105 combined ratio for the direct P&amp;C business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not sure, if I missed where that came from in material, or whether &#x2013; if it is there.  But I'd be interested to hear what exactly is being done to reduce that because it sounds like it's a very data intensive underwriting process which would involve quite a reengineering if you're really going to move it by any meanings other than prices going up and the markets helping you out. So, I was wondering if there is anything more fundamental that you envisaged doing there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I mean, on the &#x2013; yes, you've heard 105 on the direct business.  This is the combined ratio, but do not forget that this is mixing direct businesses which has been established now a number of years ago.  And things which are nearly started, as for an example what we've done in Italy.  So, when you have very fast going because it's a relatively new direct business with -- when you mix it with of "more established" businesses, of course you have a higher combined ratio.  We are very confident that the direct business is one very efficient operation for AXA.</p>
          <p>And we're confident -- I mean we have, if you look at the geographies last year, we had a bad year in Korea, where we have a sizable business for very local -- I mean specific reasons, because the prices were blocked in the market by the authorities after a significant amount of claims inflation.  So Korea has been bad news on the direct side and it's positively corrected.  For the rest of it I think we have achieved good results on the businesses which have been existing for a while and strong growth in the businesses which we have been starting up.  We're very confident that direct is creating value for the Group in the long run.</p>
          <p>So the way the ratio is going to diminish is by the expansion in size of the businesses we have started and by the continuous improvement of the loss ratios in the businesses we have since a certain period of time.  I think it's when you have a fast growing business and when you're growing your portfolios, it's something you should see. I'm confident this is going to go down.  On your first question on Protection, we're going to give you some split but there is one point I want to insist on because I think it's one of the points where we could have communicated better throughout the crisis.</p>
          <p>I think one of the elements which have been a source of "worry" for analysts and investors when looking at AXA during the crisis, was the sort of overdependency on financial markets.  And probably in your mind, Savings was more important than the reality reflected by the numbers.</p>
          <p>Protection, which is Protection and Health, which are much more resilient as you see are representing the bulk of the Life &amp; Savings earnings. Of course because the Savings earnings that have been decreased by the crisis but nevertheless they are representing a portion of the earnings which is higher than what many people think. And we think it's a strength of the Group because these are businesses which are quite crisis proof and have as we said before, very good margins going on.  Denis, G&#xE9;rald is there anything you want to add on the Direct business and on the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...Leaving the floor to G&#xE9;rald on the Life side.  On Direct I would say that the bulk of the improvement is going to come from the expense side because as Henri said some of the businesses don't have the required scale. In terms of underwriting we are quite happy with what we are doing right now.  We should also improve the ancillary income parts which is something where we are not good enough, but the two elements are expenses and ancillary income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To answer your question...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Did this answer your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The question I suppose really would be there ex-Korea and Italy, what was the combined ratio on Direct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We probably could take that off line because...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take it off line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay your first question was about geography of the Protection business. And measured as a percentage of APE which is I believe the highest measure, is at the Group level 31% of the APE of the Group. But going into more detail country-by-country, I won't go through all the country but maybe a different block of countries that would be helpful.  France and Germany probably one third -- one third of their APE is in Protection.</p>
          <p>In a country like Switzerland it's 86%; why, because we include in it the Group Pension business which is a mix of Savings and Protection which as you know most of the profitability of this business is coming from the Protection piece.  Then we have a lot of countries like Belgium, <mark type="inaudible" />, which represents between 15% and 20%.  So, two &#x2013; the other countries and maybe I could get some help from you, Mark, is Japan which is 74% and which explains also the high profitability of our Japanese business.  And also in Hong Kong where it's 50% and in South East Asia it's the same, 50%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to add some color on Japan, as Gerald said, it's the reason why the margins are so attractive in Japan is -- there are two things to bear in mind. That firstly, Japan's social security system, if somebody goes to the doctor and gets medical care 70% is paid by the state, 30% by the individual.  So the individual is ensuring themselves against what they have to pay. The plans there are cash reimbursement plans, they're not linked to any medical inflation. So that keeps our claims management well under control.  And second, with the type of distribution models we had in both Hong Kong and Japan, they are proprietary distribution models, we do quite a lot of employer sponsored stuff as well.  So, that helps us maintain those margins and keep the demand high.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We probably take the last question and then Mattieu is telling me that we have to stop.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I'm asking a third question, but -- sorry, but I want to come back to this question that Mitchell asked about the profitability of the P&amp;C business because I can understand that you can reduce claims inflation by getting rid of inefficiency in claims management but right now I mean the inflation of physical goods is going through the roof and it's probably going to keep going. Salary inflation is not great this year but will definitely go up.  I mean isn't it a massive problem unless you start getting higher price increases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No it's not. I mean, I gave you the figures for '10, '11 you can say okay, it's not coming in '11 its coming in '12, but we will have time to adjust our prices if and when that comes.  I mean we are quite confident I mean we improved our currency combine by two points in 2010.  We expect to improve our currency combine by 2.4 points in 2011, will bring it to 100%.</p>
          <p>We believe that we have relatively effective program to improve our claims procurements, to improve our forward and leakage activities and we are very, very confident that we would be able to weather that trend. I accept the point that inflation may be coming in Europe.  I'm not that convinced that it is coming that fast in the year early on &#x2013; but, quicker in the UK and the euro area, but we are reasonably confident that we will be able to adjust with our price increases and our international measures to that environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>