<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1225569" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-06</date>
    <companies>
      <company>140</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Blair Christie, Senior Vice President, Corporate Communications</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John T. Chambers, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Frank Calderoni, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Tal Liani</participant>
      <participant id="5">John Chambers</participant>
      <participant id="6">Blair Christie</participant>
      <participant id="7">Simona Jankowski</participant>
      <participant id="8">Ned Hooper</participant>
      <participant id="9">Ittai Kidron</participant>
      <participant id="10">Frank Calderoni</participant>
      <participant id="11">Mark Sue</participant>
      <participant id="12">Ehud Gelblum</participant>
      <participant id="13">Nikos Theodosopoulos</participant>
      <participant id="14">Robert Lloyd</participant>
      <participant id="15">Paul Silverstein</participant>
      <participant id="16">Samuel Wilson</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to Cisco Systems Third Quarter Fiscal Year 2009 Financial Results Conference Call. At the request of Cisco Systems today's conference is being recorded. If you have any objections, you may disconnect.</p>
          <p>Now, I would like to introduce Ms. Blair Christie, Senior Vice President of Corporate Communications for Cisco Systems. Ma'am, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you, Bridgette and good afternoon, everyone. Welcome to our 77th quarterly conference call. This is Blair Christie, and I am joined by John Chambers, our Chairman and CEO; Frank Calderoni, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer; Rob Lloyd, Executive Vice President of Worldwide Operations; and Ned Hooper, Senior Vice President, Corporate Development and Consumer Group.</p>
          <p>The Q3 fiscal year 2009 press release is on full National Marketwire and European Financial and Technology Wire and on the Cisco website at www.cisco.com. I would like to remind you that we have a corresponding webcast with slides. In those slides you will find the financial information we cover during this conference call as well as the additional financial metrics and analysis that you might find helpful. Additionally, downloadable Q3 financial statements will be available following the call including revenue by product and geography.</p>
          <p>Income statements, full GAAP to non-GAAP reconciliation information, balance sheets, and cash flow statements can be found on our website in the investor relations section. Just click on the financial section of the website to access the webcast slides and these documents. A replay of this call will be available via telephone from May 6 through May 13 at 866-357-4205 or 203-369-0122 for international callers, and is also available from May 6 through July 17 on Cisco's Investor Relations website.</p>
          <p>Throughout this conference call we will referencing both GAAP and non-GAAP financial results and the financial results in the press release are unaudited.</p>
          <p>The matters we will be discussing today include forward-looking statements and as such are subject to the risks and uncertainties that we discuss in detail in our documents filed with the SEC, specifically, the most recent Annual Report on Form 10-K and Quarterly Report on Form 10-Q and any applicable amendments which identify important risk factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from those contained in the forward-looking statements. Unauthorized recording of this conference call is not permitted.</p>
          <p>And I'll now turn it over to John for his commentary on the quarter. John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Blair, thank you very much.</p>
          <p>During the opening comments of the conference call I will focus on what I view to be the key takeaways for Q3 fiscal year 2009. First, a very candid discussion about what we are seeing in the market on a global basis relative to Q3, and its effect on our Q4 expectations, second, an update given our current economic challenges and how we're: first, reducing expenses, second, prioritizing our many opportunities for future growth, as well as how we are third, realigning our resources with a focus on investing in new market adjacencies, emerging technology, and emerging markets and finally, our revenue guidance for Q4 with the appropriate caveats.</p>
          <p>Then I will pass it over to Frank who will follow the opening comments with additional detail on Q3 fiscal year 2009. The third section of the call will focus on our business momentum from a strategy point of view, customer segment, geographic, and product basis. Frank will then follow with some additional financial parameters around our guidance. I will then wrap it up with comments in terms of Cisco's momentum going into Q4 and finally our Q&amp;A session.</p>
          <p>On to Q3 fiscal year 2009 given the many challenges that we are all seeing occur in the global marketplace, was a solid quarter for Cisco for most of our financial measurements and a very solid quarter from an earnings perspective, an expense focus perspective and how effectively we realigned resources to new markets. All of those categories were working well.</p>
          <p>In terms of those areas that we can control or influence, we continue to feel very comfortable with our long-term vision and differentiated strategy as we move into these new market adjacencies and prioritize our existing opportunities.</p>
          <p>Our new organization structure of councils, boards and working groups as discussed in the last call is operating very effectively. These structures allow speed, scale, flexibility, and rapid replication. An example of this speed, scale, and replication is since our last conference call we have added three more market adjacencies to our list which at the last conference call was at 26, these three new ones include virtual healthcare, second safety and security, and, three, smart communities bringing the total of these cross functional priorities or market adjacencies to 29.</p>
          <p>And of perhaps equal importance our largest customers understand how this highly innovative management structure and these business models we've been talking about can launch this many major products into market adjacencies with quality. And that's something probably is the key tipping point we'll talk about more later in terms of our customers grasping what this means in terms of speed but also the ability to move into so many markets at one time.</p>
          <p>We are pleased with our progress in aggressively managing our expenses and being close to exceeding our stretch goal of reducing the total annualized expense run rate by 1.5 billion. Frank, just a tremendous job by the whole team, but you and Randy led that, and I want to congratulate you on that. This was translated from a non-GAAP operating expense run rate that was a peak at a point in the quarter as high as 3.8 billion per quarter. And to the current run rate, which I put at about 3.3 billion based upon the ins and outs that may be abnormal to a given quarter.</p>
          <p>We have also addressed these new market adjacencies with resource realignment approaching $1 billion. We exit Q3 with a compelling financial position and an innovation engine from both products and business model perspective that should allow us to expand our leadership in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>The following is a quick snapshot of our Q3 financial highlights. First, Cisco generated 2 billion in cash in Q3. Frank, right on your forecast you gave me at the end of the last quarter, and remarkably accurate, resulting in a total cash and investments of approximately 33.5 billion. We repurchased 1.2 billion of stock during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share on a non-GAAP basis were $0.30 and GAAP earnings per share were $0.23. This reflected our continued progress on an expense reduction, even better than expected results from total non-GAAP gross margins at approximately 65%, solid service contributions with 9% year-over-year growth combined with our continued progress in core advanced technology, emerging technologies, and our movement into these new market adjacencies.</p>
          <p>Product book-to-bill was approximately one. DSOs were 27 days, inventory turns of 10.7. Revenue was 8.2 billion, a 17% year-over-year decrease. Non-GAAP operating expenses declined 374 million or approximately 10.6% quarter-over-quarter in Q3 and as a percentage of revenue was 39% which was dramatically better than our guidance of 40 to 42%.</p>
          <p>Our internal startups as well our acquisition of small companies continued to fill out our architectural strategies. Our video strategy from the home to the service provider to the enterprise is being described by many of our customers I talked with as world class innovation and execution.</p>
          <p>All of us understand the benefits from TelePresence, which had another outstanding quarter growing over 70% year-over-year in terms of orders and over 130% in terms of revenues year-over-year with 45 new customers in Q3 and approximately 400 new system orders.</p>
          <p>We now have half a dozen customers with 50 plus TelePresence systems deployed and a total well over 300 customers in our total customer base. For the first time we are now seeing some customers talk about hundreds of TelePresence systems and in not the too distant future to dramatically evolve not just their communications within their organization and to their extended contacts marketplace but also changing their business models.</p>
          <p>However, with the pending addition of Pure Digital, with the Flip network video capability, customers are getting the concept of how video plays out from the device through intelligent networks combined with business security all the way to TelePresence.</p>
          <p>In simple terms, any device over any combination of networks, to any content with video and not just the killer application in terms of network loads but probably the most important architectural play in the next generation of the Internet.</p>
          <p>Perhaps the most important takeaway from this quarter in my opinion is our ability to execute and innovate in 29 new market adjacencies, combined with very solid operational execution to accomplish these ambitious stretch goals while at the same time dramatically reducing expenses.</p>
          <p>In summary, for those areas that we can control and influence, we feel we are doing reasonably well. The key market transitions relative to collaboration, virtualization and video networking which will drive productivity and growth in network loads over the next decade are evolving even faster than we thought one quarter ago.</p>
          <p>Perhaps the most frequently asked questions by our shareholders are focused on how Cisco is seeing the global economy, our thoughts in terms of global business starting to level off, and what are our expectations when the possible up turn may occur.</p>
          <p>However, an important point to remember about our vision and differentiated strategy for the future, is it does not very dramatically by month, by quarter, even by year. And while we attempt to be very transparent with what we are seeing in the market and have established a very good track record in terms of seeing trends early, our views do not tend to change every month or every quarter. And even when they do evolve, to change dramatically is really the exception.</p>
          <p>It is with this consistency of staying focused on the long-term while not getting distracted by the short-term market activities that we believe has and will continue to be one of the keys to our future.</p>
          <p>Having said that, for the first time in many quarters, many of our global customers are describing their business momentum in a different way than their prior quarters, that they are seeing some stabilization, a leveling out or in other words, they are finally beginning to have something reasonably solid underneath their feet is how they are describing their current business, as opposed to what has been over the last several quarters a continued deceleration in their business.</p>
          <p>Then, almost without exception, they immediately follow those comments with a comment that even though the business appears to be stabilizing, it is at a disappointing year-over-year growth number.</p>
          <p>No one knows for sure when the upturn will occur, but as we have said in prior quarters, we are going to be very aggressive this calendar year to position ourselves for the inevitable upturn, while continuing to maintain tight financial management and aligning resources to new opportunities.</p>
          <p>Our playbook and game plan for handling economic challenges that we discussed in great detail in last quarter's conference call is simply working very well. There is also a large advantage to having a leadership team that has been through these types of challenges over four times in the last two decades.</p>
          <p>As we have said in all of our recent conference calls, it is very difficult, given all the uncertainties going on in the market, to provide a forecast given the dramatic changes in global markets, and it continues to be one of the more difficult times in my career in terms of my comfort level with the forecast.</p>
          <p>It would not be a major surprise to see the numbers vary either on the positive or negative side of revenue guidance that we provide for Q4. With all of that being said, I still believe that providing some level of guidance is the appropriate thing to do for transparency and for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Also as we've said in conference calls over many years, Cisco will always be affected by major economic changes, capital spending patterns, new and existing competitors and our ability to execute or not on our strategy and other factors as discussed in our SEC reports.</p>
          <p>For purpose of our long range goals as well as our quarterly guidance, we are also assuming that our vision of how the industry and the market will evolve will be accurate and will be effectively executed on in terms of that vision.</p>
          <p>Unlike recent prior quarters our year-over-year order rate comparisons did not significantly change in each of the three months during Q3 and while our forecast accuracy still has room for improvement, our field teams are improving the accuracy of their forecast.</p>
          <p>As a reminder for the last several quarters, our annual order rates were much worse in the third month in each of those quarters, which we then used as the basis for the growth rate that we'd forecast for the next quarter.</p>
          <p>In Q3, much like the majority of our customers, the year-over-year growth rate in each month of the quarter, were well below what we would like to have seen. However, it was consistent for each of the three months from a year-over-year perspective and the first time that's happened in quite a few quarters.</p>
          <p>In terms of linearity within the quarter, month one, month two and month three compared to their counterparts in prior Q3s over the years, the percentage year-over-year each month were much more normal or what we would have expected during normal years.</p>
          <p>And let me be very specific in stating that while the business appears to be leveling out, again at a lower rate than anyone would like, it needs to level out before an upturn could potentially occur. Again, no one knows how long this leveling out will last or whether it will result in an upturn several quarters from now or if there still remains a very real possibility it could still go down.</p>
          <p>With all of this in mind, we continue to provide our guidance, with all the appropriate caveats, one quarter at a time and encourage each of our shareholders to not get too far ahead of themselves in building on the positives of this quarter.</p>
          <p>With this discussion in mind, our revenue guidance for Q4 including our usual caveats as discussed earlier in our financial reports is for revenue to decrease in the 17 to 20% range year-over-year in Q4.</p>
          <p>Again, as a reminder, during each of the past economic slowdowns, Cisco has always navigated very effectively through difficult times to expand our share of our customer spend while moving aggressively into new market adjacencies. As a result, we were better positioned coming out of the transition versus our peers.</p>
          <p>For example, this strategy served us well during the last downturn when our strategic investments resulted in the advanced technology segments which, Blair, I think are about 25% of our business and our new organization structure of councils, boards and working groups.</p>
          <p>In summary, we believe that we are very well positioned in the industry from a vision, differentiated strategy and execution perspective. We believe we are entering the next phase of the Internet as growth and productivity will center on collaboration enabled by network Web 2.0 technologies.</p>
          <p>We will do our best to provide the product architectures and the expertise to help our customers in the implementation of these collaborative capabilities from a technology and a business perspective. We will also share with our customers how we have done this internally. In short we are going to attempt to execute a strategy over the next decade that is very similar to what we did in the early 90s, and as we said before, it powered our growth for a decade.</p>
          <p>Now, Frank, let me turn it over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start this afternoon by reiterating that I remain confident that our financial strength enables us to execute in both good and challenging environments. We believe our portfolio diversification, focus on innovation, operational excellence and speed of execution enables us to effectively navigate market transitions.</p>
          <p>Cisco posted a very solid quarter in Q3 FY '09. These results showcase our ability to manage profitability across varying economic cycles while delivering products and services that provide real value to our customers.</p>
          <p>For today's call, I will provide a recap of our financial results for the third quarter of fiscal 2009 and highlight some of the management actions we've taken to manage through the current environment and position Cisco for when the markets eventually improve.</p>
          <p>Total revenue for the third quarter was $8.2 billion, a decrease of approximately 17% year-over-year, within our guidance for the quarter of minus 15 to minus 20%. Total service revenue was $1.7 billion, up approximately 9% year-over-year with solid growth across our geographic theaters.</p>
          <p>Revenue from our recurring revenue streams represented approximately 23% of our total revenue mix this quarter versus 20% last quarter. Total product revenue was $6.4 billion, down approximately 22% year-over-year. There is no doubt that this has been a very difficult macroeconomic environment.</p>
          <p>Switching revenue was $2.6 billion, a decrease of 20% year-over-year. Modular switching revenue was down 22% year-over-year while fixed switching declined 17% year-over-year. Routing revenue was $1.4 billion, down 32% year-over-year representing a decrease of 36%, 25% and 23% year-over-year in high-end, midrange, and low-end, respectively.</p>
          <p>Advanced Technologies revenue totaled $2.1 billion, representing a decrease of 12% year-over-year. Within Advanced Technologies, video systems declined approximately 5% year-over-year; unified communications decreased approximately 7% year-over-year; and security declined 14% year-over-year. Other product revenue totaled $370 million, a decrease of 36% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Total revenue decreased across all geographies on a year-over-year basis. Quarterly revenue ranged from minus 14% in both European markets and Japan to minus 22% for both Asia Pacific and the emerging markets theater. The U.S. and Canada theater was down 15%.</p>
          <p>Despite the challenging revenue environment, the strength of our financial model enabled us to effectively manage gross margin. Q3 fiscal year '09 total non-GAAP gross margin was 65.1%, above our guidance, up 1.1% points quarter-over-quarter and 0.1% points year-over-year.</p>
          <p>For product only, non-GAAP gross margin for the third quarter was 64.6%, up one percentage point quarter-over-quarter and down 1.2 percentage points year-over-year. Despite the impact of lower volume and increased discounts, the quarter-over-quarter increase was driven by cost savings from better than expected lower manufacturing related costs and stable product mix. We are pleased with the product mix this quarter as we normally experience a slight degradation of margin due to mix. The year-over-year decline was driven primarily by product discounts, pricing, lower volume, and product mix partially offset by cost savings.</p>
          <p>Our non-GAAP service margin for the third quarter was 67%, up from 65.7% last quarter and 60.9% in Q3 fiscal year '08. Service margin performance was better than expected due to strong margins in both technical support services and advanced services from across the board cost improvements as well as some delays in certain projects.</p>
          <p>As mentioned previously, service margin will typically experience some variability over time due to various factors such as the change in mix between technical support and advanced services as well as the timing of contract initiations and renewals.</p>
          <p>Total gross margin by geography ranged from approximately 60% for emerging markets theater to approximately 72% in Japan. Gross margin improved on a quarter-on-quarter basis in U.S. and Canada, the emerging markets theater, which was up 1 percentage point quarter-over-quarter and Japan. Asia Pacific and European markets saw declines in gross margins on a quarter-over-quarter basis due to unfavorable product mix.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP operating expenses were $3.1 billion in Q3 fiscal year '09 down from $3.5 billion in Q2 fiscal year '09, representing an 11% reduction quarter-over-quarter. The quarter-over-quarter improved performance was due primarily to a decrease in variable compensation and sales commission expenses, a decrease in certain discretionary expenses, such as travel, meeting and events, outside services, marketing and other expenses, as well as a benefit of 36 million quarter-over-quarter from foreign currency exchange rates. Non-GAAP operating expenses as a percentage of revenue was 38.6% in Q3 versus 35.7 in Q3 fiscal year '08. The foreign exchange benefit on a year-over-year basis was $137 million.</p>
          <p>I would like to take a moment to thank our entire workforce for their continued efforts to achieve these results during the quarter and help put Cisco in a strong financial position. Interest and other income was $80 million for Q3 which reflects lower net interest income as a function of lower market interest rates and incremental interest expense associated with our $4 billion debt issuance earlier this quarter. Our diversified high quality cash and investment portfolio continue to perform given the challenging financial markets. Our Q3 fiscal year '09 non-GAAP tax provision rate was 22% consistent with the Q2 FY '09 and our expectations. Non-GAAP net income for the third quarter fiscal year 2009 was $1.8 billion representing a decline of 24% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>As a percentage of revenue, non-GAAP net income was 21.5%, a solid performance in this market. Non-GAAP earnings per share on a fully diluted basis for the third quarter were $0.30 per share versus $0.38 in the third quarter of fiscal year 2008, a 21% decline year-over-year. GAAP net income for the third quarter was $1.3 billion as compared to 1.8 billion in the third quarter of fiscal year 2008. GAAP earnings per share on a fully diluted basis for the third quarter were $0.23 versus $0.29 in the same quarter of fiscal year 2008.</p>
          <p>Now moving on to the balance sheet, we are very pleased with our strong balance sheet performance. We continue to further strengthen key financial metrics in spite of a continued difficult macroeconomic environment. The total of cash, cash equivalents, and investments at the end of Q3 was $33.6 billion, up $4 billion from Q2 FY '09 driven primarily by the increased cash associated with the February 2009 debt offering. Of this total balance 6.4 billion is held within the United States. Over the long-term we continue to target a net realizable cash and investments balance of 10 to $15 billion and onshore of 2 to $5 billion.</p>
          <p>We generated $2 billion in cash flow from operations in Q3 fiscal year '09. Compared to Q2 FY '09 the change in cash flow was primarily the result of the change in deferred revenue which was driven by the timing of two tier shipments and the related cash receipts during the quarter. Lower net income and higher tax payments in Q3 also contributed to the decrease in cash flows versus Q2.</p>
          <p>Moving on to accounts receivable, our receivables decreased 17% from Q2 fiscal year '09 from a balance of 2.4 billion at the end of Q3 FY '09. We remain very pleased with the quality of our receivables portfolio. At the end of Q3 days sales outstanding or DSO was 27 days, down two days compared to Q2 FY '09 driven primarily by strong collections and lower service billings. Total inventory at the end of Q3 was $1 billion, a reduction of $84 million quarter-over-quarter.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP inventory turns were 10.7 this quarter down six-tenths of a point compared to last quarter and down one-tenth of a point from Q3 of last year. Our inventory management as measured by turns remains world-class. Inventory purchase commitments at the end of Q3 were $2.2 billion, an 18% reduction from the end of Q2 fiscal year '09.</p>
          <p>For the quarter we repurchased $1.2 billion of common stock or 77 million shares at an average price of $15.57 per share. We ended the quarter with approximately $5.6 billion remaining in the current stock repurchase authorization.</p>
          <p>Deferred revenue was $8.8 billion at the end of Q3 FY '09, an increase of approximately 2% year-over-year. Deferred product revenue was 2.7 billion a decrease of approximately 6% year-over-year while deferred service revenue was 6.1 billion, up approximately 6% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>At the end of Q3 our head count totaled 66,558, a net decrease of approximately 760 from Q2 FY '09. The reduction in head count this quarter was the result of our continued pause in external hiring and the early impact of some limited restructuring consistent with our previously announced plans to reduce approximately 1,500 to 2,000 jobs as a result of realignment and restructuring activities to occur in the second half of fiscal year 2009. At this time, we expect the number of job reductions related to limited restructuring to be at the high-end of this range by the end of the fiscal year.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to highlight how we are utilizing strong financial position to sustain our investment in innovation, drive operational excellence in our business, and ensure continuous attention to our customers' needs. All of which I believe strengthens our ability to emerge from the current market environment as an even stronger force in the industry.</p>
          <p>Our business model provides us with the flexibility to continue to aggressively invest in new technologies and market adjacencies. Through strong portfolio management in one quarter we realigned resources to our top five strategic priorities, launched the first unified computing architecture to the marketplace and increased investments in key customer segments such as public sector. We remain committed to driving operational excellence and productivity improvements throughout the business. Our cost and expense management activities this quarter enabled us to manage our business costs while still investing in areas where we believe we can accelerate development in Cisco's market leadership.</p>
          <p>During the quarter we took a number of actions including reducing travel by approximately 50% compared to Q2, centralizing procurement activities to optimize our buying power, and aligning select core business processes for greater efficiency. As a result, we are well on track toward exceeding our target of removing over $1 billion from our annualized expense run rate by the end of this fiscal year and in line with our internal stretch target of $1.5 billion, a strong testament to the collective execution by our employees.</p>
          <p>I am extremely proud of the financial execution we achieved this quarter. From a working capital perspective we believe we implemented the right actions and strategies to effectively manage our cash flow and protect our strong balance sheet. With continued focus on our accounts receivable and supply chain, including our ongoing review and optimization of inventory levels, we have delivered positive results again this quarter.</p>
          <p>Our non-GAAP inventory turns of 10.7, purchase commitments in line with current demand and DSO of 27 days all remain solid and contribute to Cisco's consistent performance. In Q3 we also closed a $4 billion debt offering, a portion of which was used to refinance 500 million of unsecured debt. The key to our success has been our focus on customer needs and our ability to collaborate closely with them to develop creative and differentiated solutions such as providing extended warrantees across some aspects of our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Our financing arm, Cisco Capital, continues to provide solutions to customers and channel partners that enable incremental sales and opportunities. At Q3 fiscal year '09 Cisco Capital had a combined balance sheet and contingent liability position of approximately $4.7 billion. We continue to see positive payment behavior from our customers and believe there has been no material impact to the quality of our portfolio.</p>
          <p>As I have discussed with you today, we continue to make investments in innovation and new market opportunities. We have continued our emphasis on strong operational excellence and we've sharpened our focus on customer intimacy, all of which we believe continue to position us for future success. We are confident that through continued prudent expense management, calculated investment in high yielding business opportunities, and strong portfolio management we are managing the company to balance the priorities of growth and profitability in the future.</p>
          <p>I will now turn it over back to John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Now moving on to chapter 3 regarding strategy, customer segment, geographic and product review.</p>
          <p>From a strategy review this quarter may have been the most innovative and operationally efficient quarter in our history. The innovation and execution has never been broader and more successful ranging from product announcements, technology architectures and business architecture leadership in our customer's minds. Cisco has had an explosion of collaboration internal within our company enabled by networked Web 2.0 technologies in everything we do. I always listen carefully to our customers. In many ways our customers' feedback on this activity in Q3 was pivotal, truly a tipping point in terms of both their understanding and in many cases their commitment to next generation intelligent networks becoming the platform for productivity, standard of living and global competitiveness.</p>
          <p>In some ways it is difficult to describe why this quarter was so unique, and the rapid expansion of many of our customers' positive expectations of Cisco's ability to work with them in terms of innovation, thought leadership and execution enabled by many of these activities.</p>
          <p>Perhaps the best way to capture and summarize this effect is to give you a series of examples which occurred in this quarter and in total may accomplish my goal in sharing with you what these customers are beginning to see and their total picture and view of Cisco from a partnership and commitment perspective. Not in talking about individual products or architectures or individual services, but in the combination together.</p>
          <p>First, virtualization. Virtualization first in the data center and then going all the way to our homes is becoming a reality, as illustrated by our announcement of the Unified Computing System in March. As we discussed for some time, we are seeing significant market transition in the data center as networking, computing, storage, and software technologies begin to converge and then compete with each other in new ways. Cisco has always believed that disruption creates opportunity.</p>
          <p>We have executed well by delivering innovative solutions and unique ecosystem relationships to address this rapidly changing market. Our Unified Computing System and the Nexus product families bridge the silos in the data center for the first time by creating one unified architecture. There is little doubt this disruption in the data center will accelerate in the next twelve months due to the rapidly changing technology trends such as the rise of scalable processing and virtualization.</p>
          <p>The competitive landscape is changing, and while a new class of very large, well-financed and aggressive competitors will bring their own product categories to address this new market, we believe the network will be the intersection of innovation through an open ecosystem and standards. We will continue to not be surprised to see acquisitions, industry consolidation, and new alliances among companies as they build towards serving this new market and as we enter this next market phase, we will get closer to some partners and compete more with others while delivering the best solutions for our customers.</p>
          <p>What is most exciting about this market transition is the rise of new business models enabled by technology architectures such as cloud computing and the opportunity to finally address customers' greatest needs in terms of reducing costs and complexity by increasing their business agility. Many of our customers believe the future data center can best be enabled by the network, and we think this uniquely positions Cisco to lead through this next market transition.</p>
          <p>The Cisco Unified Computing System unites compute, network, storage, access, and virtualization resources in a single energy-efficient system to reduce customer cost and complexity. In our opinion it is truly a game changer in the data center. However, the technology architecture that occurs first in the data center will expand through the enterprise and then go all the way to the home. What you are seeing is really a new product category in the next generation data center that combines the network, computing, software and storage into one architectural category.</p>
          <p>Second, the second phase of the internet revolution is becoming viral and accelerating at three to five times the pace of the first phase of internet revolution a decade and a half ago. We all understand that Phase I was about orders being entered online, customer support provided over the internet, which Cisco led in internal utilization first and then expanded across multiple industries over the next decade. While theoretical in some customers' minds in the past, the numbers are now irrefutable and our leading edge customers are, for the first time, clearly understanding the impact.</p>
          <p>I am going to provide you with a lot of data each piece being interesting. However, it is the total concept that this data is the key takeaway just as it was for our customers. The following numbers are the growth rates achieved within Cisco in each category over the last twelve to thirteen months. Remembering, we have about 66,000 people. Login at Cisco has gone from 3,000 users to 13,000, a 300% increase. Discussion forums have gone from 2,500 users to over 40,000, a 1,600% increase. YouTube at Cisco which we call Cisco Vision is now used by 54,000 of our 66,000 employees, a 3,100% increase. Cisco's WebEx Connect utilization is up by 3,900%.</p>
          <p>The key takeaway is not just the volumes or a "Back to the Future" type of comparison of what Cisco did in terms of being the first major company to enter orders online or offer online customer service. It is the speed, skill, and replication that we are seeing that allows us to dramatically realign resources, enables us to address what many consider impossible goals: to move to 29 new market adjacencies while also reducing expenses.</p>
          <p>Third, new business models for travel. Using myself as an example, but asking you to think about this concept and how it expands to each Cisco employee and over time each employee of our customers and then how we will work and change work in the future. In the first 90 days of this calendar year I made 262 customer visits, and while I went around the world twice physically, 200 of these visits were virtual through TelePresence.</p>
          <p>Many of the meetings were first time. It has become common to present to an entire senior management team of a global Fortune 100 often a non-English speaking global Fortune 100 company or to even heads of state using this technology. We now average 4,700 TelePresence sessions weekly and have permanently cut our travel budget from the $750 million run rate it was over the last year in terms of a peak to a $350 million run rate per year. And in Q3 during these tough times as you would expect, we actually took that cut down from 350 million to 240 million on a temporary basis.</p>
          <p>Expanding how we are using collaboration and network Web 2.0 one step further in terms of innovation and operational excellence, let me use an example of how we launch our new products such as Unified Computing Systems in March. The bottom line is think about this: key takeaway, one-tenth the cost, ten times the effectiveness. And that's how it compared to examples like our CRS announcement of a number of years ago, one-tenth the cost, ten times the effectiveness.</p>
          <p>At the time of this announcement, we had 4 billion media impact. We had 13 live TelePresence locations combined in 11 cities for the initial announcement that did not include customers. 53 active attendees including six partner CEOs, 11 industry analysts, 35 press, 7 financial analysts in various locations and 832 virtual Cisco TV viewers that were invited to the session.</p>
          <p>Following the formal announcement was a customer announcement, 483 customers in the room and over 6,000 virtual attendees. Record traffic resulted in News@Cisco online: 85,000 views. Usage of Flickr, social networking photo site exploded to 32,000 hits. Record high traffic on Cisco Blogs just a platform blog or loan player hit 18,000 hits.</p>
          <p>Point four, Video architecture. Think of the recently announced acquisition of Pure Digital Flip as a tipping point in our enterprise customers' understanding of our end-to-end video strategy. While we are just starting to externally share our vision and differentiated strategy with the consumer, Ned, which is your job, and I think you're well on the way to getting &#x2013; making it very exciting.</p>
          <p>As you are aware over the last several years, we expanded our leadership, first in the networked home with Linksys then moved into video entertainment with Scientific-Atlanta followed by our announcement this year at the Consumer Electronics Show in areas such as Media Hub, unifying music from any device to any device in your home and then over time virtually.</p>
          <p>And now are dramatically expanding our network video strategy to the consumer throughout the home with our recently announced acquisition of Pure Digital and the Flip. Make no mistakes about it. We will have an end-to-end architecture in the home for video just like we are developing an end-to-end architecture for video in the enterprise.</p>
          <p>While you might think of the Flip as a consumer device, it is just as useful in our business lives. The number of applications enabled by this networked Web 2.0 device in the business world is exploding. Again using myself as an example, I carry the same two devices in my business life and my personal life, a PDA and my Flip.</p>
          <p>Another key takeaway is to understand that in my opinion the argument about consumer devices and business devices, as well as the two architectures completely blurring, is over. The real question is how do the CIOs in the enterprise business facilitate this change, and that's from a number of recent meetings with some of the top CIOs in the world. They get it. They understand the change, and it's how they facilitate it rather than how they slow it down.</p>
          <p>I had a chance to meet with our top global customer advisory technology advisors recently, which is a group who can be tough in a very constructive way. Their overall comment was very simply summed up by one of the participants saying Cisco you nailed the video architecture.</p>
          <p>And as a not too subtle reminder we believe that video will account for 90% of the load on networks in the future. Intelligence in the network is required to get the right device to the right screen with the right capability to search video content in a secure way across any combination of networks while at the same time having an ability to push the content to common communities of interest. Stay tuned because you will be hearing a lot more about video from us over the next several years.</p>
          <p>A fifth element, smart grids, and the entire green initiative is an area that many of you may not have realized Cisco's thought, execution, and partnership leadership, not to mention future business potential. We have moved to bring important solutions to the market in terms of category and architectural thought leadership in the world. In less than six months, this was highlighted by GE, Florida Power and Light and Cisco's recent Energy Smart Miami announcement several weeks ago.</p>
          <p>Sixth, smart connected communities. Through a combination of public, private partnerships on a global basis, we have developed and set the pace for what cities of the future will become in terms of how they will use network architecture for enabling everything from smart grids, green initiatives, safety and security, transportation, intelligent buildings, e-government, healthcare and education.</p>
          <p>For example, in the last month we have announced a connected architecture with the top leaders in South Korea and specifically in the Incheon, where we announced under Mayor Ahn's leadership and Gale International, the key developer of the new Incheon Economic City outside of Seoul. They believe that this vision of the future could create an incremental 200,000 sustainable jobs in this new city as well as bring an incremental growth that would add as much as 1% to the total GDP of South Korea.</p>
          <p>With all of the appropriate caveats for the opportunity for Cisco over the next three to five years it could be several hundred million dollars. We are driving several strategies with other companies and countries around the world.</p>
          <p>Sports and entertainment, an area that might surprise you, but will play out over the long run in terms of video entertainment for the home and our service provider strategy is our focus on changing the fan experience. First, it will go in sports stadiums and then it will go all the way to the home.  In one meeting this quarter, we had over 42 professional sports teams with key representatives in the meeting many at the Commissioner level from major league baseball, basketball, football and hockey. Again, more to come from our focus on sports and entertainment over the next year.</p>
          <p>In summary, I could have talked about another dozen innovative concepts this quarter alone, where we have demonstrated effective execution, and implementation into new market adjacencies. In short, our new business models enabled by our vision, strategy and execution combined with our new organization structure built around communities that we call councils, boards and working groups is working extremely well in enabling these innovative and effective operational examples like we just discussed.</p>
          <p>At this time, we will cover our customer segments, geographies, products for Q3 in more detail. The customer segments and geographies will be discussed in terms of orders unless otherwise indicated. The products review will be in terms of revenue.</p>
          <p>Now moving on to customer segments as measured by orders on a year-over-year basis, on a global terms. In terms of our overall customer segment business, the public sector was the least impacted across all of our customer segment markets, but was still down 12%. The U.S. public sector, which includes both federal and state and local was down in the mid single-digits. Japan and Asia-Pacific public sector were both positive at 12 and 20% growth, respectively. While the public sector in Europe was down 11% and emerging markets public sector was down approximately 10% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>In other global customer environments, enterprise and service provider orders were both down by 27 and 33%, respectively on a global basis. Consumer was down by 19%. The commercial market was down by 31%. Again, this is in terms of orders.</p>
          <p>Geographies. Moving on to orders by geography, and as a reminder this is in terms of orders year-over-year. Japan order growth was down year-over-year in Q3 by approximately 20%, U.S. orders in Q3 were down by approximately 22% year-over-year. Federal business was solid in the U.S. growing in the low double-digits, while state and local government in the U.S. was down in the mid-teens. The total enterprise and commercial markets in the U.S. were down in the low 20s, service provider was down approximately 30%.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Asia-Pacific. Order growth rate was down 27% year-over-year, commercial was down approximately 20%. Service provider was down in the mid-30s, enterprise was down in the high 30s, and China was down in the high single-digits, while India was down over 40%.</p>
          <p>European markets in total were down approximately 28% year-over-year in Q3. Enterprise was down in the mid-20s, commercial was down in the mid-30s, service provider in Europe was down in the low 30s.</p>
          <p>In emerging markets, not counting emerging markets in Asia, were down by 31% year-over-year. Enterprise was down in the low 20s, service provider was down in the mid-30s, commercial was down in the mid-30s.</p>
          <p>Moving on to products, product numbers in Q3 will be in terms of revenue year-over-year, but will be similar to what we saw in customer segments and geographies. Routing was down 32%, switching was down approximately 20%, and total advanced technologies were down 12% in terms of revenue year-over-year.</p>
          <p>In terms of advanced technology, video was down 5%, UC was down 7%, wireless was down 12, security and the networked home were down 14, application networking systems was down 31, and storage was down 45.</p>
          <p>Other products including WebEx, WebEx itself was up 18%, and this is again in terms of revenue, and TelePresence as we said earlier was up 138%. In terms of total revenue mix for Q3, routing was approximately 17%, switching was 32%, ATs were 25, services were 21, and the others was about 5%.</p>
          <p>In summary, although we would like to avoid the downturns, our vision of how the industry is going to evolve appears to be playing out very much as we expected. We believe our differentiated strategy is also achieving the benefits to both Cisco and our customers that we thought were possible.</p>
          <p>And finally, our execution is on target in terms of the results as measured by our customer partnership perspective, market share, and share of our customer's total communication and IT expenditures as the network becomes the platform for delivering these capabilities.</p>
          <p>Now Frank, I'd like to turn it back over to you for some additional financial guidance and other financial highlights.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John. Let me remind you again that our comments include forward-looking statements. You should review our recent SEC filings that identify important risk factors and understand that actual results could materially differ from those contained in these forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>The guidance we are providing is on a non-GAAP basis with reconciliation to GAAP. It continues to be difficult to provide forecasts given the variability and the uncertainties going on in the market. These events increase the potential that our actual results could vary materially from our expectations. Therefore, we anticipate total revenue for the fourth quarter to be down approximately 17% to 20% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>At this point, let me remind you that in light of Regulation FD, Cisco will not comment on its financial guidance during the quarter unless it is done through an explicit public disclosure.</p>
          <p>Now let me give you some additional details on the Q4 financial guidance. As we have said in the past, forecasting gross margins has always been challenging due to various factors such as volume, product mix, variable component costs, customer and channel mix and also competitive pricing pressures.</p>
          <p>That being said, we believe total gross margin in Q4 to be in the range of 63% to 64% reflecting the revenue guidance I just shared with you. We believe Q4 operating expenses will be approximately 39 to 40% of revenue. This Q4 guidance reflects normalized expenses based on the seasonality of our business and continued expense management initiatives. We anticipate that we will have removed $1.5 billion from our annualized expense run rate by the end of this fiscal year as we mentioned earlier.</p>
          <p>We expect interest and other income to be approximately $30 million in the fourth quarter. Our tax provision rate for Q4 is expected to be approximately 22%. While we expect to continue our share repurchase program, it is difficult to predict the exact weighted average shares outstanding. We're modeling share count to be flat quarter-over-quarter in weighted average shares outstanding for EPS purposes. In this estimate of share count, we are not taking into consideration any further change in stock price that could occur in the fourth quarter fiscal year '09.</p>
          <p>As a point of reference, a $1 movement in our average stock price would change the calculated shares outstanding for purposes of determining earnings per share by approximately 12 million.</p>
          <p>Regarding cash flow from operations, we would expect to generate 500 million to 700 million per month. For our Q4 FY '09 GAAP earnings, we anticipate that Q4 GAAP EPS will be $0.05 to $0.07 per share lower than the non-GAAP EPS, primarily due to acquisition charges and stock compensation expense.</p>
          <p>Please see the slides that accompany this webcast for further detail. Other than those items noted above, there are no other significant differences between our GAAP and our non-GAAP guidance. This guidance assumes no additional acquisitions, asset impairments, restructuring, and tax or other events which may or may not be significant.</p>
          <p>John, I'll turn it back over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Frank, thanks very much and well done.</p>
          <p>The following is a summary of my views of Cisco's momentum and opportunities entering Q4 of fiscal year 2009. In areas that Cisco can control or influence, our leadership from a product perspective, innovation, architecture and operational execution, not only continues to be solid, as we said before, but most important our customers are beginning to grasp the productivity implications and the importance of both the technology and architectural play. That is a big change from what we have seen before, Blair.</p>
          <p>As we've said before, even if the market slows, we don't see this changing our long-term growth opportunities. If we execute the way we have in prior slowdowns, and assuming the global economy recovers to GDP growth rates similar to those in the middle of the decade, as we continue into Q4 2009, we plan to aggressively invest in new and adjacent markets for the longer term.</p>
          <p>As we anticipated in last quarter's conference call, and it unfortunately developed as expected, the challenges that initially affected the U.S. have spread through all the countries around the world. On a global and U.S. basis, we see the same challenges and uncertainties from the economic, political, and capital spending perspective that many of you continue to witness. One of the most important things you do during periods of uncertainty is to communicate in a very open and transparent fashion with your shareholders, customers and employees.</p>
          <p>We believe Cisco is very well positioned to capture new market opportunities due in large part to the importance that the network plays in all forms of communication and IT, as well as our process and organization structure built around collaboration and Web 2.0 capabilities.</p>
          <p>Our customers even more our shareholders are telling us that we're extremely well positioned for long-term growth and an ability to move into new market adjacencies even during the most challenging of all times, which I actually believe is the time that you do move into the adjacencies.</p>
          <p>As we said on last quarter's conference call and are reconfirming now, we have always done what is necessary as an organization to ensure the long-term success of our company. We have come to the decision at this point in time that the realignment and restructuring resources to new opportunities is the most effective way, rather than a large across the board layoff, to position us for the future. If business were to change dramatically versus our expectations, we would obviously do what is necessary to bring our expense structure further in line with revenues. If that is the case, layoffs could be necessary as they have been one time in the past.</p>
          <p>However, at the present time it looks reasonably good with all the appropriate caveats for our employees that we'll be able to avoid a broad based layoff or salary reductions, and as a follow-on message to our employee family, it is up to all of us now to execute against our vision, strategy, and execution business model.</p>
          <p>I want to thank the entire Cisco family for working together as a team to ensure that our company is in a solid position to not only weather the challenging economic environment but even more importantly to be ready to accelerate if the market turns. I know it has not been easy, and we're all working hard to maintain our culture of innovation, trust, and a stretch mentality, and at the same time giving back all during a tough period of time for ourselves, our families and our friends.</p>
          <p>Again, regardless of what happens to the economy in the short-term we believe that this will not dramatically change our long-term opportunities with our vision of how the industry will evolve and our differentiated strategy. From my viewpoint long-term growth, I believe, is not our challenge. Rather our challenge is prioritization of both the opportunities and resource allocation, especially during these challenging times, that will allow to us achieve these long-term growth goals. Therefore you will continue to see us invest aggressively where appropriate while maintaining our focus on our financial models. Once again with our usual caveats as discussed earlier and in our financial reports, our Q2 fiscal year 2009 guidance is for year-over-year revenue to decrease in the 17 to 20% range. That's for Q4 fiscal year 2009.</p>
          <p>The next part I thought a long time about saying it, Blair, and I know some of our shareholders do not believe this growth is capable and would rather not talk about it, but to me I believe and I think our leadership team believes as a whole our long-term growth opportunities remain in the 12 to 17% range assuming with our usual caveats about global GDP. I think you're beginning to see our customers capture this understanding and to realize the large number of market adjacencies that we're moving in with the network being the platform for everything we're doing and capturing the vision going from the home to work across any combination of networks, with any combination of devices, with a common security strategy, we're the only player that is set to do that across the markets.</p>
          <p>So I don't want some of our shareholders to misunderstand what I am saying. I have heard your advice, but I will always try to be transparent, may not be always be right, but I'll try to be very transparent. My question is almost the reverse. Why aren't you saying 12 to 17% should be what you're targeting and maybe be more aggressive? We'll see how that plays out.</p>
          <p>We will focus on what we can control or influence and attempt to position Cisco to gain momentum in market transitions whether they're in industry consolidation, product transitions, market adjacency opportunities or economic. In summary for those area that we can control or influence we believe that our vision, strategy and execution are in great shape and producing the results.</p>
          <p>As always, I want to thank our shareholders, customers, employees, and partners for their support and continued confidence in our ability to execute during rapid industry consolidation, market transitions, and challenging economic times.</p>
          <p>Now, Blair, let me turn it over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, John. We're now going to open the floor to Q&amp;A, so we do request that each analyst ask only one question so we can get as many in before our call is over, so, Bridgette, if you could please open up the call to questions we'll go ahead and begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our first question will be from Tal Liani of Banc of America. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we can. We hear you very clear. You sound very sharp.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Super. I am using a Cisco phone here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Tal, thank you!</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a question on &#x2013; I am sure that other people will ask about expenses. I want to focus on the revenue side. Embedded in your guidance is growth in switching. Switching went down sequentially 16% two quarters ago, another 16, roughly 16% this last quarter and the embedded growth in the guidance is in the neighborhood of three to 5%. What is driving switching down so much? It's above and beyond every other &#x2013; the trends we are seeing in every other division and why do you think next quarter we're going to see such a nice recovery? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Tal, let me break it down into a couple of pieces. First of all, the quarter was really solid. I don't want to miss that key point. The second is the enterprise customers tend to move as groups, and as you know, switching ties very tightly to enterprise. Third, when you look at switching architecture, with many of the enterprises actually reducing head count, et cetera, and just now starting to load the networks with the Web 2.0 technologies we talked about, I think where you want to look at what is switching growth is where we'll be out six, 12, 24 months from now and if our architectural play is right.</p>
          <p>Having said that, I got very little pushback in terms of when I presented to our top customers around the world over the last two to three months about our architecture in switching, and candidly, their comfort level with getting actually even closer to Cisco and understanding everything from a security strategy to our leadership in each product category as well as flexibility. And even in this quarter with very strong competition from many sides our switching discounts were fine, Frank, if I remember looking at the data right.</p>
          <p>Now, I'm not predicting what the mix will be by individual products for the next quarter, Tal, so I heard your comment on that, but I am saying we're going to be fine in switching. I am very comfortable where we are overall. We will miss our forecast by individual segments, customer segments or products in a given quarter up and down, but we're pretty good on the overall trends. That's a nice way of saying I think our switching architecture is in very good shape. I am very comfortable with our strategy here and even more comfortable with our position in our enterprise accounts and moving into small markets.</p>
          <p>Thanks, Tal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tal. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question will be from Simona Jankowski of Goldman Sachs. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you very much. John, acquisitions have always been a big part of your growth strategy and you have in fact commented again on numerous occasions in the last twelve months on that remaining the case, but it's interesting that when we look back at that period your cash flow generation has been some of the strongest it's ever been and valuations have been some of the lowest they've ever been and yet you made the fewest acquisitions you've ever made in such a period of time. So, can you just comment on why that is?</p>
          <p>And then related to that, with the UCS now launched, should we assume that the focus of your acquisitions going forward may be more in the video and home virtualization side or are there still pieces of the data center strategy that need to be filled out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mona, a series of very fair questions. First of all, if you watch our acquisitions, actually Ned's team has been working overtime for the last four months, and don't worry, team, we're going to reward you with kind words, not with salary raises. A little bit of humor there. [Laughter].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much for that, John. We appreciate that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're doing a very good job. If you watch, we have done three acquisitions very recently and in the process of completing them all in our top five priorities, and Ned, I am going to have you talk about it in a moment.</p>
          <p>But Simona, to the second part of your question, we are now positioned structurally to move in internal development and acquisitions and new strategic partners because remember the partners you want in the future aren't necessarily the ones that you see out of your rearview mission mirror for the past in all of the above categories, not just in our top five priorities, but our top 29. And so acquisitions will continue to be an integral part.</p>
          <p>I think you know that myself and our senior leadership team are fairly conservative, and while, make no mistake about it, we've got a very large war chest and we tend to use it over time, we wanted to get a little bit of firmness underneath our feet before you begin to look, and I think what you are seeing is that now occur.</p>
          <p>Having said that, Ned, maybe you can talk for a minute or two about areas where you're architecturally thinking and obviously consumer which is near and dear to your heart is one of the areas that &#x2013; feel free to comfort on, but I want &#x2013; key takeaway there, data center, very important to us, we've moved very aggressively there with product announcements and architectural plays, but it's one of 29 even though it is in the top five.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, John, thanks. So first of all, I would comment that we always drive our acquisition strategy based on our strategy for the market and the market transitions we see as opposed to the fluctuations that are occurring in the public markets or in our cash balance. And we've been very clear about those top transitions as you've talked about on the call today: video, collaboration, data center, virtualization, and globalization, and the three deals we did this last quarter focused on globalization, on video and on the data center and virtualization market, and we continue and expect to continue to be very active when we see opportunities that we believe will be significant in our ability to execute across those market transitions and drive our strategy and using both cash and stock, where appropriate, to do acquisitions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And at the same time, our internal engine &#x2013; development's on fire. We're really cranking pretty well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doing a terrific job, absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Simona.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question will be from Ittai Kidron of Oppenheimer. Your line is open. You may ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and, Frank, great job on the balance sheet and on the OpEx. Two questions are for you, first on the gross margin side. Can you give us a little bit more color as to what in the mix you expect to change to drive your gross margin down sequentially again? How much visibility do you have into that or is it just a general caution there?</p>
          <p>And also with regards to the tax rate, there's been a lot of discussion about taxation of overseas profits. What's your perspective on this? How do you think the company will handle this issue if it rises?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ittai, two separate questions, both of them pretty substantive. Which one would you like for us to hit? That's my fault for not...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The gross margin one then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, first remember the gross margins, and I'm going to give it to you, Frank, are a combination of what occurs at a point in time including product mixes, so we're not really guiding up or down. We're about where we expect to be in gross margins, some quarters will be a little bit ahead of that guidance, some quarters a little bit lower.</p>
          <p>Frank, specific comments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Ittai, let me just start by saying, clearly we're very pleased with how things turned out from a gross margin perspective this quarter. Now as you know over the last few quarters, we've had several efforts under way of really driving tight management of our inventory as we've seen a decline in the overall volume based on what's happened with bookings and revenue. We've also been aggressively managing our resources to help support both on the services side as well as on the product side.</p>
          <p>We've also had some efforts underway of trying to tightly manage credit risk as the markets have been really challenging over the last several months, and of course, dealing with some of the pricing pressure that we continue to see with our discounts. So, despite all of that, what we've seen in the past quarter is really everything went in a favorable direction for us, and therefore, we did see margins come in better than what we had guided in the start of the quarter.</p>
          <p>Now, with this entire environment that we have with lower volumes and also from a discount perspective, we can't always assume that's going to continue, that everything is going to go in a positive direction. An example would be, if you look at some of our product mix. We normally see a reduction or an impact in our product mix from a quarter-to-quarter standpoint. We did not see that in the third quarter, which was a positive impact. We can't anticipate that that's going to be the same in the next quarter. So that's also what's going to impact us as we give guidance for Q4.</p>
          <p>And then the other thing that we look at is some of our cost improvements. From a seasonality standpoint, we seem to &#x2013; if we look back several years, we get the lowest amount of cost reduction in our Q4, so I've taken that into consideration.</p>
          <p>And then lastly, if you look at service margins, coming in at 67% in the quarter, that's the highest we've ever seen, and that really depends a lot on what happens on the mix between our technical services and advanced services, and we are not anticipating that that mix is going to be a favorable mix, primarily because we are being much more aggressive on advanced services, which tends to have lower margins.</p>
          <p>So taking that all into consideration is why we feel extremely comfortable of giving the guidance of 63 to 64 for Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ittai.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Mark Sue of RBC Capital Markets. Your line is open. You may ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. How does the lack of month-to-month order improvements relate to the overall tech environment, which seems to have improved February to March to April? What was the year-over-year order rate for April? And does the lack of change imply a long period of basing and it's just a return to seasonality that gets you to your up sequential guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Mark, it's a series of questions. So, let me not handle them as statements but let me do it in the reverse here and I know what you're asking here.</p>
          <p>This was the first quarter that followed normalcy, and this is to me probably from a macroeconomic issue the most important thing that we did in the quarter in terms of seeing the results. You have to have that type of leveling out and consistency in February, March, April. The second thing is I'd actually be worried if it were spiking up and down because that &#x2013; it can spike up for a month and back down the next month or a given month cannot be the trend. It's when you see it several times in a row that we are for the first time seeing a leveling out with all the appropriate caveats, it could go any way from here, but it feels dramatically better than before.</p>
          <p>And I think probably the best question that I got asked indirectly by a customer the other day was, on a scale of one to five where are you today versus what you would have said just a quarter ago and I'm not talking about business. I'm talking about total economic scenario. I would have said a three versus just a quarter ago a two.</p>
          <p>So it is that type of balance, Mark, that I think we're seeing, and you saw our range narrow, you saw our message, which was very clear, that with the changes we make through Q4; we're beginning to level out expenses, and we're going to be aggressive in making multiple moves, especially in our own internal 29 market adjacencies.</p>
          <p>So those were all positives, Mark. I'm very comfortable with where we are in the tech industry. And when I talk to our customers, it doesn't matter if it's service provider, it doesn't matter if it's enterprise, it doesn't matter if it's the channels and I talk to them all, or government and Ned, for the first time, we're starting to become a consumer player. We're well positioned across the board, Mark.</p>
          <p>So, I don't &#x2013; I think people who get real excited about a month up or down as you've seen if you listen to people giving guidance on that they would have been super excited in October. Unbelievably pessimistic by February, really down in March, back up in April, and our view hasn't changed. We've been very consistent on the execution. We're very good; it doesn't change our strategy by month. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, John...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, John, does the consistency mean that the worst is over?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It has to level out before it can get better. We'll see. My customers are saying it's leveling out. No one's projecting the turn, and it takes a couple of quarters to turn. I don't think you're going to see a dramatic turn occur quickly. I think it will be more gradual and that's what we've been saying all the way along. So, while only 5% of my customers just two or three months ago would have said it has a chance to turn by the end of this year going into next year, that's where when you all pushed me, I said, if I had to bet although no one knows that's where I would have bet. So, Mark, I don't want to read too much or too little into it, but it feels better to &#x2013; a pretty fair amount better versus just a quarter ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. We're going to move on to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question is from Ehud Gelblum of JPMorgan Chase. Your line is open. You may ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi &#x2013; excuse me. Thank you very much. Appreciate it. A couple of just clarifications. First, that I may have missed; did you give order &#x2013; product order growth for the quarter and you said that the month-by-month was the same? Did you give what that number was because I know you said the 20% for January, the down 20% last January, so I can't remember because I don't have my notes whether you gave what those three numbers were?</p>
          <p>Then my actual question has to do with emerging markets and India. Those were big growth drivers for you when things were doing very well in '06 and '07, now they've been down significant double-digits for several quarters, emerging markets down 31%, India down 40%. What status from the concentration &#x2013; conversations you were having over the last couple of quarters you're focusing much more on the U.S. as well as India. How are you looking at the reemergence of emerging markets and India? Will that take a couple of years? Do you still think the U.S. is the first to emerge and they kind of follow later? Just how does that &#x2013; how do we look at emerging markets and India and what kind of timeframe will they come back in the U.S. with respect to the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are several things. You can do the math fairly quickly. You figured out our services had very solid quarter. We're using service led solutions, advanced services, and technical support got very good execution. Couldn't be more pleased with what Wim, Gary, Joe, and the whole team is doing.</p>
          <p>In terms of the products overall, you can articulate fairly quickly, you do those numbers, it was mid-20s. And mid-20s in terms of product orders was pretty consistent in terms of the &#x2013; all three months, that's really what made me very comfortable. That had to occur before you have a chance at an upturn or even sustained leveling out time period.</p>
          <p>In terms of our strategy, it used to be a different point of view talking to customers around the world or government leaders around the world all of which I've done in the last 90 days at an unbelievable cycle, and while people might have said the global economy can come back and the U.S. perhaps can follow coming out, most every government leader and business leader would now say it has to be the U.S. coming out for them to return to reasonable numbers, and it is the exception who would say otherwise at the present time of our customer base.</p>
          <p>In terms of the emerging markets, this is when you focus on them. You say what are the big emerging markets, and our strategy doesn't go up or down based on a quarter or two. I'm very comfortable first in the U.S. leadership. I'm an optimist on our country. I think it's going to do great. I think we have an ability to bounce back like no other country in the world, and we said well before it was popular to say so that we felt the U.S. would have to lead us out of this, and we felt that it would.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we said three major emerging countries, first was China, second was India, and then we just announced two weeks ago Mexico. And if you watch what has occurred in China, they've done a very good job on the stimulus package. They have applied their changes fairly quickly, and while they've got a ways to go our growth in China was just down in the mid-single digits or maybe upper single digits if I remember the number right, and that was actually pretty good given all the traumatic change they've gone through.</p>
          <p>India got surprised. As you know they're in the middle of an election cycle and the strength of a democracy is the weakness of a democracy. You're going to have to get the elections through before they are going to make some of the changes they have to make at the government level. When businesses got surprised on the GDP growth, which I know because I was there the week before it was announced it was lower than government or business expected, and so they did exactly what happened here in the U.S., they took their foot off the gas. They're going to watch to see what happens, et cetera, and I'm very comfortable with India being a player not two to three years from now, much quicker than that assuming the U.S. does recover, which I believe that it firmly will.</p>
          <p>In terms of Mexico, again an ability to partner with a country, and we do that at the President level, where we were with President Calder&#xF3;n of Mexico, his Ministers get it, the country gets it. We were with 10 of the top 12 major conglomerates that represent 70% of the GDP growth, very well-positioned there. Nice way of saying we will use these transitions or disruptions to build customer relationships and be positioned very well from the way out.</p>
          <p>But Ehud, I know you're deliberately asking me my comfort level with emerging markets and doing it from a challenging point of view. I actually feel very good with where we are there and you will see us do the same in the U.S. I've spent a lot of time with automotive companies that probably will not produce much in the next twelve months but you'll see them. We will form the relationship tighter, and when they come back, they'll remember who was there for them and who was not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was not challenging you, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...move to the next question because we are running out of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know you weren't, Ehud. You asked a very good question and I liked the way you asked it. It's kind of like fishing with a fly. You put it out there in front of me and you bounced it on the water a couple of times and I had to go for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we are going to move to the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question will be from Nikos Theodosopoulos of UBS. Your line is open; you may ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I can, Nikos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have got a numbers question...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably. My questions are more of a numbers question. So I wanted to ask about the product deferred revenue. If I calculate it right, it fell pretty significantly sequentially by of about 522 million or about 8% of the total product revenue reported in the quarter, which on a historical basis is a pretty big change on a sequential basis for Cisco.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I'm trying to understand how did that impact the overall revenue &#x2013; product revenue number in the quarter? Why did it change so much and does swings in product deferred like that change the impact of book-to-bill? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Very, very good question. I am going to ask Frank to address it, but, Nikos, it's one that I know several of our shareholders are going to have good questions about because sometimes deferred revenue, especially deferred total revenue or product revenue might indicate a problem. It's actually the reverse for us here; all three elements of Frank's answer or four elements will probably be good.</p>
          <p>So I am really putting you on the spot now, Frank, don't mess it up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Nikos, if you look at the overall deferred revenue, from a quarter-over-quarter standpoint, both product and services down 6%, if as you all recall, we have three components of deferred revenue. We have a product business, we have a services business, and then we also have our distribution channel, which we call our two-tier channel, so the first thing I would say as far as the decline if you look at it from a quarter-over-quarter standpoint and from a year-to-year standpoint overall it was up 2%. Part of the decline has to do with just the overall reduction in volume of our business across the board.</p>
          <p>And then, the second part really has to do with our two-tier business. What we've experienced over the last two quarters is as you mostly would expect in this environment, our two-tier distribution partners have been reducing their inventory levels. As a result of that, we saw more of that reduction or a tighter management of that channel in the third quarter versus the second quarter. So when you look at the dynamics from a quarter-over-quarter standpoint, and really that plays into the deferred revenue, we had tighter inventories which in turn had a lower amount of deferred revenue.</p>
          <p>I think overall if you look at that I think that really demonstrates kind of health in the channel where we don't have huge inventories built up, especially in this kind of environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So actually our traditional product revenue decrease was even less than what our business was down, services looked very great, and channel is actually very good, Rob, in terms of positioning overall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Nikos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. We're going to move to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will be from Paul Silverstein of Credit Suisse. Your line is open. You may ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. John, given that last quarter product orders were down 14% and guidance was down 15 to 20, you came in down 17 and change. This quarter you just said down in the mid-20s, your revenue guidance is better than that down 17 to 20. Can you remind us of the translation, the linkage between your order book and your revenues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Book-to-bill was one, so you go into it with a good healthy backlog in terms of weeks of backlog. Secondly, services are about 21% of our business, so if you're kind of backing into it, think of Routing 17, Switching 32, Advanced Technologies 25, Others about 5, and Services 21%. Services were very solid on it. And the fact that probably, Frank narrowed it, with appropriate overview but, Frank, I was teasing you earlier; you're doing a great job &#x2013; couldn't be more pleased, to 17 to 20% indicates that leveling out.</p>
          <p>So it's really the mix of that and while I want to be very specific we're not calling an upturn, what we are saying is this &#x2013; it has to level out before it can go up and there's always a chance it will go down, but that tightness on that and also our expense guidance begins to give you a little bit of help, Paul, in what to expect. And that's about as optimistic as I think you should be at this point in time in the market because again remember just a month and a half ago or two months ago people were the most pessimistic I've ever seen in my life and many people said how do you remain optimistic, Cisco? And the answer is we keep our focus a year or two years out. So that's the way I'd answer it, Paul, I would view that guidance as pretty comfortable and a little bit more optimistic than we would have been just a quarter ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. We're going to try to take one more question here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Our next question is from Samuel Wilson of JPM Securities (sic) [JMP Securities]. Your line is open. You may ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>John, I hate to do this as the last question, but I'd like to put you on the spot a little bit. A lot has changed in the last 90 days, and there's been a lot of press about your relationship with IBM and HP, and I wanted to end this call by you sort of going on the record and saying what you think the relationship right now is with IBM and HP, and how you think it's changing given all that's happened in the last 90 days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. So let me expand on the question, Sam, since you're going to be our last one on that because we want to end at 3 for our commitment to you all and keep the call as tight. If you look at our partner relationships, they continue to evolve very, very effectively, and we've done that over two decades here. And while some of the partners of the past will be partners of the future, when you're going into new areas, you're going to have different partners as you move into those. And so as you think about it, think about most of the demand we deliver through our partners is created by Cisco. And that can be easily moved to other areas. It's not all of it, but it's the vast majority.</p>
          <p>The second element think about where our partnerships in the future will be and think of companies like Accenture and Wipro and MphasiS and Tata think of it as Intel and Microsoft, think of it as EMC and VMware and think of it as players like that in terms of where we're going. HP, clearly going to be a competitor and that happens, and when you have overlaps in terms of moving into market adjacencies, there are going to be some people you're going to partner with closer and there are going to be others that you are not. There will also be some areas like with IBM where we partner at times and compete at times and we do that at the Microsoft level.</p>
          <p>But the key point I want to make is if you look at those 29 market adjacencies and just walk through them for a moment and think through how many different partner and partner sets we're going to need each one and think about how broad a range we're going into with a track record of being number one or number two and every time we've entered into a market, that's pretty unique. And there are going to be times when some of our partners say that's too close for me for you to do and I clearly understand that. There will be other times when I might feel the same in reverse. I actually think that's healthy.</p>
          <p>Rob, I haven't got you in the call. A little about what is our relationship with our channels, how we fulfill business and then I will wrap it up, Blair if that's okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, John, and I think one of the most important things to consider is we did think through all of those implications relative to years ago. And we spent so much time on building what I think is the industry's most envied channel, that our ability to fill in those places where we drive demand primarily in the enterprise and service provider I think the capacity is out there as we speak. We will overlap with HP. We'll continue to work together with service partners, like IBM and Accenture and others. So I feel very comfortable with our routes to market, and I think we're in excellent place &#x2013; in excellent shape to take advantage of the upturn when it occurs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so in summary, I said this, in my opinion, was the most innovative and operationally sound execution quarter we've had. And some of you might say, tell me that again and why. If you really watch it, our product introductory cycles, we're moving into new markets with a speed no one has ever even attempted to do, and I would argue with a speed probably five to ten times what anybody else has done.</p>
          <p>Secondly, for the first time customers who've been watching this and they say, I get it, I now know what that innovation is in this business model. And secondly I watched it execute, you're going to make it happen. And that's the enterprise and service provider customers who are closest to us.</p>
          <p>Third, our relationship with our customers and channels &#x2013; never been tighter. And if you want the capability to be able to focus and pivot in one area and have Ned going with three or four major pillars in the consumer space, pivot again and go into the data center, and play in areas in terms of virtualization we haven't done, pivot again and go with a video architecture across the board, pivot again and be the world leader in collaboration and Web 2.0 and it isn't a Silicon Valley thing any more, a high tech company.</p>
          <p>Our enterprise customers know we're the leader in this. They know that we've the thought leadership. They know we can help them more than anybody else, and our relationship has been tighter. And so while many of the things you do, "innovation-wise", it isn't till the customers say, "Hey, this is a benefit to me," and bring it home, does that occur. And you're really starting to see that occur.</p>
          <p>So with all the appropriate caveats, which I thought we did a good job of covering in the script, Blair, I think what you look in terms of our future is a very bright future and my comfort level with the long-term both in terms of growth opportunities on issues we can control or influence is extremely strong.</p>
          <p>So with that, Blair let me turn it over to you to close.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Okay. So very quickly Cisco's next quarterly conference call which will reflect our fourth quarter fiscal 2009 results will be on Wednesday, August 5, 2009, at 1:30 PM Pacific Time, 4:30 PM Eastern Time, and downloadable Q3 financial statements again are available following this call including revenue segments by both product and geography, income statements, full GAAP to non-GAAP reconciliation information, balance sheets and cash flow statements can be found on our website in the Investor Relations section. Just click on the financial section of the website to access the slides and the documents.</p>
          <p>Again, I'd like to remind you that in light of regulation Fair Disclosure, Cisco plans to retain its longstanding policy to not comment on its financial guidance during the quarter unless it is done through an explicit public disclosure. Please call the Investor Relations department with any follow-up questions from this call. Thank you for your participation and continued support and this concludes our call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for participating on today's conference call. If you would like to listen to the call in its entirety, you may call 866-357-4205. For participants dialing from outside the U.S., please dial 203-369-0122. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>