<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1150219" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-04-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>820</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Brady W. Dougan, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Renato Fassbind, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">D. Wilson Ervin, Chief Risk Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4">Christian Stark</participant>
      <participant id="5">Brady Dougan</participant>
      <participant id="6">Matt Spick</participant>
      <participant id="7">Derek De Vries</participant>
      <participant id="8">Renato Fassbind</participant>
      <participant id="9">Matthew Clark</participant>
      <participant id="10">Jeremy Sigee</participant>
      <participant id="11">D. Wilson Ervin</participant>
      <participant id="12">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="13">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="14">Fiona Swaffield</participant>
      <participant id="15">Matthew Czepliewicz</participant>
      <participant id="16">Christoffer Malmer</participant>
      <participant id="17">Kinner Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="18">Davide Serra</participant>
      <participant id="19">Philipp Zieschang</participant>
      <participant id="20">Stefan Stalmann</participant>
      <participant id="21">Paul Tucker</participant>
      <participant id="22">Dirk Hoffmann-Becking</participant>
      <participant id="23">Georg Kanders</participant>
      <participant id="24">Elena Logutenkova</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everybody. Thank you for joining our call to discuss First Quarter Results. The operating environment in the first quarter of 2008 continue to be extremely challenging for the entire industry, as you know. Market condition deteriorated further in March leading to additional write-downs in our leveraged finance and structured products business within Investment Banking. As a result, Credit Suisse reported a net loss of CHF2.1 billion in the first quarter of '08. To a large extent, this loss was driven by net write-downs of CHF5.3 billion in leveraged finance and structured products in our Investment Banking division.</p>
          <p>However, at the same time, we've continued to reduce our risk positions. During the first quarter of 2008, we reduced our exposures in commercial mortgages by 25% and in leveraged finance by 41% compared to the end of last year.</p>
          <p>While, our first quarter results are clearly unsatisfactory, we remain well positioned to advance our strategy and capture growth opportunities arising out of the current market disruption. During the quarter, clients turned increasingly to the best capitalized and most stable financial institutions including Credit Suisse, and we saw good asset inflows in Private Banking and good client activity across a number of businesses for example in prime services.</p>
          <p>Moreover, our capacity to generate revenues remains strong. Excluding the areas affected directly by the credit prices, most of our businesses performed well, with revenues near, or in some cases above, those in the first quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>Growth momentum in most European and major emerging markets and in particular, the robust economic environment in Switzerland helped to mitigate the adverse affects of these market developments on our business.</p>
          <p>In addition, we generated approximately CHF1.2 billion of our core net revenues from cross-divisional activities and we have a strong pipeline of business. We are continuing to focus on efficiency. Total operating expenses declined 23% from the year-ago quarter and 12% from the fourth quarter, reflecting lower compensation expenses in both periods.</p>
          <p>Although non-compensation expenses increased 3% year-over-year they declined 19% from the fourth quarter in part due to continuing downward trend in the Investment Bank.</p>
          <p>Our business model has proved resilient to the extreme market conditions of the past 10 months and we remain well positioned to seize the opportunities arising from the changing financial landscape. Our results will demonstrate the benefits of our integrated banking model in terms of both diversification and collaboration.</p>
          <p>I'm joined on this call by our Chief Financial Officer, Renato Fassbind and our Chief Risk Officer, Wilson Ervin. In our discussions today, we're going to continue to endeavor to maintain a very high level of transparency. Renato is going to take you through the details of the results and Wilson will walk you through our risk positions and how we've managed to further substantially reduce these through the quarter. We'll then take any questions and I will sum up.</p>
          <p>Renato?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Brady, and good morning. I will start my presentation on slide five. Despite the significant valuation reductions which we reported in Investment Banking and from our money market assets left out in Asset Management, many of our businesses continue to perform well.</p>
          <p>Private Banking continues to deliver good results, demonstrating benefits of a diversified and integrated global business.</p>
          <p>In Wealth Management, we recorded asset inflows of CHF13.5 billion and our Swiss Corporate &amp; Retail Banking business produced another strong result both in revenues and pre-tax income.</p>
          <p>The valuation reduction of CHF5.3 billion masked an otherwise good underlying earnings power in the Investment Bank. There were strong performances in many of our client-focused businesses. For example, we recorded record revenues in prime brokerage and very strong revenues in global rates and foreign exchange. And while the environment was very challenging for the mortgage and credit markets, in particular in March, we continued to actively manage down our positions.</p>
          <p>Following on from the significant reductions we achieved in the fourth quarter of last year, our exposure to CMBS was further reduced by 25%, and leveraged finance balances were reduced by 41%.</p>
          <p>Maintaining capital strength and the conservative liquidity position was always a priority for us. At quarter end, our tier 1 ratio on the Basel II stood at 9.8%, only slightly below our target level of 10%.</p>
          <p>In terms of liquidity, we maintained a cash loan position of more than CHF15 billion and also increased the liquid assets accepted under existing central bank facilities from 60 billion at year-end to CHF82 billion at the end of the first quarter.</p>
          <p>In summary, while our first-quarter results are clearly unsatisfactory, our capacity to generate earnings remains strong and we remain well positioned to create long-term value and seize opportunities that arise from the market dislocation.</p>
          <p>I'll skip over slide six and seven for this call, and start with a review of the divisional results in more detail, starting with Private Banking on slide eight.</p>
          <p>In Wealth Management, we continue to deliver good results despite the challenging markets, with positive momentum across all regions. The 12 and 13% reduction in pre-tax income as shown on the left side reflects the impact from a significant reduction in assets under management and considerably lower client activity.</p>
          <p>Our client base remains strong but also cautious, given the high volatility observed in many financial markets. The cautious behavior primarily affects our transaction-based revenues, especially when volatility persists for such an extended time. We continue to invest in our Private Banking franchise and see strong indicators for growth. In the first quarter of 2008, net new assets stood at CHF13.5 billion and we continue to hire relationship managers across all regions. We added a total of 110 relationship managers during the quarter, including 40 in Asia-Pacific and 50 in Europe and the Middle East.</p>
          <p>We have talked about the need to balance our ambitious growth plans with our strong focus on maintaining our profitability and improving our productivity margins. The pre-tax income ratio did come down this quarter to 37.2%, below our 40% target level, but we remain confident to achieve the target level over the mid-term.</p>
          <p>As shown on slide nine, the gross margin on assets under management remained stable at 117 basis points. Compared to the first quarter last year, recurring revenues increased by CHF102 million or 6% to 1.68 billion. As a result, the recurring asset margin was up seven basis points to 85 basis points. This increase in the recurring revenues is in line with our strategy to further strengthen our stable revenue basis.</p>
          <p>Transaction-based revenues as shown underneath the chart on the left, decreased to 629 million in the first quarter reflecting the adverse market environment and cautious client behavior. Consequently, the transaction-based margins are up to 32 basis points.</p>
          <p>In summary, we were able to maintain the margin and actually improve the recurring component of our revenue stream from 66% last year to now 73%. But overall revenue levels were affected by lower client activity and the impact from the reduction in assets under management, which brings me to the next slide, number ten.</p>
          <p>Net asset inflows in Wealth Management stood at CHF13.5 billion, significantly above the levels experienced in the second half of last year, but slightly below the very strong performances in the first quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>We have added, for transparency, splits for our net new assets, assets under management and relationship manages by region to our quarterly report. As you can see also on the slide inflows were strong in Switzerland with CHF5.3 billion and also in the Americas.</p>
          <p>Already at the end of last year, we commented on the deleveraging we have seen in some of our larger clients' portfolios. This was a feature in particular in Europe and the Middle East or EMEA resulting in the reduction in reported net inflows to CHF2.1 billion for that region as assets were liquidated to redeem funding.</p>
          <p>The chart on the right side shows that assets under management came down by 11% during the first quarter. Currency effects amounted to close to 60 billion of that reduction as both the U.S. dollar and the euro trended lower against the Swiss franc. Negative market movements resulted in a further 43 billion reduction in assets under management.</p>
          <p>Net new assets have developed positively across all regions and continue to meet our medium-term target of 6% per annum.</p>
          <p>The Swiss Corporate and Retail Banking business, shown on slide 11, delivered another strong result. Quarterly pre-tax income of 464 million was supported by solid economic conditions in Switzerland. The result was driven by strong revenues, good cost control, and continued low credit provisions.</p>
          <p>Our results also include the CHF64 million unrealized gained on a synthetic collateralized loan portfolio. The CLO transaction referred to as Clock Finance hedges a portion of the credit risk intrinsic in the underlying loan portfolio; as spreads widened on credit protection, our position created a fair value gain.</p>
          <p>Before I leave the review of the Private Banking businesses, I would like to reiterate the fact that we expect these businesses to continue to show stable results and provide a strong anchor to our future profitability, particularly in Wealth Management, which offers unique growth prospects within the financial services industry.</p>
          <p>Let me continue with the results in the Investment Banking division on slide 12. The Investment Banking results continue to be influenced by two very distinct developments. At the headline level, the pre-tax loss this quarter was CHF3.46 billion driven by leveraged finance and structured products write-downs amounting to CHF5.3 billion.</p>
          <p>We made further progress in reducing our risk position. Wilson Ervin will present details on this shortly. At the underlying level, most client business outside the problematic mortgage and credit markets continue to perform well. Let's have a look at that with the fixed income comparison as shown on slide 13.</p>
          <p>This chart shows you a flat movement in our fixed income businesses outside the areas most affected by valuation reductions. Starting with the negative total fixed income trading and debt underwriting revenues of CHF1.4 billion recorded in the first quarter 2008; we then backed out CHF4.3 billion of negative revenues recorded in our structured products and leveraged finance businesses.</p>
          <p>After deducting the fair value gains from Credit Suisse own debt allocated to Investment Banking, we arrived at the net adjusted revenue level of CHF1.66 billion. And we compare this with the revenues recorded in the same period last year again excluding any contribution from structured products and leveraged finance, you'll see that we were maintaining revenues at the same level as the very strong first quarter results of 2007.</p>
          <p>As listed on the right, there are many businesses that recorded very strong revenues this year, in some cases even at record levels. Very strong revenues were recorded in our global rates and foreign exchange businesses. In addition, we recorded strong performances in emerging markets and fixed income product.</p>
          <p>It is also worth noting that the fixed income results in the first quarter include the CHF500 million net fair value reduction in our corporate loan book. We value around 29 billion of our corporate loans in the Investment Bank at fair value. Had we not chosen to fair value these loans, the corresponding credit provision charge on an accrual basis would have been only a fraction of this 500 million, reflecting the sound underlying credit quality of our portfolio.</p>
          <p>In summary, we have momentum in many of our businesses as we are continuing to diversify our revenue sources by taking advantage of the dislocations in the market.</p>
          <p>On slide 14; equity trading revenues decreased 33% and 36% against the comparable periods. The key driver of this reduction is equity prop trading, which incurred losses in the current quarter compared to significant gains reported in the first quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Our client related businesses continued to perform very well. Client services achieved record revenues with strong growth in client balances in the quarter and a significant number of new client mandates. We achieved good results in the global cash business and our electronic trading platform, AES. So as was the case in fixed income, many client related businesses showed a very strong performance and the underlying earnings power in equity trading remains strong.</p>
          <p>Next, let's look at the Investment Banking expenses on slide 15. We maintained our disciplined approach to compensation, as compensation expenses were reduced as a result of the lower quarterly results. To preempt any questions you may have on this, let me please say that given the first quarter result and the market uncertainties, it is too early to give you guidance on full-year absolute compensation levels &#x2013; or compensation to revenue ratios. We will need to review the strength of the basis results and staffing levels at the end of the year and also determine any potential changes in the amount of share-based awards as part of the performance-based compensation.</p>
          <p>G&amp;A expenses in Investment Banking are down in the first quarter due to continued focus on cost management and despite an increase in head count. As you may recall, we started our cost management activities some while ago at a time when the environment was less challenging.</p>
          <p>We told our employees back then that it is better to start working on efficiency programs when revenues are growing. We now have systems and programs in place to effectively and efficiently manage our cost base. We believe that these actions now put us in a much better position to adapt to current market levels going forward.</p>
          <p>Let me continue with the Asset Management division on slide 16. Our results here continue to be affected by losses in respect of the money market lift out. We recorded losses of CHF566 million on these assets in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Since we lifted the securities from the funds, we have reduced the portfolio on our balance sheet by over 75% with exposures standing at CHF2.2 billion at the end of March. While we come off an improved performance in 2007 with an underlying annual pre-tax income of close to CHF1.3 billion, the current results show that we need to continue making the necessary changes that allow us to deliver our profitable growth strategy.</p>
          <p>This brings me to slide 17. We have regrouped Asset Management to increase the focus on our strengths, namely our world class alternative investment and asset allocation businesses while maintaining the commitment towards our clients. We are now managing the division along three business lines are shown on slide 17. One, alternative investments comprising of our leading private equity and real estate businesses and our single and multi-manager hedge fund strategies; two, multi-asset class solutions or MACs comprising of active asset allocation strategies and solutions across all asset classes; and three, global investment strategies comprising of our traditional equity and fixed income mandates and also the Swiss institutional advisory business.</p>
          <p>In the columns to the right, you can see how these businesses compare in assets under management, net new asset inflows in the quarter and for the full year 2007 and what percentage they contribute to asset management revenues.</p>
          <p>Looking at the second column all the way down, the net new assets for the quarter were a negative 20.2 billion driven by outflows in money market and Swiss institutional advisory assets reported within global investment strategies. But I want to focus your attention in particular on the alternative business further up, which continues to show good asset inflows and account for 40% of the division's revenues. We believe that the alternative asset inflows will fuel further revenue growth also driven by our best-in-class capabilities.</p>
          <p>On slide 18, we have split the revenues into the more volatile private equity gains shown in the upper part of the slide and the stable asset management fees shown below. The private equity business started the year with net negative revenues due to reduced realizations and unrealized losses, and our stakes in public company investments, in particular, in China. Recurring revenues as shown below were at 648 million in the quarter. This is at the same level as in the first quarter last year despite the fall of CHF100 billion in assets under management, mostly in fixed income.</p>
          <p>Higher contributions from our alternatives business were offset by lower revenues in global investments in line with the reduction in assets under management. The overall gross margin actually improved from 37 basis points to 40 basis points, reflecting growth in our higher margin businesses. Compared to the fourth quarter, the margin came down 7 basis points. Here, the key drivers are significantly low performance fees as these are recorded on a semi annual basis.</p>
          <p>In addition, lower revenues in global investments and MACs also reflect the reduction in assets under management during the quarter. Overall, assets under management declined 13% in the first quarter of 2008, most affected by adverse foreign exchange impact and market movements.</p>
          <p>I will now close my presentation with the group's capital position as shown on slide 19.</p>
          <p>Capital continues to be a strong story for Credit Suisse as we remain well capitalized. We have now transitioned to Basel II. The chart in the left gives a high level comparison of the risk-weighted assets and tier 1 ratio as a result of moving from the old to the new method of calculation. We have included a more detailed description of the movement in our quarterly report.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, the tier 1 ratio came down slightly from 10% at the end of the year to 9.8% at the end of the first quarter. Risk-weighted assets came down by 7%. tier 1 capital also declined due to foreign exchange movements and the net loss we recorded in the quarter. This was partly offset by the issuance of 1.5 billion in hybrid tier 1 capital during the quarter, and lower deductions for goodwill and other intangible assets. We have reduced our share repurchase activity in light of recent market conditions.</p>
          <p>In summary, we have maintained our strong capital ratios without diluting existing shareholders. Compared to our peers, our tier 1 ratio is among the highest in the industry. We successfully transitioned to Basel II and will propose to pay an increased dividend of CHF2.50 to shareholders at the Annual Meeting that takes place in Zurich tomorrow.</p>
          <p>We strongly believe that a strong capital base together with a conservative liquidity profile is a competitive advantage especially in these markets. We will continue to prudently manage our balance sheet, exposures, and capital in order to remain in the position to seize opportunities that arise from the market dislocation.</p>
          <p>With that I welcome Wilson Ervin to present the next section of the presentation. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Renato. As we did at year end we want to update you on how our risk positions have developed in the first quarter. We're committed to continuing the high level of transparency. I want to take you through the key risk exposures in detail using a format consistent with the approach we took last quarter.</p>
          <p>As you know market conditions have been very difficult this quarter; prices have declined across nearly all credit markets. Conditions were tough in January and February and got worse in March. The quarter saw several forced liquidations by hedge funds and other participants which led to a cycle of declining prices and further liquidation in certain asset classes.</p>
          <p>Trading liquidity was also generally weak during the quarter in these markets due to anticipated as well as actual liquidations. The quarter culminated in some extraordinary actions by the central banks to maintain order in the markets late March. We have seen some improvements in recent weeks, but only in selected areas so far.</p>
          <p>We took significant write-downs in this quarter, as we marked our positions to market. Although these write-downs had a significant impact on our P&amp;L, we have been able to manage them within our existing capital resources. And Credit Suisse remains one of the best capitalized firms in our industry. We have also continued executing our risk reduction program which we pursued aggressively since the last fall.</p>
          <p>Let's turn to slide 21 and I'll walk you through an overview of the business lines in Investment Banking that have been most affected by the recent market turmoil. Of course at the top of this page, we show two different columns. The first columns with numbers shows the exposures at Q1 '08 and then Q4 '07 and the percentage change. The last two columns show you the net write-downs in Q1 '08 and for the full year 2007. These write-downs totaled 5.3 billion in Q1, compared to CHF3.2 billion we showed for 2007.</p>
          <p>Going down the side the first two rows describe our big underwriting businesses, leveraged finance and commercial mortgages. And the next two rows show trading based businesses. In leveraged finance, we've cut our positions from 35.1 billion to 20.8 billion in the first quarter. This is a reduction of 41% in the quarter. Net write-downs were 1.7 billion as we marked this portfolio down by 9 percentage points to an average price of 85% to keep it in line with market levels.</p>
          <p>In the next slide you can see we've also made progress in committing our commercial real estate portfolio. Here, we've reduced our exposures by about 25%, net write-downs 0.8 billion in Q1. The bottom two rows show residential mortgage and subprime CDO business. As mentioned last quarter we cut back origination activities a long time ago in both these areas. So we manage these as trading businesses.</p>
          <p>To show the exposures on a net basis, as there is no large underwriting position here analogous to the two origination base businesses at the top of the slide. The residential mortgage lines shows how our positions here continue to be reduced. They were down to CHF5.5 billion in the quarter and the subprime segment was cut to 1.1 billion. Write-downs there were modest in Q1.</p>
          <p>The next line shows our CDO positions which have been most difficult area for us. Our exposure to directional market moves is only CHF0.7 billion on a net basis. However, we will also address gross long and short positions in a later slide as basis movements between longs and shorts were the main factor in write-downs this quarter. The net write-downs totaled CHF2.7 billion in CDOs and I'll go into that in more detail in later pages.</p>
          <p>The final point before I leave this page, as you can see at the bottom, we continue to hold substantial index hedges to manage risk in these focus sectors. We've reduced these hedges somewhat in line with reductions in our asset portfolio, but they are still important in keeping our overall portfolio balanced against possible risk scenarios. We now total CHF20.9 billion of high yield credit, crossover credit and mortgage index short positions.</p>
          <p>While these hedges have been valuable, overall the efficiency of our hedges dropped with some of the dislocations in the markets in Q1. The prices for cash positions generally dropped more than they gained in the relevant index hedge which meant there was often some net write-down even for a position that was matched down in nominal terms. This is partly due to market supply and demand technicals and partly due to pressures in the financing markets. Those pressures have led many participants in the market to value derivatives, which don't require cash, more highly than bond positions which do require funding.</p>
          <p>Now let me spend a few minutes in each of these areas to give you a more detailed look at our exposures and our portfolio breakdown. First, let's look at our leveraged finance business on the next slide. As you can see on slide 22, we have remained disciplined in selling down our portfolio. Back in September we had exposure of roughly CHF59 billion in leveraged finance. We've cut that to 35 billion in Q4 and 20.8 billion at the end of March. We got some benefit from exchange rate movements in the first quarter, but the majority of the reduction was from the strong sales effort. This has been an orderly process and we've not sought to sell down by way of large heavily discounted transactions.</p>
          <p>We did sell a few loans with term financing but this amounted to only 2 billion which we show as a footnote at the bottom of the page for full transparency. We value all these positions on a fair value basis and have not transferred any of the positions to accrual books. At the end of the quarter our exposures were valued at an average price of 85% which is a significant reduction compared to the 94% mark we carried at the end of last year.</p>
          <p>Net write-downs this quarter were 1.7 billion as a result of severe spread widening, but not because of any credit problems in the portfolio, which we address on the next page, page 23.</p>
          <p>While the size of the positions are significantly lower, the distribution of them is broadly similar to what we showed you last quarter. Our portfolio is largely with large-cap companies with stable cash flows. It is generally U.S. focused with low exposure to cyclical industries. We have some significant concentration in larger deals, but the quality of the underlying credit remains good and the companies are performing on plan.</p>
          <p>Our leveraged finance business is the strong franchise for us and the distribution skills and focus have been the key asset in this market. They've come through previous downturns in a stronger position and we believe they will do so again.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to commercial mortgages on page 24. The story is broadly similar to our commercial real estate activities. As you can see, we've reduced our gross exposures by 25% during the fourth quarter, going from 25.9 billion to CHF19.3 billion. All positions are fair valued and we do not have a whole book for this business. Valuations have been written-down inline with observed trading levels for cash and index instruments and incorporating specific asset fundamentals.</p>
          <p>We took write-downs of CHF1.3 billion on a gross basis based on these market moves in Q1. Credit hedges and interest carry reduced that to CHF800 million in net terms. As in leveraged finance, we have kept a significant hedge portfolio in place to protect against further shocks or an economic downturn scenario.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn from exposures to the portfolio analysis for CMBS, and please turn page 25. The story here is largely similar to what you saw in our Q4 presentation, probably the main change is at the top left which shows a geographic diversification. Much of our sales in the quarter were in the United States, and the relative weight of that region declined. Our credit quality remains generally good with good loan to value support and low percentage of development loans. It's important to note that credit performance for commercial real estate is fundamentally different from the residential markets. Our portfolio is generally well diversified and it's secured by high quality income producing real estate.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to our trading exposure starting on page 26. These are small or nominal terms, but are closer to the center of the recent market storms, and have seen sharper price action. As mentioned, we've already been out of the underwriting business in RMBS since early 2007. Our portfolio has evolved into a secondary trading book and we show our positions on a net basis. But our shorts in this book are less than CHF1 billion at this point. So our gross positions aren't too much different from our net positions here.</p>
          <p>The main story is the further reduction in exposures. We show exposures for subprime and also include Alt-A, prime and European and Asian exposures for completeness. Our decision to the cut positions in the later part of 2007 and early 2008 proved beneficial particularly in Alt-A, as margin contention extended to that sector. The net write-downs were minimal here in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>A few other comments: We marked these books to market based on trading levels in relevant cash instruments and derivatives. And about the ABX, it's not always the best guys for valuation, it is among the most transparent reference points in the market.</p>
          <p>If the valuations for our positions are compared to the prices for the closest ABX index, they come out as conservatively marked. This is true for both the RMBS portfolio and for CDOs which we'll turn to next.</p>
          <p>On slide 27, we give you some more detail on our CDO positions which were our most difficult period during the quarter. The top box shows our positions at Q1 versus year-end on both the gross and the net basis. The second box shows how our net position evolved by category, and the last box shows the net write-downs. The bottom part shows our write-downs for the quarter, which totaled 2.7 billion and includes the losses we discussed in our previous announcements.</p>
          <p>The ABS and index category describe securities backed primarily by subprime loans. This year we lost about 1.8 billion overall in the first quarter. About 400 million of that came from declines in overall market levels. But the majority of losses were from basis risk or valuation changes between longs and shorts. Simply put, our hedges didn't work very well this quarter, and the long positions went down more quickly than our shorts rally.</p>
          <p>We also took about 0.7 billion of losses in the second category, synthetic CDOs in Q1. In this area we changed back some of the model parameters to relatively severe levels as we discussed a few weeks back. This is designed to ensure that our derivatives valuations are priced consistently with observed trading levels, even if those parameters are fairly extreme.</p>
          <p>The third category, cash CDOs, relatively flat in P&amp;L terms in Q1. This categories move to distressed net asset value basis back in 2007, and was relatively insensitive to further downward market movements.</p>
          <p>This is gives you an overview for the losses in our CDOs. They don't split to the exact write-down figure due to small adjustments in other categories such as corporate credit and rounding differences. But I hope it gives you some rough intuition behind the main drivers of this movement.</p>
          <p>As mentioned, we've taken a number of steps to correct this portfolio, putting a new trading team in February and it made some initial progress in reducing and rebalancing our positions. Our sales will be difficult in light of the low levels of market liquidity, but we have made some progress in reducing some of the risk factors that cause losses in Q1 and cutting down the sensitivity of the books. There is still risk here, but market dynamics have become a bit more stable in the market in recent weeks.</p>
          <p>This concludes our look through the focus areas of Investment Banking. There have been some other areas of interest that have been raised in the market, but I haven't talked about them in detail as they haven't had a major impact on Credit Suisse. But I will make a few summary comments here in case there are questions.</p>
          <p>One, we don't sponsor any SIVs. Two, we are not in the auction rate underwriting business. Three, we don't use monoline wraps to hedge our books. Four, our credit losses are in good shape and continue to perform well.</p>
          <p>We did see some defaults by several hedge fund clients during the quarter, but losses were minimal as our collateral protection was well structured and sufficient to fund the loans.</p>
          <p>Lastly our counterparty exposure to other financial firms are also collateralized on a daily basis. So while our write-downs have been challenging in the focus sector of our Investment Bank, we have worked hard to make sure these issues are contained.</p>
          <p>Let's turn now to the asset management division on page 28. Last quarter, we discussed some action taken to remove stressed securities from our third party money market funds, a decision we took to protect our investor franchise. Our third party money market funds continue to operate normally for our investors. They have no material exposure to SIV, CDOs or U.S. subprime and carry good levels of overall liquidity.</p>
          <p>However, we did see some further write-downs for the securities we lifted out of our money market funds in late 2007. Positions in our liftout book are mark-to-market like normal inventory and now carry typical discounts to par of 15 to 50%. The weighted average price for this portfolio was about 65% at quarter end.</p>
          <p>In the top panel, you can see an update of our gross exposures by asset type in our liftout book, approximately 1.5 billion of the exposures to SIVs which is down from 2.5 billion in Q4. We have 500 million in asset backed securities and 200 million in corporate bonds and these represent significant declines from Q4.</p>
          <p>In the middle panel, you can see how the size of the liftout book evolved during the quarter. We did execute one liftout of an FRN during the quarter when spreads for financial terms widened, but we've cut the portfolio by 1.9 billion with the majority coming from sales and maturities.</p>
          <p>The final box updates you on the write-downs taken from the liftout book. These total 0.6 billion Swiss francs in Q1 versus a loss of 0.9 billion for 2007. We're continuing to work on reducing this portfolio and bringing this matter to a close, but also in a way that protects value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>We've talked through the specific areas that have been hardest hit by the recent market turmoil. But before concluding, I'd like to turn briefly to some high level views of risk to show you how these specific areas fit into the overall picture for the bank.</p>
          <p>Page 29 gives you a trend line for two high level risk metrics for the whole bank. ERC, or economic risk capital, is a proprietary model of risk that covers all our major risk types, including market, credit and investment risk. It helps us track risk developments on a consistent basis across businesses and across time. Our overall ERC declined by 7% versus year end and is down 17% versus the Q3 level. This has been driven largely by the reductions in our <mark type="inaudible" /> and our CMBS areas as well as by a few other factors.</p>
          <p>As we mentioned last quarter, ERC has worked pretty well doing this crisis at measuring and tracking risk. More importantly, it has been helpful in our decision making, as it forced us to put on credit hedges before the crisis hit back when they were cheaper and more liquid.</p>
          <p>On a bottom half of this slide, we show Value at Risk or VaR. VaR is a narrower measure than economic risk capital, but does cover a wide section of trading risk in the Investment Bank. It is subject to some volatility because it relies on recent market data to estimate risk for a given position. When markets are benign, a trading position might count as 5 million of VaR. But when markets become more volatile as they are today, the same position might count as double that in VaR terms.</p>
          <p>In the chart at lower right, you can see that our nominal VaR figures remain elevated due to this volatility effect. This increase in nominal VaR does not reflect increases in average trading positions, which you can see by the darker bars which adjust for this effect to track VaRs if we had consistent data methodology throughout this period. This risk adjusted trend shows that our positions are pretty stable over time if using a consistent measuring stick.</p>
          <p>We've also been disciplined and trained that VaR continues to capture all trading risk in the Investment Bank. We haven't removed anything from VaR when markets got more volatile. This ensures better transparency and consistency internally and gives us a better line of sight to manage our overall trading book risk.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to turn to page 30 to summarize. This certainly was not an easy quarter. Market prices deteriorated significantly in nearly all credit sectors and hedging relationships dislocated to an unusual extent. While our hedge book was beneficial, its net performance lagged the asset side. We took some tough markdowns in leveraged finance and CMBS to make sure we stayed at market valuations.</p>
          <p>Our CDO book was especially challenging, both in terms of market conditions and write downs. We've worked hard in this quarter to fix this situation and taken the necessary steps to circuiting that portfolio back onto the right path.</p>
          <p>Market disciplines are especially important in ensuring clarity when conditions are stressed. Credit Suisse has maintained a strong mark-to-market discipline in the Investment Bank. All our focus exposures are accounted for on a fair value basis and all marks go through our P&amp;L. We have not transferred any assets into portfolios that would require a change in accounting treatment or taking them out of our VaR reporting.</p>
          <p>Our credit performance continues to be strong, both in our underwriting books and in our lending books. We've retained a significant but small hedged portfolio to protect against future market volatility or against recession-type scenarios. And lastly, in spite of difficult markets, we've achieved good reduction in exposures in our focused areas. We're encouraged by the progress we made in rebalancing risk to a level that's more appropriate for current market conditions and we work to continue that progress.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll hand it back to you, Brady.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Wilson. So a lot to go through. Hopefully you've found that useful, though. I think with that we're ready to open it up for questions. So operator, you can queue up the questions and we'll try to answer whatever we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now begin the question and answer session with analyst first followed by media. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> First question comes from Christian Stark at Cheuvreux. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Good morning, it's Christian Stark from Cheuvreux. Just a couple of questions on the Private Banking side, first on the inflows and on the hiring that you had. So, first on the inflows in Switzerland, you had strong inflows in Asia. You mentioned some impacts of deleveraging; I just wondered whether that had stabilized. Then on the hiring in Asia, you had a very good sort of increase, and there I would like to know whether those were mainly experience relationship managers which are expected to bring good net new money flows going forward or whether that is mainly people that you are training up.</p>
          <p>Then the next question is on Private Banking on the gross margin. I wanted to know if you have seen any changes in the asset mix in Wealth Management particularly amongst equities, structured product or alternative investments? And the last question: maybe you could give us an indication of the impact of the change in funding costs for the asset-based fees? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for those questions. First of all on inflows, as you mentioned, we saw a very strong performance in Switzerland, and between the Wealth Management area and the corporate retail bank, we saw I think close to CHF9 billion in inflows in Switzerland, which was a very strong performance as you mentioned. Again, I think we're probably benefiting from being stable and well capitalized in obviously more difficult times. I think that the inflows in Asia-Pacific were actually quite strong. We had a very strong quarter in the fourth quarter I know, so the first quarter was a little behind the fourth quarter, but still very strong momentum I think in Asia-Pacific. So that's &#x2013; we continue to see good flows there.</p>
          <p>You mentioned deleveraging in Asia-Pacific. Actually, we saw deleveraging in EMEA in our European business, not so much in Asia-Pacific and deleveraging clearly does have some impact on our overall net new asset flows. But overall I think very, very stable, good strong flows in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>On the hiring side, yes, we made &#x2013; I think we made good progress in hiring, and again I think benefiting somewhat from the fact that we have performed better than many of our competitors, and are viewed as a very attractive platform to join. We exceeded our targets for the first quarter and those were primarily producing relationship managers. I mean when we report relationship manager hiring targets, those are really experience producing relationship managers, not trainee-level-type people.</p>
          <p>I think in terms of the gross margin, as you say, it held up well at 117 basis points. I think in terms of the asset mix, I don't think it was broadly much different from the fourth quarter. So it remained pretty stable. We did see, however, that in terms of the gross margin, a larger portion of our gross margin performance came from our kind of ongoing, our stable sources of revenue and a little bit less from the transaction flow. So I do think that there was a bit of a &#x2013; that is one of the things strategically we're trying to actually push our revenue flow over to some of the more stable longer term sources, and we succeeded in doing that in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>And then your last question in terms of changes in funding cost, I mean we didn't really see &#x2013; I mean I guess in terms of particularly our Private Banking or Wealth Management business, I mean we benefit from clearly a strong deposit base with relatively low financing cost from that. So our Wealth Management business is &#x2013; it has excess funding, so it effectively generates additional funding. That obviously puts us in a very good position in markets like these, wherein general interest rates have been higher, and so that definitely gives us some benefit. But I'd say our funding cost was largely, I would say, flat to the fourth quarter. But again, the composition of our funding base in our Wealth Management business is clearly a big advantage for us in times like these particularly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect; thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Matt Spick at Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning. I have two quick questions. Firstly, on the capital side, your balance sheet is shrinking quite quickly and I know you're being helped in that by the dollar exchange rate but you've gone from 1.4 trillion to 1.2 trillion and you're seeing declines in risk-weighted assets. Could you make a comment about how much deleveraging you think Credit Suisse needs to do and how far through that process you are? Was it really a one-quarter process that you're pretty much through, or is there further to go in that?</p>
          <p>The second question was just on head count in the Investment Bank. I can see that you've still got about 20,600 employees, about the same that you had in the fourth quarter, and that's about 1,600 more than you had in the first quarter of 2007. So, again, I'm interested to know if we do go back to say a 2005 revenue environment, is there any reason why we shouldn't go back to a 2005 level of head count ,or am I just thinking about head count in the wrong way when I try and think about revenue productivity? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Matt. In terms of the deleveraging issue that you mentioned, I mean actually as you say our balance sheet was reduced from the end of the fourth quarter to the end of the first quarter. And primarily that was around the lot of the efforts that we've talked about in terms of reducing risk, obviously, in the specific categories that we've highlighted, but some other areas as well in terms of just reducing our risk profile.</p>
          <p>In general our leverage has been relatively stable. It's obviously &#x2013; we obviously have a lot less leverage than some of our competitors, but it's been relatively stable. And I would say in general &#x2013; so I don't think we are either have experienced or view ourselves as going through a big deleveraging process. So I would expect our balance sheet probably to be relatively stable in the second quarter, would be my guess. Now obviously that will depend on what opportunities we see and if we see more opportunities, we obviously may put more assets on the balance sheet, less we may actually reduce it.</p>
          <p>But there is not a particular objective that we have in terms of reducing the balance sheet further. We've got &#x2013; we obviously have plenty of capital. We're well capitalized. I think our leverage ratios are conservative particularly compared to a number of competitors. So I think we feel like we're in pretty good shape there. I would expect the balance sheet to remain fairly stable in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>In terms of head count in the Investment Bank, I think in general we are clearly going to be very active in reallocating resources within all our businesses, but particularly Investment Bank from some of the areas that probably have lower growth profiles going forward to areas that we're looking to grow and we see a lot of growth opportunities there. So we're clearly going to be very active with that. In general, in our Investment Bank, we have one of the leaner footprints I think in Investment Banking among the industry, which I think actually positions us well in tougher times like this. But we are going to continue to be pretty aggressive about reallocating resources. I would say right now we don't have a plan to dramatically or materially reduce head count in the Investment Bank. We are going to be reallocating it to high growth areas, which is probably the more important part of our plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Derek De Vries of Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks; good morning, couple more questions on capital if I may. Your tier 1 ratio of 9.8% that you report -- that doesn't include a dividend accrual if I'm correct. So I was hoping if you would just comment on your thoughts on the dividend, realizing it's all in Q1. And then if I assume you do, that you sort of pay a dividend this year, I get to a sort of tier one ratio I think of 9.5% with a dividend accrual there. I'm just trying to think in terms of comfort zones. Obviously you target 10%, but your dividend &#x2013; I mean -sorry -- your tier one ratio got all the way down to I think to 9% in '02 before you did your mandatory convert. So I know it's a different management team, it's a different Basel regulatory regime, but would it be fair to kind of categorize if that's your comfort range to sort of 9 to 10%?</p>
          <p>And then I guess finally on capital, the Financial Stability Forum Report that came out was pretty clear that assets in a trading book are going to require more capital going forward, and it sounded like they would use a Pillar II or Basel II to capture that. I was wondering if you had had any discussions with a Swiss regulator on that topic.</p>
          <p>And then maybe just to follow up on your answer to the last question on capital, you say your leverage ratios look good relative to peers, and I guess it depends how you define peers, but if I look at the U.S. GAAP reporting banks, I think your tangible equity to tangible assets ratio -- it doesn't look particularly strong. Is that something you focus on, or do you tend to look more to your tier 1, your buys, your economic risk capital &#x2013; can you just maybe comment on tangible equity to tangible assets as a tool to use as an analyst?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes ,sure. Thanks, Derek. On the first question, in terms of capital as you said &#x2013; I guess our view is that around a 10% tier 1 capital ratio &#x2013; I think that is among the highest for major banks you know, in the world. So we feel like we are well-capitalized around that level. We think that that certainly from virtually from all points of view whether it be a regulatory point of view or from a client point of view, we think that that is very sufficient capital. So, I think in general our target remains 10%. And we believe that particularly as we &#x2013; our hope obviously is that the business performs better in subsequent quarters and we can obviously continue to a accrete capital. So I think our view is at around 10%, that's a good level and that we feel comfortable with that. On the &#x2013; I don't know Renato do you want to answer the dividend question on that or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually included in the tier 1 ratio is a dividend accrual on an ongoing basis depending on what we estimate to be the dividend going forward. So, it is included.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, in that 9.8% you have a dividend accrual in there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As much as we are forecasting a dividend, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's fully included, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think as &#x2013; Derek as to your question about kind of &#x2013; as we say, we feel comfortable around 10%. I mean, obviously as we get further away from 10%, we obviously re-assess things but I think in general within a fairly broad range around 10%, we feel reasonably comfortable that we are very well-capitalized. I do think obviously I think a major &#x2013; I think there will be a major movement around the world for additional capital requirements. I think that's no secret, I think that will probably happen over time and without commenting on any particular any specific regulator, I think clearly there will be increased capital requirements from regulators. So we'll see how that develops over time. But again we feel like we are very well positioned at around a 10% tier 1 ratio. And I think with regard to leverage ratios, to be honest we don't see that as particularly significant. We clearly do focus a lot more on ERC particularly, VaR to some extent, and our capital ratios in general, our tier 1 is what we do focus more on. Obviously the leverage ratio does not give you any kind of an indication of the quality of the assets or quality that's on the balance sheet, or the riskiness to what's on a balance sheet. So we focus particularly on ERC as what we think is the most reasonable explanation of kind of what reasonable representation of what we have &#x2013; how we're managing our risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. That was very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Matthew Clark of Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I was hoping to just get a bit more granularity on some of your trading revenues. Just because you've given in the past disclosure, I think in 2006 you made about 2 billion revenues on the leverage loan side and about 1 billion on the CMBS side. And those businesses are obviously suffering at the moment, but we don't have any granularity on the businesses that you claim to be doing better at the moment. So, I was hoping maybe you could give an indication of the size in revenue terms of the businesses that you see are doing better at the moment. And then secondly, a follow-up on the capital side coming from a different angle. If you saw your tier 1 ratio move up towards the 11% level, would you then feel comfortable restarting the buyback to bring it back down to the 10%, or do you see 10% as being a minimum level and you would like to develop a cushion above that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Matthew. I guess, first of all with regard to trading revenues, we are not &#x2013; we're not going to do a lot of specific disclosure. But I think as we've mentioned to you, basically pretty much most of the areas outside of the leverage finance and structured product areas performed quite well in the first quarter and we've kind of given you that reference point of first quarter '07, which was obviously pretty good markets in a pretty good time for the industry. In particular, I think we've said that prime brokerage business has performed very well, our rates businesses have performed well, our cash or customer businesses on the equity side have performed quite well. I think the emerging markets business has also performed quite well.</p>
          <p>So, I think all of those are areas that have performed extremely well in the first quarter, and again I guess, rather than getting into specific levels, you wanted to kind of reference back for you all the fact that that taken as a whole, pretty much everything outside of those affected areas, private equity gains and then obviously the write-downs in these areas really performed pretty much on par with first quarter '07, which we think is a pretty strong statement about the earnings capacity of the business. With regard to tier 1 and how high we would let it go, I think obviously, again, we are comfortable around 10% I think to the extent that we were moving up above that and we didn't see the organic opportunities in the business. I think certainly we &#x2013; our intention would be to return that capital to shareholders, probably through our established buyback program. So, I think that would certainly be a direction we'd go in, subject to markets and our outlooks on the markets etcetera, but I think we would definitely &#x2013; that would definitely be something that we think about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Jeremy Sigee of Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, thank you. Could I ask two questions please? One is, to get into a bit more detail on your hedges. Could you give us an idea of the split I think as you did in the last quarter of the index hedges, the rough split between leverage finance and CMBS, and then sort of part B of that question if you like is, could you give us a rough order of magnitude of the single name hedging that you might have against the leverage finance portfolio on top of that? And then second question on Wealth Management, the geographic split is interesting, and you've given some indications &#x2013; but could you be a bit more explicit about how that split looked last year, say first quarter '07 or full year '07?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Let's &#x2013; why don't we start with &#x2013; maybe I'll ask Wilson to answer your first question on the hedges.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Hi, Jeremy. We talked in the overview slide about 20.9 billion of index hedges at Q1 '08. Those adjusts for the index hedges related to these four focus area businesses here. They reference leverage finance, crossover and CMBS type indices, as well some other commercial real estate indices. I believe that a slight majority of that is in the credit side, but we have a mix of risk there because we do want to have some diversification in our hedges.</p>
          <p>In terms of your question on single names, within the leveraged finance business for those large exposures generally with our position as underwriter, that's a difficult transaction to do, so we don't have material single name hedges against that book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeremy I'd say with regard to the geographic split in terms of the asset flows, I am sure you are &#x2013; I am sure you're probably already aware, but we've got &#x2013; in our Q1 report we've actually got a pretty good, pretty extensive disclosure on page 25 of the different regional numbers which is under Private Banking. So that will give you some indication that maybe just to answer your question a little bit, I think that we are &#x2013; I think we are definitely building momentum in the Asia-Pacific region in terms of net new asset flows. That's an area where we've actually, I think in the past we've been weaker, and I think in the past sort of 6 to 9 months we've actually been building a lot of momentum there, I think that's been good. I think the Swiss region is showing continued strength now, and maybe somewhat increased strength, so I think that's been a positive. And the other areas I would say are probably pretty much on par with last year; the U.S. has been reasonable, the other emerging markets have been reasonable, so -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Jeremy, you can find now on our internet all the details for the four quarters, so the history on those numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's good, I appreciate the disclosure. Can I just ask a small follow-up? Are you seeing any fall out from the sort of Lichtenstein issues in terms of European clients who have money offshore in Switzerland?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We -- obviously the Lichtenstein issues haven't really &#x2013; haven't directly affected us, and so I would say, obviously if you look at our net new asset inflows, they've continued to be strong, and so I'd say, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So even though there's no direct impact, it's not causing, say, German clients to rethink their money in other offshore centers like Switzerland that you're seeing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No; we haven't seen that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jeremy. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Kian Abouhossein at JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. I have a few questions. First of all, on page 12 of your presentation, looking at that slide and reconciling it with the one-off that you have given and the revenues, I assume that structured products and leveraged finance would generate about 250 million of revenues in the first quarter of '08. Is it something that looks reasonable? The second question relates to bonus accrual on slide 14 &#x2013; sorry; slide 15 -- and here, if I look at the number, it looks to me that you are taking a quite conservative approach and maybe are only accruing salary and share bonuses and maybe look at cash bonuses as you go along through the next nine months. Is that something that you can talk about?</p>
          <p>And the third question is on capital. Operational risk capital is coming down within the group relative to fourth quarter, looking at your press release. Is &#x2013; has basically the regulator signed off under Pillar II on your operational risk? And secondly, do you have any core tier 1 i.e. tier 1 ex-hybrid in mind that you want to achieve, considering that you're propping up your capital with hybrid capital? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think with regard to the first question, in terms of, I guess you're trying to back into what structured products made in the first quarter. Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Because your &#x2013; the slide is very helpful and you see if you have note one where you clearly take out the revenues and in order to reconcile it I come to about 250 for structured products and leveraged finance revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But you're trying to get to underlying revenues ex the write-downs. Is that what you're...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly. Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I mean, we in &#x2013; before we actually disclosed the specific revenues in the areas in terms of your question which seems to be about the actual revenue flows ex the write-downs, I don't &#x2013; I actually don't have the numbers. I don't &#x2013; your assumption doesn't sound like it would be way off, but I don't actually have the numbers for that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Either, so sorry. In terms of the bonus side, I mean, we've obviously accrued compensation in the first quarter. I mean, I think as everybody knows, this is a process that you true up as the year goes on and as you get a better feel for how the business develops and also how the compensation environment develops. I think we certainly feel that what we've accrued in the first quarter is appropriate, given the current kind of environment status. But we'll obviously have to reassess that as we go forward in terms of what the appropriate accrual is in future quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And sorry; it includes cash bonus as well or is it the full year share plus salary?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It includes &#x2013; it obviously &#x2013; the compensation line includes all the basic salary, benefits and also, yeah, current year charges for bonuses are included in that, yeah. Absolutely.</p>
          <p>And then the last question capital, yes, our economic capital, our ERC has been coming down. I guess your question was that has the operational risk element of that been signed off on under the second &#x2013; under two. Wilson, you want to answer that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't give you the disclosure on the specifics of the EBK approvals, but I can tell you we now are operating fully under Basel II. The Swiss system is quite a tough system in regulatory capital terms, both in Pillar I and Pillar II terms, and we are operating in that right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But is it not fair to say considering what is happening in the market, considering that we had fraud issues, mispricing issues, that operational risk should increase materially over the next year or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that regulators in general, are looking at different ways to alter capital calculations for the system. Basel II is a tough system, particularly as interpreted in the Swiss system, but I think there are some general questions that are going on both in operational risk as well as some of the trading risk areas that I believe Derek mentioned earlier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't actually think that aspect of it is adding a tremendous amount to the overall issue. I just think it's more just capital adequacy concerns of &#x2013; for the industry by the regulators. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And could you just comment on core tier 1? Have you any &#x2013; do you have anything in mind on &#x2013; if I strip out the hybrid, I think you're around 8% at the moment. Do you have anything in mind in terms of core tier 1 or tier 1 ex-hybrid?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all &#x2013; this is Renato Fassbind &#x2013; first of all, you have to understand that we have a cap given by the IR regulator of 15% of hybrid capital out of total tier 1 and that's basically what we have filled it up with our recent hybrid issuance; we were before actually below that ,and so that is the cap we can go for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, yeah &#x2013; I'd say we obviously consider our overall capital. I think it's actually a very high quality capital base overall. So we're mostly focused just on our overall tier 1 capital ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Jon Peace of Lehman Brothers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I just wanted to check what is the dividend which you accrued in the tier 1 in the first quarter? Is it going to be flat with the 250 that you proposed for the full year 2007? And the other question I had was, is there anything you guys can do to stop the reversal of the gains that you've been booking on your own debt in the second quarter as the CDS spreads are tightened? Is there any other hedging you can do to avoid just the mechanical reversal of that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks, Jon. I think on the dividend side, we generally are &#x2013; I mean we obviously will determine dividends in the context of markets, et cetera, but we, in general are &#x2013; in general plan to continue to pay a dividend which is an appropriate percentage of our earnings, just as we have in the past. And so I don't think we're going to comment specifically on what was actually accrued in any particular quarter, but that's our policy so &#x2013; and we'll continue to do that. I think in terms of your question on the reversal of the gains on fair value of own debt, I think it's a good question and yeah, there certainly are things that we can do with respect to that and there certainly are things that we are &#x2013; we have looked at and are looking at in respect of that. So our hope is that we could &#x2013; that in fact we could offset that somewhat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you do get some natural hedge in a sense from your asset portfolio to the extent that spreads for funded transactions in the market have gone down and we've benefited from that on the liability side. Our liabilities have been very &#x2013; valued more appropriately. We've also seen some lift on the asset side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Fiona Swaffield at Execution Limited.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I had questions in two areas. The first one is going back to just before Easter when you took us through the fact that you were probably going to make a loss and at that time, I think we talked lot of about weak underlying March. It's just not that easy to see it in your numbers, particularly that slide you gave about the fixed income being quite resilient, Q1-Q1. So, could you talk about what has been happening? I know we don't like to go out month-by-month, but what was it that made you so much more nervous then or has something changed over that period or was it equities that you were more worried about?</p>
          <p>And then, in terms of the capital, I'm still struggling a bit on the risk-weighted assets. Because obviously they've fallen a lot, yet I would have thought that your market risk-weighted assets would have increased significantly because of the multiplier effects on the VaR, because I think you've got quite a lot of back testing exceptions again in the first quarter. So, I can't reconcile that with the fact that your position risk hasn't really changed much. So, could you just talk about what's going on in risk-weighted assets and whether they could go down further, whether it's some kind of efficiencies you're getting or something like that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Sure. Fiona, thanks very much. I guess to the first question, I mean I think that &#x2013; I think the only thing that's changed since the call we had just before Easter, is just that the difficult markets in March just accelerated in through the end of the month. So, the only thing that really changed was that we got I think further &#x2013; you know, there were further asset price reductions and larger write-downs as a result. I think the robustness of the business, which I don't recall is specifically what comments we made at that time but that's pretty much held up through the quarter. Probably with a little less, probably I'd say the client flows in the business were a little last buoyant in the last half of March. But in general that obviously held up generally well. So, I think the main thing that simply happened was that further asset price deterioration and write-downs that resulted from that, if that answers your question. And, Wilson, can you just address the risk-weighted asset product?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. On the market risk side, as you can see in the slides, we spoke to there on VaR. We already had a relatively high market risk charge from the increase in VaR in fourth quarter. So there wasn't that much change from Q4 to Q1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Doesn't the multiplier effect go up over time as the back testing exceptions keep on coming?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It went up a little bit, but the brunt of that effect was already taken in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Fiona. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Matthew Czepliewicz of HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. Actually, can I ask one question each on Wealth Management, Asset Management, and the Investment Bank? In Wealth Management, first, the transaction margin being under a little bit of pressure, if you think back to the last slowdown and subsequent market recovery. And based on that experience, would you expect any recovery in the transaction margin to anticipate a market recovery or to lag it a bit? In another words, do you think your customers are going to bottom fish or are they going to wait for a little momentum to build?</p>
          <p>Second question on Asset Management on slide 17, the alternative investment core if you will of that business, you have net new assets of 2.2 billion and that's a deceleration from the rate of 2007 and I think one would have expected a deceleration, but is that some &#x2013; is that inflow do you think consistent with industry inflows in those areas in Q1 or might there have been anything exceptional in there?</p>
          <p>And then the final question on the Investment Bank and I appreciate this might not be an entirely fair question, but going to the CDO 2.7 net write-down from the basis pressure and the decline in the hedge effectiveness. I think Wilson, you use the term of stabilization of dynamics in market dynamics in April, if you could just comment maybe a little bit, give a little more color on that, in other word if you had struck your numbers today rather than at the end of March with that 2.7 billion have been materially different or would there not have been a great change there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Matthew thanks a lot. I would say with regard to Wealth Management. Typically as you see there is a bit of a cycle and there is a cycle to the Private Banking client behavior within the cycle. Clearly you get initially a lot of &#x2013; you get lot of activity around repositioning portfolios then things kind of settle down until such point as people do believe there is opportunity and they once again reposition portfolios to take advantage of that. I think that one of the very important features of this crisis is the fact that actually private clients in general, but certainly our private client base has been pretty much unaffected by most of the trends here, they weren't big sub-prime owners, they weren't.</p>
          <p>So they are very &#x2013; actually very healthy and I think ready to be opportunistic but at the right time and so part of it depends on what you predict as the path for the recovery. I think that I am personally more of a believer in sort of a V-shaped recovery I think it may be a pretty when it does happen and who knows when it will happen, it will actually be a fairly, it may be a fairly rapid recovery and so I think &#x2013; yeah I think our belief would be that certainly our transactional aspect of our business there will also perk up at that time. I think in general we are seeing people being fairly conservative to this. I don't know that I would say that we would see it leading but I think it would &#x2013; I think it will happen pretty quickly when it happens and so I would expect it to be &#x2013; I would say contemporaneous with the recovery in the markets.</p>
          <p>On the alternative side we &#x2013; the 2.2 billion in net new assets is obviously there is quarter-to-quarter variation and really we view that as a pretty good, a good asset inflow for the first quarter and particularly for the market conditions that we saw. I would say that there is also some seasonal aspect, I mean that tends to be more later in the year, fourth quarter can be a strong quarter. But so I think our view is that we, I don't view it as &#x2013; I view it as a pretty good performance, there are obviously very sticky assets and also high margin assets. So we like that and so I view that but we view that as a pretty good a pretty good performance but I do certainly think we'll see some variability and I hope will se higher numbers in the subsequent quarters as well. So, Wilson, you want to try to address the issues around the CDO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. As you mentioned March was a very difficult month and that was difficult both in terms of directional moves if you look at some of the indices in the market like ABX. They were negative in March and also some of the spreads were particularly difficult for our book. Since March, the ABX has stabilized. We've even seen some slight drift up. We've also seen some better trading conditions for cash which actually I think the liquidity element is probably more important from my seat as it has helped us do some trades and continue some of the rebalancing on that book. There still is risk in the book, but that's in the context of a market that is in a little less of a dislocated pattern right now. I can't give you a specific mark-to-market update on that, we don't give sort of week-by-week disclosure there but I can tell you that the trading conditions overall have been a little more stable and a little more liquid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Chris Malmer at Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Hi, it Chris Malmer at Goldman Sachs. I had two questions please. First of all, if I could just clarify on the movements in the risk weighted assets to the extent that the dollars/Swiss franc exchange rate obviously impacts both your risk weighted assets and the capital. If you can give us an idea of what the net sensitivity to the movement in the dollar is? Second question would be on the fixed income revenues, you are showing the underlying run rate is somewhat &#x2013; underlying in the quarter as being around 1.65. Would you be comfortable to basically consider this as a some sort of a run rate going forward with potential obviously to upside if markets improve from here? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think in &#x2013; your first question about risk weighted assets and currency effects of risk weighted assets and capital I think &#x2013; we think it's sort of a balanced equation -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the ratio it's more or less a balanced equation. The risk weighted assets have been affected &#x2013; as you have seen by the foreign exchange movements, but also by, some of the reductions of the exposures we had.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the second question about fixed income revenues, well, I mean, I think with regard to that &#x2013; those numbers are primarily coming from what we are talking about as kind of our non-affected businesses. And so I think with regard to those businesses yeah, I think we would view that as sort of a base going forward and hopefully markets will continue to be reasonable and we can continue to &#x2013; in those areas produce that. I mean, obviously one of the big questions is in terms of fixed income revenues and revenues in the Investment Bank generally is will we see some asset price recovery and also will we see some return to client flows in those &#x2013; on the structured products and the leveraged finance businesses. And obviously our hope is that we will see that but in terms of timing I mean it remains to be seen obviously but so &#x2013; but yeah I think it's a reasonable estimate to think that those the businesses that performed well in the first quarter will hopefully continue to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Kinner Lakhani at ABN.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, good morning. Firstly a technical question on the tier 1 capital. Are the gains on owned debt, do they register in terms of adding to the tier 1 capital? Secondly could you talk through the kind of key drivers and trends in terms of level three assets particularly in terms of composition as well as the transfers in that we've seen over the quarter? And finally in Wealth Management clearly, we've seen negative operating leverage. Do you have any ambitions to try and control that or are we firmly in the growth strategy basically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to tier 1 capital, no, gains on owned debt, do not impact capital. Secondly in terms of key trends on level three assets I mean obviously to &#x2013; we've been &#x2013; we are obviously working on reducing assets in some areas that certainly are subject to sort of the level three categorization. But separately, I think obviously what you saw I think across the industry in the first quarter was as markets got more difficult, less liquid and little more uncertain, you saw more assets obviously migrating into the level three category. And so I think what you see probably in our numbers is some combination of those two trends.</p>
          <p>And then the last thing, in terms of Wealth Management and operating leverage, we clearly do think that this is a great &#x2013; these are great opportunities to continue to grow our business, and we're going take advantage of those. We feel like, particularly in the Private Banking business, there is a real flight to quality in terms of firms like ourselves who have been more stable through this and that's something that we're benefiting from. But we also see great opportunities to add relationship managers at this point. So overall, we're obviously going to continue to be disciplined in terms of how we grow and build the business, but we do see this as good opportunities to grow the business.</p>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Davide Serra of Algebris. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Can I ask you a question regarding the trading losses? On page 60 of your quarterly you highlight how many days you had gains and losses in a very useful chart. In order to understand what happened in March, the severity of the losses, the number of days where you had the three, four times the expected loss, let's say, CHF2 to 300 million. Was it higher compared to the days where you had the gains? Because on the chart, it only shows plus 100 million and less than 100 million. So just want to know if the extreme days were higher on the losses or on the gains, because net-net you made losses, I imagine were on the losses, but just want to understand the magnitude.</p>
          <p>And secondly, if the magnitude was extreme, was it around the Bear Stearns days of the collapse? So when the situation &#x2013; when the markets were totally dysfunctional or were they evenly spread across the quarter? This in order to kind of understand how your book was positioned and is positioned, so that if it was only around Bear Stearns, then we can relax going forward. If it happened during &#x2013; if it's more stable, the losses, that kind of worries me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah; Wilson, do you want to try to address that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks for the question, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. First, as a risk manager, we don't ever really want to relax, so would appreciate if we could, but I don't think that's part of our job description. With respect to the timing of the losses, we did see more of those in the March period. March was the period of most stress in the market, I would say in the week leading up to the Bear Stearns event, as well as the couple of weeks subsequent. Market volatility across a lot of credit indices in a lot of different markets were quite disrupted. So in terms of exceptions and in terms of our P&amp;L volatility, that was the most difficult period.</p>
          <p>With respect to the distribution outside of this range, this has been an extraordinary period in terms of P&amp;L volatility compared to our past history. The distribution beyond the range is &#x2013; I think is pretty symmetric with one exception. We did have the CDO event during the quarter, and that was obviously towards the negative end of that barbell. But except for that, we saw also a number of pretty high positive days as well as a significant number of negative days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Can I have a follow-up on this? The CDO event -- yesterday Ambac in their result started to release some real CDOs event rather than mark-to-market. Does this change your view of the rest of your own CDO book because from mark-to-market losses we're now started having actual cash losses? And does this make you more bearish or bullish vis-&#xE0;-vis on how you manage that part of the book?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I would say that the market prices that we see out there -- we focus on the market prices -- those market prices do reflect some significant fundamental distress in that business and I think we will see other institutions who are in more of a &#x2013; of an accrual basis or credit basis starting to reflect those marks &#x2013; the mark-to-market system in effect upfronts that effect and we've taken all of that to our books. I guess the second issue is just with respect to our own portfolio, we don't rely on the monolines for hedging, so any second order impacts are not important for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On this point, the monoline hedges, I hear in the industry there are lots of back-to-back hedges using monolines. So let's assume your trader &#x2013; you tell him as risk manager you don't want an Ambac wrap. Then your trader goes to let's say HSBC and tells his friend there at HSBC you buy me an Ambac wrap, I buy it from you, he thought he was hedged because he had bought Ambac, so all the same protection, and then de facto this increase the systemic risk. Do you have any idea of your counterparty risk with other players? Do you monitor as a result the counterparty risks with other financial institution on a single name? So how much you are exposed to, whatever, JPMorgan, UBS, Goldman Sachs at any point in time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we do. In your example I can't comment about what our counterparties might be doing to hedge themselves on the other side. However we do monitor our counterparty exposures with all our major counterparties by category of exposure and by aggregate on a daily basis. We're collateralized on a mark-to-market basis with each of those counterparties.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's probably &#x2013; there is probably good &#x2013; maybe helpful to point out that we obviously had during the first quarter, a number of distressed liquidations of various players in the market. And we had exposure to a number of those players, collateralized and all the rest and we basically got out of all of those liquidations with basically no losses. And so I think that's probably worth pointing out. So yeah, we certainly do look very closely and I think we've got a very conservative profile in terms of those risks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's an important industry issue, it's not a big issue for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fantastic. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Philipp Zieschang of UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, a couple of questions please. The first one is on the Wealth Management business. You are &#x2013; you continue to highlight the stability of that business also going forward in your comments. I was just wondering what do you see as a say trough pre-tax margin for that business, we are standing now at 37%. It peaked around 42 in the second quarter, so if the environment continues like it is, what do you see in terms of pre-tax margin swing?</p>
          <p>The second question is &#x2013; and sorry to come back on capital, you said basically you feel very comfortable with your current, close to 10% or around 10%. You also said in another comment that you believe the regulator is going to demand increased capital from the sector. So a) do you believe you will also have to hold more capital. And b) what do you think is the timing in terms of when these current discussions are going to be &#x2013; when they are going to lead to decisions?</p>
          <p>And the final question just &#x2013; you also highlighted your ERC capital now down to 11.1 billion. I was just wondering from the outside world, why do you think this is a good yardstick for your risk given what happened to the industry and what given to happen to your bank over the past couple of quarters with write-downs close to that level? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Phil, thank you for your questions. I think our view is that we think that this 37% margin is a trough level, so we think that if markets continue to be challenging and difficult that's probably a pretty good lower band &#x2013; I mean, obviously, we can't guarantee that but we think that's a pretty good lower band. Then we actually think that probably from here, if markets get a little better, it's more likely to get back up towards the levels that you saw &#x2013; that we saw last year, so therefore in the 40s, low 40s.</p>
          <p>Capital, yeah, just maybe I should make sure that I didn't misspeak or that my comments aren't misinterpreted. I was just talking generally I think regulators around the world clearly are &#x2013; will be suggesting and asking for probably more capital. I mean we've already seen some of that and I think that will continue to be the case. And obviously Switzerland is already, as you know, is a conservative player within that, so &#x2013; but I do think there will be a trend towards more capital being required. We do feel, again, as one of the best capitalized big banks in the industry that we'll be well positioned within that, but clearly, that may have an impact on us over time as well. Wilson, could you address the ERC question, why we think ERC is a good measure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. We disclose the ERC to try and give you some transparency on our internal view of risk. While reg cap is important and we do operate as a regulated institution, I think it's critical for us to have a strong internal view of risk and capital needs across our institution. We have a very tough ERC capital measure, that measure has held up generally quite well even against the market stresses we've seen, so when we look at what the model would see as the risk versus the risks we've seen in this market, it's generally held up well.</p>
          <p>We find that to be a better yardstick in terms of looking at how we would see the allocation of risk to different sectors and how that risk is trended across time and that's why we've stressed and it's in some of our disclosure and when we talked about how that ERC trend has moved down over time, we think that's really a good internal yardstick of how we see the overall risk of Credit Suisse moving down as we've deleveraged in some of the key areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Stefan Stalmann of Dresdner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. My questions have all been answered. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; thanks. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Paul Tucker of Egerton Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and good morning. I just had a couple of hopefully simple questions. Just on the disposals that you are making of the problem assets in leveraged finance and commercial mortgages and so on, can you just give us a sense of how we should be thinking about those and what I mean is, is it the case that you are getting rid of the higher quality easier assets and the realized losses on those are relatively small and the things that are left are going to be proportionately or progressively more difficult to dispose or is it the other way around that you're kind of getting rid of other things that you think are most toxic and you're just saying let's get them off the balance sheet and not worry too much about the costs involved in doing that?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, I just wonder whether you could make &#x2013; and you've kind of alluded to it already, but whether there are any other comments that you could make looking into Q2, on how that basis risk issue has been developing with the markets becoming a little less dislocated. And then finally, there were some headlines yesterday coming out of Brazil just with respect to an employee arrested from Credit Suisse in relation to tax evasion and money laundering and I appreciate this might be a very new and live issue. But I wondered whether you could make any comment on that and maybe specifically whether that was in the Investment Bank or Hedging-Griffo or anything else that you might feel able to add? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for those questions. Maybe I can make a general comment on the disposals and then Wilson could talk a little bit more about that. We have been, I think probably, more so than any other players in the market, we have been a very consistent distributor of our risk in these areas. And part of that, as I think we do have, I think we have probably the highest quality franchises in these areas. So we've had like number one rank sales, research, et cetera. So, I think we've had better distribution capabilities and we have really been very consistent in terms of our sales of these over the whole period. You know as we mentioned, we're &#x2013; our leveraged finance balances are 65% lower than they were at the end of the third quarter last year and I think that's &#x2013; I think if you compare that to other players in the industry, I think that's been &#x2013; I think that's probably the most significant reduction in balances that are there. And we've done it consistently over time.</p>
          <p>So, I think that's &#x2013; and obviously I think that has served us pretty well. And so &#x2013; but maybe I can turn it to Wilson to let him talk a little bit about the actual sales we're making and how we're looking at them and I would say at this point, we certainly do see that there is value in some of those assets and we're not just fire-selling everything and there's been a lot of this recent noise about big portfolios being sold. Well, we've been selling very consistently over the whole period so &#x2013; maybe Wilson, I don't know if you can add to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure as Brady said, we haven't wanted to go the big fire sale route. We've wanted to be very disciplined throughout this period in moving down our assets. I would say the distribution there has more been driven by the timing of the deal process. We've sold both higher rated and lower rated assets. So I don't think there has been a significant quality difference that's been across the board. I would say as a second matter we also generally like the quality of our portfolio in both leverage finance and CMBS. The credits there continue to perform on plan. So we don't see any real difficult assets there from a distribution standpoint. It's more been a question of timing. With respect to your basis question, with respect to CDOs as I said markets have normalized a little bit in April. I wouldn't see a big uptick or big rally or anything like that. But we have seen better liquidity conditions, more stability and I think that's helpful for that book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think as to your last question with regard to this thing in Brazil, as you say it is kind of new &#x2013; it just came up last &#x2013; just yesterday. And I think all I would say is &#x2013; this individual doesn't have anything to do with the onshore businesses in Brazil, so or Hedging-Griffo et cetera and obviously we feel like we conduct our businesses everywhere around the world in a way that's beyond reproach and in line with all &#x2013; certainly our policies and local regulations, and laws and things. So we're obviously going to be looking into that and we'll obviously be defending our employee I think against these charges, so -.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Dirk Hoffmann of Bernstein [Sanford C. Bernstein].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thank you. Just two questions, the first one is on slide 29, the overall risk production particularly the 7% reduction ERC. If you strip out the FX impact there would you still say that ERC has gone down and that the VaR positioning is flat, or would you say that essentially there is at least a small uptick if you compare it on a FX adjusted basis and secondly on the basis risk we talked a lot about basis risk and CDOs. Did you experience similar things in CMBS and leverage loans?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Wilson Ervin. With respect to the decline in ERC, if you strip out currency effects it still should have gone down. There were also some minor methodology factors. We updated some of our models to current market conditions, which also increased things like-for-like. But overall our ERC positions were down during the quarter and that reflects I think real risk reduction particularly in leverage finance and CMBS. With respect to your second question on basis risk, we talked about that with respect to CDOs. We have seen some effects like that with respect to our hedges. As we mentioned early on, our hedge efficiency in CMBS and leverage finance dropped somewhat in Q1, and this is because basically the value of cash assets compared to derivative hedges changed a little bit during the quarter and that hurt some of that hedge efficiency. Hopefully that snaps back at some point, if you see some calmer financing markets, but we market those to markets and so those went through the P&amp;L during the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thanks. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>No further questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I understood there might be another couple of questions could you hold on just one &#x2013; so there are no more questions in the queue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>We have one verifying now sir one moment. Georg Kanders of West [WestLB]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. I have a question on the losses in equity prop trading. You said that most of this is the reason why revenues in the equities business were down from Q1 2007, is it right to assume that there were trading gains in Q1 2007? I don't remember it and &#x2013; or are they really equity prop trading losses up to CHF800 million. And the second question I have: is this profitability margin of 85 basis points on the assets, is this really sustainable or is this more an effect of the sharp decline in assets under management in the Wealth Management area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for these questions. Yes, I mean with regard to the equity prop area, yes, it was a substantial positive number in the first quarter of last year. And it's obviously a &#x2013; it's a negative number this quarter, so you're right that swing is a combination of that movement. I think in terms of the 85 basis points, I think our view is that is &#x2013; it is sustainable, and in fact our hope is that it will move up from there. We clearly have &#x2013; we have continuing programs to try to move it up but that's clearly &#x2013; that's one of the challenges that's an area that we'll have to &#x2013; that we are hoping to impact, but &#x2013; so we think that level is probably a reasonable level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, from Elena Logutenkova of Bloomberg</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I have a question about exposures and reducing risk exposures. You said you're going to look to reduce them further in coming quarters. And I was wondering whether you could give a little bit of color on which areas you see more opportunities to reduce this exposure now. And whether you're looking to sell any bigger portfolios of assets or what you're planning to do there? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Elaine. I mean, obviously as we say we've been a very consistent seller over the last nine months to bring down risk positions. I think, probably in terms of additional activities, I mean it will obviously be somewhat dependent on how the markets develop and what opportunities are out there. But I suspect our bigger exposures are in the same kind of areas that we've highlighted. So my guess is that, as we make sales it will probably be from those areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've been able to cut them down very materially from the pace we saw in Q3 last year. So we've already made probably most of the progress we need to make there, but based on view of the market and outlook we will continue to make some reduction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But in which area do you see more opportunities to make those reductions now, I mean in the current market environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's been pretty broad based. We, as I said, we have seen some more liquidity come into the market in April so far, that's still early, it's still tentative, but we have seen some more liquidity and across all of the sectors that we've talked about here leveraged finance, CMBS and the sub-prime sector we've continued to see opportunity to reduce and rebalance positions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What you're also seeing &#x2013; it may be worth making the point that we've seen some of the press reports on other transactions where leverage is provided by the sellers, we have done very little of that. In fact we put some footnotes into our numbers here to show, I think we did about 2 billion of sales in the first quarter on that leverage basis and so we've actually shown that in the footnotes as being reduced from our overbalances. But we &#x2013; most of our sales have been outright cash sales. Thanks, Elaine. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>No further questions back to you Mr. Dougan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well first of all thanks everybody. I know this has been a long call, so I apologize for that, but hopefully we've been able to address a number of the questions.</p>
          <p>And I would just like to reiterate, obviously conditions in the first quarter were extreme. Our results are not what we would like them to be, but they were contained in a few areas. I think the earnings capacity of the business is strong outside of those areas. I think we've seen that. Our capital remains strong, our risk reduction was very successful in the first quarter and we continue to believe that our business model with the geographic and the business diversity around the world is something that is really providing us with a lot of strength. And we see this as certainly challenging markets, but also great opportunities for us to build our client franchises and to take the business forward.</p>
          <p>So, thank you very much for your time. Bye bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>