<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1489151" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>820</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer">Brady W. Dougan</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">David Mathers</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Kinner R. Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Jernej Omahen</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Huw J. van Steenis</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Fiona M. Swaffield</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Mediobanca SpA (United Kingdom)">Christopher J. Wheeler</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Autonomous Research LLP">Jacob Kruse</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (UK)">Dirk Hoffmann-Becking</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Bank Plc (Broker)">Robert S. Murphy</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Welcome, everybody. Thanks for joining the call. Before I begin, please take note of the customary cautionary statement. Today, we've announced robust earnings, cost reduction progress and plans and a series of capital measures designed to solidify Credit Suisse's position as one of the best capitalized and funded banks in the world.</p>
          <p>There are five key points that I'd like to cover this morning. One, we're reporting a solid second quarter result with pre-tax income of CHF 1.1 billion, evidencing the strength of our business model which has been adapted to the new regulatory environment. Two, we achieved our CHF 2 billion cost savings target 18 months early and are now targeting an additional CHF 1 billion in cost savings by the end of 2013.</p>
          <p>Three, we are adding CHF 15.3 billion of capital through various measures. These capital actions will further strengthen our capital base in preparation for Basel 3 regulatory requirements and take any question of the strength of our capitalization off the table. We will effectively raise our look through Swiss core capital ratio to 9.4% from 7% by the end of 2012.</p>
          <p>Four, we are reconfirming our previously announced at or above 15% through the cycle ROE target, even with this significantly strengthened capital base. Higher cost reductions offset the impact of higher capital levels, resulting in a comparable pro-forma ROE of 12% for the first half of 2012. And five, we are committing to distributing substantial cash to shareholders from capital generation once the look-through capital ratio exceeds 10%.</p>
          <p>Why are we taking these measures now? We felt it was prudent and in our shareholder's best interest to eliminate any question about the adequacy of our look through Swiss core capital. Credit Suisse has benefited substantially from its strong capitalization and conservative funding position over the past four years. We've continued to maintain a best-in-class total capital and funding position and this is corroborated by our superior ratings and CDS spreads.</p>
          <p>However, over the past several months, the market has focused more on our common equity position. We had a clear plan to build common equity and were on a glide path where we were already double the level of capital required by our regulator, FINMA.</p>
          <p>In June the Swiss National Bank, our central bank in Switzerland, published a report, which questioned our overall capital position. While we disagree with this report, both in substance and its communication style and we still do today, we felt it was prudent and in fact necessary to respond decisively to these questions and ensure that we are in an unquestioned capital position from any point of view. And the Swiss National Bank's public statement today in support of these measures corroborates this.</p>
          <p>These measures represent an acceleration of our capital plans and take us to the top of the industry from every point of view on capital. Close to 80% of the improvement in the capital ratio to 9.4% does not dilute shareholders' percentage ownership, and those investors who take up their rights in this issue will end up being only about 8% diluted, so the measures are well balanced. But most importantly, these capital measures underscore that Credit Suisse is one of the safest banks in the world.</p>
          <p>I'll now spend a few minutes providing some detail on each of the five points I just outlined. First, our second quarter result underscores the strength of our business model and the positive impact of the changes we've made to adapt the model to the new environment. The first quarter showed that we can produce high returns in moderate markets, and the second quarter provides evidence that the business model is resilient under more challenging conditions.</p>
          <p>For the second quarter we reported pre-tax income of CHF 1.1 billion, net income of CHF 800 million and an after-tax return on equity of 9%. For the first half of 2012, we reported normalized net income of CHF 2.1 billion with an after-tax return on equity of 12%. Improved profitability in Private Banking, resilient results in Investment Banking and solid profitability in Asset Management demonstrate the balance and strength of the evolved business model.</p>
          <p>Second quarter and first half performance demonstrates that the business model is working and delivering good results even under challenging market conditions. The measures we announced last year to adapt to the changed environment are proving very effective and we see continued progress towards the best-in-class business model designed to perform well in the new regulatory environment.</p>
          <p>Second, expense reductions ensure the effectiveness and resiliency of the business model going forward. We exceeded our first quarter target of CHF 1.2 billion and normalized expenses reductions by delivering CHF 1.5 billion in reductions. We bettered that performance in the second quarter and have now achieved our CHF 2 billion cost reduction target 18 months ahead of schedule. We've now identified an additional CHF 1 billion in cost savings, roughly half of which will come from the shared services functions.</p>
          <p>With this additional savings, we have increased our 2013 expense reduction target to CHF 3 billion. We are extremely confident that we'll be able to achieve this. Our significantly reduced cost base provides us with real current and ongoing operating flexibility.</p>
          <p>Third, today we've also announced a series of measures to ensure Credit Suisse continues to be at the top of the industry with regards to capital. In summary, we are effectively raising our look through capital ratio to 9.4% by the end of 2012, up from 7%. This ratio includes a class of capital Tier 1 participation securities, which are loss absorbing and which FINMA has deemed will qualify as part of the Swiss capital requirement.</p>
          <p>As you can see on this slide, we started 7% as per our first quarter simulation for the end of 2012. We then add 2.4% from immediate capital actions including the mandatory convertible issuance during July and add a further 80 basis points from additional capital actions to occur by the end of the year, including strategic divestments. We then make some adjustments, which bring it down by 80 basis points, which bring us to 9.4% at the end of 2012.</p>
          <p>David's going to speak more in detail about the specific measures outlined on the slide, but I did want to spend a moment now on changes to the dividend in 2012 and strategic divestments and asset management.</p>
          <p>For the 2012 dividend, we are accruing for an unchanged distribution amount of CHF 0.75 per share, but we have changed the dividend accrual to 100% scrip or payment in new shares. The 2011 dividend was accrued for a 50% scrip and 50% cash and registered holders had the option to elect the form of payment; in the end shareholders elected for a 48% of the payment in new shares allowing us to retain regulatory capital. This year, there will not be an election option, 100% will be paid in shares.</p>
          <p>On strategic divestments and Asset Management in line with our strategy toward the more liquid alternatives business, we intend to sell certain illiquid private equity businesses. This is compatible with our capital efficient strategy, addresses residual uncertainties around the Volcker Rule and applies to businesses that have limited synergies with other group businesses.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we intend to grow our liquid alternative strategies, as they are more capital efficient, consistent with regulatory developments and more synergistic with our investment banking and private banking businesses.</p>
          <p>These capital measures take any question of the strength of our capitalization off the table. With this ratio at 9.4% at the end of this year, we'll be at the high end of our peers globally and this combined with our industry-leading total capital ratio, best-in-class funding and liquidity structure with an NSFR in excess of 100% and extremely high quality asset side of the balance sheet clearly confirms our position as one of, if not, the most well-capitalized banks in the world.</p>
          <p>The next slide presents the numbers in a different way calculated using broadly the same methodology employed by the Swiss National Bank in their financial stability report published in June. The measures we've announced today should eliminate any of the doubts raised by this report. Our look through total capital ratio by their calculation methodology will rise immediately to 8.5% and will reach 10.8% by the end of the year, almost double the 5.9% stated in the SNB report and clearly a leader in the industry.</p>
          <p>In October 2013, this ratio will rise to 12.2% or more than double this level stated in the report when the remaining hybrid Tier 1 instruments convert into buffer capital notes. We were very well capitalized before. We're at the forefront of the industry now. These measures accelerate the build of our common equity and should completely put any capital question to rest.</p>
          <p>As part of our immediate capital actions, we are issuing CHF 3.8 billion of mandatory convertible securities at a fixed conversion price of CHF 16.29 per share for a total of 233.5 million shares. The issue consists of two tranches. The first tranche of CHF 1.9 billion will be bought by a group of high-quality existing and new strategic investors. These securities will not have subscription rights for existing shareholders.</p>
          <p>The second tranche of CHF 1.9 billion will have preferential subscription rights for existing holders, which can be exercised over a 5.5-day period. Strategic investors have entered into definitive agreements to purchase any securities not taken up by shareholders, thereby ensuring placement of the entire offering. So if any investors do not take up their rights, their shares will be placed in firm strategic hands.</p>
          <p>The strategic shareholder group for the first tranche of CHF 1.9 billion is an extremely high quality group, including some of our existing investors, Qatar Holding LLC, The Olayan Group, BlackRock, Capital, the Norges Bank Investment Management in Wellington, and some new investors, including Temasek, and a group of Southeast Asian strategic investors. Their vote of confidence in the strategy, the bank, and this transaction is a very significant statement.</p>
          <p>Fourth, we continue to believe that our business model will generate a best-in-class ROE at or above 15% over the cycle, even with the significant strengthening of our capital base. Incremental cost reductions will serve to offset the impact of higher capital levels. In calculating pro forma ROE for the first six months of 2012, as I mentioned, the resulting ROE remains comparable at about 12%. This is a robust and balanced set of capital initiatives close to 80% of the improvement in the capital ratio to 9.4% does not dilute shareholders percentage ownership.</p>
          <p>Over the past five years, we've maintained one of the strongest capital levels with minimal dilution. The immediate capital actions we're taking now, including share issuance from the mandatory convertibles, will result in an 18% increase in share count, but those investors who participate in the rights offering will experience only about 8% dilution.</p>
          <p>And fifth, we expect the consistent earnings capacity of our business model to generate substantial levels of excess capital, and therefore, we are committed to distributing substantial cash to shareholders once we exceed the 10% look through capital ratio. We expect to achieve this 10% target during 2013.</p>
          <p>Our business model is uniquely forward-looking, as most of the work has already been completed to evolve the model to the changing regulatory environment. We have reduced capital allocated to the Investment Bank and Fixed Income in particular as we transition to Basel 3. The resulting targeted split consists of a very attractive mix of businesses with greater than 40% of our capital, allocated to Private Banking and Asset Management and less than 16% to the Investment Bank. We expect capital usage in the Investment Bank to remain at or below current levels.</p>
          <p>With a business that has industry-leading returns and capital strength and which has virtually completed its transition to the new regulatory environment, this is a model, which will be very attractive to our clients and employees and will provide best-in-class returns to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>And with that, I will now turn it over to David to walk us through the details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Brady, and good morning. I'll start my presentation on slide 13 with a summary of the financial results. In the second quarter, we achieved underlying revenues of CHF 6.1 billion, pre-tax income of CHF 1.1 billion and net income of CHF 815 million.</p>
          <p>The pre-tax income margin was 19%, the post-tax return on equity 9%. If we look at the numbers for the half-year, we achieved return on equity 11% compared to 15% in the same period in 2011. On a normalized basis though, adjusting for PAF2, but adding in an equivalent amount to deferred share compensation, the post-tax return on equity in the first half was 12%.</p>
          <p>Reported second quarter pre-tax income was also CHF 1.1 billion and that includes CHF 183 million of realignment costs related to the expense reduction initiative, CHF 39 million of fair value on debt gains, all of which were booked in the Corporate Center and CHF 107 million of gains on divestments, including a partial sale of our remaining Aberdeen stake.</p>
          <p>Before presenting the divisional results, I will point out that the legal merger of Clariden Leu into the bank took place at the beginning of the second quarter. And whilst the majority of Clariden Leu's activities were integrated in to Wealth Management, some businesses are now managed by the Investment Bank and by Asset Management. Our Swiss advisory business, previously a part of Asset Management, is also now managed by the Corporate &amp; Institutional Client's group in the Private Banking division.</p>
          <p>We've reviewed the definition and the basis on which we recognize AuMs and have adopted a new definition of these numbers. Although these changes are not that substantial at the divisional level in terms of our pre-tax income or AuMs, we have restated all prior year divisional results and included reconciliation in the appendix. I'd also note that the full second quarter financial release will be available on Tuesday next week, that is the 24th of July.</p>
          <p>Slide 14 please. The Private Banks' second quarter pre-tax income was CHF 775 million. We have a quarter-on-quarter pre-tax margin improvement from 23% to 29%. There was a strong improvement in Wealth Management's pre-tax income compared to the first quarter of 2012. Revenues increased by 4% compared to the first quarter due to higher net interest income and increased recurring revenues.</p>
          <p>If we look at the first half performance for 2012, operating efficiencies improved with a CHF 214 million reduction in the expense run rate on an annualized basis compared to the first half of 2011. And as we've said before, we would expect to achieve further cost savings for our efficiency measures in the second half of 2012.</p>
          <p>Slide 15. Net new assets were CHF 5.5 billion, with particularly good inflows in the Americas, Asia Pacific, and Switzerland. Excluding the outflow from Clariden Leu, the Wealth Management's annualized net new asset growth was 4.6% in the second quarter of 2012. Net new asset outflows resulting from the Clariden Leu integration were CHF 3.4 billion in the second quarter in line with the levels that we expected when we announced the merger.</p>
          <p>I'd also point out that Clariden Leu's net outflows have consistently declined during the second quarter with June net outflows at only CHF 0.2 billion; the lowest monthly level since the integration was announced. I'd also note that in Corporate &amp; Institutional Clients where assets under management do tend to be more volatile, we did experience some outflows from a small number of clients.</p>
          <p>Let's look at Wealth Management revenues in more detail on Slide 16 and start with net interest income, the bottom segment in the columns on the slide. Net interest income increased 4% quarter-on-quarter to CHF 860 million with higher volumes more than offsetting the impact of the low interest rate environment. Recurring fees and commissions also increased by 4% from the first quarter driven by semi-annual performance fees.</p>
          <p>Transaction-based revenues though remained at subdued levels and I'd note that these transaction revenues do include a CHF 41 million gain from the sale of a non-core business, and also in the same quarter a year ago, the results in the second quarter included a CHF 72 million gain on the sale of some real estate.</p>
          <p>The gross margin, driven by the improvement in net interest income recurring fees, increased from 111 to 115 basis points. If you exclude the divestment that I mentioned before, then the like-for-like comparison is an increase from 111 basis points in the first quarter to 113 basis points in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Slide 17. The Investment Bank recorded pre-tax income of CHF 383 million and net revenues of CHF 2.9 billion. The reduction in both our risk positions and our expenses saw a more consistent performance than a year ago with continued market share momentum. I'll go through the revenue trends in more detail on the next two slides, but if you look at operating expenses, in Swiss franc terms, the annualized expense run rate improved by CHF 1.6 billion compared to the first half of last year.</p>
          <p>Risk-weighted assets in the Investment Bank fell by CHF 4 billion in the quarter, reflecting a CHF 10 billion reduction in the said wind-down positions that we've discussed before, partly offset by increase in other business lines, particularly rates. In Swiss franc terms, risk-weighted assets increased due to the appreciation of the U.S. dollar against the Swiss franc, particularly over the last three months.</p>
          <p>Slide 18. Fixed Income revenues was significantly higher than in the second quarter of 2011, driven by more balanced business mix and lower inventory levels which reduced the hedge volatility that we suffered in the same period in 2011. The overall improvement in Fixed Income revenues against the second quarter a year ago is primarily attributable to one, securitized products which had a very difficult quarter in 2011 but was much more resilient this quarter, albeit not at the levels that we saw in the first quarter of 2012. We saw a well-balanced contribution from non-agency, government guarantee and asset finance.</p>
          <p>Second, we had a robust performance in the emerging markets compared to both the first quarter and the second quarter of 2011, with continued growth in local market lending activity.</p>
          <p>And thirdly, we saw increased market share in credit despite weaker market conditions and sustained lower levels of inventory. However, if you look at our rate and FX business, whilst we had a very good first quarter, the second quarter was adversely affected by challenging trading conditions with much reduced client flow. In terms of the fixed income revenue losses from the businesses that we're in the process of exiting, the wind-down portfolio that we've mentioned before, the charge this quarter was CHF 139 million.</p>
          <p>Slide 19. In equities, trading revenues was solid year-on-year with the 8% decline in revenues reflecting reduced client activity, although we maintained our overall market share. Prime services continue to perform well driven by market share gains and notwithstanding reduced industry activity and lower client balances. Derivative revenues though were down compared to the first quarter, reflecting sustained macro concerns and conservative risk positioning.</p>
          <p>Slide 20. Underwriting advisory results reflected continued low industry transaction volumes, although our market shares remained at or above previous quarter levels.</p>
          <p>Slide 21. We showed this slide in the first quarter results. But what it shows is the incremental impact on the normalized return from the Investment Bank's reduction in revenues, cost improvement and RWA reduction measures, first half of 2012 compared to the first half of 2011. And the point here is the impact of the efficiency improvements and the lower risk-weighted asset usage more than offset the reduced revenues with the result that the annualized after-tax return on equity improved to 12% from 8% in the first half of this year.</p>
          <p>And in terms of capital efficiency, defined as revenue per average Basel 3 RWA usage, this improved by 28% for the first half of 2012 compared to the first half of last year.</p>
          <p>Let's turn now to Asset Management on slide 22. Pre-tax income was CHF 133 million in the second quarter. Fee-based revenues increased quarter-on-quarter mainly due to semi-annual performance fees as well as higher placement fees. However, investment gains were lower than in the first quarter at CHF 27 million, due to the timing of realizations and challenging market conditions. And I'd note that the second quarter of last year also included some substantial one-off invested-related gains, which we mentioned at that time.</p>
          <p>If we look at the first half cost trends and adjusting for the PAF2, as per the other divisions, the annualized expense run rate was down CHF 134 million compared to last year.</p>
          <p>Sorry, Slide 20; let's look more at the expense performance so far this year. You may recall that a year ago, we set an expense run rate target of CHF 1.2 billion going into 2012. We refer that CHF 0.8 billion planned to be achieved during 2013, or combined, CHF 2 billion of cost savings in total by 2013. As you remember, we achieved CHF 1.5 billion of run-rate reductions in the first quarter and in the second quarter of the year, we've now achieved the CHF 2 billion annualized cost saving target 18 months early.</p>
          <p>And the charts here show you the annualized CHF 2 billion of cost savings achieved in the six months of this year compared to the six months of 2011. On the left-hand chart, the six month 2011 reported costs of CHF 11.5 billion have been adjusted in the second column to exclude variable incentive compensation and realignment costs so the third column gives you the six month 2012 adjusted operating expenses of CHF 10.3 billion &#x2013; sorry, the six month 2011 adjusted operating expenses of CHF 10.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Then let's look at 2012 on the right-hand side of the chart and adjusted in the six months for 2012 expenses on the same basis. So we start with CHF 10.9 billion but then adjusting for PAF2 and FX moves particularly the U.S. dollar against the Swiss franc, you get an underlying expenses of CHF 9.3 billion. So comparing the first half to the first half is a year-on-year savings of CHF 1 billion or CHF 2 billion from an annualized basis.</p>
          <p>We've now increased our year-end 2013 target by CHF 1 billion to a total of CHF 3 billion against our starting point. Savings of CHF 450 million are targeted in the Private Banking division and CHF 550 million in the Investment Bank. Although I would point out, as Brady mentioned, that approximately half of these savings are generated from the shared infrastructure and support services that support both these divisions across the bank.</p>
          <p>We do expect some further realignment expenses in connection with this of around CHF 525 million and roughly CHF 225 million of that are likely in the second half of this year, and about CHF 300 million of the balance in 2013.</p>
          <p>So let's talk a little bit about more about these incremental expense reduction measures, Slide 24. So let's go into the details. As you know, we've already commenced the integration of the operations and settlement functions across Credit Suisse. This activity, which was previously run separately in each division, is now being managed essentially within shared services with a single operations function for the whole group.</p>
          <p>We now expect further substantial savings following the integration of technology into this, which means that we can run operations in IT end to end, removing duplicate change in management processes, while also reassessing our outsourcing strategy in light of these changes, and the re-alignment of operations, IT, and deployment means that we can look at our cost base holistically and rebalance our onshore, offshore and outsourced services.</p>
          <p>And this, together with further alignment of cost reduction measures across the rest of shared services, will deliver the bulk of the CHF 0.5 billion reduction in spending in this area. There are also a number of measures that we list on this slide within the Investment Bank and the Private Bank to contribute the balance of these savings.</p>
          <p>Slide 25. Slide 25 shows the substantial reduction in our overall Basel 3 RWAs since the third quarter of last year resulting from the strategic realignment within the Investment Bank. Our estimated Basel 3 risk-weighted assets are at CHF 305 billion at the end of the second quarter, close to our revised CHF 300 billion end 2012 target.</p>
          <p>The increase in the second quarter of CHF 10 billion is primarily due to FX movements with the CHF 4 billion reduction in the Investment Bank offset by underlying increases primarily in the Private Bank. You'll note that we've increased our end 2012 risk-weighted asset goal to both reflect the FX rate moves and also an update to underlying estimates for the new Basel 3 regulatory regime to give an end-year target of CHF 300 billion for the group.</p>
          <p>And I'd note in this context that clearly, Basel 3 is an entirely new regulatory regime although we're now in the final six months run off for implementation, a lot of the rules are still in the process of being finalized not just in Switzerland but by regulators around the world.</p>
          <p>So, even though Switzerland is more advanced in this process than many other countries, there are still a number of uncertainties to be finalized. And clearly, we're continuing to actively evolve our business model as we adapt to these changes, and just to be clear, the intention is for the U.S. dollar, Basel 3 RWA usage by the Investment Bank to be at or below the M2T levels of $206 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide 26. To briefly summarize this, what we show here though is how the capital actions announced today will improve the look through Swiss core capital ratio. I'll spend some more time on the details in a minute, but let's look at the ratios first. On the left-hand side of the chart the first column shows our shareholders' equity of CHF 34.8 billion. In the next column we adjust for those capital items that on a fully transitioned or look through basis are deducted in the regulatory capital calculation. This includes owned debt gains, goodwill, and regulatory deductions on the 2018 definition.</p>
          <p>So, in the third column, you can see our look through Swiss core and total capital at CHF 14.5 billion and CHF 17.1 billion, respectively. That's at the end of the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Just to be clear, under the Swiss definition, total loss absorbing capital includes the issued CHF 2.6 billion Buffer Capital Notes, but not the forward exchange CoCos of another CHF 5.8 billion. And this is the ratio the Swiss National Bank referred to in the financial stability report.</p>
          <p>So moving right, the next column shows the immediate capital actions that we affected by the end of July adding a further CHF 7 billion of core capital as well as a further CHF 1.7 billion of capital in the form of Buffer Capital Notes. And that arrives at CHF 21.5 billion and CHF 4.3 billion of Swiss look through core and total capital, respectively. So on a pro forma basis that puts us at 7% look through Swiss losses in capital and 8.5% for the total capital ratio.</p>
          <p>If we then add the benefit, an additional CHF 6.6 billion from the further capital actions that will take place in the second half of the year, as well as the consensus earnings expectations for the balance of the year in the next column, this will increase these same ratios to 9.4% and 10.8% by the end of the year. With our look through core capital at CHF 28.1 billion, nearly twice the level at the end of the second quarter and close to our cap target of 10%.</p>
          <p>Okay. So let's go through the major elements of the capital plan, Slide 27. So we start at the top here, one, we've accelerated the conversion of some of our hybrids in to Buffer Capital Notes pulling forward the pre-agreed exchange that would otherwise take place in October of 2013. This increases our issued contingent convertible capital, or BCNs, by CHF 1.7 billion to a current total of CHF 4.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Second, we're issuing 3.8 billion of Mandatory convertibles at a fixed conversion price of CHF 16.29 per share, converting it to 233.5 million of ordinary shares. Mandatories converting into 117 million shares have already been placed with strategic investors and therefore are effectively already bought.</p>
          <p>Mandatory to convert into a &#x2013; the remaining 116.5 million shares are subject to take up by current shareholders, but their purchase has already been fully underwritten by strategic investors. And just to be clear, you may recall in the first quarter, we mentioned that we were intending to place 33.5 million shares in respect to the minority stake in Hedging-Griffo. This is now incorporated and included in this placing. Just to be clear on these mandatories that will actually convert in March 2013 into ordinary equity.</p>
          <p>Third, in respect with Tier 1 participation securities, you are aware that we already have $3 billion in these instruments that were issued back in two tranches in 2008 and 2010. The FINMA has decreed that this will count at a 20% haircut or an 80% effective rate towards the 150-point &#x2013; basis point premium between the Basel 3 requirement for a G-SIB bank at 8.5% and the Swiss requirement at 10%.</p>
          <p>So you can think of this in two different ways. The Swiss core capital ratio includes this and at 80 basis points to our loss-absorbing capital; or alternatively, the required rate that we have to get to under the Basel 3 rules in conjunction with the Swiss regime is now 9.2% rather than 10%.</p>
          <p>Fourthly, I think you may be already aware from market announcements that we sold our remaining 7% stake in Aberdeen Asset Management for a further capital benefit of just under CHF 0.2 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide 28. So the measures to the term I've just discussed on the preceding slide will all be effective by the end of July and are included as such in the ratios. But let me now turn to the measures that will take effect in the balance of 2012.</p>
          <p>So first, in terms of APPA, which you may recall is a deferred cash compensation award; we will offer to our employees a one-time irrevocable option to exchange their deferred cash instruments into shares. And that will be the same price as the mandatory convertible issuance. Now, clearly this is a voluntary exchange and we don't know what the takeout will be. But what I would say is we'll have a total liability of this around CHF 1.3 billion by the end of 2012. And we're assuming CHF 750 million against this CHF 1.3 billion liability. So a take-up of just over 50%.</p>
          <p>The subscription period for this option is planned for July 18 through to July 27 of 2012, which will benefit capital immediately. Okay. So two, strategic divestments. We have decided to divest a number of businesses of which the most important is the large bulk of our illiquid private equity businesses in the Asset Management division. This releases capital and risk-weighted assets but also accelerates the alignment of this business to the new regulatory regime in the United States otherwise known as the Volcker Rule.</p>
          <p>Three, real estate sales. So we initiated a substantial review of our real estate portfolio a year ago. This is already now well advanced and we would expect to have about CHF 0.5 billion of capital benefit from a number of major disposals that will be finalized in the next few months.</p>
          <p>And then fourth here, there was a normal change in equity that we'd assumed in this projection, which totaled about CHF 1.95 billion. This includes consensus earnings but adjusted for the additional realignment restructuring expenses I mentioned before and also the transaction fees associated with the capital plan.</p>
          <p>Second, the capital benefit you get from the delivery of shares in the special share base compensation, and third, the benefit that we get from reduction in deferred tax and other deduction measures under Basel 3.</p>
          <p>So, Slide 29. So just in conclusion, we provided you with a lot of different capital ratios this morning and there's no doubt the transitioning from B2.5 to B3 is a complex process with a number of different measures that we can look at.</p>
          <p>So let's just summarize. On this slide on the left-hand chart, we show the capital ratios under the B2.5 regime, both Tier 1 and Core Tier 1, the latter being the ratio currently used to determine the BCN trigger on the CoCos. At the end of the second quarter of 2012, our Core Tier 1 ratio under B2.5 was 12.5% clearly well in excess of the BCN trigger at 7%.</p>
          <p>If we look at the measures that will be completed by the end of July, our B2.5 Core T1 ratio increases to 14.2%. If you then include the additional actions and the earnings-related impact over the balance of this year, the ratio would arise to 16.2% on a pro forma basis by the end of 2012. And I know there's been some discussion around the EBA stress test, although we're not a bank regulated by the EBA, this is the ratio you'd compare to the 9%.</p>
          <p>Now, on the right-hand side, we show the look-through simulated Basel 3 and Swiss capital ratios including the immediate capital actions and assuming the completion of the capital plan by the end of this year. If we look at the simulation for the end of 2012 on the right-hand column, you see 8.6%, which is the Basel 3 common equity Tier 1 ratio on a full look through basis. The ratio we're most focused on is the Swiss core capital ratio, which is the Basel 3 common equity Tier 1 look through ratio, plus the Tier 1 participations 76 basis points that I mentioned before. Which you can see, the simulation shows the pro forma basis at 9.4% and that compares to our target of 10%.</p>
          <p>Finally, 10.8%, that's our simulated Swiss total capital ratio, which also includes the BCNs, and is the one that the SNB referred to in the financial stability report.</p>
          <p>So, on that note, I'd like to conclude my presentation and thank you very much for your time this morning at short notice. And I'd like to pass back to Brady.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, David. I think with that, we'd like to open it up for questions. So, operator, can you open up the line for questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question today comes from the line of Kian Abouhossein from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. First of all, just some technical questions. The deferred cash into CS payment for employees, what is the assumption that you take that there will be roughly 50% plus per take-up? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is related to your cost savings. You've done a great job of achieving them. If I look at the comp ratio or the cost-income ratio, though, one could argue, especially in the IB, there is more to be done. Can you maybe also talk a little bit about how you think about IB cost-income ratio on a longer-term basis going forward rather than just the absolute target?</p>
          <p>And the third one is more strategic. I'm sure there were a lot of options discussed of how to deal with the capital situation. And one could have argued that maybe the fixed income business should be reduced further from roughly CHF 150 billion of risk-weighted assets, and one of your competitors in your own country operates with less risk-weighted assets. Why didn't you choose that option rather than raising equity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kian. I appreciate the questions. I think on the first point, as you say, basically the program that we are offering is basically &#x2013; as you know, we've had this APPA program out there, which is a deferred cash instrument. It earns the ROE of the firm, and there are also our claw back provisions for the employees based on the performance of their business. So, it's a fairly, I think, well-aligned instrument for our shareholders. What we're basically offering people is the ability to receive all the payments under that program including any ROE, any claw back, et cetera, all factored into that in the form of shares set at a conversion price that's the same as the mandatory convertible conversion price that's been set or CHF 16.29.</p>
          <p>And I think our view is that &#x2013; I mean, obviously, we don't know. We'll need to go to people. And as you know, there is certainly are pressures in the industry. People would rather have less deferral, have more cash, et etcetera, but I think our hope is that people will be quite interested and bullish on participating in the stock and the upside there from this program. And so, our assumption was that we would be able to get to those kinds of numbers.</p>
          <p>We already have from our Executive Board, we have 100% participation and 100% of their APPA holdings. So, basically, the remainder is about 50% take-up from other employees who hold it. So, we think it's probably a reasonable assumption, but it'll obviously depend on various things, and we'll only find out when we find out when we make the offer to employees. But we think people will feel good about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And once they get the shares they can sell them right away, there is no kind of vesting period involved?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, obviously, the shares will be delivered as they receive the payments on the APPA. So, the first share delivery for someone who participates, and it will be actually I think next April. So, almost nine months from now. But as they receive the annual interest payments in the form of shares, should they opt for that, and principal payments over the next two or three years, that's when they will actually get the shares. But, yes, once they get the shares, they will be able to sell them but they will be in tranches and the first one beginning not until April of 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the third question, as you say, certainly, obviously, we would like to think that we thought hard around the business and the different options that we had here. And I think one of the things that we hope is good is that we view this as a balanced set of measures in terms of trying to have the maximum sort of non-dilutive impact, making the right choices around the businesses consistent with our strategy. I think your question on the fixed income business specifically is probably partly rooted in &#x2013; if you look at the performance in the second quarter, I mean, I think that we feel like we've done a lot to diversify and balance our fixed income business and very much derisk the business. And so, we feel like we are now running a sort of state-of-the-art Basel 3-complaint fixed income business.</p>
          <p>As such, it's actually been performing pretty well, and the second quarter, I think, is a good example of that if you look at the resilience of the revenues there. Frankly, it's also an area where we think there probably is the biggest diversions in the industry between those who have adapted their models to Basel 3 and those who haven't.</p>
          <p>And so, we think that there's going to be a lot of change in this portion of the industry over time, and that change is going to lead others to have to really very significantly revamp their fixed income businesses, which will probably lead to opportunities for us.</p>
          <p>So, we think we can make it a consistent earner in the meantime. Second quarter is encouraging in that respect, but also, we do believe that this is probably the part of the investment banking business, as you know well, that is going to have the greatest impact from the capital regulation and the changes, and we think we are better positioned in that given the measures that we've taken today.</p>
          <p>David, I don't know if you want to talk about the expense side a little bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. So, on the expense side, I mean I think clearly, second quarter cost income ratio investment bank was about 87%. But for the first half, it's actually at 77% once you actually normalize for PAF2. So, 79% without that normalization, 77% with.</p>
          <p>We have a KPI to the investment bank to actually get that to a 25% pre-tax margin, so for a 75% cost-to-income ratio. So, we clearly think that we are making good progress towards that goal. Clearly, we think it's better to go and that's our intention and goal to do so, and that's one reason why we've actually stepped up the cost saving target for 2013. I would say, though, that it is an ongoing and rolling cost reduction target and that we will be looking further measures above and beyond that as we implement some of the programs we've now initiated.</p>
          <p>So, I think we clearly would intend to push this further. As I said, I think our KPIs, 25% of the investment bank, 75% cost income ratio, not far off there in the first half, put a little bit more drift in the second quarter with a more difficult operating environment we're in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think also, Kian, I'd just like to emphasize our focus is on return on equity in our businesses, and that's the most important focus. And frankly, I think that's going to have to be the industry's focus going on, given the cost of capital and given the amount of capital it's assessed against these businesses. And so, that's really the way that we look at and manage the businesses.</p>
          <p>And frankly, if you have a lot leaner, from a capital point of view, in terms of the business, you're likely to have probably slightly higher costs and also costs and, to some extent, compensation costs in that business as well. As David said, we are targeting the 25% margin. We think we're going to make very good returns in the business and consistent returns, but that's really what we're focused on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I may, one more follow-up. As you said, you've done very well relative to some of the peers in your fixed income, as well as equity business. Can you just talk a little bit about how the market environment is shaping up in July relative to what you've seen in the market in the second quarter both in a fixed income and briefly in equities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think broadly &#x2013; I mean, obviously, again, it's pretty early in the quarter. I think, broadly, it's consistent with what we saw in the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question today comes from the line of Kinner Lakhani from Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. So, I have a couple of questions actually. Firstly, on the strategic divestments, which I believe may relate to private equity businesses within Asset Management, perhaps, could you give us some color on how advanced you think those disposals are in terms of the process?</p>
          <p>Number two, in terms of the APPA exchange, just wanted to make sure I understand in terms of the share dilution that comes out of it. Essentially thinking about the 750 million assumption relative to the mandatory conversion price, if that's the correct way of looking at it.</p>
          <p>And number three, if you could maybe give us a bit more color on the kind of repurchase of debt instruments and what really you're benefiting from in terms of both capital and funding costs? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thanks very much for those questions. I guess, on the first point, I guess I would just go back and stress that the measures that we're taking are consistent with the strategy that we've had in asset management and really more of an acceleration and continuation of those measures. And frankly, I think we've actually done a really good job in terms of our focused strategy there and how we've executed on it.</p>
          <p>I mean, as I think David mentioned, we basically finished off the sale of our Aberdeen stake. I think that was a very successful both strategically and financially. We sold our long-only business to Aberdeen, took a stake in exchange and have now sold that stake out at good levels. And so, I think that's a good example of the focusing that we've had in the business, and I think we've actually shown in that business that we've been very good at executing.</p>
          <p>I think, as I said, this is just a continuation of our focus on a more capital-efficient approach to the business. We're looking at focusing on some of the more liquid alternatives parts of the business. We have a lot of great aspects in our asset management business, but that does mean, as you say, that we would be looking at sales of some of the businesses on the private equity side of the illiquid side of things.</p>
          <p>I'd rather not comment on sort of exactly where we are in the process, but we feel confident that these are the kinds of asset management businesses that are actually quite attractive and that will be of interest to a pretty good group of potential buyers. And so, we feel &#x2013; and obviously there've been some other asset management business approaches, which have not been successful. We think this is a very targeted set of businesses. It's not a large conglomeration of businesses. It's a focused targeted set of businesses, and we think that these are businesses that are actually, clearly, will be attractive to a pretty decent group of buyers. So, our view is that we feel pretty confident that we'll be able to get these done. And obviously, we have done some work on it.</p>
          <p>So, David, you want to address APPA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. On the APPA conversion, deferred cash conversion, at CHF 750 million you'll be talking about 46 million shares which would come in three tranches in 2013, 2014 and then a small tranche in 2015, which is the delivery program for the APPA instruments. So, the shares are actually delivered following the election by the employee over the same period as the APPA itself.</p>
          <p>I think, quite clearly, as to make a sort of small point, which is the actual dilution of this would depend where our capital position is at that time because, clearly, if we &#x2013; as you know, we've said we are going to commit to make substantial cash return to shareholders once we actually park at the 10% level. So, we may choose obviously in the latter years to actually buy some of the market. But I think, for the moment, why don't you assume the fully diluted, that's probably the most pessimistic and prudent case.</p>
          <p>In terms of the debt buyback, I think you may remember that in the first quarter, we did a CHF 4.7 billion debt buyback which contributed about CHF 0.5 billion to our CT1 base. Mostly it's directed at good equity; some gains through the P&amp;L as well.</p>
          <p>I mean, in reality, what we're actually doing is we're retiring some of the non-equity instruments lower to Tier 1 instruments which were and actually still are required under the Swiss decree which came out in 2008 but is replaced by the Basel 3 regime at the beginning of next year. So, as essentially, we've issued both the capital notes we're aggressively retiring this stock of old capital instruments. And this new exercise really falls into that. The targeted size is somewhere between CHF 3 billion and CHF 4 billion. And we would not expect substantial gains for this buyback as the first partly relating to price and partly I think with how successful we are in terms of actually buying this debt back. However, at that size, we're probably looking at something like CHF 40 million of interest costs and there will be a modest gain to capital but not on the sort of CHF 500 million gain that we saw from the first tranche. Is that helpful?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's really helpful actually. And if I could just follow-up, just with the kind of appreciation of the U.S. dollar and the sensitivity to your earnings going into the second half of the year. I guess at this time last year the exchange rate was in a very different place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean the exchange rates at &#x2013; I mean, if we look on average, in the second quarter, it was 0.93; it closed at 0.945 for the capital ratios. Clearly, in the second quarter a year ago, it was 0.87. And I guess, at the moment, we're around the sort of 0.97 to 0.98. Now, that benefits the investment banks earnings on translation because I think you should assume that nearly all of the investment banks earnings are actually dollar-based. So, therefore, I think if one looks at one's forecast, if you assume those were in dollars, then you can get a fairly direct impact of the earnings benefit from a higher dollar against the Swiss franc.</p>
          <p>And I think we've made this point before, but just to be clear, we essentially hedge shareholders' equity against the dollar. So, approximately 65% or so of our risk-weighted assets are actually in dollars. And our shareholders' equity is essentially matched to that both at about 65% dollars, too. We essentially do that to basically hedge the capital ratios. Clearly, what that means though of course, is an appreciating dollar, you get a benefit to shareholders' equity because, obviously, it rides on consolidation to Swiss francs. So, that's the other impact from an appreciating dollar against the Swiss franc for Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question today comes from the line Jernej Omahen from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning, gentlemen. I have a few questions, some of them are clarification questions on some of the capital measures, and then I've got a couple of other questions, as well. Firstly, can you explain to us why it makes sense to issue a mandatory convertible note that matures in eight months' time? I mean, if I understood you correctly, particularly yourself, Mr. Dougan, you expressed a view that you expect participation from your own employees to be reasonably high because the outlook for the shares is, in a sense, constructive. Yet, if I understand this correctly, you're offering the mandatory convert holders a 10% discount for eight months. So, an annualized return of 12%, 13% for essentially something that, I think in normal circumstances, one would expect to be done either through a rights issue or through a placement?</p>
          <p>The second question &#x2013; accelerated book build, rather, the second question that I have is on the first capital measure, the CHF 1.7 billion of Tier 1 capital notes which you're folding into BCNs, it's surprising to see that Qatar Holdings, your core shareholder and definitely your core holder of hybrid capital is not participating in this exchange. Now, if I understand this correctly, this is a hugely important development because their holding of hybrids is CHF 4.1 billion. So, it's actually larger than the mandatory convert issuance altogether. And I was just wondering if you can shed some light why is it that if I recall correctly, it's probably for the first time since the beginning of the crisis that this core shareholder is not supporting the capital action of Credit Suisse.</p>
          <p>The third question that I have is, it is surprising to see that when you have CHF 8.7 billion of capital measures that an EGM is not called. And I was just wondering whether part of the reason, and I'm assuming that's not the case, that there's a better explanation. But maybe part of the reason for doing this via a mandatory convert note which converts already in eight months' time is perhaps trying to &#x2013; I was just wondering whether &#x2013; if you did a rights issue or a book build, whether you would need to call an EGM or not, and whether doing it via a mandatory convert note allows you not to do that.</p>
          <p>And the final question I have is on the SNB recommendations. I think that you're right when you say that you are now fully essentially compliant with what the SNB asked Credit Suisse to do by the end of the year. But there seems to be two additional issues here. So, the first one is the SNB made an explicit reference to the simple leverage ratio. And I was wondering if you can just update us on what the leverage ratio is on your calculations today and what the simple leverage ratio will be after these capital actions.</p>
          <p>And my final question is, the SNB also called for an increase in transparency when it comes to risk-weighted asset calculations and has urged UBS and Credit Suisse to report risk-weighted assets calculated on the standardized basis. And I was just wondering whether we can get that number as well. Sorry for the many questions, but thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much for all of those questions, great questions. I guess maybe we can just work backwards from what you had mentioned. I mean, I guess on the SNB recommendations, as you say, I mean I think one of the most important things is that, obviously with the measures that we've taken today, we've, I think, pretty much put to rest any of those concerns. And actually, I assume most of you have probably seen that the SNB actually issued a statement, which is actually pretty strong in terms of what they said. I mean, if you haven't seen it, they welcome the capital measures. They said those measures lead to a rapid and significant increase from the loss-absorbing capital of Credit Suisse Group. And in an environment that remains particularly challenging for the international banking system, these measures substantially increase the resilience of Credit Suisse Group. So, I think a pretty supportive statement and one that hopefully indicates their alignment with the measures that we've taken.</p>
          <p>I think, I guess, on your very last point about increase in transparency, I mean, I guess I would let everybody on this call judge that. I actually think that we have been about as transparent, if not, more transparent than virtually any other firm on all of these issues, whether it'd be earnings issues, capital issues, I don't know of any other bank that has disclosed as much about the RWA progression, the capital progression and everything else. So, I think you all are probably in a better position perhaps than some others to judge about the transparency that we had offered. So, I think that actually we have been extremely transparent and continue to be and we will continue to be. But again, I'll let you judge that.</p>
          <p>Do you want to answer the question about the leverage ratio and then we'll <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:01:12).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. So, I think what the SNB did in the Financial Stability Report is they took the Swiss total capital which they defined as the Basel 3 look through common equity and then added to that the issued CoCos as at the end of the first quarter.</p>
          <p>So, if you look at Slide 26, you'll see a number there about CHF 17 billion. I think we felt safe to get to that first quarter number, it must be at about the same number. You may recall the balance sheet at the end of the first quarter was exactly CHF 1 trillion. So, I think they closed the ratio about 1.7%.</p>
          <p>So, if we look at the sort of second quarter numbers, you see that capital increased, this is on Slide 26, to CHF 25.8 billion and to CHF 32.4 billion at the end of the year. Now, the balance sheet was about CHF 1.043 but essentially, you therefore you'd be seeing the leverage ratio on the SNB going from 1.7% to about 3.2% on a consistent definition basis. I would just state though that clearly the Swiss leverage ratio is what we actually operate under. You'll see that in the Appendix, it was about 4.7% and increases to about 5.2% once these measures are actually complete.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I think as to your questions around &#x2013; I'd probably kind of lump together a little bit your first question around the mandatory convertible form, which is convertible in eight months and your question around the capital that we're raising in the form. I mean from my point of view, actually, I think that one of the absolute best things about all these measures is that the capital that is being raised, first of all, a lot of it is from non-dilutive sources so I don't know exactly what the CHF 8 billion is that you're referring to. Obviously the mandatory convertible issue is about CHF 4 billion and there are some other measures as well. But really, the only measures that are going out in terms of the actual sort of more traditional capital raise are the CHF 4 billion.</p>
          <p>But second of all, I think that the structure of this is extremely decisive, is completely underwritten by strategic investors, still offers the opportunity to participate from the broader group of our investors. So, frankly, I'll have to say in my opinion, I think it's a very well structured transaction from all those points of view. And frankly, we obviously &#x2013; all of this is being executed within the authorities that we have from our shareholders, which we've received in our AGMs in terms of the authorized shares and the form that we can do it in.</p>
          <p>So, again, my view is that I think this is an extremely well structured transaction, and we can talk more about that. But having it fully underwritten by a group of extremely high-quality, strategic investors is, in my view, a pretty good place to be. So, when I compare it to other capital raises that have been done by banks, I think it's a pretty good structure, but I guess I would.</p>
          <p>In terms of your other question of the acceleration of the hybrids into contingent convertibles and Qatar's participation in that, first of all, I would just say Qatar has been a tremendously valuable investor and strategic partner for us. They continue to be. They have participated fully in this capital transaction; had been very supportive and that we have had a lot of dialogue with them in how we've actually structured and done this. We believe they are completely supportive of it.</p>
          <p>To be honest with you, on the issue of the actual acceleration of the conversion, I mean, their notes will still convert in October of 2013 just as it was originally scheduled. To be honest, I'm sure they have ways they think about their portfolio and their investments. They certainly find that investment very attractive. It's got a high coupon on it. It's a very good instrument.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, for us, increasing the level of high-trigger contingent convertibles is helpful. It does increase the loss-absorbing capital. It's helpful in getting an even higher number than what we are currently showing against the ratio that was shown in this SNB stability report. But to be honest, I think when you all look on the issue of capital, for us, it's not a total capital issue. It's really just around this common equity issue. And so, that's really what we were focused on.</p>
          <p>And so, frankly, they have been extremely supportive in the overall transaction, and we're actually very grateful for their support. And whether or not they accelerated this contingent convertible, I mean, we would have been happy to do it. We're okay with their considerations in not doing it. So, I don't think there should be any view that there is anything but a very strong strategic relationship and a lot of support there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot. Maybe just two very, very short clarification questions. Did I understand you correctly that when it comes to SNB's recommendation that "Banks should already be reporting risk-weighted assets on a standardized basis to help market better assess the reduction in risk", do you plan to essentially take the SNB up on that recommendation and release standardized risk-weighted assets with your full Q2 results for later on in the year or not? Just yes or no.</p>
          <p>And the second question, I was wondering, I still missed the rationale for issuing a mandatory convert which converts in eight months' time at a 10% discount to the current share price when the view clearly is, from the perspective of Credit Suisse Group, that you have a very constructive case for share price appreciation in the future. I'm just trying to understand the rationale. Is there a legal rationale where you're trying to avoid complexities of calling the EGM? Is there an economic rationale? Because from an economic perspective, it's just very hard for us to understand why this part of the capital increase makes sense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's David here. I think the point just to stress here is that financing through a managed convertible issuance is a relatively standard approach in Switzerland, and it's being used by other Swiss financials for a number of years. So, it's more or less the normal course approach, which one would take here in Switzerland. And it's the one, which the authorization and the rules actually operate. And a lifetime of that is relatively standard. So, there's nothing particularly out of the norms there. I recognize that's different from other regimes, but it's very common here in Switzerland. So, that's the point I'd make on the first one.</p>
          <p>On the issue of the standardized calculations, it's not a trivial thing to do because any bank's risk systems are actually built around the models that are in play today. So, those of course are currently B2 and B2.5 for us, and when the middle of the B3 build for all our systems to take to that phase in the beginning of next year. So, if you actually wanted to recut all the systems so they operated on essentially a B1 standardized-type basis, you have to rebuild a whole parallel set of models to actually do it. That would be extremely expensive for any sort of market risk approach. It would be difficult for some of the credit to ease the market risk. And then for op risk, it wouldn't be that difficult. But it's not, in fact, a trivial exercise that could be done that easily. And it would have substantial cost implications that we have to then build essentially a B1 system to run in parallel with B3. And I think as we all know, I mean, I think you may recall the B1 regime didn't really reflect low risk. It was one of the reasons why it was essentially retired with B2 in most places and why, basically, people are moving to B3 because of the limitations around B1 were very standardized balance sheet-type approach. But I mean, yeah, clearly, it's something we'll see, but, I mean, it's not a trivial exercise to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is too bad because it would be nice if we could go back to the systems you're in six years ago and avoid all the costs that we've had in the meantime. But that's hard to do at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I guess, that's our view is we don't &#x2013; it's complex.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the answer is no, you will not be providing standardized risk-weighted asset?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I just answered the question that it would be extremely expensive. It does not provide a better manner of risk. I think &#x2013; that's all I'll say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question today comes from the line of Huw van Steenis from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I think you already answered my questions on capital, so I just have two more. First, I'm surprised in your release that you've maintained your 15% return on equity target given that it was sort of set in the time when you were far more optimistic about the revenue environment and also far more optimistic about your capital position. Could you maybe just talk through why you think this is actually &#x2013; a, when is this target actually realizable? Are we talking sort of five to 10 years' time, and what is your realistic expectation for the next three years?</p>
          <p>And related to that, you previously thought you wanted a core Tier 1 of 10 and 3 points of CoCos. In the light of being overoptimistic in this slightly harsher regulatory terms, do you think that is still appropriate? Do you think that needs to be a significant buffer of the 10%?</p>
          <p>And then lastly on dividends, given the Board's being overoptimistic on dividends for the last two years, do you feel &#x2013; and you're going to script for this year, would it be a safe bet that for the next one to two years, we should assume zero-cash dividend, so the Board will be much more cautious about capital rule and regulations. And maybe that explains why you've chosen to do sort of a rather generous mandatory because, for next year, it's highly unlikely that you actually pay a dividend on the common equity. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Huw. Thanks very much for those questions. Yeah, I mean, I guess, with regard to the ROE, again, we have reiterated our target of a 15% ROE over cycles. I think, in the first six months of this year, we posted a Basel 2.5 ROE of 12% in what I would view as not really great environment, particularly the second quarter. First quarter was okay. Second quarter was pretty difficult. I think a 12% Basel 2.5 ROE on that basis is &#x2013; I think that's a pretty credible performance. We obviously have identified additional cost reductions that we can make. We're continuing, I think, to realize the benefits from the changes that we've made both on the cost side and a number of the alterations that we've made to the business model as a result of getting quickly to a Basel 3-compliant model. And we think we're going to continue to benefit from that over time.</p>
          <p>In addition, I think we do continue to believe that &#x2013; and we're starting to see more signs of it now that the rest of the industry is going to have to make the transitions that we've made. And as they make that, that is going to probably create more opportunity for us to take market share and to do more. And you're starting to hear a little bit more about Basel 3 from a number of the banks that talk about. And you're starting to see a little bit more about what's happening with risk-weighted assets, et cetera, around the industry. And I think that's going to continue. So, I think we're also going to benefit from that.</p>
          <p>So, we're certainly not talking 5 to 10 years as a target for a 15% ROE. I think under reasonable market conditions, our business model can produce that now. We made, I think, 16% on a Basel 2.5 basis in the first quarter. And I don't think I mean again you all can assess, but I don't think the first quarter was a blowout quarter in terms of industry conditions. It was okay. It was reasonable, but it wasn't sort of a blowout quarter. So, I think we'll continue to improve the model which will help to get us at or above that level more consistently. And hopefully we'll also have some conditions that will make it a little bit better.</p>
          <p>I think on the core Tier 1, 10% and then with the high trigger on top. I mean I think our view is, as we've said, I think when we get to a 10% sort of Swiss core look through ratio and particularly with our total capital ratios including 3% contingent capital in the form of our high-trigger CoCos. In addition, given the extremely conservative funding profile that we have, we have an NSFR over 100%. I'm not sure there are any other banks that have that. We think we have a very high quality asset side of the balance sheet as well. I think all of those contributes to us I think believing that at a sort of 10% -- that 10% look through ratio I mean we may have some small buffer on top of that. But being around that 10% ratio is going to be a pretty good place to be I think.</p>
          <p>And so, I don't think that if you're question is, are we going to have run significant cushions above that? I don't think that that's our belief right now. And with regard to dividends, I mean I think that our view is that we've got a stable business model from the point of view of consumption of capital. I think as David said, we expect the investment bank to be at or below these levels. We may see a little bit of growth in our wealth management businesses, but they're not very capital consumptive anyway. So, if we're at 10% and the business model performs in the range of how it can perform, I think there's going to be clearly a significant amount of capital that could be passed on. David, do you want to add to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just a few points, just something that what Brady said, I mean, mostly I think it is worth recalling a couple of things. I mean, the ROE within the private bank was about 25% in the first quarter, that's on a post-tax basis, Basel 3 at 10%. It was about 29% in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>And I think you may have seen in one of the slides, we reiterated and actually reinforced our other UA and capital allocation model that we intended to see less than 60% of the UA of the bank was within investment bank, less than 40% was in fixed income division, Slide 11, and more than 40% within the private banking, wealth management and asset management businesses.</p>
          <p>So clearly, for us, I think we are fortunate that we have a very, very strong market position in one of the highest return on equity businesses in the modern financial world. I think, you know, we talked about this before, I mean, a number of things we could talk about in this meeting, some of the plans, about the bank in terms of what we're doing over expenses and growth in that business. So I think that's one thing, just to put it in context, when you look at the ROE for the bank as a whole.</p>
          <p>I think the second point, just in terms of the sort of capital discussions here in Switzerland, I think the point I'd really want to reiterate, the discussions really are the 10% number which we talked about and which, clearly, given we're gaining a pro forma 9.4% at the end of the year, one would have thought we would be at 10%, everything else being equal, not too long there afterwards, subject to market conditions &#x2013; and that's not a forecast, but we're obviously in good shape.</p>
          <p>We obviously have about 2.8%, 2.9% of our B3 capital rate in highest rate CoCos, and obviously, the final tranche we convert in next of October. So we're at the 3% target under the Swiss regime. So I mean, in reality, I think the capital work that we will be doing will be around the retirement of the residual sort of the old Swiss <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:17:17) and essentially the low strike CoCos which you're required to operate under the Swiss regime and that's really where the focus of the discussions will be I figure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's I mean, and that's clearly just to reiterate, I mean that's why we've made this point about the commitment to return significant cash to shareholders once we fill the 10% loan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question today comes from the line of Fiona Swaffield from RBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I had a number of things, sorry. The first issue is the discussion about the 9.4% or the 10% relative to kind of absolute Basel 3 equity because Brady did mention that it was the absolute level as well that was important. I'm looking at Slide 26 and the CHF 28.1 billion, which I think obviously includes the CHF 2.3 billion so it's closer to just under CHF 26 billion. So I'm just trying to understand what your thinking is on the absolute because it hasn't moved that much, from a tangible point of view, it's just really the MCN. So I kind of feel there's a push and pull between this kind of leverage ratio issue versus the kind of the Swiss number of 10%. That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is, could we spend a bit more time on the gross margin, and to what extent that I mean, I'm trying to get my head around the net interest income part and the sustainability going forward?</p>
          <p>And then the third issue is, again on Slide 26, the regulatory deductions are higher than they were, I think, as of the first quarter, I remember a number of just over 8%, now they're 10.1%. And then I'm wondering if you could tie that in, in the past, you've told us moving parts of 2013, and obviously that's not in this slide pack. But when we're looking forward to 2013, has anything changed? You used to say there was a CHF 3 billion reduction in regulatory deductions. Is that still the case? So when we model out should we be including retained profit plus the regulatory deductions? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, David will take the first and the third and I'll talk a little bit about gross margin. So, David you want to start?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let me start with the regulatory deductions on page 26. So, Fiona, just a point of correction, in the first quarter, what we actually said in the look through was that rate reductions would be 8.3% as you said, however that was the rate reductions projected for the end of the year not the current time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, that's essential. And essentially because obviously you build equity over a period under the 10% and 15% threshold the deductions decline over that time. Also you'd use that deferred tax. So that's what happened. So the 8.3% you saw before was in the end of year. Obviously 10% is the actual deductions we've given as of the end of June. If you look at the slides, what we actually saw on Slide on 27 and 28, you will see we talk about our projection within this of a further CHF 3 billion in deductions. So if you start at CHF 10.1 billion, you could expect so the number to be down to about CHF 7.1 billion to CHF 7.2 billion by the end of the year. And the reason deductions are actually lower, Fiona, is because obviously you've got more common equity; it comes with these measures so you have less deductions. So that would explain those points hopefully.</p>
          <p>In terms of projections for next year, I must say I haven't looked in detail at 2013 but I would say that CHF 3 billion number is probably a pretty good estimate. We certainly would expect to burn through most of the rest of the deferred tax and continue to build equity as we actually get to target. So I would say that's a pretty good estimate actually, Fiona.</p>
          <p>On the first point, I mean just to be clear, that really relates to the 9.4% Swiss core equity. I mean, I think perhaps I wasn't clear. The ratio that we're targeting to hit is 10% on that core equity, so that's 10% including the Tier 1 participation shows that will be 9.24% on a look through bar ratio. And as I said, the other UA we're targeting is around CHF 300 million so that would be the amount to &#x2013; as you might say and look through common equity, we'd actually expect to have at that time. I'm not sure we really meant to imply anything else, actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Brady, you were happy with the absolute, even though because of the whole debate on equity to own on RWA2 assets, so there's not an intention to kind of build it aggressively from here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think we're being pretty clear. I think once we get to the 10%, I mean the Swiss rules are pretty clear, 10% 3% high stroke &#x2013; I mean, the capital discussions that I'd be expecting to have and indeed started having is really around the low strike CoCos, that's the focus next time for us. But I mean clearly, this will obviously push out the leverage ratio anyway, I think as we replied to a previous question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the gross margin question, as you say it was CHF 115 million. As you know, this quarter that was up nicely from CHF 111 million the last quarter, there is an extraordinary item in there, the sale of the ILS business so it's actually on a normalized base, I think CHF 113 million but still obviously it's a nice tick up in the gross margin so we're obviously encouraged by that. I think in terms of the net interest income, we had higher volumes, both on the lending side and the deposits, so the loan margin was slightly better, but it was offset a little bit by lower deposit margins.</p>
          <p>But overall, I think, obviously a nice move. I mean I think in general, that as you know, we have kind of stopped trying to call the turn in interest rates, et cetera, so I just think the fact that it's obviously stable and it's ticked up this quarter is a good thing. I mean I hope obviously, it can continue to tick up, but certainly, the fact that it has moved up and at least, that shows that it's clearly at a stable level so in terms of net interest income.</p>
          <p>But also, I think the recurring commissions and fees was also somewhat encouraging. There is some seasonality. The second quarter, there is a little seasonality, very slight. But in general, again, I guess I would take it more as &#x2013; I would look at these numbers as stable to slightly up and that's obviously encouraging that they have stabilized. Obviously, we'll hope we'll see &#x2013; third quarter is obviously seasonally a little bit more difficult of a quarter with August, et cetera. But, our hope is obviously that we can continue to see some of these trends.</p>
          <p>But we're mostly focused on continuing to drive our gross margin in this business, make sure that we're hunkered down in case things continue to be difficult in terms of the environment. We want this business to continue to increase its profitability on the bottom line and we'll do our best obviously to drive top line and gross margin, but we'll also continue to be prepared for it to continue to be a challenging environment. But I think this quarter was certainly encouraging.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next, question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question today comes from the line of Christopher Wheeler from Mediobanca. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. And I apologize; our fire alarm is being tested as I speak. Yeah, a few questions of clarification. First of all, the Hedging-Griffo payment, the 33.5 million shares, are you effectively just giving convertible notes or MCNs to the people who are going to get the additional shares? And is that in the CHF 1.9 billion you've already placed or it's in the CHF 1.9 billion you are opening up to shareholders? I assume it's the former.</p>
          <p>Secondly, just confirm, I think the coupon on the MCN is 4%.</p>
          <p>Thirdly, on the participation notes, have they been placed? And if so, where have they placed broadly? Have there been a few investors or broadly? And what is the coupon that you will have on that? What is the cost of the conversion of the part of the hybrid early into the CoCos, the CHF 1.7 billion, is there a cost and what is that and how will that be shown?</p>
          <p>A question on the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:25:40) on the private equity. I hate to say this for your employees but is it something you would also think you might be able to use as compensation this year in terms of paying out some of your private equity participations? My apologies for the fie test there and finally, Brady, you put out a couple of pretty strong statements after the Moody's downgrade and after stability report about how strong your capital position is. And today obviously you've done some pretty major moves to boost it further. Can you just talk about how much of that was driven by regulator and how of that was chosen by the Board's view in your view on the need to be more competitive on your capital position? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris. First of all, I hope it really is a test fire alarm and not a real one. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Or maybe <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:26:27).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe you should get out in case it turns out to be real. But thanks for all those questions. I just on the last one first, I mean, I think it's as I kind of said in my speaking notes, we have benefited tremendously from being in a very strong capital position and being really unquestioned in the safe haven over the last four years. And as you know, we've taken a lot of market share. It's been very important for our private banking business certainly but also our investment banking business, which is very client-oriented, our prime brokers business, et cetera. So, that's been a very, very important part of the value proposition overall. Again, it comes back to this question of our regulator FINMA, we're double their requirements right now in terms of the capital glide cap that they have. So this is why it's a little bit of a surreal discussion as you say was &#x2013; is there a pressure from RWA? We're double our regulator's requirement for where we need to be right now in terms of capital.</p>
          <p>And so, obviously the Swiss National Bank, an important player in the market as the Central Bank. Obviously, their opinions matter but they're not our regulator. And so just to make that clear, we felt and we were on a very good glide path now. Obviously, the market has increased the pressure a bit more on the common equity side and I think the Swiss National Bank report clearly did increase the pressure in terms of sort of questions around the common equity capital position. I mean the interesting thing as you know was out of that whole episode was that I think that all told after the SNB report and the changes in ratings with Moody's, were by the way we ended up I think better rated than all but two banks in the global cohort.</p>
          <p>At the end of all that, our fixed income spreads were actually tighter and we've actually moved in in terms of CDS spreads, et cetera, and in fact, I think benefited relatively in terms of business that we were seeing. So in a sense, it's a bit of an odd position to be in but I think our view was just this is much better to just take the questions off the table definitively. No question with our customers, with anyone out there that there is any issue around our common equity capital, and that's basically what we've done. We've tried to do it in a smart way by taking on diluted measures. By structuring the capital we did raise with a complete strategic backdrop to it so we didn't end up with shares slashing around the market, et cetera.</p>
          <p>But that's really &#x2013; and that's something that basically between management and the Board. We're very much aligned on. Obviously, we have liaised with our regulators on this. They've been very supportive. You've seen the Swiss National Bank statement, which is very supportive. So I think all told that it's really meant to just be a decisive way to take this issue off the table.</p>
          <p>I think, working backwards then, your question about private equity, we do not right now have any thoughts around that. As you know, last year we did this structure to path too which helped reduce RWA, et cetera. And we're obviously continue to try to &#x2013; we try to do the best we can around having very well aligned programs between our employees and shareholders and things that we think help further the strategy to bank. Not sure how much recognition we get for that, but we do try to do that. But right now, we don't have any thinking around that.</p>
          <p>I don't know, David, do you want to start with the Hedging-Griffo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so down with the technical points. So I think Christopher is actually right. So what we said in the first quarter is that we're going to place 33.5 million of shares in respect to the buyout of Hedging-Griffo IRC which is you know is a very successful business that we own in Brazil and part of our very strong product banking asset management and investment bank franchise there.</p>
          <p>We thought it was probably best to essentially incorporate that into these capital measures. So we've actually issued those as part of, as you say, the first tranche, the firm-place, no-crawl-back tranche and that actually has been completed and done now. And I think it was good to get that issue off the market and not their concern in terms of any future drag in terms of share issuance.</p>
          <p>In terms of the Tier 1 participation securities, they were already actually issued. They were issued in two tranches, $1.58 billion each size, the first in 2008 and I think at a coupon of about 8.25%. And the second in June of 2010 at a coupon of 7.875% and both sides are out $1.5 billion. So they're already stamped. They were fully effective under Swiss law for the B2 and the B2.5 regime. And essentially what the FINMA has decreed is that they will be effective at 80% effective rate for the Swiss, Finnish, effectively above and beyond the reduced buffers as we've explained already. So there's no new instrument being issued essentially, it's the existing ones.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and the cost of the bringing forward of the CHF 1.7 billion of the hybrid into CoCo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know that we're going to get into all the details. It's pretty nominal I mean it's basically pretty nominal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the coupon on the MCN I think is 4%, is that right, that I picked up on the Internet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>4%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Gentlemen, thank you very much for your patience. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Glad the fire alarm's off.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So am I.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question today comes from the line of Jacob Kruse from Autonomous Research. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you. It's Jacob from Autonomous. Just three quick questions. Firstly on the mandatory, is there a lock up for the shares after they convert in March next year? And secondly, you gave a guidance for this capital progression where you included the dilutive effect in 2013 of 50% scrip dividends as well as paying employees with shares I think that was $1.2 billion. Is that guidance now off the table or should we just assume that that's still how you look at your capital progression? And then just lastly, I just wanted to ask you if you have looked into your LIBOR positions, if you have any comments you can make about your own investigations and also the sort of state of regulatory debate? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yes, it's David here. So just I take the first two. So there is no lockup on the shares once the management converts next March. On the scrip dividend, I think you're probably referring to the first quarter presentation when we talked about paying per sub scrip periods. I think you're right the guidance we gave at that time effectively is superseded now but what we said today which is the ones who actually get through 10% on Swiss core capital basis. We will look to return substantial cash distribution to shareholders. So I think subject to us achieving that I think we would look to retire the scrip with ownership once and for all. So that's all I'd say on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the LIBOR issue, basically this is has been obviously a long-running issue. I mean this has been out there for the last year plus. Over that time we've obviously had increased from regulators, we've done a lot of work, we've done pretty extensive work internally, been through obviously lots and lots of emails, et cetera, particularly for the specific areas that would be involved. We have obviously analyzed that information. We've also discussed that information with the relevant regulatory bodies and we don't believe that we have any material issues in this area. Now obviously these kinds of investigations as you know can &#x2013; they can take different turns, et cetera, but we don't believe that we have any material issues that we're aware of now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, your next question today comes from the line of <mark type="ph" /> Daniel Tsu Lao from Barclays Sitton (1:34:37), please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. I have just one question regarding your capital increase. I'm looking at the very positive share price reaction today, which certainly reflects to a very logic stand, the capital actions you have announced today. As the market seems to welcome greatly your capital measures, I wonder why you have waited to take so long to actually take these measures. Can you maybe, give your view on that question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again I guess well thanks Daniel, first of all for your question. I think that as I said, we have benefited tremendously from being at a very strong capital position for the last four years. We continue to be in a very strong capital position even before this but there was increasing, I think focus in the market on the common equity portion of that, which doesn't necessarily effect our customers as much but there was an increasing focus on that and then certainly, the Swiss National Bank report, increased the focus on that and so I think our view was that these are very decisive measures. They do completely put to rest this issue and we think they're taken in a timely basis so I guess our view is that before, we had basically been on a glide path where with our regulator we were double their requirement for capital so I'm not sure given that we felt that we were in the right place and continuing to progress on that but clearly given some of the questions raised by the Central Bank which is &#x2013; those are obviously need to be taken seriously that we felt that this was a time to take the issue off the table.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David here, I mean I think there's one point just talking more about what Brady said, I think if you look at the list of actions on Slides 27 and 28, there's clearly a number of issues here, but what we're really doing is accelerating and augmenting an existing capital plan so obviously the real estate plan also issues such as the debt buyback I mentioned before. As Brady said, I think there are very good reasons for us to do that but its more an acceleration of our glide path than anything else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Daniel and next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question today comes from the line of <mark type="ph" /> Andrew Lin from Espirito Santo (1:37:39). Please ask your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, morning. Thanks for taking my questions. I don't think you've talked about the revenue profit impact from the divestment platform part of your capital plan. I was just wondering if you could give more color on that. And then secondly, just one technical question on your lower capital deductions, it's about CHF 3 billion towards the end of the year, I'm sure it's calculated that correctly but is that calculated off a Basel 3 common equity level or is that off a Swiss core capital level, I'm mainly asking because you've included it in your Swiss core ratio. So I just want to know whether we're talking on the same basis here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I think on the first question in terms of revenue and profit impacts of some of the &#x2013; I guess you're talking about the divestiture measures that we have announced...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean I think obviously Slide 10 actually shows in more aggregate some of those impacts but I don't know, David, if you...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We're assuming a pre-tax both the impact about CHF 170 million on site deduct tax, and then it's six months. So that's how that works out. So we've done that. But about CHF 170 million would be our estimates to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think again one of the things that obviously I'm sure you get the point, but the Slide 10 point is important to us which we've obviously factored in the reductions and earnings versus the cost reduction via the additional capital to &#x2013; and those are basically fairly not dilutive to earnings. So I think that's an important point. The other question that was asked David, I don't know if you caught it was lower capital deductions of CHF 3 billion. This question was is that being calculated off of Basel 3 or off Swiss core tier ratio basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a Basel 3 number, the deduction. So it's calculated off the Basel 3, look through common equity just to be clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question today comes from the line of Dirk Hoffmann-Becking from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Thank you for taking the question. It's actually just two questions left. One is can you just take us through the transition in Q1 to Q2 in terms of the CHF 14.5 billion in Basel 3 look through capital that you had, i.e. in particular how much of the about CHF 800 million in net profit did you actually translate into capital? How much was foreign exchange translation gains, et cetera? And how do you see that going forward?</p>
          <p>And the second question is on the investment bank. On Slide 46, you sort of assume an allocated capital of CHF 22 billion going forward, CHF 10 billion less than in the past. So am I right in assuming that you are happy to run the investment bank at the current leverage level which I estimate to be about 40 times going forward in order to preserve the return on equity in that division. Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No thanks, thank you very much for the input. Thanks very much for your questions. I think with regard to the second question, I think you're largely right on the &#x2013; I mean we basically said we would &#x2013; we're running. I think we ended up the quarter at about CHF 206 billion and obviously, we've said that we think that we'll be at or lower than that going forward. So I actually think the allocated capital will be more like CHF 20 billion or something on just assuming a 10% Basel 3 read through. So it's a little bit less capital. But I think our general view is that those levels or around those levels is about the right level that we believe we can drive an investment banking business that generates 15% return on equity. And that's really our target for that business. And we think actually that's a configuration that works and so we will continue to do that.</p>
          <p>I mean overall, as you say, the whole leverage question, we are basically towards the top end of the leverage ratio requirement by FINMA regulator. At this point, they had sort of a 3% to 5% ratio guideline and we're actually at about the top end of that range, at 4.7%. So we feel like we're actually in a good place from a leverage point of view, certainly, with regard to our regulator. So we're right basically at the top end of the range.</p>
          <p>We do think, obviously that the kind of gross leverage arguments are ones that we don't like that much because we think we have an extremely high-quality and low-risk investment bank. I mean, you know half the balance sheet is either in prime brokerage deposits or repo, which we view as extremely high quality. And again, I think you have to kind of put leverage and all those issues against things like funding profile as well. I mean, we think we run an extremely conservatively positioned investment bank in terms of all of those elements. So, yeah, I think our view is that we think that's sustainable and that we'll be able to continue to run it that way.</p>
          <p>David, do you want to address the first and second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just that &#x2013; the addendum, the 4.7% was at the end of the second quarter. On a pro forma basis adjusted to capital measures, the Swiss leverage ratio would be up at 5.3%. We, in terms of the FX moves coming through the balance sheet, the full financial report will be ready next Tuesday. But what you'll see there is currency translation adjustments of just under CHF 1 billion which comes through from I think the equity heading strategy which I mentioned before. This is the fact we basically swap the equity to dollars to basically mitigate against any volatility on our capital ratios.</p>
          <p>So obviously, the dollar is appreciating close to about CHF 94.50 at the end of the second quarter. Trading has appreciated more so far in July. So that's what you'll see, going forward. I don't think that would prove to be the most important item. But as I just said, you'll see this in the report next week.</p>
          <p>In terms of looking through to the end of the year, I mean, I think I wouldn't want to call an FX forecast or anything, given that about 65% of our risk-weighted assets are in dollars, the 65% of the equities in that. And if the dollar rate stayed against the Swiss franc around CHF 94.50 which was what it was at the end of second quarter, I'd expect neither the translation impact not be a way to increase nor there should be much for CTA effect.</p>
          <p>Clearly, if the dollar continues to strengthen like this, we will see that coming through the CTA, that will boost the shareholders' equity. But clearly, that will also basically boost the Swiss franc RWA on consolidation. But as I said, we're trying to hedge to an essentially neutral capital ratio there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My question was more about the Q1 to Q2. So am I right in assuming that in Q1 you had CHF 800 million profit &#x2013; retained earnings less retained earnings and about CHF 1 billion less from FX translation in your Basel 3 capital or in other words, did you have about CHF 12 billion in Basel 3 capital, of which CHF 2.3 billion was Tier 1 participation securities that wouldn't have been otherwise recognized?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So what the 1Q number would've been?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the equivalent of the CHF 14.5 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And what was your estimate, Dirk, about CHF 12 billion, was it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I just literally here don't know because I don't know what your actual deductions were. I stupidly assumed that the numbers you had in the report were the actual results. So I don't know what the number is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, a deduction effect obviously also comes under the threshold impact too. So it's not a trivial calculation. From recollection, I think it was around CHF 12.8 billion, actually, Dirk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>CHF 12.8 billion? Okay, of which CHF 2.3 billion are the participation securities, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. The CHF 12.8 billion would be the equivalent of the CHF 14.5 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. All right, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks a lot. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question today comes from the line of Robert Murphy from HSBC. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. Thanks for taking the call. Yeah, just a couple of questions. The first one is regarding your capital return. I mean you're focusing on the Swiss core capital ratio exceeding 10%. But clearly, the participation securities are actually a temporary benefit. And I think most peers are looking at the common equity Tier 1 ratio. And if you looked at your common equity Tier 1 ratio on the Basel 3, it's actually quite significantly below many peers as of today. So the question is, how aggressive can you actually be on capital return and what ratio do you think the regulators are going to look at in terms of allowing you to be aggressive on capital return?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think as you said, as you lay out the landscape, I mean obviously the BIS requirements are, there are various different tiers, there's 9.5%, 9%, 8.5%. We believe we're in the 8.5% tier so that's what's kind of required for us or banks like us. Obviously, we've got the Swiss, Finnish on top of that, which is the 1.5 points on top of that to get to 10%.</p>
          <p>So I actually think that even if you take the year-end number and even if you take out the Tier 1 participation notes, which are eligible under the Swiss requirement of getting to 10%, and you're still in the high 8%s. And so I think that's actually a pretty competitive ratio compared to most others. And also what is relevant, as you say, if others in the market are getting to 9.5%s or 9%s are the numbers that maybe need to get through on a pure Basel 3 look through for us to be, if you add another 50, 60 basis points on top of that, for us to be in the low 9%s as a result on a pure Basel 3 basis, I think that's going to position us very well.</p>
          <p>And again I would put on top of that extremely strong total capital position we have 3% of contingent capital on top of that, that's sort of in the wings. We have I think the only bank within NSFR in our funding over 100%. So I mean all that I think adds up to a pretty strong positioning. And so I think we believe we are there or thereabouts in terms of getting to the capital ratios that we need to get to, if that's your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think just one point to make on the Tier 1 participation, this wasn't our reassessment or restructuring, it was actually a decree or ordinance from the FINMA actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Yeah. I understand that. I'm just wondering I mean historically as you've pointed out, you've always actually carried much stronger capital ratios under the old regime. But going forward it looks like you're going to be more like the sort of more quality peers, but it didn't sound like you intend to be again another level higher than those peers as you used to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I would say that clearly, obviously the Swiss regime is 10% plus the 3% CoCos and we've got about 2.85% of that in issue already. And then obviously the requirement for the low strike CoCos beyond that. So I think as you look at the total ratios, I think that's going to be relatively strong capital position against...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just about anybody. So yeah. So I mean I don't think we, I think we believe we are and will continue to be among the best capitalized when you take all that into account.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just quickly one other follow-up. In the private bank, can you say what the performance fee element was this quarter versus last quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You mean in terms of an absolute amount or you mean as a...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Either in the basis points contribution to margin or in Swiss francs, whichever way you want to express it. I think you mentioned that part of the margin benefit was performance fees.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think basically I guess you're talking about I mean the Hedging-Griffo performance, which is around CHF 23 million this quarter. That's the performance element of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that will be in the recurring commissions and fees line on <mark type="ph" /> page 16 (1:50:47).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. So are there any other questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no further questions at this time, please continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well thanks very much everybody for hanging on for while maybe I'll just very quickly sum up. We do appreciate your attention and all the questions. We do view on question capital strength as core to our franchise and we believe the measures we announced today are designed to solidify Credit Suisse's position as one of the best capitalized banks in the world.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we announced robust second quarter earnings and cost reduction progress including CHF 1 billion of additional cost efficiencies to be achieved within the next 18 months. And with the business has been fully migrated to the new regulatory environment that we believe can earn ROEs at or above 15% over the cycle and which will therefore have substantial capacity to return capital to shareholders, we think this is the best-in-class business model. And we're confident that the measures that we've announced will further enhance our ability to serve our clients and provide best in class returns to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>So thanks again for your time and for your attention. And have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>