<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1427382" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-11-01</date>
    <companies>
      <company>820</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer">Brady W. Dougan</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">David Mathers</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="MainFirst Schweiz AG">Kilian Maier</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Cheuvreux SA (Switzerland)">Christian Stark</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS AG (Broker)">Philipp Zieschang</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International Ltd.">Derek A. De Vries CFA</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Huw J. van Steenis</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Jernej Omahen</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Royal Bank of Canada (Europe) Ltd. (Broker)">Fiona M. Swaffield</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods, Inc.">Matthew T. Clark</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Mediobanca SpA (United Kingdom)">Christopher J. Wheeler</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="MFS International (UK) Ltd.">Florence Taj</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Matt P. Spick</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Welcome, everybody. Thanks for joining us for our Third Quarter Earnings Presentation. I am joined by David Mathers, our CFO, who will deliver the results portion of today's discussion. In addition to a review of our third quarter results this morning, we're also going to give an update on the steps that we're taking to evolve the client-focused, capital-efficient strategy of our integrated bank to the new market and regulatory environment.</p>
          <p>I'll begin by saying that we performed below our expectations in the third quarter with net &#x2013; reported net income of CHF700 million and underlying net income of CHF400 million. As you well know, the environment in the quarter was characterized by a high degree of uncertainty, low levels of client activity across businesses and extreme market volatility.</p>
          <p>Escalating concerns around the European sovereign debt crisis and indications of a global economic slowdown contributed strongly and obviously quite negatively to a continued challenging operating environment. In spite of this, we reported a solid underlying return on equity of 12% for the first nine months of 2011, and we continue to gain share across our businesses, solid net asset inflows of CHF7.1 billion in the third quarter and CHF40.5 billion for the nine-month period with strong contributions from ultra-high net worth and the emerging markets. In addition, we saw increased market shares in our equity capital markets for the first nine months of 2011 and advanced to the number three ranking in global announced M&amp;A volume.</p>
          <p>So, clearly a tough quarter, but viewed in the context of our resilient business model and strong franchise, I'd like to make two major points. First, our status as a first mover in adapting our business model puts Credit Suisse in a position of financial strength, a differentiation that clients, counterparties and investors recognize. We were early in adapting our strategy to operate with a lower-risk profile and a greater focus on clients. This early transition positions us for improved profitability and more sustainable returns, while our peers will only be beginning to adjust for the new capital and regulatory framework. We were among the first, in 2008, to proactively establish a client-focused capital efficient business model that we've been executing against ever since.</p>
          <p>This strategy and discipline has given us an advantage during a period of unprecedented market volatility and industry change generating best-in-class average ROE of 14.9% since the beginning of 2009. We also anticipated and actively implemented many of the regulatory developments, too big to fail, liquidity requirements, Basel III, contingent capital, among others into our operating model which puts us ahead of the curve versus those of our peers who still have many of these challenges ahead of them.</p>
          <p>Today, we continue to have a strong capital position with a Basel II Tier 1 ratio of 17.7%. We have already been operating under Basel 2.5 standards since the beginning of the year and we currently have a Basel 2.5 core Tier 1 ratio of 10%.</p>
          <p>In addition, in February, we successfully secured about 70% of our high trigger contingent capital requirement, further enhancing our capital profile and potentially positioning us for more favorable financing terms in the future.</p>
          <p>Today, we have a highly liquid balance sheet and a net stable funding ratio of 97%. Our funding spreads remain among the tightest of the peer group and our long-term funding plan for 2011 is substantially completed. We also have a high-quality, clean balance sheet with minimal exposure to the peripheral European countries. Our total net sovereign exposure to these countries as of the end of the quarter was &#x20AC;900 million.</p>
          <p>All of this has been achieved despite the headwinds affecting our businesses particularly over the past year or so. Our client-focused strategy, coupled with our strong capital base, conservative funding and liquidity position and clean balance sheet has enabled us to continue to gain market share across our businesses and deliver industry-leading returns to investors.</p>
          <p>The second major point that I'd like to make is the strategic steps that we're taking to further evolve our client-focused capital-efficient business model to ensure that we continue to achieve best-in-class returns despite challenging secular trends.</p>
          <p>Obviously, we'd all hoped that the headwinds to our business, including low levels of client activity, low interest rates, market volatility and political uncertainty around the world would subside. It's now clear, however, that these secular trends may persist for an extended period, and we determined our best course of action would be to significantly adapt our strategy to ensure that we continue to produce superior returns for our shareholders and maintain client market share momentum even if these conditions do persist.</p>
          <p>In terms of the specific steps that we're taking to further evolve our strategy, I'm going to provide more detail later. But in summary, first in Private Banking, we're instituting changes which will improve our pre-tax profitability by CHF800 million by the end of 2014. In the Investment Bank, we're implementing changes to ensure that the division as a whole and the individual departments within the Investment Bank earn ROEs in excess of the group target of 15%. Third, in Asset Management, we build on a strategy that we put in place and have been executing for the past three years. We'll continue to grow our fee-based revenues and expand our range of alternative products. And fourth, we're going to reorient our entire business towards clients in faster growing economies. Finally, we've increased our efficiency targets and are implementing additional measures beyond what we communicated in July.</p>
          <p>We believe in the strength of our business model and our early and continued refinement of the strategy along with increased discipline on the cost side positions us exceptionally well to excel when the operating environment improves. Greater client activity, higher interest rates and lower market volatility would all create substantial momentum for our business. The measures I've just described are designed to maintain the strong momentum of the client franchise we've built over the last three years and achieve best-in-class returns.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn it over to David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Brady. Good morning. I'll start my presentation on slide six with an overview of the financial results.</p>
          <p>We achieved underlying revenues of CHF5.5 billion, pre-tax income of CHF0.5 billion and net income of CHF0.4 billion. Diluted earnings per share were CHF0.34. The pre-tax income margin 9%, and post-tax return on equity, 6%. Total net new asset inflows were CHF7.1 billion in this quarter.</p>
          <p>Looking at the nine-month results, and excluding fair value and debt moves, restructuring and litigation costs, we achieved the return on equity of 12%, and whilst this was below our KPI target of a 15% return on equity, it remains above the cost of equity and it was one of the highest returns on equity in the industry.</p>
          <p>Reported third quarter pre-tax income was CHF1 billion. That includes CHF1.3 billion of fair value and debt gains offset by CHF478 million of litigation provisions in Wealth Management and CHF291 million of severance costs related to our cost reduction initiatives and booked in the corporate center.</p>
          <p>Before we move to the divisional overview of our group results, I'd like to highlight the progress on our cost reduction program on slide seven. We have increased our net expense reduction target going into 2012 by CHF200 million to CHF1.2 billion. The majority of the savings will be in Investment Banking. You'll recall that we targeted a 4% head count reduction across the bank, and by the end of October, 75% of these reductions have been achieved. Overall realignment costs are now estimated to total CHF550 million. Of which, a total of CHF433 million have already been recognized by the end of the third quarter.</p>
          <p>If we turn now to slide eight, for a divisional overview of the results. Given the impact on Private Banking's results for the CHF478 million of litigation provisions, the adjusted performance on this slide shows the operating numbers for Wealth Management and Corporate and Institutional Clients. Adjusted pre-tax income for Wealth Management stood at CHF444 million and the pre-tax income margin was 21% compared to 23% in the previous quarter. Pre-tax income in Corporate and Institutional Clients remained strong at CHF217 million in the third quarter with a pre-tax margin of 47%.</p>
          <p>If we turn now to these business lines in detail, let's go to slide nine for Wealth Management. As the scale of the year-on-year FX moves continues to remain significant, we've separated out the quarterly trend in revenues and expenses relating to both FX and the underlying operational performance. So, for Wealth Management, comparing the third quarter to a year ago, you can see that on FX-neutral basis, pre-tax income would have been CHF67 million or 10% lower with broadly stable revenues offset by a CHF41 million or 2% increase in operating costs, primarily due to higher IT investments relating to increased regulatory requirements.</p>
          <p>The pre-tax income was further impacted by a CHF145 million reduction from the strengthening of the Swiss franc, resulting in the 32% lower reported pre-tax profit you see here. The bottom table shows you the same trends against the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to slide 10. Looking in more detail at each revenue component, the underlying trends are somewhat masked by the FX moves, but overall after a weaker second quarter, transaction-based revenue improved in the third quarter by 4% due to higher revenues from both client FX activity and integrated solutions, although the continued low level of customer or client confidence resulted in subdued brokerage and product issuing fees.</p>
          <p>This was the main driver in the 3 basis points improvement in adjusted gross margin to 114 basis points excluding the CHF72 billion second quarter gain which we've gotten on real estate sales back in June. Recurring commissions and fees decreased by 9% compared to second quarter as the result of a 7% decline in average assets under management and the absence of semi-annual performance fees resulting in a slight decrease in the gross margin. Net interest income declined by 4% and continues to be adversely affected by FX moves as well as by the low level of interest rates.</p>
          <p>Slide 11. Wealth Management had solid net new asset inflows of CHF6.6 billion this quarter. Contributions from ultra-high net worth and emerging market clients remained strong. The annualized net new asset growth rate for the first nine months was 5.6% with over 15% growth in Asia Pacific.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to corporate and institutional clients. Pre-tax income remained strong at CHF217 million in the third quarter, with a pre-tax margin of 47%. Continued low credit provisions reflect the high quality of the corporate loan book and the resilient fundamentals of the Swiss economy.</p>
          <p>Let me turn now to the Investment Banking. The investment bank posted a small third quarter loss due to difficult trading conditions and subdued client activity. Revenues were down 12% in the second quarter and 27% from the third quarter last year, with all of our businesses suffering from reduced client activity. FX movements continue to have significant impact on the P&amp;L trends. On an FX-neutral basis, revenues were down 9% from the second quarter and 14% from the third quarter last year. The investment bank's revenues include DVA gains of CHF538 million, rate destruction note liabilities, as well as an CHF83 million loss associated with the shift in the OIS calculation basis. I'd finally point out that the third quarter expenses include nine months or three quarters of the U.K. bank levy accrual for a cost of CHF90 million.</p>
          <p>Slide 14. We've again provided a U.S. dollar-denominated P&amp;L for the investment bank to give a more meaningful comparison to our U.S. peers. If we look at this analysis, particularly for the nine-month period, you can see we delivered a resilient performance in advisory underwriting businesses, with revenues increased in all three areas, notwithstanding a subdued market environment.</p>
          <p>Turning to fixed income, our business has suffered from the more challenging environment, particularly in securitized products and in credit. Whilst in equities, we're pleased to have seen an 8% revenue growth, notwithstanding the considerable market volatility we've experienced so far in 2011.</p>
          <p>And as a final point, the increase in other operating expenses here reflects a combination of adverse FX trends due to the higher translation of our non-dollar costs into the U.S. dollar in this format, particularly in respect to the allocation infrastructure and central costs, as well as additional costs related to increased regulatory trends, including the U.K. bank levy that I mentioned earlier on.</p>
          <p>So, now, let's look at fixed income on slide 15. Revenues were influenced by the following factors: in credits, the weaker results were driven by a substantial widening of credit spreads, low levels of client trading volumes and inventory losses as we significantly reduced our market-making positions in the light of a deteriorating environment. Within securitized products, results continued at the low level that we experienced in the second quarter of 2011, with both client activity and the trading environment remaining subdued. But again, with these trends, our rates and FX businesses showed improved performance.</p>
          <p>On slide 16, as you can see, we have slightly lower equity revenues quarter-on-quarter due to the more difficult market environment. The continued resilient performance in prime services benefited from a steady inflow of client balances. Our cash equity revenues were lower, driven by more challenging trading conditions. And our equity derivatives business continues to perform well, albeit lower than in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Seventeen. Underwriting and advisory revenues were lower in the quarter, consistent with the decline in activity levels. Debt underwriting revenues declined, driven by reduced high yield and investment rate issuance. Despite continued market share momentum, equity underwriting revenues were lower across all products, and advisory fees were reduced due to the slowdown in completed M&amp;A activity. We have a substantial backlog of transactions across all these products that have been delayed due to market conditions.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to Asset Management on slide 18. Pre-tax income in Asset Management was CHF92 million. Fee-based revenues continue to grow, however, lower market values led to unrealized losses on our Private Equity portfolio.</p>
          <p>The continued realization of operating efficiencies from platform rationalization and exiting sub-scale businesses delivered lower expenses both quarter-on-quarter and year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Slide 19. You can see that the profitability reflects the improvement in fee-based revenues comprising most of the CHF124 million and CHF22 million increase from 3Q 2010 and 2Q '11, respectively. Lower investment-related gains compared to previous periods but also lower operating expense of CHF26 million and CHF39 million respectively. And the fee-based margin improved to 48 basis points in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Slide 20. Asset Management also experienced positive net new asset inflows in the quarter, notwithstanding difficult market conditions. Net inflows in our Private Equity segment were driven by new fund raisings. We saw continued positive inflows in <mark type="audio gap" /> (17:13) index mandates although we did see some outflows from our asset allocation business, MACS, as well as certain Swiss advisory assets.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to capital and liquidity on slide 21. We continue to maintain a strong capital position with our Basel II Tier 1 ratio at 17.7%. Our Basel II core Tier 1 ratio, which excludes hybrid capital, stood at 12.6%, and the Basel 2.5 core Tier 1 ratio at 10%. Although the Swiss banks are not subject to the recently announced EBA stress test, we are already above the 9% requirement as laid out in the draft rules that have been published. And I note that these rules specifically include contingent capital, and hence, the buffer capital note issues that we issued in February would qualify in these calculations.</p>
          <p>Let's look at funding and liquidity on slide 22. Our funding and liquidity positions remain strong and we are well-prepared for the Basel III requirements. Our Basel III NSFR ratio, net stable funding ratio, stood at 97% at the end of September 2011, up from 95% at the end of the second quarter. Liquidity coverage ratio, or LCR, is also well in excess of future requirements. Our regulatory leverage ratio for the Swiss rules stood at 4.9%, which is at the top of the required range. Finally, I'd point out that our long-term debt funding plan is now substantially complete for the balance of this year.</p>
          <p>Slide 23. This slide looks specifically at our funding and liquidity profiles. There have been a number of discussions on this topic and as to how it's measured, and we thought this analysis would be a simple and a relevant way of describing it. The important issue here is to look at both sides of the balance sheet in the two charts to assess our funding and liquidity profile. The top chart shows that we've grown our surplus short-term liquidity position from CHF43 billion in 2007 to CHF110 billion by the end of 3Q '11, with substantial reduction in our reliance on short-term funding over the last four years.</p>
          <p>The bottom chart shows that we have a significant surplus in long-term funding. Of the CHF110 billion surplus, around CHF50 billion is our long-term debt and equity capital compared to our longer maturity assets, and a further CHF60 billion is surplus customer deposits in excess of our customer loans. And our coverage ratio for these assets improved to 125%. We've improved this position primarily by keeping our long-term debt level stable since 2007, while significantly deleveraging the balance sheet by reducing the amount of our longer-dated assets.</p>
          <p>Slide 24. With the continued focus on exposure to certain Eurozone countries, this slide shows that we have a limited exposure to both sovereign and non-sovereign counterparties, with only CHF600 million of net exposure to Italian sovereign debt and immaterial exposure to Greece, Ireland, Portugal and Spain. Just be clear, all of these positions are marked-to-market.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like to thank you and conclude my presentation, and hand back to Brady.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David. Now I'm going to spend a little bit more time going into some of the detail on the strategy evolution in our integrated client-focused capital efficient business model. We are proactively evolving our business model to ensure that we can continue to deliver industry best-in-class returns on capital against the backdrop of a difficult operating environment and in response to the challenging secular trends we see for the financial services industry.</p>
          <p>What are the conditions we see today? You're all very familiar with them: global economic growth expectations are subdued; the developed markets in Western Europe and the U.S. are recovering, but doing so at a slow rate, over a long time horizon; interest rates are likely to remain low for some time to come; furthermore, macroeconomic and financial conditions are likely to result in the continued strength of the Swiss franc; uncertainty around the resolution of the EU situation is creating stressed markets and volatile trading conditions; clients remain risk-averse, creating subdued activity levels; and the volume and complexity of the new regulation has business mix and platform implications for our business. So, we have to continue to adapt our business model to ensure we establish the best configuration in the new operating environment.</p>
          <p>In this persistent challenging environment, both from a market and regulatory perspective, we continue to review our businesses to ensure that they continue to contribute to our overall return aspirations for the group. This slide 27 lays out a series of strategic initiatives designed to substantially evolve our business model in response to the regulatory challenges and opportunities that we face. I'm going to cover these initiatives in detail in the next few slides.</p>
          <p>Private Banking. Private Banking continues to be a key engine of growth and value. The performance of the business has been strong over the past three years. We've raised multiples more new client money than any competitor. The gross margin remains one of the best in the industry. And in combination with Investment Banking and Asset Management, it provides a unique proposition for our clients.</p>
          <p>We remain committed to our long-term growth strategy and our KPI targets. We believe we can maintain our franchise momentum and yet, at the same time, improve profitability in the light of the ongoing challenging environment and regulatory changes. To do this, we will first continue to strengthen our dedicated coverage of ultra-high-net-worth clients and to invest in this, the fastest-growing and most profitable client segment.</p>
          <p>Second, in our cross-border business, we are focusing our coverage of those markets with sound economics and sufficient scale. We have deep relationships with a large number of affluent international clients, and they need to be serviced differently than high-net-worth clients. We will implement a more focused service model and product offering.</p>
          <p>Third, in our onshore businesses, we will intensify the focus on capturing international growth, particularly in emerging markets, reinforcing the benefits of our global footprint.</p>
          <p>We have well-defined action plans to enhance the short-term profitability and accelerate the return on investments in growth platforms. We will rationalize and adapt the use of infrastructure in our Western European markets to free up resources to accelerate investment in emerging onshore markets. We are confident that these combined measures will result in a significant improvement in performance and are targeting an incremental pre-tax income improvement of approximately CHF800 million by 2014.</p>
          <p>Our ultra-high-net-worth client business remains one of our key strategic focuses and we're committed to growing their pre-tax income contribution a further 50% by 2014. We have a strong track record, benefiting from our integrated offering, as you can see in the chart on the left. Ultra-high-net-worth assets under management represent 35% of overall assets under management, up 10 percentage points since 2008.</p>
          <p>We have relationships with 35% of the world's billionaires, up from 25% in 2008; 55% of net new assets have come from ultra-high-net-worth clients since 2008, and the business operates with a high pre-tax income margin. And as you can see from the chart on the right-hand side of the slide, ultra-high-net-worth is the fastest growing segment in the market, so the momentum we have here is very productive. Our strategies around this segment, dedicated coverage with senior bankers, seamless collaboration across the integrated bank, a comprehensive leading-edge product suite, and an unrivaled networking platform for billionaires, have been key to the momentum we have built and are key to achieving our goal of increasing pre-tax income in this segment by 50% in 2014.</p>
          <p>In our cross-border business, we're implementing a highly focused service model and offering for international clients. We'll focus on larger offshore markets and serve smaller markets depending on the cost of doing business. 92% of our cross-border assets under management are from clients' domiciled in the top 50 markets. The remaining 8% of assets under management are distributed across a number of other countries. We will serve these smaller markets opportunistically, primarily focusing on ultra-high net worth clients. 87% of cross-border assets under management relate to ultra-high net worth and high net worth clients with only 13% from affluent clients, and only 21% of the client base are ultra or high net worth. Accordingly, we will establish cost effective coverage for cross-border affluent clients, establishing dedicated teams that reduce costs, focus products and service offerings and continue to cross-refer the high net worth segment.</p>
          <p>In our onshore business, our objective is to materially increase the pre-tax profitability with the target of CHF200 million to CHF250 million in incremental pre-tax income in 2014. Our performance in onshore markets is key for the continued momentum of the business. The emerging markets will continue to see excellent growth in wealth, and the onshore businesses support cross-border transformation of the business model and allows us to tap into the very important entrepreneurial wealth in mature markets which are exceptionally well-served by our integrated business model.</p>
          <p>We are today extremely well-positioned here with a broad international footprint. And over the past few years, close to two-thirds of our net new assets were in booking centers outside Switzerland. We believe we can substantially improve the profitability of this business by implementing several initiatives. First, we'll look to increase efficiency across our onshore businesses by adopting uniform platforms where feasible. We'll look to further build out and leverage our client offering and introduce additional efficiency measures. Through all this, we believe we can produce an incremental CHF200 million to CHF250 million of pre-tax income by 2014.</p>
          <p>Turning to Investment Banking on slide 32. Slide 32 sets out the issue that we and as you all know the whole investment banking industry faces. It shows the actual annualized average Basel II and Basel III post-tax ROEs over the last 11 quarters for our three main Investment Banking division business lines namely Equities IBD, Fixed Income and for the Investment Banking division as a whole.</p>
          <p>On the left-hand side, you can see the actual Basel II returns from our businesses over the '09 to third quarter '11 period, 19% overall ROE and an 18% ROE in fixed income. On the right-hand side, you can see that exactly the same performance that mapped against the capital treatment required under Basel III results in a 10% overall ROE of the division and 7% ROE for fixed income. So, the move from Basel II to Basel III results in a fall in Investment Banking returns from 19% to 10% driven primarily by the reduction in fixed income from 18% to 7% as the risk-weighted assets in fixed income go from CHF74 billion to CHF209 billion.</p>
          <p>Now, slide 33 is the solution. By further evolving our business model, we're able to raise the returns close to the levels achieved under Basel II. The left-hand side of the chart shows the actual performance of the business based on Basel III. This is the same as the right-hand side of the previous chart &#x2013; previous slide.</p>
          <p>The right side estimates the pro forma returns the business would have made over the same period under our new business model. The pro forma calculation reduces risk-weighted assets by CHF100 billion in fixed income and adjusts for the adverse impact on revenues and the benefit from substantial cost savings. This gets us back to a pro forma after-tax ROE of 17% for Investment Banking, and 16% for Fixed Income.</p>
          <p>On slide 34, we give you more insight into how we're looking at our current portfolio of Investment Banking businesses. We've grouped each main business based on the strategic approaches we're taking. The column farthest to the left shows those businesses where we continue to invest and grow, where we have built strong market position or are focused on specific activities central to succeeding in the new environment or relevant to our Wealth Management business.</p>
          <p>The central column shows those businesses where we have a dominant position that we will defend or where we want to evolve towards growth markets and the right column represents those businesses where we cannot meet our return hurdle and we need to downsize or cut.</p>
          <p>Now, slide 35 provides you with the next level of granularity on the major businesses within Fixed Income, where we are mitigating risk-weighted assets in order to get a better picture of their annualized revenue contributions since 2009, the mitigating actions we're taking and the approximate adverse pro forma revenue impact as we evolve our business model with an indication of the associated exit costs, looking at each category in turn.</p>
          <p>Within macro, we will mitigate RWAs by over 60% or CHF40 billion, mainly in respect to the accelerated exit from low-revenue, long-dated unsecured rate trades. While this is a large portion of the RWA consumed by the business, this was identified as an exit business when Basel III details were announced given the capital costs of the businesses. And this RWA has not been revenue-productive over the past couple of years. As a result, the revenue impact is modest at less than 10% of the '09 to '11 revenue shown, although there will be some exit costs. In addition, there will be certain non-collateralized exposures that will either mature or can be hedged.</p>
          <p>On the right-hand side, you can see our outlook for the ongoing business is that while the overall market conditions will remain relatively static, we believe we can continue to build on our positive momentum here.</p>
          <p>In the securitized products area, our low-rated inventory positions will either roll off or be sold as we downscale the less capital-efficient business, reducing risk-weighted assets by nearly 50% or CHF30 billion. The adverse impact to our securitized product revenues is around 35%, although it's worth noting that the strong contribution we saw in '09 and '10 has not been sustained during '11. Exit costs should be limited given the highly liquid nature of the assets. You can see on the right-hand side that this segment, we would expect the market conditions to improve from very difficult conditions we've seen over the past couple of quarters and think that we will maintain market share as the whole industry will come under capital pressure.</p>
          <p>In credit, there will be some rightsizing of our investment-grade risk positions. We should have limited revenue impact as we optimize our positioning, although there will be some costs of implementation.</p>
          <p>In emerging markets, there will be limited impact with risk-weighted asset reductions contributing less than 5% of historic revenues as we shift towards a more flow-based model. And we will also accelerate the wind-down of the residual FIB portfolio which will be accretive to revenues compared to the '09 to third quarter '11 period, but also with some associated costs of exit. Hopefully, this gives you a better insight into why, by targeting the least productive risk-weighted assets under Basel III, we're able to limit the adverse impact on revenues.</p>
          <p>Slide 36 summarizes the aggregate financial impact of these plans. You can see in the upper left chart the RWA progression, third quarter '11 in numbers under Basel II to Basel III pro forma, 2012 mitigation and the further mitigation between end 2012 and 2014, to end up at CHF170 billion of RWA. As you can see in the bottom left chart, this results in the composition of overall group risk-weighted assets moving from 55% at work and fixed income at the end of third quarter '11 to an estimated 39% at the end of 2014. The annualized 2009 to nine month '11 pro forma pre-tax income on the right-hand side shows a small increase as reduced expense levels more than compensate for the reduction in net revenues.</p>
          <p>So, in summary, the CHF100 billion of lower fixed income risk-weighted assets reduces their portion of group RWAs from 55% to 39%. On a pro forma basis, the annualized PTI from '09 through the nine month '11 is materially unaffected as the revenue loss in more than offset by the targeted expense reduction. There will be some costs for accelerated RWA mitigation, but they're difficult to calculate being highly dependent on market conditions. We think one of the benefits of being a first mover here is that we'll be able to reduce these RWAs more cost effectively than many of our competitors who will have to move later. And as we work through the disposals, however, we will highlight our costs if and as incurred when they're significant, but most importantly, the pro forma Investment Banking return under Basel III applying the new business model results in an after-tax ROE of 17%. Driving this kind of return on a lower-risk business model should result in an exceptionally competitive return among Investment Banking businesses.</p>
          <p>Now, let me turn to how we plan to grow group revenues in faster-growing markets on slide 38. We will target more resources towards the faster-growing markets and in doing so, we aim for these markets to provide an overall contribution to group revenues of 25% by 2014, up significantly from the current 15%. In order to give you a flavor of how we intend to achieve this goal, I'll provide you with one example of growth plans in each of the regions.</p>
          <p>Within Asia Pacific, our Southeast Asian business differentiates itself through its dominant position in high-net-worth and ultra-high-net-worth clients, our leading equities franchise, and a strong corporate client base. We intend to expand the breadth of our relationships in the region by delivering products and solutions in a more integrated manner, replicating and extending the success we've already had there.</p>
          <p>In the Americas, Brazil is the key market for us where the priority is to leverage the overall dominance of our position in that country and in particular, to further leverage Hedging Griffo in order to advance our dominant position with institutional and high-net-worth clients.</p>
          <p>In EMEA, we intend to build on our integrated banking franchise in Russia, leveraging off of our equities and IBD capability where we're ranked number one, and growing our fixed income business by expanding our product offering locally and targeting a top five position. Net new asset growth from ultra-high net worth clients in this market has been impressive and we are well positioned to continue to grow the business.</p>
          <p>In addition to the strategic initiatives we've laid out in Investment Banking and Private Banking, further initiatives in both our front office and our infrastructure areas will enable us to realize a further CHF800 million of net expense reduction in 2012 and '13. The savings will be realized by maximizing deployment opportunities as our existing business footprint is rationalized, by optimizing our processes and implementing a fully integrated operating model, streamlining operational and support infrastructure through the combination of several middle and back-office support functions and the continued centralization of our infrastructure. The CHF800 million will take our total run rate expense savings to CHF2 billion by the end of 2013, giving us dramatically more operational flexibility.</p>
          <p>Before summing up, we wanted to give you an update on how the impact of the risk-weighted asset reductions will affect the Basel III group risk-weighted asset position at the end of 2014 and our Basel III CET1 capital simulation going into 2013. And here as we've used current market expectations for retained earnings, all the income-related items that we've just discussed as part of the significant evolution of the strategy are not reflected in the CET1 capital calculation. But on the left-hand side of the slide 40, we show you the detailed of calculations supporting the updated progression in risk-weighted assets for the whole firm under the proposed Basel III rule changes and taking account of the strategy realignment in Investment Banking.</p>
          <p>If you start with the CHF210 billion of risk-weighted assets under Basel II in third quarter '11 on the left hand of the chart, we'd add CHF160 billion for the expected Basel 2.5 and Basel III changes, the estimated mitigation benefit achievable by the end of 2012 is around CHF80 billion. And this will result in Basel III post-mitigation RWAs of around CHF290 billion at the end of 2012. Further optimization in Investment Banking risk-weighted assets will be redeployed to grow other businesses in 2013 and '14, so, we expect to achieve a Basel III RWA position of CHF285 billion at the end of 2014.</p>
          <p>The right-hand chart is an illustrative model of how the CET1 ratio could develop based on our capital progression from now to the end of 2012 under the Basel III rules. Left-hand column shows current shareholders' equity, we've adjusted for regulatory deductions and the next 15 month current market expectations for retained earnings, which, I'll remind you again, do not represent forward-looking statements made by Credit Suisse. And we assume a benefit of CHF1.6 billion of issuing shares from conditional capital for share-based compensation awards. So, by the beginning of 2013, our CET1 capital grows to CHF35.8 billion to give a Basel III CET1 ratio of 12.3%.</p>
          <p>We're committed to delivering resilient performance for our shareholders and believe we're the best positioned institution in the industry to produce high returns on capital. We're in this position by virtue of our distinctive business model and our proactive initiatives to aggressively evolve our strategy.</p>
          <p>With the strategic measures announced today, we are building a business model to excel in the new environment, recognizing that the longer-term secular trends will likely continue to be challenging for some time to come and I'm convinced that being a first mover will continue to be a distinct advantage for Credit Suisse in pursuit of achieving industry-leading returns.</p>
          <p>We've developed a plan that I believe will achieve this objective. In Private Banking the changes should add an incremental CHF800 million to pre-tax income by 2014. Pre-tax income margin will exceed 30% and we'll retain the operating leverage necessary to increase this beyond our 35% target as and when economic activity and interest rates increase.</p>
          <p>In Investment Banking, in bottom-line terms, these changes will ensure first that pre-tax income in a post-Basel III world will be at least as high as before with cost reductions offsetting any revenue loss from risk-weighted asset reductions. Second, that the majority of the ROE impact from Basel III changes is offset by the RWA reduction measures. And third, our pro forma analysis shows that based on the last '11 quarters' results all Investment Banking divisions achieved the group ROE target of 15% or greater.</p>
          <p>In Asset Management, the strategy that we've put in place re-orientating the business towards a lower cost fee-based model has continued to payoff even in the current economic conditions. This gives us confidence in the substantial further upside potential that we can deliver. The geographic reorientation of our portfolio towards faster-growing economies will result in 25% of our revenues coming from these markets by 2014 and will position us for stronger long-term growth in revenues, net assets and profitability.</p>
          <p>All of these plans are underpinned by a strong and conservative funding base with the incremental costs of the Basel III and liquidity regime already reflected in our profits. And this conservative approach continues to be a strategic advantage in winning new customers and increasing market share, to deliver on our KPI targets, and most importantly, achieving a sustainable ROE of greater than 15%.</p>
          <p>So, thanks for your attention so far. And with that, I think we're ready to open up to questions. So, maybe we'll start here in the auditorium before we go to the webcast questions. So, we'll have a microphone brought over.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Kilian Maier, MainFirst. The first question would be on the provision for the U.S. litigation. I mean, you probably will not quantify the position &#x2013; the whole position but maybe you can answer the question if this is an add-on to an existing provision or if it's a totally new provision for the U.S. litigation.</p>
          <p>The second question would be on Investment Banking. With the targeted reduction in risk-weighted assets, do you think that it's a position that allows you to compete in the bulge bracket area? Or do you rather envisage a position as a focused niche player like some of your local competitors or actually the one local competitor?</p>
          <p>And the last question is on the loan book in Corporate and Institutional Clients, what's your view here? Any negative impact from the strong Swiss franc going forward, or do think the current level of provisions is sustainable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for those questions. On the first question with regard to the provision for U.S. litigation, I mean, obviously, we're limited in how much we can say about it. It's a complex issue. Obviously, there are government-to-government issues involved. There are a lot of other institutions than just Credit Suisse who are involved in it. We'll obviously take it seriously. We have been working with all parties to get to a resolution. We'll continue to do that.</p>
          <p>The third quarter provision that we've announced is really an accounting requirement. I don't know that I read that much into it in terms of the matter as a whole, but that does represent our provision for that issue.</p>
          <p>On the second issue on Investment Banking, no, I mean our belief is that we'll be highly competitive in the businesses which we choose to be in. And frankly, I think our belief is that we are proactively taking these steps but the whole industry is going to have to go in this direction.</p>
          <p>I mean, obviously, this is mainly driven by the Basel III changes, the increased capital requirements that &#x2013; our belief is that the whole industry will have to adjust their business models in a similar direction. So, our belief is we can have a highly competitive model across a broad group of businesses with this strategy, so we feel confident about that.</p>
          <p>I think with regard to the, as you said, the loans in Switzerland in the CIC division, we continue to believe we have a very high-quality portfolio there. We obviously continue to take the appropriate provisions against that and we haven't had a large tick-up in provisions there.</p>
          <p>Clearly, there are some segments and some industries within Switzerland that will continue to see stress from the foreign exchange differentials with some of the export markets but our belief is that we continue to have a strong portfolio there, and obviously we'll have to see how that develops over time, but we think it is a &#x2013; we feel comfortable with the provisions that we have there now.</p>
          <p>Let me go here first, then next.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Christian Stark from Cheuvreux. I've got a question on the risk-weighted assets for the Investment Bank, which you're bringing down from CHF270 billion to CHF170 billion, where you've sort of taken a return approach, which will lead you to a return on investment, or return on equity, of about 17%, which looks attractive. I guess many investors will take the view that the 17% will still be very volatile and people will sort of be asking themselves, if you took a different approach and looked at the risk-weighted assets, how far could you reduce them in order to keep the Investment Bank at a size where you could significantly, or sufficiently, support your Wealth Management franchise?</p>
          <p>If you took a different view, so, rather than just looking at returns, and if you took a view that you wanted to keep the Investment Bank to a minimum, is there a lot more potential there to reduce the risk-weighted assets? Do you have any thoughts about looking at that kind of an approach?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, I guess the first question is, you make an assumption here that the 17% would be volatile. I mean, obviously, it would be a relatively capital-efficient approach. So, it certainly wouldn't be volatile as a result of big moves in sort of the underlying inventory, etcetera. It shouldn't be.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, there will be obviously some operating &#x2013; there will be operating risks to the business, because it will be more of a client-focused business, more capital-efficient. So &#x2013; but I'm not sure that it will be volatile. Our hope would be, we could have a relatively stable return on that business over time.</p>
          <p>I think that our view is that this is the best configuration to &#x2013; certainly, to support our Wealth Management, our Private Banking business, but also to really leverage off the really strong positions that we have in a number of parts of our Investment Banking business, and to provide very good returns that are accretive to the overall return of the group.</p>
          <p>So, it's really a combination of those two. We think this is the best structure and the best approach, best strategy to take. So &#x2013; I mean, obviously, we've looked at lots of different alternatives. But we think this is the one that really positions us best going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Philipp Zieschang from UBS. A couple of questions, please. The first ones actually relate just to the framework of the IB in the future. Here, I have a question on risk-weighted assets. You mentioned the CHF170 billion, but in your group chart you mentioned that you expect organic growth of CHF25 billion. Is all of that excluding, or outside the Investment Bank?</p>
          <p>Then again coming to the framework, your head count went up to 21,500 in the quarter. I know you have started some cost-free reduction programs. But where do you see head count after these cost reductions, after downsizing your exit businesses?</p>
          <p>Third one, on this framework, just your pre-tax margin seems to be unchanged in terms of the target with 25%, although you've mentioned that your cost and revenue impact should be offsetting each other, which could actually mean it's rather implied about 20%. So, will you change the pre-tax margin target?</p>
          <p>These are my framework questions. Then I have two more, if I may. One is just on your ROE target north of 15%. Is it right that it's calculated on 10% core Tier 1, which actually means adding the goodwill, to make it work with your group ROE target, would drive down the 15% IB target to roughly 11%, because you state CHF6 billion goodwill which we should actually add to your target? So, what would &#x2013; you're telling us the 15% is essentially a return on tangible target? If you just reconcile the new target for the IB with your overall group target.</p>
          <p>And finally, slide 40, your CHF1.6 billion positive impact for Basel III capital from these shares which are not expected to be bought back, to which degree are they reflected in your diluted number of shares for these unvested programs? Thank you. I know it was a lot. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, what's the best way to address? I mean, I think, with regard to &#x2013; as you said, the RWA, you're talking about the sort of the 2012-and-on period, you're talking about the CHF25 billion that we're saying will be reinvested in other growth businesses. I think the idea is that yes, that would be outside the Investment Bank. Was that your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So, basically, I'm trying to reconcile slide 40 with slide &#x2013; I think it is 36. In slide 40, you mentioned CHF25 billion organic growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, the answer is, we're just showing that CHF25 billion is really outside of the Investment Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, that would be in Private Bank and Asset Management. I mean, clearly, this is a somewhat forward-looking statement to 2013 and 2014. I wouldn't say that one necessarily concludes zero, but if one was to take away from those two charts that the vast bulk of that CHF25 billion was outside the Investment Bank, you'd be entirely correct, Philipp.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to take the head count question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The head count question. The reason the head count didn't fall in the quarter despite redundancies is because we actually had the incoming graduate class coming in the third quarter, which joins every sort of third quarter. So, this is always the seasonal high point in terms of head count.</p>
          <p>But I think, in terms of making a forward-looking statement on head count, you should expect that number to drop as we complete the remaining of the implied 4%, or 2,000 people this year, and then the sort of 3% which I think, as people will tell you, around 1,500 there afterwards. But some of it will also be driven by retitling the pyramid towards, I think, more junior employees in terms of the structure. So, we won't necessarily be full net, in terms of the head count number going down here to sort of any particular target for it. But you should see it fall after this third quarter, which was inflated by the graduate intake coming in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Shouldn't we add just an additional layer of reductions related to the exit businesses? They seem not to be included in your cost measures announced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the exit business, I mean, obviously, you've seen that &#x2013; you've seen, I think, already the CMBS announcement, I think was actually leaked in the press a couple of weeks ago. So, that will contribute an element of it, but I think as we move to the next stage of the cost reductions, I think as Brady referred to, a lot of that comes from actually integrating our operating platforms and various internal synergies, as well as the sort of front office business reductions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I don't think &#x2013; for instance, the exit businesses don't have a lot of head count associated with them...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If that's your specific question.</p>
          <p>And I think &#x2013; your next question was on the pre-tax margin, I guess, in the Investment Bank. I think our view is that the 25% pre-tax margin is something that we should &#x2013; we would continue to have as a longer-term goal for the business. So, I don't think we're changing that. I don't know. You said your pro forma calculations get more to 20%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You basically just said that, if you deduct that, costs are expected to &#x2013; or the cost savings are expected to match the revenue losses? And if you did that, then the ratio would fall, having the same profit number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think the target is still 25%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Still 25%, yeah. So, do you want, David, to take the question about the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Return on equity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>ROE target, given goodwill and...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, obviously, I mean, as you are aware, Philipp, we have a technical situation between 2013 and 2019 because, as you understand, the capital CET1 ratios under the Basel III rules actually will include goodwill. Now, that's the analysis we gave here, as well as the ex-goodwill calculations. So, that gives the 12% number that you see in the simulation. You then, obviously, get to a period, as you go through the 2013 to 2019, in which goodwill becomes progressively less effective, at 20% per annum, until you actually reach the sort of Basel III end state. So, I think it's probably fair to say that there isn't that much difference in terms of the opening years. But if we were having this conversation towards the middle or the end of that period, this will probably become more fairly an ROTE calculation rather than an ROE calculation, because the goodwill becomes less relevant at that point for capital purposes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But don't you define the equity base for your simulation on slide 33 on your risk-weighted asset number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I'm pointing out, though, that essentially, under &#x2013; as you can see from the difference between the numbers in the appendix, which show the look-through transition where the ratio is less than 10%; clearly, as you go through &#x2013; post the period, you will actually have to build up to 10% under that measure, as well as including the goodwill numbers. The calculations, though, we actually show here are actually calculated on a 10% RWA, so as if we have 10%. So, it's a full calculation. But I think your point is, if you take that 10% and you add goodwill to that as well, then that would result in a different number, which I think is correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. My point is basically that your slide 33 seems to be a return on tangible equity...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well actually...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Calculation, which needs to be matched to your group target of...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a return on 10% of the RWA as applied at that time basically. So, clearly, if the capital measure includes goodwill, which it does at the beginning of the period, then that would be that, but towards the end, clearly it doesn't. In which case, I think you're correct. But it becomes an ROTE calculation towards the end of the period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the last question was around &#x2013; you said that Basel III targets...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's, basically, it's again slide 40, where you show this CHF1.6 billion positive impact from the share base and I...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. But you're saying something about whether that's included in the fully diluted number of shares?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>To which degree this is included in the current number of diluted shares for unvested, the 73 million which you show.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we'll revert to you on that, just in terms of how much &#x2013; in terms of the &#x2013; is vested and how much unvested, Philipp. I'll get back to you on that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Other questions in the room, or should we go &#x2013; we can come back to the room after we go through &#x2013; I'm sure there'll be a number of questions on the call. Okay. First question on the call?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your first question comes from the line of Derek De Vries from Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I had just two questions, if I might. The first one is a bit detail oriented, but just looking at the Q3 number, there's a, I guess a CHF6.5 billion increase in risk-weighted assets and about a CHF10 billion increase in the credit risk=weighted assets. And I suspect there's something in there, in the detail explaining this, but I didn't get to that, so if you can give us some color there, it'd be helpful.</p>
          <p>And then I guess back to, sort of, the first question that was asked. If I look at the FICC business, it looks like the U.S., or the leaders in the FICC business are doing about US$2 billion to US$3 billion, and you guys are about US$750 million per quarter, adjusting for all the CVA, DVA, etcetera. And I guess my question is, do you expect that gap to widen over time as you kind of exit some businesses to focus where you're good, while the leaders probably are good across the board, or do you expect that gap; them doing, sort of &#x2013; you doing sort of a third to 25% of those guys, to maintain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Derek. Do you want to answer the RWA question first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Derek are you referring to page 51?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wasn't, but that might be where the numbers are. I was just looking at the risk-weighted asset progression between Q2 and Q3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you're looking &#x2013; yeah, I'm not sure if you're referring to the credit risk page which shows, page 51, which shows the cumulative increase, which goes from CHF147 billion to CHF157.9 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that sounds &#x2013; yeah, that's the CHF10 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the group number. The majority of that &#x2013; I think all of it is actually driven by FX moves, because at the end of the second quarter, we actually converted our U.S. risk-weighted assets, obviously, from the Investment Bank at 0.83, whereas this quarter, it was done at just over 0.9. So, that's the currency move there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But then you don't seem to have an offsetting FX move in the capital base, right? So, is that what we should expect going forward, is any risk-weighted asset &#x2013; any currency impact on the risk-weighted assets even offset at all on the regulatory capital?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think the issue is also an issue in balance because, I mean, increasingly what we're actually focused on is the B 2.5 ratio, for which you see the deductions over the page &#x2013; actually later in that section &#x2013; which you see actually fell in the period. So, there was a slight shift in terms of our B 2.5, B II assets in the quarter. So, if you were to look at it for, on a B-2.5 basis, then it is approximately neutral. On a B II basis, there was a shift between B II and B 2.5 assets.</p>
          <p>On a point of fact, in terms of the FX neutralization, we partially hedge our FX neutrality. So, in a position in which the dollar were to rise very sharply, then the Tier 1 ratio would &#x2013; well, the CET1 B 2.5 ratio would drop slightly, and the reverse would be true if the dollar were to actually fall. But it's approximately 75% to 80% hedged, so the movement is not going to be that material. But in this case, it was driven by FX and by, I think, a rebalancing between some of our B 2.5 and B II assets. And obviously, I think, when we actually move to aligning the BIS reporting to this, then this gap between the two measures will drop out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Derek, on your second question. I mean, obviously, the question whether the absolute revenue numbers will widen or narrow in gap, I guess it depends upon your beliefs around whether other institutions are going to go to Basel III and are going to have higher capital requirements. Our belief is that the industry is going to have &#x2013; is going to broadly go to Basel III and they're going to have higher capital requirements as well, based on the BIS guidelines, etcetera. And I think when that happens, there're a number of businesses that just don't actually provide the returns that are necessary. And so, my belief is that every institution will have to go through and look at this, obviously with different strengths and weaknesses in their business, but they'll have to go through this. So, my guess is the absolute would narrow but, obviously, it depends upon your beliefs.</p>
          <p>But the more important thing for us is, we're not really focused the absolute amount of revenue. We're focused on the returns that we can drive from the business. And our belief is that we can get our business, our fixed income, our FICC business, to a 16% return on equity on a pro forma against 2009 to '11 which we think, as an environmental assumption for the next couple of years, is not an unreasonably central case to have. You obviously may have your own views on that.</p>
          <p>We've obviously had some good periods there, some bad periods. But I think, as a central case, it's not a bad assumption. And if we can do that, if we can actually get our fixed income business to be a above 15% ROE, I think that's going to be a pretty best-in-class type number. So, that's what we're really focused on, is the returns on the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Derek, I just want to add in, by the way. I would just note, there was about CHF1.5 billion increase in Private Banking lending in that credit risk number. So, it's not all Investment Banking, just to be clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Derek. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Huw van Steenis from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have got three questions. The first, I suppose on the CHF40 billion of macro RWA you're looking to shrink. Whilst you've mentioned your first-mover advantage, it strikes me that every single bank is trying to get out of long-dated structured rates product, to the extent you can't sell them more quickly, can you share with us what the average duration is of that CHF40 billion book of RWAs?</p>
          <p>Number two, I'm sorry, number two is on mitigation, obviously you said it's very difficult to ascertain effectively what the cost of the mitigation will be at the moment; to the extent that it's a very wide bid-ask, how does that inform your view of the dividend? Would it be prudent, given your full look through Basel III ratios probably now bottom quarter with your global peers and your uncertainty about the derisking, do you think it'd be prudent to maybe skip the dividend for this year, or how do you think about that?</p>
          <p>My third question is on a slightly different topic, so I'm very happy to hold that back or deliver it now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead. Why don't you ask?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And third one, I'd really be more interested in your views about sovereign risk. Given the proposal to not trigger the CDS on Greek sovereign debt, does that make you &#x2013; how does that make you think about the validity and usefulness of the hedges you've got on Italian sovereign debt? Do you think we as investors, or you as management, should really think that, for all European sovereign CDS exposure, one should really just say that they are of questionable value and we should really look at the gross rather than the net exposures? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, with regard to your third question, which I'll take first, I think, obviously as you say, the developments in the market are something that I think we have to take note of, and we certainly have. And I think participants in the market obviously will and should. I think that &#x2013; I don't think it would be &#x2013; I think it would be too extreme to say that no CDS protection has any value because, clearly, I think it does have value, but there may be situations where &#x2013; as what's, I guess, happening in Greece, it may not be triggered.</p>
          <p>On the other hand also, I think you have to assume &#x2013; you have to also look at the nature of the sovereign risk as well. So, for instance, there are, obviously, government bond holdings, which is one thing, but there are also other types of exposure &#x2013; derivatives exposure, etcetera. And so, I think the questions of how that would be triggered and how it &#x2013; how that would relate to CDS, etcetera, are a little bit more complex.</p>
          <p>So, I think it's certainly something that bears a lot of focus. It's certainly something that we think about, but I also think that it's a more nuanced question than just, hey, are CDS going to be effective in hedging sovereign risk? It depends on what kind of sovereign risk, etcetera, because there are different types of sovereign risk and I think you have to &#x2013; I think it's a little bit more nuanced than that.</p>
          <p>Do you want to try to address the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First question here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, of the CHF40 billion, Huw, it splits really into two components, so CHF20 billion has a duration of less than three years, and in reality therefore, one would expect to be able to run off relatively easily. And the other CHF20 billion has somewhat longer durations. I'm not sure I can give you an average, but clearly between three and six years with some outliers from that. So, I think that's probably where &#x2013; if there are exit costs to incur, that's where we do expect them to actually be seen.</p>
          <p>In terms of potential buyers for that, I mean, clearly one point about this counterparty risk for us is that other banks may have had the opposite position on the same counterparties, so it is not necessarily true that add &#x2013; that selling a position to another bank necessarily adds to their problems. It may in fact result in a net gain for both parties. So, I wouldn't regard it necessarily as a zero sum game. It may in fact be a positive sum game in terms of the mathematics. I think we'd also probably look to see buyers outside of the Basel III arena, in terms of alternatives for our managed hedge funds, etcetera, who would not be affected by this, because the CVA calibration under Basel III is obviously quite onerous, in terms of the terms, and there is clearly an alternative return structure which will be available for holding those assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think, Huw, I think on your question around the mitigation costs, etcetera, I think that there &#x2013; in a sense, there is a wide bid-ask, because &#x2013; actually, it may even be possible that we make money on some of the disposals. So, it's not a &#x2013; I don't think it's a given that there will be necessarily even costs associated with many of the disposals, but it is obviously dependent upon markets and how things develop. So, I guess it's &#x2013; in a sense, it's a wide bid-ask, but it could also be positive as well as negative. So, I think that's important to keep in mind.</p>
          <p>I think that the question of the dividend in general is sort of a separate question. I mean, we have accrued at the 1.3 annual dividend rate in the third quarter. That's what's actually calculated into the capital numbers, etcetera. Obviously, we'll have to take a look at that in the light of fourth quarter and full year performance and a number of different issues at the end of the year and -before the board make its recommendation to the shareholders as to what we do on dividend. But obviously, I think that's something that we &#x2013; obviously, can only be determined in the context of the whole &#x2013; of the entire &#x2013; in a broader context.</p>
          <p>I think with regard to the capital levels, though, I think we continue to feel that we're in strong shape, if you look at our overall capital position; look at total capital, which is obviously relevant to senior debt holders, depositors, counterparties, etcetera, it's extremely strong; and we still think that the glide path that we have on the capital developments is one that's very secure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think &#x2013; yeah, I think difficult to comment on industry averages here, but the same time, I would point out that, if we just look at the EBA stress test, we already exceed the 9% in any event, basically. So, I wonder a little bit about the comment in terms of relative position. And clearly, the fact we actually issued the buffer capital notes is a further gain in terms of this, which isn't reflected in the glide path calculations you see there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We can take it up offline, but I think I was referring more to the top 12 investment banks, where most of them are trying to guide to between an 8% to 10% look-through Basel III ratio by the end of next year. But I agree with you, relative to most Eurozone banks, you look extraordinarily well capitalized.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Huw. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Jon Peace from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi. A couple of questions, please. Firstly, Brady, I just wanted to follow up on your observation that you thought that for the Investment Bank, the 2009 to nine month '11 run rate was not unreasonable as a central case looking forward. I mean, that's pretty favorable compared with the current consensus. It's about 50% higher as I look at it. So, my question is how sensitive is your 15% ROE target to achieving that historic run rate? And what if it was more like the run rate we've seen over the last 18 months?</p>
          <p>And the second question, is just to come back on your Basel III look-through. You're telling us it's 7.4% at the end of 2012; last quarter, you said 8.8%. So, that comes down quite a bit. The first question is do regulators actually care? Do they look at this at all and do they have a sort of back-of-envelope number below which they'd be uncomfortable?</p>
          <p>And secondly, if you could just walk us through why it's come down? I can see the regulatory deductions have moved quite a bit amongst other things. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll take the first question and maybe David can address the second.</p>
          <p>Well, I mean, obviously, as you say, everybody can have a different perspective on what they think is a reasonable prognosis for the markets going forward. And I certainly don't think we have any special insight that would give us a better view of that than you. But what we have done is we certainly have looked at the numbers, as you say, exactly that, which is to try to &#x2013; if you think that 2010 and '11 is more of a central case for the next couple of years in terms of the overall business environment, when we've run the numbers on that on a pro-forma basis, the Investment Bank comes out in sort of an 11% to 12% return area. And the group, as a whole, still ends up above the 15%.</p>
          <p>So, I guess, it's resilient in the sense that even if you think that 2010/'11 is what we're going to &#x2013; that average level of activity is what we're going to experience for the next two, three years, that our belief is we still get to an &#x2013; we still get over the 15% target for the group as a whole and you end up with sort of 11% to 12% for the Investment Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, in terms of the CET1 ratio, I mean, we've provided obviously two simulations, the first being on the transitionary basis or the CET1 ratio and the second being the so-called look through which has all the deductions as per 2019. I mean, I think our understanding has been &#x2013; we've discussed this before &#x2013; I think remains that certainly in the discussions with the FINMA and the BIS that it's very much the transitional ratio which includes the transition adjustments that is the focus for regulatory ratios. Although on the other hand, I think we know that people are interested in the look through ratios as well, which is why we've included that calculation on page 54.</p>
          <p>So, I guess the reasons for the reduction in the look-through ratio for this quarter compared to the second quarter then comes down to two issues. The first one, if we actually look at slide 54, the 35.8 number, that clearly reflects the performance in the third quarter in terms of the absolute number as a starting point, as well as the consensus expectations for Credit Suisse from the analysts, from you, over the next 15 months. So, to the extent those have fallen, that actually reduces the CET1 capital at the end of 2012. So, that's clearly the first point.</p>
          <p>The second point then, it actually relates to regulatory deductions. Those fall really into two groups. The first is, as you know, there's a 10% limit on the amount of deferred tax or timing that's actually allowed on the look-through under the Basel III rules. So, you have to have at least &#x2013; you can only have up to 10% of your common equity represented by deferred tax and timing. This is obviously separate from deferred tax on net operating losses, which is deducted immediately under the look-through transition calculation. So, to the extent that the 35.8 number is lower than it was in the second quarter, the amount of DTA timing, therefore, is slightly lower, so you're going to get leverage on that fact.</p>
          <p>The second relates to &#x2013; is purely a technical reason related to the calculation of CVA deductions under the Basel III rules. Just as we go through the QIS, there was approximately a CHF1 billion variance in that as we actually approached the detailed calculations. So, that's just the Basel rules in practice.</p>
          <p>And the third is a sort of degree of prudent provision that we've taken in terms of the pension position for the group or the Swiss pension fund at the year-end, reflecting the fact that the &#x2013; obviously, interest rates have fallen in Switzerland. In particular, the 10-year corporate bond has fallen in Switzerland. So, we've assumed a slight widening of the deficit calculation on this and that contributes the final billion in this calculation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of &#x2013; the rule set for this, I mean, I think, as you're aware, the Swiss parliament passed the TBTF rules before the election. So, the next phase of the implementation will be the Draft Capital Ordinance.</p>
          <p>The draft capital ordinance is something we probably expect to release, I think probably early in the first quarter for consultation. So, at that point, essentially, the glide path with the FINMA will require between the entry point to Basel III from 1/1/2013 towards the 10% requirement under the Swiss rules by 2019 distributed, as well as the requirement for buffer capital notes above and beyond that 10%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Kian Abouhossein from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. Few question, the first one just coming back to slide 54, the CHF6 billion deduction compares to CHF3.4 billion that you gave last quarter. I understand you just gave some details regarding the additional changes, but can you maybe break down the difference between CHF6 billion and CHF3.4 billion? What exactly are the differences?</p>
          <p>The second question is related to risk-weighted assets, the CHF100 billion reduction in fixed income risk-weighted assets clearly includes some mitigation that you already announced a while ago, roughly CHF55 billion or so of mitigation. And I'm just trying to square the numbers, what has changed? Is it that the mitigations are not achievable anymore, or are the mitigation always been part of fixed income risk-weighted assets under Basel III?</p>
          <p>And in that context, the third question is on your increase in risk-weighted assets due to growing the business. Is it Asset Management and Private Banking that's roughly 20% of the capital allocated to those two divisions. I'm just wondering why you need additional capital for those businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, maybe I can answer the third question first and then, David, you can go into detail on first and the second. But yeah, I think, again &#x2013; I think, as David mentioned, we're planning to provide some of that reinvestment into the businesses. We do think the bulk would be in Private Banking, Asset Management. And there are number of business &#x2013; I mean, we would like to increase our risk-weighted assets in those businesses.</p>
          <p>So, if you look at our lending businesses within Private Banking and the ultra-high net worth business, we see a lot of opportunities to productively deploy risk-weighted assets in that area. It's a slower process. It's not something where you can change it dramatically from day to day. But I think, as we continue to build our business forward, both Asset Management and Private Banking are areas where I think we will see opportunities potentially to be able to deploy risk-weighted assets, so, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'm sorry, I mean...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>To include acquisitions or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That would include acquisitions in the CHF25 billion? Or is it just organic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess it could. I mean, it's not really &#x2013; obviously, it's 2012 through 2014, so it's kind of a forward view. But it's mostly I think viewed to be organic. I guess it could include some acquisitions if there were acquisitions that made sense to do but there's not a specific plan right now of particular acquisitions or whatever. It could include some acquisitions I guess, but I think it's more likely to be &#x2013; the assumption is it's organic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think just in terms of the delta between the 3.4 and 6, I'm sorry, I must not have been entirely clear on my previous answer. The difference between those two numbers reflects to three factors.</p>
          <p>The first relates to the 10% limit on the amount of deferred tax on timing that's allowed, and this is obviously the end state or the look-through ratio in 2019. So, you're only actually allowed to actually count a maximum of 10% on the 2019 definition of capital, deferred tax and timing. So, if for example that 35.8 was higher, then you'd be able to have a higher allowance. If it was lower, you'd have a lower allowance because the earnings realized over the last three months are less than what was forecast, therefore, the 35.8 is lower. So, therefore, you have a reduced allowance to deferred tax on timing in this. So, that's the first component.</p>
          <p>The second component, as I said, is a &#x2013; I guess a prudent provision, shall we say, for the Swiss pension fund deficit because under the Basel III rules, the majority of the Swiss pension fund deficit must be deducted. And I think what we're looking at is Swiss corporate bond yields being lower than they were at the end of 2010. Therefore, the deficit on the Swiss pension fund as calculated under Basel III under U.S. GAAP will be higher than it was at 2010, the year before. So, therefore, we're factoring that in.</p>
          <p>And then the third component is a purely technical change relating to just how exactly how CVA is actually calculated in the Basel reductions, and that was CHF1 billion in terms of that component.</p>
          <p>So, those were the three components before. The first is very elastic, so if the CET1 increases, then that would be recovered. And if it was to decrease further, then that would run the other way. The second is really a function of pension fund mathematics and in terms of how we've actually managed that liability.</p>
          <p>In terms of the overall risk-weighted asset number, you're correct. I mean, what we actually show on slide 40 is a total of CHF110 billion of mitigation. That is an increase, it's not additional to, it's an increase from what we actually said before, both when we actually first discussed this last year and in the second quarter. Some of that increase, you can clearly see, is between now and the end of 2012 and is therefore a significant acceleration.</p>
          <p>We've also now given a target, really, for the 2013/14 mitigation as well. And I think that really reflects a balance of risk and return in the sense we &#x2013; clearly, some of the stuff &#x2013; well, actually as we've said before, probably cost us some money depending on market conditions to actually release those earlier. And I think that CHF30 billion is really a balance in terms of how we actually see those positions being run off. But it is a total in terms of the CHF110 billion, you'd be correct, that includes the number which we've actually given before in terms of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And assuming that the markets don't open up and you cannot sell assets at a good price, what would you say could be the mitigation of the CHF110 billion, i.e. how much is actually roughly related to just maturity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I think I'd probably question whether markets have to open up because, I mean, I think most of these assets are actually liquid trading positions which certainly within the credit and securitized product positions are pretty liquid. I mean, I think it's more just a question of how we actually want to time and phase those sales. I don't think there's any particular issue in terms of selling them down.</p>
          <p>In terms of the rate positions we said before, you can really split that portfolio into two halves, that CHF40 billion. The CHF20 billion essentially relates to stuff that is probably going to run off more or less naturally through the course of this. The other 20 is where we would expect some effort and potentially some costs to be incurred in terms of exiting them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kian. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Jernej Omahen from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. Good morning. I just have two brief questions left actually. The first one related to your risk-weighted asset communication. And I was just &#x2013; I was just wondering risk-weighted asset number, the CHF290 billion that you're targeting, is that in any meaningful way new or is it basically the same to what we had &#x2013; were communicated in the first and the second?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer to that question is it's lower. I think before, I think we indicated mid-range of CHF300 billion. This is CHF290 billion, below it in that sense. So, yeah, and I think there's some FX moves against it as well because you're seeing some currency. So, yes, I guess it is lower in that sense. The 30 clearly between 2012 and 2014 clearly is new.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Because I'm looking at slide 25 of your second quarter presentation and it looks very similar. But given the amount of discussion I thought I would just ask this question.</p>
          <p>The second question I wanted to ask is you made frequent references of Credit Suisse passing the EVA 9% hurdle rate imposed onto the European banks and I was just hoping if you could run us through the broad math of how you get there, because I get Credit Suisse not getting there, so I'd just like to understand what you think gets you over the 9% EVA hurdle rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Have you included the buffer capital notes, I think would be the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The CoCos?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I guess that's a question back to you. Do you think they should be included because the EBA makes it explicit that only CoCos issued on their terms, newly-issued CoCos would count toward core Tier 1? Do you think that what you've got currently will be compliant with that, in a sense, is the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To answer that, I think we'll be very confident they would be compliant with that. The structures are actually agreed in coordination with the FINMA and the SNB before we issued it. And I think, obviously, the FINMA is a member of the Basel Committee. I think it's probably fair to say that the buffer capital raise probably pioneered the market in terms of the structure. So, I think it sets the precedent for this. So, I think, yes is the answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Fiona Swaffield from Royal Bank of Canada. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks. Three issues: one, the incremental cost save, I know you gave a restructuring charge, I think from memory, CHF550 million. But was that related to the increasing from CHF1 billion to CHF1.2 billion or is that related to the CHF800 million delta that's on the slides, or is that extra 1,500 head count not really an issue?</p>
          <p>And the second, which is generally on Volcker and the Volcker Rule, and I'm trying to understand whether any of this is anything related to that or how you feel about the ability to make inventory gains, particularly in the securitization &#x2013; securitized business RMBS because you obviously had some positives and minuses that you've disclosed in the past. And so, how you feel post the proposal?</p>
          <p>And sorry, I think there is a bit of interference on the line, but slide 36, I'm struggling with it a little bit. And that's the bit on the right-hand side, whether you can help us. So, does that mean the gross number, the CHF210 million cost is much higher if we add back this unwind of negative revenues? And is that CHF420 million pro forma expense within the CHF2 billion of cost saves you announced? Just trying to understand how all the numbers tie up. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think with regard to the second question &#x2013; and I'll let David take the first and the third but with regard to the second question, I mean, obviously things as you say like the Dodd-Frank Bill are still in process. It's in terms of how it's going to be implemented, what the impacts are going to be, I think there is a range of outcomes on that in terms of the level of impact.</p>
          <p>So, I think that there are, obviously, the environment from a regulatory point of view, there are a number of things out there. Some are proposed, some are further down the line, some are more preliminary, so there are a lot of things out there that could become bigger or less big factors in the future.</p>
          <p>There's obviously lot of uncertainty around that. I think our general view is that the business model that we're evolving to will put us in a better position to deal with almost all of that, but it's not really been designed with any particular set of measures in mind. So, I think it will put us in a much better place to actually deal with all of that, but it's not really designed with &#x2013; to be a response to any one particular issue.</p>
          <p>David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, on the first point, Fiona, we haven't actually probably given an estimate of what the cost savings- sorry; for the first point, the answer is the CHF550 million I referred to is in relation to the existing program of CHF1.2 billion of cost saves which will be in the run rate by the beginning of next year.</p>
          <p>In terms of the incremental CHF800 million of cost saves that we intend to achieve beyond that, we haven't given an estimate for what we expect those costs to be, we're in the process of finalizing those plans. However, I think it's probably fair to say, Fiona, we would expect those costs to be of a similar order of magnitude to the CHF550 million we've taken so far, and we'll actually be incurring those as essentially we move to position. The U.S. accounting rules don't really allow us to take an upfront restructuring provision, they require us to actually incur them as we actually get quite specific in terms of exact changes.</p>
          <p>So, then on the third point then in terms of slide 36, and I think also slide 35 in terms of the context of this, you're correct in the sense, what we actually show here is the pro forma net revenue impact of minus 210 adding back the CHF925 million of wind down. So, if you add those two together, you'd get a gross number of CHF1.1 billion.</p>
          <p>So, if you go back then to slide 35 which actually shows it by area and that essentially runs through where we actually expect those revenue impacts to be. And clearly, what we've actually said here, as Brady outlined, is that less than 10% of the rates revenues will be affected by this, approximately 35% of the securitized product revenues. I think the point to make here, clearly, is that if we had done this in the early years, 2009, when this business &#x2013; when these particular risks were actually generating revenues, then the impact would have been 1.1.</p>
          <p>Clearly, as we've obviously not entered into new long-dated, unsecured, uncollateralized rates trades in the last 18 months or so and also, as you can see, we've given here, disclosed the revenue of securitized products business as somewhat lower, then the impact on a more recent period would be less than that. But I think in terms of just the analysis on slide 36, again, if you could revert to that, as that relates to those three year periods, you've got both the FIB wind-down assets and those numbers there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, just to clarify on the &#x2013; because obviously we can do our own math now on those numbers, but the nine months numbers, that's just not annualized. That's just nine months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's just nine months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You didn't annualize them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's just nine months, Fiona, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the &#x2013; just to be clear, the cost saving there is the pro forma reduction expenses for that. It's a little difficult to relate to these numbers because it clearly relates to three years of cost as opposed to the one year number. But the cost savings, we're actually planning to clearly get you to at least this number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Matthew Clark from KBW. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Couple of questions. Firstly, on Investment Banking compensation seemed to be up a bit both third quarter versus second quarter and nine months on nine months in dollar terms. I'm just wondering how you think about that whether that's the appropriate kind of accrual rate for this year or whether you're just waiting until the full year to decide whether you've got scope to true down a bit on that line?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, sorry if I'm being slow, but just to come back to Fiona's question on the various cost impacts, am I right to be thinking that the CHF1.2 billion net cost saved by next year should be with respect to the first half 2011 cost rate whereas the revenue at back of CHF95 million relates to the average of the last three years effectively? Is that the right way to think about it? It doesn't look like an apples and apples scope if we're trying to work out the gross and net impact of those cost saves? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think on the IB compensation side, I mean, obviously, there are a number of different ways you can compare it. I think it's in Swiss franc terms, which is the way we primarily look at it, down about 23% on the previous year's quarter. It's about flat with the second quarter. But as you know, I mean, the &#x2013; really, these numbers are just accruals and we'll actually determine where we'll come out in the context of the full-year performance after the fourth quarter, etcetera.</p>
          <p>So, I'm not sure it's that significant, but it is flat on second quarter in Swiss franc terms. It's down a lot on the last third quarter. Actually, I don't know on the nine month number but, so &#x2013; sorry. So, anyway &#x2013; so, I think &#x2013; but obviously, the most important point is that, look, it's as you know, it's an accrual and we'll judge what's appropriate in the context of what the industry does, etcetera, and what our performance is in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just quickly follow-up. Can you give a rough indication of what proportion of your Investment Banking head count are Swiss-based if you say that the Swiss franc is the most appropriate way to look at it? I'm just a bit surprised by that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, now I'm just saying it's our functional currency, so when we look at the numbers, that's generally the way that we look at it. I'm not sure. I don't actually know the number of head count that's in Switzerland. But as you say, you can look at it in dollar terms as well. But anyway, I think the more important point is, it's a third quarter accrual or it's a nine-month accrual so the actual number will be determined in the context of the full year performance, etcetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, just in terms of the cost saves, Matthew. So, the CHF1.2 billion reduction run rate will be effective from the beginning of next year, so January 2012 in that sense. I'm not sure that &#x2013; I mean, what we tried to do really on slide 35 and 36 is to give enough information for you to make the forecast. I hope &#x2013; we're trying to be as helpful as possible.</p>
          <p>Clearly in terms of the costs, as I said, the CHF1.2 billion is effective from the beginning of next year. In terms of the revenue impact of the RWA reduction, I think it will clearly depend on how fast we sell down the assets and which assets we sell down. I don't think I'd want to get drawn into a quarter-by-quarter plan in terms of how that actually works through. And clearly, it will be &#x2013; I mean, clearly, the revenues of the business will obviously depend on what the market conditions are at that time.</p>
          <p>But I think you need to think about the cost being lower, the further CHF800 million coming in then over 2012 and 2013, and then the adverse revenue impact of the reduction of RWA clearly depending very much on the market conditions you have and the starting place in terms of the position size.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I can just ask it quickly in another way, the CHF420 million pro forma expense reduction on slide 36, is that an element of the CHF1.2 billion or the CHF2 billion run rate group cost cuts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Difficult to compare because the CHF420 million is the reduction in the average expense from downscaling the scale of the businesses over the three-year period, so it represents the average over that period of time, whereas the CHF1.2 billion is a reduction for, I think, as you may recall when we discussed this in June &#x2013; July, sorry, it's a CHF1.2 billion from the first half's expense rate, times two basically, so the annualized first half expense rate. So, the CHF1.2 billion is the reduction in that. So, one is a comparison to a three-year average; the second is a comparison to the first half. So, yes, they're clearly related numbers, and as I said, the cost numbers will at least meet that CHF420 million. But, technically, you're actually comparing two different periods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Christopher Wheeler from Mediobanca. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. The first question is on the plan, obviously, for reduction of RWA within the Investment Bank. And obviously, while it's very important that you're making these changes given the market conditions, I guess the thing that's confusing me a bit is this &#x2013; when I saw the headline of 50% reduction in RWA, I was quite excited. And then I realized CHF70 billion of that was already something we talked about for over a year, very much in terms of capital management, never about enhancing returns. I just wondered when, sort of &#x2013; we've now got to the stage where you are talking about that. At what point did you already stop to refocus on the fact that mitigation could be a very good thing not just in terms of meeting Basel III but actually providing a higher return? So, that's the first question.</p>
          <p>My second question goes back to something Huw asked earlier on the capital ratios. You're absolutely right in that your regulatory ratios look robust, but we have a situation where certainly Goldman Sachs and Morgan Stanley are telling me they are going to be at 10%, all in 2012 for competitive purposes. Jamie Dimon had a, "Road to Damascus," moment at the third quarter. And in his words, changed his tone and said he thought he would be doing something similar. Clearly, we have Barclays and your friends across the road doing something similar for competitive reasons. Are you at all concerned of the 7.4, you look rather weak from a competitive position that may impact on this plan that you're putting in place? Or do you go in the sort of Deutsche Bank class, in saying, "We don't mind, our clients are very happy to deal with us regardless?" Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, I think on the first question, I think we've always taken a consistent approach to it which is clearly the reductions in RWA are clearly necessary from a return and a structural point of view in the businesses and they certainly impact both the capital ratios but also the returns on those businesses. So, I don't &#x2013; what we have talked about today is obviously an acceleration and additional steps taken there. But I'm not sure that we ever viewed it &#x2013; it wasn't sort of a phased approach but...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why &#x2013; I mean, I think, Chris, I think if you look back at the announcement we actually gave in the first quarter of 2009, when you may recall, we exited a number of businesses, complex structured derivatives, etcetera, I think that was not done with prescience of what the B3 rules would actually look like. But I think &#x2013; obviously, they did prove to be reasonably close. I think &#x2013; and that was because essentially, we'd actually looked at every business line ahead of that announcement, we looked at the return on capital we had actually achieved at that point and over the previous &#x2013; over the cycle and we made a decision as to what the viability was.</p>
          <p>I think what you're seeing today is &#x2013; and that's a calculation that's been repeated over the last three years. What we're looking at today, I think, is a reflection that one, I think there's probably a little bit more clarity around some of the details of the implications. Also I think that the market environment is &#x2013; and the economic outlook is proving tougher than we probably thought it was when we looked at this before. So it's a tightening of that analysis, but it's an exact continuation of the analysis that we actually did in late 2008, early 2009, which actually led to the announcement we made at that time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on the question of the capital levels, again, I guess I would go back, I mean, first of all, I do think that the full capital stack is something that is important to look at and you know, we have, including our BCNs, our overall cap, and you start with an 18% Tier 1 ratio which is relevant to many of our constituencies, our senior debt holders, our depositors, our counterparties. You add that to our BCN which is another 3% or so, you've got &#x2013; I think it's from that point of view, probably one of the best capitalized banks in the world, with sort of 21% total capital which is relevant to you if you're a senior debt holder or you're a depositor, etcetera.</p>
          <p>I do still continue to believe that we have a solid glide path to being, I think, in a very good place on capital, on just a narrow CET1 basis. And so, I think we continue to believe that that's the right place to be. We're comfortable with where that falls out vis-&#xE0;-vis our regulator. And we're comfortable that, again, when you look at the overall capital situation, including that issue, we think we're in a very good position. So, if that's &#x2013; so, our point of view is that we're one of the best capitalized banks in the world taken from &#x2013; looking at it from all angles. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris, I'd point out &#x2013; I mean, obviously, the numbers also both exclude the existing Tier 2 buffer capital notes but also the fact that we also forward-swapped a further CHF6 billion back in February in terms of that as well. So, if you actually put those together, I think the numbers look quite solid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from the line of Florence Taj from MFS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have two questions, actually. One, in terms of how you disclose your sovereign exposure. Do you include in that just the cash bonds that you own and the associated hedges, or would you include as well the books of sovereign CDS you may have written as part of your trading business? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is, I was wondering if you could touch on the provision you took in Wealth Management in the U.S. and how that was calculated, and if you could comment also on the various lawsuits that we've seen over the past two quarters related to your U.S. mortgage securitization activities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Maybe we'll take them in reverse order. I can start with the first two.</p>
          <p>With regard to the litigation issues around U.S. mortgages, I mean, our belief is that we've been a very responsible player in the mortgage markets. We actually, I think, as many of you know, cut back significantly our origination in 2006 which was well ahead of any crisis precipitating, so we actually cut our securitization activities in '06 because we weren't as comfortable with the underwriting environment of a lot of the products, etcetera, and obviously continued to do that through 2007.</p>
          <p>So, our belief is we've actually had strong standards and I think done a good job for our clients and our investors in the activities that we've undertaken. Obviously, as you've said, there is a lot of litigation out there. We'll see how it runs its course. I think we obviously believe that we're adequately provisioned for that, and I believe that we'll actually fare pretty well because my belief is that we have done a responsible job of participating in that market.</p>
          <p>With regard to the provisions in the U.S., I'm not sure there's a lot more we can say about it, to be honest. It's, as I say, it's obviously an issue that we're going to be working towards resolution on. This was an accounting provision that we took in the quarter, and we'll have to see how to it develops from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the $900 million number you see on that chart, that does include the net CDS position. I think just in terms of the next follow-up question which tends to be, so, in terms of the CDS position you're actually showing, for example, in terms of the Italian net position, so who are the actual &#x2013; the writers of that hedging and the majority of the writers of that are actually not Eurozone banks in terms of that protection.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and your final question is taken from the line of Matt Spick from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. It's Matt Spick from Deutsche Bank, and I actually have quite a lot of detailed questions but I think I'll take most of them offline with IR. But two top down questions, if I could. Just coming back to the staff expenses in the Investment Bank and your deferred compensation expense I think fell this quarter from about CHF850 million to CHF500 million. So, your flat personnel costs in Q3 presumably includes an offsetting increase in the non-deferred part of the expense. So, I still don't really understand under what mechanism you're getting an accrual that gives you a flat cost base in the Investment Bank quarter-on-quarter. And if that's still too detailed to answer, can you give us a top down view of roughly what percentage of the personnel expenditure you think is fixed now with all of the deferred costs and the high salaries?</p>
          <p>The second question I had comes back to the business plan, not so much on the capital release but the shape of the business in the future and you're obviously sticking with your credit franchise but your credit franchise is very small relative to the peer group. Is it fair to say that you're not really retrenching to credit per se, which is a huge complex of products, but you're more retrenching to your traditional strengths in financial sponsor, LBO and high yield? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think on the second part of the question, I think as we said, we do believe in terms of the RWA usage in the credit business. We are focused on trimming back some of the investment grade positions there so, as you say, in terms of the RWA focus that is certainly where it is. And as you mentioned, we certainly have the leading franchise in terms of leveraged finance and so that &#x2013; I think that will continue to be a very core business line for us in the future. So, as you say, we still think that the credit business as a whole is a good business, it's one where we're well positioned and which will continue to be a core activity for us. In terms of the RWA reductions it's probably more in the investment grade side.</p>
          <p>David, do you want to take the first part of the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, just in terms of the deferred compensation point, you're referring to, I think, the group numbers for deferred compensation in terms of the change quarter-on-quarter. I think the point to note is there is an offsetting impact in the corporate center relating to deferred compensation which is actually driving that, relating to the restructuring, so I think that maybe confusing the analysis, but it's probably best if we take that offline, actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Other questions here in the &#x2013; so there are no more questions on the phone? Okay. So, other questions here on the room, anybody want to take a last shot at anything?</p>
          <p>Okay. Well, just to summarize very briefly, I mean, I appreciate people's time, obviously we think that the set of measures that we've taken here allows us to continue to be in a first-mover position in the industry. We think that's actually served us very well over the past three or four years and we have produced an ROE of 14.9% since the beginning of 2009 in our business. So, we think it's actually put us in a good place.</p>
          <p>We do think that these measures that we've taken will allow us to continue to drive a business that will produce best-in-class returns and continue to help us to drive and build our client franchise over time. And again, the objective here is really delivering consistent, industry leading returns to our shareholders and ensuring that we continue to be well positioned both for more difficult market conditions but also in case there is an improvement in conditions over time.</p>
          <p>So, thanks a lot everybody for your time, and I appreciate your attention. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>