<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1443429" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>885</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="SVP, Head-Treasury &amp; Investor Relations">Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Member of the Board of Management, Finance &amp; Controlling/Daimer Financial Services">Bodo Uebber</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Trinkaus &amp; Burkhardt KGaA (Broker)">Horst Schneider</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Stuart P. Pearson</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Commerzbank AG (Broker)">Daniel Schwarz</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Kristina L. Church</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA">Rabih Freiha</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (UK)">Stephen M. Reitman</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Broker)">Jochen Gehrke</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Landesbank Baden-W&#xFC;rttemberg (Broker)">Frank Biller</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Fraser E. Hill</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Arndt A. Ellinghorst</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Redburn Partners LLP">Charles A. Winston</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Philippe J. Houchois</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd. Germany">Christian Breitsprecher</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the global conference call of Daimler. At our customer's request, this conference will be recorded. The replay of the conference call will also be available as an on-demand audio webcast in the Investor Relations section of the Daimler website. The short introduction will be directly followed by a Q&amp;A session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> I would like to remind you that this teleconference is governed by the Safe Harbor wording that you find in our published results documents.</p>
          <p>Please note that our presentations contain forward-looking statements that reflect management's current views with respect to future events. These forward-looking statements can be identified by expressions such as assume, anticipate, believe, estimate, expect, intend, may, plan, project, and should. Such statements are subject to many risks and uncertainties, examples of which are set out in the Safe Harbor wording in our disclosure documents and are also described in our Risk Report in the Daimler Annual Report and in the most recent interim report.</p>
          <p>If the assumptions underlying any of these statements prove incorrect, then actual results may be materially different from those expressed or implied by such statements. Forward-looking statements speak only to the date on which they are made. May I now hand over to Dr. Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer, Head of Daimler Investor Relations and Treasury. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. This is Mike M&#xFC;hlbayer speaking. On behalf of Daimler, I would like to welcome you on both through telephone and the Internet to our Q3 conference call. In order to give you maximum time for your questions, our CFO, Bodo Uebber, will begin with a short introduction directly followed by Q&amp;A. Now, I would like to hand over to Bodo Uebber.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good afternoon. We published our third quarter figures this morning, which were below our original expectations and the result of weaker and more difficult markets. The risks which we had flagged have been materializing over the summer months. They then further accelerated, especially in September. Nevertheless, considering the difficult market environment, our current position in respect of relative product age and spending cycle, our earnings demonstrate that our past efforts and initiatives are paying off.</p>
          <p>Here are our key figures for the third quarter. Total unit sales continue to increase in our automotive divisions by 1% to around 530,000 vehicles. Our revenue came up to &#x20AC;28.6 billion, 8% more than last year. Adjusted for exchange-rate effects, revenue increased by 3%. The group's EBIT from ongoing business was &#x20AC;1.9 billion, slightly below the last &#x2013; level of last year. Profits in the third quarter were driven by higher sales at Mercedes-Benz Cars and foreign exchange on the positive side.</p>
          <p>We faced headwinds from higher expenses in connection with the extension of Mercedes-Benz Cars' product portfolio and the current product offensive at Daimler Trucks and charges from the discounting of non-current provisions at around &#x20AC;200 million in the third quarter and &#x20AC;450 million year-to-date. Free cash flow from industrial business was a negative &#x20AC;200 million in the third quarter. This was mainly a function of higher inventories due to seasonal patterns in connection with model changeovers. In addition, we continued our high investments in future products, technologies, and markets as planned.</p>
          <p>We do not expect support from the macroeconomic and market environment in general or from the European passenger car and truck market in particular. That is why we have already initiated production adjustments in order to avoid overstocking and net pricing erosion in the forefront of our upcoming product launches. We've also intensified our efforts to improve efficiency, production flexibility, and to increase sales dynamic at all of our four divisions. At Mercedes, we have launched a program called Fit for Leadership. I will come back to that later.</p>
          <p>Let's also have a look at our performance by division. Mercedes-Benz Cars, once again, increased unit sales in the third quarter with sales of more than 345,000 units. We were 2% above the number for the prior-year quarter. Our SUVs in particular showed high sales growth rates in the third quarter, but also the new compact class is very successful. We have already sold more than 100,000 new B-Class cars and since June, we have more than 70,000 orders for the new A-Class in our books.</p>
          <p>Our third quarter EBIT amounts to &#x20AC;1 billion. Again that is a good number considering the more difficult environment. EBIT includes charges from discounting of provisions of around &#x20AC;100 million and in connection with adjustments to our technology portfolio. Mercedes-Benz Cars return on sales for the third quarter was 6.4%. At Daimler Trucks, we increased our worldwide unit sales by 3% to over 119,000 vehicles. This was primarily due to strong demand in Asia, while demand in both Latin America and Europe was below our expectations.</p>
          <p>Daimler Trucks was able to increase market share in all core markets, which underlines the strength of our product portfolio. Daimler Trucks' EBIT of &#x20AC;507 million was 9% lower than in the third quarter of last year due to lower demand from Brazil, charges from discounting of provisions of around &#x20AC;40 million and burdens in connection with the current product offensives. The division's return on sales was 6.3%.</p>
          <p>Mercedes-Benz Vans' unit sales decreased compared with the prior-year quarter by 12% to 56,000 vehicles. The division suffered from the significant market decrease in Western Europe in the third quarter and intensifying competition. EBIT fell to &#x20AC;75 million and the return on sales to 3.6%.</p>
          <p>Daimler Buses sold 8,300 units in the third quarter, 10% less than in the prior-year. EBIT from ongoing business was minus &#x20AC;29 million mainly due to the difficult market environment in Latin America. The division also booked further charges of &#x20AC;16 million for the ongoing repositioning of our Bus business in Europe and North America.</p>
          <p>At Daimler Financial Services, new business increased 16% compared with the prior-year quarter by &#x2013; to &#x20AC;10 billion. Contract volume reached &#x20AC;77.5 billion at the end of September, which is 8% more than at the end of 2011. The divisional EBIT of &#x20AC;322 million was slightly below the prior-year level as a result of normalizing cost of risk.</p>
          <p>So much for the current developments in various divisions. Next, what does the more difficult macro environment mean for our full-year results? The economic climate at the beginning of the fourth quarter still features uncertainty. Thanks to the robust development year-to-date, we expect an increase in worldwide registrations of new cars in the magnitude of 4% to 5% for the full year, mainly driven by China and the U.S. market. We expect Mercedes-Benz Cars to post higher unit sales than in the prior-year period. We will benefit from the strong demand for our SUVs, the C-Class, and our new compact class.</p>
          <p>With regard to Daimler Trucks, we also anticipate higher unit sales. The North American market is likely to be the most important driver of sales, with an extension of approximately 10%. For the European truck market, we must expect a contraction of about 10% due to the clearly less positive economic outlook and the introduction of stricter emissions standards. The Brazilian truck market is now likely to contract by roughly 20% to 25%.</p>
          <p>Regarding Mercedes-Benz Vans, we anticipate unit sales in 2012 at slightly below the prior-year level. The launch of the new Citan in the small van segment will help to push sales in Europe.</p>
          <p>At Daimler Buses, we assume that unit sales in the year 2012 will be significantly lower than in 2011, which is also driven by a weak Latin American business. At Daimler Financial Services, we expect to achieve renewed growth in contract volume and new business in 2012.</p>
          <p>What does all this mean for our expected earnings at Daimler in the full-year 2012? For the development of EBIT in our divisions, we can give the following guidance based on the most recent market expectations.</p>
          <p>Mercedes-Benz Cars expect to earn an EBIT of around &#x20AC;4.4 billion. Operating performance in the last quarter will be mainly driven by weaker European market, support of our dealer network in China, higher unit sales driven by new compact cars. Daimler Trucks anticipates an EBIT of around &#x20AC;1.7 billion, mainly impacted during the last quarter by weaker than expected European and Brazilian markets, slowdown of demand in NAFTA, and expenses related to the start of business in India and China.</p>
          <p>Mercedes-Benz Vans expect an EBIT of roughly &#x20AC;650 million. The last quarter performance will be driven by weak Western European markets continuing to impact our business and higher unit sales thanks to the Citan launch. Daimler Buses anticipates an EBIT of around minus &#x20AC;80 million. The last quarter will be mainly impacted by lower unit sales due to weak Western European and Brazilian markets and further charges of around &#x20AC;40 million for business repositioning.</p>
          <p>Finally, Daimler Financial Services foresees an EBIT of around &#x20AC;1.3 billion due to the normalization of cost of risk. Overall, the Daimler Group expects to achieve an EBIT from ongoing business of around &#x20AC;8 billion in 2012.</p>
          <p>Let's take a quick look beyond 2012. We have outlined key strategies for each division. Mercedes-Benz 2020 for passenger cars; Daimler Trucks, number one for trucks; Mercedes-Benz Vans goes global for vans; GLOBE 2013 for Buses and Daimler Financial Services 2020 for financial services.</p>
          <p>It's now important to execute these strategies and that's exactly what we continue to do. At the same time, the overall difficult market situation will continue into 2013. That's why we complement our strategies with additional measures to further enhance efficiency, production flexibility, and to realize optimization potentials to safeguard our strategic targets.</p>
          <p>At Mercedes-Benz passenger cars, we launched the program, Fit for Leadership, which is a key element of our Mercedes-Benz 2020 strategy. It focuses on two levers. Short-term, it's primarily about cost reduction, we targeted &#x20AC;2 billion cost improvement by the end of 2014. We are going to achieve this by enforcing and accelerating both already established and new measures.</p>
          <p>One example is the net-zero approach, which we outlined to you at our capital market in Hungary. We have accelerated this initiative to achieve the goal at an earlier point in time. Two other measures are that we further intensify our efforts to improve productivity in terms of hours per vehicle and to reduce overhead costs.</p>
          <p>In addition to these short-term levers, we have also developed longer-term structure and measures to improve the Mercedes-Benz Cars business system to deliver a sustainable 10% return on sales performance. However, at each of our divisions achieving the mid-term targets in 2013 has become more challenging based on current market developments. We still target this over-the-cycle return on sales goals supported by the programs at the divisions, however, from a later starting point. Investments in new products, innovative technologies, and gross markets nevertheless continue as planned.</p>
          <p>In 2014, Mercedes-Benz Cars will then have a significantly younger model line-up than today. And on the trucks, the product offensive and regional launches will also be completed. Additionally, we will optimize our business model and better exploit our potential in China. Executing our strategies and efficiently utilizing our resources will enable us to better leverage the benefits of our ongoing product offensive as well as the growth potential of new markets in the coming years.</p>
          <p>And now, we will be happy to take your questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Bodo Uebber. Ladies and gentlemen, you may ask your questions now. I will identify the questioner by name, but please also introduce yourself with your name and the name of your organization before asking your question. To practical points, firstly please avoid using mobile phones and secondly please ask the question in English. Before we start, the operator will explain the procedure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question we take from Horst Schneider.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. Thanks for taking my questions. It's Horst from HSBC. I've got actually three questions, if I may. The first one relates to the statements you made this morning and in the press conference, so if I got it right, we should assume that you keep the margins in 2013 and the car division and truck division is stable? Or have I got something wrong in that what I've seen on Newswire?</p>
          <p>Then the second question I want to ask is relating to the one-offs, so with which &#x2013; how many one-off charges we should calculate with regard to Fit for Leadership? And what does it mean in the end in terms of reduction of employees?</p>
          <p>And then the last question that I have relates to trucks. I remember that you have said &#x2013; I think it was two years ago &#x2013; that if you're not meeting the targets in trucks, you would be prepared to spin-off the truck division, or just to dispose it. So, I would like to know, now given the fact that you are here below targets, do you see now any need to come back to that promise? So, for example, to spin-off the Asian business or to get rid of Freightliner? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the questions, Mr. Schneider. With regard to the margin statement this morning, I said that we had the operating performance and run rate of the second half in 2012, I referred to in Mercedes-Benz Cars, is around 7%. That is due to the fact that we have this compounding effect of the &#x2013; on the interest rates on the long-term provisioning, there we come up with the 7%. In trucks, it's around 5% to 6% and that's just what I said this morning. And please understand that at the current point of time, we do not give any specific guidance for 2013, but please, please keep in mind that our markets in Western Europe, and especially in Brazil, will remain difficult and we will only get meaningful benefits of our programs and product cadence in the second half of 2013. That is what I said this morning, so it was not a guidance of 2013, but a statement about the performance in 2012 and somewhat about the markets and products in 2013.</p>
          <p>One-offs of the program, I only can tell you right now that, of course, we are working on the program and if we would have something to announce currently, of course we would tell you, so I can't tell you any one-offs currently, if it were needed. So, we are going there for further efficiencies. With regard to the personal staff, I made the comment this morning that we are &#x2013; I do think we are in a good position using attrition for example, using part-time retirement, using voluntary leaves for example, and also the growth which we do expect due to our product extension and market developments to use &#x2013; to come in with efficiency measures. Please keep in mind that we have also sales targets in 2015 of 1.5 million cars &#x2013; 2014, 1.5 million cars, and we will use this growth, so to say, to make the efficiency happening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sorry, just for observation, if I get it right then you &#x2013; I mean whatever the charges will be in the end, but you will likely &#x2013; I mean if there are any charges you book them in Q4 and you have to cash out then probably next year, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But don't expect us to report anything on special charges in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are &#x2013; and of course, it's the same which holds true for trucks, it's the same kind of message. We will review in trucks the Brazilian operations with regard to the market because the market is pretty much down. There we need to review our fixed costs, our fixed costs position in Brazil, but that is a different topic but is &#x2013; there we have to see what the outcome of this discussion will do.</p>
          <p>Your third question was with regard to the long-term targets of trucks and whether we can make them and what actions we would like to take. I'm pretty optimistic that we finally will make the target in trucks. What we're currently doing is that we react on markets, changes in the market. And you have to keep in mind that Europe is again 10% to 15% away from the average market we have seen in the last 15 years. It is a topic which we have adjusted, for example, in this load on the NAFTA what we have seen at the Brazilian market currently, so there's no reason to believe that we will not make the 8% margin target finally. It depends, of course, a lot of the market development on the one hand and secondly, we would like to safeguard our underlying profitability with our Daimler Trucks number one program. So there's no reason to discuss any structural topics within Daimler.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. But I mean in general from today's perspective, it's fair to assume that you don't make the 8% in 2013 at Daimler Trucks, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's mainly due to Europe and not that much due to North America and Asia? Did I get that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are right. It's more an indication of Europe and the Brazilian market. Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then next question, we take from Stuart Pearson.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morgan Stanley. I had two or three questions as well. I mean starting on the cash flow, I think we started the year targeting the best part of &#x20AC;2.5 billion or at least to cover the dividends, and clearly that's not gone to plan. I wonder if you could just update us on what you're expecting for the year and whether you think there is any real structural issues in terms of cash generation at Daimler that will be addressed as part of this efficiency program?</p>
          <p>And following on from that, given the cash generation this year, it's unlikely to cover the dividends and given the, I guess, the high payout ratio that would be involved in maintaining the dividends flat at 2.2, I mean is that a realistic expectation, just noting your comments from the press conference earlier about a stable dividend. Does that mean flat? Or could we see some reduction there?</p>
          <p>And then finally just on China, the third, comment just noting your comments in the press release regarding supporting the China dealer network, I wonder if you could give us an idea of &#x2013; some idea of how much that support would cost you in the fourth quarter? And how that support will be delivered to the dealer? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Stuart, thank you for your questions. First of all, our cash flow target, of course, had to be adjusted, no doubt. I told you during the last nine months that we are aiming for a substantial high cash flow. From today's perspective, the total year cash flow will be slightly positive. Including this slightly positive cash flow, we have M&amp;A activities and contribution to pension plans was roughly of &#x20AC;1 billion, which mean excluding this &#x20AC;1 billion, it should be in the operating cash flow of &#x20AC;1 billion roughly, which misses somewhat the dividend, but should not be a reason to change the dividend policy. So therefore, of course, we were shooting for a high cash flow contribution in the fourth quarter to make this slightly positive cash flow happening.</p>
          <p>Having said this with regard to the dividend, second aspect is the net profit development, which is year-to-date, including the expectation for the fourth quarter, in the vicinity which makes a dividend on the last year's level possible, and therefore I'm shooting further in that direction, not reducing it, but keeping it in minimum stable. Of course I'm also not too optimistic obviously to say that to increase it in that environment, but a stable dividend should be, in this regard, possible and should be supported by the net profit development.</p>
          <p>You had a third question? Do we also, in the programs, target the working capital and cash flow topics? I can clearly only say, yes, because beside any inventory development of finished cars, maybe I'm not so bad. In this year, we are pretty good, flexible on that, and you see us acting on production capacities to make this final inventories happening. But we will also shoot for looking into other parts of working capital, as it is for the suppliers. You know that receivables and other topics where you have inventory, so to say, in the production plants for example, and I do see some potential to unlock also in the cash flow area there. So we are targeting both in trucks and in cars, the working capital topic. With regard to your China question, of course I've outlined what it is <mark type="ph" /> in red (23:21). Does it come from &#x2013; it is a very low &#x2013; it's a very high double-digit number, pretty close to a three-digit, if I might say so, without saying too much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And what kind of support will that involve? Is that a pricing support to the dealers? Is that investing in rollouts or...?.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think &#x2013; I told this already this morning, we will invest this but of course it is a support for the dealer network, no doubt. But we will combine this support with a new margin system. For example, we will invest into training, coaching, so to say quality of the dealer network, and also the corporate identity of the dealer system, so to say. Also, IT systems we have in mind. So it's a total support. Of course the dealer will earn somewhat more money with that. But it is on the other hand also invested into the quality of the dealer network. And that will hurt our fourth quarter number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next in line we have Daniel Schwarz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have one additional question on the dealer network in China. The rollout of new dealers, what's the number you get in 2012? And what is your planning for 2013? Have you slowed that due to your difficulties in the dealer network? And then with regard to inventories of trucks, with the production cuts you are planning and with your market assumptions, you will get to a level you feel comfortable with at year-end. So from today's perspective, you're not planning for even more production cuts in the first half 2013? That would be my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To your questions with regard to the dealerships, we are currently having 220 dealer outlets. We have been for 50 &#x2013; expansion of 50 for this year. So then coming up a couple of others more, we had a strategic target or a long-term target of 50 for the years to come. That is a number we might increase further up with the current position.</p>
          <p>You have a question with regard, whether we further do production cuts. One is on trucks, you mentioned that. Production cuts in the fourth quarter in NAFTA and in Europe. Of course we will take out some days of production. I do think that's good news that we are adjusting our capacities to the demands. We are flexible in that topic. And also for the cash flow management it is the right measure.</p>
          <p>Within cars, of course, we are &#x2013; you have seen our A-Class third shift in Rastatt increase. Or you see us reacting partially on the compact car side, ramping it up on the one hand, having a good order intake. And in this regard &#x2013; and of course, we will adjust as you have seen also in other discussions we had, product life-cycle-related topics in other plans, that's it. So we are doing here, not because of business, so to say, but adjusting as quick as we can to different life-cycle topics and market topics.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I would have one quick follow-up question. You confirmed the truck targets in September, what was the incremental iteration? Was it across all markets? Or is that more the European market..?.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, what happened between &#x2013; within September is pretty much a slowdown in Western Europe, pretty drastically, so hesitating of ordering, so a lot of talks with customers, but no orders. Brazil did not realize &#x2013; did not materialize an increase in recovery. There are a lot of talks about the new FINAME program, which reduces the interest rate from 5% to 6% to 2.5% for customers, but that will not materialize, we don't think so in the fourth quarter, or slowly, slowly and will materialize maybe next year. So that's an uncertain situation we had and that was not foreseen. And after, of course, order intakes came also down.</p>
          <p>We reacted there in production capacity, and the order intakes we are getting right now are big fleets, but these big fleets are order intakes and discussions we have. They are pretty promising, but they are not for the fourth quarter and might not be really coming in the fourth quarter, but they are for 2013. So that was somewhat the change we had over the couple of weeks and finally, of course, the year is two months from now, and therefore the impact on the first quarter cannot be big anymore, and therefore we had to reduce also the profit expectations for the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next in line is Kristina Church.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yes. It's Kristina Church from Barclays. Thank you for taking my questions. I mean, I think firstly my question is, given your track record in terms of volumes and market share gains when compared with your premium payers, what would you say to investors in terms when you're talking about increasing spending on products and on technologies, that they will see a return in the future for that, given that your track record has not been so great on returns? And then another question on pricing, it looks from your EBIT walk-down that you give on Page 34 of your presentation, that pricing across-the-board was positive in the quarter, as presuming that mix with the A-Class was slightly negative, could you give a little bit more of an update then on sort of what the negative factors were? And what is in this &#x2013; the other cost changes lying in the EBIT walk-down? And, that &#x2013; those are my two questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, of course, well, when you see what we are investing currently in the product &#x2013; in the new products, I do say I am pretty promising. When we see the B-Class currently, for example, pretty successful in the last 10 to 12 months in order intakes. And production dropped to 100,000 units. A-Class, as I said before, we have very good feedback on the first launch. So the investment into compact car, from my point of view, seeing also the CLA which we had on the auto shows is very good and looks promising also for the returns we get from these cars. We will let also a small SUV in this segment, you know that. And of course we have started now with that strategy and the pay off, I don't think we will see. Other investments we do &#x2013; and what I'm pretty optimistic is the kind of investment we took in the E-Class now for next year. It's a new car, face-lift new car, looks pretty promising. So I think we can make a good return on this one, having in mind then the S-Class and C-Class but now I'm talking about 2014 and so on. So I do think it's a good investment.</p>
          <p>Let me do a side remark to trucks. Here we have a market share gains currently all over the globe. We see a strong upturn in the market with market share gains, old and new together, so to say. We see also in pretty good developing. In Freightliner, with market shares, we are number one in both segments, 6 to 7 and also in Class 8. We have market share gains in Brazil on a depressed market, of course. And in Fuso over a couple of months we could regain momentum. So therefore from what we are investing in new products, I'm pretty confident to get all the things back. The take-rate of the <mark type="ph" /> H-type (31:29) engine in NAFTA is also very good. So therefore also that investment I do think pays finally off.</p>
          <p>With regard to pricing, your question, we had a quarter which were positive in task compared to the third quarter last year. We had other quarters, of course, when you remember the first quarter. So thereof, we changed, of course, also our &#x2013; you know that in China we balanced more volume and pricing better, which also gets us in pricing a benefit. But also we can see that our new products like our new SUV, new M-Class, new B-Class, for that the pricing is positive. And for the others, of course, we are very competitive. And therefore &#x2013; but if you put both things together, pricing is positive.</p>
          <p>Other cost changes we had in the work. Let me start with trucks. In trucks we have the impact of the new Actros, which we announced in the early beginning of the year. There's no change to that number. We addressed &#x20AC;300 million incremental cost burden, so to say, in the Actros area, as you can clearly see in our cost work. And the same is true against our plans for Mercedes-Benz Cars. We said, we invest a lot in material cost. There are two parts, one is the CO2-related costs, which are hitting, so to say, our material costs. On the other hand, we put also a lot of money into the attractiveness of the cars.</p>
          <p>Secondly, our R&amp;D costs are up. You see that in our disclosure. The third element is the interest-rate effect on the long-term provisioning, which we disclosed with roughly &#x20AC;100 million in cars, and of course we had some investment in technologies, which are burdened in the third quarter. These are, more or less, the main areas of the cost on cars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could ask a follow-up question then, how do you think that management expertise, within the company, is viewed by the market right now considering how far behind peers you are lagging? And could you confirm whether Herr Zetsche's contract has been extended for the next three years? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Expertise within the company's market. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:58). I can't get the question right. So, of course, if you mean now the management contracts of the management team, of course, nothing, I can't answer it right now. It's subject to our supervisory board's member to make these kind of decisions, if you refer to that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we take the next question from Rabih Freiha from Exane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Thank you for taking my question, Rabih Freiha from Exane. My first one would be on your cost cutting program, when looking at the &#x20AC;3.1 billion, can you tell us maybe how ambitious this target is? I mean, should we view this number as maybe a best-case scenario? Or is there any room for potential to make further cuts?</p>
          <p>And my second question would be on your divisional margin targets for 2013, obviously you've scrapped the previous ones. I guess now you have an idea about where we could end up next year. If I look at 2013 consensus today, it's expecting around 8.1% group margin next year. Given your assumptions for 2013, can you tell us what your view is on this number? Is it close to what you're forecasting? Or it seems too high?</p>
          <p>And maybe last one on dividends, you have communicated this morning that you're committed to supporting a stable dividend for this year, should the net income deteriorate next year, should we assume also some sort of support in that sense? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course a lot of questions you had to the year 2013, and then it currently is not a discussion about the &#x2013; it's not February yet, but I'm happy to answer this question in February, so to say. I made a remark to the margins of the second half of 2012. I repeat them now once again. So we have a 7% run rate in cars and a 5% to 6% run rate in trucks, which I also said in the morning. But these are the same that we cannot make currently specific guidance for 2013. But please keep in mind that our markets, Western Europe and Brazil will remain difficult. And we will only get meaningful benefits of our programs and products into the second half of 2013. And, the Western European markets and Brazil will start weak in the first quarter &#x2013; first and second quarter. Please keep that in mind.</p>
          <p>The dividend, of course, I also said this. So I do think that the dividend can be stable based on our net profit development for 2012. That is not a message for 2013 but for 2012. And, I also commented on the cash flow, that it should be slightly positive including &#x20AC;1 billion of special items, like pension and M&amp;A. And that should give the management enough reason to keep the dividend stable.</p>
          <p>You had the question whether it's ambitious program. So of course, programs are always ambitious. The Truck program of &#x20AC;1.6 billion, the Car program of &#x20AC;2 billion and cost cutting of course, is an ambitious target and should, of course, safeguard on the one hand our profitability but also enhance and give us possibility to achieve finally our 10% target in cars. And what we said when we tried to do to accelerate things, which we saw for a later part of time, to get them already in 2013 and 2014. So we try to get the things from 15 to 16 back to this year's, and to extra miles that we somewhat can offset the market situation and our product portfolio. That's the name of the game for the next two years. And we have also said that we hope for a long-term structural measures, but it is later on in the vertical integration, for example, and other topics where we need to be finally also competitive.</p>
          <p>In trucks, it's more &#x2013; it's all the same. From a concept point-of-view, we disclosed that in June already in different tasks. 30% of that is revenue-based and 70% cost-based, which is good. The higher portion is on the cost side. Of course, some of the topics in the revenue side depends on market developments. That was one reason why we also said in 2013 it's not possible to get to the 8%. But I'm pretty optimistic that we with the markets up are getting back based on our programs that we will make the 8% at a later part of stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So next question we take from Stephen Reitman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Stephen Reitman from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale in London. Question about 2013 or some allusions you were making. You were mentioning that the revamped E-Class will be an important factor in 2013. And then you also mentioned the S-Class, but then you suggested that may be more of a 2014 impact. Does that concern that the launch of the S-Class has been delayed from what was generally thought to be a May launch to something later in the year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Stephen. So, of course, the E-Class is an important factor, of course. It's a lot of volume also for Mercedes-Benz Cars. That will roll in more in the second half of 2013. The S-Class I have not commented. So it's a safe field but I'll not discuss the S-Class. We will launch the S-Class in the summer. We have also confirmed that I do think a couple of days before. But of course, you know, that the ramp-up, so to say, then of course, will have not an immediate effect. So that will roll in, so to say, into the third quarter and will speed up, so to say, over the months in the third quarter. Therefore, of course, I can't &#x2013; it's, so to say, it was pre-sized when this date will happen, so there's no delay in the S-Class. As I said it will come into the market in summer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you can confirm that you're not expecting any extraordinary launch costs in 2013 as we had in the, sort of 2011, 2012 period relating to the front-wheel-drive architecture?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not on a normal basis, of course. It's nothing, of course, which we are now highlighting. Of course, there will be some burdens, no doubt. But not very extraordinary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So next in line is Jochen Gehrke.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Just two questions, please. First of all on your Chinese business, I understand that you're trying to address this market in a completely different way. Can you just talk us through whether you're willing to make a, you kind of like to restart to that business? And whether or not there will be any personnel changes given the underperformance that we've seen there in this market? And then secondly, more broader on Mercedes, I remember that it was about a year ago that you engaged in a very aggressive growth plan. Ever since, we've seen record sales in any quarter, but equally, negative operational gearing in pretty much any quarter as well. Now, I'm fully aware of your product cadence. But nevertheless, do you not feel that the risk is very high, that Mercedes is engaging itself in a too-growth focused strategy that leaves apart the credentials of the brand and the pricing power that should actually be around this brand, especially in light of S-Class discounting back in February, A-Class starting with pricing support right from the beginning? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your questions. With regard to China, of course, we have &#x2013; a lot of elements would be &#x2013; but we are currently discussing and implementing in China. One is, of course, the sales organization topic. We have two sales organizations, as you know, and we have currently achieved a common opinion with our partners to get to one organization, also with a legal entity shell, so to say, a management company. So I expect in 2013, that we can start, so to say, to bring this organization, also legally, together. So everything of that is &#x2013; was done. We need some, of course, some approvals, no doubt, but we have achieved there kind of a milestone.</p>
          <p>Having said this, of course you have seen also a management change as one that we have a new sales &#x2013; head of sales in China as of October. I do think he will start his position, a very experienced guy, having done a lot of markets within Mercedes, so there's also a management change in that. We will also set-up, as we here also clearly said, also a new regional center. We opened up &#x2013; we have opened up a leasing company, which is also decisive for supporting the business because it gets maturer and maturer, and of course we also mention in the sales company, that we have increased our share in our imports company, from 50% to 75%, which is good news, of course, that we are controlling it more and further. And to bring this into a next stage of optimization.</p>
          <p>Midterm-wise, we go further for profit maximization and expansion of the network. We will ensure that China's specific product and market requirements go into China through further extension of local R&amp;D capacity and competence. And of course, we are working on the production capacity, as you know. And finally, we will also, organizational-wise, talk about more responsibility within China for the Chinese business. That is something which we will discuss during the year 2013 to make it even an organization which can really be the responsible for that &#x2013; for all the parts in China.</p>
          <p>So I'm pretty optimistic that we have good changes, but of course it will need some time to finally implement that. So on the &#x2013; so the question &#x2013; you asked the question with &#x2013; compared to growth and cost to balance growth and costs finally, I can only tell you, I do think the answer is kind of, yes, we have to balance this. And one answer to that and one reason for that is our Fit for Leadership program, to come on with a very disciplined way on the cost side, to even go for more cost improvements and lowering this kind of down to make this growth really on the very efficient structure happening. So what should not be the case as we leave the structure as it is, so to say, and we have to keep the cost control on the one hand and having a good structure for this growth. That is the goal also of Fit for Leadership. Therefore your answer on the one hand is yes, and the answer is Fit for Leadership program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the next question we take from Frank Biller.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Good afternoon. There's a question on revenues per car. By looking at the revenues to car in this third quarter, I calculate about a &#x20AC;44,000. So, this is significantly up versus last year's figure, about 7%. And also versus last quarter, second quarter, it is more than 6%. Maybe you can give us the reason for this sharp increase and what you are expecting for the quarters to come?</p>
          <p>And the other question is in buses, I recognized here after a loss in the first nine months, your calculating was only a minus of &#x20AC;80 million. That should include this &#x20AC;40 million restructuring charges. So &#x20AC;165 million for the fourth quarter. What makes you so optimistic in the operating performance of buses in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Frank, thank you for your questions. The difference in revenue per unit are more or less two topics. One is foreign exchange and the second is, so to say, we call that secondary business. So we have an after-sales business, for example. And other components business, of course, which makes this happening. So therefore it's not a structure and mix topics are less of the difference, so to say. So the main aspect this year, foreign exchange. And the underlying Maintenance and Spare Parts business, for example, and Used Car business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So should we expect such a magnitude also for the fourth quarter <mark type="indiscernible" /> (0:47:08)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it should go down. It should go down because we have, of course, a lot higher unit sales on the &#x2013; it should go down. As we note to what precise number, but somewhat kind of substantially it should go down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Seasonal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. For Bus, of course, this is seasonal business. Fourth quarter is always, more or less, the best quarter in Europe. That's not to say it's in Brazil, it's not. It's in Europe. Therefore, of course, we expect this end of seasonal, normal pattern in the fourth quarter. Yeah. That's more or less the reason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So mainly the same margin then in, like last year's fourth quarter? Is that true?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't &#x2013; kind of so, of course, we gave you the numbers, the preset EBIT numbers, so please stay with that. I don't want to make lower margin target here, but you have the preset Q4 number and you can expect us to deliver this number in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next in line is Fraser Hill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, Fraser Hill from Bank of America. Broadly three questions, firstly on the restructuring. You've mapped out this &#x20AC;2 billion program in the Cars business and really it seems like there's four bullet points around this: materials cost, production cost, fixed cost, and R&amp;D and CapEx. Can you give us a little more granularity as to how those cost savings break down between those categories? And when you will be harvesting the benefits from each of those areas, just to give us a bit more confidence as to your approach on all of those factors?</p>
          <p>Following on from that, in terms of the R&amp;D reduction, how does that tally with your comments about CO2-related legislation cost and obviously what we're hearing from your peers in terms of having to increase R&amp;D to meet CO2 hurdles? How are you squaring the circle there?</p>
          <p>And then moving on to the margins &#x2013; sorry to labor this point &#x2013; but you talked about the second half margin run rate for 2012 being applicable for 2013, did I hear that correctly? Is that the right message there? Or, are you just talking about the second half run rate for 2012 being equivalent for the first half in 2013?</p>
          <p>And then finally on the &#x20AC;8 billion for this year, is that an absolute floor? You've talked about a magnitude of &#x20AC;8 billion? Or do we look at &#x20AC;8 billion as a floor? What kind of assumptions have you taken for the rest of the year? Have you assumed some sort of flexibility there in terms of worsening of conditions? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Fraser, you had a question to the &#x20AC;2 billion program? The main topics, you were rightly saying, the different baskets. The main area here of the &#x20AC;2 billion is the material cost topic. It is between one-third and 50% of that number. Don't want to disclose no more of these packages. Of course we'll get further information when we roll down through the year and give you some information where we then, at this point of times, are.</p>
          <p>You had a question to &#x2013; with regard to the R&amp;D reduction. I do think it's less here in terms of capacity reduction for R&amp;D. That is not the topic in R&amp;D. Here there's more in the program, the cooperation within the company between R&amp;D production, how do we steer our business, so to say, in the company? The pure capacities we need, of course you can imagine, we need a lot because there's a lot of work with regard to CO2, so we are further focusing on that topic in the long run. So we need to deliver CO2 targets in Europe, in the U.S., in China, and everywhere in the world. That is a competitive necessity, so to say, to sell cars.</p>
          <p>The margin, again, I have not given any 2013 guidance. I've made a comment to our run rate in 2012. And I gave the comment to the markets, which I do expect especially in Western Europe and Brazil to be very weak in the first two quarters 2013 just to give you that advice to keep that in mind. Secondly, that when you look at 2013, we have our product renewals more in the latter half of 2013, so second half. And therefore of course, the benefits are more in the second half than in the third half, also based on our program. This is what I said. So no guidance. Guidance you will get in February 2013.</p>
          <p>The &#x20AC;8 billion, of course, is the floor. Take it as we said. It's around &#x20AC;8 billion. That I do think is a pretty precise guidance for the ongoing EBIT. And the assumptions for that are clearly the market assumptions which we have given to you. Unfortunately, I have also to say that the market assumptions but that is based on the market as it develops. In cars and in trucks, when we look to the first and second quarter, we earn most of all of that bandwidth which we have given you on the worst side, so to say. And that of course, reflects also the &#x20AC;8 billion here, the &#x20AC;8 billion target. And we have given clear guidance about the markets also. When you look at our disclosure, please read it again. For the first quarter we made also a special market assessment. And you see in Europe and NAFTA, of course, you can imagine that the fourth quarter is kind of the worst quarter in the whole year, so to say. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So next in line we have Arndt Ellinghorst.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, thank you and good afternoon. Arndt Ellinghorst from Credit Suisse. Two questions. The first one is on your 50,000 employees in the sales organization, in Hungary you mentioned that you're looking into your labor intensity and the vertical integration of the sales organization in Daimler-Mercedes, specifically. Given that you now stated not to cut any head count in the restructuring process, does this imply that you've finished your analysis and that you're happy with your structures? Especially in the sales organization?</p>
          <p>And then, secondly, the question we've asked many times &#x2013; and I have to stress this because it's really coming up in every debate with investors in the market and also your peers. The question is really what is embedded in Daimler's DNA that the company keeps running behind reality? We've seen that now for many, many years, that, that your targets are too ambitious. Like this year again. Another example, your truck orders, we've been mentioning many times this year that the U.S. is slipping. Suddenly you're waking up in the third quarter that the U.S. is slipping. In China, you've been initiating a price war in the first half of the year. Now you've got to restructure your dealer network. The question really is, is there anything special in Daimler that you think you can't change moving forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Arndt, thank you for your question. So the answer to your first questions &#x2013; question with regard to sales organization, but the same answer for also other areas, is a clear, no. So we have not finished our analysis in this regard, but that was also true for other vertical integration topics. So answer is, no. The second bigger question, of course, you had &#x2013; I do think you see us currently acting with regard to market changes. I do think when we go back, as I said before, first quarter, second quarter, I cannot agree with your assessment of the markets. I do think there were pretty positive signs, also in the U.S.</p>
          <p>We had market shares up, of course, overall in the truck business and the assessment was clear. It had deteriorated over time and it heavily deteriorated now, in September, so therefore we reacted. I do think very fast, I do think also better maybe than in the past. That is my conclusion also to our overt operations to adjust our productions with regard to their changes. Of course in that situation, management takes action with a program, which I like, of course, that we go this path, which also means that we have to deliver &#x20AC;1.6 billion, that we have clearly to follow-up with you transparently where we are in this point, which keeps us also running, which is also good news, so to say. We do that voluntarily.</p>
          <p>On the car side, there is certainly beside any market developments, which also over time, over the last six to seven months, deteriorated in Western Europe. In September, we had 21%. In Italy, we had 8% to the market down in Germany, so that reflects somewhat the dynamics. But on top of that, of course I have to say that we have a challenge in China and that is something of course we cannot push to the market, no doubt. This is something we have to change, so to say. First of all though we have to see it. We have seen it and went something wrong and that is something we have to reorganize on the one hand, and to make it a very good and clean and dedicated operations. We have made management changes on the one hand, we have given some directions, we are not through with everything what we would like to do with regard to China. We have a lot of ideas, which I commented, and that is something, of course, I have to admit that it's something we have to work on, and that is something which is our responsibility.</p>
          <p>Seeing us acting also here in cars, pretty active in Fit for Leadership, is the right answer to that situation right now. And for the market side get tools as to shorter measures to secure our business, so to say, from a profitability side and get us to a discussion about long-term structural topics, which I do think aren't, if I may quote you, in some regards you also discussed some of that topics. So, these kind of discussions will happen within the company. And I'm happy that we can go this fast. So overall, not all of that is management but also markets. But on the other hand, it's also not only markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for that clear statement. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, next in line is Charles Winston.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. Charles Winston from Redburn. Three quick questions for me, thank you. Firstly, many of your competitors tend to add content-cost inflation to their pricing impact in net profit bridges. So, I was just wondering if you could give us the net impact of price and the increase content-cost on the profit in the quarter. Secondly, did I hear you right? That there was 50 new dealers in China planned for the year? Because there's only 4% to 5% sales growth. That implies quite a sharp decline in the same-store sales in existing dealers. So, I just wanted to confirm that point. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, to your second question you had &#x2013; not every new dealer is an effective, so to say, in the first year. You have to calculate that you need &#x2013; some point after, you need some time to get the dealer into a 100% efficient way. Therefore, you can't make this kind of reference to the current sales expectation. Of course next year is another year that might be not only 3% up, but maybe higher in China.</p>
          <p>The other topic, of course, we are not differentiating to the outside this kind of question you had. So we are, of course, commenting net pricing no doubts, but we don't disclose any further contents and pricing elements. Sorry to say so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just follow-up on the China point? Would it be fair to say that a reasonable number of your dealers are looking at negative same-store sales this year? Just I mean, given that distribution? Or is that incorrect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's very difficult to understand you, sorry to say so, and even other people. Of course, we &#x2013; there are negative sales and of course, that shows also the kind of dealer profitability, so to say. And that is also one topic why we decided, of course, to make the support in the fourth quarter for the dealers to make it of course an efficient network. And I commented on that, where we are investing this money.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next in line is Philippe Houchois.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thank you. The question is on cash flow. It's been the weakening for Daimler for some time. I have two specific questions. The first one, looking at your CapEx, PP&amp;E CapEx for the next few years, it looks like &#x2013; can you communicate when is the peak of CapEx for the group? It looks like the peak would be around the $5 billion, $5.1 billion or $5.2 billion, which would be below 5% of industrial revenue versus your peers guiding between 5.5% and 6%. So, if you can indicate whether my numbers are broadly right and when the peak of that CapEx spend would be?</p>
          <p>And the other side of cash flow is the working capital, which is &#x2013; you seem to be slow in improving. Inventory, in particular, I look at the past five, six years, you've always run inventory at least 80 days of COGS, compared that between 10 and 20 days more than Volkswagen and BMW. And I'm just curious about, one is, what you're doing about this in terms of action plan? It's nice to talk about cost, but that's a big part of your cost base, which impact your cash flow. And also in which part of the organization is particularly inventory heavy? Is it the truck side or is it the car side that is the culprit there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Philippe, your question first to the CapEx peak, let's talk about cars and trucks. I do think mainly within trucks, it goes on in 2014, the CapEx highest this year and next year, it goes slightly down and 2014, more. And for cars, it's after 2014, it will go down. Then we are then, so to say, through with many of our products and launches, so in cars after 2014 and trucks beginning next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, on the cash flow side; of course, we are looking also there in further improvements. Of the inventory side currently, we are planning for the fourth quarter strong decrease in all of our divisions, that is true in trucks and in cars, and so on. We prepared now in the third quarter for the peak in the fourth quarter. Within cars, it was also mainly driven by the new A-Class. The inventory increased and of course, in trucks we would adjust, as we said, our production capacity as we make our targets end of the year, which should unlock cash flow, which I need, so to say, to make my statement come true that we have a positive cash flow over the whole year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Talking more about year-over-year, I mean, obviously when you had Chrysler in your consolidation, it was lower because they carry no inventory. But, ever since you got rid of Chrysler, you've been carrying a very, very high level of inventory compared to your peers. There must be a part of your organization that is particularly inventory heavy? Or am I missing something? Is it just sufficient management across-the-board? Or is there something specific about the way you work in trucks in terms of vertical integration? Although, I would think Volkswagen has a higher vertical integration than you do, so I can't quite square those numbers. It would be helpful if you could shed some light there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Of course, you are right, there's one big part, which we have also told you before. So in Germany, for example, we have a very high share of own retail. Of course that, when you look at our balance sheet and asset side, of course it makes us heavier than other companies. Of course we &#x2013; and we said, under a Fit for Leadership, we will also look into that topic. We look at every topic, so I don't want to hide that one specific into our vertical integration processes, components, but also own retail to ascertain whether that is efficient &#x2013; efficiently positioned. And if not, we have to make it efficient.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, because we should have a positive impact on that higher share of assets and that is the name of the game, and we will certainly look at that profitability and competitiveness. Within the overall inventory, of course the main share is cars, no doubt. It's the 60% of the overall inventory, so, to say, and the next one is trucks with 30%, and of course vans and buses are lower, and that's why &#x2013; because they are using a lot of the components from trucks and cars. So, the main lever here is on the car side of course and the truck side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we have two persons left. The first is <mark type="ph" /> Austin Earl (01:04:36).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, hi, good afternoon. It's <mark type="ph" /> Austin Earl from Marshall Wace (01:04:42). I have two questions. The first is, I just want to understand a little bit on the dividend policy. I've understood your message on 2012, but it's more in 2013, I mean, is the dividend based on headline EPS as a payout ratio or maybe a normalized EPS or is it based on free cash flow? And is there a strict policy? Or you maybe use some of the cash you have on the balance sheet, if there was enough free cash flow to pay the dividend? That's the first question. And the second question was just on the reductions to production you alluded to for the fourth quarter of this year. I didn't quite hear if you did mention it. What sort of quantity that might involve both the bus and truck? And actually, if I could just ask a third question, which was just on the truck in Brazil, your &#x2013; and the Scandinavian and German peers have actually talked about intensive signs of a recovery in Brazil, and I just wondered if you're seeing that as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question. Of course the dividend policy, I commented a lot of times in this conference call. We think that we can keep the dividend stable based on the net profit development year-to-date and expected fourth quarter. Cash flow...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry to interrupt. Sorry. It is not 2012. I've understood that, it's 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's the payout in 2013. And of course please, I can't give you guidance now for 2013 dividend payout and 2014. So, what I mean is the payout in April which is decided in February based on the performance of 2012. And that's, our policy there is 50% payout &#x2013; 40% payout ratio, sorry. And I do think that means that more or less we can keep the dividend stable compared to last year 2011. But don't ask me now 2013. It's not the time to give guidance for 2013.</p>
          <p>The production topics I have already told you something. And in trucks, with regard to Brazil, we have a different opinion within the truck side, so we see a very slow recovery in the Brazilian truck market based on the FINAME program. In buses, it'd be different wherever we see an accelerating of intakes and discussions with customers. So, we see good tenders there. Also, we have a school bus tender we won for 2013 and one for an operator, which makes us a little bit more optimistic for bus in Brazil. So currently trucks is a little bit where the visibility is not yet there and a very slow, slow, slow start of the FINAME program in Brazil, which makes us also kind of a bit nervous what happens now in 2013 with the market. So, I do think there's a bandwidth which goes to negative within to slightly positive. We will see where this market is going.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And last but not least, we have Christian Breitsprecher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon. I'm Christian Breitsprecher from Macquarie. I have two questions left. One on China, you said you increased your stake in the wholesaler from 50% to 75%. Can you tell us what the cash-out was for that increase? Or at least when the cash flow &#x2013; cash-out flow happened for that?</p>
          <p>And secondly, I mean on the vans business, pretty much like the buses business, you seem to imply a hefty improvement in EBIT in the fourth quarter in absolute terms and in margin. So, can you explain a little bit where that's supposed to come from? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christian, your two questions. In the vans side, it's seasonality. So, we always have a very strong fourth-quarter sales and that should then grow in this EBIT, which we have forecasted and given as a guidance. The second question you had, with regard to China and the restructuring of our wholesale company, import company, its cash neutral, so to say. Because we are using equity in China and moving it to this consolidated entity, so therefore, its cash neutral. Thank you. Thank you. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for all your questions and for being with us today. Investor Relations remain at duty also to answer any further questions you may have. We hope to talk to you again soon. Thanks and good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>