<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1251548" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call - Q&amp;A Session</title>
    <date>2010-10-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>885</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations and Treasury</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Bodo Uebber, Member, Board of Management, Finance and Controlling, Daimler Financial Services</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Jochen Gehrke</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Kristina Church</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Arndt Ellinghorst</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Stuart Pearson</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Horst Schneider</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Daniel Schwarz</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Thierry Huon</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Jose Asumendi</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Edward Taylor</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Charles Winston</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the global conference call of Daimler. At our customer's request, this conference will be recorded. The replay of the conference call along with presentation slides will also be available as an on-demand audio webcast in the Investor Relations section of the Daimler website. The short introduction will be followed directly by a Q&amp;A session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would like to remind you that this conference is governed by the Safe Harbor wording that you find in your published results document. Please note that our presentation contains forward-looking statements that reflect management's current views with respect to future events. These forward-looking statements can be identified by expressions such as assume, anticipate, believe, estimate, expect, intend, may, plan, project, and should. Such statements are subject to many risks and uncertainties, examples of which are set out in the Safe Harbor wording in our documents and are also described in our most recent Form 20-F under the heading Risk Factors. If the assumptions underlying any of these statements prove incorrect, then actual results may be materially different from those expressed or implied by such statements. Forward-looking statements speak only to the date on which they are made.</p>
          <p>May I now hand over to Dr. Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer, Head of Daimler Investor Relations and Treasury. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. This is Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer speaking. On behalf of Daimler, I would like to welcome you to our third quarter presentation. We are very happy to have with us today our CFO, Bodo Uebber.</p>
          <p>In order to give you maximum time for your questions, Bodo Uebber will begin with a short introduction, directly followed by Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Now, I would like to hand over to Bodo Uebber.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to our third quarter conference call. Once again we are pleased to deliver strong results. During the third quarter Daimler built on its momentum. Sales, revenue and earnings rose significantly. Unit sales and revenue increased by double-digit rates compared to last year's periods. EBIT reached &#x20AC;2.4 billion and we posted a net profit of &#x20AC;1.6 billion. Accordingly, the free cash flow developed strongly and further improved our net liquidity to &#x20AC;11.9 billion.</p>
          <p>What are the reasons behind this ongoing strong performance? First, there is already established presence in the booming export markets of Brazil and Asia and we continue to be very successful in the United States. The solid demand for our attractive products continued and actually exceeded our expectations in the third quarter and ongoing favorable model mix and pricing further enhanced our earnings. Cost reductions proved to be sustainable, due to our ongoing disciplined cost management. And last but not least, efficiency enhancements and restructuring measures, which replaced our temporary crisis measure, are clearly bearing fruit.</p>
          <p>Now, let's take a closer look to each of our divisions. Mercedes-Benz Cars posted EBIT of &#x20AC;1.3 billion in the third quarter compared to 355 million one year ago. Return on sales increased to 9.5%, confirming that we are well on our way to our financial target of 10% over the cycle after 2012. All segments of the Mercedes-Benz motor range achieved sales increases in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Our dynamic momentum in China is unbroken. From July to September, unit sales rose by 140% and there's no indication of a slowdown. Our sales in China as a percentage of our total unit sales increased quarter over quarter from 6% to 13%. Nevertheless, China is not the only driver for improving sales. In other Asian countries and in the United States, we also achieved a double-digit increase.</p>
          <p>The product mix remains very favorable. Unit sales of our E-Class and S-Class increased by 34%, 35%, respectively. The E-class and C-Class sedans, as well as our S-Class continued to be the market leaders in their respective segments. The current strong demand for our top-of-the-line models in the Chinese markets continues to stay at a high level. The market launch of the long wheelbase E-Class further strengthened our product mix. And finally, our success was supported by maintaining strict cost discipline.</p>
          <p>Daimler Trucks achieved an EBIT of &#x20AC;500 million. This compares to a loss of &#x20AC;127 million in the third quarter of last year. However, it needs to be added that the Q3 2010 EBIT includes positive effects of &#x20AC;178 million from the realignment of the healthcare and pension plans in North America and other special reporting items. There were opposing effects from charges relating to the revaluation of long-term warranty and service obligation, as well as an increase in research and development costs.</p>
          <p>In line with the economic recovery and the strengthening of our position in various markets, our unit sales rose by 44% compared to the previous year's third quarter. In Western Europe the dynamic development of demand and the improvement of our market position led to a sales increase of 46% to 14,700 units. Sales in Latin America were also strong and increased by 45%. Further stimulus came from the Mercedes-Benz Actros, which has been sold in Brazil since August in order to meet the increasing demand for premium trucks.</p>
          <p>In Asia, Daimler Trucks posted a sales increase of 42% mainly driven by a high demand in Southeast Asia, particularly in Indonesia. Our trucks NAFTA unit increased sales by one-third to 20,000 vehicles. We expect the NAFTA Class 8 market in 2010 will show a moderate increase over 2009. A full recovery will not take place until 2011.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, Daimler Trucks North America was able to strengthen its market share in the medium and heavy-duty segments due to the favorable reception of the new EPA10 engines. Our efficiency enhancement shows benefits above and beyond our repositioning programs in NAFTA and Asia, which are on track or even ahead of schedule.</p>
          <p>Mercedes-Benz Vans report a successful third quarter as well. EBIT rose to &#x20AC;122 million. The main reason for this success was a growth in unit sales with an overall rise of 34%, to which all regions contributed. A significant portion of our van sales increase can be attributed to the U.S. and our new joint venture in China. At the Hanover Commercial Vehicle Show, we presented the new generation Vito and Viano, which we are confident will create additional sales momentum.</p>
          <p>Daimler Buses posted EBIT of &#x20AC;11 million in the third quarter. The decrease in earnings is due to a less favorable model mix. Whereas sales of bus chassis in Latin America continued to develop very positively, sales of complete buses in Western Europe remained below last year's level.</p>
          <p>In line with the higher sales volume of our automotive divisions, business volume at Daimler Financial Services increased as well. Growth was particularly dynamic in China and Korea. EBIT rose to &#x20AC;317 million. This improvement was mainly due to the lower cost of risks and higher interest margins. Net credit losses amounted to 0.8% in the third quarter and are lower than during the crisis.</p>
          <p>To sum up, Daimler posted another solid quarter with an EBIT of &#x20AC;2.4 billion supported by recovering markets and our strong product portfolio. Year-to-date, our EBITDA amounts to &#x20AC;5.7 billion, thereof 5.4 billion from ongoing business.</p>
          <p>And now what do we expect for the rest of the year? Markets for motor vehicles worldwide will continue to rise, in particular due to the strong demand in export markets and growth in China. As a result, we are raising our guidance for EBIT from ongoing business for the Daimler Group to more than &#x20AC;7 billion.</p>
          <p>The product portfolio of Mercedes-Benz Cars is proving itself to be very attractive and competitive. It gives us the confidence to increase our 2010 unit sales for the Mercedes-Benz brand by a double-digit rate compared to 2009. The division will continue to benefit from strong sales and good margins, as well as from the positive effects from our successfully implemented efficiency programs. On the other hand, we expect seasonally higher marketing and services costs in addition to relatively higher product-related expenditures in connection with CO2 related technologies and upcoming product changeovers. Taking this into account, we expect a divisional EBIT of approximately &#x20AC;4.5 billion for the fiscal year 2010.</p>
          <p>For Daimler Trucks, we raised our guidance from EBIT from ongoing business to more than &#x20AC;1.1 billion, thanks to the favorable sale situation, very competitive products and our successful repositioning in North America and Asia. Mercedes-Benz Vans is expected to generate earnings of approximately &#x20AC;430 million due to increased sales and efficiency enhancements. At Daimler Buses we anticipate an EBIT of approximately &#x20AC;180 million. And for Daimler Financial Services, we expect EBIT from ongoing business of more than &#x20AC;900 million supported by decreasing cost of risk and good interest margins. We expected high level of earnings of the Daimler Group and the highly level of liquidity, which we have already achieved, should provide the basis for an attractive dividend payment for 2012 &#x2013; 2010 sorry.</p>
          <p>To sum it up, we are well prepared for the future. We have an excellent product portfolio and a balanced regional footprint and we have an efficient working capital and disciplined cost management.</p>
          <p>And now I would be happy to answer your questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Bodo Uebber. Ladies and gentlemen, you may ask your questions now. I will identify the questioner by name, but please also introduce yourself with your name and the name of the organization before asking your question. Two practical points, firstly, please avoid using mobile phones, and secondly, please ask your question in English. Before we start, the operator will explain the procedure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. We'll take the first question from Jochen Gehrke. Jochen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Now we can hear you. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Three questions if I may, first of all on the outlook for Mercedes. That would roughly imply we have a billion of EBIT to expect in the fourth quarter. In the light of what you achieved in Q3, should we be aware of any costs &#x2013; significant cost increases or is this a reflection of a conservative outlook? Then secondly on the truck side with regards to North America a sequential drop in order intake, could you just shed some light on the EPA '10 changeover and what dynamics you are seeing currently in the market? And then thirdly on the strategic side, your net liquidity now is almost back to the level that you recorded pre-the crisis. What do you want to do with this money now? I'm not going to the point of share buybacks, but if you could just shed some light on your strategic thinking. I think during the quarter we read press reports about your intention to potentially look into Fiat industrial. Is this something that Daimler would be seriously considering, expanding the business via acquisitions or are you taking a different approach? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jochen. I do think even were not three questions, but even more I do think, but I'll try to do this shortly. First getting to Mercedes-Benz Cars, I do think there's first of all no worry about the development. We have seasonal-related costs in the fourth quarter. For example, marketing services costs, which we also had in the past in every fourth quarter and again we have to make the final calculation of investments for example which, leads to some increase in costs in this quarter. And we have of course increasing, as we always commented, costs for C02 related cost and that happens in the fourth quarter. Seasonal, so to say and has not the effect that we have to reevaluate our long-term targets. Our long-term targets are intact with the 10% after 2012. Even I would say when we see the development of the whole year, I do think that would add a little bit of benefits to our May discussion in China. So that's for Mercedes-Benz Cars.</p>
          <p>Then to Daimler Trucks, first order intake. The order intakes in Q3 &#x2013; let's first, the order intakes in Q2 were much influenced by big fleet yields, what we had. So, what you can see now in Q3 that this big fleet, of course I don't do it every quarter so to say. In this quarter, Q2, it happened, so we have a natural decrease in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>All in all, of course we have to acknowledge that maybe when we look back to the first quarter of this year, we had the expectation for 2011 that there is a huge increase in demand. I do think right now we would say that we have a moderate 2010 and that we have now to reevaluate the 2011 market assumptions. I do think our colleagues from PACCAR have made already an assumption of, I do think 30 to 40%. I don't know whether we are in that range, but of maybe somewhat lower but that we will talk about also at the divisional day in November. So, there will be an increase in NAFTA, but maybe also not this huge increase what we might all had expected from the beginning of 2010.</p>
          <p>EPA '010 engine is doing quite very well. Our penetration is fantastic, so the take rate is very good and we get very good feedback from customers regarding EPA '010 feedback of the performance of the engine.</p>
          <p>Your last question I do think we're already to. First, net liquidity of course first we had a strong quarter in cash flow in third quarter. We are now in total at 5.3 billion, I do think. I also already have to tell you that the fourth quarter we will see of course higher investment levels. We are very disciplined in the investments, no doubt. But in the fourth quarter we will see higher levels and we will see also a building up of inventory from Mercedes-Benz Cars, in terms of the logistical transition of car to China for example or to the U.S. So, you have to build up some inventory there.</p>
          <p>And secondly, we have the changeover of the A and B class, so we will see some inventory buildup and that will have an impact on the fourth quarter cash flow. But all-in-all the net liquid, I do think that currently we do believe that the markets will sustainable develop in our basic scenario as we also commented for the next couple of years. There is a lot of talks about double-dip risks in the U.S. There's &#x2013; are talks about the hot landing in China. There are talks about currency bourse and so on and so forth. And I don't think that it's now smart to talk about net liquidity and distribution and share buybacks kind of this stuff in that kind phase we are currently in.</p>
          <p>And therefore we will &#x2013; I'm happy to have this high net liquidity. It is from a risk management point of view the right thing to have currently, but what I can tell you right now of course, due to the high liquidity and that was comment in my speech, that I regard this liquidity level and also the operating level is an attractive level to talk about the dividend, what can be attractive for the dividend. That's no doubt and that's &#x2013; I would also confirm without saying what kind of number I have in mind, but I do think we commented lot of times about it that our payout ratios from the past were 40%. But at the end of the day we have to talk about this with the Supervisory Board in February and to make then the decision and then I do think we have a attractive base for that.</p>
          <p>You've raised a question about Fiat Industrial. I have to say I do think it's all our duty as a company to look at corporations and to look at what is going on the in the market. And therefore of course every kind of movements in the market we should focus and we should make up our minds what we are doing. I do think currently, you have not seen a move and of course if we would move- which I've not currently have not in mind &#x2013; of course it would be always a move which is in the interest of the shareholders and not in the interest of something else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay we'll take the next question from Kristina Church please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Kristina Church from Barclays Capital. I have a couple of questions. Firstly, coming back to the trucks division, I was just wondering if you could talk a little bit more about any of the effects in Q3 that we should be thinking about. Because I noted that the sequential EBIT move was rather disappointing. I would think in that for the movement in revenue, the 580 million quarter-on-quarter. You needed an 8 million improvement in EBIT. I was just wondering if it's anything in there that we should be thinking about for the trucks and whether this sort of sequential move is something we should expect similarly in Q4 and to wait till 2011 for more recovery in the truck market. And then I had a question &#x2013; I'm going back to Mercedes on foreign exchange. I was just wondering if you could update us a little bit on your hedging policies and where you stand now in coverage for 2011 and maybe also 2012 and whether you could just mention about China within that, how you hedged China, whether it's included in your net open position for U.S. dollar when you get those hedge rates. And then very finally on China as well, I was wondering if you had any comment to make about some of the rumors that there have been that the Chinese government are looking to increase their consumption taxes again in order to harm the higher engine vehicle. Is that something that you've heard being discussed? And also, they &#x2013; I think they're talking about this one car-policy in Beijing. Are these things that you see as significant risks going forward or just something that you will bear in mind? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kristina, thank you for your questions. First, I'll start with the Daimler Trucks. Of course, we have, as booked a number of 500 million where we reported that we have special reporting items, positive ones, which is also good money I have to say, &#x20AC;178 million coming from changes in pension plans and from a lawsuit we had to release of a provision, two components and we have some minor changes in the repositioning charges during the quarters, but only minor ones. Of course, what we also stated another thing it's important to see, that we had also opposing effect from charges relating to the reevaluation of long-term warranty and service obligations which hit the quarter and some increased research and development costs. And therefore of course if I look at the number adjusted so to say 320 million the quality of the number is higher than the 322 if I might say so.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter, we developed as we have guided, of course, not more, not less. I'm pleased with the development currently what we have achieved, that our further progress in trucks is depending also on Freightliner Fuso's programs and earnings situation. That develops quite okay. I have commented it ahead of plan. So, and that is number one of the bigger levers of course for Daimler Trucks, to increase the earnings levels. From a cost point of view, from a process point of view, we have done everything to put these two units on a position to benefit from every sales increase of course what we get. And therefore this is so to say to done and now we have to see of course the market developments in North America, but also in Southeast Asia, but also in Europe of course for our European business. And we are in line with our guide pair so to say also to be here benchmarked with our long-term targets.</p>
          <p>Your Mercedes-Benz Cars question of the hedging policy of course which is a Group question. In total, we have commented this quite some times. We are hedged in &#x2013; 2010, of course we don't have to talk about. That is almost done so to say the year has six weeks to go, or seven weeks to go to Christmas. We have in 2011, 60% hedged and we have a three-year rolling model. You know this and that brings us roughly in 2011 &#x2013; '12 to 20 to 30%, somewhat in that range.</p>
          <p>Of course, you know that we are doing this at all the time so to say, so we have a mixture of different spot rates so to say in your hedge portfolio. I do think for 2011 with 60%, I do think it's quite okay from a risk point of view I would say and you know that we have partially voted for options and for collars and for hedges. The portfolio there is from my point of view in a good structure. China is included in our exposure. We have commented how big the exposure is. I do think the last time we mentioned it, it was US$13 billion. There is included our China portfolio of course because China is more or less &#x2013; the renminbi is somewhat pegged to the U.S. dollar. One thing on the other thing, you have other hand you have also revenues from the Middle East for example which are also invoiced in U.S. dollars. So, the portfolio as such is of course not only the U.S. related portfolio.</p>
          <p>Your last question was due to consumption, because I'm not aware that we have fear of &#x2013; of course there are many cities in the world which are defining some rules and procedures of the even and odd number can go in and so on into the cost. We have London. We have Beijing. Right now we have to cope with that kind of environment, no doubt, but I'm not aware in China that we have a new consumption tax here, but I will follow up on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Next question we take from Arndt Ellinghorst.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for taking my question. You've mentioned our discussions in main China where you were referring to the potential scenario where Mercedes margin could be down next year or flattish. Now, you mentioned it in your own speech that the way things look right now this could be a touch better. I mean could you just confirm which scenario we're currently looking at? Is it more a flattish margin scenario? Could the margin even be higher on average next year than this year? And then secondly, you mentioned that CapEx obviously seasonally will increase towards the end of the year, inventory will increase toward the year-end. Could you just confirm that you will not burn cash in the fourth quarter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe, I begin with the second question. Of course, I would not regard one quarter, maybe even negative cash flow, as burning cash. Therefore, I mentioned the year-to-date number of 5.3 billion. I do think building up inventories in the fourth quarter for the logistical chain to China or to the U.S. &#x2013; and you know we have Chinese New Year in February. There we have where we need to have some units of course in the market that the people can buy it, and I don't know two years from &#x2013; one year, last year we made a little bit of a mistake that we had not enough volume in the market. So, I would not regard this as a cash burn. So, the working capital increase, which we will see due to China and to U.S. for example, but also for the A and B class model changeover, I do think I would not regard as cash burn, investment also not. But the fourth quarter will be most probably negative so to say due to the fact what I have already mentioned right now in terms of inventory building up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Which gets us to the second question that next year could be pretty good then in terms of your sales performance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, even I would say is a good information because, as I said, China the volume next year will be intact. I do think the market will further increase. We have no sign of slowdown. Of course, you cannot discuss is it, what kind of percentage it is. But the preparation for selling in China also with regard to mix is totally okay and intact and what we prepare is to have a good start into 2011 from a sales point of view. So, there is nothing &#x2013; it's good that we do it, because we might miss the next increase of course in the beginning of the year 2011. I do think the first question was the margin in &#x2013; of course in China we don't comment on it, but I do think to answer to your question was more with regard to the margin as such for 2011 in total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Of course, we don't go now into guidance discussion, because we have not right now February, but we might have &#x2013; maybe we don't have any guidance next year, but that we have to discuss anyway. We said on the divisional day that we next year will have from a product portfolio point of view, changeovers and preparations. So this is '11 and '12. So, therefore of course we will do everything of course to keep our margin. We will do everything even to improve it as we said to our target, but we have some headwinds from the product portfolio which we discussed.</p>
          <p>We will have some &#x2013; also some headwinds maybe from raw materials. That depends a little bit how the world economy is doing on the other hand. So, and we have seen CO2-related costs, which we also commented. On the other hand we do everything to offset and try to offset these kind of negatives with other positives, elements. Pricing of course for example is right now positive. So, that we have to take into account. We will talk of this internally in our update until December. You know that we have always our planned discussion of next year and then we will see whether we &#x2013; what kind of margin we can deliver next year. I do think it will not be a bad margin because we are in this current year on a high level. I do think we are a bit better than we have thought it May and we are fully on track to deliver the 10% after 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, I have to follow up with one thing. We've seen quite interesting incentive data for Mercedes across the board. I mean is that something for you that that is a concern, rather how fast you see it or how these incentives develop? I know your messages this is all in line with budget. But maybe the budget you set beginning of the year, given the positive pricing, should be a different one now. So, why do we see an increase in incentives at Mercedes in many markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can, I do think I can cool you down a bit because not only our data compared to our budget is better, but also our budget is lower than the last year. So, it means our incentive spending &#x2013; and I get this data of course on a monthly basis, also for the U.S., and we are following it closely, no doubt because we know that we want to derive our business not with incentives, but with profitable growth. So, the incentive spending right now is lower than last year, by far lower than last year. The pricing positioning we have is pretty good. Our hit list where we are compared to our competitors in number one, two or third position. We are in many, many markets with the highest share in number one positions in residual values, which is also important towards our bigger competitors. And therefore the pricing right now, what I see from the data is okay. There is a difference of course in the data you see and I see. Of course now maybe we can argue I should disclose it, then you see it, but I do think it's too competitive.</p>
          <p>The Autodata data in the U.S. does not include &#x2013; they only include official programs for example. So, special programs from the manufacturers &#x2013; and there might be some who are doing special programs &#x2013; you do not see in this data. When you look at the year-to-date data of the U.S. incentive spendings, we have reduced it percentage-wise more year-to-date than others. Although I don't like this &#x2013; this data is not complete and on top of my data, I look into it as fully in line, not with the budget even with the trend seasonality we had with the model-year changeover later than the other competitors and therefore we saw &#x2013; you saw all our hikes and peaks in August. I do think even my September data goes again down compared to always again down. So, all what we see also in terms of residual values there towards &#x2013; also for Germany and from the U.S. we are on very good levels. It's pretty stable. We don't see year trends to watch negatives so to say from a residual value point of view, also not in Germany. From my point of view all what I can see is everything is okay. We are heading into the right direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the increase in marketing expenses in Q4 at Mercedes has nothing to do with hedging portfolio including discounts or what so ever?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no, nothing. It's services, it's part of services, We have for example, you have for &#x2013; you have the end of the day calculations so to say for example for dealers where you get the final invoicing. Of course there might be deviations. These are services costs from certain marketing services like ads, commercials and so on and so forth. So, it's nothing with incentives and residuals or something like this. It's pure &#x2013; it's cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, everything is in line with our targets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So we should expect a good margin. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will report you in February about this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next in line is Stuart Pearson.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morgan Stanley. Just following up from Arndt's question on pricing, maybe just turning the question over to China. Obviously not all of that business is fully consolidated and some of the data we see there indicates a bit of slippage in the premium end of the market. But, nothing too untoward, but maybe you could update us on the pricing situation for luxury cars in China. And then just secondly, you touched on residual values there. Maybe you could just clarify whether there's any off-lease disposable profits in your Mercedes number for the third quarter and whether you expect anymore going forward. And then finally just on the CapEx longer term, you revealed a plan I think in Beijing back in May just showing a strong ramp-up in Mercedes CapEx. Can you just confirm whether that's still valid in either direction and whether maybe that needs to be increased with the stronger demands that we're seeing around the world right now? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Stuart. To your first question in China, I have not the information that we &#x2013; that here the price positioning is jeopardized by our development. All what we see also the data I have there from it's &#x2013; I can only discuss it from a Mercedes point of view. I don't have the data of the other competitors. The &#x2013; it's pretty stable situation in terms of the overall kind of incentive spending and of course it's not a very high one. The other data I have to follow up. The competitive data, maybe further out we can talk about this, but I have to follow up and talk to the Chinese guys, to our own guys.</p>
          <p>Residual values, of course &#x2013; just to explain the system, when we start seeing maybe three years ago or two years where we had differences in residual values two things what you're doing. You're building up provisions of course, but what you sell, what &#x2013; your new sales are correctly priced and the residual values are set at the new level. Therefore of course, you might see in some in quarters some ups and downs with changes to what you have provisioned so to say. But the new sales you are putting into the market are on the levels that you normally should not have big deviations between the residual value and your &#x2013; and the actual used car prices at the end of the day. Therefore you have minor fluctuations, but not big ones. So, the profits are not impacted by this only minor volatility.</p>
          <p>The CapEx questions, of course the CapEx we have told you in February that we will spend, I don't know 8 or 9 billion for two years 8 billion, 8.1 for Daimler. We are very disciplined in the spending. So, I expect at the end of the year that we are not fully in this 8 billion and we will keep you up &#x2013; again, we date you up in February about again two years 2011 and '12. So, due to the very disciplined approach, we are somewhat underneath this level. But again in the fourth quarter we will see a higher one than in the third and in the second quarter. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But longer-term you're still targeting a significant ramp-up in -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes of course we are. That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>About how it changed since the chart, I guess, I think as Dr. Bernhard put up in May.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We would &#x2013; these are our targets right now and we &#x2013; as I said, we update in now October and November-December. But there's currently what we decided &#x2013; what we showed you in May it's on this status.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay, so no big change. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question we take from Horst Schneider.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Horst Schneider from HSBC. Three questions, if I may. The first one is with regard to the development of personnel costs. We had this week again in German newspapers said the unions could demand earlier-than-expected for next year a pay rise. So, to which extent should we expect a burden from higher personnel costs in 2011 next to the CO2-related costs and the higher raw material costs that you expect for next year? And then the second point is with regard to pricing, maybe you can give us some indication to which extent prices have developed positively year to -date and also in the third quarter. I know you are not splitting that up in your presentation, but maybe you can give us a percentage indication to which extent pricing has improved compared to last year. And then going forward, for me the most difficult question with regard to the forecast that I have got to do is how pricing will develop also within the next two quarters and for the next two years maybe. So, I see that all premium car makers are ramping up capacity. Do you think that at some point of time the pricing could reverse and get negative again or do you expect for a longer time horizon, now stable-to-rising prices still in the premium car market? And the last issue is also related to that. The last question is with regard to Financial Services profitability. Do you think that we can work with a level of profitability that we have seen in the third quarter also in the next two quarters? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Horst, first of all personnel costs 2011, of course I cannot and I will not discuss now special subjects. In terms of the subject you are mentioning, whether &#x2013; there's a discussion of course in the industry about the two months we could put forward the major increase. On the other hand, you know this particular point of course would increase &#x2013; would do an earlier increase of something which is a relative increase of I do think 2.7% or so. And I don't think &#x2013; we don't have to discuss now the impact on this two months and to discuss what would that mean.</p>
          <p>But, in general of course next year &#x2013; this year we have now the third and the fourth quarter has not any more the wage cuts, which we had for every employee and for the management of course in Daimler. So, therefore for us next year, we will compare to the second half of this year will be so to say flat plus. The increases of course which we will have &#x2013; which we have agreed with the Unions, it will be an increase. And it will come more in a natural situation as we were also a couple of years ago. And as we always try to offset also this increase, we have to do more on the efficiency side to come to offset these impacts. That is what we are striving for at the end of the day. But, we will see relatively spoke in increases in wages and salary next year worldwide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, how many percent of your total personnel costs come out of Germany?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't disclose this subject. I do think &#x2013; look into the, please into the annual reports 2009. You find at the last pages a section where we disclosed the total volume of personnel costs, and I do think they're up 60%. You might head into the right direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pricing-wise we are &#x2013; of course we said you can understand that we cannot discuss in detail pricing here and we will not, because this would be pretty competitive data, what we are doing there. So, we are of course compared to last year was a very special year. So, the difference between last year and this year is a bigger one and I'd not only talk about one percentage point. So, it's a bigger benefit we have this year. Next year and for the future we will benefit from a I would say a better or a higher price positioning of new models for example where we even could be able to do better on the pricing side for the next years. So, I don't see a negative. I see opportunities in this regard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry again for that one. I think BMW quantified the effect and in the Q2 conference call they said I think around 1.5% positive pricing compared to last year. Do you think it's a higher number at Mercedes or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I'm happy now to know their number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just 1.5%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I don't put into the market my number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that is what they said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I do think our disclosure is very good and if the guys would like to disclose this kind of stuff, okay. I'm fine to hear it, so to say I don't want to join them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Okay, no problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Financial Services, we had of course a very good quarter with &#x20AC;317 million in earnings. This is of course not the run rate you can &#x2013; we can keep. There are two elements in that one for the fourth quarter and more for 2011. One thing is of course that we have from an interest point of view due to the low interest rate and the central banks which are not increasing the rates, and of course and that's now happened a couple of quarters again. And of course we have an open position where we earn from this point of view somewhat earnings contribution we get from this angle.</p>
          <p>And on the other hand we had two releases of provisions in the third quarter with regarding one of our non-automotive portfolio and in the U.S. because our loss situation overall in the world is passenger car-wise doing well. Trucks is on a not good level, but not deteriorating. And Eastern Europe is again on a not very positive level, but also not deteriorating. So, we had to release some of the provisions in the U.S. All in all, I would say the run rate is somewhat at 250 million right now. But that is not the run rate also for 2011. That is lower due to this interest effect, which I don't regard as sustainable for 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you quantify the release of provisions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's roughly &#x2013; the run rate currently, keep it this way. The run rate of the Q3 is roughly 250 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next in line we have Daniel Schwarz</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Daniel Schwarz, Commerzbank. One question regarding the truck guidance, you increased the truck guidance by 100 million. You had positive impact or one-off of 180 million in Q3. Does it imply you're lowering the guidance or is that the new guidance excluding the special items of the third quarter? And the second question is regarding residual values. You mentioned some positive development, is that mainly coming from the U.S.? Is that also coming from Germany and the UK? And can you say how residual values develop in China? Is it comparable to other markets or is the used car market structurally different to Europe and the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Daniel, to your first question of course we might have been precise. The 1,100 does not include the positive special reporting items, what we had until September and that were roughly 200 million, the 180 in pension and other stuff. So, it's roughly 200, I do think 200 million or so year-to-date. And of course the book number will be then higher than the 1,100.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Reported EBIT above 1.3 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, right. Yes, yes, yes. So the 1,100 is only the ongoing profit, which excludes all the special reporting items we have disclosed to you until September.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question of course residual value development. I said okay it's stable. We have a stable development on a good level so to say. And that holds true for the U.S., for Germany and UK. So, there's currently no high volatility in these markets. In China we don't have &#x2013; we might be are able to do these things, but on a very small level, so we don't have currently so to say leasing business in China. So, I can't deliver you developments here on used car prices as I would be able to do this of course in UK and other, in Germany and the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next in line is Thierry Huon</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. It's Thierry Huon speaking from Exane. I have one question about China. Could you share with us the contribution of Chinese business to the Mercedes Car a bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer is sorry to say so no. Of course, you always -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But maybe you could give us some colors because -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't, we don't disclose the regional distributions of our margin development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I know, but since usually where we've got these numbers and the equity makes up a level and so you are putting it in the EBIT. So maybe we could help us to understand how much the Chinese market now is representing in terms of profit contribution?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course China is as I said we don't disclose it. We have the unit sales there which are very favorable. We have a good mix in China because we are &#x2013; it's S-class wise one of our top markets where we sell S-class. And of course also we have E-class now with the long wheelbase in China. So, we are doing very successfully, but please ask for your understanding. We are not disclosing regional profits, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I've got another question or just as a reminder could you remind me where the capital gain you had on Tata Motors is taking place in your P&amp;L? Is that in the operating profit or it's below the operating profit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No we don't, we haven't included and we have disclosed it as the &#x2013; we have a chart in the back-up and in our Excel sheet, fact sheet. You'll see a slide where you can see the effect which was booked not in a division. It's booked under others.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it's using the reconciliation I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does this explain why?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But it's in the EBIT. It's in EBIT.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does it explain why we have such a high positive number at the elimination, reconciliation level it did?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But of course therefore we disclose also that information, that you can if you want to exclude it for your analysis you are doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And of course we have the Omega case, the legal case in where we had a release of the provision in the third quarter of over 200 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question we take from Jose Asumendi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Going back to working capital, you provided some comments on inventories for the fourth quarter. I was just thinking whether we could see an improvement on as well on payables and receivables compensating these rising inventories. And second question on trucks, as we're heading to the fourth quarter, how are you seeing the incoming orders progressing in Latin America? Do you think we're seeing a more a &#x2013; are we seeing a consolidation on Q3 levels or is there still more potential upside on those figures? And last on pricing, I mean you have to increase your prices in North America for trucks to compensate the costs of the new technology. How is that progressing and have we already seen the improvement in the profitability? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Jose. Thank you for your questions. Okay, we have the Daimler Trucks questions of the order intake in South America. We expect it roughly on the same level. Of course we have the elections there you know it. We are in a high-level first of all in this market, no doubt. But now we're expecting on the same level further developments, which does mean that after the election &#x2013; I don't know whether the election already happened. It happened, yes. Okay. So, and we didn't expect now a drop-down to stable development, which is good because the level is very high. The earnings are good. Margins are also very good in this region.</p>
          <p>The pricing of EPA '10 you ask, we have a very good position right now. We get as I said before a very good feedback from the customer with the performance on our engines. And therefore also we can so to say on our cost position for the EPA '10, which we commended is 9,000 &#x2013; the price is $9000. And so we don't have here to spend on the incentive largely because we are good in our performance and that means we are in a earnings position for our EPA '10 engine.</p>
          <p>The first question was the working capital question. Of course, there could be of course some offsetting factors from the investment level as you said, trade payables, suppliers, but also maybe also a lower receivables level that could also positively impact, but it can also be negatively. So that is something of course we will see in January of course how it developed. But you know there is sometimes a day where you close the books and then you have to trade payables in. They are up or down at this point of time and the day after they are different. So to &#x2013; and therefore I do think it's better to focus on the total year development. This quarterly development of course is &#x2013; you cannot derive too much of course positives or negatives from it. So, the year-to-date number right now is very good. Fourth quarter from our point of view will be &#x2013; what we also said, will be negative in the fourth quarter, but will be still on a very high level for the year 2010 and that is most important. And for next year we will do our best of course with a good earnings level to get also a good cash flow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question we take from Edward Taylor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello this is Edward Taylor. I have a question about the situation perhaps with reference to Fiat. If Daimler is looking at opportunities in the market, is this mainly because Daimler has identified gaps in its portfolio where it feels a need to acquire more skills? Or is it more currently a situation where opportunistic opportunities have come up and it would be &#x2013; and of course it's obvious that everyone has a duty to look at these things, just some more granularity on the drivers if any potential activity in that area? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Edward, I only want to speak in general about it because we are not in contact with Fiat so to say and therefore that you don't get a misunderstanding. But in general speaking, where we look at corporations of course whether they fit or whether they bring us more forward as we are today for example. We have our cooperation and cost-share holding with Renault and Nissan. There is one example where we are putting a lot of benefits they too, we too on our current position. And that is at the end of the day, is the question when you see some on the one hand some maybe movement in the markets where you have to look into it or not. And then you have to ask yourself whether it can improve your position. I do think we are positioned in general very good in cars and also in trucks. But again you would always look at something where you just could say your situation would even be better than the today's one. So, I do regard that as a natural behavior, what we are doing here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Okay next in line we have Charles Winston.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Good afternoon. Charles Winston from Redburn Partners, I just wanted to go back to the topic you raise in terms of the warranty charges in the truck division. If you go look at the cash flow I can see about 700 million of non-cash charges in the industrial division in the third quarter. Bearing in mind that there were some non-cash gains buried in the quarter for instance the provision release relating to the court case and things. If you add it all up, it looks as though, on a growth basis, we could have been seeing something like sort of 900, maybe even a billion, of warranty and other non-cash charges before the gains you identified in the P&amp;L. Is that thinking correct and if it is, where are these non-cash charges spread? You've clearly identified some of them in the truck division. But have we seen other warranty costs for non-cash charges in the quarter across other divisions as well? And perhaps you could sort of quantify the split of how those non-cash charges have impacted the reported margins. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Charles, I do think it was the best way &#x2013; best thing. You know I don't have a problem to go into this, but I would like to do this with a high quality. If you would call please beyond try it, because this kind of 900 and 700 millions, I cannot really follow up this kind of impacts. Our earnings quality is very good one. I can only tell you there are not &#x2013; that there are no big releases of provisions. We have disclosed our pension positives income. You see the provision &#x2013; the provisions on the page in the interim report with also no big movement I would say to, also no releases. So for your follow-up question, please call Investor Relations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I certainly will do. Certainly, I wasn't trying to impugn the result. I was actually trying to suggest that it could well have been better than the reported number suggested.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the case book has not changed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know the case book, as booked as it is right now as we have disclosed it, of course will not changed because the cash is the cash. Therefore &#x2013; yes, I can only under this way there cannot be other impacts there because the cash has to be in the liquidity and therefore that's a fixed system. But anyway let us talk about this with Investor Relations. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Will do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and thank you. This was our last question. So, ladies and gentlemen thanks for your questions and for being with us today. Corporate Communications and Investor Relations remain at your disposal to answer any further questions you may have. I hope to talk to you again soon. Thanks and goodbye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your attendance. This call has been concluded. You may disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>