<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1349042" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-16</date>
    <companies>
      <company>885</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer, Senior Vice President, Head-Investor Relations &amp; Treasury</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Dieter Zetsche, Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Arndt A. Ellinghorst</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Jochen Gehrke</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Bodo Uebber</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Andreas Renschler</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Thierry Huon</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">John K. Lawson</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Max Warburton</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Christian Breitsprecher</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Kristina Church</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Horst Schneider</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Fraser Hill</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Frank Biller</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Philippe J. Houchois</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Ranjit A. Unnithan</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Stephen Reitman</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Jose Asumendi</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Charles Winston</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst">Alexis Albert</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst">Adam B. Hull</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the global conference call of Daimler. At our customer's request, this conference will be recorded. The replay of the conference call along with presentation slides will also be available as an on-demand audio webcast in the Investor Relations section of the Daimler website. The short introduction will be directly followed by a Q&amp;A session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would like to remind you that this conference is governed by the Safe Harbor wording that you find in our published results document. Please note that our presentation contains forward-looking statements that reflect management's current views with respect to future events. These forward-looking statements can be identified by expressions such as assume, anticipate, believe, estimate, expect, intend, may, plan, project, and should. Such statements are subject to many risks and uncertainties, examples of which are set out in the Safe Harbor wording in our disclosure document. If the assumptions underlining any of these statements prove incorrect, then actual results may be materially different from those expressed or implied by such statements. Forward-looking statements speak only for the date on which they are made.</p>
          <p>I now hand over to Dr. Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer, Head of Daimler Relations and Treasury. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. This is Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer speaking. On behalf of Daimler, I would like to welcome you on both the telephone and the Internet to our Full Year Results Conference Call.</p>
          <p>We are happy to have with us today the Chairman of the Board of Management and Head of Mercedes-Benz Cars Dr. Dieter Zetsche, our CFO Bodo Uebber, and the Head of Daimler Trucks Andreas Renschler.</p>
          <p>This morning at the annual press conference, Dieter Zetsche and Bodo Uebber presented our figures in detail. The speeches as well as the charts are available on the Daimler website. Therefore, we will start the conference call with a short introduction focusing on our Q4 results, there's more time for Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Now, I would like to hand over to Dr. Zetsche.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer.</p>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. I'd like to begin with a brief summary of our results for the full year 2010 as well a look at the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>In a nutshell, 2010 was an excellent year for Daimler. We posted EBIT of &#x20AC;7.3 billion. Earnings per share were at &#x20AC;4.28. We will propose a dividend of &#x20AC;1.85, and that equates to more than 40% of our net profit.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow from industrial business increased to &#x20AC;5.4 billion despite higher inventories and investments. As a result, net liquidity of our industrial business increased from &#x20AC;7.3 billion at the end of 2009 to &#x20AC;11.9 billion at the end of 2010. In sum, 2010 confirmed that we're well on track toward our medium-term profitability targets.</p>
          <p>As for the fourth quarter of 2010, we've also done very well. In the fourth quarter, Daimler posted EBIT of &#x20AC;1.6 billion. Special reporting items excluded, EBIT amounted to &#x20AC;1.8 billion.</p>
          <p>At the Mercedes-Benz Cars, sales increased by 12% compared to the previous year. Passenger car sales of our Mercedes brand grew by 15%. Revenue improved by 24% in the same period, due to an excellent product mix and a strong improvement in net pricing.</p>
          <p>With &#x20AC;1.2 billion, Mercedes-Benz Cars almost doubled its EBIT compared to the previous year's fourth quarter. MBC profit margin was 8.3%. That reflects the quality of the reported EBIT as earnings from ongoing business include higher R&amp;D spending than in the previous quarters, plus we are facing headwinds from higher raw material prices.</p>
          <p>Daimler Trucks boosted sales by 44% and all region contributed to that success with double-digit growth rates. Truck sales increased by 45% in Latin America and by 53% in Western Europe. In Western Europe, we further increased our market share by 2.1 percentage points and affirmed our position as a market leader. In the U.S., our new engines are popular with customers, resulting in a market share gain of 3.7 percentage points in the Class 8 market compared to last year. In the full year 2010, we took the number one spot in the Class 6 to 8 segments by obtaining an after-market share of 32%.</p>
          <p>And this positive trend is bound to continue. In the fourth quarter, the order intake in U.S. increased by 82%. In Asia, sales improved by 46% in the fourth quarter. There, too, our renewed model portfolio resulted in a market share gain of nearly 3 percentage points in Japan.</p>
          <p>Global revenue at Daimler Trucks increased by 42% in the fourth quarter. EBIT grew to &#x20AC;393 million. Excluding special reporting items related to our restructuring activities in North America and Asia, it even reached &#x20AC;420 million. This translates into a profit margin of 6.1%. By and large, Daimler Trucks is in an excellent position to benefit from a further recovery of the global truck market in 2011.</p>
          <p>Mercedes-Benz Vans also saw sales growth of 18% in the fourth quarter, especially because of strong market developments in Eastern Europe, North America and China. Revenue increased by 21%, and we posted EBIT of &#x20AC;138 million, reflecting sustainable efficiency improvements. Return on sales was at 6.2%.</p>
          <p>Daimler Buses showed a 20% increase in sales, while sales in Western Europe have been flat. Most other regions showed double-digit growth rates. Daimler Buses' EBIT was up from &#x20AC;46 million in the previous fourth quarter to &#x20AC;84 million in 2010. Consequently, our profit margin also improved from 3.8% to 6.3%.</p>
          <p>Daimler Financial Services benefited from the growth of the automotive business. Its portfolio increased by 9% to &#x20AC;63.7 billion. We were also able to raise profitability and posted EBIT of &#x20AC;224 million. While this success was supported by decreasing credit losses and low interest rates, we continue to be very conservative when it comes to risk management.</p>
          <p>Now let's look ahead at 2011. As outlined this morning, we posted strong sales of cars, trucks and vans in January 2011. Furthermore, we informed about our joint venture with Toray, and we also provided a short update on our legal proceedings.</p>
          <p>Based on today's assumptions, Daimler is expecting to post an EBIT from ongoing business in 2011 significantly above 2010. Of course, there will be constraining factors. Higher raw material, energy and logistics costs, higher R&amp;D and CapEx mainly due to spending related to CO2 emissions reduction, higher spending in connection with model change-overs, as well as higher personnel cost.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, we have reason to expect that, with expected growth of global automotive markets in the years to come, we can outperform the industry average. And that's how we intend to further improve earnings of both our individual divisions and our entire group.</p>
          <p>Starting 2013, we seek to achieve an annual average return on sales of 9% in our automotive business over the market and product cycles. And we intend to do so on a sustained basis. As for our individual divisions, our goals remain to achieve a return on sales of 10% at Mercedes-Benz Cars, 8% at Daimler Trucks, 9% at Mercedes-Benz Vans and 6% at Daimler Buses. At Financial Services, we aim for a return on equity of 17%.</p>
          <p>2011 will mark another step in the right direction. All in all, I'd like to reiterate what I said at our annual press conference this morning: the inventor of the automobile is in very good shape.</p>
          <p>Now Bodo Uebber, Andreas Renschler and I will be happy to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Dr. Zetsche.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, you may ask your questions now. I will identify the questioner by name, but please also introduce yourself with your name and the name of your organization.</p>
          <p>Two practical points. Firstly, please avoid using mobile phones, and secondly, please ask your question in English. Before we start, the operator will explain the procedure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, first question we take from Arndt Ellinghorst.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Arndt Ellinghorst, Credit Suisse. My first question is a bit more strategic, I guess. What do you think, Dr. Zetsche, is the reason why your stock goes down pretty much every quarter? Your company reports earnings for the last three years. And then secondly, a bit more operational, Mercedes I think increased the inventory level at the Daimler level of around 25,000 units in the fourth quarter. Could you tell us how much of an impact that will have in the first quarter this year and how much in value terms that roughly is? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the stock is concerned, to my knowledge we are that &#x2013; depending on the day you're looking at, but they're &#x2013; most of the time, they're second largest automotive company as far as capital market cap is concerned. This is what we are looking at, their long-term development and their daily and hourly development are driven very much less by underlying performance but more by considerations within the system, which we should not focus our attention to too much.</p>
          <p>As far as inventories are concerned, on the Mercedes-Benz side we had two specific aspects. One being that by the percentage of sales not going to Europe and &#x2013; or Germany and Europe is increasing, naturally the pipeline is growing and therefore, we have on that side a reduced amount of vehicles ready for sale and an increased amount being in the pipeline to fulfill the upcoming demand in the first quarter and ongoing in China and other places.</p>
          <p>On top of that, we have a major change over in our Rastatt plant for the next generation of A and B-Class vehicles and therefore we already had to stop the production of the current A-Class in order to prepare for the new product and to still supply the market. We had to ratchet up our supply in that segment. So, these are the reasons why, not only according to plan but actually below our planned number, we increased inventory below because we sold more than we planned for in the last days and months of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the share price reduction, you don't believe that there's a more structural element to it because this is just reappearing so many times now, i.e., that just always something goes wrong within your quite significant group of companies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you certainly have a better overview than I do about the general reaction to quarterly reportings. My feeling is we're not the only company with this kind of reaction in the marketplace. Secondly, I look at our performance based on the main aspects how our products are received by the customers, how our margins are developing, how our inventories are hold, how are the costs are coming down and things like that. And in this regard, I don't see these many things going wrong in our company. Actually I think a lot of things must have gone right comparing 2010 with 2009 in absolute terms and relative to our competition, and therefore I don't see where this question could lead to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We take next question from Jochen Gehrke.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just three topics, if I may. First of all, regarding cash flow, conscious about the fact that the annual report is yet to come out. Could you help us understanding a little bit the quality of the earnings of this quarter? It seems like working capital was a significant drag in the fourth quarter and yet you produced a bit cash. Could you help us, at least on main items such as provisions and so and so forth, to understand how we should read some of the margins?</p>
          <p>Then secondly on trucks, in the fourth quarter, what you displayed is certainly a sequential strengthening, but when I keep in mind, Mr. Renschler, last quarter you highlighted that in the 5% you also burdened the quarter a little bit and that the true margin in Q3 was a 6%. The point that I'm trying to make is the sequential development doesn't look to be that big. Was there again some stuff in there?</p>
          <p>And on a more strategic side, the Daimler Trucks business is one where we know that you have put through substantial restructurings in the last couple of years and mainly NAFTA and Fuso. And yet when I annualize the revenue level now, you're back to pre-crisis levels almost, but your profitability is what we know it to be. So there doesn't seem to be a structural shift up and if you would agree, when should we expect this to happen? And then final question is on Financial Services. When you look at your partner, Renault, it seems like they can produce almost the same EBIT in Financial Services as you can, while just running a fraction of the asset base. Have you looked into this? And if so, what can you learn from your co-operation partner? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jochen, to your first question, so the &#x2013; regarding the cash flow development in the fourth quarter. When we had the third quarter conference call, I do think I announced the negative free cash flow for the fourth quarter, now we are slightly positive in the fourth quarter. So we managed it &#x2013; and we thought based on end of October, we had of course in the fourth quarter a higher CapEx spending of that's roughly &#x20AC;500 billion, I do think.</p>
          <p>Then we had also, of course, some tax payments in this fourth quarter where we saw that we had to pay taxes in Germany based on our very good performance. And of course, we had some, as Dieter mentioned it already, also investments into inventories regarding A and B-Class in China that all in all explains that the fourth quarter cash flow was somewhat lower than the third quarter, but as I've said, it was higher than we expected it at the end of Q3. So therefore, I'm very pleased with the development of the cash flow. It's very strong over the whole year, &#x20AC;5.4 billion is I would say an extraordinary achievement in this year.</p>
          <p>We have to take into account sometimes that accounts payables are in so far volatile because it depends when you close your books. So sometimes in this regard, it's up or sometimes it is also down. But all in all, cash flow was extraordinarily strong and the discipline in the company, I would say, regarding inventories even seeing at year-end at Trucks, at Vans and Buses is very good. We are far away from all-time peaks we had in new inventory and used inventory. And therefore, as I said, I'm pleased with the strong cash flow in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Mr. Gehrke, your question is, we said that the third quarter &#x2013; it goes in the direction to 6% and you will see in the fourth quarter, the same, a little bit higher. That means ongoing is 6.1% that shows what we said already outside our conference <mark type="inaudible" /> and its underlined here that we are really good on track. If you look to the markets, you are always coming up with revenue, if you look to the markets in 2010 they are everything then booming.</p>
          <p>If you look to the European market, it was plus 5% in the overall market and in the United States, it was the second worse in 54 years. And you have to look to our performance when you look to these different kind of markets and as you know, we see some more improvement in 2011. So we are, like we said, very confident to achieve our midterm target from 2013 on, the 8%, and we are on a good track to achieve this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question on Financial Services, of course I have not yet followed up the Renault figures, what we all &#x2013; we do of course &#x2013; we look at, so to say, the benchmark if you might say so. But you know our target is 17% return on equity and that drives our financial services profits because we have two roles of course in the company. One is to support our divisions in the market in sales and marketing, so to say, and you know it why our special arranged terms of financing or leasing finance and whatsoever and wholesale financing for dealers, for example. And on the other hand to earn a decent return on equity. We define this balance of supporting and earning and being profitable earning money with 17%, that goes back to also to benchmarks we looked into a couple of years ago, and we do think that this balance for our company is the best one with 17%.</p>
          <p>All in all, we will of course further do benchmark analysis if they are available. Especially I do think it's good for seeing how the risk management is developing. So that is an indication for me, for example, where we could do better maybe. I have not seen now the numbers of Renault, whether they're in risk management, where their losses are and compare them with the passenger cars' development that we have to follow up and then to make our conclusion here. But as I said, 17% is from our point of view, the right balance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Renschler, sorry, if I just may follow up, obviously conscious of the market development but nevertheless, if I look at your fourth quarter revenue level, and I were to annualize that, I'm very close to where you were in 2007-2008. And these were years where you made 6% or 7%. And now here we are, after two major restructurings in Freightliner, in Fuso and the business is producing 6.1%. Is this just too shortsighted or where am I missing the point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's little bit short sighted because revenue is one thing, as you know we had major increases in prices when you look to new emission laws in EPA '010 and other things. And this is good to bring the cost through and to stay with the price tag. So revenue, I think it's the right measure, you should look into the market development and the market development where, like I described before in 2010, was okay, but not that I'm feeling in paradise. And the next step into that will be in 2011. And the market will grow like you could see in our charts. I'm sure you have it in front of you. And we will see how the market development is coming out. Order intake is still very good. We have in January a very good order intake compared to &#x2013; and shows that we are on this way, we can achieve it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next in line is Thierry Huon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, it's Thierry Huon speaking from Exane in Paris. Three questions, please. First, on the Q3 report, it is said that if &#x2013; should the interest rates stay where they used to be previously, you would have to had &#x20AC;2.5 billion on the pension fund. Could you clarify where you are on this issue?</p>
          <p>Similarly, Dr. Zetsche said several times that capacity might become an issue for our Mercedes Car Group since demand is really high. So, do you intend to increase your capacity in Germany or in the U.S.? So could you help us to understand what you are going to do there? And finally, could you share with us the numbers about the whole material headwind you are expecting for this year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Thierry, on to your first question, first in my presentation this morning and the press conference in the backup, you will find the funded status of the pension and the healthcare obligations. Pension gap is currently at &#x20AC;6.5 billion and the healthcare funded status, this was negative &#x20AC;1 billion roughly or &#x20AC;900 million. The difference to Q3 assumption was that the long-term interest rates in November, December picked up and therefore the net present value of course of the pension obligations changed in favor to our statement compared to end of October. And that was not foreseen that the interest rates picked up in November and December and therefore the gap was not widening. It was &#x20AC;2.5 billion, I do think it was only so to say or &#x20AC;0.5 billion compared to end of last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as capacity is concerned, we are on our way to increase capacity on the one hand with a new plant in Hungary, and on the other hand, with expansion in China going to about two-thirds of 300,000 units to be sold in 2015, which means about 200,000 capacity which is three quarters additional to what we had. So these are two major expansion plans. Going beyond that, I do not expect that you would see capacity increases in Germany as incremental demand will not come from Germany either. So that is a very clear direction. As far as raw materials are concerned, we expect in 2011 compared to 2010, an incremental cost of about &#x20AC;700 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's very clear. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question we take from John Lawson, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, John Lawson from Citi. Firstly, could you just tell us whether there are any costs to you of dropping the Penske driven Mexican Smart four-seater project. Secondly, on Trucks, I think if we look at the book-to-bill again in the fourth quarter, it's one times and it's not particularly typical I think, of the gains that we might have been expecting at this stage of the cycle. Is this a mix effect? I mean if we confined ourselves just to heavy trucks, would we get a much more positive read on your book-to-bill or is there something else going on? And then finally, just on this litigation risk, which seems to have impacted reconciliations in the fourth quarter. I guess it's not particularly easier for us to fully understand there are a few potential candidates, I suppose. I mean just to help us eliminate some, did the EADS litigation question arise too late for you to consider within these accounts? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To your first question, we are early days as far as the plan for a Nissan based four-seater from Smart in U.S. is concerned. That's why the cost of dropping it will be a one digit million number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your question about book-to-bill in the order intake, they're over 100% in the year 2010 and it's indeed the first quarter we saw some slower order intake in light-duty truck. There is one reason behind, we had to clarify some delivery issue with Indonesia, and Indonesia is for Fuso light-duty truck, a very important one. So, that was one of the reason, but basically if you are going and we see some increase also overall in GDP, so that impact is a little bit better in heavy-duty and then secondly also in light-duty. That's general. If you look to the January date, we have 150% book-to-bill, again, it shows that it underlines our forecast for the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Your question regarding the legal proceedings, as we also disclosed and said that we have &#x2013; we had additional expenses in connection with the legal proceedings in 2010, which you'll find under the reconciliation item we also &#x2013; were included the expenses which related to the 125 years celebration, and also to the capital increase for our Daimler and Benz Foundation. When you go back into the past, normally the reconciliation item is slightly negative, you can look it up in the first quarter. It has also been our policy not to give further details to specific legal cases with regard to provision or expenses and that I will stick to, and I hope for your understanding that I cannot provide you with further details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>After the event, Mr. Uebber, it is your policy clearly though, because I mean in the third quarter you were quite clear about the provision reversal right? So we could see something not very symmetrical here in other words.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the third quarter, you're right. We had a legal case &#x2013; a release of a provision with regard to a legal case from the past. That is right and you find this on our, I do think, special reporting item list in our disclosure in the backup of our &#x2013; yeah, I do think, the fact sheet. There, you'll find it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So if these aren't needed, hopefully we'll see them again there sometime?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will &#x2013; we will discuss it, I think, in the upcoming years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question we take from Max Warburton.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, good afternoon. Max Warburton from Bernstein. Just got two questions, please. The first predictably is on Mercedes-Benz in China. I am sure you're aware that all of us in the financial community are trying to figure out how to forecast this market and forecast particularly premium car sales. Just wondering if you could share your latest methods of doing that. How is Daimler going about forecasting that market and particularly what are your latest thoughts for this year? And then secondly on Trucks, we have this antitrust case of sorts in Europe that seems to have broken in the last couple of weeks. Would it be reasonable to assume that M&amp;A activity in Trucks is basically going to be off the table in Europe as long as that case is ongoing? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't know if we have a comment on the latter part. Or I know there was one comment from one competitor related to their specific M&amp;A activities or expectations, not from us. We are not in any M&amp;A discussions right now, therefore it's irrelevant to us.</p>
          <p>As far as China is concerned, we saw in the past typically three numbers are forecast for the China market. One was our own, which used to be the most conservative. The next one was the one of western analysts, which was a little bit more optimistic and then the one of Chinese analysts, which was much more optimistic. And the actuals always came in better than the Chinese analysts had expected.</p>
          <p>Nothing tells us that this would continue, but we are now more in the middle using the different sources and trying to put ourself in the middle, not to be short of capacity and perquisites to follow the market opportunities. Of course we are seeing risk as well, but we have said that we expect for ourselves a sales potential of 300,000 units in 2015.</p>
          <p>We see ourself on the way in this direction in the year 2011, '12 and so on. So in spite of some news like the Beijing policy or more recent, some financing constraints, we do believe that first of all the Chinese economy will continue to grow close to a two-digits, margin and that based on this growth, automotive demand will continue to see significant increases year-over-year. And within that, we see the premium segment, which has more than doubled in recent years as a percentage of the total sales to at least grow at the same rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just a follow-up on that, I mean obviously we've seen these huge January figures year-on-year, but the comp is quite easy. Is your feeling that the pace of growth is now slowing sequentially and that we're going to get a more sensible number this year? Or is it possible &#x2013; possible that we could get yet another extraordinary year of growth in 2011 like we saw last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I neither expect that the total markets would grow at the rate of 2010, nor do I expect that we will more than double our sales in 2011 as we did in 2010. So, my understanding is that the Chinese government tries to find a balanced path forward between dampening inflation, continuing growth in order to create another 50 million jobs in 2011. And so far, they have done a quite impressive job in finding this right balance. I don't see external factors to dramatically change this picture.</p>
          <p>There is one aspect certainly, as far as automotive is concerned that we see significant concession in some of the major cities and that's something Chinese authorities are dealing with as well. But once again, overall, for the automotive and perhaps to this specific aspect &#x2013; at least in similar cases Singapore and other places, where there had been restrictions in the number of new cars you can get licenses for, in the end of the day, this always has led to a change of the structure in favor of more expensive vehicles. Whatever their specific system was. That might be different in China, but it's more likely that this would favor the premium market in these specific regional markets or metropolitan markets versus the volume market.</p>
          <p>But once again altogether we expect significant growth in 2011 for the total market and at least proportional growth for the premium market. And Mercedes should do at least as well as its competitors for &#x2013; I think four years now, we have done considerably better than our competitors as far as growth is concerned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, it's going to be interesting to watch. Good luck and thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Same is true for us. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next in line is Christian Breitsprecher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon, it's Christian Breitsprecher from Macquarie. I have two questions, one going back to the Mercedes unit and one Financial Services. When we look at the fourth quarter results, that disappointed me a little bit, but what was really the headwind there? I mean you highlight higher research and development expenses, higher raw materials, but when we look at the margin deterioration versus the third quarter, it was almost 1.2 percentage points. Is it really just those elements or is there anything else that we should be aware of that led to that deterioration, the sequential deterioration in March and &#x2013; versus the third quarter despite the fact that you had higher volumes and higher revenues sequentially?</p>
          <p>The second question is on Financial Services, also there we've seen a sequential deterioration versus the third quarter. What is behind that? Any specific issue and is the fourth quarter result something that's a good base as we are extrapolating into 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, to first answer about the Mercedes business, when you look into our history and that's not true for every single year, but in general, we had a somewhat lower fourth quarter versus the second and third quarter.</p>
          <p>To explain that in a very unscientific and general way and not accounting way, I would say we do some housekeeping in the fourth quarter where we look to the next year and where we address all the annual issues, which have not been addressed already. Specifically in this quarter, there is about &#x20AC;100 million number, which relates to employment related aspects where we prepare for some actions which we expect in 2011 and there are some other issues.</p>
          <p>So, to answer it very simply, from inside I have not seen any pressure on our performance in Q4 versus Q2 or Q3 on an ongoing basis. And I do not expect that to happen going forward. We have told you in the &#x2013; our Analyst Meeting in Beijing that 2011 and 2012, from our product portfolio point of view, are not the peak years. So, we have some product renewals, we have a little ageing of our product portfolio in average volume based all together, which will then reverse strongly with the introduction of the new C-Class, of A and B-Class and the new S-Class and so on.</p>
          <p>But these are the two years in the seven-year cycle, which are the most challenged from a product portfolio point of view. In spite of that, we will show that our strong confidence, continuation of our development towards the 10% margin in 2013 and, therefore, we feel very good about the development in the third and in the fourth quarter and expecting to see a continuous development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christian, to your second question regarding Financial Services, in the third quarter I do think I also made the remark that we had some releases of provisions &#x2013; credit reserves in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>So the &#x2013; was an extraordinary good quarter, so to say, which was not the run rate, I commented already on the road show and conference call that the run rate is more between &#x20AC;200 million and &#x20AC;250 million, and you see in the fourth quarter &#x20AC;220 million, I do think about Financial Services.</p>
          <p>We have builded some specific REIT reserves in the U.S., but credit losses develop beside this very good. So there is no negatives in that, but we have to cope also in 2011 with at &#x2013; minimum at the second half of 2011 with some rising interest rates, which normally makes it a bit more difficult for Financial Services. So all in all, kind of the run rate of the fourth quarter might be, let's say, a good indication for 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next in line is Kristina Church.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got a question coming back to the Trucks business firstly. Just more looking at your orders versus some of your competitors, particularly in Europe, it did look rather weak. It's still obviously up 37% in Q4 in total terms, but I was wondering if there is anything in there we should be thinking about versus the Scania and Volvo order numbers reported. And then as a sort of follow-on from that on the Trucks business, your outlook for North America remains at 20% to 25%, which is significantly behind where your run rate is at the moment and also where a lot of your current competitors are guiding to.</p>
          <p>Should we look at that as being overly cautious or should we think, is there something in there specific to Daimler Trucks that we should be aware of? And then just a follow-on from the raw materials question we had earlier where you guided to &#x20AC;700 million, just wondering if you could break that down a bit between the divisions and give us a bit more detail on what raw materials headwind in particular you'd expect from the Mercedes division.</p>
          <p>And then the final question is coming back to the accounting cleanup numbers that you were talking about regarding head count issues in Q4, obviously you haven't reported these as one-off items, the &#x20AC;100 million that you talked about. Is that because we should expect to see these still ongoing in 2011 or are they really more exceptional items for the quarter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To your Truck relevant questions, first of all, I don't know if somebody disclosed any order intake as far as I know, not. I can only tell you that we have a order intake increase of over 70%. Maybe you are coming to sales figures that some of us maybe have for January disclosed. I am very &#x2013; first of all if you compare January 2011 to January 2010, you have to look what kind of sales the respective company has in such a month if you make months-to-months comparison.</p>
          <p>If you are very &#x2013; you know on a deep side in January 2010, then you can of course report a lot of growth. Second thing is you have to know in our business specifically in us &#x2013; normally in December in certain countries you are cleaning up the pipeline. So, you have and you look to say it's always the first task is to fill up the pipeline again.</p>
          <p>Specifically in Brazil, this in our case very often the reason behind, for us, it's very important as I said, is the order intake. And the order intake is a very good indication and we have on a very good track of when you look to our order intake and so, we see that the market is developing like we said in the U.S. between 25% and 20% and 25%. And by the way, we gained market share in the United States also in January we gained some market share. So if the market is going up this is not a question of we don't want to sell it, then we will sell more, the performance we can see today in the market is that we're gaining market, we gained last year in Class 8 or in Class 6 and 8 if you combine this and the same you will see this year.</p>
          <p>So, we will always grow a little bit better. It's at least our assumption then the market and we will see how we end up at the end. It's a little bit too early to say it will go up 30%, could be, but our forecast from today's knowledge is 20% to 25%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Mr. Renschler, if I could just follow up on the order question was specifically for Q4 orders rather than January orders. And for Europe in particular, where you reported 34% increase whereas Scania and Volvo had closer to 100% increase in order intake.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Also there is the question of base, I don't know the actual figure of &#x2013; maybe can look on that but again, I said we have &#x2013; and you look to that one, we had one of the issues that you cannot see in the overall order intake also at the end of December. It's some delivery issues between Japan and Indonesia, that's light-duty trucks, there we fall down but it's now clarified and you will see this in the first quarter coming up again. And overall, the order intake is much higher than we expected and we see the same development and that's the most important thing for us also in January. And of course we have already 15 days in February, also in February and we are going up and we can see no reason that we cannot participate in the market growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as these kind of personnel related costs are concerned, you were asking for, this &#x20AC;100 million I was talking about is mostly part of our strive for further improvements of HPV hours where we are addressing indirect labor, mostly.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, we see growth all over the place, which means that we have no problems appearances with employment. And therefore, I do not see a recurring position of this kind going forward. And therefore, this is, we do not show that as one-time as part of our operations but it has the character of a one-timer if you want.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To your third question, I just think you asked for the breakdown of the raw material costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And roughly it's 50% related to Mercedes-Benz Cars and 30% to Trucks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question we take from Horst Schneider.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Horst Schneider here from HSBC. Three questions, if I may. First of all, maybe you could provide some outlook with regard to the potential one-offs in 2011. I mean we talked already on the conference call about the investigation here in Europe on Trucks but &#x2013; and you mentioned also in the press conference Toll Collect again and especially with regard Toll Collect, maybe can you provide us an update what is the worst case impact that you could imagine here &#x2013; will here be seen in 2011?</p>
          <p>And the second question is with regard to Mercedes-Benz and the outlook, Mercedes-Benz Cars. You said in the press conference that Daimler aims to avoid a dip in Mercedes 2011 margins. So here I would like to ask, is there still a possibility that the margins will decline in Mercedes-Benz Cars given the fact that you expect the global light vehicle market to increase by 6% or 5% to 7%? So or should we rather expect an increase in the earnings margin?</p>
          <p>And then the last question is more a strategic one that refers to acquisitions. You also said in the press conference that Daimler is still open to potential acquisitions. So, maybe could you specify that a bit? So should we expect acquisitions rather or are acquisitions possible rather in Trucks or in Cars? Do we talk about larger or smaller acquisitions? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To start with your last question, if you're running an enterprise, acquisitions should be a possibility, otherwise you would not look at all aspects of doing business. But there is nothing more specific than that and therefore there is no possibility to make any further clarifications because there are no specific plans in a very meaningful way of that kind.</p>
          <p>Generally spoken, generally spoken, as we are a premium car manufacturer and there are not too many premium car companies around, major acquisitions on the Car side are highly unlikely. Close to impossible. So, in this field, we rather would be talking about Truck related activities. But again, that is a very general comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you ruled out any tie-up with Civico, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I said that there were some talks and that they ended based on different perspectives, more on the financial part of the actual transaction than on the strategic one.</p>
          <p>When you are referring to the press conference, I'm not aware and the two gentlemen sitting right and left of myself are not aware of me having commented about the fight against decreasing margins at Mercedes. I said and I repeat that we feel confident with the 10% margin in 2013.</p>
          <p>I said and I repeat it today or at this meeting that we made some comments in our Chinese, Beijing analyst conference as far as the product portfolio is concerned. That was true and continues to be true. But we feel confident that we are on our way to the 10% margin on the Mercedes side.</p>
          <p>The one-offs, Bodo, it's your turn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One-offs is me. So first of all, of course just from a theoretical point of view, a practical point of view, if you would have special reporting items today, in my view, would have to give you some information regarding 2011.</p>
          <p>So we have given you a guidance, having in mind today not any special reporting item, as of today. But I cannot exclude &#x2013; I don't know first, second quarter that there would something to be report about it. But I don't know anything right now.</p>
          <p>With regard to your question of the legal cases, I would like to now to &#x2013; not to repeat it, but I would like to refer to my speech in the press conference. And I do think that the disclosure we have made where I commented on legal proceedings with regard to Toll Collect and the antitrust investigation but also to the EADS accusation in France &#x2013; further than this I do not want to comment further on any might be possible or such kind of events.</p>
          <p>I already stated that we do not give further details in the specific legal cases. Of course, you can refer also to other disclosure in some of the elements here from 2009 and any other stuff I have commented in the press conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But is it now fixed when the German court &#x2013; or I don't know if Toll Collect is now already at the German court. But when the German court will decide on that case? Is that already known?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there is a arbitration proceeding. It's not under the &#x2013; on a court.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>An arbitration proceeding. And we will see what the outcome will be in that case. As I said before, we disclosed in 2009 with regard to the Toll Collect proceedings in our disclosure and you will get of course -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; really a change at the 2nd of March, where you get our annual report in a written way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you cannot say when the arbitration proceeding will end?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is a kind of probability question you ask me right now. Also I cannot comment on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. No problem. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm &#x2013; coming back to you once again, I'm just shown something which is quote, unquote Daimler Chief Financial Officer Bodo Uebber on the sidelines of a press conference that he couldn't rule out that profit at the passenger car operations could suffer a dip this year, adding that the company will try to avoid such a scenario.</p>
          <p>I would have to ask Bodo, but I'm pretty sure that someone might have heard that. But nobody has said that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for clarification.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In any case, that had nothing to do with the reality.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we take the next question from Fraser Hill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Fraser Hill from Bank of America. Hello, can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fraser, we can't hear you. Maybe you use a mobile phone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, can you hear me now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Try again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, can you hear me now? Is that better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, great. Okay, sorry about that. Yeah, it's Fraser Hill from Bank of America. Got a few questions left.</p>
          <p>Firstly, I just wanted to go back to China and specifically to Beijing, I know that it's difficult for you to give a forecast. And the January numbers that we've seen thus far have, I think, reflected an order backlog from a few months ago. So can you give us a bit of feedback as to what you're seeing in your dealers in January and also in February? And specifically in Beijing, whether you're seeing any effect or how significant the effect has been from the policies that have been implemented there?</p>
          <p>Secondly, on raw materials, you've given the guidance of &#x20AC;700 million, I just wondered how much of that was locked in for the year, and what percentage of your materials have you contracted for 2011. And what sort of hedging have you got in place?</p>
          <p>Thirdly, on Financial Services, just interested why your contract volumes only increased by 9% given that you had a much sharper increase in deliveries. Is there any reason why the contract volumes didn't increase by a larger amount? Because it would seem that it might imply that you've seen your penetration rate drop? Or is that the wrong way to look at it?</p>
          <p>And finally, just on R&amp;D, what proportion of the increase that you're flagging comes from CO2 reduction measures? Is it all going towards CO2 reduction measures, or is there something else that you're spending the money on there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as China is concerned, all together, sales in China in January were good. We saw some decline in Beijing. We saw a significant up-rise in Beijing in December.</p>
          <p>So now independent of what the impact of new regulation was, you would expect this reduction in January, just based on the pull forward effect of December. So I think it's just too early to tell what kind of impact this new regime in Beijing might have on a ongoing basis.</p>
          <p>As far as R&amp;D is concerned, the last question, I would take that and then Bodo would answer the other two. The R&amp;D increase to some extent is related to CO2  reducing activities, but there is a good part as well related to further portfolio increases in our overall plan for Mercedes, which means we are investing into &#x2013; in some cases, incremental product, which according to our planning is bound to give us very nice returns. So these are, if you want, good investment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To your question on Financial Services, the increase in 2010 was 9%. Currency adjusted is about 3%.</p>
          <p>So this increase in portfolio is based on the increase in acquisition. I do think it's 11% currency adjusted. And it develops like our sales &#x2013; according to our sales in passenger cars and in trucks.</p>
          <p>The penetration rate is kind of stable. There is no big movement even in the difference of leasing and finance. There is no big change to 2009. In 2011, of course, you will &#x2013; we will see according to our sales forecast, of course, further increase also in the Financial Services portfolio.</p>
          <p>The raw material question, of course, the &#x20AC;700 million I mentioned, of course, is taking into account the hedged volume. Of course, in fuel we don't have so to say a treasury hedging, but we have a hedging according to the contract length we have in the different divisions. And therefore, of course, it has also taken that into account.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next in line is Frank Biller.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There are just two questions left here. The one is again on raw materials and the margin of Mercedes-Benz Cars. Maybe you can give us a figure of the headwind in Q4. Is there any headwind in the magnitude of &#x20AC;100 million, &#x20AC;200 million here? Or is it just going or coming into 2011?</p>
          <p>The other question is on incentives. Maybe you can give us here the incentive level in Q4? And how it's going to develop in 2011? What is your estimate here, and also on residual value development?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me start on incentives. You do understand, and we said the same in the past, that we cannot give you specific numbers in this regard because they are of course highly competitive.</p>
          <p>But we had set ourself a very aggressive target for 2010 in the reduction of percentage points of the incentives. And we have over-achieved this target. And we had not any different developments within the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>When you look at the published or observed number, for instance, yes, you will see that we have, according to these third-party reports, decreased our incentive spending significantly, and more than our direct competitors. So this is one indication about the overall development.</p>
          <p>Of course, this is a competitive marketplace. And of course, it will continue to be one. But we have been very successful, not the least &#x2013; in reducing incentives &#x2013; not the least because of our general policy that our margins and our profits are more important to us than the absolute volumes.</p>
          <p>Specifically in the U.S. for instance, you have seen that 'til November, we were leading in sales towards both of our competitors, or if you include Lexus, basically against all three. And on purpose, I mandated our Head of Sales in the U.S. that we will not come in first at the end of the year, because I knew what that would lead to. And I left this game to our competitors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your question regarding residual values &#x2013; situation is stable and good. We have, in the U.S., one of the best situations we had compared to the past, and there is no reason to &#x2013; that this situation should change.</p>
          <p> Same as that we have a stable development also regarding passenger cars in Germany. Same holds true for Trucks in comparison to the year 2009. We have further stabilizations also there.</p>
          <p>So all in all, from the residual value side, I don't see risk either &#x2013; not for Trucks but also not for passenger cars.</p>
          <p>You assumed a couple of hundred millions, I do think, in raw materials in fourth quarter. I don't want to go now to in specifics here of discussing here in millions, but it was not a three digit number which was going into the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next in line is Philippe J. Houchois.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just a quick question &#x2013; a couple of questions. One is, I was surprised to see you listed currency as a headwind potentially in '11. It was almost neutral in '10. Can you clarify a bit, what the currency effect was coming from for '11?</p>
          <p>And then for Mr. Renschler is on the Truck side in the U.S, do you see any reason, any bottlenecks, potentially that would actually prevent you from ramping up production to the level that we're starting to see in terms &#x2013; if we start annualizing orders, we're looking at 300,000 plus at this stage. Is the supply base able to cope with that increase? And is your organization able to cope with that kind of increase, if you &#x2013; if the actual market is above your current forecast?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Philippe, on your first question, of course, we commented this morning of course on the risk of the volatility of currencies, which we have to take into account if they occur.</p>
          <p>The currency duration is, at the level we are trading right now, we don't see a headwind for 2011 compared to 2010 from the currency side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So far the risk camp.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your truck-related question, so far, we see no major issue in the supply chain &#x2013; also in all flexibility in the production &#x2013; when it follows more or less our market forecast.</p>
          <p>We have to manage some of the suppliers already in a little bit more detail, but we are very confident and we saw no shortage so far. And we have a good relationship with the suppliers, work very close together with them, so I'm pretty sure we can handle also a higher market demand like we forecast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, do you have -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our own flexibility is fine. We have full production in Mexico already. We have hired some new people also in Saltillo, our new plant. So we have now stretched out there all our possibilities. So it will come into production beginning of February.</p>
          <p>The next increase we will see, like we announced then in Mount Holly, for our mid-size &#x2013; middle &#x2013; medium truck, the business class. And then we have then to hire there some people for &#x2013; to follow the demand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay. Do you have to provide financing to some of the suppliers to help them ramp up or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we are working, like I said, very good together with suppliers, and we don't have to spend any other money or something. We have reserved the production rate that we have in our mind very early.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next in line is Ranjit Unnithan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Ranjit Unnithan at J.P. Morgan. Thanks for taking my questions. I have a few.</p>
          <p>First, in terms of free cash flow for 2011, you will be paying about &#x20AC;2 billion in dividends this year. You have ramped up your CapEx from &#x20AC;3.7 billion to &#x20AC;5 billion. Do you think you will be &#x2013; your free cash flow will be greater than &#x20AC;2 billion, i.e., greater than your dividend that you're going to pay?</p>
          <p>Second, related to that, you &#x2013; well, you have about &#x20AC;12 billion of cash right now. And I think in the past you've said you'd be comfortable going to a much lower level of cash. So again, thoughts about cash relative to what is an optimal capital structure.</p>
          <p>And then in terms of your &#x2013; you've refrained from giving a margin outlook for your respective divisions. Can you explain why? And &#x2013; because you seem to be suggesting that you're pretty comfortable with Mercedes margins not declining. Can you not give us a &#x2013; some thoughts on where margins could be, particularly for Trucks and for Cars, in 2011?</p>
          <p>And I guess my last question is on China. You sound confident about I guess a more moderate level of growth in China going forward. But could you tell us how that growth in your volumes is going to be in 2011, if you had to split it between import and joint venture? Will, for instance, will about 80% of that growth in volumes this year come from JV? Or is it more likely to be sort of a 50-50 split? Some direction there would be helpful? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps I can start with the last point and then Bodo will take over.</p>
          <p>We have been in 2010 in a ratio of about 30% local production and 70% import. We intend to go rather to a ratio of about 50-50 in 2011.</p>
          <p>We are not &#x2013; we do not plan to give you our 2011 overall volume number as the sales forecast. And therefore, I can't give you our specific growth related to locally produced and imported cars. But you can see by the ratio change which I mentioned, that the locally produced vehicle will play a much more important role than in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ranjit, your question regard free cash flow, the answer is yes &#x2013; what you stated and I already commented this this morning. Our free cash flow should be significantly higher than the dividend payout in 2011. And that of course that this &#x2013; it's a positive news, I do think.</p>
          <p>That might add also then on the net liquidity side. Net liquidity is at &#x20AC;11.9 billion. Of course it's a high number, but I also commented this morning we have to take into account that we have also a pension debt of &#x20AC;6.5 billion on the one hand.</p>
          <p>And on the other hand, I do think the volatility in the market is not yet away. There are certain risks outside, which something &#x2013; sometimes are popping up. Hopefully we can &#x2013; they will not occur, no doubt. And then of course, we have to look into our net cash.</p>
          <p>But I do think that long-term, spoken also, if we would add and add on the net liquidity side in that scenario, I do think also payout ratio could change, which we currently having said is 40%. But of course, we will review once in a while, if the good situation will carry on. Currently the base case is in that line, but I do think it's again too early now to talk about any specifics regarding the net liquidity.</p>
          <p>The margin, the targets, we have announced our margin targets with 2013. I don't want to repeat them. They are at benchmark levels, these margin targets. And we have decided not to give guidance for the divisions in 2010 &#x2013; '11 &#x2013; as we have also announced it at the third quarter. Because we do think that we are now in a more sustainable mode in &#x2013; to further work on our long-term margins. We've given you a Daimler guidance, and that's it &#x2013; first for this day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next in line is Stephen Reitman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. It's Stephen Reitman, calling from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. The question really about your ability to predict your results. Obviously a year ago, your guidance that you gave for the group level was &#x20AC;2.3 billion, which of course you must have exceeded with &#x20AC;7.3 billion you've reported this year.</p>
          <p>By the time we got to the third quarter, when you're guiding over &#x20AC;7 billion, it seems that you are now &#x2013; and you reported a figure which is very much in line with that guidance. You seem now to have had much better ability to predict the fourth quarter than maybe you predicted the quarters that will be coming before that. Do you feel now you have much better visibility on your business, and obviously particularly on China? As that seems really the wild card between a year ago and where we are today.</p>
          <p>And secondly, if you could give some information as well about what's been happening on that provisioning for warranty. As you mentioned that you had lower accounts and lower accrual for product warranties, and what impact that had in the fourth quarter. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I understood very little from your question. I'm sorry for that. And when I'm looking to the faces of my colleagues, it's not that much different.</p>
          <p>As far as visibility is concerned, I think it's fair to say that the overall forecast channel GDP development and so on in 2010, by all participants in that game, was very volatile.</p>
          <p>So, nobody forecasted a 3.7% increase in GDP in Germany or many other of these elements. And in accordance to that, we had to increase our guidance three times last year and now we have somewhat beaten the last guidance we gave. We expect 2011 to be a year which follows somewhat more the expectation of January, as you do. If 2011, as far as the boundary conditions would develop totally different than all of us think right now, obviously it would have an impact on us as well. So, within the given environment, I think we have very good transparency of what our business is doing, what our costs are doing, what our market shares are doing.</p>
          <p>But we do not &#x2013; more than you do as far as the general economic developments are concerned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We take the next question from Jose Asumendi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Jose Asumendi, RBS. Three items, please. The first one on Trucks. I was wondering if you could talk a bit about the pricing environment you're seeing both in Europe and North America and whether you can actually, as Bodo said, of price increases in 2011. And order intake, I think the order intake in North America was impressive on the Truck side. Could you just comment whether you &#x2013; the current run rate will continue into 2011. And Latin America the same, it was sequentially down Q4 versus Q3, whether you are starting to see the market taking off slightly or will it continue on a high level?</p>
          <p>Second item on Mercedes Cars, if you could please provide some guidance in terms of production rates for the first quarter of '11. Just the directionally, should it be down or up versus the fourth quarter? And I guess the last question for Dr. Zetsche, I'm just thinking about the intrinsic value of the Truck business and you obviously have everything aligned. You've got &#x2013; you have restructured the operations and you have probably two very good years of strong demand in Europe and U.S.</p>
          <p>Now if you would manage to hit your margin target for the Truck business over the next years, but still the share price would not reflect the proper value for the Truck business at least in line with your peers, will you simply continue to ignore the situation or would you consider other steps to strike the real value for your shareholders? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the production rate at Mercedes is concerned, we have seasonally obviously less days in the first quarter than in the fourth quarter and on that basis, the production is always and every year lower on the first quarter. But we're basically hitting all cylinders and for choosing the max volume out of our existing capacity and therefore, we are seeing a strong demand throughout the world and we definitely will have considerably higher volume in the first quarter of this year than we had in 2010.</p>
          <p>As far as your Truck related question is concerned, our first job and we said that all the time, is to put Daimler Trucks into a position of benchmark performance. I have various times explained why I am convinced that strategically it's a good thing for Daimler to be active in Trucks and to passenger cars. When the scenario as you described it would appear, we can deal with that, but let's cross the bridge when we're getting there, in case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your other questions, when we look to the pricing for next &#x2013; last year it was very successful in the United States. We could put through the higher prices for EPA '010 very successful and its accepted in the market and the same is more or less here in Europe.</p>
          <p>In Europe we had a little bit still some issues there because some customers were used to some of the discounts in the year 2009, when some of our competitors had to give up there some special discount. So, we are there in a, yeah, a situation where we try to put the full pricing again through but we're on a good track. So basically last year it was &#x2013; we were able to achieve this.</p>
          <p>This year we are looking into the raw material situation of course, basically in the second half-year and we have to look what kind of a price increase is possible. It depends a little bit on the market development. If the market development is as high as we forecasted or maybe a little bit higher, then I think we have a good chance to put also some additional prices that may come based on some raw materials, through.</p>
          <p>Your question about order intake, as I said before, the run rate of the order intake in the United States is as good as in December and by the way, when we're making market forecast we're always talking about the market 6 to 8. So, if you are comparing it to other things in 8 &#x2013; in the Class 8 specifically could be a little bit higher already. But combine 6 to 8, it's still this 25%. Also in Brazil, the New Year started very good and so our forecast is that the market will be more or less on the same level in 2010 and the order intake shows us that this is still valid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next in line is Charles Winston.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi good afternoon Charles Winston from Redburn Partners. Pretty much all my questions have been asked. I just have one left, which in relation to labor costs. Can you just remind us the current status of your current major labor agreements in terms of wages &#x2013; what sort of inflation we should be expecting for this year? And when the current major agreements expire, in other words when they're due for renegotiation with the unions? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we are if you want in the comfortable position as far as labor is concerned, that in Germany which is not our main market but our main employment source, we have a labor contract which is valid through March 2012. So, on that basis we do not expect any unexpected developments in this parameter. We have used the flexibility in this contract, which of course did not reflect a very positive development of the overall economy. We have used the flexibility in the sense of putting the increase in place two months earlier than necessary if you want, but that's obviously a one-time effect. So the base is solid and stable for 2011 in Germany.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question we take from Alexis Albert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. This is Alexis Albert, from Nomura. I have two quick questions. The first one is, you spoke about the raw material impact of &#x20AC;700 million. I would like to know if it's the gross impact or the net impact. And related to this question, I would like to get your view on more generally, what is the ability of the industry and the ability of Mercedes to pass on the price &#x2013; you know, to pass on the increase of input costs to final customers? What I mean input costs, I mean raw material, salaries, so what is the pricing power of the industry? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Alexis, the first answer is net &#x2013; it's net &#x2013; the net impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And regarding -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know what you mean between gross or net, this does not mean that this is a net bill of material development. This is one element between content and negotiation results and technical, continuous improvement to reduce costs on the materials side, efficiency &#x2013; all of that, but as far as raw materials is concerned, this is the net effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But how much do you intend to pass on to end customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, of course the plan is to pass all to end customers and then there is the market and the markets are sometimes tell you that it was a nice try. So, but I told you as well that last year we were able to reduce our discount significantly and our plan is to continue that path. Again, depending on the overall market conditions of course and on the list pricing, you will see what we might do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the last question today we have from Adam Hull, WestLB.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, two questions on Trucks and then one just clarification on cash flow. Mr. Renschler, firstly just on Brazil, I mean you talked about the overall market but obviously you've got your new plant coming on stream, I think as a final capacity of 15,000. Can you give us some idea as to how much you could potentially produce in 2011? Just give us some idea of sort of the revenue you might be able to get in terms of growth for 2011, even in a flat market.</p>
          <p>And then just secondly, on the Trucks side, it just seems to me since the 30th of the November, you are at least mildly more confident. Is that a right read? Is that a read on the top line? Are you more comfort on the margin side as well? Then just a clarification on the free cash flow, you talk about in the net automotive liquidity, just what might happen on &#x2013; or give us some guidance on the working capital potentially quite a big move there. I think, Mr. Uebber, you were saying that in Q4 you had expected quite a big working capital outflow, wasn't as bad as that. Is that just being delayed into 2011 that outflow? If you could give us some guidance would be great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's start with your Truck questions, first the Brazilian question. Indeed we are increasing capacity because now we are putting the Juiz de Fora, the former car plant into our network and we cannot utilize this 100% this year because we have to redo a lot of different kind of equipment there, paint shop starting because you know the paint shop for a big truck is somehow a little bit bigger than for car, so we have to do something.</p>
          <p>So we utilize this capacity as much as it's possible, hopefully between 4,000 to 5,000 units and that's the reason we are very confident. If the market stays like it is, maybe a little bit lower but basically like it is, we can gain some market share in addition because we have no capacity constraints at least in this dimension, I have described.</p>
          <p>Second, when you look to the market forecast and also some of our margin development of course, we're not only couple of months older than November, but the risk of double dips or some issues are much smaller. There is more or less, we can see that the market development is going in the right direction and also our development. So, to answer it very shortly, yes, I'm more confident.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could I just ask, I mean is that more confident on the top line, you are saying you are more confident in top line. Is that also on the margin side, on the pricing developments, just in general terms as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your question regarding cash flow, I do think, yes, we will see in 2011 some increase in the inventories and other working capital elements. Finally, the equation, as I said before, is how accounts payable are developing &#x2013; that it can be on one case and you look at the 31st always can be a negative but also a positive. All in all, I do expect the free cash flow including this kind of volatility will be significantly higher than the dividend payout in 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you ladies and gentlemen. Thanks for your questions, for being with us today. Investor Relations remain at your disposal to answer any further questions you may have. We hope to talk to you again soon. Thanks and goodbye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>