<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1251454" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>885</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Dr. Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer, Senior Vice President, Head of Investor Relations &amp; Treasury</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Dr. Dieter Zetsche, Chairman and Head of Mercedes-Benz Cars</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Arndt Ellinghorst</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Andreas Renschler</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Bodo Uebber</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">John Lawson</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Horst Schneider</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Jochen Gehrke</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Christian Breitsprecher</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">John Buckland</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Kristina Church</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Adam Jonas</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Adam Hull</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Daniel Schwarz</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Thierry Huon</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Aleksej Wunrau</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Ranjit Unnithan</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Jose Asumendi</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="corprep">Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer, Senior Vice President, Head of Investor Relations &amp; Treasury</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Global Conference call of Daimler. At our customer's request, this conference will be recorded. The replay of the conference call along with presentation slides will be available as an on-demand audio webcast in the Investor Relations section of the Daimler website. The short introduction will be directly followed by a Q&amp;A session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>May I now hand over to Dr. Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer, Head of Daimler Investor Relations and Treasury? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. This is Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer speaking. On behalf of Daimler, I would like to welcome you to our Full Year Presentation. We are very happy to have with us today the Chairman of the Board of Management and Head of Mercedes-Benz Cars, Dr. Dieter Zetsche;, the CFO, Bodo Uebber, and the Head of Daimler Trucks, Andreas Renschler.</p>
          <p>In order to give you maximum time for your questions, Dr. Zetsche will begin with a short introduction directly followed by Q&amp;A. Before we start, I have a couple of admin details.</p>
          <p>I would like to remind you that this call is governed by the Safe Harbor wording that you will find in our published documents. Please note that our presentations contain forward-looking statements reflecting management's current views with respect to future events. These forward-looking statements can be identified by expressions like assume, anticipate, believe, estimate, expect, intend, may, plan, project and should.</p>
          <p>These statements are subject to many risks and uncertainties, examples of which are set out in the Safe Harbor wording in our documents and are also described in our most recent Form 20-F under the heading Risk Factors. If the assumptions underlying any of these statements prove incorrect, then actual results may be materially different from those expressed or implied by these statements. Forward-looking statements speak only to the date they are made.</p>
          <p>Now, I would like to hand over to Dr. Zetsche.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Michael. Ladies and gentlemen, good afternoon, and welcome to our analysts and investors call. I would like to start with a very brief summary of our results. In economic terms, 2009 was the most challenging year of the recent decade. This is also reflected in our result. Although we improved from quarter-to-quarter, our EBIT was minus 1.5 billion for 2009 and our net profit was even lower at minus 2.6 billion.</p>
          <p>Given this unusual situation, the Board of Management has proposed to the Supervisory Board, by way of exception, that Daimler refrain from paying any dividends for the past business year. This proposal reflects only the business developments and the earnings situation in 2009, does not have any implications for our business expectations for the current year. You can assume that we will once again pay a dividend for the business year 2010.</p>
          <p>Although our figures for 2009 were disappointing, it's clear that 2009 was not a lost year for Daimler. Because of the past year, we became significantly more efficient. Even though the markets remained weak, we increased our sales as the year progressed particularly in the fourth quarter. Above all, we've introduced measures that will enable us not only to successfully cope with the long-term transformation of our sector but also to shape it from a leading position.</p>
          <p>Last year, at our annual press conference I said that we wanted to improve our performance quarter-by-quarter. We have kept this promise. In the third quarter, we returned to profitability, and in the fourth quarter, we further improved our ongoing business operation.</p>
          <p>At Mercedes-Benz Cars, full-year EBIT decreased from positive 2.1 billion to minus 0.5 billion. Our Car division continuously improved its earnings during the year and returned to profitability in the second half of 2009. This positive development was primarily based on the market success of the E-Class and S-Class. Our new E-Class in particular, is a big success. In fact, in 2009, the sedan was the world market leader by far. In Germany, our market share was 56%, in Western Europe it was 31% and in the US, it was 26%.</p>
          <p>EBIT at Daimler Trucks fell from the prior year's positive 1.6 billion to minus 1 billion. Due to the sharp drop in unit sales, in view of the prevailing environment, we believe that this was a very respectable result. Our efficiency enhancing measures had increasing effects at Daimler Trucks as well in the course of the year.</p>
          <p>Operating profitability stabilized in the second half of the year, although it was still slightly negative. Still, there has been a noticeable upswing here as well, compared to the first half of the year, incoming orders increased by 59% in the second half.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to Mercedes-Benz Vans. In the two relevant markets experienced a massive decline in our Vans division, even though gaining market share, could impact the general market trend. Nevertheless, Mercedes-Benz Vans were in the black in 2009. EBIT totaled &#x20AC;26 million for the full year. Thanks to cost adjustment and the slight pick-up in demand, Mercedes-Benz Vans reached breakeven in the third quarter. In the fourth quarter, we earned &#x20AC;126 million, more than compensating for the losses we sustained in the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>While Buses were somewhat less affected by the economic crisis, Daimler Buses was in the black in the each quarter of the year. The Daimler Buses division posted EBIT of &#x20AC;183 million for the full year. No other bus manufacturer in the world was more profitable than Daimler in 2009.</p>
          <p>Daimler Financial Services achieved the breakeven point with EBIT of 9 million in 2009. The higher cost of risk was the main reason for the decrease, compared to 2008. Although the number of credit defaults increased, the total number remained within the anticipated range. Our risk management policies are working.</p>
          <p>These upward trends are confirmed by the development of the free cash flow from our Industrial business operations, which benefited from our successful management of working capital and strict cost discipline. Free cash flow from Industrial business increased from minus 3.9 billion in 2008 to plus 2.7 billion last year. In total, the net liquidity of our Industrial business operations increased from 3.1 billion at the end of 2008 to 7.3 billion at the end of 2009.</p>
          <p>To sum up, as unsatisfactory as our figures for the year as a whole are, we definitely picked up momentum in the course of 2009. At the same time, we never lost sight of our long-term strategic target. On the basis of our strategy for profitable growth, we have defined four levers for 2010. First, leading products and brands; second, pioneering technologies and business models; third, new markets and networks and fourth, continuing efficiency gains. All of these are based on a common foundation of highly performing and highly motivated employees.</p>
          <p>What does this mean in concrete terms? Leading products and brands are essential components of an explicit premium strategy, which is exactly the strategy we are pursuing at Mercedes-Benz Cars. There are automobile commodities, and there's Mercedes. One of our new models illustrates that in a very special way, the SLS AMG, which for many people is the ultimate dream car. It's certainly one of the automotive highlights of the year. But the SLS is by no means the only example of leading products that bear the Mercedes star.</p>
          <p>In the next 24 months, we will launch a total of 16 new Mercedes-Benz models. They include the new CLS, the new S-Class Coupe, and the most fuel efficient and cleanest S-Class of all time, a luxury sedan with a four cylinder engine. As a result, we expect to further boost our prospects for sales growth. In fact, at Mercedes-Benz Cars, we aim to sell around 1.5 million vehicles worldwide annually by 2015.</p>
          <p>Top performance is also the ultimate goal at Trucks, Vans, and Buses. However, the attributes that ensure top performance here are somewhat different from those in the passenger car segment. Whether or not a truck is regarded by customers as fascinating is mainly decided by its total cost of ownership and its reliability. Accordingly, Daimler Trucks can be relied on to be the top performers in these categories for freights transporters.</p>
          <p>Our second strategic lever is pioneering technologies and business models. For decades, we have been leading the way forward in quality technology. We aim to play the same role in the area of sustainable mobility, and we have a clear strategy for achieving our goal. We're optimizing combustion engines. We're supplementing them with hybrid-drives and we're developing and producing fully electric vehicles that are locally emission-free, built with battery powered electric drive, or with fuel cells.</p>
          <p>In all of these areas, we are making very good progress. In 2009, we reduced our Mercedes-Benz Cars fleet emissions by 13 grams to 160 grams. And we continue to forge ahead here. For example, the new six and eight cylinder engines scheduled for launch in 2010 will consume up to 25% less fuel than their respective predecessors.</p>
          <p>We aim to reduce our average fleet CO2 emissions to less than 140 grams by 2012, which will not only meet legislative requirements, but actually exceed them. Naturally, our long-term goal remains zero emission driving, and we are making progress here as well. Since the end of 2009, Smart brand electric vehicles have been proving themselves on a daily-use basis in Berlin.</p>
          <p>Still, there are two major hurdles to electric mobility based on fuel cells and batteries. For drive systems powered exclusively by batteries, it's the performance of the energy storage unit, as well as its price. And for both battery powered vehicles and fuel cells drives, it's the establishment of an appropriate infrastructure. We're addressing both issues, and we're doing so in collaboration with strong partners.</p>
          <p>Let me give you just a few examples. Together with Evonik, we are now building Europe's biggest factory for lithium-ion batteries in the city of Kamenz in the German state of Saxony. We're also working with Linde and other partners to set up a hydrogen filling station network in Germany. Together with energy suppliers such as RWE and Enel, we are working hard to establish charging stations for battery-powered vehicles. In addition, partnerships like these make it possible to increase the expertise at our disposal by sharing the huge costs associated with the development of green technology.</p>
          <p>Daimler alone invests well over &#x20AC;4 billion in research and development every year. It therefore goes without saying that we are determined to ensure that every cent spent will be spent wisely. That's why we don't just develop green technology. We also make it profitable. For example, through large-scale modularization. Our commitment here will pay off in the end. No other automaker is as well-positioned across the entire range of sustainable drive systems as Daimler.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to turn to our third strategic lever, new market and networks. As you know, the automotive sector's growth is shifting from the drives to emerging markets. The economic crisis has actually reinforced this strategy. The Chinese market in particular, continued to grow in 2009. At 65%, retail sales growth of the Mercedes-Benz brand outpaced that of all other premium manufacturers for the third year in a row. To ensure that this trend continues, we will launch the extended wheel-base version of E-Class in the Chinese market in July.</p>
          <p>We also plan to gain additional market share in the U.S., whereas in China we are expanding our sales network. And we realigned our global production network for passenger cars in 2009. Our plant in Tuscaloosa, Alabama will begin manufacturing the C-Class in 2014. We will build more C-Class and E-Class models in China in the future. We laid the cornerstone for our plant in Kecskemet, Hungary, where we will build the successor models of the A-Class and the B-Class in a production network with Rastatt, Germany.</p>
          <p>Daimler Trucks opened a new plant in Saltillo, Mexico last year. We have intensified our cooperation in Russia with the truck manufacturer KAMAZ, in which we increased our financial stake a week ago today. We are making progress in India as well, where we are building a new truck plant in Chennai.</p>
          <p>All of this shows that we are not cutting back when it comes to safeguarding the future. In fact, even at the height of the financial economic crisis, we didn't cut back. That's why it's all the more important that we control our current costs.</p>
          <p>For this reason our fourth strategic lever, focusing on continuing efficiency gain. Several of the measures that enabled us to cut costs in 2009 will be phased out in 2010. One example is the reduction in working hours, which will be discontinued on June 30, 2010. We also plan to significantly scale back short-time work in passenger car units, and completely eliminate them wherever market conditions allow it.</p>
          <p>As the impact of such short-term measures becomes weaker, other measures aimed at achieving permanent savings will first take full effect in 2010. Our goal remains to continue moving forward in this area. Responsibility to do so remains squarely in our individual business areas, which continue to vigorously pursue improvements through existing strategies, such as Go For 10 at Mercedes-Benz Cars and Global Excellence at Daimler Trucks.</p>
          <p>The question now is exactly what type of business developments do we expect to see in 2010. According to the latest forecasts of leading institutes, the global economy could grow by nearly 3% this year. It also appears possible that global Passenger Car markets will expand by 3 to 4%. The premium segment is expected to grow faster than the overall market. Because we didn't have a credit brokerage high in 2009, we don't have to worry about a hangover in 2010.</p>
          <p>What do we expect for Daimler? At Mercedes-Benz Cars, we expect to see both a slight increase in sales and a higher profit margin. EBIT will probably total more than 1.5 billion. At Daimler Trucks, we also expect a slight increase in sales even though the underlying level will be low in absolute terms. Together with decreasing costs and the initial positive effects of the realignment of our business activities in North America, and Asia, we expect this to yield EBIT of approximately &#x20AC;200 million.</p>
          <p>Positive sales trends that began in Mercedes-Benz Vans in mid-2009 will continue. From today's perspective, EBIT should total around 250 million. Expected sales growth at Buses will probably be driven primarily by market in Latin America. 2010 we therefore, expect EBIT is again about 100 million &#x2013; 180 million.</p>
          <p>Finally, at Daimler Financial Services, we anticipate stable development of the division's global contract volume and EBIT of at least &#x20AC;350 million. We expect the Group as a whole to record EBIT of more than &#x20AC;2.3 billion from our ongoing business operations.</p>
          <p>Now, Bodo Uebber, Andreas Renschler and I will be happy to answer your questions. Thank you for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dr. Zetsche. Ladies and gentlemen, you may ask your questions now. I will identify the questioner by name, but please also introduce yourself with your name and the name of the organization before asking your question.</p>
          <p>Two practical points, firstly, please avoid using mobile phones and secondly, please ask your question in English. Before we start the session, the operator will explain the procedure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. First in line we have Arndt Ellinghorst, please. Arndt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks a lot. Well, I mean, something's obviously gone wrong today with your market cap dropping by 2 billion in the course of the day despite I think, a relatively good final quarter of the year. So, I wonder if you could share your thought, what that is? What could have gone wrong? I think we all would like to hear some more details on your guidance after you've been reporting an adjusted EBIT margin at Mercedes in particular, around about 6% in the second half last year. And if we assume your revenues increase by 10% let's say for 2010, your guidance appears to go for a margin of only three to 3.5% or something for Mercedes. Are we getting something completely wrong here in the market? Is there something on pricing, on mix or on other external factors maybe that we're getting wrong, is the first question?</p>
          <p>And then also secondly, what does your guidance imply for free cash flow for the full year? You haven't mentioned that. You've generated quite some cash, so could you please talk a bit about working capital trends and cash flow for the full year? And then also finally, Mr. Renschler, maybe could you talk a bit about trucks and your guidance for roughly 200 million of profit and what volume assumptions are you using really? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you very much for the questions. The first question, I actually would like to return back to you because I would kind of agree with you that operationally our fourth quarter was not bad given the environment we're working in.</p>
          <p>And certainly, the market did not expect &#x2013; or I guess the market did not expect the announcement of no dividend for 2009, even though if you could say just technically it's totally inconsistent with our long lasting policy of paying 40% of our profit as dividend. And with no profits, this leads to no dividend, including confirming the clear intention to pay a dividend for 2010 and 2011. But anyway, that's certainly an issue we probably will discuss further during the conference today, the reaction of the market today.</p>
          <p>The guidance for next year. First of all, at least to my best knowledge, the market consensus for 2010 is above but only slightly above the guidance we gave for Mercedes-Benz Cars, give and take 200 million, or something like that.</p>
          <p>Secondly, I have not recorded a 6% operating margin in the second half of 2009. My recall is roughly 3% and 5.3% in the third and the fourth quarter, 3.5 and 5.3. So, when we are talking about -, depending on the revenue assumption you are making &#x2013; 1.5 billion EBIT as the guidance to be passed, we guessed more than 1.5 billion, this is obviously again, it's, depending on the assumption on revenues, something at the high end of 3% to a little less than 4% margin, and not totally out of line of the average of the last two quarters. There are some negative effects which we can see going forward, that certainly exchange rates add a relevant element.</p>
          <p>That is certainly a development of our labor costs, clearly, not in the first half but in the second half of the year. And quite frankly, we have a growing content of CO2 reducing technology in our vehicles as well, as we were discussing all the time. I think, at least, it was not our habit in the past and not too many competitors were confident enough to give a guidance for 2010 in specific numbers. We did that without just moving the guidance further out, I would at least say that it could not have been our intention to stretch to the maximum by giving this guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Arndt. Of course, I can talk a little bit about Trucks. We can also talk two hours about Trucks, but I will make it shorter. As you know, we gave some guidance when you look to the overall market situation there. In Europe, we see a slightly higher market than 2009. Basically, we will see this from my point of view in the second half, more in the second half of the year than in the first. And after reaching these between 10 and 15%, in Japan, we see it more or less on the level of 2009. In Brazilian market we see also some growth in the dimension of 10 to 15%. And in also in Southeast Asia, driven by Indonesia, and some other countries, there will be also some potential for an upswing in the market.</p>
          <p>And as you know, if you calculate our, let's say market shares given, of course, there will be some small increase, but it was basically a very good market share in the different markets. We can count the volume out of this forecast from the market. So, the major effect on our guidance for the EBIT is more or less coming out of the restructuring program and a slight improvement also in the volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And could you &#x2013; could Mr. Uebber maybe make some statements on cash flow? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will, Arndt. On the cash flow side, of course, we are running &#x2013; we think now, looking back in 2009, we had a &#x2013; the cash flow was pretty good developing. We worked on the inventories. We worked on the working capital, and even in the fourth quarter we put &#x2013; we could achieve a positive free cash flow, which was good and net liquidity went up end of '09.</p>
          <p>We all know that we have worked a lot on the inventories, and we are all done with the inventories. So, that in 2010, the subject of inventories is &#x2013; again, we are looking at everything and there might be an opportunity in growth from work in process inventories, for example, but of course, it's not the amount we have taken out in 2009.</p>
          <p>We will invest into technology, product technologies and also, growth in future markets, for example, in China for trucks. India, we have started our operations there. So, that is, of course, something which we will further invest in 2010, of course. But with the understanding we do that very disciplined and very focused. As Bodo Uebber also mentioned it in the calls and we have faced something also in 2009 from an efficiency point of view. So, how much could we get out from one euro of investment? On top, we have year six to fulfill. We have already addressed this, also in 2009, in the truck business.</p>
          <p>Of course, against, against this we will hold on with our now increase in units sales, the increase in revenues and to offset as much as possible. We do know how important cash flow is. We have seen that also if 2009. And on that basis of course, we go in 2010, as I said, to focus on the cash flow management. You can be rest assured that we will do so also in 2010. But I would like to leave it open right now where we end up with that management.</p>
          <p>The second &#x2013; of course, a fourth question, I do think which you have not raised, Arndt, but I will immediately tell this in markets, the dividend. Of course, you have not mentioned it. We have discussed our operational performance, of course, also with regard to net profit in 2009, and you know the number is negative. It was 2.6 billion and of course, we discussed this, the amount &#x2013; and we know that our payout ratio is, it's 40%. We have addressed it last 2008 with 40%. And we have decided to pay another dividend, which is not our expectation for 2010. For 2010, we expect definitely with our guidance of 2.3 billion in EBIT that we pay again a dividend also for the upcoming years.</p>
          <p>There's a second subject with the dividends and that refers to the local GAAP of Daimler AG. The number you do not know yet we will disclose it at the 1st of March. The number will be not better than the 2.6 billion, that I can tell you and the issue is a following that you can only distribute dividend on retained earnings. The retained earnings in our local balance sheet is 5 billion. And with the dividend of &#x2013; with paying no dividend we can book the loss in the local German balance sheet against the capital reserves, so not against the retained earnings.</p>
          <p>That means we can keep our retained earnings level of 5 billion for the future.</p>
          <p>And of course &#x2013; but that is only possible if we have no dividend payout. We can only do this legally, according to the law when we pay out no dividend that we book the local loss against the capital reserves.</p>
          <p>So you can now imagine with 5 billion of retained earnings having in mind for the future that we have a high flexibility in this regard and I do think that's very important to know for you, that for the future. And we are sure that we are delivering earnings, that we are in the possibility to let's say to go on with our dividend philosophy and even have a flexibility to be &#x2013; do even a bit more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think we understand that. It would just have been helpful maybe to get some earlier warning from you, because it was pretty obvious already in the course of last year that you will book a quite significant loss. That's maybe all I can say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll keep that in mind, of course, hopefully now into the positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I hope we will have no needs to learn from that lesson and I hope this won't occur again. But clearly the point is taken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Arndt. Next question we take from John Lawson, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, John Lawson at Citi. There's quite a big gap between the EBIT and net income line, especially in the fourth quarter. And the area of that that I wanted to ask you to particularly explore is the financial &#x2013; the interest income and financial income line. Can you give us a clue as to what the current level of pension rollover less the plan return is actually running at?</p>
          <p>And secondly, on that line, I guess you're carrying an awful lot of excess liquidity at the moment. I think I heard you this morning talk about it as if it was around eight billion. I mean, what do you regard as the interest burden penalty that is occasioning you at the moment? And how quickly can we hope to see that roll off? That's one question.</p>
          <p>The second question is well, firstly, I'm glad to hear that you're going to pay out 5 billion from the domestic company reserves in the future to shareholders. Does this &#x2013; does what might happen at EADS have any significant bearing on the level of reserves that might be in that domestic company? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John to your answer to your last question is a no. So, there should not be an impact to that. Of course, I'm happy that you mentioned the 5 billion, of course, has a potential to impact, but I know &#x2013; but I have understood what with you meant with this. Your first question, what is the &#x2013; between EBIT and net profit. It's &#x2013; so I go through, we have the interest on pensions is roughly 300 million. We will disclose this number at the 1st of March, but it's roughly 300 million. The interest cost on liquidity on excess liquidity on the one hand, but also liquidity for let's say for working capital, so to say, but we need liquidity for running all the legal entities. This together &#x2013; all in all is 500 million negative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So and the remaining part is 350 million roughly for tax expenses. So, starting with the taxes, in the tax expenses, we booked for the whole year in the fourth quarter. We made a review of our tax assets and we did some write-offs in the amount of 0.7 billion in the fourth quarter, which is of course, a one-time subject what we do. And we will &#x2013; hard to think we will not see it again, of course, we see more expectations over the next couple of years.</p>
          <p>Within the liquidity of 500 million, I expect this within 2011 and'12 that we get down with this number to let's say zero and positive. Of course, it depends how far the markets will be stable &#x2013; financial markets. We can go down very fast of course, during the course of the year 2010 towards the 7 billion level. We can even &#x2013; I do speak about the gross liquidity. We can even go further down when we optimize it further. So, this level of liquidity is a question of time when we reduce it, of course, after we have some more stable situation in terms of questions like their peak countries, big countries or other subject. And as I said, if it is stable we run it down very fast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So at the moment you'd hold it probably through the first half, but you'd expect to run it down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Somewhat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question. We take Horst Schneider [HSBC].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Horst Schneider here from HSBC. Two questions if I may. First of all, it's regarding volume structure and net pricing. The walk-down that you provide also in your presentation, could you please be a bit more specific what was the development of net pricing in 2009? And to what you expect in terms of net pricing for 2010? And especially, if you expect for Mercedes costs, a positive impact from net pricing, or if you should rather go for stable or negative impact. And the direction that I'm heading for is I would be interested if Mercedes cost is prepared to sacrifice volumes in favor of higher prices.</p>
          <p>And the second question is regarding potential one-offs in 2010. Maybe could you provide a bit more guidance, what we can expect in terms of one-offs, especially what could be a special burdens related to EADS and related charges from the A400 project. And my question would be if you would book these charges also as special item? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps I can briefly refer to the net pricing development in relation to volume, and then hand over to Bodo. Development last year was highly negative in the beginning of 2009, very much related to excess inventories, especially on the high end of their portfolio. From there on, things developed more positively, especially in the second half of the year, and in particular, against the normal seasonality in the fourth quarter as well.</p>
          <p>Now applying that there to 2010, our clear intention is to have positive net pricing in 2010. We are having right now a situation where our dealers are accusing us of not enough supply, which is very good as far as pricing is concerned. So, directionally, yes. Or the other way around, we will not sacrifice our intent to improve pricing by our volume aspiration. That is not black and white, I have to say. Of course, markets have their rules, and we have to somewhat act in these markets. That is clear. But the prioritization is very clear. We want to recover the margin. At the same time, we want to grow, but not at any price, clearly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your question regarding EADS, of course, as I said, it also in the morning, I do expect that we have not too far from today that we have a result out of the negotiation, the first results, which makes it possible that we see ideas. And also, Daimler then, afterwards can book this special item, I would say, then into the 2009 books of Daimler too. And therefore, it's not an impact in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will be booked as a special reporting item, of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, and regarding other special items potentially in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there's only one minor &#x2013; two minor subjects. These are the follow-up restructuring charges for Peugeot repositioning program and Freightliner repositioning program. In total, it should be roughly 50 million for 2010. I'm not aware of anything else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next in line is Jochen Gehrke.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. Three questions, if I may. First of all, to Mr. Renschler, in Q4, the truck division didn't improve really, sequentially when I compare that to most of your competitors. That appears to be somewhat of a clear underperformance. I wonder whether you could shed some light on why that was the case in your view.</p>
          <p>Secondly, to Dr. Zetsche, we all followed the announcement that Mr. Bernhard is now taking over as a COO. I wonder whether you could just explain to us what you expect from Mr. Bernhard to perform, what to do differently that Mr. Schmerkler and what &#x2013; I read it correctly that the Brazilian plant has actually disappeared from your production network at least when I look at one of your presentations.</p>
          <p>And then thirdly, really on your guidance, a more broad question to your communication policy here. Over the last couple of quarters already, guidance of Daimler proved to be more of a flaw rather than a sense of reality, at least retrospectively. Is that the case again? Is that the feeling that we should take away? And seeing that your stock price is falling very heavily today, similar to what happened after the third quarter release, is that actually a policy that you might think to rethink? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your first question referring to Wolfgang Bernhard, at least technically, as we announced today or yesterday evening, he is responsible for production and procurement, plus his successor on the van side will report to him. So, he's formally not a COO, which anyway in Germany is not a very typical job to be held by anybody.</p>
          <p>But other than that, first of all, of course, I expect from Wolfgang Bernhard to continue successfully the improvement on the productivity side, and on the quality side we have seen in recent years. Beyond that, it's clear that this is prerequisite for any future success that we continue with maximum cost discipline. We are always guided by a benchmark consideration for the Mercedes operations.</p>
          <p>But at the same time, it's an old saying, you cannot save your way to prosperity. There are ultimately &#x2013; there are at least but every success of Mercedes will depend on great, exciting products, on strong development of the brand, and the aspiration our customers and prospects feel for the ownership of a Mercedes car. And that is the kind of spirit we have to instill throughout the organization.</p>
          <p>If you want, guided by the claim, the best or nothing, and on that basis, I am very much convinced that the team, being built between Johann Schmidt, Wolfgang Bernhard, and Stephan Engelt, and Thomas Weber and myself &#x2013; and I exclude myself now &#x2013; is the best team I can think of to pursue exactly this objective. And as part, as a member of this team, this describes the role of Wolfgang Bernhard as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just regarding your question -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, by the way, if the Brazilian plant disappeared from our horizon. This was a mistake. It's still there and still producing the CLT, as it did in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Mr. Gehrke, your car question, at least if you look for the result in the fourth quarter, we booked 75 million of SRE inside, so we are at ending at 149 million, if I calculating right. And at least it was what we promised in the &#x2013; at the third quarter. The reason is the following thing. We actually already said there is a different mix. We had a different mix in the third quarter. We have also &#x2013; and then in the third quarter we have also some exchange rate effect.</p>
          <p>In addition, we put some product-related provisions inside, nothing else than some conservative approaches in warranty and that was the last thing we did was some &#x2013; like you would, call it, clean-up in the inventory in some markets where we had still some trucks. Mainly in Eastern Europe, we had some depreciation also done there. It was the major reason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Guidance, certainly a very complex issue. First of all, we have decided to give specific guidance, which we thought should be perceived as our sign of confidence, and a feeling of strength on our side. But, of course, what we think and what we see might not always be the same. Secondly, I think we all agree that the volatility of the environment and the transparency of the future developments, the first one still being very high, the latter one still being very low.</p>
          <p>On that basis, certainly, you do not want to give the guidance and three months later, being forced to correct it downward. So, you want to find the right balance between an ambitious goal and a reasonable chance to deliver on your forecast. Now, certainly we can discuss, is it better to promise the blue of the sky and then say what do I give on what I said yesterday if you don't meet  it &#x2013; I put it on an extreme, of course &#x2013; and then have a positive reaction on the marketplace and afterwards perhaps the negative one if you can't meet it.</p>
          <p>I think that overall last year, our stock market performance was not that bad in comparison with our peers' either. As you said, we've started with kind of a slump on the stock market. But I'm open to discuss in more detail in the future what would be the right policy as far as guidance is concerned, how ambitious, how reliable, and we might come to different conclusions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Just maybe as a follow-up to that statement, the &#x20AC;1.5 billion guidance for Mercedes, do you see this as ambitious, or should we read this as a flaw?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me be quite frank and open. In fall last year, we are building up our operated plan. In that time, we would have seen that guidance as unachievable, quite simply. Since things have developed considerably more positive to quite an extent as a result of our own efforts to some extent based on external developments, which enabled us to give you this guidance today in February. So, in April, I might tell you that was a piece of cake or I might tell you only what we have said there, we shouldn't have said.</p>
          <p>I don't believe the latter one, clear. But I just want to ask for your understanding that in this environment, it's pretty difficult to give a very reliable forecast. We do &#x2013; we have said 1.5 billion because we intent to, and we are convinced that we can deliver on it, and this means there should been an upside as well. But I'm not willing, and not able in February, now to just a minute after we gave the guidance, start to correct it in what direction ever.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question we take from Christian Breitsprecher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Breitsprecher from Oppenheim. I have two questions, one related to the exchange rate headwinds. I'm a bit surprised that you talk about headwinds from that side, because I don't really see that. The dollar had made such moves that it would be a disadvantage for you in terms of average exchange rates. So, maybe you can explain that a little bit.</p>
          <p>And secondly, on your cost savings, I definitely understand that in 2009, you had acquired a few one-off cost savings that are not sustainable. On the other hand, there are a lot of cost savings that really will take their full effect in 2010. So, can you help us a little bit with the numbers? How much was one-off, and then in 2009? How much do we really get in terms of incremental cost savings in 2010? What is going to be the net effect, where we are somehow able to model that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as exchange rate is concerned, hopefully, you cannot just look at the spot market, because for good reason, we are hedged. And in 2009, certainly, we were successful in our hedging, which means that our exchange rate, effective exchange rate was better than what you could see on the spot market, which then makes obviously the comparison to 2010 more difficult. And on that basis, we have a very substantial three-digit million number in our plan, as happened in 2010. For good reason, we have not closed 2010. So, in case the spot markets are continuing to develop favorably, we will benefit from that, to which extent we know 31st of December, benefit versus this increase we had seen &#x2013; versus this headwind we are seeing right now, certainly not worse than 2009. I think that we can rule that out. Bodo will continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe also add on to the exchange rate, we should not forget that other than three to four weeks ago, we had 145, 148. So, the question is, okay, what kind of volatility do we see in the exchange rate? And I do think we should not make any conclusion, when right now the exchange rate is right now trading at 137, what is now for the next 11 months to go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the dollar is just one currency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The British pound, and so on have their impact as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's to your question of the sustainability of one-offs in the 5.3 billion, of course, we have &#x2013; I don't think we have told you the market also last year that we, of course, try to be better than 2009 in terms of efficiency, including one-offs, one-timers or sustainable measures.</p>
          <p>We have a lot of programs, which we started already a couple of years ago with the Go for 10, the modular strategy, we have implemented the repositioning programs in Freightliner and Peugeot. We have our national base organization strategy starting now in 2009, which will head into 2010 and 2011.</p>
          <p>So all of these measures are for to offset some of the one-offs we had in '08 or in '09. But I can also promise we will have one-timers also in 2010. Because we will not give up, so to say, in terms of savings also to save some of the stuff, one-time in 2010. But, it's a long-term strategy what we have, and so in the long run we will get to more and more efficiencies of course, over the years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next in line is John Buckland [MAN Securities], please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thank you. Just on that last question, maybe I wasn't listening and concentrating well enough. But, I mean, I don't think I got any real clue about what &#x2013; how to quantify these one-timers and the &#x2013; what's sustainable, and what's not sustainable.</p>
          <p>I mean, there must be &#x2013; it's implied &#x2013; if I were to say that you've made a profit in 2010 similar to the &#x2013; or margin in 2010 similar to the fourth quarter, it would imply that two or three billion of savings are given back in 2010. I wonder if you could just comment on that. Is it a number which is completely wrong or somewhere close or, perhaps you can give us an idea what's somewhere close.</p>
          <p>And then, on the Mercedes car division, and the expenditure you expect to increase in 2010 on R&amp;D and CapEx for a new model CO2, et cetera. I wonder if you could give us some figures for that, and perhaps where you think you're going to be with all of this expenditure. I mean how can you quantify or qualify your competitiveness versus BMW or Audi or anyone else? Because clearly, you've got to be catching up and that's leading to this higher expenditure now, but how much of an advantage are you going to get when this is finished, and when will that be finished?</p>
          <p>And then on the truck division, you talk about flat market and perhaps only really improvement in the second half. The order intake clearly improved a lot in the fourth quarter and other truck makers are saying the market will go up in 2010. But you're not so confident. I just wonder whether there's something happened in the order intakes of various companies in the first weeks of &#x2013; over the last weeks of 2009, first weeks of 2010, which are unusual, and such, suggest that as we progress through this year, that we won't see such a good order intake and indeed, the deliveries will show very weak growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps your CO2 question, in 2009, we have reduced our fleet emission average from 173 in 2008 to 160 in 2009. We don't have &#x2013; because these are still not the official numbers &#x2013; the numbers of our competitors, but we are very confident that we have improved the fastest in the field. We have already said that by 2012, we want to be below 140 per gram, and you should always bear in mind, that we will continue to sell a richer mix of vehicles and coming to our similar numbers means that per segment, we have to be better than our peers in order to come to these averages.</p>
          <p>On the legal side, this is recognized and of course, their weight is considered as a parameter to allow you for higher emissions. But at the end, you have one number, and then the number that does compare without the recognition of the different distribution of the fleet, which is okay.</p>
          <p>But that means we are very much convinced that for the fleet in average, but even more so for the individual vehicle &#x2013; think for instance, about an S Class with 3.2 liters fuel consumption, 100 kilometers and 350 horsepower, with all the safety and comfort, and so on, that you can expect from S-Class. We are absolutely confident that with these results, which are real, which we can drive today with the prototype, we will be in the lead in this race for CO2, which again &#x2013; and we have said that various times, has its impact not only on our one-time expenditure on R&amp;D and CapEx, but as much or as well on the variable cost of our vehicles, because the technology's not for free.</p>
          <p>And that's one element you have to consider as well, looking forward to 2010, coming to your first question, that beyond the exchange rate, the content of CO2 reducing technology in our cars is increasing, and thereby increasing our variable costs. We have talked various times that it's our task to offset that by reducing the cost for these technologies by offsetting it with further productivity gains, and by having the customer pay for some of it as well in order to reestablish our 10% margin target. But that is a path we have to go for, and not something we can accomplish from one day to the next.</p>
          <p>With that, I would like to ask Andreas to do a better job in explaining you why the market will not develop faster than he did when he tried to explain it to me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, I think I don't see any more conservative approaches in our market forecast in Europe. We said very clearly, we in Europe, we see higher than 2009, but slightly higher. And in NAFTA we see 10 to 15%. Japan, I would see flat. Growth, two-digit growth in Brazil, and some growth also expected in Southeast Asia. And all the order intakes we see now generally are also in fourth quarter, we commented. It's supporting this market forecast. There is no order intake that supports the market forecast now that are better 50% up, very clearly not. So, that's the reason we say okay, we see several chances to have a slight revision in the sales.</p>
          <p>If you look to the fourth quarter like I tried to explain already in the past, the fourth quarter was also driven specifically in NAFTA with some pre-buy effects between in EPA'07 and EPA '10. So, the delivery of this EPA '10 trucks will be let's say going through May, June. And now, it has to be the acceleration phase. There are orders for EPA '07 coming and these are more or less in the second half of the year. So, this was the specific situation in the field of NAFTA, but overall the order intake we see is supporting our forecast thoughts in the market and the influx in orders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But just on &#x2013; excuse me. It's in Europe where you're the most conservative and it's in Europe where still all the other guys reckon that the market will go up. And I mean, you're into order intake.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; John, be my guest. We can deliver every truck even if some are getting in my order book. So, if the market is better than we see, fine. But I see not the order intake today that the market is going up plenty or so at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what Andreas is saying is fair, that the guidance of 200 million based on this market assumption, you will and I will expect when the market develops better than that that this will have an impact on the profits. And I think that's just positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And did you, could you give us the figures for what your CapEx and R&amp;D spend is going to be in 2010, the increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, totally transparent. For 2009, we were planning on a certain CapEx number and working throughout the year to maintain the content we wanted to accomplish with this CapEx and to spend less for it. And we were quite successful in doing so, not &#x2013; clearly accepting as well that there was some postponement as far as spending is concerned, as well as every year towards the end, is happening, which then of course, we're in 2010.</p>
          <p>But the original plan for 2009 was about the same altitude as the plan for 2010. We've spent less than that in 2009 and now we will work hard to come as close to the 2009 spending in 2010 as well. At that time, the plan calls for our spend and we do not want to delay or cut content which we need for our products, for our technology and for our global expansion in the markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I &#x2013; am I allowed to ask one other quick question? And that is what was the &#x2013; can you tell us what that 85 million supply support, how is that divided amongst the divisions and amongst the quarters? I think that's &#x2013; 85 million was the figure I think given in the press conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, I mentioned the number now in the third quarter, therefore, I do think it was 60 million in the third quarter, to year-to-date September. Total year was 85. It was the spending for the suppliers, I do think you mean.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And between the divisions of &#x2013; roughly the main bulk of the 85 was passenger cars. I would say maybe 60% of that. But I can &#x2013; you can call Investor Relations for this also.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, John. We take the next question from Kristina Church, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello. It's Kristina Church from Barclays Capital. I've got a couple of questions. Firstly, I was just wondering if you could update us on the negotiations that you've had with the unions on wages. I think I understand that there was a negotiation happening recently with iG Natal. And also, a little bit more about Kurzarbeit, just wondering how you expect, considering a lot of your cost savings in 2009 were based on lower labor costs, what you see for 2010 as you have workers presumably coming back off Kurzarbeit.</p>
          <p>And second question is on raw material prices and what we should be expecting for 2010, what you're putting into your numbers is still looks for the headwinds that we might see from raw materials for Daimler.</p>
          <p>And then finally, just a follow-up on financial services, I know you said you feel a high cost of risk in 2009, which &#x2013; and these one-off sell of non-automotive assets meant that your financial services division was not as profitable as previously. But, could you just give us an update again on what you're expecting from 2010 in financial services and what sort of residual value development you've been seeing, particularly in the German market? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the questions. I understood at least the first three ones and the rest will then be answered by someone else. Related to the contract negotiations which ended yesterday for one date of Germany potentially being applied throughout Germany, but that remains to be seen. My assessment is that you &#x2013; on both side of the table you always are shooting for a better result than the one you accomplish. That's the nature of negotiations.</p>
          <p>But having said that, I think the result is reasonable. I think it takes into concern on the one hand, the crisis situation of the economy for the enterprises and on the other hand, the needs there of their employees being affected. And between those two, if you want contrary demands or conflicting demands, I think we can live with the result which has been negotiated, including the fact that it's a two-year contract, which gives you a planning transparency and with reasonable numbers I think.</p>
          <p>As far as 2009-2010 of the Daimler labor cost is concerned, as you know, starting in April last year, we negotiated the short work contract, which gives us the 8.75% reduction in time, but payment as well. This runs through June this year, therefore, it's eight months versus six months of the same kind of savings. On the other hand, we have short labor, which obviously is very much dependent on the different plants and the specific demand for these products in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>This has already been reduced quite a bit. It will stay more or less stable on the truck side, and further be probably further reduced on the car side. We have reduction employment, if you talk Germany, 5.5 thousand there in '09, over the course of the year, which will have an annual effect now in the '10, which is the positive side. Last we will see further reduction in employment, basically on a natural flow, which will have another positive impact on 2010. So, putting that all together I would say 2010 versus 2009 is relatively balanced as far as labor cost is concerned, including the limited labor increase which has not a base effect being negotiated just yesterday night.</p>
          <p>Material costs, we saw a decent reduction of material costs in 2009. The way we calculate that is always the commercial success of negotiations is the technical success of more efficient designs for our parts and components. It is raw material development plus content development. So, when we talk about, for instance, CO2 technology coming increasingly into our cars, we calculate the material cost effect of that within this total number of development of material costs.</p>
          <p>And having said that, 2010 will be much more challenging or even though we see further opportunities, strong further opportunities on the commercial side and on the technical side. The content is growing, and therefore, the final result will not necessarily be a negative percentage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As to your question on financial services, if I got it right, the credit loss ratios for 2010 will slightly increase, compared to 2009, but &#x2013; and of course, that is naturally because you have some write-offs, which we also have made at the year-end, where you have customers of course, where you don't get the money anymore from, so you do a final write-off, which increases the loss rate. So, I expect this loss rate to increase in 2010, but the good news is we are well reserved for that. So, I don't expect that that will hit as an extraordinary item or so that we saw in '10 numbers and therefore, also the guidance in terms of minimum 350 million for 2010, compared to more or less zero in 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if you could give a quick update on residual values and how you're seeing those moving in Germany?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That would &#x2013; of course, is the development last year was quite favorable over the quarters, especially in the U.S. We go to a very balanced and perfect situation in terms of residual, losses of very, very low and there was only a slight volatility. We expected Q4 a little bit to go up. We were surprised it was not the case. So, yes, it's fine. We are also well reserved for that in the U.K, too. In Germany we have a little pressure on the residual value side. But we can handle that also in our &#x2013; with our current reserve for the balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next in line is Adam Jonas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Adam Jonas, Morgan Stanley. Just two questions, first again a follow-up on Kristina's question on residual values at Mercedes, I'm not mistaken, am I when I &#x2013; that you take the profit of off-lease vehicles at Mercedes? Is that right Bodo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you repeat this? I've not -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. I'll go slower. The profit that you, the profit recognized on the sale of off-lease vehicles, for example, in your lease program in the United States. That profit is taken at the Mercedes-Benz division is my understanding, not at the finance co. Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It goes both directions -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So of course, both the losses and gains or whatever the &#x2013; this in the industry side and not in financial services. We had some risk sharing agreement, but only for one or 2%, so the minor part which we share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. But majority's at Merck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So &#x2013; and you highlighted that got better throughout the year and that's pretty evidence by the data they'd provided externally. So, the question is how much of a benefit was that &#x2013; excluding your German dealer support issue of course. How much positive was that on the Mercedes share result in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Zero.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how'd that happen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A zero means, of course, we are reserved for the once a year as expected. So, there is no impact on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So absolutely no improvement? Do you think you were -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't talk now about five to 10 million up or down, but it's zero.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we have kept our reserves, so there's no relief or so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you. Next question I guess is for Renschler on trucks. You were specific, if not brave, on the 200 million profit outlook and you gave some &#x2013; a decent idea on the volume. Can I ask on pricing, what is your rough assessment of pricing behind that 200 million? Is it stable, up or down for trucks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Stable pricing. Do you think that's realistic given how &#x2013; given the develop -how realistic is that given the development of used truck prices of very low mileage used trucks that you're seeing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, we maybe experience also in 2009 and -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think 2009 was the worst market we ever had and we saw some good net pricing there. The only thing negative came up and we had some inventory trucks that we put a little but cheaper into the market. It was the only issue in net pricing 2009. And so we see a good chance that we can also phase through in 2010. There is one thing. Of course, we will also see some increase. This is more driven by emission laws. As you know, in the United States, we announced already the price for &#x2013; already we are selling EPA '10. Last year the price for &#x2013; the price tag for EPA '10 and will be for the heavy duty truck $9,000. So, if you take this in consideration, I put this out, the rest is more or less very stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. And your capacity utilization for Europe trucks in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had in 2009 at least we followed our &#x2013; whatever decline, 45%. We produced a little bit lower because we had to clean up the inventory, so we were down if I remember right 55% in capacity. And as you know, we are expecting a slight improvement so it will be a little better than the 50%. But the best thing is that we could survive parts of Europe was the flexibility instruments we had, including <mark type="inaudible" /> of course. This kind of crisis of course, we had to also &#x2013; we had no temporary worker of course. This is also a kind of flexibility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. So, slightly above 50% utilization &#x2013; and structural capacity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bodo just asked me to give one further clarification on my explanation on how we calculate material cost development. When I said the content increase is part of this calculation, this is right, but I have to be more specific than non-pricable content. So, when we for instance, add an option and we can charge for it, then it's not &#x2013; this content is not part of our material calculation. But if we can't charge for it, like for CO2 typically, at least a good portion of CO2, then it is part of this calculation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Adam Jonas. Adam Hull, you are next.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Adam Hull from WestLB. Three questions, first in R&amp;D, you've given guidance, earnings for 2010-2011, a combined number for a significant increase in R&amp;D and CapEx. But if you look at '09, what is striking is that your amortizing of R&amp;D is very low. So, if I look at your charged P&amp;L for R&amp;D, it's actually 600 million lower than the cash R&amp;D and it's not a net effect benefit to revenue. Then if you'd give us a bit of guidance, what should we be assuming for 2010 and '11 on that net effect? Will that fade toward zero?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, on short-time working, if you could give some specific figures from the government scheme, what kind of number was the benefit for the group in '09? What was it for trucks and what kind of number &#x2013; am I right in assuming you're saying sort of similar things for 2010?</p>
          <p>And then finally, on China, could you give us what the Chinese joint venture profit was in '09? I believe that's actually included in your EBIT number. And could you give us some indication of what the cash dividend, perhaps even '08 if it's too early for '09 &#x2013; what the cash dividend was in '08 if any and maybe '09? And maybe give sort of guidance on whether you expect cash dividends from that venture in the future. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So your question to &#x2013; Adam, for R&amp;D, of course, we had in the past &#x2013; in 2007 and '08 of course, due to the fact that we have developed certain vehicles at this point and later stage other vehicles, the capitalization ratio was for trucks and for passenger cars, roughly 20 to 25% roughly. That's increased over the years to 30 to 35% and that depends only because we are starting to develop or developing the future truck for zero six.</p>
          <p>Therefore, of course, the percentage is increased because the project is there and that same was true for our passenger cars when you have the certain projects, you have to 30 to 35%. Last year it was in average I do think 33% for both roughly. So, and that number I do think will stay at this range between 30, 35% also for the next two years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about amortizing, if I could ask? Would amortizing &#x2013; you're amortizing quite a low number, 6.38 in '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Amortizing is clearly, depending on the amount of units. So, you have capitalized a number of ex and then you have of course, you have a depreciation rate per unit, which depends on the total life cycle volume. And of course, the volume, you write it down and that is until the end of the life cycle of the vehicle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we expect that to rise in 2010 with regards to &#x2013; of the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, because we have more units more. We have more cost there. That's why. But it's per unit-based. So, more revenues, more units, more depreciation. I ask for your understanding that we do not consider a total number of contribution to the short labor situation in 2009 to be a needed information to the market and nor to the media and we had another question, China, same applies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And of course &#x2013; the only information of course, we always disclose how many people we are in short timing but we have said that we have extended for trucks until the middle of the year and for passenger cars, I do think 30,000 people are for the first quarter in short timing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that is 13,000 in trucks right now and 30,000 in passenger cars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on China on the JVs at least and from others we do get disclosure. It's quite an important part in the sense that you're seeing sales growth there. Your capacity's fully utilized. It's helping your unit sales, but we're not seeing that much in revenues. But just to get some idea as to what scale is, because if I look at the overall associates in Q3 in the first nine months it seems quite a small number. But I do understand it is an EBIT.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You asking for specific numbers and we are not willing to disclose that. What I can tell you is that our Chinese business, which is obviously growing very fast, is altogether between CKB and CBU a very profitable business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next in line is Daniel Schwarz, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Daniel Schwarz, Commerzbank. I have three questions. First is what is the financial effect from the McLaren transaction in the fourth quarter? Second question would be with regard to production at Mercedes first quarter 2010 versus fourth quarter 2009. And the third question was about the take rate of the Hybrid version of the S-class most recently stated at a very high level or decrease it a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you, Daniel, could you please repeat your second question? We have understood the first and the third.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>About the production scheduled in Q1 2010, how does that develop versus Q4 2009? Is it a significant increase or is it rather flat?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So to you, I can answer that right away.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to my memory, which might not last till the end, so, obviously there are two effects. First of all, we have considerably higher sales rate in first quarter 2010, compared to 2009. You heard the 24% increase in January which we reported and secondly, in 2009, we had a major challenge to reduce the excess capacity &#x2013; not capacity, excess stock, sorry, stock we had. And therefore, of course, we tried to be below our sales rate with our production. Whereas at that time, we have a lack of products there in under retail, dealer inventory sides and they're at least a very clean pipeline, before that. So, both effects will definitely create there considerably higher production rates first quarter 2010 versus 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But also on the quarter-on-quarter basis, not only on a year-on-year basis, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You were asking Q4 versus Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry I was answering Q1versus Q1. Okay. Now, Stephan is changing pages, flipping pages very fast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps we start now with the other questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I should have waited away.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To your Mclaren question of course, we have booked in the fourth quarter a charge of 87 million included in Mercedes. Of course, yeah -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, of course, you know that the Formula One and the issue within Mercedes of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not talking about the last unit, we expect the production first quarter versus fourth quarter to be roughly flat, perhaps slightly below. But we will increase our inventory, because we need to do that looking forward to the spring sales. And therefore, this does not relate to the comparison in sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question we take from Thierry Huon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon, gentlemen. The two quick questions, first of all, could you give us your assumption you have taken in terms of ForEx for your guidance, especially regarding the dollar versus the euro? And second question, just a clarification. The contribution of the JV in China is booked at the car division's EBIT level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your second question is clear is a yes. We don't have anything between EBIT and net profit &#x2013; in the net profit area. So, it's allocated or directly booked into the respective divisions. And with that question that is mainly now passenger cars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And your first question, we don't disclose due to competitive reasons our exchange rates when which we take for the year. But it's also not far from the current volatility you see in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We did not answer the question of the take rate on hybrids, on S-Classes and in the very early stage we said it's about 20%. Now, it's about 15 to 20%. So, relatively stable, different in different markets. For instance, in Japan, we have a take rate of more than 30%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I may, I have sub questions. It &#x2013; regarding the margin expected for the truck business in 2010, roughly speaking we could derive from what you said that the operating margin would be around 1%. What kind of volumes would you need to show a significant improvement in the operating margin at the truck level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Every truck is counting, so 1,000 more will help. We-based our forecast on our market estimation and we said very clearly, in Europe we see only a slight improvement. In NAFTA it's differently and based on that we calculate it. If it's 1,000 trucks more, it costs us a lot. Don't forget, 50% lower market, 50% situation, it's dramatically, so it's 10% we're higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's because if you look at the operating leverage you showed in 2009, it was not that huge. So, this is a reason for my questions, because you have now there's the impact of the restructuring put in place in Asia and in the U.S. and I was wondering when we will see some significant improvement to the &#x2013; in the margin and what kind of volume would be required to get there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, to answer on the bookends of this question, if we were to come back to the volumes we had before the crisis, obviously our profits will be and our margins will be much better than before. Because obviously the breakeven number has been taken down considerably. If you can keep all of your fixed costs at the current levels when volumes comes back, it's unquestionable some will come back. But certainly our productivity has grown and the restructuring programs of course, will have a lasting impact. But now to break that down to 100 trucks more gets you 1% more margin, I don't think will lead us anywhere.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But our restructuring programs are set up to decrease the breakeven point and we are on a very, very good track there also in the U.S. and in Japan as well. So, now we are coming to a pace where we can deliver with slightly market improvement the breakeven like we said, last year, is the big target for next year. And if the market is coming back of course, we have a lot of opportunities. But again, as I've said before, we don't see a 150% order intake increase, otherwise we would have a total different forecast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For sure. Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Next in line is Aleksej Wunrau.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Aleksej Wunrau, BHF. Two remaining questions, please. With regard to the dividend and the retained earnings of five billion, I did not quite understand why you chose to keep them at that high level. Is this because possibly you like to keep the chance of doing a share buyback in the future? And secondly, on &#x2013; or would you possibly update us on the state of important and pending lawsuits against you or the company that could result &#x2013; potentially result in a cash drain in the next years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Aleksej, to your first question of course, it's not related to any share buyback. We have not share buybacks in mind right now. We have different things in mind in the challenging environment right now. The five billion of retained earnings is of course, due to the fact we have currently five billion retained earnings, and if we book our loss in our local GAAP against the capital reserves, of course, we will stay at the level of five billion, nothing more, nothing less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So why did you not offset the loss against retained earnings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because the loss is quite a high one and we would like to have in the future the flexibility to pay dividends as we have already said on the 40% level. And if we book &#x2013; if we would book a high level of loss against the retained earnings they would go by far down. So, it would go down so far that we would not have the flexibility for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I will look at that. And regards to the second, to -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To the second, of course, there is no update on the current lawsuits. We are &#x2013; we have some of course, but there is no new information. We have of course, the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I mean, could you please outline -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Disclosure, under the first of March, you will see our disclosure regarding our lawsuits, the ones we do have and the ones we disclose of course. But there's no new information to any lawsuit I could think about right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And could you remind me please of these, of the ones you already disclosed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You will see that on the 1 of March, then when we will disclose our full disclosure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And when you take the third quarter disclosure, you are basically already there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's not too much difference since then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay next question from Ranjit Unnithan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Ranjit Unnithan from J.P. Morgan. Just a few questions. One, could you clarify, of the 5.3 billion in savings that you realized or countermeasures that you realized in 2009, how much will be retained in 2010? It's my first question.</p>
          <p>Second question is you had destocking obviously and negatively impacted your results in a big way in 2009. So, is there a way you can quantify that for us at the group level? So for instance, I'm thinking you cleared out a lot of inventory in the first half of 2009 and you probably have priced aggressively to do that. How much did that impact you? And you also produced at a rate much lower than sales, so how much did that underabsorption of fixed costs impact you in 2010 as well? So if you could quantify those two factors.</p>
          <p>And my last question is could you put your CapEx and R&amp;D increases in 2010 and 2011 in context? So it's a pretty steep increase coming up in 2010 and 2011 but is it a &#x2013; does it sort of go up and then sort of come back down starting in 2012, 2013? Or is this sort of really at the new level of investment for pretty much the foreseeable future? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps as far as the 5.3 billion is concerned, as we've said various times, our intention is to maintain that cost level through 2010 and this requires us to replace the one-time effect of 2009 by structural lasting, or potentially new one-time effects in 2010. Of course, the first one is what we &#x2013; in the first place intend to accomplish.</p>
          <p>When I've got you right, you were not asking about destocking about the cash flow impact, but about the operational EBIT impact. And as far as this is concerned, one aspect is do we have to grant higher rebates or discounts on a stock car versus order-bid car. The answer probably is yes, and there is certainly an element of cost to it, operational cost to it and that as I said, before, is one reason why our discount levels increase quite a bit in the first quarter and develop more favorably throughout the year.</p>
          <p>As far as production rates versus sales rate is concerned, this has no effect on our EBIT number. It has an effect when we have a de-stocking on the dealer side. Then of course, retail sales do not transfer into EBIT profit on our side. But when we talk about the company stock, then our EBIT is affected almost the same if we sell a stock car or newly produced car.</p>
          <p>So the effect really comes from the increased discounting based on stock cars, but we are not able to quantify that specifically. I only could tell you qualitatively, this was one reason for inflated discounts in the first quarter altogether.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One indication for your question CapEx and R&amp;D, specifically in the truck side is very, very much connected to zero six. We have to stop now in this let's say challenging market condition times, the zero six program and this will be also then going down again after the launch of zero six. So, this is a dramatic burden we have in front of us because zero six means a hell of a investment, not only for us, for all truck manufacturers in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the car side, as far as our product cycle is concerned, 2011 is a pretty peak year based on as we already said 16 products being launched between '10 and '11, as far as CapEx is concerned. As far as CO2 investments are concerned, certainly we will have to go forever in reducing CO2. Still I would assume that '10 and '11 are kind of the peak years in this regard and there will be some relief going forward, in the R&amp;D spending we need to create further CO2 reductions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could squeeze in one more question, on Q1, you probably have good visibility since we're nearly through the month. How is Q1 tracking if you could comment on the EBIT perspective versus Q4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say on the one hand we see the momentum continuing which we have observed and I think shown to you for Q4. On the other hand is seasonally, Q1 is typically a little weaker quarter and this is not different in 2010. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question we take from Jose Asumendi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Jose Asumendi, RBS. I was just wondering on trucks if you could please just give us &#x2013; if you could please quantify how far have you reduced your truck inventories, if you could give us figures for end 2008 and end 2009? And the second question, I was wondering by order in-take by region, would you agree that in North America and Europe you're seeing a high order intake in the first quarter versus the fourth quarter of '09? And the third question would be on cash generation. When I look at your competitors, on trucks, the fourth quarter production went up quite heavily and therefore, that created a very strong cash inflow. I was just wondering how deep the truck division contribute to cash in Q4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Your first question, through the year we decreased our inventory basically by 50% more or less. It was driven through the pipeline inventory, because as you know, trucks are normally ordered from a customer, a customer order is behind. So, it's basically the majority of this was pipeline inventory. So, we were very successful.</p>
          <p>As I said, before at the yearend, we had some of the volumes still in Russia and Romania, and some of the eastern part of the countries where we have no chance to sell this in different countries. So, this was one of the issues in the cost model. Cash, we are not announcing whatever division-wise. I don't get the approval from my <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
          <p>But I do think we can say for the total year, every division. And I do think it does not make sense, not for quarters, to look at the cash flow because it's from a volatility point of view, for an inventory point of view, doesn't make sense to comment on this, but from a total year point of view, everybody contributed here in the cash flow management and the focus we had in 2009. Inventory-wise, I would say it was more related to Mercedes-Benz cars than it was on trucks, because they were a higher inventory in the starting point for cars and then for trucks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on payables, there's more on trucks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No more comments on the cash flow in this regard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on order intake?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What was it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On order intake in the first quarter versus the fourth quarter, I mean, should we expect -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First quarter of 2010 now, you mean or what -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have not finalized it, this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, the trend you're seeing currently now. Do you think it's -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I've said before, the first quarter is supporting our market forecast. We don't &#x2013; the biggest good situation we had last year was that we had achieved the bottom line in order intake. So, after summer, we see some slight increases, order intake worldwide. And it's on a stable level also through December, January and also, what we can see in February.</p>
          <p>The only difference is EPA '10 because as I said, there was in the first quarter of 2009 a pre-buy, and so far, the order intake of EPA '10 is not accelerating to a level, then in the fourth quarter, we will see this through the first half of year. That's the estimation we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jose. And now we have Max Warburton, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. Good afternoon, everybody. Thanks for making the call last this long and spending the time to speak with us. I have just got one question really, a sort of philosophical question for Dr. Zetsche. Your contract was extended yesterday.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not a philosopher, but okay -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But you're CEO of one of Europe's largest companies, so there must be some sort of management philosophy behind what you do. And first of all, congratulations from our side on the extension. But you've been in this position for I think four years and achieved a lot. And it's obviously been quite a frenetic time with a lot of external challenges, but what things have you been frustrated at Daimler that you've not yet been able to implement? What are the sort of things that in the next three years you would like to see Daimler do that haven't been possible due to other distractions so far?</p>
          <p>And sort of related to that, I mean, just as a management team you've been perhaps the most pro-shareholder at various points, with that massive share buyback a few years ago. And then there's this move on the dividend today, the &#x2013; maybe it's just communications. But certainly your institutional shareholders see it as probably anti-shareholder, compared to what some of the other options would have been.</p>
          <p>How are you &#x2013; are you happy with the balance at the moment in the company between the capital side and the labor side? Do you think the balance is right in terms of how both sides are being treated and what are your thoughts in the next three years about how that balance might shift? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the question. Let me answer the latter part of your question as it's less philosophical. My best understanding after we discussed this internally is that for the very reason Bodo explained, deciding for no dividend versus obviously, a relatively limited dividend, which you have been the other option. And on the other hand, maintaining a significant flexibility in returned earnings to freely decide on our dividend policy in the future versus booking it against these &#x2013; being forced to book it against these reserves and then have no flexibility in the future whatsoever.</p>
          <p>My understanding is that this was a very shareholder-friendly decision. Perhaps it didn't get across or when you look through the share price development, obviously we didn't get it across. But the reason to make this decision was exactly to decide in favor of the shareholder. It would have been easier for us to say well we &#x2013; whatever it is &#x2013; have $0.20 for instance, per share as a dividend and we wouldn't have gotten any criticism and we would have to deal with that next year.</p>
          <p>So that was not because of labor, not because of management. It was supposed to be in favor of the shareholder. Again, perception of that successfully. And perhaps without you having asked for it, you and others might have gotten the perception that, introducing the C-class, our decision not to grant labor stability, but to exclude lay-offs for a long period of time would have been a very labor friendly and shareholder hostile decision.</p>
          <p>I can only tell you deciding for a favorable footprint, as far as production is concerned for this company, is strategically extremely important and valuable, caused us some pain today for the management, and some better articles, but very much improves the prospect of this company for the long run in favor of the shareholder, whereas &#x2013; and the same applies for cash commit. Whereas what we seemingly granted was definitely at least for &#x2013; of the west, because never in the past we have laid off the people in Germany for the simple reason that it's more costly and lasts longer and just doesn't give you any advantage, versus the same reduction in personnel on a, for emphasis voluntarily basis and therefore, we didn't give anything but we gained a lot and labor could get some nice articles what they have accomplished. That is fine.</p>
          <p>But again, in essence, my deep conviction is that this was another decision, which was totally in the interest of the shareholder and not of the German labor side. So, of course, at the same time, we try to take care of our employees, by trying to get good balance within Germany, and so on. That is clear. That's a responsibility of ours as well.</p>
          <p>Now, to your first part of the question, certainly one frustration, which was external, was that it seems that 2007, beginning of 2008 we have gone through all through the construction side and done all the basic work from Smart to Chrysler and you name it. And now we are basically at our strategic profitability levels and now could go for the art of management of fine tuning and further leveraging the system. While obviously reality developed differently, and we are now sitting here with a deep loss, which is a terrible frustration of course. But on the other hand, it's a big motivation to bring the company back to where we were one and a half years ago. And I'm very confident that with this team, which is around me, we will accomplish that and this then will be a lot of satisfaction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you, well Dr. Zetsche. Ladies and gentlemen, thank you very much for your questions, for being with us today. Corporate Communications, Investor Relations will remain at your disposal to answer any further questions you may have. We hope to talk to you soon again. Thank you, and Good-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>