<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1227971" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-04-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>885</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Dr. Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer, Senior Vice President, Head of Investor Relations &amp; Treasury</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Bodo Uebber, Finance &amp; Controlling and Daimler Financial Services</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Dr. Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer, Senior Vice President, Head of Investor Relations and Treasury</participant>
      <participant id="4">Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer</participant>
      <participant id="5">John Lawson</participant>
      <participant id="6">Bodo Uebber</participant>
      <participant id="7">Arndt Ellinghorst</participant>
      <participant id="8">Andreas Renschler</participant>
      <participant id="9">Thierry Huon</participant>
      <participant id="10">Horst Schneider</participant>
      <participant id="11">Jochen Gehrke</participant>
      <participant id="12">Max Warburton</participant>
      <participant id="13">Daniel Schwarz</participant>
      <participant id="14">John Buckland</participant>
      <participant id="15">Christian Breitsprecher</participant>
      <participant id="16">Frank Biller</participant>
      <participant id="17">Aleksej Wunrau</participant>
      <participant id="18">Ranjit Unnithan</participant>
      <participant id="19">Adam Jonas</participant>
      <participant id="20">Stefan Burgstaller</participant>
      <participant id="21">Philippe Barrier</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Global Conference Call of Daimler.  At our customer's request this conference will be recorded.  You can listen to the replay by dialing the numbers you will find on your invitation.  The replay of the conference call will also be available as audio webcast on-demand in the Investor Relations section of the Daimler website.  The short introduction will be directly followed by a Q&amp;A session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>May I now hand over to Dr. Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer, Head of Daimler Investor Relations and Treasury.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.  This is Michael M&#xFC;hlbayer speaking on behalf of Daimler.  I would like to welcome you to our first quarter presentation.  We are happy to have with us today the CFO, Bodo Uebber and the Head of Daimler Trucks, Andreas Renschler.</p>
          <p>In order to give you maximum time for your questions, Bodo Uebber will begin with a short introduction directly followed by Q&amp;A.  Before we start, I have a couple of admin details.  I would like to remind you that this call is governed by the Safe Harbor wording that you find in our published document.  Please note that our presentations contain forward-looking statements reflecting management's current views with respect to future events.  These forward-looking statements can be identified by expressions like assume, anticipate, believe, estimate, expect, intend, may, plan, project, and should.</p>
          <p>These statements are subject to many risks and uncertainties, examples of which are set out in the Safe Harbor wording in our documents and are also described in our most recent Form 20-F under the heading Risk Factors.  If the assumptions underlying any of these statements prove incorrect, then actual results may be materially different from those expressed or implied by these statements.  Forward-looking statements speak only to the date they are made.</p>
          <p>Now, I would like to hand over to Bodo Uebber.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to our conference call on the results of the first quarter of 2009.  Let me first comment on the information about Chrysler.  Almost two years after we signed the agreement transferring 80.1% of Chrysler to Cerberus on May 14, 2007 we agreed last night with Chrysler, Cerberus, and the US-Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation PBGC on our final separation from Chrysler.  It is important to say that we achieved a solution which makes us independent from Chrysler future on the one hand, but even more important releases us from all potential litigations from Cerberus or Chrysler as well as liabilities for representations and warranties in connection with the 2007 transaction.</p>
          <p>After discussions with the PBGC Chrysler and Cerberus, we agreed to a concept which enables us to redeem our remaining 19.9% in Chrysler Holding.</p>
          <p>Daimler will forgive its 2nd Lien Loan and Subordinated Loan which have already been completely impaired in our balance sheet in the course of the annual close 2008.  We agreed to provide pension payments totaling USD 600 million to Chrysler pension plans to be made in three equal installments over the next three years.  The existing guarantee to the pension benefit guarantee corporation will be reduced from 1 billion to USD 200 million.  This guarantee will expire in August 2012.</p>
          <p>Daimler remains responsible for certain guarantees including the reduced PBGC guarantee and some further guarantees for which the open amount exceeds the existing cash collateral by less than USD 100 million.  Daimler furthermore remains a supplier to Chrysler of components such as engines and transmissions as well as a provider of certain services including certain dealer financing until the end of September 2009.  The maximum negative EBIT effect in Q2, 2009 is expected to amount to up to USD 700 million also considering minor positive effects.  The total cash burden for the years 2009 to 2011 is expected to be USD 600 million in equal amounts.</p>
          <p>So, now let's come to our original topic of this conference call, the Q1 results.  Business in the first several months of 2009 has been seriously affected by the financial and economic crisis which actually accelerated in some industrialized countries compared with the previous quarter.  And the global crisis spread more and more to the emerging markets.  Weak car and truck markets worldwide had a negative impact on the sales of our automotive divisions in-line with the lower unit sales, revenue decreased by 22% to &#x20AC;18.7 billion.  First quarter EBIT fell to minus &#x20AC;1.4 billion and net profit decreased from plus &#x20AC;1.3 billion last year to minus &#x20AC;1.3 billion.  But, we maintained our strong financial position in this very challenging environment.  The net liquidity of our industrial business at the end of March amounted to &#x20AC;3.7 billion, in fact we strengthened our position with the investment of our new shareholder Aabar of Abu Dhabi which required a 9.1% stake in Daimler at the end of March.</p>
          <p>And it goes without saying that we have intensified our cost cutting efforts and working capital management in all divisions.  We have initiated group-wide measures to reduce or avoid expenses and cash outflows by &#x20AC;4 billion.</p>
          <p>On chart number 4, you can see an overview of the key figures for the first quarter of 2009 in comparison to last year's results.  Earnings per share fell in line with net profit.  The free cash flow of our industrial business was impacted by the poor economic development and decreased from plus 1 billion to minus &#x20AC;1.1 billion despite our improvement in working capital management during the first quarter.  I will come back to the financial situation later.</p>
          <p>Let me first comment on the operating business.  The main reason for the decline in EBIT from plus 2 billion to minus 1.4 billion was a reduction of sales volume in all of our automotive businesses.  Another negative effect on EBIT at higher costs especially at Mercedes-Benz cars resulting from the ramp-up of the new E-Class expenses for the lifecycle management of certain models and emission reduction technologies as well as further fixed cost burdens.  These negative effects more than offset the benefits of our countermeasures which we could realize a positive contribution of more than &#x20AC;400 million in the first quarter.  The financial and economic crisis caused a significant impact on the profit within our Financial Services business largely due to higher cost of risk.  Currency exchange rates had a slightly positive effect.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to the divisional results starting with Mercedes-Benz Cars.  Due to the global downturn of the automotive market, but also because of the model changeover of the E-Class, the division's unit sales decreased 27% to 231,000 vehicles.  The decrease affected all the E-Classes and all major regions worldwide.  However, the S-Class and C-Class sedan successfully maintained their leading position in their segments.  Deliveries of the new E-Class sedan started in Western Europe at the end of March. 50,000 orders had already been placed at the time of the market launch.  Unit sales of smart cars decreased by 9% in total, however, increases were achieved in the US and Germany.  The division's revenue fell in-line with unit sales by 27% to &#x20AC;9.1 billion.</p>
          <p>Mercedes-Benz Cars posted EBIT of minus &#x20AC;1.1 billion in the first quarter of 2009.  The significant decrease was primarily caused by the reduced sales volume due to the drop of market demand and the model changeover of the E-Class.  Further negative effects on earnings resulted from a less favorable model mix and the ongoing market pressure on automobile prices.  I've already explained the burden from cost increases and fixed cost burdens in connection with Group EBIT.</p>
          <p>In light of the economic crisis, we took resolute counter-measures to adjust costs.  On the other hand, we continued our efforts to enhance efficiency. This is true not only for Mercedes-Benz Cars but for all our divisions.  As already mentioned, the new E-Class sedan was launched in Western Europe at the end of March, the station-wagon version of the E-Class will follow this autumn.</p>
          <p>At the beginning of March we presented the new coupe of the E-Class which will replace the current CLK coupe.  The compact SUV GLK which has been fully available since the end of 2008 is now also offered with a new fuel-efficient diesel engine introduced in the E-Class.  In the course of the year, the Mercedes-Benz model range will be complemented by additional environmentally friendly hybrid and BlueEFFICIENCY models.  The S 400 HYBRID is very important in this respect and will be launched in the summer.  With our new four-cylinder diesel engine and the gasoline engines with direct injection, we will achieve significant reductions in fuel consumption and CO2 emissions.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to Daimler Trucks.  The Truck division was also affected by the economic downturn and sold 65,000 vehicles worldwide, 39% fewer than in the prior year quarter.  The Trucks Europe/Latin America unit sold 23,000 vehicles, a decrease of 32%.  In Western Europe unit sales fell by 19% while sales in Germany were actually slightly higher.  A pronounced incline was reported in Eastern Europe caused by the economic crisis and financing difficulties.  Due to the continuing economic slowdown in the US, sales by Trucks NAFTA decreased by 37% to 17,000 units.  The decrease was also caused by a new emission regulation in Mexico introduced in August 2008 which has lead to pull-forward effects in the preceding quarters.</p>
          <p>Trucks Asia sold 25,000 vehicles in the first quarter minus 46% compared to the prior year period.  The decrease affected not only Japan but also important truck markets outside Japan especially the Middle East, Indonesia, and Turkey.  The truck division's revenue dropped by 22%, to &#x20AC;4.9 billion.</p>
          <p>Daimler Trucks' first quarter EBIT fell to minus &#x20AC;0.1 billion compared with 0.4 billion last year.  The reduction was primarily caused by lower sales volumes in all major regions worldwide.  In addition, we had expenses of &#x20AC;45 million resulting from the repositioning of our Trucks business in North America.  Positive effects resulted from our efficiency improvements and measures taken in the context of our Global Excellence program.</p>
          <p>The new Mercedes-Benz Actros Construction was launched in the first quarter of 2009.  This trucks for construction side, was a member of the Truck of the Year 2009 family and is equipped with several new features.  Daimler Trucks also focuses on improving the fuel efficiency and reducing the emissions of its products.  The division's hybrid truck activities are concentrated on our Global Hybrid Center in Japan.</p>
          <p>During the first quarter, we sold the 500 Fuso Canter Eco Hybrid truck.  This truck fulfills the new Japanese emission regulations coming into effect in 2009 and which will be the strictest in the world.</p>
          <p>Mercedes-Benz Vans was significantly impacted by the decline in market demand.  The division sold 29,000 vans in the first quarter, a drop of 58% compared with record level of the prior year.  The market decline affected both the midsize and the large van segments in all major markets worldwide.  Massive reductions were recorded in Eastern Europe and the US.  Despite this fall in demand, Mercedes-Benz Vans was able to defend its leading position in the Western European market segment of midsize and large vans.  In line with the drop in unit sales, revenue was down 45% to &#x20AC;1.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Mercedes-Benz Vans EBIT deteriorated to minus &#x20AC;91 million after plus of 186 last year.  The lower earnings were caused by the sharp decline in unit sales despite the favorable prices of our vans.  Although the initiated countermeasures, efficiency enhancements, and positive exchange rate effects were unable to compensate for the impact of decreasing demand.  The vans of the Mercedes-Benz brand continued to demonstrate their popularity with customers and experts by receiving numerous awards once again in the first quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>The business segment which is least affected by the economic crisis is Daimler Buses.  The bus unit sold 6800 vehicles worldwide, 26% fewer than a year earlier. The decrease was mainly caused by fewer sales of bus chassis in Latin America whereas sales of complete buses in Europe increased by 14%.  Revenue was therefore almost stable at &#x20AC;904 million.</p>
          <p>In Western and especially Eastern Europe unit sales again surpassed the prior year level.  The business and the City Bus segment continued to develop positively in this region.  In the NAFTA region, sales increases in the US and Canada due to the ongoing strong demand for hybrid city buses were unable to compensate for the decline we experienced in Mexico.</p>
          <p>In Latin America, unit sales of bus chassis dropped by 40% because of the current economic crisis, while sales had been particularly strong in Brazil in the prior year quarter.</p>
          <p>Daimler Buses achieved an EBIT of &#x20AC;65 million after 75 million last year.  The decrease in earnings was caused by the overall lower sales volume.  However, our efficiency measures in the context of the Beyond Plus program had a positive effect on earnings.  At the end of March, more than 250 customers in 15 countries experienced the Mercedes-Benz articulated bus Citaro G BlueTec Hybrid.  This 18-meter-long hybrid city bus can operate for significant distances without emitting any pollutants at all.  Diesel consumption and CO2 emissions can be reduced by up to 30% compared with conventional buses.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, we are continuing our efforts in the field of alternative drive systems with the fuel-cell bus of the future, the Mercedes-Benz Citaro FuelCELL Hybrid.  This bus will be presented in the early summer of this year.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to Financial Services.  New business in the first quarter amounted to &#x20AC;5.9 billion.  This was 12% below the prior year.  Adjusted for exchange rate effects, the decrease was 13%.  As a consequence of the low sales volume in the first quarter, the contract volume of our Financial Services business decreased by 2% compared with year-end 2008.</p>
          <p>The merger of the business operations of Mercedes-Benz Financial and Daimler Truck Financial in the US was successfully completed in the first quarter.  EBIT of Financial Services division fell to minus &#x20AC;167 million compared to 168 million in the prior year quarter.  The main reason for the decrease in earnings was higher cost of risk. Compared to the first quarter of 2008, cost of risk increased by &#x20AC;268 million which resulted from an increase of reserves to cushion future expected losses adequately.  An additional burden comes from the expenses related to the expansion of Mercedes-Benz Bank's direct banking business.  In addition, EBIT includes losses from the sale of part of our non-automotive lease portfolio in the US.  The net credit loss rate for our financing and leasing portfolio was 0.73% in the first quarter of 2009.  We consider the current allowance for credit losses to be adequate in the present situation, but of course, additional provisions may be necessary especially if economic conditions worsen.</p>
          <p>Now, let's take a look at net profit and earnings per share.  Lower earnings from the operating business also affected net profit.  For the first quarter of 2009, we posted a net loss of &#x20AC;1.3 billion.  There was an income tax benefit of &#x20AC;0.3 billion due to the fact that the Group recorded a loss before income taxes in the first quarter of 2009 and this compares to an income tax expense of &#x20AC;0.7 million in the prior year.  Earnings per share in Q1 2009 decreased to minus &#x20AC;1.4.</p>
          <p>Our key balance sheet and financial figures are shown in the next chart.  With &#x20AC;16.7 billion at the end of March, we have a comfortable level of gross liquidity for all our operations.  This amount still includes the dividend which was distributed after the annual meeting in early April.  The increase in liquidity was caused by the growing account deposits at Mercedes-Benz Bank, the capital injection from Abu Dhabi, and the bonds issued recently.  These inflows of funds increase our financial flexibility to cover upcoming funding needs and to continue our high level of investment in the future of our company.  And for the rest of the year, we plan to issue bonds in a very limited amount only.</p>
          <p>The net liquidity of our industrial businesses increased to &#x20AC;3.7 billion after &#x20AC;3.1 billion at the end of 2008.  The Group's equity ratio adjusted for the dividend payment was 23.8%, and thus slightly below the level of the year-end 2008.  Equity ratio of our industrial business decreased from 42.7% to 42.1%.  For the first three months of the year, the free cash flow of the industrial business was minus &#x20AC;1.1 billion.  Of course, it is not satisfactory.  But it represents a significant improvement compared to the fourth quarter of 2008 where the free cash flow of the industrial business was minus &#x20AC;3.5 billion.</p>
          <p>The free cash flow reflects the market driven sales decline in all divisions and the earnings situation, but we have also made progress with our working capital management.  In the first quarter, we significantly reduced production volumes below unit sales in order to adjust inventories to a lower level.  But during the first quarter, we reduced our vehicle inventory from 220,000 units to under 200,000 units at Mercedes-Benz Cars and from 46,000 units to under 40,000 units at Daimler Trucks.  And we have initiated additional measures in order to further reduce our inventories especially within our passenger car business to a level inline with current market volumes by the end of the second quarter.</p>
          <p>As shown on chart number 22, our net liquidity in the industrial business increased from 3.1 to &#x20AC;3.7 billion.  This was largely the result of the capital injection of nearly &#x20AC;2 billion from the new investor Aabar based in Abu Dhabi.  The reduction of our working capital contributed plus &#x20AC;1.3 billion to the higher net industrial liquidity.  Net industrial liquidity was negatively impacted, however, by &#x20AC;2.4 billion mainly due to the weak sales and earnings development in Q1.</p>
          <p>The Group's total nominal financing liabilities increased to &#x20AC;63 billion with a volume of &#x20AC;33 billion. Bonds are the main funding source of Daimler, bond issues in the last month have shown that we have good access to the debt capital market, although at higher cost.  In the next three quarters, bonds of &#x20AC;6.6 billion fall due but we plan for the rest of the year only very limited bond issues.  We will first of all use our high liquidity to cover upcoming funding needs and debt maturities.</p>
          <p>We expect most of our bank loans to be rolled in the future, we plan to keep commercial paper on a low level and we will maintain our solid amount of account deposits at Mercedes-Benz Bank.</p>
          <p>We increased our share capital at the end of March, our investment of Abu Dhabi acquired all new shares and now holds 9.1% of our share capital, the cash inflow of &#x20AC;1.95 billion gives us greater flexibility to invest in innovative automotive technologies in this period of economic uncertainty and macro economic instability.  A broad range of initiatives, which we had already undertaken to react to the changing market environment, is complemented by these investments.  In order to mitigate the impact of the economic crisis and to adjust all expenditures for the lower level of revenue, we initiated measures across all divisions and the Group's headquarters.</p>
          <p>We have already initiated immediate expense cuts and reduced our production with the flexibility measures like work time accounts or short-time work.  With the Employee Council of Daimler AG, we have agreed on a package of measures to be taken to reduce labor costs.  The key points of the agreement are the collective reduction in working time for employees who are not included in short-time working arrangements, a reduction in the contribution paid by the company towards the short-time benefit and the postponement of the upcoming wage increase.  My colleague, Wilfried Porth, will explain the details in a press conference later this afternoon.</p>
          <p>We also focus on non-personnel cost savings, for example in the area of material costs, and we prioritize our investment plans because we want to limit our cash outflow to the necessary minimum.  But we will still invest reasonably in our key strategic areas in green technologies, new products, new markets, any new businesses in automotive related areas like Carterville.</p>
          <p>With all the focus on cost reductions, of course, we do not neglect our dedication to the attractiveness of our products and look for potential to increase revenue.  And we target to realize an earnings improvement of &#x20AC;0.8 billion from the increase in revenue related, for example, to modified marketing and pricing strategies.  In total we expect an overall profit impact of these countermeasures of about &#x20AC;4 billion in 2009.</p>
          <p>And last but not least, we also work in the area of working capital efficiency both with regard to our vehicle stock and to our logistic chain.  We are committed to rigorously adapt our production program to the market demand.  Our aim is not only to reduce the stock of our new vehicles, but we have also significantly reduced our used-car inventory level European-wide in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>The working capital improvements in the first quarter were related to the stock reduction of both new and used cars.  In the second quarter we expect further working capital reductions mainly from the new car side.  And we realize further potentials in the field of manufacturing supplies and spare parts.  In other fields, we look in this, in it, in is the entire value chain from procurement to payment and the harmonization of payment terms and we do this across all divisions.</p>
          <p>What are all assumptions for the automotive markets in 2009?  The extended duration of the global economic crisis will be of great significance also for the ongoing development of worldwide demand for motor vehicles.  From today's perspective, global demand for passenger cars will continue to fall substantially.  We expect worldwide market contraction of 10 to 20% compared with the prior year.</p>
          <p>Prospects of the medium and heavy duty truck markets are also unfavorable.  Significant decreases of 40 to 50% are expected through Western Europe and Japan and of 20 to 30% in the NAFTA region.  We also anticipate a distinct decline of the emerging markets.  We presume a gradual recovery of the truck markets not before the end of the year, this year or the beginning of next year.</p>
          <p>For the van market, we do not foresee a significant improvement compared to the market decline experienced in the first quarter.  With regard to the bus market, we expect stable demand for the city bus segment in 2009.  However, we believe that the conditions for the coach market will remain difficult.</p>
          <p>Which consequences will these assumptions have on our sales this year?  Mercedes-Benz faces extremely difficult year 2009 with an up-to-date and competitive product range as presented a few minutes ago.  But despite the introduction of new models and environmentally friendly drive systems, we will not be able to avoid the expected weakness of major sales markets.  Overall, Mercedes-Benz Cars unit sales in 2009 will be lower than in the prior year.  However, we expect our market shares to remain at least at last year's level.</p>
          <p>Daimler Trucks anticipates a distinct fall in unit sales in full year 2009 as a result of the economic, global economic crisis.  We believe, however, that we can maintain our sales in our core markets.  Due to a stagnating demand and the ongoing recession in major economies, Mercedes-Benz Vans does not expect an improvement in unit sales in the coming months.  Daimler Buses anticipates lower unit sales in 2009 compared with the record year 2008, but still on the solid level.</p>
          <p>What does this mean for earnings outlook for 2009?  For Mercedes-Benz Cars, we assume that the low point of EBIT was already reached in the first quarter. In-line with increasing sales of the new E-Class and the savings effects from the wide-ranging measures we have initiated, we expect positive earnings in the second half of the year as a whole.</p>
          <p>The sharp decline in demand in the Daimler Truck division will have a further negative impact on earnings in the second quarter.  Burdens of &#x20AC;150 million arise from the repositioning of Daimler Trucks North America of which &#x20AC;45 million was recognized already in Q1.  Mercedes-Benz Vans also expects further negative impact on EBIT, especially in the second quarter due to the strong decline of market demand.  Despite the decrease in unit sales and the difficult development in the coach market, Daimler Buses expect to achieve positive earnings though substantially lower than in 2008.</p>
          <p>Daimler Financial Services expect significantly lower earnings in 2009 due to the substantially higher credit cost.  The low point should already have been reached in the first quarter.  In order to alleviate the impact of the incline in unit sales and revenue, we have initiated countermeasures designed to reduce costs and avoid expenses throughout the entire Group.</p>
          <p>These measures will supplement the existing efficiency enhancement programs and will be implemented in the coming month.  As a result, we expect to achieve cost reductions or to avoid cost increases in a total amount of &#x20AC;4 billion.  Based on these measures, which will have a full impact in the second half of the year and due to the launch of the new E-Class, we anticipate a gradual improvement in operational earnings as the year progresses.  But, EBIT in the second quarter is expected to be significantly negative once again.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you very much for your attention and I will be happy together with Andreas Renschler to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Bodo Uebber.  Ladies and gentlemen, you may ask your questions now.  I will identify the questioner by name but please also introduce yourself with your name and the name of the organization before asking your question.  Two practical points, firstly, please avoid using mobile phones and secondly, please ask your question in English.  Before we start the session the operator will explain the procedure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we take the first question from John Lawson.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John Lawson from Citi.  I wondered if you could first clear up a bit of confusion that I have about the Chrysler detachment.  You still have some supply business current with Chrysler, are the receivables from that still carried at full value, I just wanted to know if there was any residual risk there?</p>
          <p>Second issue, I guess I struggled a bit with your net interest cost.  We've seen your, the difference between pension interest and returns is about 50 million negative.  So, is it correct to think that 150 million would be a reasonable, negative, would be a reasonable run rate for net interest expenses across the year?  And then finally, just on cost of risk, I mean, this is largely a provision right now, I guess, I wondered whether you'd just be kind enough to help us understand what kind of geography or segments that might be concentrated in?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, John, I'm sorry when we confused you a little bit, or I hope I can clarify some of the issues.  Of course we are, we say as a supplier to Chrysler in terms of engines and components and of course we do apply kind of accounting rules we have when we get to, let's say, delay of payments.  And therefore we do apply certain rules in this regard and therefore I do think we are, from my point of view, well protected in this area. But we also plan for this component supply to apply for the supplier protection program in the US, which was also discussed with the government in the US.  So, that would also, let's say, give us the kind of security of course in this regard.</p>
          <p>And of all of the other issues I do think I have already commented on before, as I said, we also well reserved in the financial services area for our service to Chrysler until September, so I feel fine with all the risk provisioning we have done there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have this remaining guarantee which is less than USD 100 million for something, of course, we needed to guarantee at the point of time when we made the deal, it's less than $100 million.  So, all in all I can say, okay, this chapter is closed.  We have closed the chapter and that is good for our company, that is also good for Chrysler I do think for their future, and I'm looking forward to develop the remaining part of Daimler further into the future.</p>
          <p>You asked what the net interest payment as I have it in mind, it is one-third pension and two-thirds roughly from the interest side, and I have not yet a detailed forecast for the year, so that I do think that will stay with that kind of ratio, one-third, two-third.  And the cost of risk, of course, many, some comments to that.  Of course, what we have done is we have made specific provisions for, so to say, specific accounts.  It is mainly in the truck business.  Of course, our truck customers of the longer it takes, of course, for having this market in the US and in Europe and in Eastern Europe.  So, that is more the regions of concern.  In this regard, we have made specific provisions in that area for credit risk.  That was one area and the other one, you have seen the slight increase of course of credit losses of 73 basis points, fourth quarter last year was 63 basis points and that is a rolling kind of accounting scheme when you come to 12 months when you look at the good quarter goes away, a bad quarter so to say comes in.  And of course, then we do this provisioning, I do as I said also in the call with regard to the future, that this is the kind of low point from my point of view, from a provisioning point of view also.  And therefore, I do think we are well covered with that kind of provisions today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next question Arndt Ellinghorst, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, it's Arndt Ellinghorst from Credit Suisse.  First question on cash flow, please.  Your cash burn in Q1 was probably not too bad with 1.1 billion, now moving forward, you mentioned the 4 billion in efficiency gains for the rest of the year.  Could you specify how much of that are real expected cash savings compared to last year?  And then on working capital, you had a positive swing in the first quarter, so, for the rest of the year, could you give us some indication how much in additional working capital reduction you could realize?  I think you mentioned in discussions earlier on for the full year 2 to 3 billion.  So, could that be in that order of magnitude?</p>
          <p>And then obviously, if I bring that together, the question is why don't you feel comfortable to at least give us some indication of what you expect in terms of free cash flow for the full year?  So, would Daimler be able to reach a breakeven free cash flow I guess is the question for the full year?  And then the second question on Trucks, we realize that incoming orders are down 68% for Daimler, production is only down 36% and you did increase dealer inventory by selling more trucks to dealers than dealers delivered to end customers, I think roughly 1800 units.  So, is that telling us that you're just not able to cut production fast enough in your truck business and could you please specify how production will be reduced moving forward?  Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Arndt, of course coming to your first question, of course, the program we have initiated most of that is cash flow relevant, so from the 4 billion is roughly 90% cash relevant. Of course not included in the 4 billion of course quite clear don't even have to mention it, but the working capital of course is something which is not included in the 4 billion.  And you are right we said 2 to 3 billion, I would, from today's point of view, see a working capital improvement which is higher than 2.5 billion, but ask me a couple of months later whether we come to 3 billion of course we do everything to optimize the cash flow and of course having said this, that should also give us more opportunities than in the EBIT side.  That is quite clear.  So, having the program of the 4 billion and the 2.5 billion end of &#x2013; we looking at the CapEx spending, you have seen the numbers in the first quarter which are less than the first quarter of 2008 without jeopardizing future investments, we need to take for our products and technologies and so on and so forth.  I do think there are opportunities to, let's say, reasonable reduce it also with respect to the future.</p>
          <p>You had then a question to Trucks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think then the question was why, I mean, if you put out these numbers, why isn't that enough to give you a comfort zone...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, sorry but that is the &#x2013; that is a question of market volatility.  Of course, we have bandwidth of market volatilities and nobody can tell you right away with 100% probability what kind of scenario really will come up, we have kind of idea we have given you ranges, of course, maybe to think we come out but at the end of the day we have to take into account that the volatilities are still high and what we can do on the cost side, we do, but of course the other side is the revenue side and that might come &#x2013; deteriorate a little bit more and therefore we will come up with clear guidance in this regard when we are able to have again a clearer picture, I'm sorry for that but the volatility is there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the truck sides, I think the heavy duty Trucks side &#x2013; on heavy duty truck side we have the opposite effect, we decreased production more than sales. We could sell more this year in all the regions in NAFTA, in Asia, and also in Europe.  I think your question is going back to commercial vans and there we had a effect indeed.  In the fourth quarter we cleaned up the pipeline, so to say, because we want to start with a fresher people of another very full pipeline.  So, the reason for the first quarter that you can see a difference between the sales and the production line is really we had to fill up our pipeline again.  So, you will see there the effect in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Again on the heavy truck side, we had the opposite, we have never, we are producing one truck if there is no customer, so, production volume is much lower than sales in the heavy truck side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how much do you expect to bring down production levels moving forward, will that go down faster from the 36% in Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, if you look commercial vans, the plan is that we are decreasing the production line accordingly to the actual demand, after we have filled the pipeline.  In the Trucks side, I can give you only example in Trucks, we have decreased already in our German plant for Mercedes-Benz Trucks, we decreased production up to 50% alone. So, we will go down.  We have the flexibility inside our plants that we can adjust it.  And then for the heavy truck side because it's always customer ordered, you don't find one truck that we build, we build on the inventory level. What you could see in the fourth quarter in heavy truck, again, is that there are some cancellations where you can put the customer into a bad position to take it because otherwise you challenge him too much and this kind of inventory you will see going down through the year.  But, it's a very low number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next question, Thierry Huon, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon.  It's Thierry Huon speaking from Exane BNP Paribas.  One simple question, could you remind us what was the change in the accounting on the Financial Services to, you made since we had a big swing compared to last year.  And the second question is about the Q2 when you said that we should expect a significant loss for the second quarter, is that mean that it should be in the same magnitude as the one we saw during the first quarter or do you expect any improvement to come?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thierry, maybe it's misunderstood, but cost in the Financial Services side, we have not had an accounting change, so we applied the method as we have done it last year.  We applied that this year, so there is no change in method.  I commented on the specific provisioning, we have made in the truck area, truck customer area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm thinking about the revenue, sorry, the revenue....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the revenue stuff, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The revenue stuff is  the following, that is, okay, the revenue stuff I have not commented yet, is right. So we have the least maturity as we get into the company have to be applied as revenues and costs and not only as a profit impact.  And that, were done as a change that increases revenues on the one hand, but nothing changes in profit and nothing changes in cash flow.  So, we have adjusted the revenue side by 3 billion roughly, something, for the whole year is a 3 billion number, and for the quarter, I will get this number, you can ask Investor Relations.  But as I said before, it's no profit and no cash impact....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With that accounting change, so to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the second question was regarding the, of course, we have commented on that we expect, of course, we expect a significantly negative Q2, but as we also on the Daimler side, we commented, we expect a step-by-step improvement of earnings which of course should mean that Q2 should be somewhat better than Q1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Maybe, I will ask a very last question, could you remind us what would be the full year cost for the restructuring measures?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Full year cost of...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Of the restructuring measures?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The restructuring measures, of course, we have already announced last year in October or November, the Freightliner restructuring, repositioning program which will be roughly &#x20AC;150 million and this is also, I do think within our papers, mentioned.  And of course, as long as I don't know any other further numbers, I cannot deliver to you something because then I would already have it on hand.  But of course, we said clearly also that our Daimler earnings guidance in a step-by-step earnings improvement excludes, so to say, special reporting items or you can also call it is an operational step-by-step improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  But does that mean that from the four billion counteraction measures, we should not expect any significant cost to put them in place?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't exclude anything but is in the future regarding special reporting items or other measures, we have to take.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, we take Horst Schneider, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hello, good afternoon, Horst Schneider here from HSBC.  Three questions, if I may.  First one is on the CapEx plans which you only outlined in the annual report and you gave the guidance for R&amp;D expenditures and CapEx for PPE.  So, now you talk about it to reduce investments or cancel some projects.  So, could you please tell us what is then the impact here on the guidance that you gave in the annual report, to which extent can we reduce here the numbers that you have provided?</p>
          <p>Then second question is regarding Mercedes, you say in the presentation that you had the &#x20AC;2 billion negative impact from volume structure and net pricing at Mercedes.  Could you please give any indication how that splits up between volume and net pricing? So, yeah, I may be concerned about the pricing development here in the premium market.</p>
          <p>And we heard also from the rental car companies, 60 or some comments here that especially here, the E-segment is severely under pressure from a pricing perspective.  And the last question is then related to the E-Class launch, could you give us any indication how many costs were incurred on the E-Class launch in the first quarter?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Horst, coming to your question of course the CapEx side, of course we are looking at this very carefully, CapEx and R&amp;D, analyzing as I said where we can reasonably reduce it without jeopardizing our future within product technology and so on and forth.  So, I expect the numbers being lower than 2008 but I will not give you now a specific number, we do that on a case-by-case basis but, as I said, it will be lower than 2008, the numbers for CapEx in directionary R&amp;D.  The CapEx may be a little bit more than R&amp;D, stay please with that guidance.</p>
          <p>On the pricing side of course, there are impacts but I don't know, even I do not want to give you a percentage, a very low one-digit number from sales contribution, we have given you in the presentation which I've already have seen the number there and that is one single digit percentage out of that.  And of the E-Class of course, there is some details there we don't provide this kind of details, is an impact which is double-digit but in the higher amount double digit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next is Jochen Gehrke, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon.  I have two questions.  Mr. Uebber, first of all on your 4 billion cost reduction program, could you maybe talk us through how <mark type="inaudible" /> this will kick in sequentially, is this mostly something for the second half and how much of that will actually spill over into the year 2010, assuming that this is not yet all implemented for full year 2009?</p>
          <p>And secondly, on your working capital statements, you said you want to be benchmarked on inventory management and days of inventory.  What is benchmark?  Could you quantify that?  Could you give us a number, what are the days of inventory that you're shooting for, noting that it's been a while that Daimler was benchmarked in inventory management.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jochen, your question regarding the 4 billion, I have in my presentation, I have mentioned the first quarter impact was something more than &#x20AC;400 million, of course that means that the difference of the 2 to 4 billion should move into the, within the next three quarters of course.  That is quite clear.  The 2010 effect out of that, of course, that is something where we give you some guidance when we talk about the guidance of 2010.  It is quite clear that the 4 billion are not, let's say, in all aspects sustainable.  When we reduce, for example travel costs to 10%, of course you can imagine that might not be sustainable but it is right to do so in the current year.</p>
          <p>When we go through CapEx and through IT so, non-product related projects, of course yes, we reduce them drastically and rigorously but of course there are some amount which we cannot maintain.  So for the years 2010 and '11 of course we have to provide also our efficiency programs which we have made in place.  For example, you go for 10 within Mercedes-Benz Cars, our so-called modular strategy which will provide us also some opportunities for the years to come.  Having said this, of course if we have to use also with Global Excellence in the Truck area to further improve our profitability for the year 2010 and 2011 and we will not, we will also concentrate on this development to make sure that we have impacts on the profit side, efficiency side, for the years to come.</p>
          <p>Your remark regarding what is benchmark, of course, I would like to know from the competitors what is benchmark and we do that on a high level.  Of course what we try to do to get, we are now back on 2008 levels, right now. And we like to achieve, end of Q2, the so-called normal level and even then we might have some opportunities as a kind of range, we have a 45 to 60 days inventory roughly in, within Mercedes-Benz Cars, of course that we like to optimize more to the 45 than to the 60 but it depends a little bit also, in today's point of view in the structure of our inventories where we might have too many, let's say, SL for example and too less on the other car lines which we have to optimize in the structure itself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next in line is Max Warburton.  Max, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there.  Good afternoon.  Just a couple of questions really on mix at Mercedes. On all of the divisions we seem to have a much bigger decrease in unit sales than we do in revenues and I think I understand that in Trucks that's largely to do with service revenues.  But for cars, both in Q4 and again in this Q1, there's an amazing resilience of revenue per unit. Given what's happening with mix, could you just help us understand exactly how revenues get booked, so that revenue per unit can remain flat year-on-year when S-Class and E-Class obviously down a lot?</p>
          <p>And just related to that, another thing us analysts do as you know, is look at operating leverage, the difference in revenues and then the difference in EBIT and it looks like Mercedes has 66% operating leverage in this quarter which looks sky high.  I mean just looks, it looks too high compared to other companies.  Could you just help us understand whether the revenue recognition of Mercedes is different to other companies or whether the operating leverage is much worse, so there's some special effects in here that explain why there was such an impact on EBIT when, given the decline in revenue?  That's really the first question.</p>
          <p>And the second one is very simple, any positive developments on mix on incoming orders? You know, we're seeing fuel prices down and we're seeing mix in terms of vehicle size in the states improving.  Are Mercedes seeing any improvement in people ordering bigger engines in their cars?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mix, of course, I do think the revenue recognition in our company is no different to others.  So, there is no difference. Of course, I have not talked to other CFOs but of course, we are doing it on a normal accounting way as every other company is doing it, there's no special in that regard.  Of course, we are pleasing, of course, it is an issue, of course where we do recognize not 100% for example, but on a pro-rata basis so to say per month, no doubt, but there is no other specific.  Of course, the mix impact you said, is right.  We have also, if you look at the revenue per unit, of course, you see a dollar impact and you see of course a mix impact there.  But it's clearly the mix impact is the high volume here also in the first quarter with less S-Class is of course, we have the E-Class model change and that is also that what comes back.  What is the good news is that we are &#x2013; that we are with the E-Class with 50,000 units well underway to, although we have a market challenge right now, it seems to be that we &#x2013; that the E-Class, thus according to plan so therefore in that difficult market environment, is a very positive news and the mix of course should over the quarters also be better than in Q1.</p>
          <p>Of course, one thing which holds true more for all of the divisions that we have after-sales business within our revenues where -- of course the revenues are pretty stable and not affected, so to say, by the crisis in the markets.  A little bit of course but Trucks of course, units of the Trucks of course has an impact but on the passenger car side it should be stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just to follow-up on that, I mean, as analysts trying to model this stuff, when we think about the impact of mix one would think that revenue per unit would go down in a company like Mercedes, when there's such a dramatic mix shift.  I mean, just again are, are there any one-offs with used cars or something special in leasing that explains this or really is revenue per unit really holding up in euro terms...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Believe me, there is no special effect in that regard in revenues that is of course as it is booked.  Of course, the sales, when you look at the sales development and the differences between Q1 '08 and Q1 '09 the percentages in car lines when you look at the S-Class, I do think the difference is more than 50% and in E-Class of course, its more than 34%.  So, the percentages there are of course far higher than the average revenue you can see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.  I mean, but is there something very positive going on in price realization in A-Class or C-Class, I mean, is that mix getting better because I guess you would agree, it seems strange that it's so firm?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, it is strange and of course not strange but of course there is impact on the sales difference we have.  Of course we do, also as we said it in the 4 billion program that we do everything on the revenue side what we can do, no doubt, and we will use every opportunity to structure and positioning our cars also in terms of pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for this.  Good afternoon, everyone.  Three quick questions, if I may, first is the SEC investigations are dragging off for years now and I understand that you obviously for very apparent reason you don't want to comment on any possible earnings charge related to that, but maybe you could give us an indication on whether to expect an announcement in that respect, this year, or any indication on a possible timeframe?</p>
          <p>Secondly, April is almost over already, so could you give us an indication maybe on how car sales at Mercedes-Benz have developed this month, so far?  And the third and last question will be, Dieter Zetsche said, I think it was last week, that the talks with possible investors from China haven't been terminated.  Question would be, would a Chinese state owned fund be as welcome as an investor as, for example, other investment?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course your first question to the SEC investigation, we are in contact with the respective government agencies in the US and we are in talks and in touch and there's nothing to give you as a new information.  Everything what is known in the market is known in the market.  And therefore we go on and to hope that we come to a final agreement when it's ready at this point of time.</p>
          <p>You asked for the, of course, for the April numbers, April numbers, the only thing, of course we don't, can't give weekly or monthly forecasts here, only thing what I can tell you that April is according to our internal plan and that is a good news overall.</p>
          <p>And your third question was in China, also in China, of course, regarding investors. As we have to understand that we of course hopefully do a reasonable job to both our investors. I was last year, I don't know traveling to the whole world, talking with investors.  I will do so also in the future.  I will go to Frankfurt tomorrow afternoon, Friday in London.  I will go to New York and Boston and I will go also this year to China, Singapore, everywhere to attract our company to investors.</p>
          <p>Therefore, I don't have to comment this normal course of business what we have.  But of course, in China, on top of that, of course, we have a business relationship with new investments for a very big market and it might feel that we are in touch with governments and related parties very often and try to do a good job that we get our market shares up in China.  Because, currently this market is up by 10% and the kind of the only market which gives a little bit light at the tunnel that the world is going to more into a reasonable, into reasonability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Next in line is Daniel Schwarz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Commerzbank.  First question is whether you could give an update on the situation on the supplier side, have you seen further significant deterioration in Q1 and has there been costs and cash outflows included in your Q1 accounts?  And second question is how does your used car prices or how so well development of used car prices?  And the third question is on slide 25 you provided a split of the planned cost savings and 40% of the 4 billion is related to personnel that's 1.6 billion, that's less than the 2 billion that have been communicated some weeks ago, where comes this deviation from?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Daniel, first of all, of course the two suppliers, it might sound crazy.  The impact in the first quarter right now is minus 2 million for the three quarters we had, but I have to tell you that we got a repayment from distressed suppliers from the past.  So, roughly if you exclude this number of the repayment from one case we had in the past, so, it's roughly 20 million.</p>
          <p>Of course that is not the run rate we will see in Q2 and Q3.  So, I expect these numbers will go up in the next quarter to come because the problems we &#x2013; the supplier side had of course is a huge one and of course, I think, that we would get more expenses and burdens on this side.</p>
          <p>You asked for the &#x2013; you asked the question regarding the used car prices at all in the new passenger car wise.  In the US, we have a stable situation and in UK too, there may be a slight and we of course that was based also on a very good used car business.  We have double-digit increases in our used car business in that respective countries and that was also true for the German situation, where we had really good business on the used car side. Little bit also based on the government support programs we had there.  The Trucks, Andreas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The used part in the Truck business is more under pressure because there &#x2013; if there is no market for new trucks, also the used truck market is very weak but we have no additional pressure to expect on the residual value on our own used truck we have an inventory because we put this very conservative already into 2008, but at least there is no, like in the passenger car side, increased its pressure on the used truck prices on the whole world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Now we take...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the last question you had to &#x2013; sorry to this &#x2013; to the 4 billion program and the 40% in personnel cost.  The 40% of course with our German program up pretty safe so to say that we get into that &#x2013; it includes not only the German part of the company but also the international part where we have already restructuring in the US with freight.  And for example, and we have of course reduced personnel in Turkey for example and in other specific countries where we have production.  The 2 billion of course is a number which includes not only cost cuts or cost decreases but also avoided cost increases, for example when you give &#x2013; when you have a sales increase in the tariff area or in management of course its number would have been very far higher, if we had not done this kind of action.  That number reflects the 2 billion.  So, it includes the difference of cost increases and cost cuts to the baseline we get right now.  If you compare it of course with balance sheet impact and cash impact, the number which is included in the 4 billion is 1.4 billion.  So, looking at the cost position in '08 and the forecast of cash position in 2009, the number is 1.4 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  But it seems also that the 4 billion, this is not a reduction versus a budget planning but the reduction from the status quo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is a reduction of 2008 compared to 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Okay, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next is John Buckland, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  John Buckland from MF Global.  Just as we are talking about that cost measures, you mentioned that some of these cost measures aren't sustainable.  So, what, can you just give us a clue what is the fixed cost reduction and what's the variable cost reduction in this, because you're talking about lower, obviously work time reductions, pay, bonus reductions, and postpone of wage increases. If and when volume increases, how much give-back will there be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, John, my answer to that is I do think there's enough potential in this company for 2010 and the following years to act with efficiency program whether there is Global Excellence, Beyond Plus, Beyond Bus Plus, kept us number one, Go FOR 10, and so on and so forth.  And therefore, I do think we have also other measures as I said before modular strategy to offset some of that of course which is might not, might only be for a limited period of time.  But I can also tell you if the crisis holds longer, we stay at this levels.  We can do so for a longer period of time, no doubt.  So for, whether it's travel, consulting, whether it's some kind of CapEx, of course, infrastructure costs, and so of course, there's a lot where we can stay with for a longer term if needed.  But as I said before, there are also opportunity for long-term efficiency plans which we have incorporated in our long-term planning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Just on an accounting thing, in the report it says that other includes a compounding of provisions charge of 360 million which is an increase of 250 million. How is that number divided by the different divisions, is it just pro-rata or is Mercedes Cars get a disproportionate increase of that &#x2013; of that figure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a good question.  I think get the advice that you call Investor Relations that we can prepare our answer for you, so, we are not right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have to lookup where you have this information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Where and then to give you a concrete answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  The other question on inventory, you did mention what the inventory reductions had been and what the levels were now.  I wonder if you could just repeat that because I couldn't write it down.  But and then how do we relate those inventory levels with the actual sales levels because I did write down something like 200,000 cars and 40,000 trucks, which is pretty much the level of sale.  So, in other words, you seem to have some three months of &#x2013; three months of inventory for both cars and trucks, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, when I mentioned in the call the 200,000 units as of Q1, is passenger cars compared to 220,000 year end and I mentioned trucks with 40,000 I do think and coming from 46 getting to 40,000.  So, that was as mentioned, as we discussed already with Andreas, I do think possible benchmark of course we have to compare what kind of days of supply and so on that is and to keep that on a low level and to could drop here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But are these levels still much too high that's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, much too high is a question of benchmark.  So, we first of all, we reduce it to the sales level of course.  We have seen of course, you know, we have last year in passenger cars had more sales then production.  So, we have to bring that &#x2013; to bring that down this in Q2, we will achieve a lower number of course in this regard.  And so, we go further down.  But at the end of the day, we will look also into that level whether it can be further optimized, as we said before and within trucks we do that over the quarters to adjust it.  So, therefore in the comparable numbers, the sales numbers we had were 230,000 in passenger cars compared to production of 208,000.  These kind of numbers of course are all in our fact sheet regarding trucks, van, buses, and passenger cars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  We take next question from Christian Breitsprecher, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon, it's Christian Breitsprecher.  Just two clarification questions, firstly on what is still at risk at Chrysler?  Could you just give us a number what is still at risk there after your risk provisioning on your receivables?  And secondly, with regard to the outlook for Mercedes, you're saying that you expect a positive result at Mercedes for the second half as a whole.  For me, that implies that potentially we might see a loss also in the third quarter or how should we read that outlook?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christian, to your questions regarding Chrysler.  First of all walk you again through, we have the deliveries of components and engines.  When we get under the Supplier Protection Act in the US, there must be, there is no risk and of course we do apply the normal write off as we have this kind of business with also other OEMs and other companies.  So, I don't expect there a risk in that field.  We have Financial Services as a service provider so to say for the international markets until September to this year and we are provisioned there that I can say there is no underlying further risk in that business.  And certainly I commented on the guarantee and the guarantee is less than, is covered by a collateral.  The difference between the guarantee and the collateral is less than $100 million.  So, from my point of view, financially the chapter is closed and over.</p>
          <p>Secondly, you had the question of the guidance regarding Mercedes-Benz, take it as it is.  We have a volatility in the market and we will change our outlook when we do have better information, might be encourage you to that we can be more precise for the time being.  We leave the guidance and our wording as it is.  And we mean it as we have said it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Frank Biller.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon.  I have a question on the Financial Services division, looking at the revenue side it seems rather high, here this increase about 12% compared to Mercedes-Benz Cars and drop off 27%.  So, here maybe you can give some clarification what's behind these high revenues here and why is it sort of dramatically increasing versus shrinking sales?  Are you very aggressive here in pricing or what's the reason behind?</p>
          <p>And the other thing is based on your outlook earnings line, Q2 outlook is it including the loss of roughly &#x20AC;0.5 billion coming from Chrysler, there's a significantly loss in Q2.  Is it showing only a slight loss excluding this Chrysler loss?  And for the auto EBIT line, you said the second half clearly positive here and I heard something that the whole year should come out positive, am I right with that assumption?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, your question to the revenue side of Financial Services.  The revenue increase is based on two effects.  One thing is that of course during the course of the year 2008, we had the portfolio increase, and this portfolio increase of course leads to a higher revenue side. Compared to the year end of course, our portfolio decreased by 3.8% because it develops according to the sales guide but the increase of portfolio in 2008 over the month as its outcome in a higher revenue and we of course we have a higher quarter-by-quarter higher lease maturities, leasing business and lease maturities within financial services that also is the other equation that the revenues increased.</p>
          <p>But of course the decisive question when you look at Financial Services as a portfolio, and as I said, the portfolio is decreasing that helps us a little bit on the refinancing side of course, because the portfolio gets down.  The support is more or less on the same level we have done in 2008.  So, the penetration rates are, so to say, not less than last year but also not far higher than last year.  Then you had a question to the &#x2013; your second question was regarding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>About the earnings guidance, is it including the Chrysler...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's not included.  In our earnings guidance on the Daimler side we have said operating EBIT should be stepwise better so that includes not special reporting items. I would regard Chrysler as a special reporting items so that's not included.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And for the whole year, are you confirming a positive EBIT guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the whole year -- of course as a management we strive for, yes of course, being positive for the whole year but as I said before the volatility in the markets is so high that we cannot give a clear guidance but on the other hand we cannot also not seeing this volatility exclude that we are negative for the whole year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next is Christian Hitsnow.  Christian Hitsnow from <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, sorry, I was just wondering if you could clear up a couple of things very quickly.  First of all, briefly the issue of Chrysler, how much money have you lost all together net-on-net in the course of the past 10 years that you had it as a division in your company just for the record books more or less?</p>
          <p>Secondly, I was wondering you had said that you expect to use your liquidity to help finance your operations so you don't have to issue I guess lot of bonds over the course of the remaining quarters.  Could you tell me then would you still have a net industrial liquidity at the end of the year or at the end of each successive quarter or do you expect that in order to achieve something like that you would actually have to raise equity in the fourth quarter once the lockup with Aabar is over?</p>
          <p>And just sort of on a small strategic question, is it the time now to finally ditch Formula One? It hasn't really worked out for Mercedes. Last year, you basically lost all the points I believe and there hasn't been any tremendous success in this season.  So, Porsche doesn't need it, does Daimler actually need to keep pumping money out for Formula One?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christian, your question regarding Chrysler, of course, this question was raised many times and we always have commented on it that it's almost impossible to make a total calculation, all of that because we were so close together that we have so to say one balance sheet and you make tons of analysis to even answer that question.  And I would say without question that chapter is now closed and these kind of questions are history for me not to be answered so to say anymore and that is good.</p>
          <p>Second, you were questioning on that liquidity of course, our liquidity, we confirm that we do very limited amount of bonds maximum this year, as we said and our net liquidity, I'm sorry for that, but as we do not give a precise guidance on EBIT and cash flow, I cannot turn up now and tell you precisely, okay, that's no hello, there is net liquidity there.</p>
          <p>We do everything of course to look on the cash flow side, we have mentioned it.  All actions we have taken, you can see that in the first quarter with working capital.  We will do so in the next month and quarters again to save money, avoid expenses, cut costs further, bring inventories down to keep liquidity so to say up at levels which are good for us.</p>
          <p>Formula One, in our company, there is more or less nothing which we cannot discuss, which we can &#x2013; there is nothing which we cannot discuss means, okay, we discuss everything and year-over-year, we are sometimes reviewing also Formula One. And but even for this year, even if you would step out of Formula One, you would not save any cents this year because contracts are more longer term.</p>
          <p>But that is only a financial position I had right now; the other one is a marketing position and if we have some new information regarding this, we would inform you of course immediately.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>At the moment, it's just not an issue at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I said we are discussing in the company everything what is wholly cost, because we are in a crisis.  But as I said before, I have no new information for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And to be totally clear about this, you may actually end up at the end of the year with a net industrial debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's not what I said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, please, if you go into the press and you quote me, that's not what I have said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, got you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next it's Aleksej Wunrau, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Aleksej Wunrau, BHF-Bank in Frankfurt.  Three short questions please, would you please quantify the amount of the credit loss provisions in the first quarter?  Secondly, the high unit prices in the truck and bus business?  What do these relate to?  Is it a mix, is it a sort of mix problem or benefit or is it pricing?  And thirdly, you changed the disclosure of your operating leases on the cash flow statement, so in the line vehicles and operating leases what amount would you recommend as to assume or to model for the total year '09?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question, of course, I mentioned that in my presentation that the difference between Q1 and Q2, Q1 sorry, in 2008 and Q1, 2009 is 268 million higher reserves than we had in this comparable quarter.  So, that is what we have done.  The second question, I hand over to Andreas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The contribution compared to the first quarter of 2008 and compared to the first quarter now of 2009, we have a positive exchange rate effect inside, and so far a very stable after sales business.  And this both brings us to this, if you compare it to revenue from the first quarter to this increase, what is this meaning, because the after sales business is still high on the same level than in the comparable first quarter of 2008, but the overall volume is down so the portion of after sales is higher and this is the effect, so after sales effect because of the decline of the sales volume and the positive exchange rate effects.  That's the only reason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And your last question, the only indication I can give you that you take the Q1 number, this is roughly 880 million I do think, which you see on page 21 in vehicles and operating leases kind of times four would be the best guess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That means you would contract your leasing book by that amount, by roughly that amount?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is more finance lease in this regard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, I'm going to clarify that one. But just a follow-up on your high operating leverage that came particularly surprising to me, so I wonder what caused this inflexibility in your material cost, is it part through agreements with your suppliers or pay on production schemes or maybe the long-term steel contracts, or is there any other sector that contributed to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you repeat that? You were referring to what disclosure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the high operating leverage...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>High operating leverage...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the very low EBIT there that is the reduction in the top-line, what caused that high operating leverage, is there any volumes that you guarantee to your suppliers that you take from your supplies, are there any partial agreements?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no and I don't know &#x2013; I'm a little bit confused where you are coming from, but the answer is no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So can you elaborate on that one, what were the sectors that caused that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, but I don't understand the question really.  We might also call Investor Relations that we can clarify your question you have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I've already called it. Though, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next it's Ranjit Unnithan, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi it's Ranjit Unnithan of JP Morgan.  The point you made earlier about the countermeasures, they add up to 4 billion, can you clarify how much is cost avoidance and how much is cost reduction of the 4 billion? I think I heard a number earlier saying that 1.4 was the cost reduction.  I just wanted to sort of confirm that.  My second question is on the bonds that are maturing in the rest of the year, it's about 6.5 billion, and you said you're going to issue very few bonds.  So essentially how are you going to pay for those maturities from your existing liquidity if you can clarify that?  And the last point I guess is on, last question I have is on your EBIT walk and the 2 billion year-on-year impact on the car division.  Is almost half of that relating to model mix issues and the remaining half volume, any split you can provide there would be quite helpful?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, regarding the 4 billion question of course we have made our disclosure with what is revenue related, what is material cost, what is personnel cost related, and this number is compared to 2008.  So, it is compared to as book numbers 2008 compared to a forecast in 2009.  You had a further question of course our liquidity will decrease as long as our maturing bonds of course are going down and we don't go to issuing a bond new.  Of course we expect our cost liquidity respectively going down and on the walk you had the question of the 2 billion, yes, what was your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, just the split between how much of it was volume and how much of it was price mix and model mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry as I said before but that was a question before that pricing is a low single digit number out of that, but we don't provide this kind of split in that regard.  It's mainly volume but also as we said before mainly volume means over 50%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And to sort of come back to an earlier question about the 4 billion, I know you made the distinction between how much of it is personnel and what have you, but I guess my question was, if you were to look at your cost base of 2008, you were going to spend a little bit more than that, and you avoided some expenditure.  My question is, versus the cost in '08 how much have you actually taken out in this 4 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have 40%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>40%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are taking out 40% times 4 billion, it's roughly 1.6 billion.  We are taking out compared to '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  All right, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next in line is Adam Jonas, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, Adam Jonas from Morgan Stanley.  I just have two questions.  First, back to the Mercedes division profitability and I guess it's more of an accounting question.  Can you walk us through, just an example, if you get an off-lease vehicle that comes, that you crystallize a value either through your CPO program or at auction, lower than what you had provisioned, does that flow through Mercedes profit as a net cost item?  I guess in other words, if you're having the same residual value issues on the off-lease vehicle that every other premium player is having, do you account that as kind of a normal course of business and expense, and could that partially also explain why Mercedes profit is under pressure?  Just from an accounting perspective, can you confirm how you do that?</p>
          <p>And then my second question is on the E-Class, where you have 50,000 orders.  And previous communication to the market, you seemed a bit more positive about the early reception, how the orders were, I think, you said greater than expected, and how in absolute terms it was significantly higher than the C-Class and given the C-Classes are much larger program that was fantastic, and very good news.  Now, you're saying that it's, I believe your words were, it's according to plan.  Am I reading that right that you kind of toned it down a little bit? And if I'm wrong, and it's still absolutely, it is an excellent motor and I'm sure there's a lot of interest in it.  I'm just curious again exactly where, who is buying this car, sorry to be cynical, but, how many of these things are painted a light beige-yellowish color with a Stuttgart license plate on it or specifically which country are these really selling well? Because when I asked you before, I believe the answer was, these were, it was too soon to tell because they were just dealer orders, that they weren't final retail orders at that point.  Can you give us a little more visibility?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Adam, you had a lot of questions.  Of course coming to your last questions, of course, we have said and we stated that the E-Class in this order intake is better than, the E-Class is better than the C-Class.  But, we have not said in the past that we are far better than expected.  We are, let's say, better than, you would expect the E-Class in that current crisis environment, that holds true.  And therefore the 50,000 order intakes are and we commented also on that, that it is not, everything out of that is retail orders because we have also some dealer orders in that of course in Europe for example where we have a better quality, no doubt, in this respect our own dealerships which we have in Germany for example, a high percentage out of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, regionally, is it Europe, is it Germany, is it Spain, is it the strong consumer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Europe. It's simple Europe.  Europe, I cannot tell, you know, what part of Stuttgart, but of course it's Europe.  Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, and then your question to the accounting is, you are right, with your, what you walked us through, with the leasing, that is right for the US for example.  We have a kind of difference in Germany because in Germany due to our own retail of course we have the production cost so to say in our balance sheet and then we depreciated to the end of the term.  So that is the only difference of course when you look at the accounting worldwide so to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Well, if you look at your competitors, that type of reconciliation of off-lease vehicles to the prior provision can be many hundred million euros.  Is &#x2013; notwithstanding that the accounting in Germany is different, if you look at where you do it BMW style, are we talking about tens of millions or low hundreds of millions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But Adam, we are &#x2013; they are also adequately reserved, because we have to do a write-off for example, when you see the production costs, so to say, everything in the balance sheet we have to write it off, if we do see the expected &#x2013; the expected that is in Germany.  The expected value getting down so you have to make a write-off, so to say, on that future production costs, so to say, from a market perspective.  So at the end of the day, I would guess is also not a huge difference here to anybody else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we are talking, so that can help explain this decremental or variable margin that keeps coming up on this call, the change of profit or the decline in profit divided by the decline of revenues being 66% is enormous but, so you're, we're acknowledging that some of that is the higher provisioning on a lower residual values.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can you quantify it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You see now that creates a problem now if, to be with all due respect, it creates a problem for comparability, because even though it's admirable that you are running this through the P&amp;L as a normal expense as I think it's probably the right thing to do.  It's hard for investors...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> In Europe, we have provisions for that and we don't have a further impairment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right but...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Therefore it's included there in the US.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you're &#x2013; but to the extent that BMW, for example, is providing a bit more visibility on the magnitude of these provisions and residuals.  Now, they call it unusual which maybe they shouldn't, but that's a question of debate.  It makes it hard to compare how you are doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You do the following and you might send us an e-mail with that disclosure and we look at this.  Yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Or you can be prepared with...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> BMW and I do think we are providing a lot of transparency and I don't want to refer to the net liquidity and other stuff where we do think we are perfect in transparency compared to others.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But please send me an e-mail where I can see what BMW is providing there and I consider to look at this whether we can do it also in the quarters to come or even give you a number for Q1, but I would like to see this kind of disclosure there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's fine.  As long as you're prepared to provide the more information is all that's valuable to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Adam, you know where we have seen the last years, I do think I was not hesitating.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To provide more and more information to the capital markets step-by-step.  We have now four divisions disclosed.  We have a perfect transparency in net liquidity, differences between financial services and industry.  I do think it's not bad, but I'm always happy to get information for improvement.  So, send it to us and we will consider...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we see there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we're on the same side.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Cheers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Unfortunately we can take only two more quick questions.  First one, Stefan Burgstaller.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, thanks for taking my questions.  Stefan Burgstaller from Goldman Sachs.  Just in layman terms, when you think about the restructuring program, the 4 billion cost savings, how do you think about it? How much is temporary in your mind and how much is actually structural, if you could just give a, the broad shape of this, it will be very helpful?  Second, I do appreciate volatility has an impact on the eventual outcome in terms of profitability, but you clearly have a budget, you clearly have an idea how you expect the top line to develop.  And I guess the 4 billion cost savings program must have been sized to achieve something and is the something a breakeven outcome for the Group? And if it isn't a breakeven outcome, what have you been using as a measure to size the 4 billion program?  And out of, let's say 1 out of 10, how confident are you as the CFO of Daimler that we have seen the worst in the first quarter of 2009?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, the first question, we took a program of course to, which has short-term impact and so to say the question whether what is sustainable or what is at the end of the day a one-time or whatever I, so to say, don't care, right now, because we do whatever we can short-term and everything we are happy to get there and we don't split it up in this regard.  And as I said before, I do think that this kind of cost measures we can forward for a longer period of time not only for 2009, if the crisis holds longer.  And we have prepared this program, honestly said and we commented on that also in February not on the best case, but more on the worst case side.  So, when we go to the cost side, it's better so to say to go on the worst case side than on the other side. With sales of course, try to get the best case scenario. Try to. Of course, it might not get to but on the cost side, more on the worst case scenario.  And if you ask me how confident am I as a CFO, as I have prepared interim reports and I have prepared the presentation, and of course, I am in close contact with my colleagues operational wise, that is a statement from all of us and especially also from me, that we have a stepwise improvement in operating earnings throughout the quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and last the question from Philippe Barrier, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'm Philippe Barrier from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.  Just two questions, first one is regarding the Financial Services, may we have a split of the &#x2013; with &#x20AC;268 million between the contribution of trucks business and car business in these provisions, a bit to <mark type="inaudible" /> a cost of risk in Q1?  And second question is regarding the attractiveness under the capacities in Europe, actually given the present trend in market, we may see a stronger overall capacities taking place in the market.  Do you think that the trend, you have to look to the capacity, production capacities at Daimler in Europe or in Asia to face the risk of declining market for the long period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Philippe, your question, of course, we don't disclose none, this kind of details what is trucks and passenger cars, all I can tell you the difference from the 268 more is for trucks, far more for trucks than passenger cars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your question, Philippe.  In NAFTA, we already adjusted capacity in our DTNA, Daimler Trucks North America repositioning program.  So, we think this adjustment is sufficient for also for lot of markets in Asia. Specifically in Japan, not Asia, but specifically in Japan, we are working at the moment in a program to look into potential steps what we have to do to adjust the capacity.</p>
          <p>In Europe, we have always said, we are going through a very or we went through a lot of fluctuation also in the past.  So in the last couple of years, we've put a lot of personnel capacity, in addition into our plants, mainly temporary workers and we worked special shifts everyday also Saturday and Sunday.  So, the first step was in Europe now to get rid of our temporaries, we have done this already and some other countermeasures and now the key program is the labor council will have it.  So, technical capacity, this is not an issue because as you may remember we had some issues in, two years ago with to be yeah able to deliver what our customers want, so it's more or less when you have to make some adjustments like we have done it now, in other words we saw a short working &#x2013; shortened working week and other steps, so this is the first step that we can work on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>More than that technical capacity is not necessary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your questions and being with us today.  Corporate Communications and Investor Relations remain at your disposal to answer any further questions you may have.  We hope to see you soon again.  Thank you and Auf Wiedersehn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>