<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1266525" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-10-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1183</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Dr. Gurdon Wattles, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Stefan Krause, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Christopher Wheeler</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Philipp Zieschang</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Stuart Graham</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Matthew Clark</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Huw Van Steenis</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Kinner Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Derek De Vries</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Fiona Swaffield</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Jeremy Sigee</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, I am Vicky the operator for this conference. Welcome to the Deutsche Bank Third Quarter 2009 Analyst Conference Call. Please note that for the duration of the presentation, all participants will be in listen-only mode and the conference is being recorded. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity to ask questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Dr. Gurdon Wattles. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Vicky and thank you everyone for joining. Good morning. Welcome to the Deutsche Bank third quarter results call. A little after 7:00 this morning European Time we put the PowerPoint charts, the earnings release and the interim report on the web and Stefan Krause the group's CFO is now going to take us through the selection of PowerPoint charts which were published.</p>
          <p>After that we are going to turn it over to Q&amp;A. We have a large number of participants on the call and I would ask for your understanding and in fairness to all participants make sure as many people as possible get to put their questions if we could say two questions per questioner. Thank you for your understanding on that. Anything that we don't cover then, please go ahead and call the IR department and we will make sure your questions get answered.</p>
          <p>At this point I would like hand over to Stefan Krause to take us through some of the charts Stefan please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Gurdon, and also from my part good morning, ladies and gentlemen, from Berlin today, not from Frankfurt as we had our supervisory board meeting yesterday here with the results that we informed you about yesterday night. So also welcome back to those that were on the call, yesterday. I would like to quickly go through the slides in the usual manner and then obviously I am happy to answer any questions you may have.</p>
          <p>If we start on page three, our group performance, we did have revenues of 7.2 billion in the quarter, a lower provision for credit losses of 544 million versus the previous quarter, income before income taxes of 1.3 billion, and a net income of 1.4 billion as we had announced. This results in diluted EPS of &#x20AC;2.10 and pre-tax return on average equity of 15%.</p>
          <p>On our capital and balance sheet, our Tier 1 ratio grew once more. We have now several consecutive quarters of Tier 1 growth to 11.7% and a core Tier 1 ratio for the first time above the 8% with 8.1%. We have reduced risk-weighted assets of 288 billion and total assets down 4% again to 1.66 billion (sic) [1.66 trillion]. And in our US GAAP pro forma calculation total assets were also down with &#x20AC;915 billion. Our leverage ratio of 25 times continues to be within the target range.</p>
          <p>On the liquidity and funding, with this quarter we completely finished our funding plan for 2009 with a total of 60 billion of capital market issued and we continue to have a very good cash and liquidity position.</p>
          <p>Slide four is a summary of our results. For year to date we have achieved an EBIT of 4.4 billion and a pre-tax return on equity per target definition of 18%. Our EPS at 5.62 three times the first nine months of 2008 and our dividend accrual remains at the rate of prior year's dividend as in the first and second quarter</p>
          <p>As you know we don't take a decision until year end, then the board recommends to the supervisory board what dividend proposal should go to the AGM and that's why it is our tradition to just accrue to the previous year's dividend.</p>
          <p>Our pre tax return on equity per target definition is marginally lower than reported. We had a gain on the sale of Daimler AG of course, which is excluded as you know from our from our usual target definition.</p>
          <p>On page five, we show our net revenue at 7.2 billion for the quarter, that included a negative impact from Ocala, the transaction in Florida of approximately &#x20AC;350 million. We had some impact of some other specific items, which we will cover in the respective business segment discussion.</p>
          <p>On page six, we show now our provision for credit losses that were 544 million in the third quarter of 2009 and as you can see substantially reduced from second quarter levels. Of this, investment banking credit provisions are 323 million, including 250 million due to reclassified assets under IAS 39.</p>
          <p>IAS 39 provisions are, as I have told you in previous discussions, mainly situation specific individual provisions and certainly this is not a calculation that shows any trends as we are working on the specific assets that were reclassified.</p>
          <p>In PCAM our reserves is 240 million, which are almost entirely related to our retail business within PBC. I will talk about the IAS 39 and PBC credit environment in a few minutes if you bear with me.</p>
          <p>On page seven, we cover our non-interest expenses as a whole. Our total non-interest expenses were 5.4 billion in the third quarter. Our compensation expenses were reduced versus the prior quarter. The delta is mainly related to the lower severance. As you remember in the second quarter call I had told you that the bulk of severance that we applied this year in order to do some of the restructuring we went through, was mainly expensed and would affect the second quarter, you will see in the third quarter significantly lower.</p>
          <p>In the current quarter, our G&amp;A expenses included a provision of 200 million, which is related to the bank's offer to repurchased certain products from private investors. To give you the background on this, due to a technical problem that we had in the composition of the underlying portfolio of the fund, the bank intends to restructure this fund. And because the relevant <mark type="audio gap" /> close end funds contained illiquid assets, the bank has decided to offer a repurchase of the product so as to provide investors with an exit from investment in that situation. Again, it's an offer as you restructure. We do not know how many of our investors will make use of that offer at this point in time, but we have taken a reserve for it.</p>
          <p>Other non-compensation expenses were 364 million in the quarter this was effect mainly the policyholder benefits and claims, in respect of the bank's investment in Abbey Life, which as you know always is a cash flow item which is offset by a corresponding amount in the revenue lines or just a hedge. But it was substantial this quarter because of the market environment that basically leads to the valuation of this number.</p>
          <p>On compensation let me clarify one issue, obviously we have had a long compensation discussion going on right now and how new compensation structure will look like. For us the most important principle is that we would like to continue to attract and retain top talent and obviously we would like to keep to market practices here. We will keep a compensation system that is mainly driven by what is happening in the market, that's why we're closely monitoring competitor actions.</p>
          <p>We definitely also, as some of our competitors have announced, have the intent to gain full compliance with G-20 and FSB guidelines. We had done already some of that in 2008, to highlight some of the main issues; obviously, we're looking at base salary versus variable. We're looking at stock versus restricted cash. We're looking at multiyear deferrals. We are looking at claw back provisions for senior people and obviously we are also looking at robust governance mechanisms that ensure independence of the decision makers around compensation items.</p>
          <p>On page eight, we show our solid profitability. I think we can definitely say, if we look at the first nine months, it is a quantum leap forward from the year 2008 and we have therefore significantly recovered from the bad situation we went through in 2008.</p>
          <p>On page nine, the net income of &#x20AC;1.4 billion, reflects a tax benefit of 78 million that does include some positive outcome of the tax audit settlements that were though partly offset by some revaluation of deferred tax positions which then resulted in a net benefit of 369 million.</p>
          <p>In addition like every quarter we have some tax exempt income which was about 174 million in the quarter. It's mainly related to the sale of our Daimler shares and the Postbank equity pick up, and as you know we do annualize this tax expense and that was about in the same level in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Including these specific effects and an accounting adjustment for this annualization of the tax exempt income, our ETR would have been in accordance with the range of our mid-term guidance of 30 to 35%, approximately. So on the full year, though, we now believe and the guidance we'll give you now on the ETR is that we definitely believe that we will stay now below 20% based on this significant one-off we had in this quarter.</p>
          <p>On page 10, we show a chart that we are obviously specifically proud of, our ability deliver increased capital ratios has been proven once more in the third quarter of 2009. We now have the highest Tier 1 ratio since the introduction of the Basel standards. The core Tier 1 ratio, which excludes the hybrids has also increased to 8.1, this is therefore for the first time above the 8% threshold.</p>
          <p>Risk weighted assets have continued to decrease versus prior quarter end driven by, on the one hand obviously FX effects on the one hand, but also by asset reduction as we have and have continued to de-risk the bank.</p>
          <p>Sal. Oppenheim, as I said yesterday, we continue to be very confident that the acquisition of Sal. Oppenheim will not stress our sore Tier 1 ratio. We have on the one hand two more quarters of retained earnings. And the second obviously, as I told you yesterday, I showed you a maximum of the Tier 1 impact we expect and as we go now into the closing process you can assume that we will continue to work on reducing that Tier 1 impact.</p>
          <p>On page 11, we show the Tier 1 capital development. Here obviously in the third quarter, the highlight is our hybrid security issuance of 1.3 billion and then combined with our net income &#x2013; our positive net income, our capital generation was 2.7 billion. And I show on the chart it was offset by FX effects, equity based compensation because we had the vesting in that account in August. And then obviously our pension plan accounting change that we did in the fourth quarter last year that now shows the volatility that we had made you aware of.</p>
          <p>On page 12, we show our total assets development. We have continued to strictly mange our asset base, our IFRS assets decreased 4% to 1.66 trillion. Our pro-forma U.S. GAAP assets, which are mainly adjusted for, as you know, derivative nettings and other nettings, decreased to 915 billion at a slower pace than before, but we have continued to be able to deal with the bank and therefore lower our balance sheet volumes.</p>
          <p>Our leverage ratio, the 25 times, that's in line with target. It is slightly up versus second quarter, because obviously on the one hand our equity has increased, but &#x2013; and our U.S. GAAP pro-forma balance sheet has reduced, however, our pro forma fair value gains that we apply on the capital calculation on owned debt have almost halved in the quarter.</p>
          <p>If I go &#x2013; move on now to page 13. As you know, this is the other part of our bank's balance sheet that we remain very confident and that we based on the strengths of the bank is our funding position that remained very strong compared to the beginning of the crisis. We continue to focus on the high portion of our unsecured funding and stable funding sources and we have completed, as I talked you at the beginning, our capital markets and retail deposits funding plan for the year already in the third quarter. So we don't expect any further measures to be taken in the fourth quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>Our cash and liquidity reserves exceed and continue to exceed our short-term wholesale funding of 76 billion, so good liquidity position overall. For 2010, we have relatively modest funding needs. Obviously we will have some capital market maturities that in our view can be funded without difficulty as things stand. We have to keep in mind that obviously, our significant balance sheet reduction that has gone on since the beginning of the crisis has also eased up this part of our business.</p>
          <p>Let me now cover some of the segment results and page 15 now illustrates the P&amp;L in our CB&amp;S segment and let me highlight some of the specific items that we had in the third quarter CB&amp;S results.</p>
          <p>The CB&amp;S results reflect, as I had told you previously, approximately 350 million related to the Ocala Funding situation, a commercial paper vehicle in Florida, as you know. I think you've read in the newspaper all about this transactions. It also shows the 300 million in losses related to specific risks that we have covered in our structured credit business. These negative effects on the one hand were partly counterbalanced by some net mark-ups mainly related, by the way, to our other favorite topic of the monolines which is 390 million of which 263 million were booked in sales and trading debt.</p>
          <p>We only had 38 million fair value losses on debt in sales and trading equity that's where we booked it. CB&amp;S expenses include a charge of 200 million to the already specified banks offer to repurchase this certain investment product I mentioned already.</p>
          <p>On page 16, I detail now the sales and trading revenues. Without the impact of the above mentioned items, especially the Ocala Funding then also the losses related to the write-downs on the specific risk in structured credit and the monoline driven mark-ups, if I take all those effects together our sales and trading revenues would have been higher by approximately 400 million and this is all in sales and trading debt, which shows you the strength of this business in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Despite these effects our sales and trading revenues are therefore really at a record level, 9% higher than the previous record in 2005. And against the second quarter it was a lower drop than the normal seasonal drop of 16% that we would've expected for the traditionally weaker Q3 results.</p>
          <p>And I think that what is especially impressive is that result now has really been achieved despite significant balance sheet and risk weighted asset reduction of which 40% and 20% respectively from peak level, so significant reduction in assets has not led into a cut in revenues, to the opposite have led to record levels of revenues.</p>
          <p>Risk weighted assets and our value at risk, we have further reduced from the second quarter to complete the picture at lower asset base with less risk, our revenue base is very strong, which shows the current strong margin situation we are experienced. We also have reduced some of our Tier risk through the de-risking of legacy assets as our business is more client focused.</p>
          <p>And now, on page 17, I go to sales and trading debt revenues that were 2.2 billion without the net effects of the specific items I just mentioned, debt, sales and trading revenues would have been 2.6 billion. Our recent markdowns are related to legacy credit assets which result in several billion risk weighted asset reduction in the coming quarters.</p>
          <p>Margins as you see them have continued to normalize from the peak levels, but are approximately depending on different type of product between 10 to 60% above the pre-crisis level. And something we are also very proud about in the current market environment, we have been to increase market share in the U.S. and Europe across all major products including FX, rates and credit.</p>
          <p>For example to give you some examples, according Greenwich and Euromoney, we're number one in global FX and we are number one in all major regions in this, in fact we're number one in European interest rate derivatives, number one in European investment grade credit, number three in U.S. fixed income and number three in U.S. interest rate derivatives. So, overall very good scorings.</p>
          <p>In credit by the way, we had our best quarter since 2007 in our businesses despite the fact or including the effect that our new strategy of creating more flow and client focused business has certainly completely paid-off.</p>
          <p>Our unique emerging markets local franchise has also produced excellent results across the board and now we're regaining the benefit from our ongoing investment in commodities with offices in Houston and Calgary expanding our range of products and services for our clients, so really good results across the board in that area of the business.</p>
          <p>On page 18, the same good development in sales and trading equity, this is our best quarterly revenue performance since 2007 of the peers that have disclosed, we rank number three globally by Q3 revenues. That's really a strong and great position that we have and historically certainly a big step forward.</p>
          <p>Despite some of the market normalization, our results were 2% higher than second quarter and we did include here 38 million of fair value losses on debt. Investment in cash equities is paying off. We're improving and continue to improve our position in the U.S.</p>
          <p>In July we won the Euromoney award for best equity house in North America and according to Bloomberg we have now 6% market share to compare out of 4% market share in 2007. We were voted the World's Best Prime Broker by hedge funds and global custodian prime brokerages survey. In derivatives our focus has shifted towards more flow and listed derivatives. In Asia, we won a number of equity derivatives awards from Asia Risk. In our prop trading, a substantial reduction of risk, as we had discussed in previous quarters and notional capital. Therefore obviously when you look at these great results in both trading areas, our &#x2013; we definitely have an improved asset efficiency and &#x2013; as we've also been able to achieve a much lower risk appetite as you can see one page 19.</p>
          <p>Our revenues per asset are now nearly three times the 2005 levels. We have reduced our asset base significantly versus pre-crisis levels, as I have outlined. Risk weighted assets have been reduced by nearly 20% compared to prior year levels. Our VaR has come down, our constant input VaR, which means adjusted for the impact of market data after it has decreased to its lowest levels since the beginning of the crisis and is over 50% lower than in the peak about a year ago.</p>
          <p>On page 20, we show you our Origination and Advisory revenues. We have also produced a solid quarter. M&amp;A activity in the industry remain very low. Our business in this area benefited from strong equity origination performance which was, by the way, the best since the second quarter of 2007. And a very good investment grade market driven by strong customer demand for debt and equity market issuance products, as you know, I'm sure &#x2013; you all are aware of.</p>
          <p>If we move on page 21 to our GTB business segment, it delivered 194 million, even under high pressure we have a very high pre-tax return on equity in this business.</p>
          <p>On page 22, I give you some more details about the performance in Global Transaction Banking, the business obviously, remained exposed to the low interest rate environment and the low corporate activity as a whole, that's significantly negatively impacting the business for GTB.</p>
          <p>Of course, on the other hand and that's a technical effect I need to make you aware of, GTB benefit from our risk based funding effect of about &#x20AC;63 million because of its refined funding methodology I already mentioned in the last call. That was valid for second quarter 2009, but obviously not for 2008 and on a year-on-year comparison there is a difference in the definition of the profits of Global Transaction Banking. Again the impact was &#x20AC;63 million</p>
          <p>Of course, on a Group level, yeah, there is a corresponding debit; on a Group level this evens out. So the Group level numbers are not impacted, it's just an internal, different allocation of our funding costs.</p>
          <p>We recently, as you know, announced that we now have signed heads of an agreement to acquire the ABN AMRO commercial banking activities in the Netherlands. We do believe that the combination will create a powerful platform for our clients. We therefore will become the fourth largest provider of corporate investment banking service in the Netherlands; obviously, assuming that we can complete this &#x2013; finally complete this transaction that we have waited so long for.</p>
          <p>On page 23, I come now to PCAM and the good news is that Asset and Wealth Management has returned to profitability with a pre-tax profit of 134 million. And this was mainly driven by the absence of specific charges, but also by some initial positive effect from the recalibration measures across these businesses and platforms and we saw also some more customer activity and the improving markets show already first sign of &#x2013; positive signs in the profit development in this business area.</p>
          <p>On page 24, Asset Management's performance was again driven by the higher market levels and tightening spreads, which led to an increase in retail revenues and performance fees, mostly in Europe. We have again right sized our global platform. Since we started restructuring in November of last year, more than 600 people have left already that platform, which represents about 18% of the workforce in that business area.</p>
          <p>Our net new money in Asset Management was 5 billion. PWM performance also continued to recover, driven by the stable revenue base and a positive contribution from the risk-based funding. The effect was much smaller, obviously, than in GTB, but we had an effect here. Since September of last year, we have reduced our head count by more than 300 people, primarily in Asia in this business. Net new money generation in PWM was &#x20AC;5 billion, an annualized growth rate based on invested assets of about 11% growth rate.</p>
          <p>We see all the specific items predominately behind us in this business area, obviously are making this statements assuming that we will not have a significant change in market. To complete, while the risk-based funding had a negative charge to Asset Management of about 6 million, the risk-based funding had a positive effect of about 18 million in PWM.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, we go into our private and business clients' P&amp;L. They reported an income before income taxes of 149 million. If you go to page 26, the revenues were impacted by this continued wariness of retail investors around the uncertainties in markets right now, and also obviously impacted by the low interest margin situation we have. This was obviously only partially counterbalanced by some revenue increase we had in our credit product.</p>
          <p>The provision for credit losses decreased slightly versus the last quarter, obviously as we have focused and had some more rigorous management activities and collection efforts that showed some positive effects. We see some additional severance in Q4, but relatively modest. We have done obviously some restructuring around mid-year. Obviously through the delays that severance package originate, we see some of people walking off the platform only at the beginning of next year.</p>
          <p>Again, expenses decreased, mainly driven by this reduction of the severance payments, and I think that was the biggest effect in their cost. PBC had also securities inflows of about &#x20AC;1 billion.</p>
          <p>As here on page 27, we now show you the described net money flows by quarter and we spread it out by our three different business divisions that you see that we have been able to grow our asset base.</p>
          <p>Let me now go into last part of my presentation and cover quickly some key current issues. And I think we come now to the main and most favorite topic of the market around Deutsche Bank. Right now, we have taken &#x2013; I really would like to say it once more, we have taken a lot of time. And we've done a lot of math and we've looked at worst case scenarios, likely scenarios. We have looked at all the measures that we've taken. We looked at all the regulation that's coming. We've looked at the structuring of the business. We have really done a company-wide very extensive research on our capital base, on the future, on our long range planning, on what our risk-weighted assets will look like in the future. And again, with done this &#x2013; doing this review and looking at possible new rules, expected new rules, but as I show you on page 29, also looking at effects that will counter the increase in &#x2013; driven on risk-weighted assets, looking at our business plans, etcetera we can &#x2013; I can overall reaffirm that our target of the Tier 1 ratio of above 10% on a going forward basis, we will be able to achieve despite the headwinds we might have in terms of higher risk-weighted assets and we are including now what I would call the double punishment scenario that on the one hand we will see an increase in risk-weighted assets and second we will see an increase in ratios as well, which at the same time is a double punishment and we continue to stick to our statement that we are fine on the capital front as you look into our planning and the only comment we have been making for this is any acquisitions that we have to make certainly will require then capital measures.</p>
          <p>On page 30, I give you the usual disclosure on the loan book, maybe we cover some of the specific questions that may arise. In the questions, we've included here the IAS reclassified assets and we show you in which buckets they sit. And deliver therefore also an explanation why this portfolio has been more impacted by loan loss provisions.</p>
          <p>In the different manner it's not run rate loan loss provisions, it's one-time specific items, I will gladly answer any further questions you have about our loan book and discuss it in questions.</p>
          <p>I show now the pro forma impact on IAS 39 reclassifications on page 31, as you know we are obliged to that and just mentioning it briefly you saw the significant decrease that we had in the gap between accrual accounting and mark-to-market accounting that went from 6 billion, both in capital and P&amp;L down to 4.2 billion a reduction of 1.8 billion. So the expected narrowing of the gap between the mark-to-market driven in illiquid markets, in our view a wrong valuation of this effort is now closing the gap. On the other hand, of course, any loan loss provisions that we take on this portfolio are also helping to reduce this gap. As you saw, we have not further reclassified any assets in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>On page 32, we show the problem loans. IFRS impaired loans have risen by about 100 million since the second quarter, due to increases which were largely offset by charge-offs and repayments. Problem loans were up by 500 million, materially all loans &#x2013; these are loans where the borrower is in financial difficulty, basically, but these exposures are either collateralized or guaranteed. So despite the fact that we had this significant increase, I could almost call it a no risk or risk free increase because of the type of loans that have gone into that bucket.</p>
          <p>Our impaired loan coverage, which excludes collateral, rose to 47% and if you would exclude the much lumpier IAS 39 reclassified loans, coverage before collateral improved to 59%, which is very much in line with our European peers.</p>
          <p>On page 33, we wanted to give you some sense for how our delinquency ratio development is also to explain mainly effective. We do see the same effect that some of our competitors have reported with rising delinquencies mainly in consumer portfolios. At the same time, if you look at the mortgage portfolio you see how stable it has developed throughout the crisis only slight increases, but not material increases. And then if you look at the small corporate book, we also see the reported increases in delinquencies. But now, again, because mortgage the loan book represents about 70% of our PBC loan book, that's the explanation why we continue to track below reserve levels of our competition. Something to do with, obviously, how our loan book is built-up and what assets it comprises. So we have just higher asset positions on those assets that run lower delinquencies.</p>
          <p>On monoline exposure, good news in the third quarter, overall our monoline fair value exposure before CVA was reduced by 1.8 billion in the quarter. As you can see from the chart, here on the chart we put the two quarter comparisons on the reserving logic. We do our reserves against this exposure will also reduce by 945 million.</p>
          <p>The overall notional amount of our monoline insurance is down approximately 30% from its peak, 29% from its peak, driven by the expected roll off of the high quality corporate CDOs which have had a short maturity and again by the previously mentioned significant settlement and commutation of contracts with &#x2013; to monolines.</p>
          <p>So you see in the highest risk bucket the non-investment grade monolines, that contains the highest risk category of the assets. Basically, we are at nil exposure by end of the third quarter. And reserve levels in all other buckets remain at the previous quarter levels.</p>
          <p>So on page 35, to really sum up and we always like this chart, because it shows the progress of Deutsche Bank throughout the quarters of the crisis from year ago, our position has continued to improve significantly. We're considerably more profitable despite the fact that we continue to absorb quite a significant amount of charges related to legacy positions.</p>
          <p>Some of our businesses have been recalibrated, we have taken risk down. We have taken leverage down. We have improved our operating performance. We have increased our Tier-1 capital ratio, which is at the highest level it ever has been. Our core capital has also steadily improved and again, I reiterate again some of the feedback we received to Sal. Oppenheim acquisition does not concern us in that regard as we will be able to manage down this 85 basis points and our balance sheet efficiency has therefore significantly improved also in historic context. So bottom line a bank that's less leveraged, that's better capitalized, that shows lower risk, but at the same time shows higher profitability.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much. And I am open for any questions you may have now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Stefan. Can we have the first question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. The first question is from Mr. Christopher Wheeler, MainFirst Bank. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. And well done on good set of results, obviously. My couple of questions are about, well, first of all the asset management business. Again, obviously a much improved performance. However, if I just extrapolate some of the numbers, it appears to me that the gross margin on your asset management piece in the first nine months was about 30 basis points and then if I strip out, what I think might be 60 basis points on the retail element it appears the rest of the assets under management earned about 15 basis points. You've talked about the cost cutting, the job change &#x2013; job losses, but it appears to me with the cost ratio in the combined entity of private and wealth management still up in the 80s, you still seem some way off even in improving markets from having the right cost base to match the revenue opportunity in that business. And I am sorry to keep going on about this every quarter, but perhaps you could just give us some flavor as to how you are going to get that cost income ratio to perhaps where it should be?</p>
          <p>And the second question just relating to the same area of business, you kindly gave us some indication as to how private wealth management has actually done at a pre tax level in the last two quarters. Can you tell us whether you actually did make money? I guess you did, perhaps give us some feel for the extent of that profitability in the quarter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Christopher for your questions. Let me cover this asset management business. Number one, you are completely right. That business continues to be exposed to the crisis. We do have obviously lower fee income and that continued. It did improve somewhat in the third quarter. We still obviously lack to a large extent also the performance fee component and our business model is certainly more performance fee skewed than it is base fee skewed and therefore obviously as markets recover, we might see higher margins in that business, hopefully as the performance fee component kicks-in. But at the same time this is one of the discussions that we had in the bank in terms of recalibrating this business is moving it further away from the performance fee concept and more into a regular fee concept.</p>
          <p>What have we done in terms of restructuring and changing this business, you wanted some of these components, is we have done a lot of work on the mid and back office. And we have seen some good opportunities, for example, just to give you a very simple example. We've moved some of that out of the U.S. into Europe. We have moved some of our fund administration. We are consolidating the number of funds that we run. We one &#x2013; certainly one of the areas where we have to do a better job in the future. And while the business and the management is focused strongly on is just to reduce the sheer number of funds that we run. We are consolidating this.</p>
          <p>We did look at Asia; we have right-sizing Asia. Obviously, we have all our risk business within this and we are restructuring debt. For example we are selling some component of this business, which deals with the management and of our commercial real estate positions. So, I think, there is a lot going on that will result in a much improved cost income ratio. I hope I gave you some ideas of some of the levers that we can pull.</p>
          <p>Your second question was the...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Private Wealth Management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Private Wealth Management, yeah. It was a profitable business. We had around 40 million in EBIT. So it did contribute in this quarter. And also there we see the same effect that we see clients coming back and the business recovering. So, about 30% of the Asset and Wealth Management P&amp;L this quarter came from PW, just to give you a flavor for the number. Thank you, Christopher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we have the next question, please? Thanks Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Mr. Kian Abouhossein, JP Morgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I have a few very quick ones. First of all, structured credit write-downs of 300 million. Is this the last write-down that should be, we should expect or should we assume there is further clean-ups to come in the next quarters?</p>
          <p>Second question IB capital down 13% quarter-on-quarter, risk weighted assets down 4. You're running capital roughly in line with '06 level in the investment bank. Just trying to understand why capital is declining?</p>
          <p>Third question IB revenues, you are below the top 3, top 4 players in fixed income equities. But is that something that you are happy with and you will have a more steady business in the fixed income and equity line due to being more flow focused? Or is it something where we expect you should over time take again more risk and as a result you will be in line with some of the top players in terms of revenue generation?</p>
          <p>Very quick, one last question, corporate and investment, you had a &#x2013; sorry, corporate and adjustments, you had a relatively large negative impact. Even if I strip out owned debt, I still don't understand exactly the number, if you could explain it. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On our structured credit mark downs, I think one thing we've learned is not to use the word last throughout the crisis, but we defiantly are getting closer not to see any of them. But again, in the third quarter we were surprised by, for example, this Ocala transaction. These are events, I think, but I would certainly describe it as a more normalized business. I think we definitely believe that the bulk of issues are behind us. But obviously in our recapitalization planning, obviously, we do have some assumptions of further de-risking if you so want it, further work on assets now, that needs to happen at not the increased pace we saw throughout the crisis quarters but we certainly will see some of it coming. But definitely I would say not at the levels that we &#x2013; that you saw in the beginning &#x2013; in the leading quarters of the crisis. So that's for that.</p>
          <p>The IB revenue is below, we don't share your view. Again, I tried to highlight how strong our IB revenues were in the fixed income area. We had an outstanding performance for Deutsche Bank in the fixed income. We had record levels in the fixed income. Our comparisons show that we are faring very well versus also some of our competitors. So I don't think that's an area that we have any problems on. We don't understand where the perception of this as a weakness comes from, because we really have historic record levels and are developing quite well, despite the fact that, yes, we changed our business model quite considerably in this business area.</p>
          <p>On the C&amp;A, large negative. The main issue is obviously the timing differences we have between our M-to-M &#x2013; mark-to-market versus accrual accounting on our TSY function -- our treasury function &#x2013; our treasury and how we allocate the treasury cost. You saw some positive effects in the previous quarter and now obviously we saw the considerable swing back in the third quarter. This is an effect that, over time, evens out, because obviously we clean up the different levels. But certainly, based on the risk, based on the swing this number will show, you will always see this kind of volatility in this space, and it can be pretty sizable, especially if we showed a couple of quarters of positive development.</p>
          <p>Your last question was the IB capital and that's a more fundamental and strategic question. We have de-risked this business quite considerably. You see the lower VaRs that we've had, which was considerably down. We see &#x2013; you'll see -- and therefore obviously some of the assets we got rid were assets that carried higher risk-weighted assets. But the free-up, and that's exactly the concept we're looking at, the free-up of those risk-weighted assets will provide us with potential for growth in the investment bank as we move along. And therefore I think it's a natural and a good development based on the fact that we de-risked the platform.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But if I look at the &#x2013; if I take risk-weighted assets against allocated capital, you run at a Tier 1 of about 8.3 on allocated capital at 8.3. Sal. Oppenheim yesterday, we talked about 11, it used to run closer to 9 to 10 historically. I'm just trying to understand why in &#x2013; post what happened, your models would tell you to reduce capital?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again on the investment bank, our allocated capital is down. And that is something that's really because our internal economic capital has dropped much more significantly than the regulatory risk-weighted asset has dropped and that's the effect that you're seeing there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kian. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Philipp Zieschang, UBS. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Two questions please. The first one, could you comment on your expectations with respect to loan loss provisions. I know it's a tough one, but in PBC, we've seen actually a positive development quarter-over-quarter. But could you just share with us your view about 2010, and probably also the proportion between the IAS 39 related loan loss provisions versus the underlying?</p>
          <p>The second part -- I'm still trying to get my arms around where you are in terms of de-risking. Could you just tell us, where are you with the measures you introduced probably earlier this year or late last year, with respect to debt savings rating, i.e. de-emphasizing credit prop, et cetera, et cetera? Is this going to led to further reduction?</p>
          <p>And tying this into your slide 29, where you say your asset reduction initiatives, is this something new or is this a continuation? And could you please add probably a risk-weighted asset number which you think this could actually lead to in terms of reduction? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Philipp, thank you for your good questions. On the loan loss provisions, I think you make a fair statement. It's very difficult to forecast some of those buckets, and the most difficult bucket to forecast is the IAS 39, because these are event &#x2013; single name driven situations. If the economy improves, there are some leveraged loans in there -- as an example, if the economy improves and these companies do better then certainly we might have less of loan loss provisions to deal with than if the economy worsens.</p>
          <p>So it will be contingent on that, and it's case-by-case. It also could be specific company situations that lead to loan loss provisions. So this will remain just volatile. That's all the guidance I can give you on the IAS portion of it.</p>
          <p>On the development, and that's what I wanted to show you, the delinquencies on the development of PBC's loan loss provision. Again the main driver is &#x2013; we are well structured in terms of our composition. So that's why we don't expect now as the mortgage piece of it seems to be as evened out at this level and you saw some of the other delinquencies also even out. We expect &#x2013; we don't see right now this whole thing going down either. We don't -- but we don't expect a further raise in this figure as we move forward.</p>
          <p>For 2010, the only one that's really somewhat predictable is obviously the PBC loan loss provisions in the retail, in the sections of this portfolio. And it's our view currently that we will be slightly up from current levels. Again, this assumes a similar situation, economic environment situation as we have right now. For all of the rest of the portions of the loan loss business, it's very difficult to make forecast and predictions.</p>
          <p>On the asset reduction, this is just a continuation of the efforts we have done. If you look into Deutsche Bank's balance sheet, we still have some considerable positions within our balance sheet that I would classify as legacy. These &#x2013; as you know one of the concerns that we raised and one of probably the issues that we learned through the crisis that we needed to address is the longer term assets. We do have some stuck assets and we need to reduce those. Some of these stuck assets, and that's our capitalization concept includes that, do carry some significant risk-weighted asset charges, that's why it's highly attractive for us to work on it. We are not talking about unsubstantial numbers in this area, but again, I would like to abstain from giving you fixed risk-weighted assets number for each one of the line items I outlined in my chart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Philipp. Could we have the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Stuart Graham, Autonomous. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. I have one question, actually. Sorry, it's actually going back to the Sal. Opp. deal from yesterday. Can you just explain why 1.3 billion is the right price to pay for it? Because I think on a fair value basis you are saying you think it's worth minus 0.3, and it seems to me the partners were pretty much forced sellers. So can you just sort of explain why 1.3 is the right number, and why you couldn't negotiate a lower price than that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Stuart, believe me one thing, if you were our new price negotiator then I have a lower price , but you also have to stay realistically.</p>
          <p>At the end, just taking all parts apart, Sal. Opp. has approximately an equity capital of 2 billion, okay? So if we didn't pay anything, we first acquired obviously a risk free environment, if you assume that we have negotiated deductions, yeah, in that amount. So I think number one, step one, we acquire a place that for which, in the purchase price, we have accounted for all potential risk, markdowns, et cetera, that we saw in the due diligence. And I think to negotiate a capital base of 2 billion down to zero is, I think, a good achievement.</p>
          <p>And then, let's not forget, we are buying a very high quality, 100 &#x2013; more than 130 billion large portfolio as a whole, yeah, including 116 billion of private wealth management and asset management portfolio. And if I look at the trading multiples, the selling multiples, we had even in pre-crisis levels, in crisis levels, all these valuations were above 2% to 5%, yeah, of assets under management. And by paying 1 billion for it, and obviously using the 1.3, which contains a pass-through component -- let's not forget that we initially will pay 1.3 billion, but we intend to sell a portion of it, so our true payment is 1 billion -- so to pay 1 billion for 130 billion assets and 116 private wealth management assets, honestly I have problem to understand why anybody would question that this is a good price.</p>
          <p>At the end, you have to get the counterparty to sign as well, yes? So it's something that &#x2013; and you also have to be realistic that a transaction of this &#x2013; is a distressed investor &#x2013; a distressed seller to some extent, yes. But it is a good company, this is well-run company, it's a well run value proposition. And it's a healthy customer base and healthy employee base that we acquire with it. So I think that's my evaluation of the pricing consideration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess what I am struggling with is, it's an asset which comes with a lot of off balance sheet liabilities, which we can't really value, and we're having to kind of trust that you've been able to do due diligence...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's exactly what I said yesterday in the call. We are taking a significant hit to cover those, yeah? To an extent that you can assume that we will be probably &#x2013; and that's a big incentive for the shareholders is &#x2013; this component of this off balance sheet has a big incentive for the shareholders to have &#x2013; not to see this risk materialize. And these are financial incentives for them not to happen.</p>
          <p>And the disagreement in the deal process was exactly that. Was this &#x2013; we put a very high, conservative value on this risk. They disagreed with us, and that's why we put this earn-out structure in place. If they're right, they'll get a price incentive. If we were right, we are completely protected.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Stuart. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Matthew Clark, KBW. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. First question, on the de-risking burden that you showed in previous quarters, I think 1.1 billion in the first quarter, about 700 in the second quarter. Was there any de-risking burden in the third quarter in addition to the disclosed write-down items?</p>
          <p>Next question is just coming back to the corporate center. Maybe I missed your answer, but just wondering if you could say a bit more about the seeming hedging losses that are going on there &#x2013; is there some &#x2013; are they economically meaningful? Is that accounting noise that you think we should ignore, just how to look at that?</p>
          <p>And then thirdly, coming to Sal. Oppenheim, could you just talk about the long term capital needs of that business? So, even if you aren't able to shift risk-weighted assets with the carve-out of the investment bank, presumably you've got an idea of what sort of risk weighted assets you need to run those businesses long-term, say five years out. Could you maybe give us an idea of that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first question is we disclosed everything we had. The 300 million -- we discussed it -- honestly, we discussed it at length. Because we've had this effect in the previous quarter, and we disclosed it's not significantly more. It has come down significantly, but the 300 million, there is no more, this was it for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Second on these hedge losses, it's just accounting noise, something you don't &#x2013; shouldn't worry about. It's again the MTM versus accrual accounting effect, yeah?</p>
          <p>So &#x2013; on your Sal. Oppenheim deal, let me go back. We disclosed to you the 85 basis point worse case scenario, assuming obviously that &#x2013; which I think is likely, that we use the same Postbank structure to pay for the transaction because, of course, this is highly attractive for us to do so. We are now selling the investment bank and selling the investment bank assets, which will be a significant reduction.</p>
          <p>For the remaining of the business, once we are through the rest of let's say some other asset clean-ups, we are through the sale of some other assets in the bank, we are through with paying down some shareholder loans in the bank, we will see a substantially reduced assets, total asset base of Sal. Opp. That's just what's going to happen.</p>
          <p>With this substantially reduced asset base in Sal. Opp., you can really &#x2013; and that's the best guidance I can give you &#x2013; you can look at traditional risk-weighted asset charges, capital charges that a business of a size of 130 billion in assets will traditionally carry. It will be clean. That's why we're moving it over. It will not be as mixed business activity anymore. It will be more a clean asset management, private wealth management business and company for Deutsche Bank. And you can apply traditional capital charges to that type of a business.</p>
          <p>The problem right now is that we have some assets that we had, due to the speed in which we had to consummate the transaction to avoid a further worsening of the situation in Sal. Opp., we decided to take onboard all the assets they had. But we have obviously -- and that's why we're disclosing plans to sell some of the assets that strategically don't make sense to us, and especially some of the assets that carry risk-weighted assets and capital charges that don't make sense there.</p>
          <p>So in your projections, you can assume that this will develop into a pretty clean, focused private wealth management and asset management type of business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just to follow-up, can I take &#x2013; you don't expect any losses on sale of those assets because that's taken into account in your conservative valuations or write-downs on inception?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We wiped out 2 billion of equity in the deal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question is from Mr. Huw Van Steenis, Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. So congratulations again on your investment banking results. Can I just get back to the legacy assets? Probably sort of three questions.</p>
          <p>One is you mentioned I think at a recent presentation there are four leveraged loans you're currently renegotiating in Q4. Obviously, you can't tell us the outcome yet, but could you give us a sense, would it be your expectation, the provisions on the IAS 39 assets in Q4 would be materially higher than Q3? Or any sort of color you can give us on that?</p>
          <p>Number two, is there any way that you could &#x2013; I think you've taken, over the last five quarters, about 1.2 billion against the IAS 39 assets. Could you sort of schematically break that into leveraged loans, commercial real estate, and other?</p>
          <p>And then thirdly, particularly for commercial real estate, I think it's quite difficult for us to track your expectations versus what the outcome. And obviously some of that will be next year. From a management point of view, what sort of cumulative loss are you expecting for the commercial real estate portfolio? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Some <mark type="inaudible" /> questions. First, on the legal assets, I didn't say that we're renegotiating, we are restructuring, yeah? And it's only to clarify maybe a word.</p>
          <p>Our leveraged loan is a traditional situation where we have a company -- again, I told you when we reclassified these assets, we looked at the quality of these assets at that point in time. And these companies continue to service their debt. That's not the issue obviously.</p>
          <p>And therefore, yes, we're working on some of these companies. To be honest, it's very difficult to say when these negotiations, when these restructurings will conclude. You always have to assume that some of the aspects will take some months until you kind of, on the one hand, take respective management decisions, agree on restructuring, and then it will take some time until operational effects then show the improved results. So that's why it's so difficult to project what is going to fall into Q4, what is going to fall into next year, and that's all the best I can tell you right now. It will remain volatile.</p>
          <p>We see as these situations are being worked on, as the situations evolve, to develop, of course a worsening in the environment or situation &#x2013; specific situation of the company may change this number. And as these are large exposures, obviously a minimal additional charge-off is already in the size of a few hundred million very quickly. So, it will just &#x2013; all I can really say -- it will be volatile.</p>
          <p>On the &#x2013; we don't expect, obviously, and at current levels, we don't expect necessarily these be higher than the ones we had in Q2. That's our current expectation, but I really have to put this big caveat on one of these situations may change over the next couple of months. We go into January when we have to do &#x2013; finalize our account numbers, situation might have changed. Business trends might have changed. We might have to take a hit on that.</p>
          <p>On the commercial real estate business, it's about only 10%, yeah, in there. So it's not a high number. So we don't expect this to be a larger exposure. So in that area, year-to-date IAS loan losses are primarily leveraged finance hits. Yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, that's the guidance I can give you on those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Huw.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question Mr. Kinner Lakhani, Citi. Please go ahead, sir,</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. I've got two questions. Firstly, could you give us some guidance in terms of the outlook that you see for bid offer spreads? And to what extent you see a spread/volume trade-off, i.e. volumes could pick up against further spread compression?</p>
          <p>And the second question, just coming back to your IAS reclassified assets, the 34.7 billion that you show on page 31, do you disclose anywhere what the RWAs are attached to those numbers? And is that essentially a run-off portfolio? Maybe if you could give us some kind of duration on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me start with the bid offer. We have always said, we have really gone into the beginning of this year with very good margins, and then we saw, in the second quarter, the beginning of the deterioration of these historically high margins. And we've always made the statement that bottom line, we believe, and that's what I also told you, we're right now on a pre-crisis level, depending on the product, between 10% to 60% up. And that's what we expect it also to be, yeah.</p>
          <p>So, I think, we will just see a better margin environment. And when you go into the reasons for that, everybody is trying grow capital charges, everybody is pricing for risk accordingly, et cetera. So therefore we need definitely see this push. And certainly the leverage has moved from customers, and an increase in supply of this type of product to now rather a market in which demand is somewhat reduced -- in which supply somewhat reduced, sorry -- in which demand started to go up. And therefore, what we have seen in this area is that we are in control of pricing and price control is back at the banking side of it.</p>
          <p>And there's obviously one thing you can assume. As capital requirements increase, this area will continue to be difficult and customers outside will have to face higher pricing.</p>
          <p>We've seen some competitors coming back. We see some banks recovering. And certainly we will see competition on it. But we do believe that, overall, we will see higher margins on a going forward basis.</p>
          <p>On the IAS-39 risk weighted assets, that's a number we don't disclose, yeah? We don't give this number. So just for your information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Kinner. Our next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Derek De Vries, Bank of America. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. I have two questions, I want to touch on I think what Kinner just talked about.</p>
          <p>On slide 19, you show that interesting revenue to assets of 297 versus the history of about 128. My cynical nature, I guess, is to just say, we go back to trend and therefore your revenue is more than halved versus the current levels. So I am hoping maybe you can help convince me otherwise by explaining is it the velocity that's different? Is it the spreads that stay different? Have you made market share gains? Or why is that 297 sustainable?</p>
          <p>And then the second question is just a quick one. Can you just remind us the risk-weighted assets and the goodwill from the ABN acquisition, so we can plug that into our model?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think that -obviously I understand that this is a very core discussion around what's going to happen to revenue lines and revenue pools on a global level, and we have done quite some work.</p>
          <p>The main trends we see -- I think we definitely -- and that's what I already said -- we definitely believe that we will see higher pricing levels than pre-crisis, and we will see higher margin levels than in the pre-crisis situation. Not to the extent we saw at the beginning of the year, I repeat myself, but to the extent or to the levels we are achieving around now.</p>
          <p>The reason for that is, again, we have many competitors not come back at this point in time. We have and we will see an increase on demand. We have, on the competitor side, reduced and restricted supply. And therefore, obviously, that's one effect we see biasing towards higher margins. The second is everybody in the crisis has learned that you need to price for risk better, that you need the price for capital charges. We are all confronting a higher capital charge environment. Also that believes &#x2013; assures us that we will have more pricing discipline.</p>
          <p>I agree with you -- will this stay on for 10 years? Nobody knows. But will this stay on for the foreseeable future as we move out of the crisis. I think we see more biases towards higher margins than we see negatively biased towards lower margins.</p>
          <p>Of course competition will return. Of course we have seen some practices already again that we saw in the pre-crisis times. We can never make a prediction on how speedy we will go back to this type of environment. Our belief is, though, it will take some time.</p>
          <p>And on the volume side, obviously we have less competitors in the environment. We are gaining market share. I also had in my presentation, we strongly believe that we will continue to be a market share gainer, and we do believe that for example the slide to quality will continue.</p>
          <p>I think that many of our customers that have seen Deutsche Bank perform well throughout the crisis, that there will be a benefit for those banks, number one, that have stayed out of state capitalization. And number two, of banks that have stayed loyal to the customers throughout the crisis. I think that will enable us to continue to build market share. And we have taken some strategic decisions in our global markets businesses to build out and to invest into some businesses.</p>
          <p>So therefore, we see market share up, we see higher than pre-crisis margins, and so that's why we are not concerned about the ongoing. And then, obviously, we will see a growth in regions like Asia, and that's why we definitely believe that we will be able to maintain this rhythm of revenues we have right now. With, you know, the same type of profitability.</p>
          <p>On top of it, we have de-risked this platform, we have gotten more efficient, so even on the cost base in this business, we are so much better than the pre-crisis level, so that's why we believe that profitability in the investment bank will continue to be a very interesting assumption.</p>
          <p>The risk-weighted assets for ABN by the way, they will be non-material for closing. And we don't expect this closing to happen this year, so now we are just in finalization and waiting for the respective approvals. But in our pro formas this year, there is no substantial goodwill or risk-weighted assets for ABN &#x2013; ABN AMRO. And going down into next year, it's not a significant impact that really worries us in terms of capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Derek. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mrs. Fiona Swaffield, Execution. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Madam, could you speak up a little bit? We can't hear you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, can you hear me better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you could focus on slide 16, I've been confused for some time about the underlying. And I think you gave a slide at a recent conference where you obviously added everything back, as someone previously said. So the underlying run rate is coming down pretty fast.</p>
          <p>Would you agreed that Q3 looks to be down about 20% on Q2? I think, something like 4.3 billion ex all the one-offs? It's now about 3.5, 3.4, or am I missing something? And if that is right, then is it just the bid offer spreads coming in or is it seasonal? Because I always thought that Q1 was seasonal. And then should we think that Q3 is more of a normal rate in terms of trying to forecast sales trading revenues going forward?</p>
          <p>The second area is Postbank. I'm just trying to understand what makes from here, in terms of change of ownership structure, what are kind of the touch points and what would determine your decision in terms of whether to buy out minorities, etcetera?</p>
          <p>Then the third issue is on the slide on the moving parts on capital. I just wondered, I mean, it looks to be, to me, to be quite tight. I mean when you talk about dividend, could you be more specific about how much scope you have to pay dividend if you're trying to rebuild the capital? I just wondering in 2010, do you think you can have a normalized payout ratio, or do you think it will take you to 2011 to go to a normalized payout ratio? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, three good questions. The first one is of course Q3 is always seasonally impacted. We've seen it over many years. Q3 is a weaker quarter than obviously Q1 and Q2. But as I outlined in my presentation, again, we did not see a significant seasonal impact in this quarter's comparison. Next year, we may see it again. We didn't see it this year. And if you look in the underlying calculation, again, we are, as I outline, including these one off items about 400 million higher, than what the reported number is if I do this underlying calculation, yeah? And therefore we see &#x2013; we had an excellent quarter taking into account that this is seasonally a weaker period of the year. So, we are very happy with these results and I think they definitely compare very well with what you &#x2013; what else you've seen in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Can I just add &#x2013; this is where I am confused, because at the Bank of America conference, you put up a slide on sales trading revenues where you were saying the underlying was 4.3 in Q2, because you would add back 700 to the Q2 base. Am I missing something?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we &#x2013; we are trying to find it out. Can we follow-up offline on that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...comparison? The second &#x2013; as a second question you ask on Postbank, yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Postbank the position right now, we have no need to move quickly, yeah, and our trigger point for this is, you know, we put the optionality in place because we wanted to have the optionality. We put the optionality in place, because we wanted to see how the crisis developed, how situation is for our capital planning that enabled us to do good capital planning. We have time till 2012, bottom line.</p>
          <p>And what should change our mind or the other drivers of our main decision is more general environment. Postbank, they're doing a great job. They are managing the business very well. They are reducing their risk. And as we've always said, why should we therefore go in quicker. We are very well running our joint project and creating the synergies between the two organizations. So, we are not losing any time in realizing synergies. People are working on processes, people are working on systems. People are working on consolidating some of our processing. People are working on revenue opportunities.</p>
          <p>We are creating products that Postbank can sell. So, we are achieving absolutely the same levels of synergy. I always made the 20% deduction that you can take out eventually when you take down some of the corporate center activities. But other than that it's really no urgency for us to move from an operational point quicker into the Postbank transaction. And the environment currently is helping us to move ahead and have &#x2013; and get to an asset that may carry less risk weighted assets at the time of purchase than it's carrying right now. And therefore obviously in terms of our capital planning, that's something we are looking at.</p>
          <p>In terms of the dividend, to be honest, if you look at the slide on this thing, it's traditionally we accrue to previous year dividend policy because we don't have a new decision. I will honestly say we don't see a big pressure on dividends right now. It's the environment. You know, so many things are hampered for dividends right now, cannot &#x2013; aren't able. So don't see this big. I think right now the priority is to continue to build capital. For us to continue &#x2013; the priority continues and remains not to dilute our shareholders. And therefore, of course, we will build up dividend over time, but certainly no need for an increased payout there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can I now, in the interest of time, we have time for two more questioners, and please I ask you to keep it succinct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Jon Peace, Nomura. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Thank you very much. Just a couple of quick question on slide 29, the capital, you talk about a Tier 1 of greater than 10% by December 2012. Could you tell us what you think of your core Tier 1 target within that?</p>
          <p>And just also on the dividend, are you looking to a payout ratio still in the medium term and what would that be and how quick might it be until you get there?</p>
          <p>And finally just on the leverage ratio of 25 times, is that still an appropriate target? Should we be looking at leverage based on total equity or tangible equity? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The honest answer to all your question is, at this point, we don't know. There is so much in the environment, yeah? We don't have a capital definition to which eventual new rules will apply. We don't have a capital ratio that regulators will defend. We don't exactly know how these different measures, the first estimate that we have on how all these changes in regulation will apply. We just honestly don't know. This is something, hopefully within the next couple of weeks, will be clarified and resolved.</p>
          <p>We do not have a core Tier-1 target, because right now we are managing the bank to Tier-1, that's what we have. We understand that obviously a new capital definition, that, by the way, will look differently than the current eventually core Tier-1 definitions, but that's why in our sense &#x2013; in our view is unnecessary at this point to put out another type of a definition that we don't know how it will materialize. So we don't have that.</p>
          <p>Everything we hear, though, tells us that 25% leverage will be fine and absolutely okay, and this will be probably the most likely scenario that we see right now. Could we be wrong on that? We could. If though what we believe and the majority of the voices we heard around negotiations are telling us initially actually is that it will be below that. Initially we thought that the most likely scenario would be a 20 times and now we definitely believe on all what we're hearing it will a 25 times.</p>
          <p>So on that front, that's regretfully hopefully another quarter. Next quarter we will be able to be more specific, maybe it's going to take another two quarters to be even more precise and specific. Then we would issue new targets. Then we would issue &#x2013; and that's why we would like to stay with our current target until the point new definitions are around.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. May we now take the last question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question is from Jeremy Sigee, Barclays Capital. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. Just one very simple question please, you referred to a big debate about compensation and clearly there are many, many dimensions to that. Given that kind of it's another don't know element, are you just accruing mechanically at the moment using the formula-based approached that you discussed in the past or are you applying some of the subjective judgments from that debate or adjustments to what revenues you pay comp on at this stage? Are you being mechanical or are you trying to reflect the debate already?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are materially mechanical, to answer your question. There have been some slight adjustments which mainly refer to the expected payout because I think the one robust part of it will be that it will be &#x2013; there will be multi-year deferrals, yeah? So there have been judgments because in our &#x2013; it is a mechanical approach but that assumes a judgment on inputs and on the one input we made an adjustment because we assume that we will have the deferral component. That was similar to last year. Let's not forget in 2008 we did have a larger part of deferral already applied so we are trying to stay more consistent to what we saw in it, but other than that, it's materially mechanical.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you're not, for example, adjusting revenues to say this element of revenue there is windfall profit from wider spreads or from cheap central bank funding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Jeremy, and thank you all for your attention and your questions. The Deutsche Bank IR team welcomes follow-up questions and additional questions. At this point once again with our thanks I would like to close the call. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the conference call is now over and you may disconnect your telephones. Thank you for joining and have a pleasant day. Good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>