<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1171736" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1183</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Wolfram Schmitt, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Anthony di Iorio, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Dr. Wolfram Schmitt, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="4">Michael Rohr</participant>
      <participant id="5">Anthony di Iorio</participant>
      <participant id="6">Wolfram Schmitt</participant>
      <participant id="7">Huw van Steenis</participant>
      <participant id="8">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="9">Anthony di Lorio</participant>
      <participant id="10">Kinner Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="11">Jeremy Sigee</participant>
      <participant id="12">Matthew Clark</participant>
      <participant id="13">Christoffer Malmer</participant>
      <participant id="14">Stuart Graham</participant>
      <participant id="15">Dirk Hoffmann-Becking</participant>
      <participant id="16">Philipp Zieschang</participant>
      <participant id="17">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="18">Fiona Swaffield</participant>
      <participant id="19">Georg Kanders</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and good evening. I am Sherry, the operator for this conference. Welcome to the second quarter analysts conference call. Please note that for the duration of the presentation all participants will be in listen-only mode and the conference is being recorded. After the presentation there will an opportunity to ask questions.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
          <p>At this time I'd like to turn the conference over Dr. Wolfram Schmitt, Head of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you, Sherry and good morning to everybody. This is Deutsche Bank's second quarter call. Earlier today we have issued our earnings release, our financial data suppliant, the full interim report and I trust you all have in front of you the set of PowerPoint slides which will support this call.</p>
          <p>I have to draw your attention to the leader disclaimer as usual regarding forward-looking statements. I trust you have read them all and carefully and so therefore I don't have to read it out. It's an integral part of all our disclosure documents.</p>
          <p>It's my pleasure to introduce Tony di Iorio, CFO of Deutsche Bank, who will in good tradition brief you on this call on our quarterly financials. But I have to add that for all of us in Deutsche Bank it is a very special call, because it's Tony's last analyst briefing due to his retirement end of September as you all know.</p>
          <p>Tony, on this note let me hand over to you. The air is yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Wolfram, and good morning everyone and thank your for joining us on the call. This morning we announced our third -- second quarter results and if you start from the PowerPoint presentation, I'll flip through these charts and then we'll be happy to answer questions when we are done.</p>
          <p>Group performance was income before taxes of 600, net income of a comparable amount to diluted earnings per share. The highlights of the quarter's performance are probably in CB&amp;S [Corporate Banking and Securities] where we reported a 300 million loss for the quarter despite the fact that we took mark-downs of 2.3 billion which we'll discuss a in little more detail in a minute and we believe that result show the strength of many of our underlying businesses.</p>
          <p>The stable businesses: GTB [Global Transaction Banking] and the PCAM [Private Clients and Asset Management] business reported income before taxes of 900 indicating the results of our investments in those businesses and the resilience of those businesses even in difficult market such as we have experienced. Corporate investments had income of 300 million: some of that was from the sales of industrial holdings; some of it was from dividends, the second quarter is the normal height of the dividend season here in Germany; and it also had some mark-downs on our option position to buy more shares in the Chinese bank, Huaxia.</p>
          <p>Capital risk and liquidity show continued strength. Our Tier 1 ratio at the end of the quarter was 9.3% well above our eight to nine range that we have targeted. There were significant reductions in exposures and we'll go through those charts shortly. We still have ready access to the funding markets. We have raised over 40 billion in the first half of this year in the capital markets with debt with a maturity of greater than one year which stabilizes our funding source and we have reduced our balance sheet by 159 million from a restated number in the first quarter adjusted for some net downs that we have not been taking previously, but I will describe that in a second.</p>
          <p>If you turn to the next page, you will see the summary and I won't spend too much time on this. Revenues were down, but that's after the 2.3 billion of mark-downs. I want to focus for a minute on the tax line, because the tax line was a small net credit and this is due to three factors.</p>
          <p>The first is the geographic mix of our earnings because of the mark-downs, we experienced losses in some entities in the United States. The tax rate in the United States is the highest of all of our geographic tax rates. So that reduces our global rate mix.</p>
          <p>In addition to that we had a benefit after the successful resolution of some pending tax matters, which we had provided for and we have released what we had provided. And finally we had a negative effect because of the decrease in our share price; we released some previously recorded tax benefits on the deduction from the amortization of our equity compensation. So despite that charge in the quarter, the other two factors reduced our tax rate to a small negative.</p>
          <p>If we turn to the next page, you will see the -- where we took the mark-downs of the 2.3 and what we did with exposures during the quarter. And I am not going to read each of these because we'll go through them as we go through the businesses, but on the exposures that we're going to show you in detail, we have 2 billion of which 200 million was in our leveraged finance portfolio and the balance was in our sales and trading businesses.</p>
          <p>In addition to that we had about 100 &#x2013; just under 100 million of write-downs on some European RMBS securities that are not shown on this chart.</p>
          <p>And we also took an impairment; this is the third straight quarter in which we have recorded an impairment on available for sale securities related to our consolidated conduits. We have talked about this in the past. And this charge had been reflected in the equivalent of other comprehensive income. We deemed an event to have occurred and therefore transferred that from our equity section through the P&amp;L and that was about 200 million.</p>
          <p>If you go to the next chart, you will see our net revenues are down 39% to 5.4 billion. And that -- a lot of that has to do with the mark-downs and with the strength continuing in our stable business.</p>
          <p>If you go to the next chart, which looks at expenses and I want to spend sometime on this. Our expenses are down 23%. And they are -- if you look at the compensation number, this is driven by lower performance during the period. And as we've indicated in prior meetings, we look and true-up on a year-to-date basis, the impacts of the performance and the schemes, the general accrual schemes we have for compensation.</p>
          <p>When we look at accruing incentive compensation, we look at two primary factors. The first is segmental performance and we accrue at different rates in each segment consistent with compensation levels in the market in our different businesses. But we also look at group performance and if overall group performance is not at a standard or a level that management believes is appropriate then we always keep the option of adjusting the segmental accruals. And we -- the barometer we use to make this evaluation is our overall comp ratio and you'll see later or in the disclosures that our comp ratio for the quarter was just over 50%, so it's about 50%. So that's how we approach it and we true that up on a year-to-date basis each quarter.</p>
          <p>Compensation in this quarter, in the first quarter also included some accelerated equity amortization and we've mentioned this. And this has to do with grants made in the first quarter to individuals who were eligible for early retirement, therefore don't have to provide service for those and we &#x2013; so therefore we expands them when granted. That number was a first quarter event, we did not have &#x2013; we have a comparable number each quarter, but it's those people who in that quarter have reached that early retirement, so the number is decreased by a significant amount.</p>
          <p>If you look at the dark blue the general administrative expenses you will see that likewise that is down. And that's due to a series of factors. The first is favorable FX movements in respect to the euro, the second is lower litigation accruals compared to the second quarter last year and the third is cost containment initiatives and this is principally in discretionary areas. We look &#x2013; we have looked at professional service fees, travel, entertainment and similar expense and have seen good reductions in those.</p>
          <p>In addition there was a charge in the second quarter last year, related to the renovation project, currently ongoing in our headquarters in Frankfurt and that was a second quarter '07 event that was not repeated.</p>
          <p>There is a small 100 million shown at the bottom, which we've been isolating that was a credit in the first quarter for policy holder benefits and claims in respect to Abbey Life, the closed book insurance company that we have acquired in our global markets business. This quarter it was a charge and that has in both quarters zero net pre-tax income effect, because there is a comparable amount in revenues.</p>
          <p>If we look at segment results, you will see on page seven, the description of what those results are and I'll go though and &#x2013; page nine; I am sorry, page nine &#x2013; and I'll go through each of the business segments in a minute, but let me just focus on consolidation and adjustments.</p>
          <p>We reported a loss of 176 million there, the bulk of that loss is due the true up of our management accounts on which the segments are based to IFRS. And that number could go up or down depending on what happens in the individual businesses.</p>
          <p>If we look CB&amp;S, CB&amp;S and we mentioned this in our summary, reported a pre-tax loss of 311, but that is after taking, reflecting mark-downs of 2.3 billion. We saw solid volumes in our flow, sales and trading businesses, including our finance business, our FX business and in equities our -- some of our cash equity business, as well as in our prime services businesses and we will go through those in a minute.</p>
          <p>We had lower revenues in origination and advisory, including the 200 million charge for leveraged finance and we saw substantial reductions in exposures. Some of our peers have shown the chart similar to page 11 and so we thought we would also include it.</p>
          <p>Looking at a comparison of what the pro forma revenues would be in CB&amp;S, absent the mark-downs. And if you saw in the prior page, we reported revenues of 2.2 billion, the extreme right bar. If we were to add back to that, the 2.3 billion of mark-downs net of hedges, we would have had pro forma revenues of 4.4, which is within 900 million, less than a billion from the second quarter last year. And I want to emphasize the second quarter last year was our strongest second quarter in our history, so we are comparing against a very strong standard.</p>
          <p>If you go to Sales and Trading debt, you will see that our revenues were down to 602 million for the quarter. And this is where 2 billion of the mark-downs are reflected. If you look at the businesses that contributed, we have strong results from the FX, rates and money market businesses with strong client flows.</p>
          <p>One of the things we're seeing not only in this business but throughout, and I'll comment on this in equities in one of the businesses in a minute, has been an increase in market share and a migration of clients to Deutsche Bank from many of our peers that are having or experiencing more difficulties in the markets than we are.</p>
          <p>Now our credit business revenues are down, and this was due to a reduction in our structured credit business. We took some of the mark-downs in a monoline business against this activity. And we also &#x2013; however, we did see a good flow in our customer flow business.</p>
          <p>Commodities was down and this is primarily due to trading losses in the U.S. power market. Commercial real estate is down, we took mark-downs here, but we are continuing to reduce the risk and in our RMBS this was the largest mark-down area we took, about 1 billion, and this has principally been in the Alt-A portfolio. Many of our peers began aggressively selling down their RMBS positions in the second quarter and we as others experienced a mark-down here, because of the drop in the valuations in the market.</p>
          <p>If we would go to Equities, you'll see that our revenues are down there as well. Our equity derivative business saw reduced activity. And likewise, we have a smaller ongoing effect in correlation from the first quarter much smaller in size, but yet continuing.</p>
          <p>Cash equities, very challenging markets, but we see continued growth in North America. The Prime services business is the other business where we've seen migration of flight to quality, so to speak or how we would express it with not only existing clients doing more business with us but likewise, with new clients that we previously had not done much business. Designated proprietary trading is flat to the second quarter last year.</p>
          <p>Origination and Advisory, revenues were down. Our Advisory business M&amp;A volumes are down for the quarter, however, we had our strongest ever ranking in announced volumes, number four globally, as is shown on the chart, number two in Europe, Middle East and Asia and number four in the United States. So we've maintained and in some places increased our market share, albeit the reduction in overall volumes.</p>
          <p>Equity origination we saw the same trend with declining market values, issuance of equities likewise, with the reduction in the M&amp;A activity has declined. We're happy with the performance of our investment grade debt origination where we've been -- we've shown an increase in the revenues for the comparable period and we've maintained a top five ranking. And in our high-yield and leveraged loan business this was characterized principally by the mark-downs we took -- although we did show healthy net interest margin offsetting, so we took 200 million of losses approximately, in the mark-downs, but that was offset by just over 150 million of net interest margin.</p>
          <p>That net interest margin has been declining as we derisk the portfolio. And we'll continue on that trend as we continue derisking unless we &#x2013; the business comes back to where it was previously, although we believe, risk-wise and the transactions we're seeing in the market, are being structured very differently and many of them are coming from the strategic buyers rather than the financial buyers.</p>
          <p>The next several pages deal with our exposures and the progress on our exposures; these are detailed here, but also in more detail in our interim report, as well as with more extensive narrative than what is here. The first is CDO subprime exposure. This exposure, and the next one on the residential mortgage-backed securities, the data that's shown here assumes the loss we would have if 100% of the underlying assets defaulted, and there was a zero recovery from that default.</p>
          <p>As you can see, our gross exposures are down, and our hedges are about where they were, and they are down slightly, as they've been readjusted. So, our net exposure is about flat.</p>
          <p>We'll spend a little more time on the next chart, which shows our RMBS business, and you can see the reduction in the Alt-A portfolio of about 1 billion. That is principally from our mark-downs. On the CDO book, we were able to liquidate positions. In the RMBS book, the liquidations were fewer. So the bulk of the change is the mark-down.</p>
          <p>As I indicated earlier, there was extensive selling in large blocks by many of our peers during the second quarter. This put considerable pressure on values and that is reflected in the mark-downs we took of about a billion in this quarter.</p>
          <p>We've monitored this risk very carefully. We're looking to do other things to de-risk. I would mention that there's still a considerable size, albeit it lower, and therefore there is basis risk between these positions and the hedges. Many of our monoline hedges are also in this area. And we'll talk about that on the next chart, as to what we've done there.</p>
          <p>The monoline exposure in the Alt-A book, you can see, has increased from March to June. And this would parallel the change in the value of those positions. And on a total basis, therefore, we're up. On a net basis, however, we have provided over 500 million for potential credit impairments on this monoline activity in the quarter, and we derive these numbers on a fundamental name-by-name analysis, looking at ratings, in many cases there're some very extensive discussions with the monolines as to their situations and claim-paying ability. And we're now have total allowances against this book of 800 million, of which about 700 million is taken against the exposures on the left-hand side of the chart. The balance is against other monoline exposures. And if you look at the first comment on the right, you'll see that that exposure is an additional 2.2 billion.</p>
          <p>In our interim report, we've included an additional disclosure this quarter for the first time, which analyses this monoline exposure by rating band, and so I'd reference you to that.</p>
          <p>If we turn to our Commercial Real Estate business on page 18, there is a summary of our traded loans. And you can see that our net exposure -- or carrying value, rather -- is down to 10.7 billion. I do want to add -- make a couple of comments as to comparability to the prior period.</p>
          <p>First is, in the prior disclosures we did not include exposures in Asia, which we have for the first time here, and those exposures are less than a billion, Asia Pac. In addition to that, we had in place some synthetic risk reduction in the first quarter that we did not use -- did not put on the table, showing the reduction of what impact that would have, but we're including it on this chart.</p>
          <p>Overall, those adjustments would not have changed the trend, and we're showing a drop of considerable size on a pre-reserve or pre-allowance basis, from 16.4 to 12. And on a net basis, down from 14.4 to 10.7, so whichever way you look at it, considerable.</p>
          <p>We took 543 of additional gross markdowns during the period. You can see that at the bottom of the chart. And we had some hedges against that. If you look at the distribution, of our remaining exposure, net exposure, you'll see that the largest area of exposure we have is in Germany, and the reduction has been most felt in North America, where we're now down to less than half.</p>
          <p>Since the end of June, we've had additional reductions that are not reflected on this chart, and we'll be reporting on those when the third quarter events occur. We're continuing to look to sell. I'm sorry, that's leveraged finance, not the commercial real estate, commercial real estate does reflect through the synthetics, the others, I apologize for that.</p>
          <p>On leveraged finance, the next chart, we have had continued reduction here. These numbers are comparable to the way we presented them in the prior quarter. You can see that there were considerable sales of 7.2 billion. There are some new commitments being made and I alluded to these earlier when we talked about the origination business and we've also had some cancellations.</p>
          <p>That brings our carrying value at the end of the quarter to 24.5 billion, as I indicated earlier there've been some additional reductions since the end of June which we will report on the third quarter and these bring our exposure to approximately 50% of where it was at the end of August last year so very considerable activity here.</p>
          <p>I should add, because there were some questions at the last meeting and in some of your reports, you raised the question as to level at which we're valuing these comparables to our peers. Every week we publish a report showing the prior week's sales activity and one of the parameters that I look at that report is on the sales we have made, how close our realized profit or loss is to our unrealized i.e. our marks. And I can tell you that we have been selling positions through July at approximately our marks and to me that's says that our very thorough analysis process and there is a lot of judgment involved in most of these valuations, are producing results that are comparable to what we're liquidating positions in the market.</p>
          <p>In both, the commercial real estate as well as the leveraged finance we've included additional disclosures which will show you the industry areas to which these commitments or loans apply and I think from looking at that chart you will see that there are some notable areas that we are not exposed to &#x2013; notable industries, automotive for example and that could make a difference between your estimates as to what these mar-downs or carrying values are and the actual values that we place on them.</p>
          <p>Although, the actual values are ultimately determined by what we can sell for in the market I want to reiterate that the values at which we are selling are at or near, with very little difference, our marks.</p>
          <p>If we turn to the next chart, on the stable businesses, you will see that there is continuing solid performance, 854 million, which is up from the second quarter last year. And I will go through these in detail.</p>
          <p>First in terms of GTB, very slonge trajectory. 283 million, up 15% on our income before taxes from the prior year second quarter. And this has been characterized by growth in our custody business, in our trade finance business and we've seen this growth in revenues despite the effects of lower interest rates and the weakening dollar, particularly.</p>
          <p>We announced in July, the acquisition of the Dutch mid cap business of being -- coming out of ABN as per the large three-way acquisition there. And this indicates our strategy of looking for strategic expansion in stable businesses where we see values that will generate positive shareholder return within a reasonable period of time.</p>
          <p>If you turn to Asset and Wealth Management [AWM], here we've had a decline from the prior quarter -- prior period quarter by 17%. And this is due to two primary factors. The first is our fees that are asset based were lower, consistent with declines and deterioration of markets, particularly in the equity markets and this affects our mutual fund business specifically. And also a reduction in activity in our real estate business, particularly where in the prior periods we either showed performance fees, which we said were lumpy, and in the current markets those are down. As well as reductions in both the sales of businesses that were reflected in the second quarter last year, which we disclosed on one of our Australian businesses, as well as the sale of investments that were held in this business either into funds or into the market.</p>
          <p>On the positive side, we showed net new money during the quarter in invested assets of 8 billion and for the year-to-date in the Asset and Wealth Management business of 15 billion. We think that this is a very positive and strong result. In talking to the people in these businesses, particularly the Private Wealth Management business, we are seeing a flow out of other banks that are currently experiencing problems in a greater extent than we are. And we believe that we have opportunities here to further strengthen these businesses particularly in the Private Wealth Management arena.</p>
          <p>As far as PBC [Private &amp; Business Clients] is concerned, we have an increase of 11%, 328 million, above -- 11% above the second quarter last year. Revenues of almost 1.5 billion in the second quarter and this came from increased margins on both our deposits and loans. But, particularly on the deposit side where we've seen active campaigns in our retail branch network, raising deposits. I'll show you a chart later where we talk about stable funding and as a bank with a large retail presence, we have opportunities to provide more stable funding in this area. We've mounted fairly active campaigns here in Germany and we've been very successful, particularly in our Norrisbank business where our deposit flows have been very strong.</p>
          <p>We've also seen increase in insurance brokerage and a lot of this has to do with some retirement products here in Germany as well as in our payments and accounts services businesses and that's been somewhat offset by a reduction in the securities brokerage business consistent with the reduction in the market -- in the market conditions.</p>
          <p>As far as net new money here, we've seen 3 billion of inflows in the second quarter and 7 billion for the whole year. If you turn to the next chart you'll see what has driven our change in invested assets in PCAM and we're slightly above where we were at the end of the quarter and as you can see on the chart that comes from both from negative performance in the market as well as some other activities which have to do with sales of businesses, transfer of businesses.</p>
          <p>Modest FX effect this quarter; in prior quarters, the FX effects were much stronger. And you can see that the 10 billion of net new money in PCAM again this portends well, we think, for the future and we anticipate continuing net new money coming in to the bank.</p>
          <p>If we turn to Risk, Capital and Liquidity, our provisions for the quarter &#x2013; and I'm on page 26 here, provisions for the quarter were 135 million and if you look at the bottom of the page you'll see the business areas that drove that. In CIB [Corporate and Investment Bank] we had a net recovery though lower than where we were in the second quarter last year of 9 million but an increase in PCAM from 124 to 145.</p>
          <p>This increase comes from two principle factors. The first is the growth in our consumer finance business and as volumes grow credit costs would grow with them. And this we saw particularly in Poland which is a key strategic buildup area for us and our credit business -- consumer credit business there is performing very well, as well as increased credit costs in Spain where we've seen some softening in the market and those are reflect.</p>
          <p>If we look at our problem loans on the next page you will see that under the IFRS definition of an impaired loan, we're down to the level where we were in the second quarter of last year, 2.5 billion. Our coverage ratio is approximately the same at 65%.</p>
          <p>For transparency and for reference we also show on this chart, the difference between the impaired loans and the problem loans. The problem loans are under the SEC definition, U.S.-GAAP definition and because we report that in our interim and 20-F reports, we've included it here for your reference.</p>
          <p>If we turn to the Tier I ratio and this is something that shows significant strength, we've had yet another increase to 9.3 billion and -- 9.3%, I apologize, with risk weighted assets of 305 billion. And I would mention as far as our dividend assumptions are concerned, we continue to reflect in our net -- in our Tier I capital a reduction for the dividend on pro rata basis equal to the &#x20AC;4.50 that we paid last year.</p>
          <p>As I said in the first quarter call this is not a commitment to pay that dividend, but it is a prudent treatment and in some respects it shows the strength of this 9.3 number because it was not achieved by changing our dividend accrual or by other means. So it's something I would reflect on and we'll be monitoring the dividend as we go through. The dividend decision is one base on recommendation in the beginning of next year by the Management Board and has to be ratified by the Supervisory Board.</p>
          <p>Balance sheet size has been an issue of much discussion and in fact we've had reports from many of you raising the question and we do hear you. I would like to reiterate that the principle benchmark we use is risk weighted assets and if you look at the prior page you will see the achievements that we've made there. But we hear you and we are looking to do some things as well in balance sheet size. What we've done in this chart is shown, several things. It's a very busy chart, and I will try to give you a highlight -- a high level view of it.</p>
          <p>At the end of March of this year, we reported assets of 2.3 billion. Subsequent to March, we went back and reviewed the treatments of netting that we were applying under IFRS and we identified additional netting of 156 billion that was possible. So want to show the transparency of the number we reported previously to the number that you will see in our interim report now.</p>
          <p>So the 2.305 billion has been reduced to -- 2 trillion -- I am sorry. I will get my millions, trillions and billions mixed here. The 2.3 trillion we reported at the end of March has been adjusted in our interim reports to 2.150 trillion. And we wanted to show you that bridge so that when you went back into the reports and looked at your models it was clear that -- what drove that.</p>
          <p>However, during the quarter, there was some further reduction of 159 billion, most of it coming in the positive mark-to-markets from derivatives, but also in trading securities and in the reverse repo line. So from the numbers you were using to calculate ratios previously we're down 314 billion although, only 159 billion of that is due to activities. The bank has recently asked Stefan Krause who will succeed me as CFO effective October 1, to head a project working with the businesses to find opportunities to reduce the balance sheet further, consistent with our goals of growing revenues and growing solid performing businesses and Stefan will report on that to you when he produces his first analyst call in the third quarter -- for the third quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>One of the issues we do want to highlight is, it is tricky using gross balance sheet numbers. And we have mentioned this to many of you and I know we have not convinced you, but in our persistent effort to make the point &#x2013; I hope we don't bother you by this &#x2013; we are going to show you the calculation again. If you look at the prior page, the fair value of our derivatives as of June 30 was 640 billion.</p>
          <p>If you really look at the credit risk inherent in that portfolio, you would see that it's a whole lot less. There is -- there are legally enforceable master netting agreements that we have available to us. Many of these derivatives are with exchanges. Where we have a difference after netting, we do ask our counterparts to provide collateral if we are in a net receivable position and we have some of these derivatives with sovereigns and other public sector entities. If we were to adjust for those effects, the exposed credit risk on this portfolio is 77 billion.</p>
          <p>I should also add that in most cases because of the collateral, much of the gross or the net exposure provides funding or other collateral that we can use to hypothecate and raise funding. So the funding impact and the credit impact of this large mark-to-market in our derivatives book has a very different risk profile from assets that we or others may carry in other categories.</p>
          <p>If we continue on funding, you'll see the effects of our -- what's happened to our stable funding base and we continue to strengthen it. Since June of last year, we have transferred substantial amounts of short-term funding, dependence on overnight funding, to more stable capital markets and retail deposits as well as fiduciary balances. And I talked about both of the capital markets before. We've had 40 billion of long-term debt issued so far this year with maturities medium-term to long-term debt of greater than a year. And I talked earlier in PBC, but somewhat in PWM [Private Wealth Management] of the efforts to increase our stable deposit base.</p>
          <p>The next pages raises another very interesting phenomenon which has not yet translated itself into equity evaluations. But if you look at what's happened to our five-year CDS spread what we can borrow money for. Our spread albeit higher than where it was a year ago is substantially lower than many of our peers at 63 basis points. And we draw your attention to that.</p>
          <p>That's the end of my prepared remarks. The highlights here are similar what's on the first page. So I'll stop and turn it back over to Wolfram, then we will entertain questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Tony and Sherry I will hand it over to you direct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. The first question is from Mr. Michael Rohr of MainFirst. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. Very good morning. Three questions from my side.</p>
          <p>First of all in terms of the underlying fixed income revenue, if we adjust for the one-off that you had in the quarter in secondary fixed income we are just talking a 5% year-over -year decline and I just wanted to know apart from the strong flow business that you had, how much do you think is due to the market situation i.e. people seeking Deutsche Bank for liquidity management, hedging and other trades that they need in the current market environment?</p>
          <p>Second question which refers to page 12 of your presentation again, if you could quantify the decline in the structured products revenues that you had and potentially elaborate a bit more on the trends going forward for this and how much this might influence the revenue line going forward, although it might be relatively small item?</p>
          <p>And the final question, more a personal view question to you, Tony, and how far do you think are you in terms of de-leveraging at Deutsche bank in terms of balance sheet size and how comfortable do you feel in the environment right now? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Underlying revenues in fixed income, we think a substantial -- we think that there are two basic drivers. The first is our footprint, the breadth and depth of our relationships because if we didn't have that then nothing else would happen and nothing else would matter. So we have a very strong franchise and we've said this all along. There have some issues and dislocations in the market that have affected the revenues and performance. But we continue to be convinced that we do have the strong depth and breadth globally by product, by any measure that you would look at the abilities of our people.</p>
          <p>We are seeing increased market share as well. I wouldn't quantify that right now. And we are seeing clients migrating to us. Now how much of that has to do with leaving where they are, how much of that has to do with our product and our platform, I don't that I am &#x2013; I can give reasonable rational answer to that, but we are seeing the effect and we do measure the increased market share and we are seeing it. So I believe your hypothesis that the decline is small and that's due to of flow of clients, we believe is correct.</p>
          <p>As far as the structured business is concerned, we're definitely seeing a reduction in that activity. We are looking to do some things and we believe that looking forward into the future at least for some time we'll see more straightforward plain vanilla product offerings. We believe that the structured product business is not over and our belief is founded on some very basic facts.  Bank capital is under pressure. Businesses around the world have demand for continued funding and if it can't come from the banks, it has to come from other sources and we believe that one of those sources is structured credit, perhaps in a different form from what had been offered structured previously, probably a different risk profile and other parameters but we don't see this business as over.</p>
          <p>With regard to deleveraging, I don't think we want to forecast a number as to where our balance sheet would reach. There is a lot of dynamics going on. Some of that has to do with what's happening with values in the market because if we have positions that increase or decrease in value, that affects the balance sheet size, but we do have a program underway. As I said it's got the new CFO or the future CFOs leadership, so it's got board member leadership and we'll be reporting and he'll be reporting to you on that as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I please add that you limit to one question or keep it really crisp because I know we have a lot of in the queue. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Huw van Steenis of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning everyone. I just wanted to ask just a series of questions around the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Number one, a number of banks have been suggesting they think there might be a new treatment for trading book assets over the coming two or three years. Any views on that?</p>
          <p> Jamie Diamond recently was very critical of the calculation of risk weighted assets for some of the U.S. investment banks and I was wondering if you share some of his concerns and what that may mean for yourself?</p>
          <p>Then lastly, we've obviously now seen the U.S. investment banks' balance sheets for the first time. What's interesting is their assets to risk weighted assets ratio is roughly 3:1, I think yours is about 6.5:1. If I even adjust yours to U.S. GAAP basis it's about 4.5:1 and I was just wondering what you think contributes to why your assets to RWAs [Risk Weighted Assets] is so much higher than some of the U.S. peers? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Huw, can you just clarify the first question on the trading book treatment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A number of the European banks are suggesting they thought that the Basel committee may have another look at what the right weightings would be for the way some assets on the trading book are treated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, the risk weightings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the risk weightings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry; I thought you meant the fair value treatment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no I apologize. I'm sorry for the lack of clarity. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome Huw. I don't want to forecast or project what the Basel II committee or any other regulator is going to say, or for that matter Accounting Standards Body. We will just wait and see what happens and if they change, then we will modify our calculation.</p>
          <p>On your second question, what I'd draw your attention to is the composition of the balance sheet. This is the reason that we don't believe, and I know there's different views here and we respect and appreciate those views. We don't believe that you can look at gross. And the very point you've made &#x2013; now if the risk weightings on trading assets change, obviously, that's going to have an impact. But if you look on page 29 at the largest component of our balance sheet, it's on the derivatives. If you look at the reverse repo book, if you look at some -- you can't but we can -- what's in our trading securities, you've got to take effect for the inherent risk in the balance sheet positions. If we hold &#x2013; others &#x2013; we hold a larger percentage of our trading securities in governments or a smaller percentage in governments, that's going to make a difference in terms of risk profile.</p>
          <p>If we have the chart that I showed on page 30, limited funding risk and limited credit risk and a derivatives book that has a very large number, we think it is potentially misleading just to use the gross position. So assets to risk weighted assets, while not perfect and perhaps the regulators are going to modify their definitions but has merit and you have to look at it that way. The amount of capital that we have has to be consistent with the risk we are carrying not a very blunt measure of absolute size.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Kian Abouhossein of JP Morgan Securities. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Two questions, first of all if I look at your underlying cost income ratio...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kian, can you speak up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I look at your underlying cost income ratio in CB&amp;S I get to first quarter 56 -- sorry second quarter 56% and first quarter 67, so about 61% underlying clean cost income ratio, which tells me that you will have to accrue material bonuses in the second half. Can you give me kind of your view on how you will look at cost income going forward or is there any items in the revenue line that you don't need to accrue bonuses for, which mean that we could run at much lower level than what we use to at CB&amp;S?</p>
          <p>The second question is related to your write-downs. Could you explain to me how you get to your monoline write-downs? We have quite a good understanding how the U.S. guys are doing the write-down. I am not sure from the statement how you come to your very limited write-down for monoline.</p>
          <p>And the second issue is on if I look at your U.S. RMBS assets, I get to a write-down of about 50%. We know what Merrill has done in terms of write-downs on CDO. We know the ABX has deteriorated materially in July. Have you adjusted for the deterioration in AAA ABX on your RMBS book?</p>
          <p>And lastly why aren't there any write-down on CDOs? I don't think I have seen any CDO write-downs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Kian. Let's start with the underlying cost income ratio. I think you're making an incorrect assumption. You started off by saying or one of the comments you made is that we are going to have to make material bonus accruals in the second half of the year. The bonus accruals we make are based on, not underlying, but actual NIBBT [Net Income Before Bonus and Taxes] and we give reference &#x2013; of course underlying has to be reflected in somewhat, but we give &#x2013; we also give effect to our total comp ratio.</p>
          <p>We've had extensive discussions on this, we've had extensive analysis done by our HR colleagues in terms of what affects the current accruals will have and it was the conclusion after this analysis, is that our bonus accruals reflected in the first half of the year would be appropriate for the performance in the first half of year. If performance changes materially, obviously there is going to be a change in that number because we do true up on a year-to-date basis.</p>
          <p>With regard to the write-downs on the monolines, we have included a chart in our disclosures, showing a distribution of our monoline risk by rating band and I don't know how anyone else has put values and looked at impairments either on this or values on the RMBS or CDO which I'll get to in a minute, but we do in all these cases a fundamental name-by-name individual analysis. Let me cite you some data that is shown in our interim report. I know you guys haven't had a chance to study this yet, but we show our monoline exposure for monoliners rated AAA, for investment grade monoliners as a group that are not AAA, and for non-investment grade monoliners. We show the notional as well as the fair value and the allowances that we have taken. And if you look at that chart, you will see that we've got provided a small amount for the AAA, we've got 60% of our fair value to the non-AAA investment grade provided, and we've got 60% of the non-investment grade provided. So I don't know what this will &#x2013; if this sheds more light on your question but I'd study carefully this table, look at the movements in the table.</p>
          <p>What you will see is that there was a large notional movement in the first quarter &#x2013; at the end of the first quarter -- from the non-AAA investment grade to the non-investment grade. But, again, we don't just use external ratings. We have extensive conversations, our credit people, our business people do, with the monoliners, with the management of the monoliners and so -- that's the only thing I can tell you there.</p>
          <p>As far as RMBS is concerned, and the CDOs, these are very complex instruments to value, there is a lot of judgment involved. But you have to look beneath the security to see what's there. Vintages, the performance of the underlying mortgages, or other assets, with regard to default rates, with regard to severity of losses, with regard to prepayments, are important elements. At the end of the day, we price to the market, but we validate many of those prices -- most of those, by looking at models.</p>
          <p>We validate the values of many of our RMBS securities by looking at remittance data on the actual pool of mortgages underlying the security. We don't look at the ABX to value anything, the same as we don't look at the leveraged debt indexes to value our leveraged finance. We do it on an inherent fundamental basis. Based on that, we believe our values as of June 30, and in prior periods, were appropriate, and I don't know what else to say to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of you don't look at clearing prices like on the CDOs right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We absolutely do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We absolutely do. Now we've sold some CDOs during the period. Now if you look at the level of our exposure on the CDOs, and where that's come historically, it has been taken down considerably, so we absolutely look at clearing prices. I said we validate, and where there are no clearing prices, we may depend on some models, but the models are not based on -- based to a great degree on what is happening in the inherent portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And I don't want to take more of your time. But I think that there are some issues of what the U.S. banks are doing clearly, mark-to-markets, Citibank clearly gives indication how their mark-to-market and monoline exposure, i.e. cash flow based, on CDS spreads rather than credit ratings. So I think there seems to be a difference of mark-to-market aggressiveness between the different players. But I understand we do not have much time to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kian, that's a suggestion and not a question. I recommend we postpone this after...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and again I am aware that we have a long list of your colleagues who are still waiting so can I please &#x2013; we would appreciate it, everybody focus and we can give everybody our time. Can we move on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Kinner Lakhani of ABN AMRO Equities. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi good morning. Just wanted to come back to the leverage question. I appreciate your comments, but if we take out the netting effects in derivatives and we also strip out all collateral trading assets, in line with the U.S. definition of leverage ratio, I work out a leverage ratio that is close to 50 times compared to what I understand your U.S. peer group being closer to 20 times?</p>
          <p>Second question was in relation to the rates business, just wanted to ask you about what &#x2013; about your views on the sustainability of the strength, and also if you could try and quantify for us the benefit from what you call favorable market positioning?</p>
          <p>And final very quick question, what is the extent of CDS [Credit Default Swap] protection that you bought against monolines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hold on a second, let me just &#x2013; okay. With regard to the first one, I would be interested in your calculation because we come up with slightly different effects. But I go back and I don't know that we are going to resolve this on this call. We believe you've got to look at risk and because even in some of the data that is not so transparent, I talked about trading securities before, there are positions there that are hedging liabilities, where we are short something, there are positions where you have to look at the liquidity. Whatever the imperfections of the regulatory capital calculation, those calculations are based on inherent risk. They are not based on macro numbers. We are not going to convince you guys, and Basel might change their position, but we believe it's important to look at the underlying risk.</p>
          <p>With regard to the rates business...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can postpone and come back to that later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, Kinner, your question was still on the rates business. Could you rephrase that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's sustainability, and particularly to quantify the extent of favorable market positioning or prop trading basically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not &#x2013; a lot of it is customer flow. The businesses that are in there, are interest rate derivatives, credit derivatives to our clients. We believe that business is not moved only by the current market conditions, but demand for products. People need risk management tools, and that business provides it, and so there is some element of positioning there. But a lot of it comes from what I said earlier, the breadth and depth of our relationships and our technology and that we believe will continue.</p>
          <p>As far as the Credit Default Swaps on the monoliners, that number &#x2013; maybe we'll just have to get it to you. I don't have it here with me and maybe you can just &#x2013; you can contact Wolfram and they can talk to you about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kinner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Jeremy Sigee of Citi Investment Research. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Just three quick questions please.</p>
          <p>Firstly, in GTB, AWM and PBC on my numbers all of the beef is driven by low cost numbers, which you've commented on. I just wondered if you could talk a bit more about that, whether we should view the new run rates as a sustainable level or whether we should view this as a slightly favorable quarter on costs in those three divisions?</p>
          <p>Second question, I am not sure you have given us the carrying value for your &#x2013; the average carrying value of your RMBS portfolio and your CDO portfolios. Could you give us that?</p>
          <p>And thirdly, can you give any update on your interest or otherwise in Post Bank?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. With regard to the first one, I think Jeremy, you're correct. The growth in those stable business profits are coming largely from reduced costs. I indicated earlier that some of that reduction in cost is due to lower accruals of incentive compensation. We believe we will continue growing in revenues, particularly in as we have in GTB and PBC. And we will see a turnaround, although it maybe delayed, in AWM so the revenue growth we believe as the markets began to settle and stabilize when that happens, I don't know, but we will continue to focus on the expenses.</p>
          <p>With regard to the average carrying values on RMBS and CDOs, I don't think we prepared to give those numbers out. First of all, I don't know what they'd tell you, because comparables on a large average could be misleading because there's a mix of exposures and you have to understand the exposures and so I don't know what that would do.</p>
          <p>With regard to your final question, we've indicated many times in the past that we're interested in looking at all strategic opportunities that are available, particularly those in our stable businesses, and specifically here in Germany. We do that analysis, reviewing the strategic fit and the return to our shareholders and we'll continue to do that. But I don't think we're prepared, as we have &#x2013; as we've stated in the past, to speak about individual matters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Jeremy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Matthew Clark of Keefe, Bruyette. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Two questions, firstly on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matthew, we can hardly hear you. Can you speak up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you hear me now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Much better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Firstly on acquisitions, could you just tell us what return on investment you would expect, or demand as necessary, in the current environment to make an acquisition attractive to you? So maybe to define that, the net return meaning net profit of the acquired entity plus the net value of any synergies as a proportion of your consideration paid?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, on the credit default swaps, spreads have been meaningfully tighter than the peer group. Firstly, is this genuinely indicative of the real funding costs. as far as you are concerned? And secondly, how do you expect this to translate into a competitive benefit and over what time period do you see yourself &#x2013; or if you see yourself taking market share as a result, which business areas and what kind of pricing impact do you think that will have? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Matthew. As far as acquisitions are concerned, our standards have not changed from those that we have disclosed earlier. We look, and I'll break this down into categories. One of the important things we look at is return on equity, so we look at the purchase price; we make some assumptions based on our internal models, and the risk and goodwill or intangibles in the target and come up with some assumptions as to what the capital or the equity component of the purchase price is.</p>
          <p>Then, we do forecasts including the existing business, cost synergies, revenue synergies, cross-selling opportunities, etcetera and we look to recover our pre-tax weighted, adjusted, cost of capital, which we assume to be 14%, within a period of two years or so.</p>
          <p>And we look to achieve our hurdle rate of 25% by the fifth year or so. Now there's many other factors that go in: the impact on our Tier I ratio, the impact on our diluted EPS, how are we going to fund it, is it going to take &#x2013; what other resources is it going to take to do the acquisition?</p>
          <p>That said, this is not a black-box into which we feed data and wait for an answer to come out. There is significant attention paid to strategic fit, to footprints, to growing in areas where we believe we should grow, namely the stable businesses. And these standards have not changed, and we continue to apply them consistently to the way we have in the past.</p>
          <p>With regard to the CDS spread, it's got to be indicative of something. If we're borrowing money at 63 over, then that says those that are lending us money have a view on the strength of Deutsche Bank. If we can borrow money cheaper than others, and that money is available to us in the supply that we need, then that has to translate into a competitive advantage. In some cases, that competitive advantage is going to result in a larger balance sheet, so we go back to the questions we had previously, but we do take all these factors into account, but we believe it does afford us a competitive advantage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks Matthew. Next please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Christoffer Malmer of Goldman Sachs International; please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning. It's Chris Malmer here from Goldman.</p>
          <p>A few quick questions, just on slide number five, you show 100 million of write-downs on European RMBS. Give us any detail on any -- what type of RMBSs these are, any geographies, and if this is the first time you're actually taking provisions on European RMBSs? Anything you can say on carry value? I took your comment previously so I assume you won't be able to say much on the carry value there.</p>
          <p>Second question on the same slide, just on the write &#x2013; the impairments on the AfS [Assets held for Sale] assets, any clarity on those 200 million, whether there's actually equity asset that you're impairing at this point or if these are the types of assets that you have deemed as being impaired so taken them over the P&amp;L?</p>
          <p>Finally, just on the slide number 12, on the underlying fixed income revenues if I just look at the sales and trading revenues in fixed income, they were about 2.7 billion underlying I think. I took the 602 and added back the 2.1 billion of write-downs. That represents quite a significant increase on the first quarter. I think the same calculation gave me about 2.2 billion underlying. Would you argue that the significant increase there, just sequentially under similarly &#x2013; roughly similar market conditions -- is basically this, what you refer to as favorable market positioning? So the market moves that were basically more favorable in the second quarter, or are there any real changes in the activity levels between Q1 and Q2? Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Chris. Chris, on the European RMBS we have the largest piece is in UK. We have some traded securities &#x2013; these are not the mortgages that are generated in our private banking PBC business, these are in &#x2013; obviously, in global markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The largest component is in UK. Yeah. It's in the -- I just was checking; my recollection was we did disclose it. We've got about it's 1.2 in trading in the UK. And there is a piece in Germany and a piece in Spain. These are not subprime assets, but they are probably of a nature similar to Alt-A, subprime somewhere in that variety. We have taken some write-downs in the past, some markdowns. We've disclosed this because it's less than 100, but it rounds to 100. So when we get to that size, we felt it was important to disclose it and that's why we did.</p>
          <p>The size of this is not -- exposure is not of a magnitude similar to what our U.S. RMBS is. And on page 16 of our interim report, we do give the distribution, it's 1.8 billion in trading assets, 1.3 in the UK, 300 in Italy, 200 &#x2013; I missed that before &#x2013; 200 in Germany, and 70 million in Spain. So if you can look at that -- the write-downs were 71, and that's why we disclosed it.</p>
          <p>As far as the impairment of the AfS assets, these assets are sitting in DB-sponsored conduits that we have consolidated. If you remember, Chris, in the past we indicated that there was about 27 billion of DB sponsored conduits that we consolidate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The specific largest piece of this impairment has to do with a CDO, so debt security that was in &#x2013; these were principally underlying U.S. subprime and RMBS Alt-A mortgages. We had written it down in OCI in previous quarters. We went through our valuation process at the end of the quarter, and we did a very extensive analysis here looking at the factors that I referred to earlier in my answer, I think to Kian or to Jeremy, and we concluded that the impairment was -- that there was an impairment and therefore we just moved the money from OCI into P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>With regard to &#x2013; oh, the debt. The favorable market positioning, the designated proprietary activity was not a major piece. There was some, but, I don't know if it was an equal amount, but there was a substantial amount from increase in the flow business, customer business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect, that's very helpful. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Chris. Next please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Stuart Graham of Merrill Lynch International. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. Firstly, thanks very much for the extra disclosure. I have three very quick questions.</p>
          <p>Firstly, on the reduction of the balance sheet, could we be imagining something like &#x20AC;500 billion of lower assets, or is Mr. Krause's project much less modest than that?</p>
          <p>Secondly, on the LBOs, can you split the 7.2 billion of sales by where you provided financing and where you didn't provide financing to the buyers?</p>
          <p>And third, everybody else was selling Alt-A in Q2, why were you not selling Alt-A? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the final one, Stuart. I don't know why everybody else was selling Alt-A and we &#x2013; I think sold some of it, but most of it was on the markdown. So, I don't know how to answer that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess, my question is, did you think they were fundamentally at right value and the valuations that people sold at were very, very short?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we think the valuations from many of the others were on bulk sales. So, we look to try to find where market levels are after those bulk sales, particularly in the U.S. RMBS. We -- if the question is, are we holding them because we think the values are coming back, I don't know that that's how we would manage the book. This is a volatile book. There is a lot of risk, as I have said, in it. We mark the positions where we see. There was not a reason to sell them. We're not under pressure, either from a liquidity standpoint or other standpoints, so we didn't.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the LBO sales, I don't have the breakdown with me, but I think it's important to talk about how we treat those sales when we determine that there is a true sale. There was some large -- a large portion of that number, was financed. We did provide financing. But in order to account for this as a sale, we have to satisfy ourselves that there has been a risk transfer, and that the first loss piece, which is the equity investment, is sufficient to cover the losses. We've written provisions in the financing agreements where we would get first call on interest payments as well as principle pay-downs and in all cases, we've looked at the financing rates to assure that they are arm's length.</p>
          <p>And so we go through an analysis, if the question is, did we really unload the risk? We couldn't have accounted for it as a sale if we had not. We believe the provisions and the conditions of the sale effectively transferred the risk. We continue to have credit risk, but we think of a substantially different nature and risk inherent in those was therefore sold.</p>
          <p>With regard to the balance sheet size, I don't want to put Stefan in a position before his analysis is done. He is &#x2013; one of the things he is going to be challenged with is balance; is looking at where we reduce the balance sheet and what impact it has on our business as well as on our capital and so rather than give a number prematurely I would suggest we all wait and see what Stefan concludes after he's completed his analysis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you wouldn't rule out it could be hundreds of billions rather than tens of billions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we wouldn't probably have to assign it to the CFO if it were tens.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, cool. Thanks</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That'd be rather different, Stuart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Indeed, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Stuart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, next please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Dirk Hoffmann-Becking of Sanford Bernstein, please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, thank you. I'll try to limit myself to one question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The impact of a balance sheet reduction on the businesses is something you've just mentioned. If we look at the &#x2013; this quarter's results, actually the reduction in balance sheet did not impact the business or is that a sort of misperception? Because your underlying revenues went up even though the assets went down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that a question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that a question or a comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a question, whether the reduction in assets has any impact on the business, on the underlying business and whether you believe there are more assets around that can be reduced without impacting the business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dirk, I don't know that I'd venture a forecast on that. I think the analysis has to be completed. Obviously, the size of the balance sheet is predicated on the business model and the business. The balance sheet size would not be there if it didn't have an impact on the revenues. I think the issue that has to be addressed is how big the magnitude of the impact relative to the size of reduction and so any reductions that occur are going to have some revenue impact. And I think the analysis, one of the things the analysis is focusing on is not just the revenues but the P&amp;L impact and whether or not those revenue impacts have ancillary effects. And so it's a very complicated question but we believe any reduction in the balance sheet is going to have some impact on the revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Dirk. Next please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Philipp Zieschang of UBS. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Quick question on the derivative book, what is the 77 billion underlying credit risk which you disclose on slide 30, what is the risk-weighted asset equivalent to that or/and what is total risk-weighted assets related to the book if we include also operational risk? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The RWAs on that 77 billion are probably just under that number. And that doesn't surprise us because if you think about it, the process that we've gone through is going to say, 77. There is probably some risk-weighting that might be over or less than one. And then you add the operational risk to that. I don't know what the operational risk is, what the charge is, but I think we disclose somewhere our total operational risk charge and I believe that number is somewhere around 35 billion. So some of this is on derivatives, some of it isn't and so I don't have the breakdown here with me, Philipp, so but that number is going to be in the same basic range. It's probably 5-10% smaller in terms of the RWA effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Jon Peace of Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi morning. I just wanted to ask a quick question on sales and trading equity. Your equity derivatives, you told us dropped quite sharply on prior year, I noticed one of your recent competitors talked about record revenues in the second quarter. So I just wanted to see if you could give a little bit more color on the drop on what your outlook was from this point?</p>
          <p>Also on the same subject, what proportion of total equity revenues was designated prop this quarter? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to the first question. I think it depends on the nature of the equity &#x2013; of the equity derivatives business a substantial portion of ours is related to the structured note business. We have seen a softening in the demand for structured notes and so the volumes of new business were down and the impacts have also come from correlation. I mentioned in the last quarter that we have seen correlations increase. We have continued to see that but at a mitigate &#x2013; at a slower rate and so the negative effects of increased correlation is substantially less that it was in the first quarter, but it is having an effect in the second.</p>
          <p>With regard to the proprietary, the designated equity prop, we've indicated that we saw that number being somewhere in the 10 to 20% range, say about 15 and it's run at about that range in the second quarter this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Ms. Fiona Swaffield of Execution. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I had two questions.</p>
          <p>The first issue, just coming back to compensation, just to understand how you're looking at it. So you're basically saying that don't look at the provisions, it's all about the group performance and so we should assume that you're passing on the write-downs to the staff. What I was trying to ask you is, that's all well and good, but what if your peers don't do that? Because looking at everybody else, they don't seem to be accruing bonuses in that way. Is it that you're taking a view that in the second half they will? So they will all true up? But are you not worried about being uncompetitive in terms of compensation particularly within the investment bank is the first area?</p>
          <p>And the second area is risk weighted assets; you mentioned that you've been managing them very actively and if I look at the credit risk weighted assets they are flat Q2, Q1. Could you kind of explain the moving parts? So how much of this is due to netting, how much involuntary asset growth have you had from the warehouse in leveraged finance? Try and give us a feel of whether this is sustainable or if they could rise in the future. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Fiona I don't know that we would characterize what we've accrued as passing on the losses to the employees. But...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The reason I said that is that if you look at -- you look to your compensation ratio, but you did it on reported revenues, which obviously includes quite large right-downs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't do it on reported revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do it on net income before bonus and taxes. That's where the formulas come and then we aggregate the effects and then we look across the whole firm at the revenue fact. So but in the first instance, it's based on a business-by-business analysis.</p>
          <p>Joe Ackermann has been very active in an IIF analysis, looking at compensation levels. The bank believes that compensation should be reflective of performance not only of the individual business, but of the firm and the effect that that has on the shareholders. And the view currently is that these accruals will be sufficient to pay the bonus levels. We have discussed with the businesses and it's obviously an active discussion ongoing. But it's the bank's view as to what it would be interested in paying.</p>
          <p>Obviously, we've got to look to our peers. We've got to look to the competition. We've got to look at the effects that it would have on the franchise. But we also have to look at the effects on the shareholders and on the returns to the shareholders. So all of these elements are critical and in the equation.</p>
          <p>With regard to the credit change in RWAs, you are right; they are about flat. We have seen an increase in the PCAM credit RWAs and this is reflecting the growth in the businesses that I talked about earlier, with regard to Spain and Poland but also here in Germany. There is also an impact for our commitment to increase our stake in the Chinese bank, a small piece. And so we have seen an increase there. We've seen a decrease in RWAs in global markets and this is combination of lower exposure in the structured product area and a slightly higher exposure in corporate finance in part as part of the sale of the leveraged finance positions that we talked about earlier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Fiona, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The final question is from Mr. Georg Kanders of WestLB Equity Markets. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a question if I get it right about the dividend accrual. Is it the same level as last year on absolute terms or is it just a relative in the payout ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Georg, it's on absolute terms, not on relative terms. So just to make it clear...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...last year our dividend was &#x20AC;4.50. In the first six months of this year we have allocated against Tier 1 capital &#x20AC;4.50 per share. We have allocated &#x20AC;2.25. So just taken 50% of last year we put 25% in the first quarter, 25% in the second quarter so we have reflected in the Tier 1 capital a dividend assumption of &#x20AC;2.25 as of June per share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Sherry did I understood you right, this was the last</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, gentlemen there are no more questions registered at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Before we close, I would like to give Tony maybe the opportunity for a concluding remark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Wolfram mentioned before that this is my final call. I was reflecting on that in talking to Wolfram recently. I have been, in my career, through 60 -- approximately 60 of these. Some of the times it was as the primary speaker and other times it was sitting, helping prepare or support the speaker. I've got to tell you every one of them has been different. The level anxiety before each one does not change, but in every one I both learned something and had a series of to-dos as we will after this call.</p>
          <p>I want to thank all of you for your attention, your participation, your diligence, your questions and your challenges because all of that is helpful to all of us. So thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Tony. All the best, and this ends our call. Good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen thank you for joining. The conference has now concluded and you may disconnect your telephones. Have a pleasant day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>