<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1512182" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8657</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head of Investor Relations">Michael Sia</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Piyush Gupta</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley Asia (Singapore) Pte Ltd.">Nick Lord</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer, DBS Hong Kong, DBS Group Holdings Ltd.">Sebastian Paredes</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Sok Hui Chng</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities (Asia) Ltd.">Stephen J. Andrews</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="China International Capital Corp. (Hong Kong) Securities Ltd.">Sally Ng</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="CLSA Singapore Pte Ltd.">Asheefa A. Sarangi</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="CreditSights Research">Matthew Phan</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Standard Chartered Securities (Singapore) Pte Ltd.">Jaj Singh</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Singapore Pte Ltd.">Robert P. Kong</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Daiwa Capital Markets (Singapore) Ltd.">Srikanth Vadlamani</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Asia Ltd.">Sharnie Wong</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="CIMB Research Pte Ltd.">Kenneth Ng</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael Sia, over to you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everybody and thank you for joining us for this third quarter conference call. With me, Piyush and Sok Hui. And in Hong Kong, there's Sebastian and the rest of the teams here in Singapore and Hong Kong. So we'll start with just a brief recap of the points from Piyush and then we'll take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, good morning, everybody. Thanks for dialing in. I think I'll just recap quickly a couple of observations I made at the media call which we just concluded. I think on the whole, I'm actually quite pleased with this quarter's performance. This is our second best quarter ever. Top line, we've exceeded $2 billion for the second time and bottom line at SGD856 million is a strong bottom line, so quite pleased with the overall numbers.</p>
          <p>I'm actually also quite pleased with the fact that we were able to demonstrate high degree of resiliency around the region. And it's quite clear, Asia slowed down through the third quarter, slowed down in the second, but certainly slowed down in the third quarter. But by and large, our business activities, loan volumes around the region stood up quite well. We continue to see good demand, particularly Singapore business lending, including the mortgage book in Singapore and our activities around the region.</p>
          <p>The headwinds we saw were really China and within China also, particularly trade finance-related. As we'd noted, we built up a large trade finance portfolio, China-related in a year ago, third quarter last year. And so, there was a large amount of maturities concentrated into the third quarter this year as a consequence. Typically, so far we've been able to replenish our maturities and then grow the book some.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter this year, we weren't able to replenish our maturities. And therefore, while our originations were in line with first quarter originations, were 5% lower than second quarter originations. Because the runoffs were quite high, that resulted in some reduction in the overall loan book, both in China and Hong Kong. I think the more material thing in China this quarter was really margin, because NIMs continue to come off quite sharply. They were down second quarter. They were also down quite sharply third quarter.</p>
          <p>The good news from our standpoint, though, is that, across the region and including in China, we're beginning to see the bottoming out having happened. In fact, in the last two weeks, we're beginning to see some pickup. And therefore, as we project out over the next quarter and frankly next year, we feel quite comfortable that we should be able to hold margins at these levels, perhaps even improve them a little bit. Our budgets have been at slightly higher levels than now. And we think we should be able to continue to get loan growth overall in the China business in the low double digits.</p>
          <p>The other thing which I was pleased about this quarter, in addition to the fact that the business held up quite well, is that we were able to identify this opportunity in the fixed income space, fixed income markets, very early and able to <mark type="ph" /> resource (3:19) and respond to that. And as a consequence, we've been able to get on the radar for different kinds of bond issuances this year.</p>
          <p>So we've done a lot of G3, we've done dim sum, we've done other currencies. We've done outside Singapore issuances into Singapore. And therefore, this quarter, some of the pickup in income really came from these revenue streams which we traditionally have not been very active or very big at. So that's been quite good.</p>
          <p>Two other comments in observation, one is on the deposits. There were a lot of questions in the middle of the year about whether deposits would be a constraint and whether deposit competition would prove to be a problem. It's worth noting that in the third quarter, that has not been the case, and we've been able to grow our deposit base very nicely, perhaps too nicely, if anything, and has been quite broad based. We grew Singapore savings account, we grew CASA &#x2013; current account. We grew GTS deposits, we grew dollar deposits, so very broad based deposit growth. And other than Singapore FDs, where early in the quarter, we increased our pricing to match our two local competitors. In all the other deposit categories, actually, we've been able to drop the deposit rates. We didn't have to increase pricing anywhere at all. So deposits have been a positive story.</p>
          <p>The last thing which I wanted to mention is provisions. And a couple of people asked me about how come our provisions are so low. And the reality is that our SPs are pretty consistent with last several quarters, that's seven basis points. And if you look at the last several quarters, they've been in the seven, eight, nine basis points range. The reality, we're still not seeing the stress in the portfolio and we're not seeing it in any of our portfolio across. There've been some pickup and noise in the SME segment, but we saw that in the second and third quarter. It's sort of isolated and sporadic, there's no systemic increase.</p>
          <p>So, the SPs are low &#x2013; continue to be low on account of that. General provisions really came off this quarter and they came off because the loan book was flat. Actually in dollar terms &#x2013; in Sing-dollar terms, the loan book actually shrank. So, if you really had to &#x2013; we're supposed to keep 1% general provision. If we went by that formula, I would have been able to reverse SGD 30-odd million in general provision; <mark type="ph" /> ensure that (5:40) we added SGD 15 million in general provision.</p>
          <p>So, we really &#x2013; relative to what we should have done, we actually increased GP by SGD 45 million. Our total coverage at 134% is at historic high, and frankly, we don't think it's appropriate to keep increasing coverage beyond this point because any incremental increase in provisions does not count to capital beyond the threshold. And so, we've reached a threshold where it would be capital-inefficient for us to keep increasing coverage from here on.</p>
          <p>So I'm going to stop there and then throw it open for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Aaron, we can take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now being the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question, Jack Lord (sic) [Nick Lord] (6:36) from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, [ph] Jack (6:45).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's actually Nick Lord, not Jack Lord. I think he was in Hawaii Five-O. Couple of questions. First of all, the fall in risk-weighted assets that you saw in the third quarter. Could you just, I think, certainly you said in the conference call that you thought that that or some of that was related to a change in accounting or something like that or change in...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>... risk recognition &#x2013; sorry, within the loan book. So I just wondered if you could talk a little bit about that and whether or not you think you can further efficient out of risk &#x2013; further efficiency out of the risk-weighted asset book.</p>
          <p>And then the second question was just on deposits. I think in the call, Piyush, you said there were 3 billion of those deposits were hot money. What currency were they and what part of the book were they in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, on the risk-weighted assets, Nick, we're down SGD 8 billion. Of that, about SGD 3 billion is really cosmetic because it's the translation impact. The Sing dollar strengthened. So SGD 3 billion of that SGD 8 billion is really a currency impact of a stronger Singapore dollar. SGD 5 billion is the real reduction.</p>
          <p>Now, one of the points I made before, see, our &#x2013; the way we &#x2013; our risk density, loosely speaking, the way they convert total assets to risk-weighted assets is not at the most efficient end of the spectrum. And so, our risk density is about 63% total assets to risk-weighted assets. If you compare to the European banks, European banks convert down to 20%. So as I remember, the Swiss Bank at 15% and 18%. In fact, so the point I make is when people talk about the Swiss finish at 19% capital, that's 19% on one-fourth of my denominator.</p>
          <p>So, we really have a lot of opportunities to improve the efficiency of how we calibrate our risk-weighted assets. We know we've got a very specific agenda and several people working on doing this right. One &#x2013; let me give you a couple of example of how this works.</p>
          <p>So, if you have collateral against loans, then this can work to a less risky loan form, that's obvious because collateralized. But for that to work, your collateral management system should be in good order and you should be tagging collateral correctly to the loan. If you're not tagging collateral correctly, you wind up overstating the riskiness of the loan and therefore wind up having a higher RWA. So if you improve the collateral title, you get relief because you just tagged the collateral better.</p>
          <p>So we've been able to do a few things in the last quarter which has given us this $5 billion of risk-weighted assets released. We think over the next year or two, we have the capacity to be able to drive that down quite substantially. I told you we have 63% and we are at the one extreme end. On an average, Asian banks are in the mid-50s.</p>
          <p>The StanChart, HSBCs of the world are in the mid-30s, the Europeans are in the 20s. So clearly, there's an opportunity for us to get a lot of efficiency from that.</p>
          <p>Your second question around deposit, that was a 13 billion in deposit growth currency adjusted. Obviously, 9 billion or 10 billion was, what I call, granular or yearly deposit and we had about $3 billion from a couple of clients, actually one in Hong Kong, China, so I think that is probably a U.S. dollar deposit. And the other one is a Singapore client, this is probably a Sing dollar deposit. That's a couple of split, half in half, half in Sing and half in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>More in Sing dollars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Nick, for the record, I said that it is due to appreciation of the Sing dollars as well as ongoing capital computation process improvements. So that will actually cover, I guess, the improvement in data quality, better linkage to collateral system that Piyush has told you about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just &#x2013; by the way, thanks very much about it. And you phrased it far better than I did. But can I just ask, I mean if you do that, you're obviously going to release more capital. And you've already got a reasonably, as you pointed out in the presentation, a reasonably strong capital ratio. I mean, what are you sort of thinking you will do with this capital?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're going to continue to grow our organic book. And if Danamon happens, then we continue to grow our Indonesian book as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you think you've got the scope to deploy all this for organic growth then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do, we do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perfect. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question, Stephen Andrews, UBS. Please go ahead, Stephen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good morning. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you. Mine is just a question, sorry, to come back to the net interest margin progression, but it's clearly getting a lot of attention. Can I just ask, in the detail you give on the NIM, especially on the asset yield, it looks like the biggest driver of fall in asset yield in the quarter has been on the securities book.</p>
          <p>We're seeing securities yield fall I think to 2.45% from 2.57%, so it's down another 12 basis points in the quarter, and it's down 27 basis points since the end of last year. Can you talk us through what's driving that down? I know interest rates are very, very low. Is this just still repricing coming through? Is it change in the composition of that securities book or &#x2013; and should we expect that to start to stabilize now? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> Steve (12:01), actually the securities yield is a lot of noise, and it doesn't materially impact our overall NIM from an underlying business standpoint. The biggest change to the security NIM generally tends to be from the traders' decision of switching from differing currencies. So, if they go along all the bonds, the yields go up just because all these are high-yield currency, and if they switch from there and go into U.S. dollars or yen, they just get a lower yield.</p>
          <p>So, it's really not driven by &#x2013; because remember when they do this stuff, they're really not driven by yield considerations. They're driven by a total income they make between the trading gains, the yield and the net interest income. So I personally tend to ignore the securities yield line myself, because it's not indicative of anything. It's the totality of the income which is more indicative.</p>
          <p>The real issue around NIMs, as we said, is really around the China NIM. Our overall &#x2013; if you look at the lines above that, the &#x2013; our NIMs for customer loans are distinct &#x2013; our yield for customer loans are off by two basis points. Actually, China was three, and the rest of the region was up one. And similarly, if you look at the deposit side, our cost of deposits was up two basis points, and the same thing, China deposits were up three and the rest of the region was minus one.</p>
          <p>So our NIM story, the reduction is to a large extent a China story. Our total reduction in NIMs of 5, about 4 &#x2013; 3.5, 4 of that is really China related, and we've talked about that. The interest rate liberalization in China and, more importantly, the onshoring of a lot of the trade finance has been the driver of that.</p>
          <p>The other driver of NIM, which is worth a couple of basis points for us continues to be from our liquidity buffer. As you know, we built up a SGD 10 billion liquidity buffer. We still have a substantial buffer though we're trying to reduce the sizes of buffer a little bit because post summer, we figure we don't need the same kind of buffer. So we'll probably bring it down to about half.</p>
          <p>But at this point in time, that extra liquidity that we had, we're putting it into interbank and then putting it into placements, which are very low yielding. And that is the other cause of our NIM, a couple of basis points have in fact really come from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question, Sally Ng from CICC. Please go ahead, Sally. Hi, Sally, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Hi, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, Sally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I have two questions. First, when I look at your net interest margin in Hong Kong, it doesn't seem to have been impacted by the &#x2013; what's going on here in terms of the higher R&amp;D funding cost? I think the NIM in Hong Kong is up, like, two basis point Q-on-Q. Just wondering if you could comment on how you're seeing that affecting your CNH business in terms of the higher R&amp;D funding costs here and the overall CNH business momentum in Q3.</p>
          <p>Second question is just more regarding to one of your competitor earlier this week, Standard Chartered talk about deterioration in the onshore Indian wholesale banking book in terms of the asset quality. Just wonder given that you also have a presence in India, what are you seeing in terms of the asset quality there and where you see the cycle in the next three to four quarters? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Hong Kong, yes, you were right, our margins have improved and we continue to work that improvement. Actually, Sebastian, on the phone. So I'll pass on to Sebastian to answer what he's doing so the margins are improving. But on the offshore renminbi, <mark type="ph" /> directly, we've (15:53) not been aggressively growing our offshore renminbi deposit base because of where the reports are. And so, we've really not been in the game, but I'm going to in a minute give it to Sebastian to answer the questions around CNH.</p>
          <p>On your questions around the India portfolio. India portfolio is actually in reasonable shape. We're not seeing the same stresses that some of our competitors have because we've had any exposure to some of the large corporate areas that have gone under problem. So we have very limited exposure to power. We have very limited exposure to construction. We have very limited exposure in some of the industries which saw some of the headwinds.</p>
          <p>Now, on an overall basis though, as the Indian economy slowed through this year, there was some increase in stress, but it's not material. So, we have some small, couple of cases in India at the low end. So for us, it would be in the $5 million and $10 million range, which have gone into our NPL, but it's not been material at all.</p>
          <p>Again for India, I'm actually a little more bullish now than I was six months ago. I think some of the new policy pronouncements that the Finance Minister has made, I think that couple of rate reductions, the 50 basis points from RBI as well as the reserve ratio requirement that they cut yesterday will all start creating more tailwind in the Indian economy going forward. So I'm actually a little more bullish about next year's prospects for India than I was about this year's prospects.</p>
          <p>Sebastian, do you want to take the question on the NIMs in Hong Kong and particularly the offshore renminbi?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you, Piyush. On the overall NIM, I would say two things. The first one is much more disciplined on asset pricing, so we've been very, very disciplined in pricing for risk in Hong Kong. And the second one, the asset mix, as you &#x2013; as we've guided before, we have slowed down our retail mortgage book because of low pricing. We have concentrated on asset classes that produce higher returns and higher opportunities for gross sales. So that has had a very important impact in our NIM, and will continue to have impact in our NIM.</p>
          <p>With regards to the RMB, yes, a lot of the RMB transactions and volumes in Hong Kong have reduced mainly because the cost of U.S. dollars and availability of U.S. dollars in Hong Kong has reduced the appeal for RMB. And in our particular case, our RMB loans have slightly improved from RMB 13 billion to RMB 14 billion. And our loan book has reduced in line with the slowdown on China demand. But we are beginning to see some slides of improvement.</p>
          <p>Our NIM in RMB is maintained, even though I agree that we see some banks increasing dramatically their RMB rates, but our franchise has been sustained.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. If I can just have a follow-up question on what's been announced in the property measures by the Hong Kong government last Friday. It might be too early to comment, but would be keen to know your view on the impact on the mortgage business as well as the overall &#x2013; the property market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The first impressions are that volume clearly is going to dramatically reduce in Hong Kong, especially on the residential side. But a lot is moving to the office space and to the commercial space buildings. We have spoken with many of the developers and main companies here. And they believe that the impact on prices are going to be like we saw in Singapore, a decrease at the beginning, slight decrease, 5% to 10%. But in the long term, it will continue to be pressured up because of the lack of &#x2013; the difference between demand and supply. But most of the flows now are moving into the commercial and office building space.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me also add. I think as Sebastian pointed out earlier, as you know, we deliberately started giving up market share in the Hong Kong mortgage market over the last year, year and a half because we figured that it was not an efficiently-priced market. And as a consequence, even if there is some slowdown in the Hong Kong mortgage flows, it does not impact our business very materially.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's very helpful. Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sally. Our next question, Asheefa Sarangi from CLSA. Please go ahead, Asheefa.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. My question just relates to the business that you're doing on the fixed-income side. So to your point, there has been a pickup in this side of the business particularly really across the region. And my question relates to how much of the business that you've been writing in the region has had credit enhancement attached to it, i.e. Letters of Credit. If you could confirm sort of the number of deals in the quantum. And then my understanding is that the fee that you're taking for that Letter of Credit is approximately 100 basis points upfront. And that will be good if you can confirm that as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think we've, actually, they're only a couple of deals which are credit enhanced. I think we've done, maybe, under five, so I think it's probably three. If I remember, one out of India and a couple out of China. So out of our part total 150 or 200-odd deals we've done, this is really not an important part of the business. They're two or three deals. And frankly, I won't be able to tell you off the top of my head how much we charged for the credit enhancement, but I'm sure we can check that out and come back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. Also, my second question just relates to the Danamon transaction. The capital position looks good on a standalone basis. But if we adjust in the extent that you get just a 40% stake to start fully loaded in their Basel III, the capital position starts to look a little bit tight. How are you thinking about that if indeed you only start with 40%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not speculating about that at this stage. We've put in an application with the guidance of the regulators to buy the entire stake of the market of 67% and then subsequently do a tender offer to build the stake up to 99%. And at this point in time, we see no reason to speculate on any other possible outcomes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question, Matthew Phan from Credit Suisse (sic) [CreditSights] (22:27). Please go ahead, Matthew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Matthew Phan from CreditSights, actually. Could I just clarify on your U.S. dollar funding? Previously, you've said that you partly fund this by swapping Sing dollars into U.S. dollars. Can I just <mark type="ph" /> ask (22:47) during the normal course of business, is this done in the market or with the MAS and at what price? And also, under a dollar liquidity emergency situation, and clearly, we're not in that situation now, but just to understand better, if there was an emergency situation, will the MAS provide swap funding and what would be the price of that emergency funding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, we do both market and MAS, but the MAS is indeed our largest counterparty. If we look at the overall size of the swap market, it's quite deep. It's like, depending on typicality, it's about SGD 200 billion in the swap market. We, on a typical basis, swap about SGD 35-odd billion, so we're not a huge part, we're a large player, but we're not a dominant part of the market.</p>
          <p>At what price we swap, I'll have to get back to you. I have no idea what my <mark type="ph" /> data (23:40) is actually so far in terms of the specific price.</p>
          <p>In terms of what is the backstop? We've actually had several discussions with the MAS to figure how active they will continue to be in the swap market. As you know, we can only go from precedent. MAS will never commit to saying that there will always be present in the swap market.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, MAS has been a fairly enlightened partner. So to create instability in the Singapore market is unlikely that they will go that route. So it's about all I can say on that matter.</p>
          <p>In terms of pricing, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (24:06) Michael or somebody can get you some range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sure. Thanks for that. And just a follow-up to that, one of your international competitors has commented that central banks in Singapore and in Japan as well are sort of limiting the amount that the local banks can swap from local currency to U.S. dollar. So are you experiencing this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we are not. So &#x2013; but and they're followed as part of the monetary policy. From time to time, they decide to come into the local currency market and into the swap market. So they might actually sterilize through getting to the borrowing and lending in Sing dollar as opposed to swapping.</p>
          <p>That's purely a function of the monetary policy decisions I think and how they want to act. But we've not seen any sign of their wanting to limit or not coming into &#x2013; being there for the swap market, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay, thanks very much. Just one more question on a separate topic. Regarding your loan-related fees, this was quite strong in the third quarter, but I noticed that the loan balance declined. So could I just ask what the loan related fees are earned from and what is behind the increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Loan-related fees are typically earned from originations of loans. The balance <mark type="indiscernible" /> (25:18) of originations and maturities. So if a large amount of loans mature and we originate the same amount of loans, we book the fees and then the overall balance won't increase. Just to make a point though that we are very conservative in our recognition of loan-related fees. So again, we benchmark with our competitors and we recognize far less of origination fees upfront than any of our competitors do. We amortize a large part of our fees.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question, Jaj Singh from Standard Chartered. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, good morning, Piyush. Most of my questions have been asked, but perhaps I could turn your attention to your minority stakes. After the recent sale of the 10% in BPI, you still have 10% in BPI and you also have, I think, around 3% in Thai Military Bank. I want to understand, what's the rationale of holding on to such small stakes, and do you have any intention of getting rid of them? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've been quite clear that our non-strategic positions are something that we'd always be open to considering at the right circumstance, right price. And so, we're not wedded to these stakes. On the other hand, we've got to be able to do the right &#x2013; make the right economic choices, including getting the right price for them from the right <mark type="ph" /> business (27:05).</p>
          <p>If you look at the BPI 10% stake, it was a good time to be able to divest. We found a good buyer who was a partner. The currency was at a high, the stock was at a high, so it was a good time to do that and it allowed us to gain significant capital efficiency. The balance 10% stake does not give us the same capital efficiency.</p>
          <p>So, on the first 10%, we were able to release $1.5 billion in capital. On the next 10%, we only released 100 odd million dollars of capital. So it's not as compelling as the first 10%, but yes, I mean at the right opportunity, we'd always be willing to look at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Perhaps I could ask another question. This is going back to the previous speaker. This is in regards to the U.S. dollar LDR. So your U.S. dollar LDR has improved to, I think, from 150% from last quarter to 129%. Is this going to be the new norm?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, I don't think we should think as a norm, because I told you before that I really think of fungible currency LDR. I'm less fussed about U.S. dollars <mark type="ph" /> specifically (28:13) because if I have Aussie, I have euro, I'm quite happy to treat them fungibly because those markets are deep and liquid enough. So, I think if you look at non-fungible currency LDR, which has also dropped sharply to 106%. But I've said in the past that I'm actually quite comfortable running a fungible currency LDR all the way up to 120%. So I won't call this a norm, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> By the way, (28:36) just to the other thing, so I should point out that, in addition to the minority interest we have in BPI and some TMB shares and so on, we also have a lot of other ammunition. Sok Hui pointed out in her presentation that our AFS portfolio is in the money by $600 million. Last year, it was in the money by $400 million. So we've actually added a couple of hundred million dollars in value which we've not harvested. So frankly, we do have the capacity to actually take gains on large amounts of portfolio at the right time and at the right price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In addition, for the unrealized gains on the AFS portfolio, come 1/1/2013, Basel rules allow you to actually recognize them as capital. But today, we can't.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question, Robert Kong from Citi Singapore. Please go ahead, Robert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Robert Kong from Citi in Singapore. Couple of questions. First of all, on your NIM, in terms of your budgeting for next year, what kind of assumptions are you looking at underpinning your NIMs, in particular given that, in a QE3 world and a strong Sing dollar world, we could see perhaps further falls in short-term rates in Singapore SIBOR and SOR?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Robert, we are budgeting flat NIM because we don't know, it could happen that you might see pressure on SOR. And, interestingly unlike QE2, we've not seen the same inflow of money this time with QE3, I think partly to do with the China concerns that people in the West have, partly to do with the fact the U.S. economy is looking a little bit better. And therefore I think some of the money is going into the domestic U.S. economy. So we've not seen the same kind of flows.</p>
          <p>But you're right, there could be some pressure. On the other hand, we're also seeing the ability to continue to increase pricing in several of our markets. Sebastian just talked about Hong Kong where, through both asset portfolio change as well as being very disciplined about pricing, we've been to able to price up. We are seeing that in several markets as well, and particularly in the build-out of the SME business and SME profile, we've been able to get some pricing benefits from the one side. So net-net, when we put this together bottoms up, there are some swings and roundabouts. But on an average, we are budgeting a stable NIM.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And sort of my second and final question, this is being asked on behalf of an investor. They commented I think to me, that there were some concern about the growth in your off-balance sheet commitments and whether that would have some impact on capital. I just wonder if you could just explain what may be the concern there and what's behind that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look at the off-balance sheet disclosure, the figure actually refers to both commitments that are revocable as well as irrevocable. So for accounting purpose, you take everything in. But for capital computation, you only have to put capital against irrevocable kind of commitment. So of the total figures, actually you see that only a very small component actually attract capital under the capital rules.</p>
          <p>So, we actually have that classification and I think for 30th September, the amount that is actually deemed to be irrevocable is actually SGD31 billion. So, despite the big figure, you see of SGD100 billion over, only SGD31 billion are commitments that were made to the customers, for example, a term-loan facility that we expect to draw down. A large part of the other sort of working capital lines that we make available to the customer typically don't actually get drawn down; so that would be the context that I would put to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert, is there any other questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's it. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> There are no questions in queue. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question, <mark type="ph" /> Goran (32:59) from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi this is <mark type="ph" /> Goran (33:02) here from UBS. There's some chatters that the MAS is talking to the local banks in terms of where the interest rates are, especially for mortgages, in relations to how low they are given that, I guess, Singapore hasn't quite been able to stop the increase in housing prices. So, can you please tell us if we are to expect any administrative moves which might force interest rates up for mortgages?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>MAS is not in any conversation with me; so they just talk to all the other banks except DBS, who knows.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question, <mark type="ph" /> Gin Singh (33:48) from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead, <mark type="ph" /> Gin Singh (33:51) your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sorry. Just a quick question on the overall strategy, but clearly the regional plans. Hypothetically speaking, what happens if the M&amp;A situation pans out or falls through, either for Indonesia or Malaysia? How does that work in terms of the overall plan, in terms of bringing ASEAN, in terms of contribution, up for the group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The simple plan is an organic growth plan. And we can look at our track record now and see that every year, we move the needle by two, three percentage points; i.e., our growth outside our core market becomes a larger percentage of the group. And so, if the M&amp;A doesn't work out, we will continue to work organically. Over the next three, five years, we can safely see the &#x2013; India, China, Indonesia, et cetera, getting to 30% contribution for the group in that timeframe ,and we'll be happy with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And one other question on the sort of the broader after ASEAN free-trade thing, any thoughts on whether the implications are for DBS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the implications are still to be seen, because the 2015 economic community, the one area whether there's just lack of clarity about whether any dramatic changes will happen is in the financial services sector. And so, it's like I said, still relatively unclear about what that might mean, is it an opportunity or a threat, frankly, for any of the banks in the region.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question Srikanth from Daiwa Singapore. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for taking the question. Had a question on your loan growth outlook for 2013. What are the sort of expectation you have and could you give some geographical-wise sort of overview of where you think the growth would come in? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're, at this point, assuming that we will grow loans at about the same rate as this year, which is between 9% and 10% of loan growth for next year. And we continue to expect that loan growth will be fairly broad, because the large part of the growth is really business lending. Almost 80% of our loan growth comes from there, 20% comes from the consumer part of the business.</p>
          <p>And at this point, we still continue to see fairly robust loan demand across multiple sectors, both trade, short-term working capital, loans out of Indonesia, India, China, Singapore itself, is quite robust. And so, when we do our calibration bottoms up, we think we should be able to get the same kind of loan growth as we had this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Like, this year Singapore has held up fairly well, given the &#x2013; expected slowdown in the macro, does the 9% to 10% loan growth expectation also incorporate that Singapore will remain as robust as it was this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think Singapore was particularly robust this year. If you look at Singapore GDP, we barely escaped the recession. Second quarter was originally negative and became positive; third quarter is negative; fourth quarter doesn't look so strong. So I don't think you'd call this year a very robust year for Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I meant the Singapore loan growth because your YTD Singapore loan growth is in excess of 10%, right, so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very right. So my point is this, that the underlying loan growth this year has been in the face of a fairly moribund macroeconomic context, and I can see that repeating next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question, Sharnie Wong from Barclays. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I had a quick question on your Hong Kong business, especially in offshore RMB, just from my channel checking with some of the local players, they're saying that loan yield could potentially come under pressure because I guess it's falling demand for mortgages. So the only source of growth really is in corporate and also more recently offshore RMB and that's why deposit rates are so high. So can you just talk a bit about what DBS is doing differently to make your margins improve rather than shrink like some of your competitors? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'm going to pass the question to Sebastian again. Sebastian, you want to take that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. What we've been doing with RMB deposits is basically placing in short-term trade RMB asset classes. We have stayed away from buying long-term bonds of RMB even from last year. So we maintain a very disciplined NIM expectations on RMB deposits and asset classes. And our liability cost of RMB has remained. We do acknowledge that some of the banks have increased RMB rates substantially, but we have not suffered any drop in our RMB deposits for the last six months, I would say.</p>
          <p>Now our RMB loans have decreased in the last month as I said because dollar rates are lower, however, we've been able to place that RMB into the interbank which right now yields above 3.2%, 3.5%. So our NIM and RMB has remained.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sharnie. Our next question, Kenneth from CIMB. Please go ahead, Kenneth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Kenneth Ng of CIMB. Just some questions from the media call just now particularly about investment banking fees and the debt capital market. One, I think I'll take one question at a time. Piyush, do you think that record debt capital market flows in Singapore for three years now, would that continue in the next few years? The reasons?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think the answer is yes. If we think about it, I think that Asia debt capital market just seem to grow, and frankly, I think it's not just trade cash bond. I think we would see a growth of asset-backed losses as well, covered bonds, securitization. Just because the demand-supply balance between the need for investment particularly infrastructure finance and the banking system availability of credit is just so huge. So I just think this is a megatrend which will continue to drive Asia.</p>
          <p>If you look at this year, the ringgit has been quite active. The Koreans have been issuing actively into Malaysia. In addition to the Sing dollar being active, the dim sum market being active, the Thai baht. So I just think that we're beginning to see strong pickup in fixed income capital market debt financing relative to the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The follow-on question to that is that, you, well, all these cost budgetings are taking place, you also mentioned there were new, country like India, Indonesia other than traditional Hong Kong, players issuing Sing. Typically, from what I understand in the business, when this thing happen, there's a lot of <mark type="ph" /> swap deals or (41:12) swap spreads you can earn on the treasury side, why haven't treasury been stronger this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Actually, we do earn and we did earn swap spreads in the treasury side, but remember treasury, there are two elements, right? So one is the trading book and trading book, really conservative in our positioning through the summer and into the third quarter because <mark type="ph" /> it follows (41:33) uncertainty around what's happening, and whether you have a major crisis around Europe. We've just not been very aggressive in position-taking.</p>
          <p>On the customer flow side, we had some advantage from the stocks you talk about. That's absolutely right. On the other hand, as the trade finance business and offshore renminbi arbitrage business has leveled off, we gave up some customer opportunity and revenues in that part of the business. So it was pretty much a wash.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, <mark type="ph" /> perfect (41:59). Thanks. And last question, you were mentioning that you were building up presence in Hong Kong for this stock capital expertise side. Today, I would say with your stock capital piece be 90 &#x2013; 100% mostly Singapore, is the non-Singapore side also gradually building up contributions in this...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Non-Singapore is also building up. As I mentioned, we're still dominant here. What we've been doing so far is originating business from issuers outside Singapore, but to a large extent, tapping into the Singapore market. So that has been the large part of the business. But for that, you still need to have the <mark type="ph" /> fiscal commercialization (42:34) capability. But we've also done other things. We've done a large number of dim sum bond issuances this year for example. We've done <mark type="ph" /> GT (42:42) issuances this year. Most of the issuers are those who have been in China, Hong Kong. So we've been building up our business and capability in North Asia as well. We think we can take it another level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understand. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. As there are no further questions, we would now begin closing comment. Michael, please begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So thank you, everybody, for joining us. We will see you next quarter. Thank you, and goodbye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's conference call. Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>