<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1267499" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-11-06</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8657</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Koh Boon Hwee, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Chng Sok Hui, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Conrad Tan</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Sam Holmes</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Rajan Raju</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I just want to start by &#x2013; with three key messages for everyone today. First of all, our core businesses did well, and the pipeline for our business remains very healthy. As an example, our net interest income hit an all-time quarterly record for the DBS Group at 1.14 billion. Our fee income this quarter has been the highest since the onset of the financial crisis. DBS Hong Kong's quarterly earnings were up 88% year-over-year, and the DBS Group as a whole, our earnings were up 40% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>The second point I would like to make is that our asset quality has begun to stabilize. Our non-performing loan rate has fallen from 2.8% to 2.6%, and this is likely to continue to taper off as the economy improves. During this period, we have put a lot of effort into focusing on risk management and into working proactively with our customers.</p>
          <p>The third point I would like to make is that, I believe DBS Group is well positioned to take advantage of the nascent economic recovery. Our balance sheet is strong. We are well capitalized. We remain committed to our customers. We have been very disciplined in managing our costs. And although 2010 may not be as buoyant as all of us might like, our outlook for the first half of 2010 is positive.</p>
          <p>I will now ask Sok Hui, our CFO, to take you through the details of our financial performance for the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. We delivered better earnings for the third quarter, as allowances declined. Net profit rose 2% from the previous quarter and 40% from a year ago to 563 million. The improved operating conditions in the first half of the year continued into the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Net interest income grew 3% from the previous quarter to a record SGD 1.14 billion. Net interest margins and assets remained steady. Fee income was robust at 361 million, which was the highest level since the onset of the global financial crisis and up 14% from year ago.</p>
          <p>Overall revenues fell 12% from the record high in the previous quarter largely due to lower trading and investment income.</p>
          <p>Expenses were kept at the previous quarter's level as we continue to exercise cost discipline. Allowances declined 43% from the previous quarter as asset quality stabilized. Specific allowances for loans fell from 83 basis points in the previous quarter to 70 basis points. New NPL formation eased during the quarter and loan repayments continue to be healthy across most markets.</p>
          <p>Net interest income rose 3% from the previous quarter to a record SGD 1.14 billion. Net interest margin improved slightly to 2.03% due to lower funding costs. This more than offset the impact of lower yields on loans and interbank assets as market rates remained soft.</p>
          <p>Excluding currency translation effects, loans grew by 1% during the quarter. Contributing to loans growth were housing loans in Singapore and Hong Kong, which grew 3.8% quarter-on-quarter, reflecting industry trends in both markets. We also saw growth in foreign currency corporate loans during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Deposits grew 1% over the quarter led by foreign currency deposits. While Singapore dollar deposits were flat, we continue to see an increase in the proportion of savings in demand deposits.</p>
          <p>Fee income rose 1% from the previous quarter to 361 million. Stock broking and investment banking benefited from improved capital market conditions. Other activities such as trade and remittances and credit cards remained strong.</p>
          <p>Other non-interest income was below the previous quarter. There were lower trading gains and interest rates and foreign exchange activities as well as lower asset valuation gains. Also contributing to the lower non-interest income was smaller gains from the sale of investment securities which fell to 7 million during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Costs were maintained at a similar level for the first two quarters of this year. Wage costs fell slightly from the previous quarter as head count was maintained, while non-wage expenses rose slightly due to higher IT costs. Compared to a year ago, costs rose 10% as bonus accruals have been curtailed in the year-ago period. This quarter's cost to income ratio was healthy at 40%. While higher than the previous quarter's ratio, it remains better than 2008 average of 43%.</p>
          <p>Turning to Hong Kong. The figures on the slide incorporate an appreciation of the Singapore dollar against the Hong Kong dollar of 2% from the previous quarter and a depreciation of 3% from a year ago,</p>
          <p>Earnings rose 44% from the previous quarter and 88% from a year ago to 143 million on lower credit cost and cost management. Net interest income rose 2% from the previous quarter on higher loan volumes driven by residential mortgages.</p>
          <p>Interest margins were unchanged from the previous quarter at 1.94%. An improvement in prime-HIBOR spreads was offset by lower asset yield as market interest rates remained soft.</p>
          <p>Non-interest income was 13% lower. Fee income was higher in stock broking, unit trust sales and trade and remittances. This was more than offset by lower trading gains and lower sales of treasury related products.</p>
          <p>Expenses fell 4% from the previous quarter as both staff and non-staff costs declined. Allowances declined 80% from the previous quarter as NPLs improved from 2.4% in the previous quarter to 2.0%. During the quarter, new NPL formations slowed, repayments remained strong, and collateral valuations improved from better property prices.</p>
          <p>The Group's non-performing assets declined for the first time since the onset of the financial crisis. The NPL ratio fell from 2.8% to 2.6% with the improvement broad based across markets. Net repayments from corporate and SME costumers in Hong Kong and China continued for a second consecutive quarter.</p>
          <p>34% of non-performing assets are still current in interest and principal similar to recent quarters. Overall loan loss allowance coverage improved to 90% and to 128% if collateral was considered.</p>
          <p>With the economy regaining its poise, the worst of asset quality pressures are likely to be behind us. Nevertheless, lingering risks remain in the short term as asset quality trends can lag. Assuming a reasonable gradual recovery, we should see NPLs trend down.</p>
          <p>We are keeping our dividends at $0.14 per share this quarter. Based on yesterday's closing share price, DBS shares give investors an annualized dividend yield of 4.3%.</p>
          <p>In summary, we have had a strong nine months. Operating trends have been healthy as revenues have held up while our cost structure has improved. Earnings before allowances for the first nine months were at a record.</p>
          <p>For the coming quarters, we will continue to strengthen our franchise by focusing on our customers, on costs and on risk management. Asset quality has begun to stabilize as NPLs have declined for the first time since the crisis began.</p>
          <p>We have seen NPL formation ease across the board and repayments picking up as economic conditions improve across markets. While risks remain in the short-term, our balance sheet is strong as we are well capitalized and have ample allowances. As this year's results have shown, we are well positioned to capture growth opportunities as they arise. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sok Hui. We will commence our question-and-answer session. As always, can you please introduce yourself, your name and which publication you represent? Could I have the first question please? Could you use the microphone please, Saeed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Saeed here. You said that there will be a positive growth in 2010, so when you say positive growth, are you saying that profits in 2010 will be significantly higher than, say, 2009 profit, the full-year profit, according to your estimates? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think my exact words were that our outlook for the first half of 2010 is cautious but optimistic. I did not make a forecast for profits.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know that. And you also know my answer, right? You didn't forecast, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question please. Gabriel? Pass the microphone to Gabriel please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Koh, a year ago the bank around this time announced 900 job cuts, if I remember correctly, just a year ago. Are we going to see a pick-up in hiring now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have never had a complete freeze on hiring. We've been &#x2013; we continue to hire through the process. It is a question of whether we hire more aggressively or less aggressively, but in terms of bringing people on board, we do that on a continuous basis. Given that our outlook for the first half of 2010 is cautiously optimistic, I think we are &#x2013; we have &#x2013; we will continue to hire.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Conrad?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Conrad from The Business Times. Can you just tell us a bit more about your outlook for loans growth, because it's been flat across the industry for the past couple of quarters, do you see that picking up in the coming months? And also similar question for net interest margins. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'd expect our loan growth to actually be better or to be in line with the industry growth. So, how fast we'll grow depends very much on how the industry grows. But certainly in a more recent period, we have seen a pick-up in mortgage loans and that part of our loans have been very strong. Conrad, you had a second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Net interest margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Net interest margin. I think you're aware that DBS net interest margin has several components, one of which is the surplus funds. They are placed in interbank market, and for the whole of this year, their rate has been extremely low, close to 10 basis points. So assuming that rates begin to pick-up, I think we should see better net interest margins, but we also know that credit spreads have been &#x2013; have come under some pressure. So I think as a balance of these two factors, they will determine our net interest margin going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any questions from this side of the room?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sam Holmes from Dow Jones Newswires. Your OCBC counterpart, or rather CEO David Connor said NPLs, he expects they've peaked, is that something you're able to say for your Group as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as I indicated in our opening comments, our NPL has come down this quarter, 2.8% last quarter, 2.6% as the economy recovers, we expect that to continue to improve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kevin, could you use the mike please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm Kevin from Reuters. Besides organic growth, are there any certain businesses which DBS is keen on growing quickly which may involve mergers and acquisitions? And if so, what are these businesses? For instance, one of your competitors recently bought a private bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as we have always said, our focus is on growing our franchise organically and we continue to do that given an overall reasonably positive environment in our Asian footprint. But if opportunities do arise we will look at inorganic opportunities as well, but we are intent to stay very disciplined about what we are willing to pay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> I think the reality of mergers and acquisitions, if you want an asset, you probably have to pay slightly over the top, because it's very unlikely anyone's going to sell an asset at cost or around cost, but they want to get a premium. So when you say you're going to be reasonable and you're not going to pay, are you prepared to pay what you call a premium, what you call a goodwill premium?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, because no one is going to let a good asset go for cheap, right? So if it is meaningful, certainly you're going to have to pay for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe just spin it around, do you think DBS is still constrained by say, overpriced acquisitions made several years ago? And that this has made DBS very reluctant to bid high?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't really think so. The Dao Heng acquisition, whatever it is, did transform DBS. Without it, we probably would not be in as many markets as we are today. I think you can always look back on these things with perfect hindsight, but I think if the asset is worth it, if it is strategic, if it adds value to DBS, then I think we would be prepared to pay for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Kevin, I think as previously mentioned, if you were referring to the previous ING acquisition by OCBC, I think DBS had come up to &#x2013; I think kind of Calamander Capital have said that DBS's private bank is rank I think number six versus ING Asia, which is number 14. So, as you could have seen that, I think we already have a fairly leading position in the private bank space. Any other questions? Gabriel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Koh, in some quarters the way you slashed bad debt allowances so significantly this quarter versus a year ago or versus the previous quarter, it seems to suggest that you &#x2013; that the bank is not exactly cautiously optimistic but is in fact really optimistic, do you agree with that? I mean, do you think that there is a risk to being too optimistic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I do not think that that is the way you should read that. Banks have a rigorous process about how they pick provisions, whether it is specific or how they classify a loan at NPL. I think if you have a process, you need to stick to it, so that you have consistency, period-to-period, quarter-to-quarter, and because if you start deviating from your established processes then it becomes a very subjective exercise. So I don't think you should read my outlook for 2010 and correlate it to whatever numbers those are. The two processes are completely unrelated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Gula?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gula from The Edge. I think I have three questions. First one is your ROE is down to single-digit, and your CAR is one of the highest in the industry, and you have the rights issue in December '08. So, are you &#x2013; how you are going to deploy your capital in the most efficient way? That's first question.</p>
          <p>Second question is, DBS was believed to be in the running for ING and you were...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For ING Asia private bank, and you walked away, so why did you do that? And the third part of &#x2013; the third question is related to the second question. Is &#x2013; how important is private banking to DBS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is a significant number of questions. Let me start off on the issue of capital. In spite of the fact that the economy seems to be recovering, the financial industry still lives in pretty uncertain times. Across the world, all banks have been raising the amount of capital that they have, and if we were unique before in terms of &#x2013; for example, our Tier 1 capital, we are no longer unique in comparison globally, because almost everybody else has also bulked up.</p>
          <p>There is also ongoing discussions from a regulatory point of view about how much capital banks might need going forward. So, it is true that our capital ratios look good, but we still live in pretty uncertain times. Sok Hui, you want add something to that?</p>
          <p>Now, your second question is that, let me answer your third question first, private banking is very important to the DBS Group. It is an area of business that we want to be successful in, we are committed to it.</p>
          <p>Now let me get back to your second question. According to the rankings, we are number six. We have a reasonably large private banking practice. If an inorganic opportunity presents itself that makes sense to us, we would pursue it, but we would not pay a premium for entry into the business because we are already number six in the business. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think, according to &#x2013; just to give you the numbers, Gula, according to the Calamander Capital, DBS manages about 22 billion in client assets versus INGs estimated to be at about 16 billion US.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's US dollars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes US dollars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Any other questions? Saeed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of Hong Kong, I just looked at the numbers, Hong Kong accounted for 21% of net profit in the first nine months of this year, and Singapore accounted for 54%. Where do you see the Hong Kong number to be in the long term?</p>
          <p>How much did it account for your total profit because it seems a lot of analysts have been critical that the Hong Kong business is not delivering the value for money, do you think that you need to change your strategy on Hong Kong? I can see that numbers have come up 88%, but last year was a very bad year. So, do you think there needs to be a change in strategy in Hong Kong or a change of business focus? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We review &#x2013; of course, I mean, we all want Hong Kong to do better and we are pretty confident that we can do better. We review our strategy in Hong Kong constantly, so I'm not going to make a forecast about exactly what ratio it will be of our total earnings. But we are pretty confident that our performance in Hong Kong will continue to improve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This problem of Hong Kong &#x2013; is one of your problems in Hong Kong being that DBS is almost like a full banker engaged in most business, although, within Hong Kong DBS is quite small, unlike, say, in Singapore where it is a very dominant player?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly in terms of &#x2013; in terms of market share, I think we have a lot of opportunities in Hong Kong. But there are also advantages associated with being the largest in terms of economies of scale. So, you are right in a certain sense, but I would not like to leave you with the impression that we try to duplicate in Hong Kong what we do in Singapore across the board.</p>
          <p>We are in fact relatively focused in Hong Kong in the corporate business on our SME business, and in the consumer banking business we are fairly focused on serving, recognizing that we are not dominant in that market on basically serving a priority banking niche.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any last questions? Ellison?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. There's been quite a bit of speculation that when Piyush starts, which is Monday, right? That you would soon step down as Chairman, it seems a bit weird, because you need &#x2013; I mean, you need to show him the ropes I presume, for a short while at least. Can you confirm you at least stay the term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My goodness, this is the first time I've heard all that. My priority when Piyush comes on board on Monday, the key goal is to bring him up to speed as quickly as we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about your Chairmanship term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe that I'm the person who is going to be bringing him up to speed. Would you like to do it instead?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, will you stay until the next AGM at least?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have not thought about that, because my first priority in the next few months is to bring him completely up to speed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can't you answer the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I already have answered the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you feel you have a tenure as Chairman, a fixed tenure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do we have fixed tenures?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> period for the Chairman as to how long, is it five years, is it fixed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't think it is fixed. No, I do not believe that it is fixed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you plan to stay until as long as you can?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't say that either. But as long as you can means until the day I drop dead. That would be a little extreme, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think suffice to say for now he is looking forward to having Piyush on Board such that he can resume a non-Executive role on the Board and become non-Exec Chairman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can tell you what I'm going to do as soon as he is up to speed, and then to go for a really long vacation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Conrad?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Conrad again. I just want to ask you a bit more about the customer loans book, clearly the growth this quarter &#x2013; whatever growth there was, came from housing loans in Singapore and Hong Kong. Would you be able to tell us whether it was more on the Singapore side or the Hong Kong side? And can you also give us an idea of where loan spreads, customer loans I'm referring to, loan spreads are going?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rajan, do you want to take that question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the mortgages, actually it was both between Singapore and Hong Kong where we grew. Obviously, in Singapore we've got a larger book, so more growth obviously came from Singapore than Hong Kong. But we are pretty pleased with the way that Hong Kong business has also started to build a mortgage book.</p>
          <p>Most of the loans actually that we focus our efforts on &#x2013; were on resale properties. That's the piece that we made a plenty of progress in. And in terms of the way we look at the market itself, we do think that some of the properties we are starting to seize, there is some amount of slowdown, but there is still a fair amount of interest amongst consumers to look at buying or acquiring property. That's the piece I can talk to you about the mortgage side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rajan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The loan spread...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The loan spread?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there has been more competition in the market recently, so I think there is some pressure on the credit spreads.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gula.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Gula. Can you just go back to private banking and ask you whether you plan to hire more private bankers, because there's been a bit of merry-go-round recently? And also, are you &#x2013; what's your outlook for AUM growth in private banking for DBM?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Second question is easy, we don't make forecasts. The first question, yes, we plan to hire more relationship managers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Should we have the last two questions please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> relationship managers, is this private banking, or private banking and priority banking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, her question was private banking, so I answered that. If you want to ask whether we will hire more relationship managers in priority banking, the answer is also yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Visa Yunwin from Zaobao. I've just got an enquiry regarding High Notes 2. So I heard there's some request for redemption for High Notes 2, recently there's credit events, so is there any possibility or plan for DBS to do so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, what was the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>About High Notes 2, are you planning or thinking of offering redemption to the investors? Like <mark type="inaudible" /> and UOB did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far I know as of right now High Notes 2 is safe. There is no &#x2013; I mean, if you are referring for example to the Chapter 11 filing by CIT, it does not affect our collateral &#x2013; it affects the collateral basket, but it doesn't put it in danger. And we have never put up any plans for redemption.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But in view of the credit events, so &#x2013; just I mean there is a possibility the more credit events could happens. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is always the possibility that there will be more credit events.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is there any plan if such case happens?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will cross that bridge when we come to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Cold we have a last question? Okay, well, thank you very much and see you next quarter then. Have a good weekend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>