<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1454469" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-02-09</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8657</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Strategic Marketing &amp; Communications">Karen Ngui</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Sok Hui Chng</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Piyush Gupta</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Thomson Reuters">Kevin Lim</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Thank you for joining us today for our Full-Year Financial Results Briefing, which includes also our Fourth Quarter Results.</p>
          <p>Without further ado, I'm pleased to hand the floor over to my colleague, Sok Hui, our CFO. After Sok Hui gives us more details about the results, then Piyush, our Group CEO, will give you more color about how we achieved our record-breaking SGD3 billion &#x2013; SGD3.35 billion net profit for the year, okay? Thank you so much. SGD3.035 billion, yes. Thank you. I got a little bit carried away here. Yeah.</p>
          <p>Okay, Sok Hui. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. We achieved record earnings of SGD3.04 billion in 2011, up 15% from 2010. Total income reached a record of SGD7.63 billion, driven by higher business volume and customer flows. Net interest income reached a new high of SGD4.83 billion. Loans grew 28%, while deposits rose 16%, as we captured lending opportunities across the region and strengthened our deposit-gathering capabilities.</p>
          <p>The higher volumes were partially offset by a decline in net interest margins from 1.84% a year ago to 1.77%. Non-interest income rose 2% to SGD2.81 billion with higher customer income offset by lower market-related income. Fee income rose 10% to SGD1.54 billion from higher contributions in a wide range of activities led by wealth management, trade and remittances, and investment banking. Trading income fell 24% to SGD680 million, as a 20% increase in income from cross-selling treasury products was more than offset by lower trading gains.</p>
          <p>Other non-interest income was 28% higher at SGD584 million from higher gains in investment securities. Expenses were higher at SGD3.30 billion, as investments in people and infrastructure were made for business growth. The cost-to-income ratio was healthy at 43%.</p>
          <p>Total allowances fell 21% to SGD722 million as asset quality improved. Specific allowances of SGD244 million were one-third the amount in 2010, while general allowances more than doubled to SGD478 million, reflecting a more prudent provisioning policy.</p>
          <p>ROE for 2011 rose to 11% from 10.2% in 2010. For the fourth quarter, we earned SGD731 million, up 8% from a year ago. Net interest income rose 17% to a quarterly record of SGD1.29 billion. Increase was due to a 28% growth in loans, which resulted in a more effective deployment of our surplus deposit. Non-interest income was little changed at SGD626 million. Fee income fell 4% to SGD342 million.</p>
          <p>Weaker markets affected stockbroking and investment banking contributions, which offset higher customer-driven contributions in trade and remittances, loan activities and credit cards. Trading income fell 19%. From lower trading gains, our income from customer flows was comparable to a year ago. Other non-interest income rose 50% to SGD151 million, as we realized gains from the sale of investment securities. Total income grew 11%, while expenses rose slightly faster at 13% mainly from higher staff costs. Total allowances rose 46% to SGD229 million due to higher general allowances set aside.</p>
          <p>Compared to the previous quarter, net profit was 4% lower, as total income fell 3%. This was due mainly to a gain of SGD47 million in the previous quarter from the transaction to combine DBS Asset Management and Nikko Asset Management. Excluding the gain, fourth quarter earnings will be 2% higher. Operating trends were sustained and business momentum continue to be healthy.</p>
          <p>Net interest income rose 6%, as loans grew 5% and interest margins were stable over the quarter. This helped to offset lower non-interest income due to seasonally quieter markets at year-end. Fee income from stockbroking, investment banking and loan activities fell, while income from cross-selling treasury products was also lower. Allowances were little changed as an increase in specific allowances was offset by lower general allowances.</p>
          <p>Net interest income reached a quarterly record of SGD1.29 billion in the fourth quarter. Net interest income has been on an uptrend over the past several quarters, the result of steady loan and deposit growth during the period. The higher loan and deposit volumes over the past two years more than offset the impact of a soft interest rate environment in Singapore and rising deposit costs in Hong Kong. We were also able to temper the pace of margin decline with balance sheet management efforts. In the fourth quarter, interest margins of 1.73% was unchanged from the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Loans grew 5% on SGD9 billion from the previous quarter, bringing growth to 28% or SGD43 billion over the past year. Half of the growth was due to trade finance, as we took advantage of market opportunities to gain new customers and increase wallet share of existing ones.</p>
          <p>Deposit increased 3% or SGD6 billion from the previous quarter and 16% or SGD32 billion over the past year. With loans growing faster than deposits, the loan-to-deposit ratio rose from 79% a year ago to 86%. This was a deliberate move to deploy off excess deposits more effectively.</p>
          <p>The SGD32 billion increase in deposits in 2011 was significantly larger than the SGD10 billion growth in 2010 and the annual average growth of SGD15 billion between 2005 and 2010. This reflects our expanded ability to garner deposits, as we expand our customer base and build up cash management capabilities.</p>
          <p>Our strong fundamentals and high credit ratings have also distinguished us from competitors, improving our ability to attract new sources of funding. During the year, our traditional leadership in Sing dollar deposits was augmented by a strengthened capacity for garnering U.S. dollar funding. We are now tapping new sources of U.S. dollar deposits, including from MNCs. We also have wholesale funding programs from which we have raised $8 billion so far. Our surplus Sing dollar deposits also enables us to tap the swap market for U.S. dollar funds.</p>
          <p>With a diversified range of options, we are now able to raise U.S. dollar funds in the most cost-effective way for the desired tenants. We are confident of being able to match loan demand with the necessary funding. We expect to grow both in a low double-digit range in 2012.</p>
          <p>Full-year fee income rose 10% to SGD1.54 billion. Contributions from wealth management and trade and remittances slightly increased, growing 41% and 25% respectively, as efforts to develop these businesses yielded results. Investment banking fees were 21% higher from stronger primary debt and equity market activity. These gains were offset by lower stockbroking commissions.</p>
          <p>Fee income in the fourth quarter amounted to SGD342 million, which was 4% lower than a year ago and 14% below the previous quarter. Stockbroking and investment banking contributed to the weaker performance against both comparative periods, and this was partially offset by higher credit card and wealth management fees.</p>
          <p>Full-year other non-interest income fell 6% to SGD1.26 billion. Lower trading gains were partially offset by higher gains from the sale of investment securities. We deploy our excess liquidity in fixed income investments, and a low interest rate environment made it conducive to realize profits done in 2011.</p>
          <p>As at end 2011, the unrealized mark-to-market gains on the investment portfolio stood at SGD411 million. Fourth quarter other non-interest income of SGD284 million was 7% above a year ago, as investment gains rose. It was 20% below the previous quarter, which had included a SGD47 million gain from the transaction to combine DBS Asset Management and Nikko Asset Management.</p>
          <p>Customer income for treasury products rose 20% for the full year to SGD822 million, as we continue to improve the cross-selling of interest rate and foreign exchange products to corporate and retail customers. Customer income now accounts for 42% of total interest and non-interest treasury income compared to 36% in 2010 and 27% in 2009.</p>
          <p>The increase in customer income offset a 7% decline in other treasury income of SGD1.15 billion from balance sheet management, market-making and warehousing. Total treasury income rose slightly to SGD1.97 billion.</p>
          <p>Full-year expenses rose 13% to SGD3.30 billion, as we invested in staff and infrastructure for higher business volumes and future growth. The cost-to-income ratio was healthy at 43%. For the fourth quarter, expenses rose 13% from a year ago and 4% from the previous quarter to SGD885 million.</p>
          <p>Our growth markets of China, Taiwan, India and Indonesia grew strongly during the year. The four markets accounted for most of the growth in earnings from operations outside of Singapore and Hong Kong in 2011, which rose 53% to SGD587 million. These earnings accounted for 19% of the Group's earnings, up from 14% in 2010.</p>
          <p>Earnings from China and Taiwan combined jumped from SGD47 million in 2010 to SGD178 million. Loans booked in both countries rose 34% to SGD16 billion, which resulted in a 68% rise in net interest income to SGD550 million.</p>
          <p>We opened eight outlets in China in 2011 and one in January 2012, bringing our network to 25 branches and sub-branches in nine cities. In addition, our operations in Taiwan were locally incorporated in January of 2012.</p>
          <p>Earnings from South and Southeast Asia rose 40% to SGD285 million, with India and Indonesia contributing to the majority of the increase. Loans booked in South and Southeast Asia, which also includes Labuan branch, rose 16% to SGD11 billion, while net interest income rose 28% to SGD361 million. We are now the fifth largest foreign bank in India by assets. In Indonesia, we expanded our loans to SMEs and consumers during the year.</p>
          <p>Asset quality in the markets outside Singapore and Hong Kong improved in 2011 and remain healthy. Total allowances fell 46% to SGD100 million, and specific allowances fell in all countries outside of Singapore and Hong Kong.</p>
          <p>Hong Kong reported full-year earnings of SGD571 million, up 7% in constant currency terms. Total income rose 8% from higher loan volumes and customer-driven non-interest income, partially offset by lower interest margin and higher general allowances.</p>
          <p>Net interest income rose 9% in constant currency terms to SGD789 million. Loans expanded 26% from a year ago led by trade finance. Deposits rose 3%. The higher volumes were partially offset by a 21 basis point decline in interest margins to 1.39% due to competitive pricing for customer deposits. Non-interest income increased 6% in constant currency terms to SGD664 million. The increase was led by customer flow income for treasury products and trading gains in CNH activities.</p>
          <p>Fee income from wealth management and investment banking was also higher. Expenses of SGD646 million, so 3% in constant currency terms, as lower provisions for constellation notes were offset by increases in staff and non-staff costs. Profit before allowances improved 18% in constant currency terms to SGD807 million. Total allowances almost doubled to SGD130 million due to higher general allowances. Specific allowances remained low as asset quality remained healthy.</p>
          <p>The NPL rate for Hong Kong was 0.8% compared to 1% a year ago. For the fourth quarter, Hong Kong recorded net profit of SGD130 million. This was 8% below a year ago in constant currency terms, as an increase in net interest income was more than offset by higher expenses and general allowances. Net interest income rose 12% to SGD211 million from higher customer loan rates offset by lower margins.</p>
          <p>Non-interest income was little changed at SGD151 million. With expenses rising 6% to SGD184 million, profit before allowances was 5% higher at SGD178 million. Higher general allowances accounted for most of the 43% increase in total allowances to SGD24 million.</p>
          <p>Compared to the previous quarter, net profit was 14% higher in constant currency terms as allowances declined. Net interest income rose 7%, as higher average loan rates boosted net interest margins by 10 basis points to 1.35%. Loans grew 3% led by trade loans, while deposits declined 2%. Non-interest income rose 5% from better trading results, which was partially offset by reduced customer flows for treasury products in the last quarter. Expenses increased 16%, as staff and computerization expenses rose. Total allowances fell 47%, as both general and specific allowances declined.</p>
          <p>Asset quality trends remain healthy. Non-performance assets rose 4% from the previous quarter to SGD2.9 billion due to one legacy exposure in the shipping portfolio. 40% of our non-performing assets are still current in interest and principal, including the new shipping NPL. The NPL rate was unchanged at 1.3% from the previous quarter. Allowance coverage rose to 126%. If collateral was included, the allowance coverage would be 165%.</p>
          <p>We had SGD32 billion of available-for-sale investment securities at end 2011, roughly divided between Singapore government, other government and non-government debt. There was also a small amount of equity in the portfolio. European government and bank debt amounted to SGD2 billion or 0.6% of assets with most of the holdings in AAA-rated government or supranational entities. The total AFS portfolio had unrealized gains of SGD411 million at end 2011 compared to SGD387 million at end 2010.</p>
          <p>Our capital position remains strong. The Tier 1 ratio of 12.9% and total capital adequacy ratio of 15.8% are comfortably above regulatory requirements. The end 2011 capital position ratios take into account the Basel 2.5 having implemented with effect from December 2011.</p>
          <p>Compared to the previous quarter, both ratios were 0.3% higher, as eligible Tier 1 and total regulatory capital increased, while risk-weighted assets were unchanged at SGD214 billion. Loan growth during the quarter resulted in an increase in credit risk-weighted assets, but this was offset by a reduction in operational risk-weighted assets with the lifting of the operational risk multiplier in October. In addition, we set aside lower capital for market risk in the fourth quarter despite the implementation of Basel 2.5 rules.</p>
          <p>Under <mark type="ph" /> MAS (18:14) Basel III requirements for the calculation of the core Tier 1 ratio, which will take effect from 2013, there'll be no deductions against common equity until end 2013. In 2014, deductions will be set aside at 20% and they will progressively rise to 100% in 2018.</p>
          <p>Based on zero deductions, the core Tier 1 ratio at end 2011 was 12.9%. If full deductions are assumed, the core Tier 1 ratio was 11%. Both core Tier 1 ratios are comfortably above regulatory requirements.</p>
          <p>We are paying a final dividend of SGD0.28 per share, bringing the full-year payout to SGD0.56 per share, unchanged from the previous year. Based on yesterday's closing price, the dividend yield is 4.1%.</p>
          <p>The scrip dividend scheme will apply to this dividend. For shareholders electing to receive their dividend in scrip, more shares will be issued at a 5% discount to the average of the closing share prices on 9th, 10th and 11th May.</p>
          <p>In summary, our performance in 2011 was the result of our focused execution of strategy, prudent risk management and a strong balance sheet. Despite a soft interest rate environment, we're able to achieve record earnings that exceeded SGD3 billion for the first time.</p>
          <p>With company's strong earnings generation and careful capital management, we will have sufficient capital to continue supporting our customers' financing needs. Our expanded deposit-gathering capabilities will ensure that we have sufficient liquidity. We remain committed to building a leading Asian banking franchise and are well positioned to capture growth opportunities in a judicious and disciplined manner in the coming year.</p>
          <p>Thank you. I will now hand you over to Piyush.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Sok Hui.</p>
          <p>I'm just going to recap a little bit of what Sok Hui mentioned, because I think there are two or three important points to focus on, and then talk about a few other things which are relatively topical. And Sok Hui has taken you through the numbers. I'm not going to do that.</p>
          <p>I want to make &#x2013; re-emphasize three or four points. The first is we had a really strong fourth quarter from our top line performance. Fourth quarter top line is obviously driven by net interest income, 6% growth at SGD1.29 billion, it's very strong, reflects continuing growth in net interest income quarter-by-quarter, as you can see now for the last couple of years. But frankly in some ways, I'm even more pleased by our overall performance, including the rest of the non-interest income line.</p>
          <p>Total income, if you look at our total business, 3% down quarter-on-quarter. That includes the SGD47 million from Nikko, which we recognized in the third quarter. So if you ex that out, we are actually flat to slightly better, which for a fourth quarter is actually very dramatic. Fourth quarter typically, as you know, December winds up, customer flows tend to run down, trading <mark type="ph" /> is doing this (21:41). So seasonally fourth quarters tend to be slower.</p>
          <p>On top of that, this fourth quarter was particularly challenged, because as you can see from the results of every other major bank around the world, people took some large knocks in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>So I think our ability to negotiate through the fourth quarter rapids &#x2013; and we continue to deliver very strong fourth quarter earnings performance, top line performance &#x2013; is something which is worth reflecting on. I think it was very good.</p>
          <p>The second thing I want to focus on a little bit is our trading performance in particular for the year. So there's &#x2013; I mean we'll have to go through the numbers carefully to see all of the stuff. But our trading performance comprises, one, the customer activity. Customer activity was up 20%, and that's a couple of hundred million bucks of net gain we had, which we've talked about before, that was very good.</p>
          <p>If you look at the non-customer activity, the non-customer activity comprises stuff we do on the interest line for yield, stuff we do on the trading line, which is buy and sell, and stuff we do which shows up on the sale of investments line. Because we are going in and out of the investment portfolio.</p>
          <p>If you'll put the whole trading thing together for the year, we're down about SGD80 million bucks for the year compared to last year. To me, that's actually quite fantastic, because again, as I pointed out before, this year has been a graveyard for most people on the trading side on the investment banking side. So I'm very pleased about the resiliency in our non-customer-related trading performances.</p>
          <p>If you look at our investment portfolio, Sok Hui made the point, we started the year with the portfolio being in the money by about SGD400 million. We ended the year with the portfolio being in the money by about SGD400 million. So all of the gains we've done have not been by selling the family silver. They've actually been very, very judicious and smart, creative things. I'm quite pleased about that.</p>
          <p>The third piece I want to draw your attention to is this whole &#x2013; this thing of what we've done to build up allowances. So if you look at our fourth quarter, we had strong top line. Then there is some growth in our expense number. Our cost-to-income for the quarter is 45% <mark type="ph" /> and between (23:50) 46%. But that's a fourth quarter average, so some bonus accruals and cleanup. It's not &#x2013; <mark type="inaudible" /> (23:55).</p>
          <p>Our allowances number has gone up. Our tax number is very low. The tax number, we knew we were getting benefit from and Sok Hui can explain that. But as a consequence, we took the opportunity to make sure that we were conservative on allowances again.</p>
          <p>So our loan book grew SGD9 billion, SGD10 billion. We needed SGD90 million, SGD100 million in general allowances. But we put SGD130 million bucks into general allowances. So the way I think about it, most of the gains we got in the tax line. We actually adjusted into the allowances line. So our real performance is not a tax-driven performance. It's a very, very strong fourth quarter performance for the year. So third point I wanted to make with respect to the numbers.</p>
          <p>The fourth point is this, if you look at our growth momentum and our earnings quarter-on-quarter, we are getting very comfortable that our earnings are showing quarterly trend and we are hitting the SGD1.9 billion range quarter-after-quarter, SGD1.8 billion, SGD1.9 billion quite consistently and that's something to reflect on this, degree of stability and consistency in the earnings that you see. So those are the four comments I wanted to make with respect to our numbers and the fourth quarter performance per se.</p>
          <p>Slide, please. Okay, something I thought might be topical to focus on, one, asset quality. I talked about it at the end of the last quarter, there're still some concerns out there about what's happening, so we'll talk briefly about that.</p>
          <p>Liquidity, we were asked a number of questions the last time about LDRs, liquidity, how you're doing. So we will talk briefly about that.</p>
          <p>And then, I want to take some time to just take you through some of my nine strategic priorities. They're the ones which move the needle. I read some analyst reports in recent times which said DBS needs to demonstrate, it's delivering against some of these to be able to convince people about the sustainability of the performance. So I just thought I'd reflect and walk you through what we've done on some of these things.</p>
          <p>On the asset quality &#x2013; slide please &#x2013; so Sok Hui made this point. So I'm not going to spend too much time, but our NPL data, 1.3%, is unchanged. And we pointed out before that the way we classify our non-performing assets is actually very conservative. 40% of what we put in non-performing is actually still current in interest and principal, right. So we just use internal triggers to move it to non-performing, but it's not as if we didn't get paid or <mark type="ph" /> they're really &#x2013; which distinguishes us (26:14) quite good.</p>
          <p>Including the legacy shipping one we recognized in non-performing in this last quarter, it's current in principal, it's current in interest. We've just been ahead of the curve, if you ask me, in recognizing that, because it hit some internal triggers. <mark type="ph" /> So, as I said, might as well take that (26:30).</p>
          <p>Allowance coverage at 126% is very solid. It went up from 124% to 126%, the extra SGD40 million we put into general allowances in this quarter, but at 126% we're very comfortable. We have no specific reason for building the allowances. We don't have any insight into stuff coming, it's just being conservative and prudent and we had the capacity to do it, so we've done that.</p>
          <p>And I guess, our investment portfolio continues to be of high quality. Sok Hui pointed out, we have 30-odd billion between Sing dollar SGS, between other governments, between private sector. It's a solid quality investment portfolio. We will not recognize any losses below the line, we've not had to. Our gains in the portfolio are still the SGD400 million we started off with.</p>
          <p>So whether you look at our loan book, whether you look at our investments book, whether you look at any of this thing, our asset quality is actually very good. As I'm looking out, I'm seeing no headwinds. Interestingly, notwithstanding all of the issues in the global environment, our delinquency rates are not going up, our stress or this thing is not showing any signs of trouble in any of our portfolios, in any of our countries. So I'm relatively comfortable at this point in time that the asset quality is actually very good.</p>
          <p>Slide? On liquidity. So if you look at the liquidity piece, this was a point Sok Hui made, it's worth reflecting on. We grew our loans SGD42 billion or SGD43 billion this year. That's substantial, 28% loan growth, right. But to me what is far more important is to recognize that we grew our deposits SGD32 billion this year, right.</p>
          <p>Our deposits normally grew at SGD15 billion. Last year, our deposits grew at SGD8 billion or SGD10 billion. Deposit growth has more than doubled. In fact, actually, relative to last year almost tripled, right.</p>
          <p>I think that speaks to very profound implications for what we are doing with our liquidity and our franchise, because we are really stepping on the accelerator in terms of being able to fund our growth, right. If you look at the box on the side, so Sing dollar grew SGD11 billion, Sing dollar on an average generally grows at about SGD8 billion. So we've actually upped our Sing dollar deposit this thing.</p>
          <p>But the thing that really moved the needle were the dollar deposits. Last year, we grew dollar deposits by zero or SGD1 billion. This year, we grew dollar deposits by SGD10 billion. And that's coming on the back of both our focus on GTS and our focus on wealth, right. And so you can see those numbers there.</p>
          <p>Out total GTS deposits, GTS brought in SGD16 billion of the deposits. Wealth brought in SGD9 billion of those deposits, right. So these are solid underlying business drivers, which are delivering what we want them to deliver. They're bringing in liabilities. They're allowing us to fund accelerated growth in our asset book.</p>
          <p>On top of that, from a liquidity standpoint, the other thing we did this year, which we pointed earlier, is that we decided to start relying, to some extent, on wholesale funding. We never used the wholesale markets before and I made the point last quarter that we figured that it was not smart of us to have zero presence in the wholesale market.</p>
          <p>So we've been more active in the wholesale markets. We've put in place a commercial paper program. We raised SGD6 billion in that. We get very good pricing on commercial paper. We're not a &#x2013; we're a much sought-after name in the commercial paper market, because we have a very good rating and we're a rare commodity. So we can actually leverage that well.</p>
          <p>And then, we focused on raised institutional monies, which are swap and interbank in our reported numbers, but they're really institutional monies offer different this thing, where we work on institutions and get a better tenor and quality of institutional borrowings. So I'm actually very pleased with where we are in terms of our overall liquidity and our deposit-gathering capacity.</p>
          <p>We did temper off our loan growth in the fourth quarter, which is what we said we would. Our third quarter constant currency, we grew loans at about SGD12 billion; fourth quarter, we brought it down to about SGD9 billion, because we said we're going to grow loans more in pace with the deposit growth that we have. But our deposit growth is good enough to be able to sustain a fairly good level of loan growth. And so that's the second thing which I think is worth focusing on.</p>
          <p>Slide? Some of the things in the <mark type="ph" /> pipeline is (30:32) Singapore. And for two years, I've been saying for us to win in the region, we must win in Singapore. And I'm really pleased with where we are with our Singapore business. The business is doing well.</p>
          <p>Our full-year business, as reported in Singapore, is up 7%. Frankly, pure Singapore franchise, the way I look at it, is actually up 9%. The reason it's 7% is because my regional treasury also gets counted in the reported Singapore numbers, but I really think of that as different from our Singapore franchise business. This is actually up 9% from year ago.</p>
          <p>And if you look at the momentum, we have momentum on both sides, the institutional side of the business, as well as on the consumer bank side of the business. And that's really interesting in a low interest rate environment to get the kind of momentum in our consumer business.</p>
          <p>If you remember, the principal driver for us in Singapore is we got to get the LDR up, right. LDR was too low; we were in the mid-50s. We have too many Sing dollar deposits, we weren't using them smartly. Our LDR for Sing dollar is now up to the mid-60s, at 64%. And you can see that our market share is growing systematically, maybe, growing a percent point of market share we have, so that's very good.</p>
          <p>So I feel good about the progress we've made over there. We clearly had a fantastic stellar year on the capital market side in the corporate space. And then we just were top of the league table, say, everything by a mile and more, equities, debts, REITs, syndicated loans, you name it. We just &#x2013; we're top of the league tables for every one of these.</p>
          <p>Slide, please. On the consumer side, this is tough, but we really worked hard. And I told you, this is where we have to make a big impact. We really thought that we had lost position in the consumer space over the last decade.</p>
          <p>I'm really pleased that our strategies in the consumer side are beginning to bear fruit and you can see the impact of those. So, one, as you remember, I told you that we are going to use our branch distribution and instead of using it only as service points, we are going to make them sales points, right. We experimented with a pilot in the early part of the year with some 12 branches. In the later part of the year, by the end of the third quarter, we rolled out the pilot nationwide.</p>
          <p>That pilot is already beginning to deliver results. So if you look at three metrics I've chosen to show here, one is the investment sales, i.e. the amount of sales we do in our investment product in the normal branch and then with the new branch and you can see the dramatic difference. The second metric I've shown is the number of RMs in the branch network who are now selling mortgages.</p>
          <p>In the year, from first quarter to fourth quarter, it went from 41% to 51%, frankly my Jan numbers, which I just got, 65%, right. So suddenly from 40% of the RMs in the branches doing stuff, now two-thirds of the RMs are beginning to sell mortgages. Our goal is to get every one of them selling mortgages into the network in this thing over the next quarter or so. So that's dramatic, because it completely changes the origination nature of your mortgage business.</p>
          <p>The third thing I have is, what I call, mortgage protection. So we sell insurance along with the mortgage, which is cross-sell. When you sell it through the branch network, you get much better lift in the ability to cross-sell that than you do when you sell it through the realtor route or through the director's route and so that's also quite visible, right. So I'm very pleased that whole branch model and using the distribution we have in Singapore meaningfully is kicking in nicely.</p>
          <p>The second thing we did, we have a mass-market business, we have this 2.5 million low-end accounts and we got to figure out how we service them well, but service them in a cost-effective manner, right. And so, we've done a couple of things. We added 60 new locations through the SingPost tie-up and we added six more, what we call, basic banking branches. These are the 200 to 500 square feet small branches we're creating, to be able to increase our touch points, but not increase our cost, right. So that's actually we need to work really well, too.</p>
          <p>And frankly, this is coupled by the fact that the migration to online is happening very rapidly. We can see every quarter the percentage of traffic that's coming into the physical, terrestrial distribution is shifting to the traffic that's coming in through the online space for us. And the fact, therefore, that we're the leading online bank, both internet and mobile, is extremely welcome and so we continue to push unless there's paying dividend.</p>
          <p>And finally, our service, we continue to focus on getting the service right. So our branch queue-time is now down under nine minutes. If you remember, when I first came in, I told you it was 25 minutes to half an hour. So we've now got it down to under nine minutes.</p>
          <p>And at our contact center, my first year, the average wait time was eight minutes, we got it down to one minute, now it's down to 20 seconds, in terms of speed of actually 12 seconds in the last six months than now we're creating. And in terms of call, answer within 20 seconds, we now got it up to 82%. So we're now really at world-class levels in terms of how we're servicing our consumer business, consumer franchise in Singapore.</p>
          <p>So I guess, I want to say that from a Singapore standpoint, I'm pleased with the progress we've made over the last couple of years, certainly the last year and we're seeing it in our numbers, we're seeing it in our drivers, we're seeing it in the service quality that we're being able to obtain. And I actually feel that we've really turned the Singapore business around quite substantially.</p>
          <p>The second thing we said that's important for us is to get the Hong Kong franchise to start paying off. And as it goes back to &#x2013; we have bought the franchise, we spent a lot of money on it, we're getting the juice out of the franchise.</p>
          <p>Sok Hui showed you this number. If you look at our operating income for the year, constant currency, right, it's up 18% year-on-year. Now, some of this is flattered. It's flattered, because the expenses this year were substantially lower than last year, because last year we had the constellation provisions we've made and so on.</p>
          <p>But even if you back out the expenses, our top line growth in Hong Kong is running at roughly 8% constant currency. Getting 8% top line growth in the Hong Kong business, again, in this environment with the funding issues and with the competition in Hong Kong is actually a great performance. And I would say, we're pleased with our ability to have been able to deliver that.</p>
          <p>If you remember, there are two things that we're focused on in Hong Kong from a strategic standpoint and then a couple of more we're doing really more tactically. The first strategic thing is to use Hong Kong to drive China and to drive the China business. And I'm not going to, because &#x2013; I'm not going to over-focus on this, because we mentioned this now for the last two, three quarters. But if you look at the progress we're continuing to make in the offshore renminbi space, it is very strong.</p>
          <p>We acquired over 2,700 customers booked in Hong Kong related to the offshore renminbi. We've got RMB7 billion in deposit growth. We got RMB22 billion in RMB loan growth, right, and that's very good.</p>
          <p>So, actually, we hit by the fourth-quarter situation, where our offshore renminbi LDR is now very healthy. Our NIMs in offshore renminbi, which were almost zero, because you're taking the money and putting it in PBOC. Those NIMs are up to 50, 60 basis points. So that offshore renminbi business, we not only have a good presence, but what we promised early that we think we'll be able to figure out and &#x2013; how to make money on this business, that's happening. So we're beginning to make decent money on the business through the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>One of the charts we put up there &#x2013; as you look at our treasury business in Hong Kong, so we put two, the treasury sales and the trading income in Hong Kong. The red part of it reflects that part of the business that has to do with renminbi and the non-red, peach or beige, whatever, reflects the business, which is to do with all the other currencies.</p>
          <p>And if you look at &#x2013; it's quite clear that the renminbi-related activity in Hong Kong in our treasury is now the majority part of our business, right. So 60/40 on the sales side; 40/60 on the trading side, but roughly half of our entire Hong Kong treasury business is now renminbi-related, right.</p>
          <p>I told this comes on the back of the fact that we have some 15% market share on the interbank. We have 10%, 12% market share on the flow business. That translates into this. It's becoming to be a meaningful part of our overall business and a big driver of our growth.</p>
          <p>We've also had good momentum in continuing to acquire state-owned and privately-owned customers in Hong Kong. This is apart from the ones we acquire in China, the customers we're acquiring in Hong Kong. So all together, we have really been able to refocus our Hong Kong franchise to really meaningfully leverage on the China activity and that's what we want to do, strategically. So that's beginning to pay off.</p>
          <p>Slide, please. The other piece we said, and we came to this conclusion only in the second half of the year &#x2013; of last year by the third quarter, is that we're really going to take the consumer business and make it an affluent wealth business, like all of our other countries. And so, we started doing that. We're going to reposition our branch network, that would take us a year, 18 months to do, but in the meantime, we're beginning to get the traction on investment and insurance sales income, right.</p>
          <p>So you can see the 30% growth in the income in Hong Kong that reflects the shift and reflects the effort we're putting to build up that wealth activity in Hong Kong. So that's the second strategic part of the agenda. The other two, as I said, are less strategic. We've said that in every market, if we find an opportunity to do consumer assets, we will, right, but it's not consistent across the board.</p>
          <p>In Hong Kong, we find unsecured loans portfolio as a great opportunity. We're now the number four player in that portfolio. So we're doing that and outpacing the industry's growth.</p>
          <p>And the other thing we've done in Hong Kong is never going to be a big business for us. What's important in the context of our overall corporate franchise is we've been able to revitalize our niche capital markets activity.</p>
          <p>And so, for example, Sing dollar bond issuances for Hong Kong's blue-chips in Singapore, we've done 10 trades in the last few months and we're clearly leading in this space. So we may be able to do that because we found that niche and we can exploit that niche.</p>
          <p>So all together, I'm quite pleased with where we are in Hong Kong. We have re-energized, we've re-strategized, we've refocused the business and the results are beginning to show in the operating income numbers. So it's a good thing.</p>
          <p>Outside of Hong Kong, we said, the other big thing is we really have to exploit the opportunities we have, principally India, China, Indonesia growth markets and Taiwan, because we have the opportunity to milk our Bowa acquisition, right.</p>
          <p>And the truth is that we've been able to do that. And if you look at our performance now, this is consistent and is tracking. This year, our businesses in these markets are up 38% on a declared basis. Actually, on a &#x2013; in the way I look at the business, which is management books, our total businesses outside of Singapore, Hong Kong, grew up to 22% this year, right. So it's a little different from Sok Hui's financial number of 19% and that's the way a business would look.</p>
          <p>But where customers lie and how we originate this thing, it's up to 22%. It's growing 3% a year. In financial terms, it grew 5%; in management terms, it grew 3%. And so if you look at this thing from a management standpoint, and I keep saying, if I manage to grow this 3% a year for the next two, three, four years, outside Singapore, Hong Kong, I can see us getting to 30%, right, of our total business. It's not bad.</p>
          <p>If you look at the Greater China piece, it's hit 29% last year, right. So a tad shy of 30% of our business is not coming from Greater China. So if you look at the growth we want to engineer from the growth market, and I'll say, that's coming in. That's kicking in nicely. The growth rates at a country level, which are all 30%, 40%, 50% growth rates, are quite dramatic, right. So I feel very good about that.</p>
          <p>If you look at the drivers, the drivers are all consistent. So this is not arbitrage. This is not opportunistic. This is underlying business, which is growing. Our loan books are growing, our deposit books are growing, our distribution networks are growing, our loan syndicated activities are growing and in every country, customers are growing and cross-sell is growing.</p>
          <p>So this is real genuine customer growth, customer business-driven growth in all of these markets and I'm pretty confident that as we look at the future, over the medium term, this is very sustainable for us. Our market shares are still very small and the small market shares, you have the capacity to grow, right. So we think we can continue doing this.</p>
          <p>Next, please. Wealth; so if you look at wealth, our total wealth income is now up to SGD620 million. If you remember, what Su Shan manages for us under the wealth piece, we consolidated our wealth continuum. So right from Treasures, Treasures Private Client and Private Bank, all three segments, we manage in one pot. So this number, if you ask me, is comparable to the number you would see from a Merrill or any of the classic private banks. It might not be comparable to the numbers you might see from an HSBC, who might not report the premium banking as part of wealth, right.</p>
          <p>So I manage the whole thing <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:31). But if you look at the wealth continuum, it's SGD620 million of total income, right. And so there's beginning to be &#x2013; it's still not 10% of the bank, it's still 8%, 9% of the bank. I told you before, my strategy is I want to get this to be 12% of the bank and see how we can. But directionally, we're getting there, because this business growth and this income growth are outpacing the rest of the bank and so we're headed in the right direction.</p>
          <p>If you look at our total earnings assets of SGD103 billion, those grew nicely 13% in the year. And we're getting momentum across all three segments. We have very strong momentum in the Private Bank. We launched &#x2013; by the Private Client segment, now six months ago, soft launch in this thing, we're getting very good early traction in that segment. We have almost 5,000 customers in this segment, partly internal switches and partly new customers. And we're getting very good strong traction in the lower end of the segment as well. So I'm quite pleased with the progress we are making overall in terms of the wealth space, right.</p>
          <p>GTS, it was the other one I wanted to reflect on. If you look at the quarter-by-quarter growth, I mean the numbers are quite evident, right, we had &#x2013; it was SGD165 million a quarter business, it's now a SGD320 million quarter business. That's almost doubled over the last couple of years. And the doubling is both on the trade side and the cash side. So if you look at this thing, both businesses have doubled, right.</p>
          <p>Cash, I told you, it's the principal driver of our deposits. So from SGD14 billion in deposits in the first quarter last year, we're now up to SGD45 billion in deposits. I mean that's dramatic and that's a big part of why you want to do the GTS cash business.</p>
          <p>The loans business affects mostly the growth in our trade &#x2013; in our trade finance activity. But both the underlying drivers of liabilities and assets are growing very strongly and showing up, therefore, in the income that we're generating and creating on the GTS side.</p>
          <p>Those are the key things I wanted to focus on. So assets are good, liquidity, we're demonstrating that we have the capacity to fund and liquidity will not be a constraint. And in terms of sticking to the knitting and focusing on our strategy, we are continuing to do that and we are seeing the results. We're seeing the results in Singapore, we're seeing the results in Hong Kong, we're seeing the results in our external market, we're seeing the results in wealth, we're seeing the results in GTS.</p>
          <p>I didn't talk about T&amp;M, because I've talked about it the last couple of times. Sok Hui showed you a slide, which showed that the customer activity in Treasury is now up 43%, 44% from mid-30s, which was in turn up from the mid-20s. So we have fundamentally changed what we're doing in the Treasury side of the business.</p>
          <p>So I'm going to stop there and leave with it. Clearly, this thing about trying to build an Asian-centric franchise for the new Asia, we think we're on track, we think the results demonstrate that we're on track and we think the outlook, as we look forward, is very positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much, Piyush. I'm a little bit mindful of time, because we are scheduled to have another media briefing with the Hong Kong media at 11:30. So please quickly ask your questions and we'll try and get as many of them through as possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> So if I can start (45:36), two questions. First is &#x2013; okay, sorry, I'm Kevin Lim from Reuters.</p>
          <p>First question, DBS has gained share in areas like trade financing. But how about other areas which the European banks are retreating from? Say ship financing, aircraft financing, even say real estate financing on a portfolio basis. Are these businesses you're interested in?</p>
          <p>Can you also reiterate what Sok Hui said about &#x2013; she said about projecting low double-digit loans growth. The low, does it mean like low 20% or like the first digit is one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> One and a one-one. (46:10).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, first digit. Sorry, can I just tuck in one last question? How about Iran? Because DBS has done some trade financing and business with Iranian firms. It's not against the UN sanctions, but with all the sanctions imposed by, say, the Europeans and the Americans, has that affected your business in any way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take all three.</p>
          <p>First of all, as a general rule, no. A large part of the businesses the French and European banks are exiting are not really exciting for us. I mean we have a shipping portfolio, we do some aircraft and so on. We have a big real estate portfolio. But as a general rule, what they exit from there does not give us customer leverage. For me, it's interesting to look and grow stuff, but I think I can get customer leverage.</p>
          <p>Also in the economic environment we're in, to do long-term, long-tenor ship financing and property financing is not a lot of fun.</p>
          <p>So the short answer is no. We are not particularly focused on those parts of the economic spectrum that the European banks are leaving. We are focused on the commodities and the trade piece, where they were big, and we are basically using the opportunity to grow that out.</p>
          <p>The second I told you, it's not a two-handle, it is a one- handle, so it's a low one- handle. I think the answer is quite simple. We grew 28% this year, right? And we grew 28% this year, our deposit book grew 16%. We already told you that in future, our loan growth will be more in line with the deposit growth.</p>
          <p>We could grow faster this year because our LDRs were low. Since the LDRs are low, we just could take out and push more loans. Now our LDRs are getting to the level where we don't have that much cushion anymore. So now our loan growth will be more in pace with our deposit growth.</p>
          <p>It also then added to the fact that I think overall Asia growth will be slower this year. I think Asia will be slow by at least 1 to 2 percentage points, and that will have an impact on loan demand. So I think you're talking about low double digits is &#x2013; with a single &#x2013; with a one-handle, not a two-handle, as a consequence.</p>
          <p>The third question, Iran.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Iran.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually I'm not even sure we have an Iranian business. To the best of my knowledge, we don't. So I'm not sure where you got that one from. And even <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:13) we have...</p>
          <p>So I guess, so issue with Iran is &#x2013; really Iran itself doesn't bother us. The issue with Iran is if you have a closure of the Hormuz Strait, and what impact that might have to do with oil price. So that's a general stress. And one of the things we have stressed is that, that if Strait of Hormuz closes, if oil spikes up to $200, what impact does that have on our business? And that impact is not specific to dealing with Iran. That has to do with any of our clients in any of our countries who are heavily energy reliant. And so it's obviously &#x2013; but that's a normal stress condition we have tested.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just want to ask you a question. In terms of clients who are dealing with Iran, I mean how is that affecting your business? Because there are clients who are Singapore clients, but they are dealing with Iran. So you don't directly deal with Iranian companies or Iranian entities, but you must be dealing with clients who are actually be &#x2013; who have dealt with Iran though. Because a lot of oil trade, commodity trade goes through Singapore?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not material.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:17) question? Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You already touched upon the tax rate part, so this quarter it's apparently 6.5%. And can you just tell us as to how you managed to achieve that? And whether it's going to be sustainable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I'm going to let Sok Hui answer that for only one reason. Because I don't want you to call me a birdwatching CEO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, typically the tax authorities finalized, right, previous years of assessment in the last quarter. So we actually had two additional years of assessment finalized with the tax authorities. And there's also a higher proportion of tax-exempt revenue, given that we actually sold some of our investment portfolio which are in SGS which are tax-exempt. So it's very straightforward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (50:03).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, 6.5% is not sustainable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think you should look at just the full-year kind of trends, because like I said, tax tends to be finalized in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So how much was the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (50:16)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the &#x2013; if you normalize for some of these effects, it will be quite similar to third quarter, which is about 15%. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But if you go back to that, as I made the point, right. So, yeah, we had a tax windfall, if you will, of this thing. But we, effectively the same time, bumped up our general provisions. Right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (50:40) you had a question. Okay, same question. Any other questions? <mark type="ph" /> Nishan (50:44)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Your quarter-four strong performance is not typical, because that's when things wind down. So are you saying you basically got market share from your competitors?</p>
          <p>And is the &#x2013; because I think a few weeks ago, you were talking about how you were not seeing a big slowdown in your customers' business. Can you give us an assessment again of how the slowing economy or the global environment is affecting businesses in Singapore?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So when I say it's not typical, because what happens is that on the treasury side of the business, both the customer flows as well as the trading activities, they're pretty much grind to a halt in December. So you really have only two-thirds of the time to make money. So typically a fourth quarter is always much slower because of that. It's an important part of our business, both the customer flows and trading.</p>
          <p>This year, what happened is we did see that, so that's <mark type="ph" /> kind of an issue (51:41). But our net interest income came in much stronger. So that allowed us to compensate for some of that stuff. And on the trading, well, trading was slow. Because of the interest rate environment, we were able to continue to harvest gains, right. And so we were able to balance that out.</p>
          <p>But the more important <mark type="indiscernible" /> (51:58) of your question, we continue to see fairly robust economic activity all around. And which is why I made a comment earlier this year that from everything I'm seeing, whether in Singapore or around the region, we are not seeing the train coming off the rails at all.</p>
          <p>So we're not seeing a hard landing. We're not seeing a 0% to 1% growth environment. Our customers are not showing that, customers' order books are still good. Our loan pipelines are still good. Economic activity is still good.</p>
          <p>And so, maybe it will slow down. I suspect that as an overall assessment, Asia will slow down. But we're not seeing any <mark type="ph" /> precipitate (52:36) slowdown in our underlying business. And in fact, we're hitting the beginning of this year, very strong momentum.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> Sam (52:44)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the issue of stabilizing NIMs that we're seeing, you said that some of the balance sheet work you're doing there. Could you just tell us a bit more about what you're doing there to stabilize NIMs? And given that we have seen them sort of plateau at the last few quarters?</p>
          <p>Second question is on U.S. dollar deposits. Sok Hui said that we're seeing some of those coming from MNCs. Can you just give us a bit of color about where you're sourcing a lot of this from, and which geographies and which sort of companies are doing it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I'm not sure I want to give you company names.</p>
          <p>But on the first thing, on the NIMs, the main thing we've been able to do is pricing. So we've been able to start pushing loan pricing. And particularly since dollar liquidity started tightening in Asia around the pace. So we've just been pushing loan pricing across the board.</p>
          <p>And so one of the biggest factors of getting NIM stabilization is we've been able to push loan pricing up, right. So that's been a significant help.</p>
          <p>The second is we've been able to continue to manage the cost of funding. So steady stuff that we do, depending on what you need, how much you have to pay for it.</p>
          <p>But our rating helps, and we can, therefore, continue to access <mark type="ph" /> market (53:58). I told you, in our CPs, we're raising at sub-LIBOR, for example. So you can continue to manage your cost of funding judiciously.</p>
          <p>One of the reasons that we said we would build the wholesale market activity is that &#x2013; our actual way to fund in the wholesale market is sometimes cheaper than to fund with customer deposits. So if you go to Hong Kong today, the customer depositing is war, and you just have to wind up paying 60, 70, 80 basis points over LIBOR. If I go into the CP market, I can fund at 10, 15 basis points under LIBOR, right? <mark type="ph" /> On this thing. (54:40)</p>
          <p>So we've been more smart on our funding, and how we do it, but the big push has been the ability to be able to push our loan pricing up, right.</p>
          <p>Now, the <mark type="ph" /> third view we have (54:36) in the fourth quarter is the pressures on SOR, which were there in the middle of the year and into a part of the third quarter, came off in the fourth quarter. And that's essentially because LIBOR, and SIBOR and SOR all corrected relatively in the fourth quarter, relatively, so that obviously helps us when that happens. So that's the other thing.</p>
          <p>I think I have reasonable comfort that we should be able to maintain and hold NIMs. I think it will still be somewhat volatile though. Because if a flood of money flows into Asia again this year, and it's not inconceivable that that will happen, then that will start putting pressure on Singapore rates again, right? But at the same time, we've been able to take pricing up and manage our deposit pricing, as well. So I think we should be able to be fine.</p>
          <p>In terms of the dollar deposits and the funding, the basic thing we were focused on &#x2013; I said two businesses, GTS and wealth, right. And both businesses were being helped. In the wealth space, apart from wealth in Asia increasing, there's a lot of wealth coming in from Europe and the Middle East into Asia. So that automatically helps us build a wealth <mark type="ph" /> this thing. (55:52)</p>
          <p>And on the GTS space, we've been very actively focused on working with western multinationals, both out of Europe and out of the U.S. Particularly American multinationals are very cash-rich. I mean Apple is sitting on $100 billion of cash. There's a $1.5 trillion sloshing around with U.S. multinationals.</p>
          <p>Frankly, even U.S. banks are very cash rich. U.S. banks are very, very liquid. Well, U.S. banks aren't putting the money to work because of capital constraints, not because of liquidity constraints. But there are large pools of dollar liquidity which are there.</p>
          <p>So we basically, as you know, we've got a couple of points. We've got a U.K. presence, and we've got a U.S. presence through our LA agency. And we re-geared both those outfits to focus on building out customer relationships, so it allowed us to go in as a cash management bank and as a deposit provider. That's paying off.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. <mark type="ph" /> Robin (56:27)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I ask you about the increasing compliance cost, regulatory burden that's coming out of the U.S. It's impacting banks everywhere, including in Singapore. I understand you've written into U.S. authorities to appeal on the Volcker Rule for an exemption. And also how &#x2013; what about in terms of FATCA? There was some kind of decision on that. Are you planning to be a participant as a foreign financial institution <mark type="indiscernible" /> (56:57)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's quite clear that if you had to go through all of the compliance activities that are coming out of the U.S., it would be very costly. It is actually quite prohibitive. And that is one of the main platforms that the entire international community is using to advocate with the U.S. authorities.</p>
          <p>And some of those provisions are clearly to my mind, extra-jurisdictional and extraterritorial. And they wind up with a huge cost impact on international financial institutions, which is not warranted relative to the impact we have on the U.S. economy or the size of our <mark type="ph" /> business in U.S. (57:29), it's completely disproportionate.</p>
          <p>So on FATCA, again, we <mark type="ph" /> grow a thing (57:32) &#x2013; we wrote in on FATCA with the ABS, as well as with &#x2013; actually, we got all of the associations in Southeast Asia to write in jointly. We've lobbied through various industry associations, IIIF, IMC.</p>
          <p>There has been some changes in the FATCA <mark type="ph" /> sir (57:47), which came in day before. Frankly, I've not had time to understand exactly what they mean and whether they've dramatically changed the landscape on FATCA. And maybe <mark type="ph" /> Ken (57:58) can answer.</p>
          <p>When I first &#x2013; what I saw in the paper seem to suggest that they've created a carve-out for European countries, but it didn't list Singapore in there. So I'm not sure whether they've done a very European-specific carve-out, but the rest of the world is still impacted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:13).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we've got to go through the details. And if it turns out that they have done something for the Europeans, but not for the rest of the world, then we're just going to have to make more noise and play it harder, right.</p>
          <p>Similarly on the Volcker Rule. In the Volcker Rule, in a nutshell had two fundamental issues that impact the whole world. One, for the U.S. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:33) as long as they are dealing in U.S. Treasury, you &#x2013; it's not yet counted as proprietary trading. But if you are dealing in any other government securities, then it's counted as proprietary trading, <mark type="ph" /> right (58:42). So for us to not deal in SGS or in Hong Kong dollar and Hong Kong, et cetera, is obviously a problem.</p>
          <p>But there's something, I mean, George Osborne wrote to Bernanke as well. And also people are all writing and saying this is illogical.</p>
          <p>The other is the cost of compliance from a reporting standpoint. This is fairly onerous reporting requirements from around the world into the U.S. Fed.</p>
          <p>So we are hopeful. Our conversations from various things suggest that the U.S. also realize that some of these effects are unintended consequences of what they're really trying to do. And so they're open to seeing what they need to do to eliminate these unintended consequences.</p>
          <p>So our base case is still that the US authorities will find the right <mark type="ph" /> come (59:19) and balanced response. So we don't have to incur all of the compliance costs that you are alluding to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Piyush. On that note, it's thank you so much for coming and look forward to seeing you in the next quarter then. Thank you very much, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>