<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1391359" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-04-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8657</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Chng Sok Hui, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Piyush Gupta, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Piyush Gupta</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Chng Sok Hui</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Good morning, everyone. I guess we see some empty seats here; probably some of those are still having a hangover from attending some of the GE rallies, yeah. Yeah. But thank you very much for coming for our Q1 results.</p>
          <p>We are happy to say that as you have seen this morning, we have a record set of results. We'll start off today's presentation with our CFO, Sok Hui, who will give us an overview of our of our Q1 financials. After that, Piyush, our CEO, will give a little bit more color and context into the results, the underlying drivers between our great set of results. And I also want you to know that we are joined over the phone, you can't see them, but they can hear you and you can hear them, by our CEO in Hong Kong, Sebastian Paredes; and Crystal Chow, who's our CFO in Hong Kong.</p>
          <p>Okay. So, without further adieu, Sok Hui, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. We achieved record earnings of SGD807 million in the first quarter, up 52% from a year ago and 19% from the previous quarter. The performance was underpinned by broad-based business growth, reflecting the momentum we are gaining in the implementation of our strategies.</p>
          <p>Total income reached a new high of SGD1.91 billion as we captured opportunities across the region. Sustained loan expansion and stable margins resulted in higher net interest income while stronger contributions from customer-related treasury sales, capital markets and wealth management boosted non-interest income.</p>
          <p>Overall, expenses were little changed from the previous quarter at SGD773 million. Profit before allowances rose 20% from the previous quarter to SGD1.14 billion. Allowances fell 20% from the previous quarter to SGD125 million. Half of the allowances this quarter were general provisions. Specific allowances fell from 25 basis points of loans in the previous quarter to nine basis points as the NPL rate improved further to 1.8%. ROE for this quarter is 12.1%, up from 10.2% for the previous quarter as well as full year 2010.</p>
          <p>Net interest income rose 1% from the previous quarter to SGD1.12 billion. A fewer number of days in the first quarter had an impact on net interest income, adjusting for this net interest income would have been 4% higher. Net interest margins was stable from the previous quarter at 1.80%. Further residual margin pressures due to the soft interest rate environment, our balance sheet management efforts helped to temper the pressure.</p>
          <p>Loans rose 4% from the previous quarter or SGD5.4 billion to SGD157.5 billion. In constant currency terms, it grew 5% or SGD7.0 billion. This brings loan growth from a year ago to 18% or to 22% in constant currency term. Loan growth was led by broad-base corporate borrowings in Singapore, Hong Kong, and other Asian markets in line with the regions continued economic expansion.</p>
          <p>Deposits rose 3% from the previous quarter or SGD5.8 billion to SGD199.5 billion. In constant currency terms, it increased 4% or 7.0 billion. Deposit growth over the past 12 months was 10% or to 13% in constant currency terms. Deposit growth this quarter was led by Singapore dollar savings accounts and Chinese yen fixed deposit. The Group's loan-to-deposit ratio was unchanged from the previous quarter at 79%.</p>
          <p>Fee income increased 16% from the previous quarter to SGD416 million, the growth was broad-based. Investment banking fees benefited from significant IPO activity during the quarter. Contributions from trade and remittances and wealth management grew as initiatives to expand these businesses gained momentum. Loan related income also registered strong growth.</p>
          <p>Trading income increased 57% from the previous quarter to SGD258 million, the increase was driven by 28% increase in income from customer flows. Customer flows also contributed to a larger proportion of total treasury interest and non-interest income than the previous year. Gain from the sale of investments, securities, and fixed assets were little changed from the previous quarter at SGD90 million.</p>
          <p>Overall, non-interest income increased 26% from the previous quarter to SGD787 million. As a percentage of total income, non-interest income rose to 41%, continuing the rising trend in the past three years.</p>
          <p>Expenses fell 1% from the previous quarter to SGD773 million. The cost-to-income ratio of 40% was similar to the quarterly average of 41% last year. We expect the cost-to-income ratio to rise moderately this year as the rollout of our strategic initiative continue. We will remain disciplined in our investment spending and ensure that it add value to the development of our regional franchise.</p>
          <p>This slide shows the performance for Hong Kong. It incorporates an appreciation of the Singapore dollar against the Hong Kong dollar of 3% from the previous quarter and 10% from a year ago. Hong Kong's earnings rose 32% from the previous quarter and 6% from a year ago to 190 million. In Hong Kong dollar terms, earnings showed a stronger increase of 34% from the previous quarter and 16% from a year ago.</p>
          <p>Net interest income was no change from the previous quarter at 190 million. Net interest margin fell slightly by one basis point to 1.48%. Loans grew 2% in local currency terms driven by corporate and SMEs. Reflecting industry trends deposit volumes were slightly lower.</p>
          <p>Non-interest income rose 27% from the previous quarter to 200 million, boosted by higher contributions from treasury cross-selling as well as better trading gains. Expenses fell 12% from the previous quarter to 155 million due to lower computerization and advertising costs. Allowances declined 44% from the previous quarter to 9 million as the NPL rate improved 20.9% from 1.0%.</p>
          <p>ROA for this quarter is 1.33%, up from 1.01% in the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Asset quality continue to improve. Non-performing assets fell 4% to 3.1 billion as new NPL formation declined. The NPL rate improved from 1.9% in the previous quarter to 1.8%. Allowance coverage rose to 103%, if collateral was included; it would amount to 134%.</p>
          <p>Our capital position remains strong with Core Tier 1 at 11.5%, Tier 1 at 14.2 and total cost at 17.2%. During the fourth quarter of 2010, we had raised 2.5 billion of preference shares to replace 2.1 billion of existing preference shares due to recall in the first of half of 2011. During the first quarter of 2011, we redeemed 1 billion, and we'll be redeeming the other 1.1 billion in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>The results have given us a strong start to the year. The performance has been underpinned by broad-base growth and reflects the momentum we have built up in implementing the strategy announced last year. We're well-positioned to continue capturing opportunities by serving new and existing customers as we expand our franchise across the region. Our balance sheet is strong, we have ample capital and liquidity, and our asset quality is healthy. So, remain focus on execution to create value for both our customers and our shareholders. Thank you.</p>
          <p>I'll now pass it back to Piyush.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I guess it's safe to stay that we're very pleased with these quarter's results. We obviously had a call for us at DBF, but as best as we can tell that probably a record for our industry in Singapore on a quarter earnings basis, which is great. Yesterday, at our AGM chairman asked investors to be patient, I'm glad we haven't had to try the patience for very long. I think the results have been pretty decent.</p>
          <p>I want to just give some color to some of the results, might be helpful. First, you think about our total income, the SGD1.9 billion income numbers are extremely good, underlying it however what is even more exciting is that it reflects the execution of our strategy on almost every income line.</p>
          <p>Our interest income grew nicely. As Sok Hui pointed out, if you adjust for number of days, the two-days short in this quarter, and if you adjust for translation losses, actual interest income grew quite strongly. And it was driven by both loan growth, to our underline loan growth of about 7 billion, 5 billion-ish after translation and even more important by stabilizing interest margins. The interest margins stabilization reflects a strategic thrust. The margins continue to be under pressure in both Singapore and Hong Kong.</p>
          <p>In Hong Kong particularly, deposit rates continue to be high. There is a pressure on the loan of margins, Singapore as well rates have been all-time low. So, our ability to hold margin reflects really two things. One, we have been pushing out and growing our business in the other countries, and part of this margin stabilizing reflects our growth in China and India, where we've been benefited from the upturn in the interest rate cycle.</p>
          <p>What that tells you though is that the proportionate share of the other market in our total loan mix is beginning to be material, so it can actually have impact in our total group margins.</p>
          <p>The other thing behind our interest margin is obviously the balance sheet management activities that we have been undertaking over the last several quarters, including managing our duration longer. That's beginning to kick in, as well. And as a consequence, being able to hold very nicely, grow NIM by a business point. In the face of the issues in Hong Kong and Singapore is something that we're very pleased about. It's the result of very specific focused actions that are showing impact.</p>
          <p>On the other income lines, our fee income as Sok Hui again pointed out was strong and it wasn't one category of fee income. Investment banking was very strong. There were some unusual large transaction in place, loan fees is very strong, but the other fees, wealth management, and I think I have a slide on that later, but we're very encouraged by the growth in our wealth management franchise and the fee income growth that's being reflected.</p>
          <p>Our transaction banking fee, same things. Its annuity fee, but coming in and growing very nicely, very strongly as well. Trade remittances, everything is up. So, very broad-based fee income growth, which reflects again focused in several areas that we've been pushing over the last year and half.</p>
          <p>Finally, in terms of the trading income, once again I'm actually very pleased by the fact that the customer related T&amp;M income continuous to increase rapidly. As you know, last year, our customer related income grew 48% from the year before. And I had made a comment at the end of the year that I thought there was still a lot more headroom in this category because we really think that there's a lot more opportunity for us to take our T&amp;M products into our customer base. So, this quarter continued to reflect that gain. Some very sweet and sizeable gains, partly the offshore <mark type="ph" /> revenue (13:48) we trade helps. We continue to lead in that. I have a slide on that later, but that reflection that income line as well.</p>
          <p>So, I guess the quality of the top line has been extremely robust, driven by multiple engines firing and multiple engines firing linked to our strategic intent. I must admit, it's unusual for all engines to fire at the same time and therefore, I would caution against extrapolating by multiplying our first quarter income by four, it is unlikely that everything will fire at the same time. At the same time, the truth is the underlying momentum is very good.</p>
          <p>The other thing, which is good our cost-to-income ratio. It again as flagged early last year. They've been expected to see our cost income ratios strength to 45. That hasn't happened, and in part it hasn't happened because the income line has started kicking in much earlier than I anticipated. And therefore, as we are now, our cost income will still continue to head up. But I now have a sense that we're unlikely to get to the 45 range that I had originally anticipated, so I think there might be some question for that.</p>
          <p>We continue to be benefited by the credit cycle. There is something, which we have been calling for several quarters; it's beginning to show up consistently in our numbers at this stage. Again, as we look around at the immediate future, we don't see any prospects of any uncertainty, so this looks like a pretty robust line at this point in time. And I guess when you put all of that together you wind up with an ROE of north of 12%. We haven't had that kind of ROE in several years now, four or five years, so that's something, which is extremely pleasing, that we can at least for the quarter deliver a return, which is lower our hurdle rates and our cost of capital.</p>
          <p>I do want to take you to our nine priorities. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (15:38) slide, please. So, this is just to recap the all nine. I'm not going to talk about all nine; I'm going to talk about the five that we've highlighted because there is, I guess, a significant integration impact on those five outside. If we look at Singapore, the percent is on the top of our list. The good news is it continues to gain market share in Singapore, it's driven by business lending, underlying actually our market share in the consumer side after several quarters of gain actually slacked off in the first quarter, particularly in the mortgage side of the business with the government impact actions in January. Those actions, as I've indicated before, tend to impact our customer base a little bit more than the market because we tend to be slightly lower income customer based.</p>
          <p>So, but the business loan volume is going really strongly and so net-net our market share in Singapore dollar loan continues to go. As you know, that's very more important to us, so that we can reduce the interest rate vulnerability from our Sing dollar book. So, I'm quite pleased.</p>
          <p>Some months ago, I think September, October, I had indicated to you that one of the things we're trying to do in Singapore is see how we can take our distribution of branches and convert them into a source of strength as sales distribution channel. For several years, we've treated them as distribution from a service standpoint, not from a sales standpoint. So, four months ago, we launched a pilot in 12 branches, where we tried to create these branches and convert them into an owner-entrepreneur model. So, branch manager owned the customer base &#x2013; I won't go to detail, we spoke about that.</p>
          <p>Our early results on those pilots are very encouraging. In those 12 branches, as you can see from the chart, the productivity at the salesperson level is showing significant lift compared to our control branches. The control branches are also up in this because our overall business is doing well enough, but control branches have been up by 12%, 16%, our test branches are up by 40% to 50%. And that gives us a tremendous degree of confidence that the model we are trying to adopt to build out on our distribution platform in Singapore is robust.</p>
          <p>In the course of this year, we will be expanding the pilot progressively and expanding to other branches both in Singapore and around the region, but there's something that's of great comfort to us.</p>
          <p>The other thing in these branches, we've also started making the other piece work, which is engaging with our SME customers. And again, our results in this, had in those last three, four months pilot have been encouraging, so we're able to leverage the branches, branches to start doing a lot more SME community banking around the branch footprint. So, both good pieces of news.</p>
          <p>The other thing in Singapore, which is worth noting on, we &#x2013; commenting on, we launched the offshore RMB products in Singapore two or three months ago, and frankly to my own surprise, they have just gone gang busted. It has been incredible the pace of RMB adoption in Singapore. Our Singapore, our RMB option deposit in Singapore as of mid-April are now about 13 billion. In Hong Kong, we're about 18. In Hong Kong we started doing this in June, July last year, in Singapore we started two months ago.</p>
          <p>So, the amount of take up of this, and it's not just the revenue deposits, we sold somewhere around $4.5 billion, worth in dollars, worth of RMB related offshore products in two months, which is deposit products, CLI linked product, investment linked product. So, it has been extremely encouraging. Also, our asset category trade settlements related to the RMB offshore, which we booked in Singapore over this period of time have also been extremely strong. So, offshore RMB and Singapore's role as another potential center for offshore RMB is actually beginning to be quite encouraging from a Singapore standpoint. Slide, please.</p>
          <p>In Hong Kong, which is other priority taking, Sok Hui talked to you about the results, the results have been quite good. But underlying that I guess two or three pieces of focal area, the focus; one as I said, we wanted to improve our position in the last corporate space; especially the Chinese company is coming into Hong Kong. Well, that's working extremely well. Our position with both the state-owned enterprises, privately-owned enterprises, they're making good inroad.</p>
          <p>We've been &#x2013; begun to do a lot of RMB bond issuances in Hong Kong, Road King Infrastructure was one we did, we have several more in the pipeline. We were able to participate in some other large capital markets trade including the Hutch trade. So, the last quarter corporate position is improving.</p>
          <p>We're gaining traction in consumer banking, particularly on the consumer finance side, and on the wealth side.</p>
          <p>On the consumer finance, consumer finance assets grew very strongly. Our market share on the unsecured space has gone up. We think we're now up to rank number four, we moved in rank as well. So, that's very good.</p>
          <p>On the wealth side, bank assurance premium is up; wealth commissions are up, so that we need to get good traction as well.</p>
          <p>And finally, again, back to the offshore RMB story, the Hong Kong position in offshore RMB continues to be very strong. We are doing a whole range of different things. I told you our deposits are up to 18 billion. We acquired over 750 corporate customers in the first quarter on the back of this RMB trade. We've been bookrunners for several RMB bonds, Singamas was another one. We launched the first RMB life insurance plan in this period of time. And so the RMB, our market share in RMB interbank continues to be around 20%. On market share &#x2013; the customer flows are still &#x2013; still got 10%. So, by and enlarge, our RMB business and activity in Hong Kong also continues to be very robust. Slide?</p>
          <p>I think this is the third piece of our thing, which is the geographic mix of our business. Our organic efforts in all of our markets outside Singapore, Hong Kong are continuing to also bear a lot of fruit. India, Taiwan, China, Indonesia every one of our markets in the quarter grew nicely. Our year-on-year growth in each of these markets is very strong. As you can see, these growth rates are substantially higher than our growth rates in Singapore and Hong Kong. And as this continue, project these out, they have begin to get to a stage, where these countries are a meaningful part of our business mix.</p>
          <p>In absolute terms, our countries out of Singapore, Hong Kong did about 100 million in the first quarter of last year in terms of net profit, that's up to about 175 million now. That's beginning to make a meaningful impact in our total number. I already pointed out, that the impact of these countries on our NIM numbers is also beginning to be material.</p>
          <p>By country, Taiwan was the strongest quarter ever. We had very strong cross-sell momentum in treasury products, in syndications. Our non-interest income in Taiwan actually grew up over a 100%. And in this quarter we actually also relocated our Taiwan business into a new headquarters. So, in our completely new premises, we had a back office last year. We're now putting new front office headquarters.</p>
          <p>In China, we continue to make progress. We opened three branches in this quarter. We're tracking to try and get to 50 branches in three years, this means you go to do somewhere around eight or 10 branches a year. So, we did three in the quarter. We're well on track to doing the eight or 10 that we expect to grow out in China this year.</p>
          <p>Our business was strong. There's very strong cross-sell momentum in Beijing markets in GTS. Our fees almost doubled in this quarter, actually.</p>
          <p>Our integration of the Royal Bank of Scotland business is on track. We've already shifted over somewhere around 3,500 customers. We've actually made offers to about a 150 employees. We moved about 300 or $1 million in deposits, so it's working consistent with our original business plan projection. So, that's a good story.</p>
          <p>In India, our customer franchise continues to grow. Our local currency assets grew 34% quarter-on-quarter in India, which is extremely good. We launched our debt capital market business in India. We launched &#x2013; completed two deals.</p>
          <p>We're quite pleased with this award we won. We won the cash payment award again, but we were awarded &#x2013; I think, the business standard, "The Best Foreign Bank in India," a couple of weeks ago, which we thought was extremely encouraging because this wasn't in any small bank category. This was across the board and the face of several foreign bank competitors, who've been in India for over 100 years. So, we're obviously beginning to make an impact in that market.</p>
          <p>And in Indonesia, we're beginning to gain traction. Our consumer banking business was getting traction, of course, BI is a &#x2013; the rules yesterday or a day before, putting a freeze on all wealth management acquisition activities for a month. It will sort of slowdown momentum for this quarter, but that's I think an aberration, just in a long-term sense, the business is doing well in Indonesia too.</p>
          <p>Moving on, the other thing, wealth management, as you know, we focused a lot on wealth. We have integrated our high-end wealth premium offering and a private bank offering all under &#x2013; the single distinct between Su Shan, <mark type="ph" /> Per Lim, Si Bo (25:02), we got a very strong team and that's beginning to show up our year-on-year growth rate are very impressive for the overall wealth segment. Our income is up 16%. Non-interest income is up 35%, which means even though interest rate is having a drag; margins having a drag; the fee income is kind of kicking in very nicely. And that's true both on the private bank side and on the treasury side.</p>
          <p>On Private bank, we just launched a series of new offerings including alternative investments, family offers, philanthropy, advisory services, cornerstore, investment banking kind of activities and the growth rate of revenue is quarter-on-quarter, therefore, is beginning to be very encouraging.</p>
          <p>Last week, we did a soft launch of a new upper end segment we called Treasures Private Client. So, we're going to have two segments at the top end, the private bank segment and the private client segment. And on the back of this launch, we will probably be &#x2013; take a more formal launch approach in the year, but I think that will give us continue momentum and much more growth in the wealth business. So, we feel quite good about where we are on this one.</p>
          <p>And the last one on GTS and T&amp;M, there's &#x2013; the other part you have &#x2013; if you look at GTS, the first time we actually put it out, GTS numbers, but if you look at our GTS numbers year-on-year, they grew from about SGD179 million to SGD222 million and that reflects both cash and trade. It reflects an increase in both deposits and asset volume. And because GTS is A, annuity income that's very good. And B, this is also in an environment, where it's facing head-winds from interstate. So, if you look forward and expect the increase in interstate at some point in time, this franchise will become even more valuable to us.</p>
          <p>So, the good thing about the GTS business is the last part of the business also is international. It's outside of Singapore, Hong Kong, so 37% of the total income is really coming from outside of Singapore, Hong Kong and that speaks to what we're trying to do, make sure that our overseas international businesses are deep-rooted, and we feel good about that.</p>
          <p>On T&amp;M, again, I spoke about this before, but we continue to see very strong growth in treasury customer sales. We are up another 28% quarter-on-quarter, and up almost 79% year-on-year. Again, if you look at the bottom part of the slide, the good news is so far most of that momentum has been coming from the corporate side, institutional side. We've began to see momentum now in the consumer side, as the wealth management offerings pick up, but what that say is that we still have more dues in terms of what more we can do to push treasury product and treasury business activities into our customer base.</p>
          <p>So, again, in summary, we're very pleased. We just have had a strong set of results across every top line, expense line, credit line, couldn't have had asked for a better set of results, frankly, if I had written the script myself.</p>
          <p>Before I end, I just do what I'm going to do, my standard quarterly disclaimer. So, before you people have to ask; no, we're not in conversation with anybody on any inorganic deal. We have no &#x2013; no acquisition is imminent <mark type="indiscernible" /> (28:11) Indonesia or anywhere else. So, just to set your mind that &#x2013; so, I'm happy to take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, Piyush. Yeah. On that note, we can, I guess, focus the questions on our great results. So, can you please identify yourself and where you're from, and I see Reuters has already put out a story on our cost income ratio by the way, yeah. <mark type="ph" /> Saeed (28:33), yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to ask on this net interest margin. Do you think that the low interest we have seen &#x2013; we see the bottom now for these interest margins or further erosion in interest margins are unlikely for the rest of the year? I mean obviously recovery will take time for the U.S. trade and everything, but do you think you'd hit the bottom for that, number one?</p>
          <p>The second thing is you mentioned that the Bank Indonesia has basically halted new <mark type="ph" /> acquisition (29:04) of private banking business in Indonesia. Isn't that only applicable to city or is this across the board?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the first question, yeah. I think we are about at the end of the NIM compression cycle. I think there are still headwinds like I said in both Hong Kong and Singapore. The SIBOR is still at the low end. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:27) continues to bounce around, it actually came off very sharply before the recent that I don't think that's going to go away.</p>
          <p>In Hong Kong, in addition to the U.S. dollar impact, there's also the impact of the Chinese banks borrowing and the deposit impacts in Hong Kong, and I don't think that's going to go away.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, I do believe that the compensations that we are getting from our other country franchises and from our balance sheet management activities will continue to help us take care of the continued pressure and this thing in Singapore, Hong Kong. So, directionally, I think you saw our &#x2013; NIM was beginning to level off even at the end of last year, and was down to 179. This time, it's up a bit two points. So, I think <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:08) pretty consistent now.</p>
          <p>On the Indonesia thing, actually what Bank Indonesia did yesterday is an industry wide exercise. So, they asked all banks to stop acquiring any premium or high value customers for the next month, and they've asked all banks to review their entire customer acquisition processes and strategy <mark type="ph" /> and order (30:28) profits, and once they've given everybody a clean bill of health, they'll sort of reopen the figures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think, <mark type="ph" /> Saeed, (30:35) I think about 23 banks would be covered by Bank Indonesia's, if you will, mandate, and one month period starts on 2nd of May, yeah, and they call it a cooling of period, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question, please. Sam?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sam from Dow Jones. If you could just talk a little bit more about the NIM again, have you been &#x2013; could you &#x2013; are you expecting to diversify more your geographic spreads of your mortgage business is this part of us seeing stabilization in your NIM <mark type="indiscernible" /> (31:15)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Geographic spread of the mortgage business means?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, just sorry, the way your mortgage business is distributed between Singapore and the rest of Asia...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Singapore and others, no. No, our mortgage business is predominantly a Singapore, Hong Kong business ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And while we have a small mortgage book in China and in Taiwan, the mortgage component of our activities, outlook of our principal market is very small. So, our growth and our growth in our loan book outside of Singapore, Hong-Kong is impressive, but it's mostly business. It's on the institutional side, not on the consumer mortgage side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Piyush mentioned earlier that you had benefited &#x2013; the NIM had benefited from contribution from India and China. Just more on the context of rising interest rates and our book was actually well-positioned to benefit from that NIM increase in China and India, which in turn has now made an impact at the group level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Sok Hui. Next question? Conrad?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm just wondering &#x2013; in terms of the Singapore loan book, what's the demand like after the measures that were announced in January by the government.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is actually kind of pretty similar to what we saw in August last, when they did the measure. Loan demand came off pretty sharply for the first couple of months, and then picked up. It didn't pick up all the way to the pre-August level. And the same thing at that time, it's a little more challenging for us because loan demand picked up at the top end of the market more than it picked up at the lower end of the market.</p>
          <p>So, post the January actions, we've seen pretty much the same thing. Loan demand came off very sharply in February and March, is beginning to recover somewhat in the last month. But, again, recovering more strongly at the higher end of the market than at the lower ends of market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Joyce?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Joyce from Bloomberg. In your statement, you said the global economy remains fraught with uncertainty, what kind of uncertainties do you see going ahead? And just to clarify on the SIBOR, how do you see that moving this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the uncertainty is around the global economy are consistent with what there have been over several quarters. You have the situation, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:40) situation. The U.S. situation, where Bernanke's statement over the last couple of days continues to put in a long period to recovery, which means that interest rates are likely to stay low for an extended period of time. I was originally anticipating some interest rate pickup in this year, towards the tail end of this year. And now, it looks pretty clear that that's unlikely to happen till right into first quarter of next year, at least that's what the markets are pricing it. And so, clearly, the U.S. demand side remains sluggish.</p>
          <p>The first quarter GDP numbers came in lower than expected; and frankly, it's sort of difficult to unravel, but it does seem that business demand, investment demand, government demand, everything was off, everything was low. So, I worry. Exactly this time last year, all of this scare and worry about a double dip got triggered off by a low first quarter GDP number. So, bottom line, I don't think the U.S. economy is out of the woods, and so that's one set of concern.</p>
          <p>I think the European debt situation continues to be very, very uncertain, right. So, whether, obviously, the issue is around Greece and Portugal, but Spain as well is not entirely clear. And therefore, how much Germany comes to bailout everybody else, is there a restructuring, which might happen in the offering, how do they deal with the total situation, it is still quite unclear. Implications of that on the global economy could be substantial.</p>
          <p>And finally in Asia, we continue to be &#x2013; to struggle with this conundrum of overheated economies and inflation; and therefore, all of us, central banks, by and large, are scurrying to tighten monetary policy in one way, shape or form, are either through interest rate policy, extended rate policy or frankly, micro-prudential regulatory policy. The impact of that is always uncertain.</p>
          <p>The biggest risk we face is if in their balancing of trying to cool off the economies they overreach and so you wind up with a hard landing, and if you have a hard landing, particularly in China that will have pretty serious implications in all of the rest of Asia. All of these things are not different from where they've been over the last couple of quarters, but I guess my point was that there is no clarity around any of these yet; it still seems to be as uncertain as it was over the last quarter or two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Piyush.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (36:19).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. By and large, SIBOR rates have been low and trending. The <mark type="ph" /> SAR was in more of the thing (36:27) really came off very sharply before the <mark type="ph" /> resetting, after resetting (36:29) it sort of corrected up little bit. But I don't see SIBOR moving up in a hurry. Our view is SIBOR always tracks the U.S. dollar. And by and large, SIBOR trails the U.S. dollar by a quarter or two, three, four months. So, until dollar rates start moving up, it's unlikely to &#x2013; that you see SIBOR moving up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is a good time, I guess, with not many questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, just what &#x2013; in light of what you said about the global economy, what &#x2013; how does this affect your view on what lending growth will be like this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our loan growth is always up 4% for the quarter, 3%, 4%, so it's tracking to what I said in the beginning of &#x2013; end of last year, that we're looking to see a plus, minus low double digit growth rate for the year. And I think we should be able to track to that.</p>
          <p>Interestingly, loan demand does not correlate one-to-one with GDP. And that's for a couple of reasons, for last year, for example, a large amount of the loans that were &#x2013; are taken up last in the corporate side, were really refinancing. They weren't new capacity formation. Through the late part of last year and early part of this year, we're beginning to see capacity creation. So, sometimes the capacity creations are &#x2013; tail the GDP growth. And so, I have seen a very strong loan pipeline on the traditional corporate side as we look ahead.</p>
          <p>On the consumer retail side, it's really mortgages, which around the region are slowing off, as every central bank is really focused on trying to slow down mortgage loan growth. And so, that continues to be uphill across the place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (38:22), I was looking at your investment banking fee, it was up from a year ago, in fact, a year ago about 100%. And obviously, first quarter, we saw the Hutchison IPO. Do you see sort of that momentum slowing down in the rest of the year, given what's happening in Japan and sort of the &#x2013; or do you see the deal pipeline fairly decent for the rest of the year, I mean just give us some color on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I guess there's two ways to answer. First of all, from our standpoint, our market shares in investment banking have never been huge, and therefore, for us as long as we can get a reasonable deal pipeline &#x2013; so, our own fortunes don't necessarily pack the macro-market and from our standpoint, we're seeing a decent deal pipeline, right and because we are focused in the mid-caps space. I told you on the renminbi bond offshore issuances in Hong Kong, for example, we've done a couple of trades this year. We see a robust pipeline of doing that, so we have a decent deal pipeline. Now, all of them are not going to be Hutchinson type $6 billion issuances. So, but yeah &#x2013; this is not bad.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (39:30).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nothing that we see eminent. I mean we are &#x2013; we have a small role in the Glencore trade, which is obviously a huge IPO. It's $11 billion, $12 billion IPO which is coming up, but we are only a <mark type="indiscernible" /> (39:48)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (39:50).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (40:02).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I doubt it, not in the near future and this &#x2013; that would be wrong. I haven't thought about it, but unlikely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Any last questions before we wrap it up today? All right. On that note then, yeah, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you. Thank you all for coming today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>