<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1453172" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-11-02</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8657</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Strategic Marketing &amp; Communications">Karen Ngui</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer">Piyush Gupta</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Sok Hui Chng</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Treasury and Markets and Group Executive">Andrew Ng</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Thank you for coming to our Third Quarter Results Briefing. It's a Wednesday; I have to remind ourselves that it's a Wednesday because traditionally we've sort of been issuing our results on a Friday. So, we're quite happy with our results and I guess we wish it were a Friday then we would have the weekend the next few days ahead, yeah. But anyway, long weekend. So, maybe, Piyush saw the subtle message here, yeah.</p>
          <p>[Laughter]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>[Laughter] Don't look at me, but Andrew might do it for you, he might give the word [indiscernible] (0:34)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, we will start off this morning with Sok Hui, our CFO, who will share with us &#x2013; give us more details about our third quarter results, and how we've done year-to-date for the full first nine months. after which Piyush will give more color into some of the things that we've been doing to mitigate a somewhat tumultuous quarter, if you will, and yet still produce a pretty good set of results.</p>
          <p>So without further ado, Sok Hui, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. We achieved record earnings of SGD2.30 billion in the first nine months, up 17% from a year ago. Total income reached a record SGD5.72 billion, driven by growth in business volumes and customer flows. Net interest income reached a new high of SGD3.54 billion. Loans grew 26% from a year while deposits rose 19%.</p>
          <p>The higher loan and deposit volumes were partially offset by a decline in net interest margins from 1.86% a year ago to 1.78%. Non-interest income rose 3% to SGD2.18 billion, also a record, as higher customer income was offset by lower market-related income. Fee income rose 15% to SGD1.20 billion from higher contributions in trade and remittances, wealth management, loan activities and investment banking.</p>
          <p>Trading income fell 25% to SGD547 million, as lower trading gains more than offset a 31% increase in income from cross-selling treasury products. Other non-interest income rose 22%. Expenses were higher at SGD2.42 billion, as investment in people and infrastructure will make for business growth. The cost to income ratio was at 42%.</p>
          <p>Total allowances fell 35% to SGD493 million. Specific allowances for loans declined 80% to SGD102 million, as asset quality improved, while general allowances rose 85% to SGD347 million. ROE for the first nine months reached 11.3%, above the 10.2% recorded a year ago.</p>
          <p>For the third quarter, we earned SGD762 million, up 6% from a year ago and 4% from the previous quarter. Customer income trends were sustained as total income reached a quarterly high of SGD1.97 billion. Net interest income increased 1% from the previous quarter to SGD1.21 billion. Loans grew 10% from regional corporate borrowings, half of which were for trade finance. Excluding currency translation effects loan growth was 7%.</p>
          <p>The impact of loan growth was partially offset by lower interest margins, which fell 7 basis points to 1.73%. Fee income was also higher, rising 3% from the previous quarter to SGD397 million. Trading income was similar to the previous quarter at SGD143 million, after 15% increase in customer flow income was offset by lower trading gain.</p>
          <p>Other non-interest income doubled to SGD240 million helped by gains of SGD47 million from the sale of investment securities and the transaction to combine DBS Asset Management and Nikko Asset Management. Expenses rose 6% from the previous quarter to SGD847 million, leaving the cost to income ratio unchanged at 43%.</p>
          <p>Total allowances of SGD231 million was 69% higher than the previous quarter, as general allowances was substantially increased by 89% to SGD187 million. Specific allowances for loans remain low at SGD41 million as asset quality continue to be healthy.</p>
          <p>Net interest income. Net interest income reached a record SGD1.2 billion, up 1% from the previous quarter and 13% from a year ago. Continued loan and deposit growth was partially offset by lower interest margins. Interest margins fell 7 basis points to 1.73%, interest rates in Singapore further softened during the quarter, reducing asset yield.</p>
          <p>In Hong Kong, margins were affected as deposit costs where re-priced faster than loan use. We also grew deposit faster than loans in Hong Kong during the quarter. While interest margins &#x2013; headwinds remain, there are a few mitigating factors. Credit spreads are improving, which will increase loan use over time. Swap offer rates in Singapore have also recovered from the lows in August. In addition deposit rates in Singapore were adjusted in October. These factors will help to limit further pressure on interest margins going forward.</p>
          <p>Loans rose 10% to &#x2013; or SGD17 billion from the previous quarter to SGD186 billion, bringing loan growth for the past 12 months to 26% or SGD38 billion.</p>
          <p>Excluding currency translation effect, loans rose 7% during the quarter. Loan growth during the past year was led by regional corporate borrowing of which half was for trade finance. Deposits grew 4% or SGD9 billion during the quarter to SGD220 billion bringing deposit growth for the 12 months to 19% or SGD35 billion. Our Singapore dollar LDR has been rising and is now at 62%, in line with our strategy to deploy more of our Sing dollar liquidity to Sing dollar loans.</p>
          <p>This still leaves us with a considerable amount of additional Sing dollar deposits, which we use as a supplement to foreign currency deposits for funding foreign currency loan. In addition, we regularly tap on other sources of foreign currency funding such as negotiable certificates of deposit, commercial paper, medium-term notes and sub debt. This gives us a range of options to raise funds for foreign currency loans in the most cost effective way. Combining Sing dollars and foreign currencies, our overall loan-to-deposit ratio rose to 84% during the quarter. We expect to grow loans in greater tandem with deposits over the next few quarters.</p>
          <p>Fee income increased 3% from the previous quarter and 17% from a year ago to SGD397 million. Several activities delivered higher contributions compared to a year ago. Trade and remittances fees were up 47%, while wealth management fees rose 35%. Loan activities were also higher. Fee income for each of the first three quarters of 2011 were higher than all of the four quarters of 2010 as initiatives to improve fee income delivered results. Other non-interest income rose to SGD357 million.</p>
          <p>While trading income was little changed, gains from sale of investment securities rose 85% to SGD152 million. There was also a SGD47 million from the transaction to combine DBS Asset Management and the Nikko Asset Management.</p>
          <p>Total treasury income was SGD1.5 billion for nine months 2011, little change from nine months 2010. Customer income for treasury products, however, rose 31% during the first nine months to SGD672 million as we improved cross-selling of interest rate, foreign exchange and other treasury products to corporate and retail customers. For the third quarter, customer income was 15% higher than the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>The increase in customer income offset the decline in other treasury income, which fell 21% to SGD843 million in the first nine months. Customer income accounted for 44% of total interest and non-interest treasury income, up 32% a year ago.</p>
          <p>Expenses rose 17% from a year ago, and 6% from the previous quarter to SGD847 million. The cost to income ratio was unchanged from the previous quarter at 43%. For the first nine months, the cost to income ratio was 42%, slightly above the previous year's 40% and in line with guidance as we invested in staff and infrastructure for higher business volumes and future growth.</p>
          <p>Hong Kong. Hong Kong reported nine months earnings of SGD441 million. In constant currency terms, they were 12% higher than a year ago, as higher income and lower costs were partially offset by the increase in general allowances.</p>
          <p>Net interest income rose 80% in constant currency terms to SGD578 million. Loans expanded 23% from a year ago driven by domestic and cross-border trade loan. Deposits rose 11%, the increase in loans and deposits volume was partially offset by 28 basis points decline in interest margins to 1.40% from deposit price competition. Non-interest income rose 9% in constant currency terms to SGD513 million. The increase was led by customer flow in terms for treasury products and trading gains.</p>
          <p>Fee income from trade and remittances, and wealth management were also higher. Expenses of SGD462 million were 5% lower in constant currency terms, but would be higher after adjusting for compensation to Constellation customers last year.</p>
          <p>Profit before allowances improved 22% in constant currency terms to SGD629 million. The increase in allowances to SGD106 million was due to general allowances. Specific allowances remained low as asset quality remained healthy. The NPL rate was 0.8%, compared to 1.0% a year ago.</p>
          <p>For the third quarter, Hong Kong recorded net profit of SGD108 million, a 23% decline from the previous quarter in constant currency terms. Net interest income fell 5% from the previous quarter to SGD189 million from higher deposit costs. Loans grew 7% led by trade loans, deposit increased 9%. The faster re-pricing of deposit costs and loan yields, as well as the faster growth in deposits resulted in a 27 basis points decline in net interest margin from the previous quarter 1.25%. Non-interest income declined 22% in constant currency terms to SGD136 million as volatile markets reduced trading income and customer flows for treasury products.</p>
          <p>Expenses were little changed at SGD153 million. Total allowances fell 19% in constant currency terms to SGD43 million as both general and specific allowances declined.</p>
          <p>Asset quality remained healthy. Non-performing assets fell 4% from the previous quarter to SGD2.8 billion, 37% of assets classified as non-performing, a few current and interest and principal. The NPL rate improved from 1.5% in the previous quarter to 1.3%. Allowance coverage rose 11 percentage points to 124% as a result of the significant increase in general allowances this quarter. If collateral was considered, allowance coverage was 158%.</p>
          <p>Our capital position remains strong with core Tier 1 at 10.7%, Tier 1 at 12.6%, and total capital adequacy ratio at 15.5%, which are comfortably above current regulatory requirements, as well as the recently announced <mark type="indiscernible" /> (13:28) Basel III requirements to be fully implemented in 2019. If the listing of the operational risk multiplier on 28th of October is taken into account or core Tier 1, total Tier 1 and total CAR will increased by 0.2 percentage points each to 10.9%, 12.8%, and 15.7%, respectively.</p>
          <p>Our third quarter and nine months' results have demonstrated the success of our strategy implementation. They were driven by higher business volumes and customer flows. Our growth has been underpinned by prudent risk management and a solid balance sheet. Our liquidity is ample, our asset quality is healthy, with high allowance coverage. Our capital adequacy ratios are comfortably above regulatory requirements. We will continue to grow in a focused and measured rate, as we manage the short term uncertainties ahead.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention, and I will now hand you over to Piyush.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, thanks, Sok Hui. So, I'm just going to do a couple things &#x2013; the other slide, please? So I want to recap what Sok Hui mentioned. First of all, clearly we had a nine-month record, revenues at SGD5.7 billion, which is a record, which is both net interest income, non-interest income. And as you can see from the quarterly stuff, we have fairly steady rate of earnings, even if you back out the DBS Asset Management SGD47 million bucket in the last number, it's still SGD1, 916 million, or SGD1,918 million or something, SGD1,920 million odd, which is still a solid number, and consistent with how we've been doing over the quarters. Our ROE is good, it's about a percent up above where it was.</p>
          <p>I guess the key thing is I'm particularly pleased about the third quarter results. I mean, quite clearly we had record income of SGD1,960 at the third quarter, which is good. We have continued strong loan growth, just SGD12 billion odd ex the currency impact, with solid fee income; with some of the weakness in the capital market side of the income, so, brokerage and investment banking was somewhat short, but more than made up by fee income and other banking areas, remittances trade, and so on. We had record TMU and GTS numbers.</p>
          <p>Most of all, I'm very pleased with the fact that we negotiated a very tricky quarter quite well. If you look at most of the earnings release on any of the large bulge bracket banks, everybody took a bath in the treasury and markets business in the quarter. And as you know, we are an active player in that market, and for us to be able to manage this quarter as well as we did, I think, is quite commendable.</p>
          <p>Also this quarter, we've been able to post good results despite I think SGD189 million to our general provisions, right. And the general provision partly replaced loan growth for the quarter, but partly reflects just a conservative attitude to where the global macroenvironment is. So, we just loaded up on our provisions, our coverage is now up to 124%, which is pretty much almost back to our previous pre-crisis high in terms of coverage levels. And we just did this to maintain a conservative posture given all that uncertainty coming down.</p>
          <p>So as you see on this next slide, and clearly, it's a good quarter, good quarter driven by customer engagement and as I recall, we're firing on all cylinders of our business. IBG, the institutional bank is doing extremely well, continues to have a fantastic year. On the whole IBG is running at almost 50% above last year. It's the largest part of our business, it's like 60%, two- thirds of our business. It's a growth engine in all of our markets outside of our core markets, so that's great.</p>
          <p>The consumer bank, private bank together the whole &#x2013; the retail and consumer proposition is steady, and which is good given the interest rate headwinds. As we've always mentioned, this is the part of the business that suffers the most in the interest rate environment that we are in, and to be able to maintain a fairly steady boat, frankly, if you look at it year-on-year, it's growing even quarter-on-quarter, I'm quite pleased with the performances there is pretty steady.</p>
          <p>The transaction banking performance, which is what we're trying to grow as I mentioned before, instead of just being a loan house, we want to try and diversify into a whole range of other activities. GTS is an important part of that. The growth in GTS has been very strong and this is both cash management and trade and trade finance, trade fees, trade finance, cash management. So, that's been very pleasing.</p>
          <p>And treasury, I've talked about it. If you look at our whole treasury business, it's been remarkably stable through all of the volatility of this year. Part of it is from the fact that, as we mentioned before, we're changing the nature and complexion of the business to doing a lot more customer activity. As Sok Hui pointed out, our customer part of the business is now up to 44% for the nine months, and that gives a level of stability in this business that we did not previously have.</p>
          <p>The non-customer portion, other income, which is not just trading by the way, it's trading, it's balance sheet management, it's warehousing, the whole work. That moves around a little bit and you see it was SGD300 million, SGD230 million, SGD300 million, but on the whole the overall nature of that business is relatively stable.</p>
          <p>Slide, please? Then if you look at it also by geography, again, I've indicated this before. We're very pleased that our focus on organic growth in the markets, I would say. Singapore, Hong Kong continues to do us extremely well. So, in the quarter and for the nine months, India is up 34%, China is up 47%, Taiwan is up, Indonesia is up. So, quite clearly this rebalancing of the mix of our earnings is helping, these countries collectively are now 22% of the bank's total, this thing, anything outside of Singapore, Hong Kong. So, again, directionally headed in the right direction.</p>
          <p>Slide, please? All right. So, what I thought I'd do is spend a little bit of time talking about four things, which are obviously challenging in this quarter, and I think some of these have been in the minds of several people, the analysts, as well as the media. So, I just thought I would spend a little bit of time focusing on that. So, you get a sense for where we are, what we're doing, and how we're trying to manage through these uncertain situations and times.</p>
          <p>So, the first one, if you look at asset quality in terms of where we are. I mean, clearly the first thing to notice is we've been growing the loan book, and we've been growing the loan book aggressively. We've got a 25 odd percent growth in the loan book year-on-year. That's pretty solid and substantial loan growth. Within that, we've grown SGD38 billion, it's about half and half. Half is trade finance, half is other loans. But the first thing to reflect on is, this whole loan growth is conscious, and it is in some ways opportunistic. In the sense that it's quite clear to us and as we think about our 10-year strategy for where we're trying to take DBS.</p>
          <p>So, we want to be able to use our loan book to get into large corporate customers and on the back of that, we then cross-sell into GTS and treasury and markets and trade finance, et cetera. That's the business model that we're trying to work with. So, building out our loan book is an important part of that. What the loan book in the last couple of quarters allowed us to do, because of the uncertainty and the opportunity in the environment, it has allowed us to build positions with clients, new clients, and existing clients, than the normal course would take us an extraordinary long time to build.</p>
          <p>So that's why it's opportunistic in the sense that the last two quarters' volatility, the European banks are pulling out, China has got loan quotas in place, people have liquidity issues. This is the time for a bank like us to be able to leverage our strength. We have capital. We have liquidity. So, this gives us the opportunity to leverage market conditions, but it's not opportunistic in the sense of short-term gain. It's opportunistic in the sense that it allows us to accelerate our strategic agenda, right?</p>
          <p>So, we know what we're trying to do and this has been a great opportunity to be able to push the pedal on being able to achieve our strategic agenda quicker than we normally would have been able to do.</p>
          <p>The second point, I wanted to make is, if you look at the nature of this, SGD19 billion of that comes from trade finance, 15%. Our trade finance typically if you look at the second column, is 18% of our mix. In fact, if you exclude the recent growth, trade finance is about 15% of our business maybe, it's like one-sixth or one-seventh of our business, but in the last year it's been 50% of our growth, and that's been conscious, because we go into new companies and new customers, particularly in China where we're trying to build this business out. We're being conscious about customer selection, we're being conscious about the profile of the business we want to build. So, this is short-term. It's self-liquidating, it's six months to one year financing. It allows us to build positions with companies, which are naturally strong because they participate in international trade. They're not domestically-oriented, real estate or construction companies. And therefore, we think it's a good strategic way for us to be able to build into the customers and the client that we seek to be able to do business with.</p>
          <p>The non-trade finance 50%, is mostly in Singapore and Hong Kong; 70% of that is in Singapore and Hong Kong, it's core clients. They're clients, we know well. It's clients we can support through this crisis. The rest of the 30% is evenly spread. So, it's India, it's Indonesia, it's most of our client franchise, but it's fairly solid existing client franchise. It's not too much of a concern.</p>
          <p>All of our loan growth has been accompanied by cross-sell. So, it's not just reporting loans on the book. We're using the loans to be able to create a broad business. You can see that from our non-interest income to total income. You can see that from our total fee &#x2013; base fee to total income, whichever metric you use. You can see that from our customer T&amp;M activity. So, we're broad basing the franchise as we go in and build this asset book.</p>
          <p>I think the points I want to make is, apart from the fact that we are thoughtful. We know what we're trying to get into. We're keeping it low risk. We're choosing the customers. It also shows up in the big numbers. Our NPLs are down to 1.3%. That's partly helped by the denominator increase, the denominator is better, but it's also helped by the fact that we're not seeing any decline in our asset quality, it's pretty steady. And our coverage is up to 124%. So, while we're doing this at the same time, it's not specific provision, it's general provisions, we are sort of being able to park and cushion ourselves to any downside that might come.</p>
          <p>So on the top, I want to take these couple of minutes to make sure people understood. We have been growing loans aggressively. It's been knowledgeable, it's been thoughtful &#x2013; in what we think is a fairly sound manner, and it is aligned with our strategic agenda of what we're trying to build out.</p>
          <p>Slide, please? I thought I'd spend a little bit of time talking about China, because a large part of our loan growth, not a large part, but a substantial &#x2013; this thing has been in China as well. If you think about our total loan growth for the region, I mean, all the SGD38 billion, about SGD15 billion was Singapore and then SGD15 billion is Hong Kong, China. So, that's an important of what we are trying to do.</p>
          <p>Now if you look at China and break it out, right, this is what I've mentioned, half of our China portfolio is trade finance. So, this is the kind of stuff we're talking about. We've added almost 300 to 350 companies this year in our China mix.</p>
          <p>These are &#x2013; so let me back off a bit. We created a very detailed China strategy as we did an India strategy some time ago. The strategy focuses on which cities we want to bank in. We've chosen specific cities we will grow out in. We've chosen specific industry groups that we're interested in growing out in. And we've chosen specific racks in target markets. So, we defined target markets by industry and trying to define target markets by name.</p>
          <p>So we know exactly which companies we want to do business with in China. So, as we build out this China portfolio, it is within that &#x2013; within the boundaries of that strategy. The trade loans that we have are about 60%, 65% either backed by cash or backed by bank support, LCs from the policy banks. So &#x2013; but fundamentally they're still not just banked in that, we're choosing the customers, we're choosing who we go to and then in addition to that we get cash security or we get bank security. So, this is a very, very solid, sound business.</p>
          <p>The building and construction, which is other language might interest people; of the SGD1.6 billion, SGD1 billion is to Singapore and Hong Kong developers who are doing business in China. So, about SGD600 million of that is really to Chinese SOEs kind of companies. It's about half, half of it is corporate lending to the Singapore, Hong Kong names, half of it relates to projects, in all cases the projects have been completed. Our loan to values are down at 30 &#x2013; are at 30%. So, it's a very conservative portfolio, we're seeing no stress in the portfolio. It's a very conservative low LTV portfolio it's highly focused on principally Singapore, Hong Kong developers who are in the China market doing business. So, it's not something that gives us any concern or any issues.</p>
          <p>Our manufacturing loans are 54% collateralized by cash and property. So, it's a couple of billion dollars. But overall we look at the China portfolio, we're not seeing stress. NPL ratio is at 0.5%; our coverage is very high and part of it driven by regulatory requirements, coverage is very high and as we look at our delinquencies, as we look at our pipelines, we look at the stress test, we stress tested our China portfolio every, which way. We stress tested the real estate portfolio, we stress tested the SME portfolio, we stress tested individual industry lines. We are not seeing any signs of any stress or any headwinds coming down the pipe on any of our China book.</p>
          <p>The third part of our asset thing, which I talk mainly about is Europe. So, we have really no direct exposures in Europe, we don't really lend to &#x2013; to any European name. The bond portfolio, which people have asked us about, so we thought we put this thing up there. Of our total bond portfolio, obviously we are in &#x2013; multiple areas. Sok Hui mentioned that we hold a lot of U.S. treasuries, we hold a lot of stuff. But our European part of our bond portfolio is SGD2 billion, SGD2.1 billion.</p>
          <p>And there's been simply in supras, in Germany, in U.K, the gildes, the Bunds, there's some EBRD paper, there's CFW paper, so all AAA, right. So, we have nothing outside of that in any of our bond portfolios. So, to me this is pretty rock solid portfolio with nothing to worry about. We've a couple of hundred million bucks of bank-related stuff, most of it is in the U.K. and most of it is top-notch banks just like the HSBCs of the world, right? So there is really nothing in that, which is anything to worry about either.</p>
          <p>So if you look at the nature of our European industry, we have really no exposure to PIIGS, we have no exposure to any of the peripheral countries. We have a fairly solid bond portfolio, not a large part of our bond portfolio in any measure.</p>
          <p>So net-net if you look at our asset quality, we've been growing the book, but we're very confident and comfortable with where we are. We think our asset profile and our asset portfolio is in good shape. We're not seeing headwinds. We've increased coverage, our NPAs are down.</p>
          <p>Now if the global economy tanks, frankly, Asia will slow next year. If Asia slows then the portfolio of NPAs will pick up, definitely. We are down to 7 or 9 basis points of SPs, and that's unusually low. So, there will be some pick-up, but it's not going to be extraordinary, it's not going to be out of the ordinary, and it'll be in line with a true cycle kind of phenomena. So, again, this is not something that gives me sleepless nights, let's put it like that.</p>
          <p>Right, next. Second I thought I'll talk a little bit about our NIM situation. Slide, please? All right. So, this is the &#x2013; this thing, right? As we said, we were impacted by two things on NIM. If you remember we kept four quarters of NIM at about 1.8 and frankly, 1.8 is hopeful that we won't have any more NIM problems, in fact, I was hopeful that if you started getting some interest rate increases NIM might start going up and boy, were they wrong. So, at this point in time, I stopped looking for any interest rate increases in the medium term.</p>
          <p>But the factors impacted in two ways. We're impacted in Hong Kong. In Hong Kong we're impacted I'd say a little bit on the asset side, a little bit on the funding site. Asset side was deliberate because we keep putting on the trade finance business, it tends to be lower margin business and because of cash back to a large extent, marginally low because it's a secure form of this thing. So, there is some pressure on NIMs on the asset side, but most of it is in the funding side. And so, in Hong Kong we paid up for deposits in this quarter. So, we paid up because we wanted to make sure that the Hong Kong overall situation, apart from funding from Singapore, we always fund from Singaporean market, that we retained our position in the Hong Kong market.</p>
          <p>That is strategic. In a sense, we can let our Hong Kong deposits and positions run off and fund it externally, but when you think about your Hong Kong franchise, you don't want to let that happen. So, you want to retain a foot in the Hong Kong deposit market and the Hong Kong funding market. Now, if you want to play that game then you have to pay at market rate. Unfortunately, market rates in the Hong Kong deposit scene are high, and so they've put some pressure on our NIM.</p>
          <p>Now this is a tactical thing, right? It depends quarter-to-quarter, we don't have to fund. We don't have to go to the Hong Kong deposit market. So, it depends on the profile of our business, what we think we need to do as we build and reposition our business out. So, half of our NIM pressure was that.</p>
          <p>The other half of NIM pressure was Singapore. And the red line, frankly, tells you all; that's SOR. And the SOR offer rate collapsed in August, it stayed low through September, came back. And if you look at where it is now, it's actually frankly, back to comfortable levels now, but I think it's going to say choppy. And it's going to stay choppy for &#x2013; and as long as U.S. rates are low and as long as you don't know what happens in the U.S. QE3 comes, doesn't come, interest rates and SOR rates would stay choppy and loans. So, that puts pressure on us obviously, because as SOR is down, SIBOR is down. On an average I think SIBOR for the quarter, for our book is down by about 6 odd, 6 to 8 basis point. And that impacts parts of our portfolio. So, parts of our portfolio are priced on SIBOR and SOR is impacted.</p>
          <p>Now having said that, I think we've taken appropriate measures. One, we've been fighting off, trying dropping rates on the deposit side for the longest time. And you know rates kept creeping down, and we held rates because we just figure that given our position in Singapore, it's not a good thing to do. But finally, at the end of the day we couldn't. We followed the markets. So, in October we've taken these down by a bit, but that will give us some cushion on our spread.</p>
          <p>The good thing is that re-pricing is kicking in. It's kicking in nicely both in Hong Kong and now in Singapore, frankly, around the region &#x2013; and this happening around the world. I think people are being able to &#x2013; industry is being able price up both for credit, as well as for liquidity. And we are seeing that show up now in our numbers. So, the re-pricing is kicking in, and so that gives us some of this thing.</p>
          <p>And finally, SIBOR and SOR, I think is going to be choppy. For the time being, it's normalized close to normal, and we will see whether we have many more of these downwards spikes like August, hopefully, hopefully not.</p>
          <p>So where we are now at 173 basis points, I think we have a fighting chance of being able to keep our NIM in that range. I don't &#x2013; unless again the SOR collapses again for extended period of time then there might be some pressure. So, maybe, here or there, but I don't see that dropping off a cliff.</p>
          <p>I think on total net interest income frankly, we'll be able to retain and hold our net interest income, for sure, and so I'm pretty confident about that. So, NIM was the second thing people &#x2013; but it's been a challenge to this quarter. A lot of if requires tactical action, and frankly, daily actions on adjusting and feeling how you manage your portfolio. And I am actually quite pleased with how as a team we were able to negotiate through this interest rate environment.</p>
          <p>Slide, please? Well, the third thing people are focused on, people talked about liquidity, and particularly our non-Sing dollar liquidity, how we're doing on our non-Sing dollar liquidity. If you look at it as a group, a group LDR of 84% is very healthy. We pushed it from 80% to 84%, this links back to the asset growth I talked about, this was deliberate. We figured, we had the capacity, which very few of our competitors do, and we decided to leverage the capacity in this quarter to be able to go and build strategic position. So, if you look at our Sing dollar LDR at 62%, it's moving up, that's in line with our strategy. It used to be in the 50s, we moved it to the high 50s, it was 60% last time, it's up 62%, that's a conscious choice because we want the balance our Sing dollar balance sheet better, and we continue to do that. But at 62%, that still means that leaves us a lot of firepower, to be able to fund other loan books to the extent that we need to. Our non-Sing dollar LDR, 115% is over 100%, but, it's not off the charts.</p>
          <p>Now, if you look at the next chart &#x2013; it reflected &#x2013; if you look at the non-Sing dollar part of a balance sheet, the first thing to reflect on, is that we're seeing good growth in our non-Sing dollar deposits. So, we're &#x2013; not only are we growing the loan thing, but we're seeing good non-Sing dollar loan growth. It's &#x2013; a lot of it, is in U.S. dollars. We've activated our GTS business, the cash management franchise is kicking in well. So, if you look at our performance sum, as you've seen in the last year, our dollar loans are up about by SGD6 billion, or our SGD7 billion &#x2013; our dollar deposits are up by SGD6 billion, or SGD7 billion. So, I'm quite pleased with that. That we're beginning to generate non-Sing dollar liabilities quite nicely.</p>
          <p>That notwithstanding, we obviously grew the non-Sing dollar loans faster than the deposits. So, our funding gap went up from SGD6 billion to about SGD15 billion, so, funding gap went up by SGD8 billion to SGD9 billion over the last year.</p>
          <p>Now, for us an SGD8 billion, or SGD9 billion increase in the funding gap is not an issue. First of all, in terms of the swaps we do from Sing dollars to this thing, we increased our swaps over the last year up by about SGD5 billion, in terms of what we swap up. Frankly, as we look forward, our projection is that the swap market is actually quite deep, and it's like a SGD150 billion swap market right, and we are a small part of the swap market.</p>
          <p>Our projection is as we build our business out, our Sing dollar deposits tend to grow at about SGD10 billion a year and so, and we make effort, depending on how much we go on fixed deposit, current accounts, savings accounts, but we get about SGD10 billion increase. And so for us, 50% of our growth every year, we should be able to swap increment. We're not uncomfortable with that. We think the market is big enough, as the market keeps growing, and we look at historically we back tested that over the last 10 years. As the market grows, the swap market keeps growing. So, we think we should be able to do that much, so I'm not overly concerned with that. There is enough capacity to do that.</p>
          <p>And second, wholesale funding. So, we focused on building out a wholesale funding book. Actually, we've built out our wholesale funding over this period quite nicely, a lot more than we needed for just our funding growth. We've launched a CP program that's &#x2013; we'll be raising SGD4 billion, SGD5 billion in CP now, which we didn't do before. We've gone through institutional funders and being able to fund through that. We updated, and we took SGD1 billion in MTN in the last year.</p>
          <p>Our reliance in the wholesale markets used to be almost zero. We now consciously said, we will go into the wholesale market and keep that funding source alive. If you look at banks like us, people fund 50%, 60% in the wholesale markets. Now, we obviously don't want to do that, and we don't need to do that. But to keep some 15%, 20% of our funding in the wholesale markets is a good thing just for liquidity and to keep it ready and going. We don't need it, as you can see, but we do it. So, we take and then we place it out again, just to make sure we're active in the market.</p>
          <p>So bottom-line, our liquidity is very healthy. We have no concerns about our liquidity situation. We have a lot of Sing dollars, more if we needed to swap it. Our non-Sing dollar deposits are coming in healthy and coming in strong and our active participation in the wholesale market helps to make sure that our name is known, we're recognized. And so if ever we need to go to the markets for funding, we won't have a problem for raising money.</p>
          <p>The last thing I want to talk about in terms of this quarter, and what it takes to manage is our treasury business. Now, again I made this point before, but I just wanted to underline that; if you look at total treasury income and this is the way I look at my total treasury business side. So, it includes the trading income line, the interest income line, the investment sales line, et cetera, et cetera, including the balance sheet management activity, as well as this thing.</p>
          <p>If you look at the top line, the customer-related thing that's steady and growing, and that has built a lot of solidity to our total treasury income as I made the point; third quarter is 44% of our total income. This whole year has been 43%, 43% and 44%, so it's getting 45%, over time; if I can get it to 50% of my total treasury, I'll really feel good; half of my treasury income is customer-driven.</p>
          <p>And if you look at the rest of the stuff, which includes what we do from trading asset balance, it's not that bad, I mean, it's obviously a little more choppy the customer flow, but it's not bad. And again, I wanted to underline the fact that if you compare us with any of the large houses in the treasury and market space and particularly after the third quarter in September, I think we did a fantastic job in terms of just managing through this crisis and volatile times on our treasury portfolios.</p>
          <p>All right, so then the next item, I want to spend a little bit of time talking about my usual &#x2013; think about the &#x2013; I'd thought I'd do a different slant on this, every time I tell you internal metrics, and how we're doing internally. So, this time what I have done, is I've told you about how I think the external world is beginning to view us on most of these nine metrics.</p>
          <p>Slide. And I've done that through the prism of the various awards that we get. Now, I don't necessarily go and count awards. But at the end of the day to me, if you start getting into the award category and most of the awards are customer polls. It just tells me that more and more customers are beginning to cite us as a credible player or a credible source in that particular area. And so you discount ranking and position, you just think of it contextually that if our name begins to get more and more cited in certain areas and certain businesses then it could &#x2013; must be that the market is beginning to recognize and reflect what we think internally our metrics are showing, right?</p>
          <p>So in Singapore, if you will, we've &#x2013; I'm not at liberty to cite another award. I was going to put it up there, but then I was told it's embargoed so I can't talk about it. But we were named Bank of the Year in Singapore by an important award, which I can't tell you about, but it is the first time in several years, right? And so to me that's quite important. In the past few years several of our competitors have won that. So, it's important to know that, we obviously seem to be gaining traction.</p>
          <p>We won the Retail Bank of the Year Award. We won obviously a lot of the investment bank-related awards in Singapore, even equities, Best House Equity (sic) [Best Equity House], but we're winning the Cash Management Award in Singapore. So, the things that matter to me, we are beginning to get on the radar for cash management. We're definitely clawing our way back in retail banking and by putting them together we're definitely beginning to regain our position as the premier bank in Singapore, which is in line with what we want to do, entrench our leadership position in Singapore.</p>
          <p>Slide. In Hong Kong the left part we've always had, I mean, we win the SME awards in Hong Kong. We are really a good SME house in Hong Kong. So, there the thing is how do we up our game. And we do think that we are in good pole position now to up our game in the SME space. But again, in Hong Kong, I'm quite pleased that we're beginning to get recognized for cash, and we're getting recognized increasingly for treasury, right? So that's good. It's consistent with what we're trying to do, build out GTS, build out treasury, and we're beginning to get recognition on both of those dimensions.</p>
          <p>Slide. If you look outside Hong Kong, right, so this one in China same thing, treasury and cash management. We are getting into &#x2013; ranked first for Foreign Cash Management; ranked third for Medium Cash Management. So, treasury and cash management we're being recognized in China. Treasury and cash management we're beginning to get recognized in Taiwan. And India is across the board. I was very pleased, we're the Best Foreign Bank in India because that was against every bank, including HSBC, Citi, Standard Chartered who have been there a 100 years. So, I'm now going to subscribe to Financial Express [Laughter]. It's my favorite paper.</p>
          <p>But it's not just that. If we've been winning a lot of recognition for cash and this thing in India and trade finance in Indonesia, again the point I wanted to make was &#x2013; don't get into the words, per se &#x2013; is we're beginning to get on the radar in each of these countries for things we're doing, and it's consistent with where we are placing our effort. We are placing our effort to build out the treasury, the cross serve, the customer business, GTS cash, and its showing up.</p>
          <p>So this is the other one, which I like very much and I mean, it's obvious why. Best Private Bank in Singapore, Wealth Manager of the Year in Singapore, Best Local Private Bank in Singapore, and what more do you want me to say? I'm actually quite pleased.</p>
          <p>Our wealth thing is kicking in nicely, as we've launched &#x2013; as I promised, we've launched a market campaign on the wealth space in this quarter. It's doing really well. We're getting a lot of inquiries, we're getting a lot of pick-up in the second half of the year since we launched it. Our AUM inflows is pretty much double every month from what we are seeing earlier. So, I'm quite pleased with the traction we have.</p>
          <p>Slide? GTS, I already talked about, cash management we're seeing, trade we're good at, and we've always been good at and frankly, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:45) to us. Cash is where we would focus on trying to build position, and so we're seeing it around the place.</p>
          <p>T&amp;M is the other place. We really have a solid T&amp;M house, and I told you we've changed the nature of our business from high 20s customer business to mid-40s customer business. It's a fundamental shift in the nature of the business, and we're getting recognized for it. So, Regional Derivatives House of the Year, actually second year in a row. To me, that's a big award because this is a place where all the bulge bracket guys compete. Ranked fourth in Asia for overall interest rate and a third for interest rate, fourth for currency products, derivatives, and so on. So, I mean, clearly this is beginning to be a recognized strength of DBS.</p>
          <p>Slide. Finally, a third award I want to talk about. So, I told a lot of you guys this story two years ago when I came, about my unhappy experience at the DBS call center. I went there two years ago, and our call wait time was eight minutes, our abandon rate was 26%, our call handling time was 375 seconds. It was horrible.</p>
          <p>Well, two weeks ago, we won the Best Call Center in Singapore, a Gold Medal, Best Call Center for across this thing. We are hitting every hurdle. We've got the best metrics that I've seen in any call center anywhere. We've always been the best call center in Hong Kong. By the way this is not awards, but all I &#x2013; these are internal metrics. All our queues across Singapore are down by 50%. Our ATM queues are down. Our branch banking queues are down. Our contact centers up and ticking. Our ATM uptimes are up. So, I feel really good about the progress we're making on the customer dimension. And it's good to know that it's being recognized externally as well.</p>
          <p>Slide.</p>
          <p>On the management people thing, we got a lot of awards. Safest Bank, we've talked about. But SIAS had us, and we won runner's up. We've got to get to top. This time, the Most Transparent Company in the corporate governance. In terms of internal audit effectiveness and excellence, we ranked number two. Euromoney ranked us number two for the most convincing and coherent strategy on so on. So, clearly we are beginning to get the shop more stable and in order.</p>
          <p>And finally, it's not &#x2013; the last one on award, but I thought I'd put it up anyway. We do this Gallup Surveys. We've been doing the Gallup Surveys of internal employee engagement for the last five, six years, right? And so we've been showing improvement over the years. We're very pleased, we got this survey results last week and the results have us up now at the 80 &#x2013; whatever, 81st, 83rd, 80th percentile of all global companies in terms of the level our employee engagement. And these are the standard, the 12 Gallup questions they ask everybody. And I'm not going to go into too much detail, but I wanted to leave that one thought, that the quality of our team has come together really well. Both our leadership team, but also down the thing, we've added a lot of people. As you know, we've added 3,000-plus people in the last couple of years, as we've invested in building our businesses.</p>
          <p>But we've been able to do that, where at the same time, make sure that we're creating a consistent culture, a culture that is a very DBS culture, right, and doing this thing that works with DBS. DBS has always been good at teamwork. So, DBS has always scored off the charts on teamwork. Frankly, this is something, which is not true for other firms, including my previous firm.</p>
          <p>But with being able to make a DBS culture, which is a uniquely DBS culture, it takes the value the DBS had and a whole bunch of other things, and we're obviously getting traction with our own people. And to me that's a great resounding endorsement of lot of the things we're trying to do. If we have this portion, right, and we have the customer portion right, I think the rest of our results will continue to improve.</p>
          <p>I think that's the last slide I had, if I remember right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Piyush and Sok Hui. We'll proceed to the Q&amp;A portion of our results briefing. So, on that note the usual drill I guess and first off the mark as always, <mark type="ph" /> Saeed (46:43), yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You said that wholesale funding &#x2013; DBS doesn't do a lot of wholesale funding, and it's good to have 15% to 20% in wholesale funding. You don't want to grow as much as a 50%. So, is there like any sort of projected target you have in the next year or so? How much of funding would you get from the wholesale market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually I don't have a target for how much amount. But I put in turn management cap, right. We really had none and the problem with having none is that if you suddenly want to go and issue a CP or an MTN or go and borrow in the internal markets, if your name is not recognized, if you don't have a program in place, and if you've not been actively working the program, it's very tough.</p>
          <p>So it seems to me it's kind of overly conservative for us to have zero presence in that market at all. If you look at most, well, the Europeans obviously are doing 60% of the volume, the Australians do another 60%, 70% wholesale funded, the Europeans do a lot of it, the American banks are in the 30% to 40% range, wholesale funded. And for me, therefore, I'm geared at about 20%, we've built it up, we were almost nothing, we have now built it to about 20%.</p>
          <p>So that's a good thing to have, to keep roughly 20% wholesale funding program going. So, if you need to, you have depth and relevancy in the market. And we are doing it well, we don't need the money, so that's the good thing. So, we fund, we are now 20% funding in the wholesale market, but then we've also been placing out on the other side. It's not that we using it to fund our books, we are actually going and placing it out into market assets. And it's really to make sure that we have a set of programs and market activity and presence that is consistent, and it can be there if we need it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question, please? <mark type="ph" /> Emily (48:34)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, what is your outlook for loan growth in the next few quarters, especially for home loans? And secondly, the growth in expenses has outpaced your total income. Do you have any plans to maybe have tighter control over that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the loan growth as you know, I mean, well someone asked me earlier, so, the middle of the year I said we're going to slow down loans in the second, but actually what I said is I think the market opportunity will disappear, that was my &#x2013; I figured that this whole opportunity we had in the second quarter would not continue in the third quarter because I thought the macro economy would stabilize. As it happens, the market opportunity didn't disappear. In fact, the market opportunity increased, and we took use of that opportunity to continue to build our customer position.</p>
          <p>But &#x2013; and so far what we're able to do, if you remember, our loans have been growing faster than our non-Sing dollar deposit. We were able to do that because we can fund it conveniently. Over time, as we get to a situation where we used our capacity to fund from the Sing dollar, then our loan growth will be constrained by both, our view on credit risk, but also our ability to fund. And as Sok Hui mentioned, I think going forward, our loan growth therefore, will be more paced by our deposit growth, how much we fund in the deposit market, we'll pace our loan growth more in line with that.</p>
          <p>In terms of the housing loans and the Sing dollar, it's been slower. If you look at the string of pace, our growth has already been coming up. We actually have been giving up some share in the Sing dollar and in fact, even housing loan market, mainly at that point. For the last year, we've been deliberately ceding share in all of our housing loan markets because we're just not that aggressive in terms of financing the marginal housing loan. So, I think it will continue to be at the pace it has over the last quarter, I don't see it dropping off substantially from there either.</p>
          <p>In terms of expense and revenue base, so if you remember, almost two years ago, I gave guidance that I expected our revenue expense ratios, our cost income ratios to head up to 45% because it seemed to me that there were investments that DBS needed to make both in people, technology and business lines, which we would have put money against. As things are, we are up at the 43% range, and I think last quarter or quarter before, I said I don't think we'll get to 45%, actually. Now, that I've got some stuff and I think we'll &#x2013; we might pick up a shade below 45%, but it'll be about that level.</p>
          <p>And so for the time being, we've continued to be in strong investment mode. As we go forward, though, we've had two years of investments under our belt, we are slowing down because we don't &#x2013; we've done a large part of the people bill that we needed. So, our people growth is going to slow down quite sharply. In fact, already in the third quarter, our total growth and headcounts was substantially lower than the second quarter, which was substantially lower than the first quarter. So, you can see the trend line and trajectories coming off very sharply. We grew 800 people in the first quarter, 600 in the second quarter, sub 400 in the third quarter, and that's where we're headed. So, I think it's going to level off.</p>
          <p>Also on technology, a large part of our technology expenses are already there, and we've done it. So, we've got to get a few more systems in place. We're going to get our payments in June in place in the early part of next year. We're going to roll out our Internet platform, so both consumer and corporate in the first half of next year. So, there is some more investment required in some of those applications, but a lot of the heavy lifting has been done. All our resiliency programs are pretty much done. We've brought in new mainframes, new storage systems, hot standbys; all of that has already been done. So, hopefully we don't have to replicate too much of that, but there is some more investment in applications. Net-net, I think our total investments are beginning to taper off, and which is why I'm confident we're unlikely to hit the 45% levels &#x2013; it'll taper off from where we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Piyush. Any questions from this side of the room? <mark type="ph" /> Peter (52:23)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wondered if you could address the trade story. We've learned that it's now 80% of your lending business, it's 50% your growth. How much are you becoming a trade bank, and how much of your growth is sort of the industry growth, the growth or trade-off into Asia trade and trading in Asia in general? And why are your competitors not keeping up with this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, actually it's a mix of, I think, three different things. One, like I said, market opportunity. So, you go back to the trade, a lot of it is China and the reason a lot of it is China is you go back to what's happened in China, China has SGD3 trillion of trade, if you look at the exports and imports. Most of the SGD3 trillion that Chinese trade has traditionally got financed in the Chinese market. So, the Chinese policy banks and the Chinese local banks have financed this trade. In the last year or two with the tightening in China and with the interest rate arbitrage, a lot of these people have figured out it's easier to get it financed offshore than finance it onshore. So, the market has developed. People are more actively willing to finance trade offshore today than they were before. So, there is a market opportunity, which is driving this, obviously.</p>
          <p>The second thing is, it's a conscious strategic choice for us. So, we do want to do a lot more GTS. If we go back to our strategic thing at the top end, if you go back to strategy, we want to be a broad corporate bank, we want to build SME, we want to build a world franchise. The broad corporate bank means you want to stop &#x2013; move from being a loan house, and we were heavily a loan house, to being a diversified corporate bank, which really means do more trade finance, do more cash management, do more treasury business; that's really the heart of what a broad corporate bank is.</p>
          <p>So the second is this, we're consciously pumping up our presence in cash and trade. We've hired people, we've built a GTS team, we built a commodities trade finance team. We've hired people from the market to do structured trade, we've done straight trade, and so on. So, we've put resources against it, and we're consciously pushing that pedal.</p>
          <p>And the third thing is really a function of DBS's strength. Over the last two quarters, we're one of the few games in town who had the capital and the liquidity to do this. And so a lot of people might have wanted to do that, but are constrained because either they have capital constraint, so they can't grow their balance sheet, or they have funding constraints, so they can't fund and then put on something on the balance sheet &#x2013; we have neither.</p>
          <p>So it is just a happy circumstance, so what happened in China, our own strategic choices and our own strength fundamental strengths that allowed us to capitalize on this opportunity that other people are not being able to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> (54:45)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know. So, I don't have an answer to that at this time. I mean, I haven't tracked what the total market growth would be. Certainly, we'll be much further ahead than our projections or what we've originally &#x2013; we have a 10-year agenda on China and going into the China business and growth. We're doing much better than we were hoping to do. We can check that for you though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, Piyush. <mark type="ph" /> Christine (55:17), you had a question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The staff cost. Because, I think the market has already priced in global recession and some other investment banks have already started laying off people. What's your take on this? What measures do you &#x2013; does DBS have on this?</p>
          <p>And second question is, what's your take on the systemic risk that could spread to Asia, Asia financial system due to the European debt crisis? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first one, so this is frankly, the difference between us and the global investment houses is exactly that. We're building a broad commercial bank, diversified in the Asian context, and we're not starting with cost income ratios of 58% and 60% or 70% and 80%, which some of these houses are. Also, our fortunes are not linked to markets, right? So, we're starting a situation, we're heavily linked to capital markets and market and then your volatility in those markets, you don't have a choice. You've got to go and start slashing and burning, because how else would you protect your thing? We are none of those things. Our starting position is different is different. Our business model is different and therefore, and frankly, the reason we choose to play in Asia is a little different right, where we're not facing the same circumstances.</p>
          <p>So, we have no plans, need, or anticipation to try and have to cut head count or do any of these things; it's not likely to happen. What we are doing is tapering down, tempering down our growth. And frankly, irrespective of the market condition, and this has been conscious all along, we said we'll invest two years, and then we will try and leverage. Internally, the words I use is, we're going to make our investments sweat a bit. So, we put on 3,000-plus people. We've thrown a lot of technology. So, we're going to spend the next year or so trying to make that sweat direct productivity out of the investments that we've made. And I think that will be enough for us to continue to grow the business we're growing without having to be precipitate about taking people out of this thing.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we have a very focused strategic cost management program. We launched a program earlier this year. I'm a big &#x2013; I'm old-fashioned, I'm a big believer in that re-engineering and Lean. I just figure that if you run your processes well, you get customer value, you can then reduce customer cycle times, you can improve customer outcomes, and in the same process, you can get cost advantages. So, we've got a strategic cost program, which has been now running for most of this year. We think the strategic cost program will allow us to drive efficiency. So, we can continue growing the business without having to add more people into growing the business. That's what we're trying to do.</p>
          <p>On the other question on systemic risks, our baseline case is still that Europe and the U.S. will be like Japan. That you will see 1.5 or 2 percentage points of growth, couple of percentage points of growth over an extended period of time, call it 5 to 10 years, right? In that baseline scenario, we think Asia will slow. Asia will be at least a couple of percentage points off, but Asia will not have a precipitate blood bath, right? And therefore, we think that in a slow Asia growth rates of 6%, 6.5%, we think we can do good business in a slowing Asia, and that's our baseline case.</p>
          <p>In the baseline case, there will be volatility, which has to be &#x2013; I think the markets are destined to a lot of choppiness, and will continue. That's the new normal. I think this whole risk-on, risk-off trade, which changes every day, every week for sure, but certainly this does every day, this is going to be the nature of the beast for some time to come, and just have to be very careful about therefore, how you manage through this. But our agenda, which is a long-term strategic agenda in Asia, means we're quite happy to run through these ups and downs, because as long as our long-term direction is clear, and we are headed for the long-term direction. Now, there is a <mark type="indiscernible" /> (59:02) possibility that our base case doesn't come to pass, i.e., you wind up with Europe going to pieces, breaking apart, you have another Lehman crisis, so you have a, god forbid, another 1930 scenario of the Great Depression. So, could that happen? Yeah, if you believe Nouriel Roubini, he says it will definitely going to be happen right. But Roubini always says that.</p>
          <p>So if you figure that, that's a possibility then of course, Asia will be impacted. And in that circumstance, if Asia is impacted in this thing, of course, we'll be impacted. It has to be. We're a big player in Asia, and so the notion that the world goes through a 1930/Lehman and DBS will sort of be in a cocoon; that's not going to happen, let me assure you, right? We're part of Asia.</p>
          <p>My only view is that given the nature of our business, given the nature of Asia and given the nature of what we're trying to do, and our view on our portfolio is, we will do relatively much better than anybody else would, because we see no stress in our portfolio. We've seen nothing coming down the pipeline. We've got no exposure. So, if things really get very bad then yeah, we will also get impacted by that. But I think we will do a better than most other people here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think it's time for one last question, last two questions then. All right, <mark type="ph" /> Robin (60:10)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Just on the trade finance question. You spoke a lot about the China portfolio. Can you just share how much of that is RMB settled trade, is that growing and do you see a significant growth in that? And I think you mentioned before, you wanted to be a buyer in Asia. Do you think now is a good time for doing that, and is Europe just not in you radar at all in terms of assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The RMB settled trade is increasing, and nicely. So, our total RMB CNH booked now we have about 50 billion odd in CNH deposits, and about 18 billion to 20 billion in CNH assets. That CNH asset is all RMB settled trade, and that's growing nicely. So, we're beginning to get a better balance between the CNH liability and asset part of our book.</p>
          <p>On the values and this thing, we're at the right time and right place, we'll always be a buyer. At this point in time, I don't see anything, any obvious opportunities in Asia to go looking around. As you know, in Asia, the biggest issue is regulations. And so you can't do anything in China, you can't do anything in India. The Indonesians don't know whether they want anything done or don't want done, they can't do &#x2013; for somebody conservative like me that means you can't do anything in Indonesia. So, it's kind a tough. The prices got to be right, the regulations have got to work and I don't see anything on the immediate horizon. Europe, we're not a buyer, and we're quite clear.</p>
          <p>We are quite focused on our Asia-focused strategy and notwithstanding some good values in Europe or the U.S., we just don't think that we would bring incremental value to anything that we went and bought, it would just be a bolt-on to which we brought little value. If any of the European banks, as a consequence of the crisis, winds up shedding, interesting Asian asset that is something that we might look at. What we got from RBS in China was a case in point, it was small, but I'd be very happy to do trades of that sort.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. <mark type="ph" /> Gula (62:10)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. So, NPLs, in your base case scenario, what do you think NPLs are likely to be over the next year &#x2013; so to &#x2013; 12 to 15 months? And in your worst case scenario, what do you see NPL?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I haven't done the projections on either of those. [Laughter] Maybe Sok Hui has?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> (62:35)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Laughter] I thought you have a view on the base case NPL projections.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We haven't done this in terms of NPL ratio right because that would be mean that <mark type="inaudible" /> (62:49) NPL is bad assets over your total assets, but our base case scenario is that specific provisions will probably go up next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay on that note -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me add to that, because one of the reasons why they will go up, you see SPs are a function of your growth SPs and your recoveries, right, and of course, most of the recoveries have already been had. So, there is not a lot of mileage there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you. But <mark type="ph" /> Sam (63:14) did you want to ask one last question before we wrap up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Just in relation to the Chinese trade finance, you talked about its opportunistic nature. To what extent are you talking about it being a product of the &#x2013; not to get, technical, but at basis swap between &#x2013; the basis swap between offshore and onshore R&amp;D. Is that presenting opportunities for people to go in, and or is it just driven purely by demand to -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's a bit of both, but in the early part, it was more basis swap now increasingly the arbitrage rate, the curves have narrowed so fine, so the basis swap difference there is not that huge. And in the beginning you could make some money by doing offshore financing relative to numbers, it's a lot less now. So, a lot of it is not just pure actual demand that is done. If you look at the fact that &#x2013; see also based on differences scheme if you funded in dollars versus the other thing, just back to Robin's question, right? We are beginning to fund a lot more CNH, so you don't get that cost currency funding advantage because you're funding in the same currency and there is marginal base. So, most of it is just a natural demand.</p>
          <p>I see Andrew, you want to add to this quick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think as Piyush said, I think in the beginning of the year, when we come out on CNH, I think the curve on CNH is pretty discounted. So, that's why it attracts quite a fair bit of people to put all that trade settlements trade though CNH. But now actually it's the other way around. So, people are going back to use the onshore rate to settle rather than using the CNH. So, I guess you will have like a cycle up and down on the CNH, but in the fairly long-term basis I think these trade settlements using Renminbi, is the trend. So, you will continue to see this kind of volume to grow bigger and bigger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on that note, we will call this quarter's briefing to a close. Our full year results briefing will be held sometime in February next year. So, I guess this is the last time we'll be meeting for this year. So, all the very best for the next &#x2013; rest of 2011 and apologies, we'll have to dash off because Piyush and Sok Hui will be speaking to the analysts right now. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>