<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1369734" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-10</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8657</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Sok Hui Chng, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Piyush Gupta, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Sam Holmes</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Kevin Lim</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Gabriel Chen</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Christopher Howells</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Peter Hoflich</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and a very festive Year of the Rabbit greetings to all of you. We are starting the Year of the Rabbit with a new format. As you can see, we are now having our staff briefings in the morning. I think our friends in the media &#x2013; sorry, the staff briefings in the evening and the media briefings in the morning. And I think all our friends in the media are quite pleased with this new arrangement, so I'm told. Yeah, so we are nice and fresh right now. I think Piyush and Sok Hui are very eager to tell you more about our full year 2010 results.</p>
          <p>So, without further ado, I will pass the floor over to Sok Hui who will tell you more about our results. After that, Piyush will give you a little bit more color as to what are the key drivers behind our good results and then thereafter we will take on questions from all of you. Okay, thank you. Sok Hui, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, everyone. We achieved record earnings in 2010. Net profit rose 28% to SGD 2.65 billion reflecting the early success of strategic initiatives implemented during the year. The performance was underpinned by strong loan growth, customer driven non-interest income and an improvement in asset quality.</p>
          <p>Revenues rose 7% to SGD 7.07 billion. Higher treasury product cross-selling revenues contributed to a 28% in non-interest income. This more than offset a 3% decline in net interest income resulting from interest margin pressure. The impact of lower margins for the year was alleviated by strong loan growth of 16%. The growth was broad-based across businesses and countries and included market share gains in Singapore. Expenses rose 12% as head count was increased to support higher business volumes and investments were made for organic regional expansion.</p>
          <p>Profit before allowances reached a record SGD 4.14 billion. Allowances fell 40% as the NPL rate improved from 2.9% at the start of the year to 1.9%. Specific loan allowances halved to 43 basis points of loans while more general allowances were made in line with the stronger loan growth.</p>
          <p>For the fourth quarter compared to a year ago, net profit rose 38% to SGD 678 million. The fourth quarter's year-on-year comparisons reflected the full year result to trend. Stronger non-interest income offset the impact of lower net interest income while allowances declined with improvement in asset quality. Compared to previous quarter, fourth quarter net profit was 6% lower. Trading income fell in line with quieter treasury markets during the year end. There were also lower gains from the sale of financial investments. However, business volume growth momentum continued to be healthy.</p>
          <p>Net interest income rose 3% from the previous quarter to SGD 1.11 billion. Loans grew 3% from regional corporate loan demand and Singapore housing loan drawdowns, while interest margins were stable. Fee income rose 5% to SGD 358 million as we benefited from higher investment banking activities and wealth management product sales.</p>
          <p>Expenses rose 7% to SGD 780 million due to branding campaign costs and infrastructure investments. Credit costs, on the other hand, declined 19% to SGD 157 million as specific allowances fell.</p>
          <p>Net interest margins for the year fell 18 basis points to 1.84%, the result of a soft interest rate environment and lower credit spreads. For the fourth quarter, interest margins were little changed from the previous quarter at 1.79% as the decline in loans yield was offset by lower deposit costs.</p>
          <p>Loans rose 16% or SGD 21.5 billion during the year to SGD 152.1 billion. If currency effects were excluded, loans grew 21% or SGD 26.9 billion. The growth during the year was broad-based across customer segments and across countries. Strong corporate and SME borrowing resulted in double-digit loan growth in Hong Kong, China, Taiwan, India and Indonesia. In Singapore, our loan growth of 21% was faster than the industry's.</p>
          <p>Full year fee income was unchanged at SGD 1.40 billion. While wealth management, stockbroking, and investment income were higher, the increase was offset by lower margins for trade and remittances and a decline in loan related income. Fourth quarter fee income was 5% higher than the previous quarter. Wealth management revenues were higher as unit trust sales rose 73% and bancassurance product sales grew 33%. We benefited from better customer demand as well as our efforts to develop this product segment. Investment banking revenues were also higher compared to the previous quarter as a result of more active capital markets, such as IPO activities.</p>
          <p>Full year other non-interest income grew 79% to SGD 1.35 billion as treasury product cross-selling revenues and gains from the sale of financial investments and fixed assets were higher. Fourth quarter other non-interest income of SGD 265 million was 32% below the previous quarter as treasury markets were quieter and we had fewer gains from the sale of financial investments. However, it was significantly higher than the SGD 87 million we reported a year ago.</p>
          <p>This is a new slide. Total treasury income rose from SGD 1.71 billion in 2009 to SGD 1.92 billion in 2010. All of the growth came from treasury product cross-selling as T&amp;M worked with our Institutional Banking Group and Consumer Banking Group to structure products for customers to hedge market risk or take advantage of market movements.</p>
          <p>Income from these customer flows rose 48% to SGD 687 million and accounted for 36% of total treasury interest and non-interest income. This was 9 percentage points higher than in 2009. Interest and non-interest income from other treasury activities was flat at SGD 1.23 billion. This income is derived principally from managing the excess liquidity in our balance sheet, from market-making activities, and from managing residual positions arising from customer flows. At the same time, the value at risk of our trading book has declined with average value at risk falling 18% to SGD 27 million from the previous year.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter of cost-to-income ratio was 45%, higher than the previous quarter, but similar to a year ago. The increase compared to the previous quarter was due partly to lower revenues. The full year cost-to-income ratio rose from 39% to 41%. As more of our strategic initiatives are implemented and as head count has increased to support higher business volumes, we expect the full year cost-to-income ratio to rise gradually towards the 45% level over time.</p>
          <p>The figures on this slide for Hong Kong incorporate a 7% appreciation of the Singapore dollar against the Hong Kong dollar in 2010. Hong Kong's full year earnings rose 25% from a year ago to SGD 579 million. As with the Group's broader trends, improvement was due to stronger non-interest income and lower allowances.</p>
          <p>Net interest income fell 12% to SGD 783 million as interest margins declined from 1.92% in 2009 to 1.60% due to competitive pricing for housing loans and customer deposits. Loans rose 19% in local currency terms, largely from corporate and SME borrowing. Non interest income grew 43% to SGD 682 million, from a range of activities including treasury product cross-selling, wealth management sales, and loan syndication.</p>
          <p>Hong Kong is seeing benefit from the increased liberalization of the renminbi offshore market. Expenses rose 20% to SGD 720 million. The increase was due largely to compensation for customers who had bought Constellation Notes. Excluding this amount, expenses were little changed. Higher staff costs from a head count increase was offset by savings in occupancy and general expenses.</p>
          <p>Allowances fell 65% to SGD 73 million as the NPL rate improved from 1.7% a year ago to 1%. What is not shown here? Well, I'd like to let you know that in local currency terms, profit before allowances shown an increase of 4% instead of the decline of 3% and net profit in local currency terms grew 33% instead of the reported 25%, because of the appreciation of the Singapore dollar against Hong Kong dollars.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter, the Singapore dollar appreciated against the Hong Kong dollar by 7% from a year ago and 3% from the previous quarter. Hong Kong's fourth quarter earnings of SGD 144 million were 13% better than a year ago. Similar to the full year strength, the improvement was due to higher non-interest income and lower allowances.</p>
          <p>Compared to the previous quarter, net profit was 24% lower. Net interest income was stable at SGD 192 million. Loan volumes were little changed. In local currency terms, our deposits grew 6%. Net interest margin fell 7 basis points to 1.49% due to a decline in interbank rates as well as a larger proportion of interbank lending in the asset mix.</p>
          <p>Non-interest income fell 19% to SGD 157 million as trading income and sales of treasury products declined due to seasonal factors. The decline was partially offset by better wealth management revenue and higher gains from fixed asset sales. Expenses rose 20% to SGD 177 million due to higher advertising, one-off technology costs, and higher staff costs.</p>
          <p>Allowances declined 6% to 16% as general allowances fell. Again, to give you the numbers in local currency terms, profit before allowances year-on-year would have shown a decline of 1% instead of the 9% reported, and for the comparison to third quarter last year, profit before allowances would have shown a decline of 25% compared to the decline of 28%.</p>
          <p>At the net profit level, compared to fourth quarter last year, in local currency terms, net profit would have grown 20% instead of the 13% reported, and the decline compared to third quarter will be 22% compared to the decline of 24%. That again shows the appreciation of the Sing dollar against the Hong Kong dollar and the impact it has in our books.</p>
          <p>Slide 11, asset quality improved progressively during the year. Non-performing assets fell 24% from a year ago and 8% from the previous quarter to SGD 3.2 billion as recoveries and write-offs exceeded non-performing loan. DBS remained prudent in its classification and 40% of non-performing assets are still current in interest and principal. The non-performing loan rate improved from 2.9% a year ago and 2.1% in a previous quarter to 1.9%. Accumulated allowances rose to 100% of non-performing assets and to 127% if collateral was considered.</p>
          <p>Our capital position remains strong. We have total capital adequacy ratio at 18.4%, Tier 1 at 15.1%, and core Tier 1 at 11.8%. The Tier 1 ratio includes the 2.5 billion of preference shares raised in the fourth quarter, which is meant to replace 2.1 billion of existing preference shares due to be called in the first half of this year subject to regulatory approval.</p>
          <p>We are paying a final dividend of SGD 0.28 per share for the second half of 2010. This will bring total dividends to SGD 0.56 a share for the full year, unchanged from 2009. Based on yesterday's closing share price, DBS shares gave investors a dividend yield of 3.8%. The Scrip Dividend Scheme will be applicable to the final dividend. For shareholders who opt for scrip, new shares will be issued at a 5% discount to the average closing share prices on 12, 13 and 16 May.</p>
          <p>In summary, 2010 was a significant year for DBS as we laid the groundwork for our strategic priorities and achieved some early successes. The record earnings we achieved in a soft interest rate environment reflect the solid execution of our strategic initiatives. We recorded strong broad based loan growth including loan market share gains in Singapore and higher cross-sell revenue. Our asset quality has improved, while our capital position remains strong. We'll build on the momentum in 2011 to strengthen our customer proposition and increase shareholders' returns.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention, and I'll now hand you over to Piyush.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thanks, Sok Hui. And so let me start by saying Gong Xi Fa Cai to everybody, Happy New Year. I was as surprised as all of you over the tables. I think the tables are a good addition, so I must thank my colleagues in our marketing function for having thought of this.</p>
          <p>Sok Hui has laid out our numbers. I have a couple of slides which might seem like repeats, but I thought it would be helpful to give you a flavor for how I see the business along two dimensions. One, I will have a couple of comments about the overall business and particularly our lines of business, the institutional side, the consumer side and so on. And then the second part of my talk, I really want to focus on the nine priorities I set out for the company a year ago and give you a sense for how I think we are doing against those, what we've done last year and where we are trying to head to in the course of this year.</p>
          <p>So, if you look at the top level stuff, it's pretty obvious, 7% revenue growth, we're actually quite pleased with in the context of the interest rate environment and the challenges we've had on interest rate. We actually did better than our internal budget and that is quite a task, because when we budgeted for the year we built in some expectations of interest rate rises in the later part of the year, which obviously didn't happen. So we're very pleased at the momentum we were able to build, and particularly across the non-interest income, our cross-sell activities more than made up for the margin compressions and the interest rate issues.</p>
          <p>As you can see, our non-interest income was up 28% year-on-year, which is very significant. We feel very pleased about that. Resulted in SGD 2.65 billion in net profit, which we think is not a bad number. Obviously, it excludes the charge we took in Hong Kong in the third quarter, so when you exclude the &#x2013; we take the charge into account, it's only SGD 1.6 billion.</p>
          <p>ROE, we feel very pleased about at 10.2%. At 8.4%, as better the figure we were barely returning our cost of capital. We've at least started being a positive return entity relative to cost of capital at 10.2%. We are hopeful that this is headed in the right direction. So trajectory seems to be good. And obviously, a lot of that was driven by credit, by the credit, the same period is down at 1.9% from 2.9%, was obviously a significant contributor.</p>
          <p>By line of business, so our Institutional Banking business really had a very strong year, very good year. Our total revenues were up 11% for the Institutional Banking business. Profits are up 40%. And if you really look at the underlying nature of the business, it is very broad-based, so we have growth across the customer segments. When we talk about customer segments in this business, we think of them as the large corporates, the middle tier and the small SME space, and our growth is pretty consistent across. And frankly, some of the growth in the SME and the mid-caps outstripped the growth in the large corporates, which is consistent with the direction that we are trying to take the bank in terms of strategy.</p>
          <p>In terms of country breakdown as well, we had very consistent growth across our country, and then particularly growth in Taiwan, in China, in India was very, very robust. Growth in Singapore was extremely rewarding. We grew market share substantially, as you can see, from 20.3% to 22.5%. Now, over two percentage points of market share growth in the business loan segment is actually quite extraordinary. And so between Singapore and our core markets, growth was broad spread &#x2013; across the customer segments, growth was fairly broad spread.</p>
          <p>The treasury and markets, apart from loan growth which was good, as you know, our loan growth was substantial in the overall district. The cross-sell with treasury and markets was very pleasing. As you know, early in the year, we spent a lot of time trying to build the connectivity between the markets business and the corporate business, and that's paid off quite nicely.</p>
          <p>We have seen the impact of this, again, across all our countries. So we've had very strong movements in the cross-sell in Hong Kong, in China, in Taiwan, in India, in Singapore. So it's not just uni-dimensional; it's across the board and it kicked in very nicely. Our GTS business, which is another part of institutional bank, did extremely well too. Our deposit growth was strong. As you notice in the fourth quarter, our margins were protected in large measure because our cost of deposit funding was lower. Some of that is reflected in our CASA growth and much of that is because we're beginning to gain momentum in the GTS business, that was too through the year.</p>
          <p>And our trade finance business is very good, particularly, in Greater China, where the RMB opening gave us a great opportunity to build a trade finance position. We took full benefit of that, so that allowed us to drive a strong GTS performance as well.</p>
          <p>In the consumer space, things are more challenging, because clearly the biggest pressure from the interest rate environment comes in our consumer spaces. As pointed out before, SGD 50 billion of surpluses really are consumer generated. On a through-cycle basis, those surpluses are very valuable to us. In the lower end of the interest rate cycle, they put pressure on all our consumer performance. So the fact that we were able to grow revenues 3% in the face of a lot of downward pressure on those returns, on those surplus deposits is actually not bad at all.</p>
          <p>Our net profit is down 20% and that really reflects a couple of things. One, the payments we made out for the Constellation Notes program we passed on to the business, which had to be done in a full way. But second, we also continued to invest in growing our footprint. The branches we opened in India, branching in China, the expansion of the network around the region, those are &#x2013; and frankly, in upping our service levels quite substantially. We added to the network substantially in Singapore, added a number of ATMs, branch <mark type="inaudible" />, filled up our staff positions in Singapore. So, all of that resulted in an expense drag, which does not show up in compensated increases on the revenue line, because of the interest rate situation.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, there is some very positive momentum in underlying drivers. We had very healthy asset growth in both Singapore and Hong Kong, and frankly, we gained market share across every category in Sing dollars. Through the year, our mortgages are up in market share, so as cards, so as unsecured, and that is true in Hong Kong as well, unsecured in Hong Kong, and assets in Hong Kong up as well.</p>
          <p>Second, our wealth business really picked up traction in the second half of the year. The first half was slow, partly the environment, but partly of our own making. As we mentioned earlier, we were very concerned about making sure that we had very robust sales processes. We do not want to stub our toes again as we did through the crisis. So we took our time and we actually held back for a quarter or two, just to make sure that we were really comfortable about our sales processes.</p>
          <p>But in the fourth quarter, in particular, the processes and the sales process kicked in quite nicely. Sok Hui told you the numbers. Our unit trust sales were up some 80%, 90% in the quarter. Our bancassurance is up 30%, 40%, and again broad spread. In both of our principle consumer markets, which is in Hong Kong and Singapore, but also we need to show traction in some of our other markets, where we have branch presence and footprint, like Taiwan and Indonesia.</p>
          <p>Our service levels and innovation, the other big thing we're quite pleased about in the consumer business. We really moved the needle substantially on what we call the big six. Our queue times, as best as we can, are down to about half. For the last second half of the year, we met our 15 minutes queue time hurdle 80% of the times, which is a substantial move up from where our branch queue times used to be. Our ATM up times reflect that. Our call centre metrics reflect that. So we're quite pleased about the movements we made in terms of the overall service proposition.</p>
          <p>Moving to treasury, Sok Hui made this point, I do want to underline this. This is the third piece I'm very pleased about. From time-to-time, people have questioned the preponderance of the T&amp;M, treasury and markets revenues in our total revenue mix. First of all, we've always maintained and &#x2013; saw and Sok Hui disclosed it as we have tried to pull it out to make it clear to you at this point, that our revenues are actually fairly broad. Our prop trading revenues are not very large, notwithstanding the fact that they're all called trading income or trading revenues.</p>
          <p>But this year, we actually made substantial progress in further de-risking the business. And we did a couple of things. One, as you can see, we focused very hard on the customer flow revenues. And 48% growth in that revenue base was a very material driver of our total performance this year. Again, I mentioned to you before, it's broad-based. It's in the corporate space. It's in the consumer space. It's in multiple markets, multiple countries, so I feel good about the texture of that customer revenue base. It is a good solid annuity base. Momentum is good and we think we have a lot more room to grow. We can continue to grow that customer revenue in the trading space quite nicely over the next couple of years.</p>
          <p>Another thing we did is we brought a lot more science and method to our whole balance sheet management process. I mentioned last quarter we created a corporate treasury function early in the year. That corporate treasury function has been instrumental in a more professional capital and balance sheet management activity.</p>
          <p>In the balance sheet management space, we have a lot more method, if you will, in terms of usage of our surpluses. And so we have much better clarity on what amount of the surplus you put into which asset bucket, what tenures, what asset ties, what levels of relation. Broadly, we have a lot confident about the fact that our total T&amp;M business as a consequence is relatively de-risked from where it used to be.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the nine priorities. The nine priorities, these are the ones I laid out a year ago, so I'm just going to take you through each of those. In terms of Singapore, as we mentioned before, we feel very good. We gained market share. Now, as I mentioned before, Sing dollar loans has been our Achilles' heel, because we held these big SGD 50 billion of Sing dollar surplus deposits, so if you can't deploy it meaningfully into Singapore dollar loans, then we will continue to be interest rate vulnerable.</p>
          <p>To reduce the interest rate vulnerability in our book, we have to grow our Sing dollar loan portfolio. We want to do it without compromising on pricing and which is why we've been trying to do &#x2013; use different tools. Distribution and duration are the two tools we are using to try and improve our position, so we are not having to give up on loan yield as we do this.</p>
          <p>As you can see, Sing dollar mortgage, Sing dollar auto, Sing dollar car, Sing dollar business, we grew market share in every category this year. In several of these categories, this is the first time in a decade that we've been able to grow market share, so we feel particularly good about that.</p>
          <p>We piloted our new retail operating model. I told you we're trying to see how we can convert our retail network in Singapore from purely a service distribution channel to a sales and service distribution channel. So we have chosen 12 branches. We launched the pilot in the fourth quarter. It's early days yet. It will take us a couple of quarters in this year to really make sure that we're getting the benefits, the lift that we expect from this new model in these branches. Once we are satisfied that we are getting the lift, then we will take this and roll it out, the rest of the system. We've made significant upgrades to our customer experience through our network enhancement. I mentioned that. I won't go into it again.</p>
          <p>We maintained leadership in the capital market space. You know, we are not a bulge bracket investment bank from a regional context, but we feel very pleased about, a) the position we have in Singapore. We just &#x2013; and I should say, we were in every deal that mattered in Singapore in the last year. We did all the big IPOs. We were in all the rights issues. We were in everything in leads. We have dominant market share whether Sing dollar bonds, whether the equity space, whether the IPO space, whether the REIT space, and our market share position in gains last year were substantial, relative to previous years. So I feel particularly good about that.</p>
          <p>We said we focused on trying to improve our payments position in Singapore. I think we moved the needle substantially. We have 225,000 new users on our mobile banking application. It still continues to be one of the top three or top five iPhone applications in Singapore last I saw. We continue to get very good feedback on that. What's more impressive is people like using it, not just for inquiries, but for payments, and that's very encouraging.</p>
          <p>And finally, we made the first steps towards carving out our Singapore organization and separating that from our group management structure. Early days, more work to do. What do we need to do this year? Again, continuing to build Sing dollar, the Singapore position is still a priority. Our Sing dollar market share priority doesn't change. We need to continue to work on that. We think there's still more room for us to grow. If we can get the benefit of the new operating model in the branches and we can actually make that happen and drive it out in the second half of the year as we're hoping to, then that should help our whole asset gathering capacity even more than we've been able to see in the past year.</p>
          <p>The second big thing we have to do in Singapore is really breakdown our country management model. We've been slow deliberately, because it's a big change for us. And so for the first three, four months, we've been easing our way into the process. We expect to make more progress this year, so we start pulling the Singapore country organization together in a meaningful way, so that begins to mirror the way we manage each of our other country organizations.</p>
          <p>In terms of Hong Kong, we really strengthened our management team. We feel good about that. We have a much stronger management team in place. I have joined the Hong Kong Board, as has Peter Seah as Chairman. As I sit in at the board meetings and I go across the country, because I feel that as a management team it gets together and has its hand and grip around the country business. We made substantial progress this year.</p>
          <p>We improved our position in the red chip space. If you remember, we're doing a strategy that's trying to build out a Hong Kong franchise on the back of the China customer flow is a big part of our strategy. We really did well with that. We more than doubled our customer base in that segment. We've 80% growth in our asset book in that segment. Our revenues are up almost 200% in that segment, the China red chips into Hong Kong. We feel very good about that.</p>
          <p>We also feel very good about the progress we made in the renminbi space. The renminbi opening up was a surprise. And nobody called it. Nobody knew it would open up as rapidly as it did. From the June/July announcement and the August one, the changes in October, we feel very good that we stayed ahead of the curve. Through the entire second part of the year we were quick, we reacted to the changes very quickly, and that allowed us to produce customer products as well as market share positions, which were leadership positions.</p>
          <p>Even today, we have about 20% market share of the renminbi dollar interbank market in Hong Kong. We continue to have substantial double-digit market share of the customer flows. We have close to 5% share of the renminbi deposits in the system, of the trade assets in the system, so we continue to maintain a leadership position in the renminbi space. We offered a lot of &#x2013; at the end of the year, we had about SGD 10 billion in deposits. We have opened almost 2000 all-renminbi corporate accounts. We were the first to offer CMH yield enhancement deposit. We were the first to compete the dollar-renminbi FX swap and a cross-currency swap, so clearly continue to lead in the space.</p>
          <p>I personally believe that this internationalization of the renminbi will be one of the defining things in our generation over the next five, 10 years in the Asian marketplace, so to retain a position in that is frankly exciting and important to us.</p>
          <p>The third piece, I told you earlier that we want to do is segment our consumer base better and make sure we are marketing the right products to the right customer base. We made good progress with that and that reflect in the strong momentum we have with the unsecured loans, our investments and insurance sales. All of that went up nicely, and particularly in the second half of the year, as the efforts of our segmentation began to bear fruit.</p>
          <p>In terms of where we are headed, this year there's three or four things we really want to do. With the new team, we have started trying to drive a far more granular strategy for Greater China as a whole, China, Hong Kong, how we make this thing work. So we're trying to drill the strategy down to the next level of detail. We hope to have that done over the next three, four months, and that should allow us to be more leader-focused around which customer segments, which blocks of business do we want to drive in that whole Greater China space.</p>
          <p>We want to continue to maintain our leadership in the renminbi space. We think we have good opportunity. As you know, a couple of days ago we announced a range of renminbi products in Singapore as well. By the end of this month, we will have the broadest renminbi offering in Singapore. We are doing that partly &#x2013; developed in Singapore partly leveraging our Hong Kong footprint and work we have. Between Hong Kong and Singapore, we hope to have the most exciting offshore renminbi capability.</p>
          <p>And develop funding plan, as you saw, I mentioned earlier in the year, we took out impairment for Hong Kong. The funding situation in Hong Kong has been challenging this year. It has been compounded relative to any other market because of the presence of the Chinese banks in Hong Kong, which has had an impact both on the fund on the deposit side of the business as well as on the lending asset side of the business.</p>
          <p>Our NIMs in Hong Kong, if you see over year-on-year, came down 32 basis points. They're substantially higher than the company. The company NIMs are down 18 basis points, so Hong Kong is obviously more stressed. Developing a robust funding plan for Hong Kong is something we've been working on over the last three or four months. It is something that we will continue to work on in the first half of next year, something that's going to engage us this year as well.</p>
          <p>Moving on from Hong Kong, if you look at the other countries, again in terms of rebalancing the geographic mix of our businesses, as we have maintained before, our principal thrust is organic growth. We will invest in these four markets. We will continue to invest and grow in them and the truth is we are having extremely good momentum.</p>
          <p>In China, our big focus this year, if you remember, was to get the loan deposit ratio right. Because of the regulatory requirements, everybody is expected to come down to a 75% loan deposit ratio this year. We began the year and double that &#x2013; close to 150% &#x2013; and we made really substantial move. So we're well on the way to achieving our targets on LDRs this year &#x2013; double that deposit base, with the lenders focus. Our loans grew 34% at the same time.</p>
          <p>We also had very strong cross-sales momentum. I told you our Treasury momentum extended to China. We also had strong momentum in GTS this year in China. And the RBS integration that we announced in December is actually proceeding on track. I'll talk about it in a minute again.</p>
          <p>In Taiwan, we've turned around the franchise a year ahead of plan. I indicated that to you earlier in the year. That's moving extremely well. Our revenues are up 23% for the year, loans up 40%, deposits &#x2013; 39%, deposits up 38%. Our customer base is expanding very nicely. So we grew almost 10,000 affluent customers through the year. We also had substantial growth in the corporate customer space.</p>
          <p>As we go forward, our big challenge in China, first challenge, we want to integrate the RBS transaction, RBS we have integrated well. We feel good that we're improving our integration capabilities. What we did with the Bowa Bank and how we were able to take it and bring it and fold it into our business in Taiwan was a precursor to what we think is core capability that we're building.</p>
          <p>We think we can repeat that with RBS. It's not a big trade, it's small, but if we do it right, we have the opportunity to add SGD 1 billion in deposits, to add 30,000 customers. This is a trade which allows us for actually no cost to us a roughly two to three year head start over what it would have taken us to build that same footprint organically.</p>
          <p>So integrating it and getting the leverage from that is an important agenda item for us in the first half of this year. We will also continue to focus on brand expansion. We hope to be able to grow another eight or &#x2013; branches in China in the course of this year. So if we can do that, that will be very nice.</p>
          <p>In Taiwan, our big agenda item this year is we want to switch from branch to subsidiary. As you know, we're a subsidiary in China, we're a subsidiary in Hong Kong, we're a subsidiary in Indonesia. We're a branch presence in India and in Taiwan. We will switch to a subsidiary in Taiwan this year. We will pump in the required amount of capital. That will allow us, hopefully, to start scaling up our business even quicker than we've been able to so far. It will obviously take some effort, so that will be a large part of what will engage us in Taiwan in the first half or the first three quarters of this year.</p>
          <p>As we move on in India, again we grew our corporate <mark type="inaudible" /> business 22% year on year. I have mentioned to you, if you look at the last four, five years, our Indian business, the corporate business has been our fastest growing business. It continues to grow very nicely and we continue to diversify our revenue streams.</p>
          <p>We're building a rupee book, so we're not just a dollar book; that's working very nicely. We increased our cash mandates by 30% in the year. We grew 78% in our trade volumes, so good momentum. We're quite proud about the awards, the only awards which I put down in this thing. We were once again awarded the best small bank, best small bank, it's first of all not foreign bank, it's all small banks. If I remember right, it is all banks up to Rs. 10,000 crores in assets &#x2013; so I mean small is middle in size; we're not really that small &#x2013; in the faster growing small banks, so we feel good that our position is in good shape. We added two more branches in the last quarter; we opened up Kolhapur and Cuddalore. So we're now up to 12, so proceeding nicely.</p>
          <p>Indonesia, Indonesia, frankly, was our most challenging franchise in the first half of the year, I indicated that. We worked hard and struggled with it for three months or for three quarters. I feel good about where we ended up the year. Fourth quarter traction in Indonesia finally was very strong. The business turned around across all dimensions, every segment turned around. We started making progress and rolling out our SME strategy in Indonesia. We had good solid loan growth. We've now developed a good capital markets pipeline and we also had good growth in wealth management sales. So fourth quarter in Indonesia, a substantial improvement, traction is looking good.</p>
          <p>Where do we go for this year? In India, the RBI came out with these guidelines on subsidization. They were asking for a commentary back in the next two, three months. The guidelines look positive and interesting. There are a couple of question marks which we have to wrestle with and engage with the regulators on.</p>
          <p>But if things go well and the guidelines and a couple of questions are addressed to our satisfaction, then like Taiwan, our bias is to subsidiarize in India as well. And if we do that then that should allow us the capacity to start branching aggressively in India, which is something that we will seek to do. It continues to be an important part of our strategic agenda.</p>
          <p>In Indonesia, like I said, I'm pleased our fourth quarter allowed us to get good traction and momentum. So our biggest agenda this year is to take that and start building on the back of that. As you know, in Indonesia, we have a 40 branch network. We grew the network in the last couple of years.</p>
          <p>Frankly, the network is not paying for itself, which is one of our challenges. Our progress in the fourth quarter is we've got the model right now, so we're going to start putting our foot on the pedal to start getting that network to start delivering the returns that it should be delivering.</p>
          <p>Outside of that, in terms of reasonable SME <mark type="inaudible" /> hired the team like I said. We've got most of the people in place, in the fourth quarter, we started doing some good work on building the SME model that we want. As I told you before, we want to do not just incremental expansion; we want to do an exponential growth in the SME space.</p>
          <p>And to get exponential growth, you just got to rethink the way you want to do the business substantially. We are about halfway down the process. It will take us a few more months to actually bed down the process entirely. And so this year, we need to finalize that in the first half of the year and really go to market effectively in the second half of the year. We really think that there is a big opportunity for us if we get this one right.</p>
          <p>It's actually pretty parallel to our position in the wealth space. Again, the same thing &#x2013; we've got the team, we've hired the people. We are halfway through developing a wealth model which is a differentiated wealth model which will allow us to compete effectively and scale up our business exponentially. Again, the intent is to try and finish and get that model done in the early part of this year and then take it to market in the second half of next year.</p>
          <p>In both SME and wealth, it's not as if we just &#x2013; you saw from our numbers, it's not as if we're just sort of biting our time getting the models done. As you saw from our numbers, we've also started reaping some of the low hanging fruit.</p>
          <p>When we get the right team in place, we start doing some of the right things. So we're beginning to get traction already both in the SME growth and in the wealth growth. But the exponential shift that we will hope to make to the big agenda items for this year.</p>
          <p>Finally, on GTS and T&amp;M. T&amp;M I spoke to you about the whole cross-sell thing. On GTS, like I said, as we go, again we invested in a lot of people, lot of talent, we have completely refurbished and strengthened this team which we brought on board in the first half of this year and the results started showing.</p>
          <p>So our GTS liabilities are up 23%. As you know, GTS liabilities are low cost deposits; cheaper than the fixed deposits and <mark type="inaudible" /> get otherwise, so that's very good. Our trade assets are up 54%. This is a high quality asset. It allows us to use our funding and it's high quality because it tends to be a self-regulating short-term asset, so that's good. It also comes with cross-sell because it comes with the fee business and it comes with the Treasury business attached to it; so we feel good about that. The renminbi settlement I told you about. We booked SGD 1.3 billion in trade assets in the second half of the year which we thought was very good. Opened about 12,000 new accounts for customers. Our internet banking platform is beginning to get traction as we focus hard on bringing our customers up to pace. We have about 80,000 corporate customers now who are using our platforms and linking in from over 100 countries. And so T&amp;M I talked about.</p>
          <p>What do you want to do, GTS? We really have to spend time this year completing the build out of our capabilities and that's their existence. We're going to revamp our whole internet offering and that should be in place in the second half of the year. It's going to be world class and it's going to be a substantial step up even from where we are today.</p>
          <p>We also need to continue automating and getting straight-through process &#x2013; processing across our end-to-end payment standards. We've focused hard on it, but with the application and introduction of some systems, which will happen by the middle of this year, we should be able to move that quite substantially forward. So the build-out of our cash capabilities across the region is a big agenda item.</p>
          <p>Our sales process, we have traditionally not been one of the best selling companies in terms of selling GTS products. So we've made effort and progress last year in building a sales team and linking it into the bankers. We will work hard on that and make that connectivity work even better this year.</p>
          <p>And on the Treasury market space, I think the cross-sell is important, but we're going to focus hard on getting broader distribution channels and particularly through our electronic FX platform, a range of electronic FX platforms, so that allows us to access both internal customer segments and end customers directly and more electronically.</p>
          <p>The last piece is on the customer experience. As I said, I think we've made progress. We improved &#x2013; we launched a process improvement methodology, which is sort of proprietary to us now. It is working really well. It has taken traction. It is being applied across the company in big pockets and small pockets and people are actively working on thinking about process and process change.</p>
          <p>I talked about the big things that we fixed. We've developed a service, a values-based service program which we will launch in the early part of this year. We identified the service value. We call it RED, which stands for Respectful, Easy and Dependable, so we're going to launch that in this part of the year.</p>
          <p>We also rolled out an MIS framework for managing regional and multi-country clients. So how do you manage, cross-region global relationships, multi-country, we didn't have something like that before. As you look out to this year, rolling out the service values program and continuous improvement will be a large part of our agenda, we'll continue doing that.</p>
          <p>One thing we didn't get around to last year which will be on our agenda this year is analytics. So we will drive much harder on building a customer analytics platform this year.</p>
          <p>Sales culture and sales processes, I think we're doing a good job in making sure we sell responsibly. We need to make sure we stay on top of that, but we want to also make sure that we bring the right sales practices and techniques across the organization so we will do that.</p>
          <p>And our service architecture for our corporate business. Our corporate business we don't have a standard service architecture there &#x2013; call centers, relationship associates, etcetera. So we've got to think through that and that's going to be on our agenda for this year.</p>
          <p>Finally, the last couple of ones on our regional management framework. This is stuff we did in the early part of the year. I spoke to you about it. We resolved our matrix management organization. We put in standard country management structures. We set up regional standardizing units for accounting and operations, for credit policy, for technology and so on.</p>
          <p>We created a corporate Treasury function to manage capital and return. We put in place a balanced score card which we manage all our businesses by now including the whole company and the Group. We aligned our incentives to the score card. We set up a talent management framework which we worked on. We set up a DBS Academy for training. But this is &#x2013; actually, it takes a long time, and frankly, we have a lot more to do on each of these dimensions, which we'll continue to work on this year. So drive process standardization, we're still nowhere where we need to be; we're going to do more of that.</p>
          <p>We're going to spend more time in terms of our risk architecture, risk appetite and risk models. Particularly as we go into the SME space, we must get this right because this is a core competency of having a great SME business. Our capital and balance sheet management with the whole Basel 3 set of guidelines and accompanying changes &#x2013; we've got to stay on top of that and stay ahead of that, so we will do that.</p>
          <p>Our talent management, we've started working on that. We have more way to go; so we will do that. And then this whole thing about a culture change, a culture of individual accountability and having fun as we work, we will continue to work on that.</p>
          <p>Finally, the last piece on technology, as I said, it's the ninth priority. As you know, we feel good. We developed a good technology blueprint last year. For every business, we have a three year roadmap, what applications, what functionality, when we will put it in, how we will put it in.</p>
          <p>We made good progress in the second half of the year in terms of rolling out many of those applications. So we now have a consistent core banking system in every market. We were able to roll that out in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>People from Infosys, who own Finacle, came to meet me a month ago and they said that in their experience, in their entire history, they've never seen any bank roll it out to as many markets as successfully and as stably as we were able to in the last six months. So that is actually something we feel good about.</p>
          <p>We created a new trade system which has allowed us to build a trading stream, and we put in place a wealth management system which has allowed us to focus on the wealth proposition. We worked hard on the resiliency of our technology, notwithstanding like I said the issues we had in the middle of the year.</p>
          <p>We actually made good progress in terms of improving our disaster recovery capabilities and our resiliency capabilities. And so as we think about next year, what do we need to do?</p>
          <p>We need to make progress on our strategic systems roadmap for Singapore and Hong Kong. So we have a broad outline, but like I said, every other country we now have on Finacle, Singapore and Hong Kong, we don't, so we've got to think our way through how we're going to handle the Singapore and Hong Kong thing. Actually we have thought our way through it; we're going to start executing that.</p>
          <p>We need to complete targeted applications roll-out. As I said, I mentioned the applications in cash management, but we also have several critical application roll-outs this year which will make a big difference to standardizing us and getting product capability.</p>
          <p>We need to complete our resiliency plan. We told you they were two year programs. We're half way through it; so we have one more year of finishing our resiliency program. And we need to start gaining more traction on the innovation efforts. We made some progress. This year, we're going to work very hard in making sure that we can be reasonably cutting edge in some innovation fields.</p>
          <p>So if we can get all of these &#x2013; as I say, our agenda for this year therefore is not too much different, and that's how it should be because our priorities are consistent. We see these priorities as priorities that will take us two or three years to get into place to achieve progress on.</p>
          <p>And so to a large extent, we're going to continue to build on what we did last year. I've given you a sense for areas where we didn't do last year, but we will focus on going forward and areas where we hope to get the benefits of the momentum we built up last year as well.</p>
          <p>So that should give you a good sense for where we are in the business now and where we hope to take the business in the course of 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Piyush. We have about 10 to 15 minutes or so for questions and answers. So could I have the first question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sam Holmes from Dow Jones here. Just looking at your mortgage volumes here, 16% growth in 2010. If I'm not wrong, that's above what you were talking about at this time last year when you were talking about what you expected for that year. Just looking at the momentum, you still had a bit of momentum in the fourth quarter and that's even after the August housing measures. Given the somewhat punitive measures that we had earlier in January, could you just give us a bit of guidance about what volumes are going to do this year and what we've seen so far?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's early. So, it's too early to call. There's been a slowdown, but the slowdown also happens because of Lunar New Year, it happens every year. So, it's been kind of difficult for us to understand so far how much is the impact of the January guideline, and how much is the impact of the seasonality of the Lunar New Year.</p>
          <p>So, it'll take us a month or two to really start figuring out what the impact of the January measures is. Our own general sense of course volumes will come off. They did come off somewhat after the August numbers, and so we think these measures will have some impact and they will continue to come off.</p>
          <p>As a general rule, our observation after the August guideline, Sam, was that the top end of the market came off for a month or two and bounced back. The lower end of the market, as in the smaller value properties, came off and stayed off. So, if you assume that that's any guidance to what we might expect to see in this part as a consequence of that, you might see that, that the top end might continue to be robust &#x2013; the top end is driven by cash and liquidity. There's still a lot of liquidity, lot of demand, and lot of cash in the top end.</p>
          <p>One of the things &#x2013; so in general, we think momentum will slow somewhat in the macro market. One of the things, plus and a minus for us. As a general rule, our presence in the lower end of the market is much stronger than our presence in the top end of the market, right. So, when you have a slowdown in the lower end or in the top end, it hurts DBS because that's our market is slower.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, some of the changes in the rules make it a lot more possible for us to post the top end of the market in a risk acceptable manner because they reduced LTVs at the top end. And once you reduce LTVs at the top end, maybe you can actually start being more judicious about what you want to do in the top end of the market.</p>
          <p>As we build out our wealth proposition and as we marry that with a more judicious set of LTVs at the top end, we think we can actually start winning some share in the top end of the market that we've not done in the past, so <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>We think there will be some slowdown, but we think we have opportunity to grow in the upper segments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you think you'll match the 16%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have any...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think low-double digits is what...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Kevin, you had a question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Actually, this is regarding &#x2013; sorry, this is Kevin from Reuters. The question regards Danamon. I'm sure you know there's lots of speculation. So the question basically is this, has DBS spoken to Temasek about buying Danamon? Or has Temasek approached DBS directly or indirectly about buying over Danamon from Temasek?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Short answer is no, and I guess your answer especially for Reuters because Reuters keeps coming up with this every quarter, somebody in Reuters dreams this up again. So you've been asking me this question every quarter for the last four quarters. I've told you this every quarter for the last quarters. We have not talked to anybody. We have no conversation with anybody. Nobody has talked to us. There is no change. We saw this statement from the BI yesterday. Nobody has talked to BI. So this is all Reuters's driven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Top mark for persistence citing Kevin, yeah. All right, next question please. Go ahead, Gabriel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we get a sense of your relationship between IBM? Are you looking at diversifying your vendors? Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know we actually indicated that earlier. So frankly, this has nothing to do with the July slide. We, already as part of our technology, strategy and roadmap, built over the last 15 months, frankly even before I came, had build up a study to diversify our vendor concentration. So if you look at over the last two years, I don't have the slides here. But we've actually already diversified and have a much broader range of providers than we did. We don't have the kind of concentration with IBM that we used to even two years ago. And we can lead to a head down the path, that doesn't mean we're going to walk away from that. IBM is a good partner. We work well with them. They continue to manage our data center. They continue to provide us a lot of application support, but in terms of diversification and making sure we deal with the right partners, with the right application, with the right hardware, yes, that is part of our strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and, Gabriel, I think as Piyush mentioned earlier on, I think that was all put in place I think even before he joined back in '09, yes. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Can I just <mark type="inaudible" /> credit exposure in the Middle East and how does it affect IB Asia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, credit exposures in the Middle East are pretty stable. From what I told you, we recognize a lot of our problems in the Middle East earlier. We've done a complete review in the context of Egypt and the Middle East maneuver. And frankly, we don't see anything as a consequence of any of this unrest. Our exposure to Egypt is actually almost zero. It's inconsequential. And the rest of the exposures, we've done a review of all of our exposure and they seem to be pretty final and I don't see anything in there which should pop out and surprise us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I have a question. I don't quite understand in your regionalization, you said you plan subsidiarization in Taiwan and India. What's the difference between that and what you've got now or how does that help you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I was in Kyoto on last Sunday; meeting with all of the central bank governors from Asia and several from around the world, and interestingly, for our four-hour discussion, over an hour was on this one question, branches with the subsidiaries. So the real difference between that &#x2013; banks traditionally, international banks have often operated as branches, which means as a legal entity, you are an extension of your mother legal entity.</p>
          <p>So if you are DBS Singapore, we open a branch in Hong Kong, then there's really DBS Singapore legal entity operating in Hong Kong and the legal entity <mark type="inaudible" /> branch. What that means is that with single capital base, single ratings, then everybody deals with the mother irrespective of which location in the world they're dealing with.</p>
          <p>When you subsidiarize, you actually create a separate legal entity and the legal entity there has its own capital base, its own capital situation and so on and so forth, that tends to be locally incorporated. In the past, some regulators have been indifferent to whether they wanted multinational banks to operate as subsidiaries or operate as branches.</p>
          <p>In the consequence of the GFC, a lot of regulators are beginning to think it might be better to have subsidiaries because then you can ring-fence subsidiaries and regulators feel they might have better control over subsidiaries within their jurisdiction. So that's from the regulator standpoint. It's not a given, a lot of the debate we had in Kyoto was half of the central bankers thought it was a good idea, half thought it wasn't. But directionally, a lot of people in the global system are beginning to think that subsidiaries might be good to allow ring-fencing.</p>
          <p>From a bank standpoint, from our standpoint frankly, in terms of management contract, it really shouldn't matter whether you operate through a branch or a subsidiary. Operating from a subsidiary has some overhead to us because we got to have incremental governance processes. We got to have local boards everywhere where we have a subsidiary.</p>
          <p>The incremental cost becomes worthwhile if the locally incorporated subsidiary is given additional benefits of power. In most countries, if you subsidiarize, you do get advantages of distribution. So if you subsidiarize, they give you branching. And if they do that, then it becomes worth our while because the cost of governance is not huge. So we're quite happy to put on a local board and that allows us to get and start branching out more rapidly. That is potentially the case in India. So the rules they've introduced say that if you want to stay a branch, then they will stick to the limit of 12 branches for foreign banks in a year. But if you become a subsidiary, then they would give you branching equal to local banks which means that you can open an RTFC to six cities freely and tier one and two cities, you have to go to the Central Bank and get approvals exactly like the local banks have to do. So that opens up the game for you quite considerably.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And I think &#x2013; well, I think it's also in addition to what you said, it's a demonstration of our commitment in these various markets to kind of be there and stay there to grow in Taiwan and India.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we acquired it &#x2013; when you acquire a bank &#x2013; so DBS Singapore buys a bite into DBS Singapore effectively. So it's a branch and then you can...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>40 branches, 40 branches we have...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have 40 branches, but they are part of the mother. So now we can create a separate company and put it into the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is being done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> How hopeful are you that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm quite hopeful because I'd say there are a couple of things that are issued as discussion paper. They're expecting comments back by the end of the March in the discussion paper. The discussion paper is encouraging. There are two or three things in the discussion paper which are still unclear which we have to resolve and make sure we're comfortable with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, really the branch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't know what other people's plans are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think as far as the Singapore Bank goes I think with the CECA agreement, I think we went in very aggressively, and that's why we have 12 out of the 16 branch licenses that the CECA wants at Singapore Bank. Chris?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris Howells from MediaCorp. Two questions; first of all, expenses continued to go up on staff cost. I was wondered if you could give the guidance as to where you see expenses going? And secondly, as you mentioned, your RMB business growing strongly in Hong Kong, about SGD 10 billion in deposits, and you've recently rolled out deposits and products in Singapore. How do you see growth there in deposits and what are your ambitions there for RMB in Singapore?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Chris. So, on the first one, I've been giving guidance to the year that we are investing. We see these couple of years at least in investment mode and so we're adding head count and adding technology. I think there are a lot of things we needed to do to put in place. And so through the year, I said you should expect to see our cost-income ratios trend towards 45. In fact, the last quarter people wanted to know why they hadn't started seeing it yet because it's still close to 40, 41 and I said you haven't seen the full impact. You should start seeing it.</p>
          <p>That having been said, some of our fourth quarter expenses were one-timers. You've seen our brand campaign around the region. So, we actually took expenses related to the brand campaign in the fourth quarter. So, there is some one-timers in the fourth quarter. But directionally, we will continue investing and you would see that. Our head count is up substantially year-on-year.</p>
          <p>In terms of the renminbi thing, we are expanding &#x2013; we don't have a specific renminbi deposit or distant target because it's new. So, we're sort of &#x2013; it's surprising me everyday how fast the renminbi base in Hong Kong is growing. It's unclear to me how fast it kind of will grow in Singapore. I'm optimistic that it will grow fast. So, even in the three days since we introduced it, we started seeing very quick traction. We did over $5 million CLI product in the first day, right. And so again, it surprised me.</p>
          <p>I told my people you won't see anything for a couple of weeks and they came and said you are wrong. We've got deposit on day one. So, I'm bullish, but I haven't established a target because I really don't know how deep is deep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Peter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter Hoflich from The Asian Banker. At the start, you mentioned I guess one of your &#x2013; behind some of your expense rise was the organic regional expansion. I wonder if you could tell me &#x2013; I think that's summarized in points of two and three, but I wonder if you could tell me what's your most significant regional investment there. And then maybe going forward, I'd like to get that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, what happens people...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I also have a question about inorganic expansion and what your capacity...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, organic expansion, you got to figure out that the way, which is set up a branch, it's a simple rule of thumb. In an efficient function context, a branch should breakeven in let's say 18 months, good branches in good countries breakeven in 12, but 18 months, you should get break even. And you should get paid back in circa 30 to 36 months.</p>
          <p>What that means is that every time we set up a branch, you have a drag for at least two to two and a half years, so there's the cost of putting up branches. So as we build out a branch network, if we expand &#x2013; as I said, we want to try and get to 50 branches in China in the next two years. If the subsidization thing works out, well, we probably want to do the same thing in India in the next few years.</p>
          <p>Every time we set up a branch, it's not just the physical premises, the technology, but the people. You put in 20, 30 people into a branch and so that causes head count growth. So our biggest cost of this thing is the people. We put more people into our Taiwan branches; we put more people into our Indonesia branches. We're changing the texture of the branches, some pure service model to sales model. So, we're putting salespeople into the branches. All of that is part of the organic expansion investment that we make.</p>
          <p>The other piece is obviously technology. As we standardize our technology and roll it out, so I say we put Finacle into eight countries &#x2013; all the countries, so every time we take it and put it out into the country system, you revamp, you pull out all the old technology, put in a fresh technology, you test it, you wire up all the systems, link it and then putting a standard technology which is going to be then amortized for a period of time, but a lot of upfront costs should take while doing it. So that's another part of the expense.</p>
          <p>In terms of an organic expansion, we have &#x2013; we've built capacity in the sense of &#x2013; the real thing I mentioned before, to be able to do, I believe, is your underbelly must be strong, your prophecy must be standard and you must have standards which you set. So you know if you want to take on and doing on a deed, you know how to take it and run it in a systematic and standard way. And so we build capacity by the standardization we've been laying out, so it feels doing accounting, operations, technology, credit and so on. But as I indicated to you, it's long-term view, and we have a lot more to do this year in terms of making sure that our standards are robust and work well, in terms of being able to do that.</p>
          <p>I'm encouraged however that our ability to absorb pull up all this thing was great. So far, RBS is on track. So I think we're building expertise in terms of being able to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perhaps the last question. I think &#x2013; sorry, Syed, you had a question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Hong Kong business. I mean, obviously there was some progress in the last quarter. But this quarter, most of the analysts saying that that on the <mark type="inaudible" /> profits have actually declined 9% and quarter-on-quarter-on-quarter. And also, the NIM for our business had also declined. So, you're still carrying Hong Kong at over two times' book and the bank, group as a whole is about 1.3, 1.4, I don't know what it look like today after the earnings. But do you think there's a need to further write down on Hong Kong? And secondly, when do you think a clear strategy would come out on Hong Kong that really becomes a powerful engine for growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, first of all, just to answer, we don't think there's a need to impair Hong Kong. We do an impairment test every six months based on our projected cash flows and what we think of the business. And we just finished that test again. And we don't have any need to impair the Hong Kong asset. 9% as Sok Hui mentioned is currency adjusted. A lot of that is Hong Kong dollar to Sing dollar currency change.</p>
          <p>If you ex that, it's about flat. It's actually only minus 1%, if you ex the currency change. Also what we did is we pushed down a lot of the expenses we had to take for Constellation payout et cetera and for technology into the Hong Kong business in the fourth quarter. We had incurred them, but we haven't reflected them in the Hong Kong business.</p>
          <p>So some of it is actually noise, which is from internal group movements of this thing. So actually I feel actually very good with the momentum we already have in the Hong Kong business. But like I said, the China red-chip business and the RMB business and the consumer business. However, like I said, we're also trying to build out a more granular, more detailed strategy for the &#x2013; the final which customer segments, which lines of business, what do we really push and go. And we should have that in place in the next couple of quarters, in the first half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think we're running quite late, so perhaps one last question. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> and assuming that that is addressed, do you have an exact plan which talks about profitability of the three branches in three years...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the second part, no, we don't have an exact plan. Once you're clear about this, then we will create an exact plan for what is the right expansion strategy and expansion path. And in terms of the staff, it is just lack of clarity. So, for example, the dilution guideline, that's still not entirely clear in the thing. So, I had conversations with the Governor. We are fundamentally comfortable with that, we just need to establish things like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sorry Conrad, I think just a quick one. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We'll have to figure, it's part of that plan. Once we figure what we want to do, we'll put that out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. A quick one, of the SGD 39 billion of mortgages you have on your book, how much of this is Singapore?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, if we do remember, the Singapore mortgage number is about 25, I want to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Hong Kong?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Singapore is about 25, Taiwan is small, China is small, so 25 and 11 or 12. Do you remember Judy, the numbers? If I remember right, it's about 25 is in Singapore and about 12ish in Hong Kong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can double check and come back to you, Conrad, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you very much, everyone and sorry for the slightly abrupt ending, but it's been sort of overrun and we've got our Hong Kong Media Briefing lined up next. Thank you and Happy New Year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and again Happy New Year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>