<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1157280" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-05-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8657</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jeanette Wong, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Koh Boon Hwee, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Richard D. Stanley, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jeanette Wong</participant>
      <participant id="5">Richard Stanley</participant>
      <participant id="6">Chung Li Chu</participant>
      <participant id="7">Matthew Wilson</participant>
      <participant id="8">Maria Chan</participant>
      <participant id="9">Frank Wong Kwong Shing</participant>
      <participant id="10">Amy Yip</participant>
      <participant id="11">Koh Boon Hwee</participant>
      <participant id="12">TK Chan</participant>
      <participant id="13">Michael Chang</participant>
      <participant id="14">Koh boon Hwee</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>First quarter 2008 results presentation. Today is a very special day for us. We have Richard Stanley on board with us, his fourth day at work. And you will get to meet Richard later on, but to start off we'll have Jeanette Wong, our CFO to share with us highlights of DBS's first quarter results. Jeanette please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon ladies and gentlemen. Today I have our Chairman, Koh Boon Hwee; our new CEO, Richard Stanley; our COO, Frank Wong and as well as Amy Yip, our CEO from Hong Kong. And I think at the same time we also have TK Chan as well as Chung Li Chu in Hong Kong while hosting the Hong Kong media and analysts. So, welcome everyone to our results briefing.</p>
          <p>Let me start with some highlights in our first quarter performance before we take questions from the floor.  It was a steady performance in the first quarter despite continued volatility in financial markets. The $603 million we earned is 2% below a year ago, but is 8% better than the last quarter. Our net interest income was 9% higher than a year ago, reflecting strong loan and deposit growth over the past year. We managed to offset margin pressures and unfavorable interest rate trends to maintain net interest income at the previous quarter's level. Fee income was also higher than a year ago, rising 14%, but fee income did decline 7% from the previous quarter because of the slowdown in capital market activities in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Trading losses widened this quarter as it included the $86 million loss from Rosa, which we had mentioned in our fourth quarter results announcement. Under other income, we also had higher gains this quarter from the sale of investment securities, which included a 53 million gain from Visa IPO. We remained disciplined on expenses, which were flat from a year ago and just 1% higher than the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Provisions now from the previous quarter as the previous quarter had included provisions for our CDOs. Overall, our asset quality remains good. Our key ratios are steady, net interest margins fell 2 basis points to 2.09%.  We were able to offset the impact of lower interest rates by growing our assets and improving our assets and liability mix. Non-interest income contribution was little changed at 32% of total income. The decline in fee income from capital market activities and lower trading income was offset by higher gains from investment sales. Our effort to remain disciplined on costs also resulted in us maintaining our cost to income ratio at 42% and our ROE improved to 11.6% from 10.9% in the previous quarter. Our net interest income was maintained at the previous quarter's level of $1.06 billion despite lower interest margins.</p>
          <p>Sing dollar SIBOR fell from an average of 2.4% in the fourth quarter to 1.6% in the first quarter of 008.  This reduced our loan and Interbank asset yields.  By actively managing our deposit cost and achieving a better asset mix from loan growth, we were able to keep our Singapore interest margin stable from the previous quarter. In Hong Kong, our interest margins declined 13 basis points to 1.9%, loan yields fell more quickly than deposit cost.  While prime-Hibor spread were wider by 53 basis points from the fourth quarter, margins did not improve as there is a lag in the repricing of our fixed Hong Kong dollar deposits. We will continue to manage pressures from a low Sing dollar SIBOR, credit spreads are improving for new corporate loans, although the existing loan book may take a few quarters to be fully repriced. While there has been more competition in housing loans, our strategy to provide customers with prices that are fair, transparent and sustainable, have kept our mortgage use at a healthy level. Sustained loan growth also helped to improve the asset mix and offset margin pressures.</p>
          <p>Loan growth continued to be strong.  While this quarter's growth was broad-based across industries and regions, the strongest growth was in Singapore corporate borrowing. Housing loans also rose in both Singapore and Hong Kong in local currency terms. Growth rates for the various segments are as follows: Singapore housing loans, we were up 1% for the quarter and up 7% for the year; Singapore SME loans, we were 1% for the quarter and up 10% for the year; Hong Kong housing loans in local currency terms were up 4% for the quarter and up 1% for the year; and Hong Kong SME loans, again in local currency terms, were up 4% for the quarter and up 10% for the year. Corporate loans as a whole were up 14% for the quarter and up 43% for the year. We continued to see a healthy pipeline in loan demand from our customers.</p>
          <p>On fees, in the first quarter, capital market activities were subdued and demand for investment products are also softened due to uncertainties in the financial markets. Our stockbroking, investment banking and wealth management fees were lower by a combined 31% from the previous quarter.  This was partially offset by a 70% increase in loans indication fees. Trading results were affected by continued dislocations in credit markets.  Widening credit spreads, together with the previously announced losses from Rosa's liquidation had impacted our trading income. We are however, had trading gains in our foreign exchange and interest rate businesses as a result of favorable trading environment and increased customer activities in these areas.</p>
          <p>On the whole, our total not-interest income was still better than the previous quarter, because we were able to offset less favorable trading income with income from the sale of investment securities, which amounted to $211 million.</p>
          <p>Expenses were maintained at 2007's quarterly average of $655 million.  Compared to the previous quarter, staff cost rose 9% due to annual wage adjustments.  The increase in staff costs was offset by declines in other expenses, such as advertising and promotions. We will continue to watch our expenses carefully; we recognize potential headwinds if revenue slowdown from weaker economic growth in Asia, or if capital markets remain subdued, or if credit quality deteriorates. We will also have margin headwinds if interest rate levels remain low. We will continue to invest in our customer franchise and in our regional initiatives in Indonesia, Taiwan, India and China.  We expect to remain disciplined, and we'll look at increasing productivity in our core markets to fund our regional investments.</p>
          <p>Moving on to our Hong Kong operations. The figures on this slide incorporate a 4% appreciation of Singapore dollars against Hong Kong dollars over the previous quarter, and an 8% appreciation from a year ago. These numbers are all in Singapore dollars. Net interest income fell 10% from the previous quarter, because of exchange rate effects and lower margins, although Hong Kong also saw higher loan volumes. In local currency terms, loans rose 5% for the quarter and 12% for the year in Hong Kong. The growth was led by SME and corporate borrowings, while housing loans also rose this quarter. Non-interest income continues to drive earnings. Compared to the previous quarter.  Although we saw declines in stockbroking commissions and unit trust revenues, this was more than offset by increase in treasury product sales to SME and corporate customers and a gain from Visa IPO. 26 million of the group's 53 million gain from the Visa IPO was booked in Hong Kong.</p>
          <p>Expenses in Hong Kong was also carefully managed, as operating costs were lower than the previous quarter. Lower specific provisions also resulted in total provisions falling 30% from the previous quarter. This contributed to a 13% rise in net profit in Singapore dollar terms.</p>
          <p>A brief review of our asset quality and capital position. Our non-performing assets rose 2% from the previous quarter on an expanded asset base. But the NPL rate fell to 1% from 1.1% in the previous quarter.  NPL rates in most countries and businesses were either better than, or similar to the previous quarter. Our credit quality remains healthy and we do not detect any systemic weaknesses at the moment. 38% of our non-performing assets are still current on interest and principal repayments, but we had classified them as non-performing on a prudent basis. Our provision coverage continues to improve with the coverage ratio at 138% of non-performing assets from 135% in the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Let met now cover our provisions on our CDO portfolio. The total CDO portfolio fell to $1.44 billion, this is Singapore dollars, at end March from $1.5 billion at end December. The decline was due to currency movements and we had some repayment of non-ABS CDO. On our CDOs &#x2013; all our CDOs are still performing and we expect another repayment of about U.S. 50 million of the non-ABS CDO due in the fourth quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>We took a further provision charge of 20 million in the first quarter for the non-ABS portfolio, which increased the provision coverage of this portfolio to 6%.  Those in the trading portfolio do not require provisions, as their value our mark-to-market for P&amp;L. Total provisions for this quarter was 12 million because we had an 8 million write-back for the ABS portfolio.</p>
          <p>Coverage for the ABS portfolio is still at 90%. With total provisions amounting to 282 million for our CDO portfolio, we do not expect any further provision charges for CDOs to be significant in the coming quarters. We received regulatory approval to adopt Basel II Internal Ratings Approach for computing part of our regulatory capital requirements, starting January 1st 2008.</p>
          <p>The approved wholesale portfolios are on foundation IRB, and the approved retail portfolios are on advanced IRB. The adoption of IRBA has resulted in better alignment between capital requirements and risk in the approved loan portfolios. The overall result has been capital savings for corporate and housing loans, partially offset by capital charges for operational risk and certain trading instruments.</p>
          <p>Our overall risk-weighted assets have declined.  With lower RWA this quarter, our Tier-1 CAR has increased from 8.9% in the previous quarter to 9.2%. Our Tier-2 CAR fell from 4.5% in the previous quarter to 4.2%, as the amount of general provisions qualifying as Tier-2 capital is lower under Basel II. Under Basel II, expected losses from the IRB credit portfolios are deducted from general provisions first and the remaining provisions are then considered as Tier-2 capital.</p>
          <p>So Tier-2 CAR also fell because our U.S. dollars of debt is impacted by a weaker U.S. dollars against Sing dollars. Total CAR, however, will remain unchanged at 13.4% from the previous quarter. We are paying dividends of $0.20 per share this quarter. As in the previous quarter, this amount will be paid on a one-tier tax-exempt basis, which implies higher cash dividends to our shareholders. Based on yesterday's closing share price, DBS shares gave investors an annualized dividend yield of 3.9% and I will end our presentation here. Thank you and we'll take questions if you have any.</p>
          <p>Can I invite our Chairman, our CEO, COO, and Amy on to the table, and Karen will be moderating all Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We have a panel based in Singapore as you can see sitting before you, our Chairman, Koh Boon Hwee, our Vice Chairman, Frank Wong, our CEO, Richard Stanley, CFO Jeanette Wong and our CEO of Hong Kong Amy Yip. We also have our two colleagues in Hong Kong, Chung Li Chu, who is the CFO of DBS Hong Kong, and TK Chan, Deputy CEO of DBS Hong Kong. Before we kick off Q&amp;A proper, I would like to hand the floor over to our Chairman to say a few words here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good afternoon ladies and gentlemen.  It is my pleasure to introduce to you Mr. Richard Stanley, who is our new CEO. And that's the only preamble I have before we go into put Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, thank you Chairman. It's &#x2013; I just want to say hello to everybody. I don't think, I know most of the people in the room, although some I do.  I can't avoid the tie in the right hand side, but it's good to be back home in Singapore.  I am honored to have the chance to lead DBS.  We have a great team and we look forward to a bright future. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Richard. Thank you, Chairman. As we start the Q&amp;A, can I please ask that you introduce yourself and name the organization that you are from before you ask the question and perhaps we will start up with the first question in Singapore. Anyone try...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" />.  And my second question is to Mr. Stanley.  How do you expect to grow DBS's international business, especially business in China, where you have a large <mark type="Inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think on the first question, the outlook is challenging. I think the economic data around the world, you are almost as familiar with it as I am, but as Jeanette has indicated, we do see opportunities in spite of the interest rate environment. We believe that there are things that we can do to ensure that we mitigate the interest rate effects, which you have seen in our first quarter results. We also have managed our expenses relatively well, and in this environment we believe that DBS is financially strong and well capitalized to take advantage of some of the opportunities that represent itself as banks around the world find more difficulty, given their capital constraints.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me ask the second ques &#x2013; answer the second question. I've had four working days, so I don't have a very clear answer &#x2013; precise answer, but clearly we have a tremendous opportunity to build our business in some of the key markets in this region.  The long-term prospects are great.  China is important but so are India, Indonesia, Taiwan, the <mark type="Inaudible" /> integration is proceeding and so, over time, we &#x2013; obviously we will put a lot of focus on these markets in addition to continuing our performance in Singapore and Hong Kong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you. As you ask the question, can I please ask that you step forward to the microphone so that our colleagues in Hong Kong can also hear the question?  Patricia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Patricia from Dow Jones Newswires. Can you give an outlook on your growth in lending?  Do you expect it to slow down for the rest of the year? And second question is, can you explain a little bit more of the 50 million payments just going be done the fourth quarter related to the CDO portfolio? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on the growth and lending Jeanette?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our pipeline continues to remain healthy.  We actually had really exceptional growth last year of about 25%. We have been telling a lot of our investors as well as the press that that is really an exceptional year considering that under previous five years before that we've been seeing a lot of like single-digit type growth in the system. So, do we expect to continue to see 20 over percent growth?  I think a lot depends on housing for local over the next few quarters. But we ourselves don't expect a repetition of that 25%, but getting to single-digit I think would be a stretch given where our performance has been over the first quarter and on pipeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you Jeanette. I'd like to move over to Hong Kong right now. Question from Hong Kong.  Oh, sorry, the CDO question, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I had mentioned that we expect a repayment of US 50 million of the CDO, this is a non-ABS CDO, which maturity will be due in the fourth quarter and we expect that, fourth quarter '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Hong Kong, please, any questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> Looking ahead, will you foresee the momentum of growth will continue to be coming in from the non-interest income posit instead of interest income, and will you think that the net interest margin which is narrowing down for first quarter will continue to have some compression <mark type="Inaudible" />  And secondly, the question maybe to Mr. Richard Stanley, market as I guess is expecting, with you joining at DBS will quicken the pace of DBS investing in mainland banks, this you have good track record in explaining China market. So, I would like to elaborate a bit more after your closing your plan in exploring the opportunities both organically and inorganically in China? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeanette, perhaps you could take the first question.  For question on momentum of growth, were you referring to DBS Hong Kong or DBS Group Holdings in total?  The journalist from Apple Daily?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hong Kong is fair as with Group. The first question is on whether -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps you could do the Group question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The Group is more on interest income &#x2013; on interest income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So perhaps if you could answer the Group question first and then let Li Chu, hand it over to you to answer for DBS Hong Kong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will continue to grow both our net interest income as well as our non-interest income quarter-on-quarter. That's basically what we will expect, as opposed to one or the other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Li Chu, would you like to continue from that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think similar for the Group in Hong Kong we would expect to grow both lines of revenues. We do expect our non-interest income to continue to grow, based on our ability to generate products for our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Li Chu. Richard would you like the second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Second question &#x2013; main focus &#x2013; priority focus is on organic growth in our priority markets. Inorganic opportunities are in my mind opportunistic.  If opportunities come we'll explore but the primary focus is on building out DBS's organic performance in all the key markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Next question from Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, Matthew Wilson, Morgan Stanley. You seem to agree that the outlook's challenging and you point to provision coverage of 138% as being strong.  However, that's a tad misleading when your NPL ratio is only 1%, so if you look at it in terms of provisions to total loans, it's only 1.8%, the 25-year average was 3%, it's been as high sort of 7 or 6, and how quickly do you see line loss charges sort of reverting back to the main so you get a sort of stronger coverage level, and then can you apply that in to perhaps the pro-cyclical nature of Basel 2?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeanette, would you like to take that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll answer that. Basically, I would say that we pride ourselves for very strong credit risk management, and if you look at our loans and the NPL rates, and the kind of powerful activity with putting provisions, I would say we feel like this &#x2013; there is nothing systemic in the horizon that would cause us any worry for us to kind of grow our provisions. But we do recognize, though, that we have five years of very benign credit environment. So, we recognize that if you were to look forward, the kind of credit environment where you have single-digit basis point provisions every quarter may be less regular, and you may get to the double-digit type specific provisions every quarter. But even then, I don't think we have any room to worry, because our credit risk basically it's on top of most of our credit, our loans, and we look at everything on a portfolio basis as well. So, we've been very, very proactive with credit risk management on that basis...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And we also recognize the fact that risk Basel II, credit risk management, and capital &#x2013; capital management is going to be more challenging, because Basel II, it is very pro-cyclical.  Which means that every time you have risk ratings going lower or going down, you actually have higher risk-weighted assets, and therefore a higher capital requirement. So, Basel II is pro-cyclical, but it basically it just means that our capital buffer, well we will have to be on top of our capital buffer, and we have to be very proactive about looking at credit risk going forward. But that basically is part of what we call good risk management in the first place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Jeanette. A question from Hong Kong, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Maria from South China Morning Post. A question, just a follow-up about your net interest margin in Hong Kong.  We have seen a decline of net interest margin in Hong Kong and Jeanette has mentioned that part of the reason is because of the less effect of the repricing of the fixed deposits. But under the low interest rate environment this year, the year expected the banks. I mean in Hong Kong through, fees that are our net interest margin improving in the second quarter and the rest. And how, how about the net interest income, do we expect that there will, trends to our positive growth in the next quarter?  And the questions about the mainland business. Mr. Stanley just mentioned that the bank will grow the business organically and maybe, look for acquisition if best opportunities arise, but I mean based on organic growth, what is the plan of DBS, for this year, the expansion in mainland? Yesterday, Bank of East Asia said they already get approvals to launch the debit card in the mainland, which analysts expect that will be a great boost for their deposits.  How about DBS, and what DBS has done, regarding on these issue? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you Maria. Chu, would you like to take the first part of Maria's question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, in terms of the net interest margin for Hong Kong, as Jeanette had mentioned earlier, the Hong Kong interest rates and the U.S. dollar interest rates plunged significantly in the first quarter.  Even though our customer fixed deposit base is actually very short-term in tenure, the fixed deposits were not able to reprice at the same speed as they declined in the interest rates. However, we are seeing in March and in April, the ability of our fixed deposits to reprice at current low interest rates. So that will all go well for the net interest margin in the following quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chu. For the second part, relating to organic growth in Mainland China, can I direct that to Frank?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah Maria, the &#x2013; we're going to have about ten branches by the end of the year in China. We look to open more sub-branches as we got to know the licenses to conduct local currency business with the local residents and that will help us to propel into different areas in the consumer banking business. Along with that expansion, therefore, we will try to grow our debit card business and hopefully credit cards as the licenses would permit so, over time. So I think as we expand in our consumer banking business, debit card business will be part of that as with deposits and any others.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Frank. Question from Singapore please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks very much.  Trevor Colswich from ABN AMRO. So I guess I've got about three questions, most of them are numbers questions. The first is on your net interest margins, specifically on the loan spread or at least the loan &#x2013; the loan yield. What surprised was the massive drop quarter-on-quarter in the loan yield and I was wondering if you can talk to me a little bit around where you think pricing is at this point of time? Are you are able to get better pricing?</p>
          <p>And why did you get this &#x2013; where did you see this massive drop, I think about 60 over basis points, quarter-on-quarter on the loan yield. So, that's on the margin side. Then my second question is on the investment gains side.  If you take out the very nice VISA gain, then investment gains are still very, very high compared to some of the, that's a recent experience.</p>
          <p>I guess my question would be to what extent are you are you going to be willing to support your earnings by a continuous high level of investment gains in the face of the current net interest income, let's say weakness?  And then my final question is on the CDO write-back.  That was a small amount, I think something like 8 million, if I remember correctly. Is this the first of ongoing and ever-increasing write-backs that we can expect? Or is this really a one-off sort of element? Those are my three questions. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Charles. I'll answer all three. I mean, on the last one, it is not a first of many, I think it was a just a one-time thing. So, and it's small. So, I would just look at that as small or one-time thing. On loan yields, I would say that one of the reasons why the loan yields look like it's dropped a lot, it's really because Sing interest rates and U.S. interest rates has dropped a lot and I don't think corporate spreads or the corporate loan spreads, could catch up with how fast loan yields, interest rates actually dropped over the past quarter.</p>
          <p>I mean in Singapore itself it's about 1%, in the U.S. it's about 1.5. So credit spreads will take a while for it to &#x2013; to work through all loans that gets repriced over time. But we expect that over the next couple of quarters, our team of relationship managers will continue to work and make sure that they improve the credit spreads on loans. So, we would expect that. On investment gains, I would say really if you take out the 53 million, I recognize it looks -- we still have a lot of investment gains as a result of all our investments. Now, you must realize that our loan deposit ratio is in the 70s. We are generally a net lender in the market, either in the interbank market or we are a net investor. So, it is not surprising for us to see investment gains, whether it's in debt securities or other forms of securities. That's very much part of our business in Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you Jeanette. Back to Hong Kong then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> from Asia Integration. Recently a bank has lost a personal data of their customer in Hong Kong.  What measures have your bank taken to protect the personal data of their customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Amy can I direct this question to you please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have very secure systems and processes in place to ensure the confidentiality of all our customers' data.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Singapore, next question. Matthew, one more from you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Last one, then.  A question for Richard.  Obviously, the face of DBS has changed a bit from when you were first appointed CEO to when you have come on board. I wonder if you could sort of give us a feel for how involved you were in the changes in the senior management composition in terms of replacements, and also obviously only four days into the job but do you foresee many more changes in the composition?  Because you've got a Rolodex of contacts you'd love to bring on board?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Matthew. First, one, I was aware of and fully endorsed the changes that have been made thus far.  A focus for me will be to work with the existing DBS team. I do not see a wholesale change as we have a great team and one of the things I intend to do is to work to make sure that our organizations optimize.  But we have a great pool of people, which we will work with.  In terms of people leaving, turnover's a fact of life in any, in corporate life. People leave, we wish them well, but we have others that replace and come in and bring in new blood, but again my focus is going to be on working with the existing great team at DBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Koh, a lot of the changes happened while you were acting in the Executive Chairman role, would you like to elaborate on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I echo what Richard said.  I think people coming and leaving in an organization is part and parcel of business life and while we regret people leaving, if that's to create opportunities and in this instance we have had ability to replace those positions internally and that provides us the opportunity to bring a younger group of people up into the leadership of the company, which I think in the long run is also positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Back to Hong Kong then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi this is from Cable TV. I would like the question to answer in Chinese if you can, too? [Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] that is the extensive of my Cantonese. Can my colleagues in Hong Kong, please help to translate that question? Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the question is what type of control measure we have for our customers' data in particular, with the recent loss of server in other bank, what type of control measure we have and in case we loss those data, what measures will we take?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, TK. Amy would you like to elaborate on that one again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign language].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and great Amy.  Okay, back to Singapore. Any questions from someone over the corner here, do you have a question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay. It's Michael Chang from Deutsche Bank. Just three questions if I may. First question relates to the trading losses, 161. How much of that was trading from the trading securities portfolio of the &#x2013; Rosa originate to corporate CDOs? Second question relates to just credit quality, the sense DBS seems to be conveying is that credit quality is still very benign areas of stress &#x2013; and minimal if any.  Do you see any areas of stress at all and if so, which particular areas?</p>
          <p>It seems that some of your peers are becoming a big cautious on the lending space.  And just last question, probably directed to Richard.  You said you are &#x2013; you have only been here for &#x2013; I think been in DBS officially for a few days. Yet you are quite adamant about the organic growth focus of the banks.  Could you just elaborate on your line of thinking on that front?  Do you see many opportunities for &#x2013; profit generation from the existing franchise, probably more so than you can get from any acquisition, or just trying to understand your line of thinking on that front?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you Michael.  Perhaps on the first question on trading losses. Frank, Can I direct that question to you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a very straightforward, easy answer.  Half of the number reported was due to Rosa, which was reported early on to the public. The other half due to sold the CDO trading portfolio, which we have gotten from Rosa for which we've hedged against with CDS, credit default swaps.  On the basis we will run quite a bit as one is the cash market, the other is a &#x2013; is a derivative. So, as this reflects the basis that the correlation hedge really didn't work as well as it should be.  But over time you should align yourself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Frank. On credit quality, Jeanette?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On credit quality, this quarter is about 13 basis points of our total loans. So, it is higher than what we had in the previous quarter. But it's true that, if you look &#x2013; you are to look at the average of '07, it really isn't anything to shout about or worry about. We recognized that, like I said earlier, when I answered Michael's question is &#x2013; we recognized that we are &#x2013; we had a relatively benign credit environment. We are always very watchful every year of potential, systemic areas or risks, in such an areas, but so far this &#x2013; the &#x2013; so far what we have not seeing are things that would worry us.  But we are keeping an eye, very much so, on our SME businesses to make sure that, if there is a downturn in the economy out here in Asia, none of them goes through unnecessary stress. So, we are always very watchful. This is very much part of our credit risk management process and our credit teams are very much interacting with customers as well as with our relationship managers to be on top of our credit risk overall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, Jeanette. The third part of the question I believe it's directed to you Rich.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Organic question. Your personal organic is very, very basic. Every day we'll come in, add clients, add people, train people, add products. In all the key markets, we have a very good footprint -- again I was very happy to see the breakthroughs recently in Taiwan and India expanding our network.  I think DBS has a &#x2013; already has a pretty good footprint in China and certainly in Indonesia. So, again, the focus of the management team has been and will be to continue to build this out; add clients in our core areas and that's a long-term gain.  I mean, it takes time to build an organic business, but we've started, we'll continue, we'll accelerate where we can. Inorganically, things come, and if something comes up we'll take a look at it but our strategy is not predicated on waiting for a deal &#x2013; another deal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, Rich. Back to Hong Kong then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, I am Lawrence Sid from NLBNC, now Businesses News Channel. I have the three questions about &#x2013; and the first one is about the CDOs. It seems that last time in the 2007 result press conference, DBS had an offer on the CDO at the reduction in the CDO is already in loss, but at this time in the first quarter there is a further reduction in the CDOs. Can you focus that there and, further, any further reductions in the CDOs in the next quarter or in the Rosa?  And second question is about the net interest income. The net interest income in Hong Kong has dropped at 10% year-on-year and focus that a net interest income will be dropped also in this year?  And the third question is about the mortgage rate. Some bank in Hong Kong announced plans to increase the mortgage rate in this year, and then any similar plan for the DBS in this year?  As we have the Cantonese channel and Mr. Frank &#x2013; Mrs. Frank Wong or Amy can answer the questions in Cantonese once more. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. The first question on CDOs, perhaps Jeanette you could take it and then Frank, perhaps you could help to translate into Cantonese. Yeah</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Sorry I can't answer in Cantonese. But basically, I mean the CDO reduction is a result of repayment, and there are going to repayments this year as well.  I have mentioned one, which is the U.S. $50 million repayment in the fourth quarter. So, you will expect to see some reduction in our CDO portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Frank could you make...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I just add a few words.  With our portfolio, we have a good dynamic portfolio in bonds and CDO. CDO is a small part of that. As when bundle it, we have unhedged and sold and restructure, we hedged many of them. So, we really have reduced significantly what would be deemed as CDO complex rates.  So, when you talk about credit ratings, really is a dynamic business and we do provide a lot hedging through the CDS, which is credit default swap indices and others. So, to answer your question, where there will more losses, where can more gain for that matter, the market moves by 20, 30, basis point a day. So, it's a trading business to some extent, this is not easy to predict.  Maybe I will switch to Cantonese very quickly.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, [Foreign Language], Frank.  TK and Chung, can Chung please take the question on the dropping net interest income and perhaps TK is the one on the mortgage rates in Hong Kong?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, maybe I'll use English first and then I'll do Cantonese.  As Chung has mentioned with the repricing of time deposit in future months, that would be a favorable factor and besides that, I think as Jeanette mentioned because it's quite a spread, improvement will take time and therefore as we improve our long mix and as well as the spread effect coming into the picture, then there is also an opportunity there.  But for in Hong Kong in particular, because the primary is already preloaded, savings depository are also preload, even if U.S. further reduce the primary, there is not a lot of opportunities in Hong Kong for a further reduction in that area. So, that sector will probably be neutral. [Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Chun, would you like to elaborate on that or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No I think TK has really explained it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>But we are also challenged, Cantonese-wise. Okay, but  sort of reaching 1:30, perhaps you could have one last question from the floor in Singapore, followed by one last question from Hong Kong.  Regrettably our panel members will have to leave right after the press conference. So, perhaps I would move to the other side of the room, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We have to run for our <mark type="inaudible" />, so I will be as quick as possible, but I have a got a list a questions, so please bear with me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, let me start from the top. So, the question is for Mr. Koh. Sir, when you announced Jack's resignation last year, you said you will be taking a more active role in management, which I guess you have been doing, but now that Richard is here, does that change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As of last Friday, Rich is the CEO of the Bank and I am back to non-Executive Chairman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. If you can also explain the process of appointment of some of the senior positions &#x2013; the Head of Consumer, Head of Treasury kind of positions, which fell vacant. Typically, you would allow a new CEO to form his own team.  You would also go through a process of finding out the best person available in the market. But in these cases we find internal promotion, which is good in a way. But, can you explain the process?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The process in DBS is a &#x2013; is a quite straightforward and simple. As I indicated, that when a position opens up we will try to look for the best candidate possible to fill that job. And that includes looking both externally as well as internally. Within DBS our philosophy is to continue to develop, train and provide opportunities to our people if they are competent and capable to broaden themselves. We were very fortunate in this instance that for both the Consumer Banking Head and of Head of our Trading and Markets area, we had very capable successors prepared.  All of these moves were discussed intensively between myself and Rich Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That takes us to &#x2013; to Richard I guess.  Well you have been here for a short time already you have been looking at DBS for a few months I guess. As of now and I mean it's probably premature for you to &#x2013; to elaborate on your strategy, but strengths and weaknesses and not that we have a great franchise, we have great team kind of stuff, but something with substance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a hard question to answer.  Four days on the job. We are in a fantastic region with tremendous long-terms prospects.  We have a strong base in Singapore and Hong Kong, the two core financial centers of Asia. We have some of the largest and fastest growing countries in China, India, and Indonesia in the neighborhood we were &#x2013; we already are there. We have a client base that is both emanating out of Singapore and Hong Kong and is being developed in the local markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Putting all that together, adding products and adding great people around the region, building the client base and just becoming more and more pan-Asia as we know, that's the strategy. In broad &#x2013; that's not going to change. That's the strategy before, that's the strategy today, I don't see it changing. Execution will be key.  And that's what I will be focused on the first 90 to 100 days, is putting the right structure in place to implement and further accelerate this strategy. To me, that's substance, I don't know if you agree, but that's I would call substance and hopefully, and I expect that over time, to really hit the bottom line and you'll see these markets grow as a percentage of DBS while Singapore and Hong Kong continue to grow as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, and weaknesses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Weaknesses, I think generally speaking, we probably need to, as we enter these markets we need to build our staff strength in the local markets.  We have again a great base  in Singapore and Hong Kong and we have a great team to start in China and the Indonesia, but like all banks in the region, local and foreign, we will need to continue to develop our people to be able to operate effectively in the local markets, within the local regulatory regions to bring products and customize them as appropriate to fit these markets.  And as I have said many times before and I say it today, that in financial services people is the biggest differentiator.  That may be &#x2013; to me that's substance as well and it's not different at DBS.  And I have my first staff meeting this morning with the Chairman and my colleagues and we gave some of the messages; and training and people development is going to be a key &#x2013; be key focus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you are saying there are some weaknesses amongst people and you would like change that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No &#x2013; no, that's not what I'm saying.  I am saying that in certain of the newer markets we need to expand upon and build upon what is already a good team and this is a challenge that is shared, I can tell you, from -- by all our competitors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Okay can we move back to Hong Kong then for the last question from Hong Kong? Well, you're still not done yet. How many more questions you have there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two or three, let's see...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>You are going to miss the OCD Briefing here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am trying to be as quick as possible yeah. I have something...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay all right yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Moving on to Frank and as briefly as possible. Could you please explain CDSs large position, the net position, and are you worried about the whole thing at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No &#x2013; No.  It's part of our business credit management.  Credit rating has become more dynamic. Our mode of our bonds is, CDOs bonds and rate it.  As such, when you don't feel comfortable you want to use the American IDEX  -- IX index to hedge some of it.  And the CDS is value-traded.  For example, investment banks can make a price, one big scrap, one billion, or either size for example. So, we use that to hedge of one portfolio.  Now as you noticed the &#x2013; the solid demand for liquidity here and therefore to CDS as a hedge against some of the bonds that we have, it goes up and down. So, the valuation depends on which that you do the evaluation &#x2013; happens to be March 31st, and so we bought those &#x2013; those differences between the hedges and a value of more derivatives and the cash bond. And that's what it's all about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And when does it run out?  I mean, are you building further positions on CDSs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, if it's &#x2013; is it's no bigger than the number -- it moves around, but the numbers that we've reported have been probably is about 300 million, that was on Jeanette's chart.  300 million Sing of bonds trading portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am talking about the credit default slots.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I couldn't hear you good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The 117 billion gross notional exposure.  That's in the annual report.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The notional exposures is just as what is &#x2013; what &#x2013; what we have on a bond, on the cash, and the notional value of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the make position would be how much?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Make position is moves around, it's none of concern to us at all actually, it's marginal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, my last question is...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I am sorry Jeanette, I think would like to elaborate...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me add something. I mean that at end '07 you quoted 117 billion, and our net exposure at that point in time was 3 billion.  But at end of March our total notional was 121 billion, but our net position then was half a billion, half a billion. So, I think like as Frank said, so CDSs are used to hedge some of our structured credit positions. Our guys also do trade CDSs.  One of the things people look at counter-party risk behind these CDSs, but I will say that 94% of all our CDSs are done with the top ten market makers of CDSs in the markets. So the lights of your shop, Morgan Stanley, Goldman, JPMorgan, Deutsche et cetera and all that, these are our counter- parties. So to a large extent, I think the use of CDS is going &#x2013; is very common among banks who are very active in trading credit. And we do keep an eye on our risk, and our counter-party risk, but that's very much part of our risk management now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank very much. My last question is for Chun in Hong Kong. Thank you. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I can hear you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. NPLs in Hong Kong have picked up lately.  Is it because of semi-exporters from China who are facing some difficulties or what is going on there and do you see further deterioration there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if you &#x2013; if I remember the NT, the net non-performing assets for Hong Kong between December and March, is fairly stable.  I think it's about 419 million Sing dollars.  In terms of the credit environment in Hong Kong, if you look at our &#x2013; our specific provision charges it has been, it's actually down quarter-on-quarter.  However we are really monitoring the portfolio of SMEs that we have and to make sure that our relationship managers do follow up on their customers and really pick the appropriate action as necessary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you're not seeing any deterioration as yet, especially your loans to SMEs in China?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's not going through to our P&amp;L at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chung.  And the last question from Hong Kong please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maria, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We have seen that the loan interest income in Hong Kong here rose, 44% year-on-year, but income compared with the last &#x2013; the fourth quarter actually, rose above 19%.  Do you expect this slower growth in the non-interest incomes will continue?  What is the driver for the earning of, I guess Hong Kong this year?  As we have seen, the first quarter, the stock market performed, quite significantly and people expected that the income will be a better.  Do you think such scenario will be carried on, for the rest of the years? And I just want to characterize about the profits.  For Hong Kong here, the pretest profit, a record in Sing dollar has fell 2%, year-on-year, but in Hong Kong dollar terms, I mean the net profit here has grown by 11%.  Is that the fell-off after profit in Sing dollars is mainly due to the currency exchange reason or are they other reason, cost to drop off the Hong Kong dollars, I mean the Hong Kong profits? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Chung, would you like to take those questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me answer the second question first.  The difference in the percentages between the Singapore dollar numbers and the Hong Kong dollars is entirely due to exchange rates. The numbers that you see are prepared on the same Singapore generally accepted accounting principles. In terms of the first question that Maria had, this was in relation to the non-interest income for the DBS Hong Kong. Yes, the DBS Hong Kong results were affected by the poorer investor sentiment. So, in terms of the sales of our wealth management products, our new trusts, similar to other banks in Hong Kong, we are seeing a decline. Fortunately, we have been able to look at other products to sell. For example, in the first quarter we did very well in terms of sales of premium deposits, which actually doubled in terms of volumes. So, I guess going forward, what we want to do is to make sure that we produce products that are suitable for the environment and simple for our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much. On that note, I'd like to bring this press conference to a close. We will see you back again on August the 7th.  That's when we have our next quarter's results. Thank you very much everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>