<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1199829" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-01-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>156</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Karen A. Fletcher, Vice President, DuPont Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Ellen J. Kullman, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Jeffrey L. Keefer, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">James C. Borel, Group Vice President</participant>
      <participant id="5">Kevin McCarthy</participant>
      <participant id="6">James Borel</participant>
      <participant id="7">Laurence Alexander</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jeffrey Keefer</participant>
      <participant id="9">Ellen Kullman</participant>
      <participant id="10">Robert Koort</participant>
      <participant id="11">Jeffrey Zekauskas</participant>
      <participant id="12">Karen Fletcher</participant>
      <participant id="13">Mark Gulley</participant>
      <participant id="14">Michael Judd</participant>
      <participant id="15">Sergey Vasnetsov</participant>
      <participant id="16">Chris Shaw</participant>
      <participant id="17">Frank Mitsch</participant>
      <participant id="18">Peter Jacobs</participant>
      <participant id="19">David Begleiter</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Chris, and I will be your conference operator today. At this time, I would like to welcome everyone to the DuPont 2008 Fourth Quarter Investor Call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. After the speakers' remarks, there will be a question-and-answer period. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>In the interest of time, management requests that you limit yourself to one question and one follow-up question, and please pick up your handset to allow optimal sound quality. If you have additional questions, you may reenter the queue. To listen to the webcast, please go to www.dupont.com. Thank you.</p>
          <p>It is now my pleasure to turn the floor over to your host, Karen Fletcher, Vice President of Investor Relations. Madam, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Chris. Good morning, and welcome. With me this morning are Ellen Kullman, CEO; Jeff Keefer, Chief Financial Officer; and Jim Borel, Group Vice President of DuPont's Production Agriculture businesses.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, I'd like to remind you that we're webcasting this call, and you can access it through our website, dupont.com. We'll be using slides today which are posted on the website along with the news release that was issued earlier today. I invite you to turn to slide two.</p>
          <p>During the course of this conference call, we'll make forward-looking statements. All statements that address expectations or projections about the future are forward-looking statements. Although they reflect our current expectations, these statements are not guarantees of future performance, but involve a number of risks and assumptions. We urge you to review DuPont's SEC filings for a discussion of some of the factors that could cause actual results to differ materially.</p>
          <p>We will also refer to non-GAAP measures and request that you please refer to the reconciliation to GAAP statements provided with our news release and on our website. And finally, we've posted supplemental information on our website that we hope is helpful to your understanding of our company's performance.</p>
          <p>Please note that in discussing segment performance, comments on results are before significant items, and all references we make to earnings are on a pre-tax, operating basis. In addition, all comparisons are on a previous year basis unless otherwise noted. We also provide considerable detail about segment performance on the DuPont's IR website.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll turn the call over to Ellen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Karen, and good morning, everyone. I'd like to begin my remarks by connecting back to the investor call we had on December 4. At that time, we outlined an aggressive set of actions to keep us ahead of rapidly declining market conditions. We established cash as our primary objective and intensified our actions to drive for cash, productivity and efficiency. We put in place ambitious metrics and rigorous monitoring and accountability requirements. I'm pleased with the rapid response and quantifiable results from our leadership and employees in these volatile times.</p>
          <p>We ended the year with a strong balance sheet and delivered solid cash performance against our year-end goals. Market conditions continue to be difficult. Many of our automotive OEM customers' plants that we supply remain idle. Customer destocking across multiple industries has carried over into 2009. Consumer confidence is down, and our market environments remain very challenged with the exception of agriculture.</p>
          <p>Most of our businesses are seeing volume declines in the first quarter on par with what we experienced in the fourth quarter. And when we review the business segments, we'll share our best perspective on continued volatile market conditions.</p>
          <p>This morning, we will update you on our aggressive action to drive for cash. I want to emphasize that we are working from a position of strength. We know we cannot afford to be complacent. We are moving into 2009 with urgency and a disciplined focus on execution of the fundamentals.</p>
          <p>We're also going to talk about opportunities starting with Ag where our outlook calls for continued growth. For the full-year 2008, our Ag &amp; Nutrition segment sales grew 16%, and earnings grew 24%. Ag market fundamentals remain strong. While some currency headwind is expected in 2009, we remain bullish about the growth opportunity for this segment.</p>
          <p>Beyond Ag, demand for photovoltaic products and Nomex aramid fibers remains strong. We continue to steadily invest in our R&amp;D pipeline, laying groundwork for growth opportunities to come. This along with our cost productivity work is positioning us well for the inevitable recovery in each one of our segments.</p>
          <p>At this point, I'm going to turn the call over to Jeff to go through financials. And after the segment reviews, I'll share perspectives on the year ahead. Jeff?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ellen, and good morning, everyone. The business environment remains very challenging and uncertain. We have moved very rapidly to adjust to the new external conditions. We are focused on cash generation and what we can control, cost reduction, tight capital expenditure control and working capital productivity.</p>
          <p>Our actions have traction. We exceeded our fixed cost objectives for 2008 and accelerated our efforts in the fourth quarter as the economic reality changed dramatically. Our free cash flow was in line with expectations, and net debt ended lower than our target. We enter 2009 with a strong balance sheet, excellent liquidity and a favorable cost of borrowing. Our actions and strong financial position will give us strength in 2009.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide three. Fourth quarter reported earnings per share was a loss of $0.70, including the finalized pre-tax restructuring charge of 500 &#x2013; $535 million or $0.42 a share. Excluding this significant item, earnings per share was a loss of $0.28 per share, in line with our guidance.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide four, and recapping the regional sales results compared to prior year. Worldwide sales of $5.8 billion were down 17%, reflecting the impact of the global downturn and unfavorable currency, which more than offset pricing gains.</p>
          <p>Full-year 2008 worldwide sales were $30.5 billion, an increase of 4%. 64% of sales were generated outside the United States. As we further diversified our geographic mix of businesses, emerging markets grew 13% in 2008, representing 29% of total sales, up two percentage points versus last year. We are well positioned in the right markets with the right science-based products when the markets eventually recover.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter sales in the U.S. were $1.9 billion, down 15%, reflecting 7% pricing gains and a 22% decline in volume. The volume decline reflects demand weakness and inventory destocking in many end markets, but notably, North American auto production was down about 28% and U.S. housing starts were down about 35%.</p>
          <p>While all segment volumes were down, Coatings &amp; Color Technologies and the Performance Materials platform were substantially down. All segments showed positive pricing performance as the Ag &amp; Nutrition segment led in percent gains year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, first quarter business conditions remain challenging, reflecting about a 40% decline in auto builds, and about a 30% decline in housing starts. On the positive side, first quarter will reflect a solid start to the North American production agricultural season, which Jim will discuss in a few minutes.</p>
          <p>Europe sales of $1.7 billion were down 20%. 5% pricing gains were more than offset by 6% unfavorable currency, and a broad base volume decline of 19%. The volume decline reflects the downturn in the auto, electronics and industrial end markets, in addition to timing differences in agricultural sales patterns.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead; we expect fourth quarter challenges to spill over into the first quarter across many end markets. Asia sales of $1.2 billion were down 16% versus last year same period. Volume declines of 20% and 2% portfolio change more than offset pricing gains of 6%. These results reflect softness in all end markets with the exception of Ag &amp; Nutrition segment, which was up moderately.</p>
          <p>The Electronic &amp; Communication Technologies segments' regional performance was most affected by the downturn in Asian demand, reflecting both demand declines as well as inventory drawdown. Our outlook assumes that the environment will continue to be challenging with limited visibility at least until after the Lunar New Year.</p>
          <p>Finally, Latin America sales of about $900 million were down 9%. Currency and volume headwinds more than offset 15% pricing gains. Sales were up for our Safety &amp; Protection segment, and our pricing momentum was strong in Ag &amp; Nutrition. However, the softness in auto end markets and seasonal patterns in Crop Protection markets more than offset the gains. The outlook will reflect currency headwinds and weak end markets excluding agriculture.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide five. While Karen and Jim will cover the segment fourth quarter summaries in a couple of minutes, I did want to highlight the successful year of the Ag &amp; Nutrition segment. For the full-year 2008, the teams delivered sales of $7.9 billion, an increase of 16%. The segment now represents 26% of consolidated 2008 sales.</p>
          <p>Looking now at the fourth quarter earnings per share variance analysis versus prior year on chart six. Pricing gains delivered in each region and in each segment contributed $0.44 per share. For the quarter, we fell short of covering variable cost increases, but for the year, we ended 2008 ahead $0.05 per share. This success locks in the fifth consecutive year of our local pricing gains. We will continue our pricing discipline in 2009.</p>
          <p>Moving to variable cost. Excluding the impacts of currency and volume, net variable cost increased $0.48 per share in the quarter, representing about a 15% increase in raw materials, energy and transportation costs, about as expected. As we look back to 2008, we estimate the full-year raw material, energy and transportation cost increase was about 14%, representing more than $2 billion in incremental cost. Given the huge run up in these costs, significant resources were deployed to variable cost reduction efforts in 2008. This delivered $400 million in savings during the year.</p>
          <p>As noted on December 4, our outlook for 2009 anticipates the cost of raw materials, energy and transportation, excluding the impact of currency and volume to decrease between four and 6% in 2009 with some potential upside possible. If you peel that estimate back, we are expecting a moderate increase for Ag &amp; Nutrition inputs, which partially offsets the larger decline expected for the remaining businesses.</p>
          <p>For the first quarter, we anticipate our raw material costs to remain high despite falling prices in the marketplace. This reflects primarily higher costs, still remaining in our inventories and to a lesser extent purchasing patterns, contracts and products mix shift toward the Ag &amp; Nutrition seasonally strong sales.</p>
          <p>We anticipate year-over-year raw material cost declines will begin to be realized by the second quarter. Rest assured we will use all the purchasing power we have, and this combined with our variable cost reduction efforts at our plant sites is expected to deliver $400 million in benefits during 2009.</p>
          <p>Volume decline was $0.55 per share headwind. It reflects the 20% decline in sales volumes as previously covered. Our outlook anticipates volumes excluding Ag &amp; Nutrition to be down at least to fourth quarter levels, as we expect inventory destocking and weak demand to spill over into the first quarter.</p>
          <p>The headwind related to low capacity utilization was $0.21 per share or about a $230 million charge. This is not increased spending; these are fixed manufacturing costs normally reflected in inventory that are expensed as production rates drop. This ensures our inventory values are not inflated. As a reminder, we idled over 100 of our facilities' production lines in the fourth quarter to aggressively manage inventory and cash.</p>
          <p>All other was a charge of $0.05 per share primarily reflecting the absence of proceeds from non-core asset sales in the fourth quarter 2007, offset by a $0.02 gain from pharmaceutical earnings. We expect pharmaceutical earnings to be about flat for 2009.</p>
          <p>Fixed cost was a net gain of $0.02 per share in the quarter. The cost improvement work to better align spending with demand is built upon the foundation of our productivity efforts put into place over the last several years. This puts us in a much better position to deliver on our goals. In the fourth quarter, we exceeded our goal to have 4,000 contractors off roll by year-end.</p>
          <p>Our fourth quarter SG&amp;A expense is down 7% versus the same period last year, with the general and administrative expense down over 20%.</p>
          <p>We continue to highly differentiate our R&amp;D spend. For the fourth quarter, Ag &amp; Nutrition, Safety &amp; Protection and Applied BioSciences investment in R&amp;D increased while the other platforms declined versus the same period last year.</p>
          <p>Total company spend is down 4%. In total for the fourth quarter, we delivered about $120 million in benefits from our fixed cost reduction programs with full-year benefits of about $425 million, surpassing our goal of $400 million.</p>
          <p>As described on December 4, we are taking aggressive actions to deliver $730 million in cost reduction programs in 2009, 130 million benefit from restructuring and 600 million productivity benefit. The non-cash charge associated with the pension remeasurement is expected to be at the low end of the previously stated range of 40 to $0.50 per share. The 2009 anticipated pension global cash contributions remains at about 300 million. On the preliminary balance sheet, the change in other liabilities primarily reflects the result from the year-end plan remeasurement.</p>
          <p>The tax effect for the quarter exceeded our forecast, ending at $0.09 per share benefit versus the same period last year. The benefit primarily results from geographic mix and one-time tax benefits. The benefit from geographic mix includes the effect of pre-tax losses in high tax rate jurisdictions, which had a cumulative tax benefit. Our tax rate assumption for 2009 continues to be about 26% versus full-year 2008 base rate of 20.4%. And finally, exchange losses amounted to a $0.07 charge versus last year same period and also exceeded our forecast, thereby offsetting the tax benefit.</p>
          <p>Turning now to cash and debt on slide seven. We generated $2.1 billion of free cash flow in the fourth quarter of 2008 and 1.1 billion of free cash flow for the year, which includes $2 billion reinvested in the company via capital expenditures. We paid $1.5 billion in dividend payments and ended the year with net debt at 5.9 billion, which is 9.6 billion in debt, net of 3.7 billion in cash and short-term investments.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet remains strong. We closed 2008 with minimal commercial paper outstanding. Our borrowing rates both on long and short-term debt continue to be low.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide eight and summarizing. 2009 is going to be a very challenging year. We expect weak economic conditions and continued volatility throughout the year. We are lowering our full year guidance to a range of $2 to $2.50 per share and setting first quarter guidance at a range of 50 to $0.70 per share.</p>
          <p>Lower guidance is based on our expectation of continued weak market conditions across a broad base of end markets excluding agriculture. Our 2009 cash priorities continue to be a $1 billion reduction in working capital, capital expenditure spend rate of 1.6 billion and maintaining our dividend and strong balance sheet. Our free cash flow target continues to be about $2.5 billion.</p>
          <p>I will conclude by reinforcing our focus is on cash generation and working on the factors we can control: cost reduction, working capital productivity and tight control of capital expenditures. We are committed to deliver gains in our Ag &amp; Nutrition segment. We have confidence in delivering against our goals because of the momentum we built in 2008. Our actions ensure we'll be even stronger when the environment improves.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to turn it over to Jim for the Ag segment update. Jim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff. Turning to slide nine, our Ag &amp; Nutrition sales for the quarter declined 2%, so $1.2 billion, and we incurred a seasonal pre-tax loss of $164 million. For the full-year 2008, however, even in light of global economic conditions and unfavorable currency impact later in the year, the performance delivered by our Ag segment was remarkable. We met our goal of delivering $8 billion in segment sales, and, as committed, we delivered over 20% earnings growth for the year.</p>
          <p>Let me break the segment down, starting first with Crop Protection products. Sales were down modestly in the quarter, primarily due to lower herbicide volumes. Despite favorable local pricing, earnings also declined substantially due to lower volume, higher raw material and energy costs, and the absence of a gain from an asset sale in the fourth quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>Let me share more specifics about the Crop Protection products volume, however. In the U.S. there was a drop off in pre-season purchases, as growers delayed ordering inputs and finalizing planning decisions due to the volatile commodity markets. Similarly, our European distributors remained cautious and delayed some of their purchases until the first quarter next year &#x2013; first quarter '09.</p>
          <p>Fungicide and insecticide supplies were tight, which also tempered volume. And in Latin America, volume declines due to the severe drought in Argentina and substantially lower herbicide sales were partially offset by <mark type="inaudible" /> pricing.</p>
          <p>So that gives you a picture for the last quarter for Crop Protection. But in the context of the full-year 2008, Crop Protection products had a banner year with record sales, including Rynaxypyr sales of over $50 million. That along with more favorable variable margins and productivity improvements in fixed cost and working capital drove substantially increased earnings and strong cash flow from operations.</p>
          <p>Moving to Seed, fourth quarter sales increased 11% led by strong local pricing in Brazil and North America, and by volume growth driven by increased shipments in the Southern U.S. This was partially offset by lower unit sales in Latin America and Europe.</p>
          <p>Let me be clear on Latin America; we had another impressive season of performance. Fundamentally, unit sales were down because planted acres were down. In addition, some Brazil corn sales did shift to Q3, but that was partially offset by increased soy sales in Q4.</p>
          <p>Overall, we are confident that we have gained both soy and corn market share in Brazil; in fact, 2008 is going to be the sixth consecutive year of share gains for both corn and soybeans in Brazil. We also expect to have gained corn market share in Argentina and in the important high value northwest market in Mexico.</p>
          <p>For the full-year 2008, Seed sales and earnings, both were up significantly. Gross profit increased in all regions. We met the $4 billion sales mark, led by strong local pricing and global volume growth, along with some help from currency. We're winning along with our customers, as we delivered record revenue and earnings, while also investing record amounts in R&amp;D, field sales operations and production capacity.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to 2009. Since planning intentions and the timing of the season, are as fluid as exchange rates and commodity prices, we'll be closely monitoring agricultural economics and customer plans, as well as competitive actions.</p>
          <p>But even with that, let me reaffirm our North America Seed price and market share commitment. We will gain share, and we will increase net price by solid double-digits. And we have this momentum in Europe as well, where we expect corn market share gains in both emerging and mature markets.</p>
          <p>Turning to the overall Ag &amp; Nutrition segment. Despite substantial currency headwinds we expect to deliver sales and earnings growth for the first half of 2009 that keeps us on track to deliver 15% compound annual earnings growth from '07 to 2010.</p>
          <p>Karen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jim. Please turn to slide 10. Coatings &amp; Color Technologies segment sales of $1.3 billion were down 21%. The pre-tax loss of $65 million reflects local lower volumes, including charges for low capacity utilization and rising raw material cost that were not fully offset by higher U.S. dollar selling prices.</p>
          <p>Titanium dioxide sales and earnings declined substantially, driven by a substantial volume decline in all but a few emerging markets. This reflects the global slowdown and pronounced global supply chain destocking in November and December.</p>
          <p>Demand was essentially flat in Eastern and Central Europe and India. Global volume continues to be pressured by very weak demand for architectural coatings and plastics markets, but was in part offset by sequential and year-over-year higher local selling prices. We are holding market share. In addition, we've seen selected customers increase their share of titanium dioxide purchases from DuPont, as we represent a stable committed supplier to the coatings, plastics and paper industries.</p>
          <p>Coatings sales and earnings also declined substantially due to an unprecedented volume decline in motor vehicle sales, resulting in lower paint sales to the OEMs. Just to put things in perspective, North America motor vehicle production was down 28% versus prior year quarter, and Western European motor vehicle production was down 27%.</p>
          <p>Refinished paint products volume dropped significantly, driven by supply chain destocking, particularly in North America. The stronger U.S. dollar and higher raw material costs more than offset higher local selling prices.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead to the first quarter for Coatings &amp; Color Technologies, we expect all markets to remain weak; global motor vehicle production levels to drop lower sequentially; global demand for titanium dioxide products to moderately increase sequentially, reflecting coating seasons in the Northern Hemisphere; and higher demand for refinished paint products as inventory levels have moderated.</p>
          <p>As a result, we expect substantially lower earnings versus prior year quarter with improvements sequentially. As we plan for significant volume and pricing pressures, our teams are focused on delivering productivity improvements in cost and capital.</p>
          <p>Please turn to slide 11 for Electronic &amp; Communication Technologies segment. Sales of $834 million were down 13% due to weakness in consumer electronics, automotives and industrial markets, offsetting strength in photovoltaics and pricing gains in fluoroproducts. Earnings of $9 million reflects broad-based market weakness, charges due to low capacity utilization, higher raw material costs and the absence of a land sale gain in fourth quarter '07.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the first quarter. We expect sequential and year-over-year volume declines, reflecting the global downturn and raw material, energy and transportation costs that are expected to flatten sequentially and trend down. The segment is confident it will meet aggressive fixed cost reduction targets and that these actions will contribute to partially offsetting volume declines.</p>
          <p>Please turn to slide 12 for Performance Materials. Sales of $1.2 billion were down 30% as weak demand drove down volume 32%, partially offset by higher U.S. dollar prices. The pre-tax loss of $129 million reflects lower volumes across all Performance Materials businesses, charges for low capacity utilization, weaker sales mix, product availability due to hurricane impact, and the impact of higher raw material costs that were not fully covered with higher U.S. dollar selling prices. As previously reported, part of the earnings decline is attributed to the shutdown of the neoprene production line in Louisville at the end of 2007.</p>
          <p>In total, volume declined about 32% for the quarter. I'd like to update you on our operations in Orange, Texas. If you recall, that site was significantly impacted by Hurricane Ike. After extensive repairs, three polymer units are now operating. The ethylene cracker unit is not operating, but we expect to recommission it during the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead to the first quarter, we expect lower demand for motor vehicle markets to continue with competitive pressures on both volume and price. We will continue to have supply limitations with our ethylene copolymers products due to rate limitations and product scheduling as our plant in Orange, Texas, comes back up to full operating capability.</p>
          <p>Performance Materials is aggressively taking costs out. As an example, over 60% of their contractor force was taken off roll by the end of 2008. In addition, they are actively reducing working capital through disciplined processes and the use of redeployed highly capable employees. First-quarter earnings are expected to be down substantially over prior year, primarily due to weak demand and continued downstream supply chain destocking, particularly outside the U.S.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 13 and looking at Safety &amp; Protection segment. Sales of $1.3 billion were down 10%. Pricing gains, particularly in aramid and chemical products were more than offset by lower demand as all businesses experienced the impact of the global economic slowdown and destocking that was taking place in the value chain.</p>
          <p>PTOI of $105 million reflects lower volume, charges for low capacity utilization and increased raw material prices, partially offset by higher U.S. dollar selling prices. The impact of the housing market is the largest contributor to the earnings decline. The segment is facing tough market conditions in housing as North America housing starts were down 32%, and we're still seeing inventory destocking as downstream participants de-leverage in response to credit tightness.</p>
          <p>Kevlar and Nomex product lines again delivered pricing gains. Nomex delivered volume growth primarily driven by electrical paper products. The new Nomex capacity line was commissioned in fourth quarter. Given the global economic slowdown, we intend to maintain our investment plans to increase Nomex and Kevlar capacity, but we'll slow down the pace a little to keep our spend rates in line with the new reality.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead to first quarter, we anticipate moderate sales and earnings declines for Safety &amp; Protection, as the housing market will continue to be weak during the quarter.</p>
          <p>That completes our segment review, and I'll now turn the call over to our CEO, Ellen Kullman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Karen. Last October as the pace of deterioration accelerated in key markets. We quickly issued a call to action to senior leaders throughout our company.</p>
          <p>Essentially, we immediately shifted our focus to fundamentals and execution, making sure we increased our sense of urgency and matched our operating framework to the severity of the recession that we were all clearly facing. We put in place very concise corporate directives focused on cash generation, reduction in cost and capital expenditures and improvements in working capital, and we reinforced those directives with clear scorecards and accountability.</p>
          <p>All employees received and heard the same message: Cash is king. We put a strict focus on performance through the end of the first quarter. We gave every business and function specific targets, and we're reviewing progress on a regular basis.</p>
          <p>During this time, we also recognized how especially critical it is to say &#x2013; stay close to the customers. It was important to clearly understand our customers' needs, secure every order and even seek out new opportunities. One benefit from our customer intimacy in the fourth quarter was about a 40% decline in past due accounts.</p>
          <p>The teamwork between our account leaders and our business financial folks was outstanding and clearly paying dividends. Business teams were actively engaged with customers to secure every order. They took a customer-by-customer, region-by-region approach to understand their situation and make decisions that delivered maximum value to DuPont.</p>
          <p>We made it clear to our leaders that one size does not fit all; each business has to uniquely assess their own market dynamics and solicit input from key customers and implement decisive actions to yield immediate results in a way that is consistent with our corporate directives.</p>
          <p>Last week, we just completed the most intensive meeting with the top 75 leaders in my history with DuPont. Our leaders are very clear on what they must do in this environment. We're revisiting market and customer segmentation; it's changed since last year and we're marrying it to a new resource deployment plan so that we can reduce cost while improving our line of site to our customers.</p>
          <p>Our aggressive action plans are the direct results of all of these activities. While Jeff gave you updates on various components in these this plans, I'd like to recap four specific areas to drive for cash and to eliminate or avoid cost. So please turn to slide 14.</p>
          <p>First, fixed cost reductions. We identified immediate spending cuts; we announced a restructuring program last month, and that program is on track to deliver at least $130 million in benefit in 2009. We have another $600 million in fixed cost projects under Richard Goodmanson's direction, and I'm confident we will meet or beat these targets.</p>
          <p>You've already heard from Jeff about the status on eliminating contractor positions, only one of many examples of delivering against these commitments. Other examples are the elimination of merit salary increases in 2009 and the implementation of diminished working schedules at certain sites.</p>
          <p>Second, variable cost reductions. Clearly, raw material prices are significantly lower as we head into the New Year. And although we will not realize a benefit in the first quarter, we still expect full-year benefit to be around $1 billion. We're also implementing a wide range of projects, for example rationalizing SKUs, or driving process yields.</p>
          <p>Third, capital spending. We will cut capital spending by about 20% for the full year and are continuing to assess each project justification to determine whether further cuts are warranted. We're approaching this on a zero base approach and raising the bar on project justification. Some of the cuts will delay projects to match our revised long-term outlook in market demand.</p>
          <p>And fourth, working capital reductions. We will reduce working capital by $1 billion in 2009. This is in our control, and we will deliver. As I mentioned earlier, strong focus on accounts receivable and past dues paid off in the fourth quarter and we'll maintain our vigilance in this area.</p>
          <p>Significant projects have been identified, and we're beginning to staff them, focused on inventory productivity. Our first mega project in this area is already underway using our DuPont Integrated Business approach. We are evaluating systems and processes to ensure we produce only what we need, in some cases, shifting from a make-to-stock approach to a make-to-order.</p>
          <p>Another example is to holistically evaluate supply chains and see where we can take out warehousing, streamline shipments and optimize the whole, rather than incrementally grow from a baseline that was established under a very different set of market and regional conditions. I'm confident that our work process and our capabilities of these teams can deliver.</p>
          <p>I'd like to address our outlook for 2009. We will be transparent. We don't have a crystal ball about the future, but we'll share the assumptions and the expectations for the full year that are built into our EPS range and update you as appropriate. We reduced full-year EPS guidance by $0.25, primarily due to lower volume expectations for the year. We're staying close to our customers so we can respond to the changes in demand rapidly and efficiently.</p>
          <p>One last comment on R&amp;D investment. Overall, we're maintaining a robust and market-oriented pipeline of R&amp;D projects and an outstanding bench of talent under the direction of Uma Chowdhry and Tom Connelly. While R&amp;D spending is being trimmed in certain businesses and timed appropriately to market conditions, we will continue to invest more in high growth areas such as seed, photovoltaics, aramids and biofuels.</p>
          <p>When you put it all together, we're keenly aware that we are in the midst of a continued challenge and dislocation on a global basis. Our actions reflect this, and we're attacking costs and expenses aggressively, keeping tight controls over fundamental elements of our operations to maximize efficiency, productivity and cash.</p>
          <p>This emphasis on fundamentals also means protecting our core competitive advantages and making sure we position ourselves for the inevitable recovery. We will emerge in partnership with our customers, stronger, leaner and more agile and better poised for growth.</p>
          <p>Karen, back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Ellen. Chris, we're ready to open up the lines for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now begin our question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question is from Kevin McCarthy at Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Jim, I was wondering if you could quantify the amount of seed share gains that you've achieved in Brazil in corn and soy, as well as your expectation for U.S. corn share gains in the upcoming planting season here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Kevin. First of all, down in Brazil, share will certainly be up. The dust hasn't settled on the complete season, but it will be up, I'll say, a point or more. But it's &#x2013; until we get the season completely finished, we won't have actual numbers. Similar kinds of things in Argentina. I think our gains in the northwest market in Mexico will be even more than that. In North America, I'm not going to be &#x2013; I'm not going to try to size it right now; it's too early with nobody planting yet. But clearly, we're confident that share will be up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then as a follow up, you mentioned that herbicide volumes have declined in Latin America. Would you elaborate on that? Is it a function strictly of the drought in Argentina, or are there credit availability issues or other fundamental issues that you think may be at work there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good question. The drought in Argentina certainly is having some impact, so that's one of the factors. But overall, a lot of it is more timing than anything else. In Latin America, we saw some delays. And in Europe, I think I mentioned that we saw some delays with distributors kind of holding off until first quarter. We think the volume will still be there, but it's moving around a little bit.</p>
          <p>From a credit point of view, there is some issue in terms of delays while people are looking for cash. For example, we've got some farmers that are holding grain, looking for better prices. And so while they're holding the grain, they don't have the cash to invest right now. And in the big picture, they're going to be fine, but they may not have the cash at the moment. So, overall, we feel like the volume will be there, but timing is a bigger issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Alexander Laurence (sic) [Laurence Alexander] at Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. First question is in terms of the overall &#x2013; on the industrial side &#x2013; to what extent do you think you can maintain pricing as raw materials fall starting in Q2 and Q3?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Alexander, let me take that question. I think that we've had &#x2013; you can look at our track record, and it supports our pricing, the success that we've had. I want to emphasize here that we really price value in use, new products, product differentiation. We've also over the last several years put in pricing discipline. So I think based on that new capability, we're in good position to maintain our pricing through this. We will see in some segments some pressure that are more commoditized. But again, our pricing discipline will allow us to hold and lag the market there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I guess secondly on vendor financing, can you address your overall policy on vendor financing and how that's changing and also in particular what you're seeing in the seed market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Overall, our vendor financing, we have a very strict credit function working with each of our sales organizations in each of the businesses around the world. As we mentioned, we had a particular focus in the fourth quarter on past dues, and we reduced them over historic levels by 40%. It is an area that we stay on top of day by day because we think it is an indicator of the health of our customers and we want to make sure that we are very active in that area. Jim, you want to comment on Ag?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ellen, a couple of things. First of all, collections from '08 are on track; in fact, past dues for us are kind of at all-time lows so that's not &#x2013; hasn't been an issue. As we're looking in North America for example to '09, we're seeing a slight increase in grower elections for deferred pay versus cash, but it's not huge, and it's still &#x2013; but it's within the range that we were expecting. But we are seeing a little bit more demand for deferred pay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Robert Koort at Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Jeff, you've done a pretty good job over the last year or two beating into our heads that this industrial pricing index for chemicals was a proxy for your raw materials. And I guess you've talked to some improvement later in the year. Why wouldn't we see some of that more immediately as you've eaten up some of the high priced inventory in the fourth quarter?</p>
          <p>And I guess related to that, you gave an outlook that suggested the first quarter end markets as dismal as the fourth. Should we expect the same kind of 20% volume erosion or do you think you've taken care of some of that destocking and you can operate at a bit better utilization rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks for the question, Bob. Let me try to address your raw material question first. For the full year, we still expect to be in the same range that I talked to you about on December 4, a four to 6% decline. That's a combination of two pieces: up for Ag inputs and down in our other businesses.</p>
          <p>Yes, we had our inventories in the fourth quarter come down; I'm very pleased with that. But we still have for the remaining inventory high cost raw materials held up, and that's really the dynamic that we're dealing with here that it's just going to spill over and into the first several months of the first quarter. And so I'm not anticipating any significant declines in raw materials in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>On your second question, I'm sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just you took a pretty big hickey in the fourth quarter on your operating rates, obviously from destocking across the customer base and gave the comment that the first quarter looks like the fourth quarter from a demand standpoint. Would we expect your operating rates to be equally impaired or we actually see some improvement there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think first of all let me comment on volume, and then we'll talk a little bit about production. From a volume standpoint, I did a very thorough review of all the businesses over the last couple of weeks here. And what we see is as I said volumes down equal to or perhaps a little bit more than the fourth quarter that we have not seen the end of the destocking.</p>
          <p>Having said that, the business response will be very situational, based on their individual situations. So I can't make a general comment about that, other than to say that as the quarter continues to go on, I would expect the trend in our idle mills expense to go down or improve if you will.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Bob. I'm sorry, Bob. There's two areas you might consider as you dissect our portfolio. Certainly on the industrial side, Ti02 and fluoro both have seasons starting in the first quarter. And although the season will not look like first quarter of last year, I think sequentially you'll see those improving.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go now to Jeff Zekauskas at JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One of the themes of the conference call so far has been your strong balance sheet. Is now &#x2013; and we're also in an environment in which there are all kinds of interesting assets that are being offered to different companies at discounts, and some of them are quite large. Is your balance sheet sufficiently strong that you if you came across a four or a $5 billion acquisition that was offered to you at very attractive terms, is your balance sheet strong enough that you could actually engineer that kind of acquisition?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Jeff, what do you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me speak in general. Our philosophy here in this current environment, strategically we're still looking to grow particularly in Ag and Safety &amp; Protection. We're monitoring our pipelines and making sure we understand exactly what the opportunities are. But Jeff we are going to be cautious in this current environment till we get a little bit more visibility. And I think that what we're seeing now is asset values are down. I think those opportunities are going to be out there, but we're going to be cautious about jumping a little too early.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And for my follow-up question. You mentioned this low capacity utilization charge. So, is this something that you're doing that's different from an accounting standpoint, and how did you arrive at the precise number that you arrived at? And what's the 2009 number using your guidance assumptions, if there is an unusual accounting change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's no unusual accounting change here, I can assure you of that. We typically have taken idle mills, this is basically prescribed by GAAP accounting. Fundamentally what happens here is, is when you fall under about a 60% utilization rate, rather than taking a cost to your, to inventory you need to take them as a period cost. So as I said, this is not increased spend. This is just timing of when it hits the balance sheet, or I mean the income statement, so that's really what's going on here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the purpose of that is so we don't inflate our inventory values, that we get those right. Going forward as I said, it's very murky and volatile out there, but as the destocking ends, and we reach some steady state of demand, albeit a lot lower than last year, I would expect those charges directionally to go down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go next to Mark Gulley of Soleil Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I want to focus on the balance sheet as well and operating rates. Given the fact that you're going to be drawing down working capital by $1 billion, how should I think about the change in operating rates from '08 to '09?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, our operating rates through the fourth quarter are operating pretty well against a demand signal. When we're taking our working capital, specifically inventory down, we do it &#x2013; we're doing this systemically, starting with raw materials and basically it's a cycle time. It's a production wheel issue in terms of getting the velocity of our inventory up.</p>
          <p>And so we'll be turning our inventories more for the year. That's systemically how we're going to get to the $800 million reduction in inventory for the year. And that's on a plant-by-plant, business-by-business basis, understanding the service levels and understanding really that production wheel and different ways of doing it. We are putting people and process against it, and we're very confident in our ability to achieve it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And for my follow up, although I haven't dissected the numbers precisely, given that the decent results in Seed and given the reduction in sales in crop &#x2013; in the overall Ag &amp; Nutrition area, it would appear as if Crop Protection chemicals are particularly weak. Jim, can you talk about any areas where, for whatever reason, Crop Protection chemicals were worse than your expectations in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The only things that I'd highlight are the things I mentioned before. We saw volumes below what we were maybe expecting going into the quarter, but not unexpected when you see what was actually happening with the timing and some of the economic situations. And I think the important thing about crop, both of the Ag businesses, but particularly Crop Protection there is that fourth quarter is not a huge quarter. When you look at the year, Crop Protection had a really significant year, record sales and earnings and productivity prove this out. And I think you really need to look at that quarter in the context of the year, and we're expecting continued progress going into '09.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike Judd from Greenwich Consultants. Your line is open, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. You mentioned that your goal was to reduce working capital by roughly $1 billion. And if I look at the last couple of years on a quarterly basis, there is typically a really &#x2013; there's a substantial build in working capital, obviously in the first quarter, the March quarter.</p>
          <p>Is it reasonable to expect that given the current environment that the magnitude of that typical build in working capital will be substantially lower this year, but that sort of the sequential changes in working capital throughout the rest of the year look similar. So I'm just trying to get a little bit more of a sense on a quarterly basis how the cash flows look from a working capital perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you have to dissect our agriculture business from the rest of the businesses if you think about that, because in the first quarter Ag is building inventories for season. And so that has &#x2013; that's very different than our industrial businesses. We have challenged our businesses for a 5% productivity ex volume and currency for the first quarter. And so we're trying to get at, whether you're reducing volume or increasing volume as you are in Ag, you can still get productivity, and that's basically where the focus is. So there's just a very different situation between our Ag and industrial business on the cycle through the year on inventory that comes into play in that first quarter build.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So just as a follow on to that, I understand the Ag component of that, and that won't really change. When I look at the changes in working capital last year and the year before, I was wondering if part of that big build was just due to preparing in the other businesses for the seasonal up tick that you would expect in the second quarter and that basically that could be substantially different this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, Mike, in the past year or so, one of the things that drove up inventory values was really the high cost of raw materials coming in. So I think that's a phenomenon that you saw there coming into our inventories as we had this $2 billion incremental cost year-over-year and incremental cost the year before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Sergey Vasnetsov at Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I'm pretty happy that nobody asked my question because the focus should be on their minds, maybe some people have the answer and I don't. My question on the earnings outlook trajectory for 2009, and while I'm not asking for specific quarterly EPS comments, I would like to understand your assumptions built in on a two to 2.25 expectations.</p>
          <p>So if I take a look at DuPont's quarterly results for the past ten years, the first quarter, let's say if it's in mid range, $0.60, a difficult second quarter is plus minus &#x2013; and by the same plus, minus $0.10, so let's say 70. So 60 plus 70, $1.30, is at least the second part of the year on a quarterly basis at $0.40 each. And those seem to be pretty robust numbers. So question is, is could you comment on your directional expectations, the main assumptions on economy and energy? Do you have some explicit expectations for the strong second half year recovery?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let me give you some opening comments, and then we can get some added help here. So if you think about our restructuring, the benefit of that will be seen in the second half of the year. And if you think about as our raw materials turn, the benefit of that's largely going to be in the second half of the year. So the second half of the year is going to be different in 2009, then maybe some of the historic pattern that you've seen because we will see a tremendous amount of that $730 million in fixed cost productivity and the variable cost productivity hitting our books in the second half of the year. And so that's a major component. Jeff, what would you add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I just &#x2013; the only thing I would add is that we are not predicting any turn up, the economic recovery. We're assuming that as we said that the markets would remain down, and so given that we're not waiting for a recovery. What we're focused on are our actions and the things we can control, and as Ellen said, that'll largely what will pay off as we go through the year into the second half, Sergey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. As a follow-up, you commented that you tried to work off your inventory. The inventory value's about the same in the fourth quarter as it is in the third, and seasonally sometimes it picks up slightly still. What was going on there &#x2013; what are the volume of your sales were dropping even faster that's you were not able to adjust your inventories as much as you'd like to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we were very successful in adjusting our inventories, and our businesses did a good job, but we do have hold over that is going to flow over into the first quarter, as I said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Chris Shaw at UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. I think I'm following up a little bit on Bob's question, but just in terms of &#x2013; basically are you seeing any sort of, in any of your myriad of product lines, outside Ag and photovoltaics and things that are strong, but like anywhere where there is actually some signs of hope where the destocking has come and now people are coming back and reordering product?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we're seeing is a very &#x2013; one term I would use erratic environment. We'll get orders one week, and then two weeks later they'll be backing off because they're not seeing down their value chains trade. So, the order pattern is episodic at this point in the majority of our industrial markets. We're staying very close to it, understanding we &#x2013; we think that we'll see additional indicators from Asia as we come through the Lunar New Year.</p>
          <p>And so, from &#x2013; in the kind of mid February, we should understand really at what level they're going to be operating at there because they basically didn't come back from the end of the year and are really looking to start up again in mid-February.</p>
          <p>So, again it is about maintaining that customer closeness during this period and understanding their issues down their value chain and really keeping our people focused on working capital productivity and fixed and variable cost productivity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, on pensions. Can you just give me estimates what the pension headwind to EPS would be, and what kind of contributions you're going to have to make this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure, I'd be happy too. So, in the December 4, I gave a range of 40 to $0.50 a share, a charge due to &#x2013; and that's a non-cash charge due to pensions. We're still in the process of finalizing the remeasurements, so I don't have a pinpoint number for you; that will be available when we issue the 10-K. But what I can tell you is based on what we've seen so far, we will be at the lower end of that 40 to $0.50 range.</p>
          <p>On the cash contributions, we're expecting somewhere in the range of $300 million this year; that's global. It's really largely outside the U.S. as legally required. We do not see a cash call from our principle U.S. pension plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from Frank Mitsch, BB&amp;T.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Follow-up on the balance sheet. I think you said your net debt was at 5.9 billion at the end of the year. What's your targeted level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We were shooting for a target of about &#x2013; lower than 6.3 billion, Frank. So, we exceeded that target for the year, and we ended about flat versus last year on net debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and so is there any reason that you need to take that materially lower than where it is right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not anticipating taking it materially lower, but I think in this environment, our cash discipline policies haven't changed. We're going to maintain a very strong balance sheet, and we face a lot of uncertainty now. So that's something that's front and center for us. I think that's also in the best interest to shareholders because we want to ensure the dividend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then you mentioned, some additional R&amp;D &#x2013; areas that you're ramping up R&amp;D spending included Biofuels initiatives. Can you talk about potential commercial successes there in 2009, 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are continuing our investment in biofuels area. We are on track with the programs that we put in place and committed to a little over a year ago. We're making progress in key areas with the pilot plant down in Tennessee and things like that. And I think you'll see throughout the year as we continue to make our milestones that we'll be more than happy to come out and discuss them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Frank, just to add to that, we're looking at earnings impact still 2012 and beyond. We haven't pulled that forward. It's basically on track, as Ellen said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And maybe, Frank, just one additional comment. I think what you saw in the fourth quarter was a very differentiated approach, and you should expect to see that as we go through 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from Peter Jacobs at Ragen MacKenzie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. The first question I have involves the decline in shareholder equity that we saw between the third and the fourth quarter, and it was about $5.5 billion. And if I just kind of rough it out, I can get a billion of that decline due to of course the loss in the fourth quarter plus the dividend. So that other 4.5 billion, I'm assuming that's primarily accounting for the unfunded status of the pension funds at the end of the year. But what else would be in there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, you had the principal thing; it's earnings and the under funding of the pension as a result of primarily the swing in asset values.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can you quantify kind of what kind of decline that you saw in the pension assets for the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, we're still finalizing all of that. That will be available shortly when we issue our 10-K.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris, I think we're at the end of our hour. We'll take one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And our final question comes from David Begleiter at Deutsche Bank. David, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Jim, there have been claims of aggressive discounting in North American corn seed by you. If that's not true, how would somebody get that impression?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dave. Let me be absolutely clear. The answer to your question is unequivocally, we have not been doing that. Let me go back and give you some background. We came out with our pricing in September. Since that time, we haven't altered our programs, we haven't relaxed any early order dates, we haven't increased any discounts for early orders. Our sample budget experience so far has been actually below what it has been the last several years as a norm.</p>
          <p>Recall back in December I talked our product performance. We've got a great product line up that's delivering real value to farmers. And we price to value, we've got an advantage route to market with folks working with farmers, get the right product on the right acre. And we're going to gain market share and double-digit prices based on the fundamentals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, I can maybe be a little stronger than, Jim, I think is holding back a little bit here. I guess the phrase I'd use is, "hell, no." Our pricing discipline cuts across all of our businesses; we take it very seriously. And we are absolutely committed in driving for value in all of our markets including our Ag space. And so I think that people can make quips here and there, but I think you've get to come and talk to us about the facts, and we'll be happy to share them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>I want to thank you all for joining us on this call. It's my first quarter as CEO, and so it's been a really interesting process that we're on. I tell you, I really have a tremendous amount of focus on our cost productivity, both fixed and variable and our working capital productivity. Our people are aligned behind very clear directives on this productivity and what we need to deliver this year and I'll look forward to talking to you in the future. Karen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Chris, that concludes our call. I'd just like to thank everybody for joining us this morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's DuPont fourth quarter 2008 conference call. You may now disconnect your lines at this time and have a wonderful day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>