<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1450439" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-02-09</date>
    <companies>
      <company>586</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Executive Director">Paul Steven Walsh</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Director">Deirdre A. Mahlan</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Philip M. Morrisey</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="President, North America and Chairman, Asia Pacific, Diageo, Plc">Ivan Menezes</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Asia Pacific">Gilbert Ghostine</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Ian M. Shackleton</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Diageo Africa">Nick Blazquez</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Simon L. Hales</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Andrea Pistacchi</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Mitchell J. Collett</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Bank Plc (France)">Antoine Belge</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief marketing officer">Andy Fennell</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Trevor Stirling</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Melissa G. Earlam</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Jamie M. Isenwater</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Alex Molloy</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="corprep" affiliation="President-Europe">Andrew Morgan</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Davenport Securities">Ann H. Gurkin</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies International Ltd.">Simon J. Marshall-Lockyer</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst" affiliation="Natixis SA (Broker)">Olivier Delahousse</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International Ltd.">Nico J. Lambrechts</participant>
      <participant id="22" type="analyst" affiliation="Liberum Capital, Inc.">Pablo E. Zuanic</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and welcome to this Interim Results Webcast. Deirdre and I are going to follow our usual format and speak for about 40 minutes on the key highlights of these results, then we'll be joined by our executive colleagues to take your questions. Today, we're also joined by Nick Blazquez and Randy Millian as this is the first time we've reported our results across five regions.</p>
          <p>As you saw from our announcement this morning, our first half performance has been strong and it's a balanced performance across regions and categories. In an environment of uneven global economic growth and the varying consumer trends, we have seen our performance improved in developed markets and continue to strengthen in the faster growth markets of the world.</p>
          <p>Stronger volume growth and improved price mix has accelerated our top line performance. Our volume performance improved in the developed markets but it was the performance of our scotch, vodka and beer brands in the emerging markets, where volume was up 10%, which was the main driver of our overall growth. Together with the acquisition of Mey &#x130;&#xE7;ki and Serengeti Breweries, this increased our emerging markets business to almost 40% of the total.</p>
          <p>In markets where the economic trends are stronger, we have taken price, which, together with almost 20% volume growth of our super premium brands, draw the 4-percentage point price/mix gain. This price/mix, together with the cost savings we've delivered, expanded operating margin in a period in which we have significantly increased marketing spent behind our brands.</p>
          <p>Our first half performance of 9% organic operating profit growth and double-digit EPS growth underpins the confidence we have in our brands, in our routes to market, and our people. And we are signaling this with a 7% increase in the interim dividend.</p>
          <p>However, this is an uncertain world and the economic and political prospects in some markets in which we operate are challenging. We're cautious ask to the trends we will face in the second half, but we believe this first half performance gives us the platform from which to deliver our medium-term goals.</p>
          <p>I'm going to stop there for now and hand over to Deirdre, who will look at our financial performance in more detail. Deirdre?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Paul and good morning everybody. At our November conference, I spoke about efficient growth. By that I mean investing to drive the top line while generating margin improvement. This first half performance demonstrates that the investments we have made and continue to make in our brands and in our sales capabilities are delivering efficient growth.</p>
          <p>Our marketing expense was up again, 10% in this half, and as a percentage of net sales it was up 40 basis points. The bulk of this increased investment, over 70%, was targeted at emerging markets, where we see the greatest opportunities for growth.</p>
          <p>Net sales grew 7% in the half, reflecting a continuation of the underlying trends we saw in the first quarter. It was driven by solid volume growth of 3% and 4 percentage points of positive price/mix, split almost evenly between price and mix, reflecting the strength of our brands and our investments in them. This price/mix, together with the efficiencies we've made in our supply footprint, drove gross margin expansion of 70 basis points. We've reduced overheads in developed markets and we're beginning to reach scale in many of our emerging markets, resulting in operating margin expansion of 60 basis points.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow was &#xA3;500 million in the half and we are maintaining our progressive dividend policy with a 7% increase in the interim dividend.</p>
          <p>Now I'll take you through some of the detail underlying this performance and I'll start with the drivers of net sales growth. Growth of scotch in emerging markets, especially Johnnie Walker, C&#xEE;roc in North America, and our beer brands in Africa, continued to be the key drivers of volume growth while Smirnoffs return to growth and the continued growth of Captain Morgan outside of North America provided additional volume upside.</p>
          <p>Mix was driven by the strong performance of scotch, particularly the deluxe and super deluxe segments, which accounted for 41% of net sales growth. This was due to continued emerging market growth and consumer confidence at higher income levels in the developed markets.</p>
          <p>Double-digit growth of our premium vodka brands also drove positive mix. Price increases in the emerging markets were the biggest driver of the price element of the net sales growth. The completion of the acquisition of Mey &#x130;&#xE7;ki accounted for most of the non-organic net sales growth in the period.</p>
          <p>Scope changes also reflect the purchase of our controlling stake in Serengeti Breweries and the sale of wine brands in North America in fiscal 2011. Under recent accounting changes, acquisition costs are taken to the income statement and we have reported operating profit from acquisitions net of &#xA3;39 million of acquisition costs. Weakness in some of our African currencies and in the U.S. dollar was partially offset by the strengthening of the euro, giving a slightly negative overall FX impact on net sales.</p>
          <p>The underlying performance was strong throughout the half, although as we have described when we reported first quarter results, one-off factors flattered our net sales growth in that quarter. The phasing in North America was balanced, 5% in both quarters, although the first quarter benefited from better price mix.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe, the first quarter was flattered by lapping the destock in Spain last year. In the second quarter, we reduced promotional discounts, primarily in Great Britain, which led to lower volumes. In Africa, Guinness growth slowed in the second quarter with weaker performance in Nigeria. This was due to the environmental, social and economic factors including heavy rains and increased security challenges. In the first quarter in Latin America, we saw buy in ahead of price increases in Mexico and in Venezuela. Phasing was affected by soft comps as currency restrictions constrained sales last year.</p>
          <p>First quarter net sales in Asia were strong due to a buy in ahead of price increases in the Middle East and phasing of shipments in Southeast Asia. Our second quarter performance was in line with expectations with a strong festive season. In summary, our first half top line performance has been robust across our regions and categories.</p>
          <p>We continue to invest behind our brands to support this top line growth. Our reinvestment rate increased by 40 basis points to 15.8% with marketing investment up 10% and nearly three-quarters of that increase was focused on emerging markets. For most categories, spend was up in line with the total increase.</p>
          <p>In scotch, 80% of the incremental spend was in emerging markets, principally focused on Johnnie Walker. Investment behind the brand was driven by Asia and Latin America as we continued to drive recruitment and premiumization.</p>
          <p>Spend on our vodka brands increased in both the developed and emerging markets. We increased spend significantly behind Smirnoff on the "I Choose" and "Nightlife Exchange" campaigns. In developed markets, investment was again driven by C&#xEE;roc, Smirnoff and Ketel One in North America.</p>
          <p>In beer, spend was also focused in the fastest growth markets with spend in Africa up 25%. Investment in Guinness increased across all its major markets and was up double digit in North America and mid single digit in Europe and Asia Pacific.</p>
          <p>Turning now to margin; gross margin improved on an organic basis, up 70 basis points, mainly driven by price increases and the mix improvement delivered by the growth in scotch. Input cost inflation has been mitigated by cost savings from restructuring coupled with our continuing program to improve the efficiency of our supply footprint. As a result, increases in cost of goods sold per unit were held at about 1.5% mainly driven by a 3% increase in Africa given the higher inflation rate there.</p>
          <p>Every region delivered gross margin improvement. North America benefited from their supply restructuring programs and positive price mix. In Western Europe, gross margins improved due to lower cost of goods, particularly in beer. In Latin America, Africa and Asia Pacific, strong volume growth and price increases drove gross margin expansion. In Africa double-digit top line growth reflected the higher inflation rate, which also affected input costs, but gross margin still improved.</p>
          <p>As you saw in the previous slide, we have invested behind our brands and targeted those opportunities that will drive the greatest future growth. We continue to invest in our emerging market platforms and overheads in these areas were up 15%. These investments were largely offset by savings from our restructuring programs, which delivered benefits of &#xA3;13 million in the first half. In summary, we have increased our gross margin and invested in the long-term growth of the business while expanding our operating margins.</p>
          <p>We delivered free cash flow of &#xA3;500 million in the half. Higher operating profit drove nearly &#xA3;125 million of incremental free cash flow. However, outflows were higher in the half driven primarily by the increase in working capital. This half always has a seasonal increase in working capital.</p>
          <p>In addition, though, we increased investments in this half in maturing stock to fuel our future growth and incurred costs in respect of the move to our new rum distillery in the Virgin Islands, which has now started production.</p>
          <p>One-off factors included higher debtors due to buy in ahead of expected duty increases in January 2012 in France. Nigeria also increased its stock holdings to mitigate the potential disruption as we brought on much needed new capacity in the peak season. The impact was amplified by weaker sales due to the current economic challenges there.</p>
          <p>Higher interest payments were primarily driven by lapping the interest rate swaps, which we monetized last year. Higher tax payments were due to the phasing of payments and tax audit settlements in the U.K. Our capital expenditure is higher this year due to our investments in Nigeria, East Africa and North America, coupled with lower disposal proceeds.</p>
          <p>The costs associated with the initiatives that we have put in place to improve operating margin and make this business stronger are reflected in exceptional charges. I anticipate these charges will actually be lower in fiscal 2012 than we had originally planned with a total cost of about &#xA3;100 million against the &#xA3;120 million we announced in August.</p>
          <p>Similarly, I expect the cash outflow from these activities to be lower than we had originally estimated, about &#xA3;180 million this year, roughly &#xA3;25 million lower than we announced in August. The gain we reported as sale of businesses reflects the change in accounting for our additional ShuiJingFang investment as we now have majority control of the Quanxing holding company.</p>
          <p>Now, let me spend a little time on the exceptional tax charge of &#xA3;518 million. As we anticipated, the tax rate before exceptional items has reduced to 18% this year from 22% previously. We currently anticipate the 18% will be our ongoing tax rate. The reported tax rate includes the exceptional tax item you saw on the previous slide and is therefore 45.2%.</p>
          <p>Last year, we didn't have any exceptional tax charges and so the pre-imposed exceptional tax rates were in line. During the period, we finalized negotiations with tax authorities, which confirmed a favorable change in the basis of taxation relating to intangible assets, mainly brand values and how they are amortized for tax purposes. This has reduced the ongoing tax rate and brought it in line with our cash tax rate.</p>
          <p>However, this change in the basis of taxation resulted in the lower write-off of deferred &#x2013; in the write-off of deferred tax assets, which we had established under the previous tax basis. This write-off gave rise to a non-cash charge of &#xA3;524 million, which increased the reported tax rate.</p>
          <p>And finally, moving down the income statement to EPS, associate income was up &#xA3;18 million driven by the performance of Mo&#xEB;t Hennessy. The net finance charge was broadly unchanged. Our effective interest rate was about 50 basis points lower at 4.7% and average net debt was up roughly &#xA3;750 million to &#xA3;8.3 billion as we funded the acquisition of Mey &#x130;&#xE7;ki with short-term debt and our strong free cash flow.</p>
          <p>I would expect our interest rate for full year to be a little higher than in the first half given floating rate interest forecasts. Also, I'm currently assuming we will move to a higher proportion of fixed debt, but the final decision will depend on the interest rate outlook and market conditions.</p>
          <p>EPS excluding exceptional items was up 16%. Excluding the impact of the reduction in the tax rate from 22% to 18%, EPS was up 10%.</p>
          <p>In summary, Diageo is building momentum. Our net sales growth was strong in the half with continued growth in emerging markets and a solid performance in North America. The restructuring of our European business was achieved as planned and overall the performance there was in line with our expectation.</p>
          <p>Four percentage points of positive price/mix marks a significant improvement over last year. This price/mix improvement and our efficiency programs led to a further gross margin increase. We've invested behind a number of priorities we believe will drive growth, primarily in emerging markets and behind growing categories in North America and Europe.</p>
          <p>Our increased focused on cost is delivering results and coupled with our top line performance it generated 60 basis points of margin expansion. And finally, we've maintained our robust financial base and our strong debt-to-EBIT ratios while funding our acquisitions in the half.</p>
          <p>As Paul said, we are cautious about economic trends in 2012 but the solid and well-balanced results we've delivered in the half give me confidence that we are on track to achieve the medium-term guidance we described last August.</p>
          <p>And now I'll hand back to Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Deirdre. At our conference in November, I spoke about making a strong business stronger and these results demonstrate that we are doing just that. I'm going to spend some time now talking about how we've built the momentum, which Deirdre has just described. And I will start with the investments we have made to drive top line growth.</p>
          <p>The momentum behind our improving top line growth is the result of our consistent investment in marketing behind effective campaigns, our successful innovation program and the renewed focused that we have put behind regional sales teams.</p>
          <p>We have more of the world's leading brands than any other company. We are focused on extending those leadership positions and in the half we have gained share in over 60% of our markets. Our strategic brands have grown fastest.</p>
          <p>Johnnie Walker has generated a third of our growth, but it didn't set the pace. Buchanan's grew even faster with 27% growth, and C&#xEE;roc grew 50%. In Vodka, Ketel One grew over 10% and the strong performance of Smirnoff in Western Europe, where it grew 9%, was a big contributor to the overall improvement in the brand's performance. 11% growth of Guinness in the emerging markets helped offset the weakness of the beer category in Europe and Guinness grew 5% globally.</p>
          <p>Let me start with marketing, which we increased by 10% in this half, following a 10% increase in the same period last year. Our incremental marketing spend has been focused on the biggest growth opportunities and that is why over 70% of our incremental spend was in the emerging markets. But we have also increased our marketing spend in North America, targeted at the growth opportunities. As consumer trends are mixed in that market, in some areas spend has been maintained.</p>
          <p>We're increasing our spend on our vodka brands to lead the growth of that category and we've increased marketing spend behind the launch of new products. We're also spending more on advertising specifically to the increasing ethnic diversity of our consumers. This focused approach to our spend in North America is also demonstrated by our spend by price point with investments up significantly on premium and super premium brands.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe, spend is up behind Smirnoff Red and Captain Morgan as these are growth categories where we have clear leadership. Smirnoff has had a strong performance in the first half particularly in our key focused markets for Western Europe of GB, Ireland, Germany and France. Our spend was around mass participation in Smirnoff "Nightlife Exchange" and our media spend reached 23 million consumers with 14,000 mentions in print media. Similarly, Captain Morgan grew double digit in Western Europe behind significant up-weighted spend in Germany and France.</p>
          <p>In addition to increasing spend, the range of our brands gives us enormous scope to reach consumers over a number of platforms. So while marketing was up, our marketing impact increased by even more.</p>
          <p>In China for example, we now have an online shopping page for Baileys on the Chinese equivalent of eBay providing a cost-effective way to reach 190 million female Internet shoppers. In Mexico and Colombia, we launched "Buchanan's Time to Share." It's a word of mouth campaign supported by TV, where consumers who donate four hours of their time to volunteer work connected to education get a ticket for an exclusive concert with an international artist. Nobody will be able to buy a ticket. The only way to go is by donating the four hours.</p>
          <p>The launch of the new Johnnie Walker Blue Label bottle this half was through a series of exclusive private tastings in China, in India, Thailand, Vietnam, Brazil and Mexico. And each one had a local cultural relevance. We then leveraged social media and created nearly $30 million worth of coverage.</p>
          <p>In Africa, Guinness has carved out an important space as the number one beer for football fans in Nigeria with activities such as bringing the Argentina football team to play the Nigerian Super Eagles, for the first time, in "Guinness The Match." It generated &#xA3;2 million in earned media value as the match was broadcast live to an estimated audience of 42 million people. And of course we're now running a second series of the highly successful Guinness Football Challenge.</p>
          <p>In Africa, we are now filming our ads in the region in several local dialects and featuring the local community.</p>
          <p>Diageo has a track record of successful and sustainable innovations and at our conference in November, we showcased the depth of our innovation pipeline in North America with particular focus on C&#xEE;roc, which we introduced new to the world, and is now a major super premium vodka brand.</p>
          <p>We're using innovation to access the key growth trends, the luxury opportunity, the emerging middle class and the female consumer. And in the half, we launched a further 80 new products.</p>
          <p>We are premiumizing our brands through innovations and we delivered nearly 20% growth of our Johnnie Walker super premium brands through special gift packs; first, for Diwali and more recently for Chinese New Year. You can see the great packaging we used for Johnnie Walker XR21 on this slide.</p>
          <p>Understanding consumer motivations in this luxury space is key to success. Gold is an important part of the festival occasions across Asia. And we test launched Smirnoff Gold priced at three times that of Smirnoff Red. And the rate of sale is 1.5 times that of Smirnoff Red and it's driven 3 percentage points of share gain and gained 5 percentage points of share against the nearest competitor.</p>
          <p>Innovations are also meeting the opportunity we see in the growth of the emerging middle class and we are launching heritage brands such as Haig in Latin America at affordable price points. We also believe there is significant opportunity to unlock growth from exclusively targeting female consumers. We're doing this across all markets, for example with Smirnoff Whipped Cream and Fluffed Marshmallow in the U.S, and Baileys Biscotti in Europe.</p>
          <p>Innovation unlocks growth in the developed markets. In Ireland for example, we have introduced new liquids and dispense mechanisms to offer perfect cocktails in bars, which do not normally serve cocktails. Smirnoff Mojito is now available in over 600 outlets, which is selling a total of nearly 40,000 cocktails a week.</p>
          <p>Having built our sales capability centrally, last year we moved the focus of our sales operations into the regions as part of our operating model changes. We can now tailor our consumer programs and our innovation agenda with each of our key global customers.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe for example, more than 50 customers agreed new initiatives in sharper marketing and category development, which are forecast to deliver an incremental net sales benefit of over &#xA3;20 million.</p>
          <p>All our regions increased their ease of shop programs. In Western Europe, it was implemented in 27,000 stores, up nearly 25% on last year.</p>
          <p>In the half, we also deployed more shopper marketing initiatives than in any previous half year with an increasing mix of programs that are differentiated for our priority customers and where we can leverage our wide brand range by category. And on the slide you can see our Smirnoff execution in European duty free.</p>
          <p>The operating model changes we implemented for F12 had two ends: to drive efficiency across the group and to focus our resources to drive growth. This new operating model is now in place. We've delivered the overhead reductions we planned in corporate costs and in Western Europe and North America. Overheads are flat in North America, down &#xA3;10 million in Western Europe, and corporate costs are down &#xA3;30 million. While overheads are up in the emerging markets, they're down as a percentage of net sales as we drove efficiencies in those markets as well.</p>
          <p>Our supply restructuring, primarily in North America and the U.K., is also on track and as Deirdre said, has mitigated input cost inflation in these regions. We've, therefore, have been able to hold cost per unit flat in these markets which has contributed to the gross margin improvement that we've delivered.</p>
          <p>We've announced changes to our Irish brewing operations to create a center of excellence. Just like our investments in distilling capacity in Scotland and in brewing in Africa, this investment in a single facility for Ireland will improve our costs per unit and reduce our environmental footprint.</p>
          <p>At the beginning of the fiscal year, we introduced a new performance management system based on 21 key markets and aligned our incentive systems to drive enhanced accountability. As I travel between our markets, I can see the impact this is having in improving the line of sight between actions and outcomes. It's early days, but I'm confident that this change will be key to delivering our aspirations at a market and regional level.</p>
          <p>Diageo's emerging markets business is based on the route to market and brand strength, which we have built through consistent investment. The individual leadership positions of our brands combine to make Diageo the leading international spirits company in Latin America, in Africa and in Asia.</p>
          <p>The focus of our investment in the emerging markets has continued again this year and in the half we've increased marketing spend by 20% and investment in our sales and marketing organizations by 15%. This investment drove volume growth and eight percentage points of price mix as we accelerated the organic top line growth of our emerging market business to 18%.</p>
          <p>In addition, we're expanding our brand portfolio in these markets. In Brazil for example, where our business was 80% scotch we've seen very strong growth of our vodka brands, especially Ketel One and C&#xEE;roc. And while our scotch brands grew over 20%, we are now building leading positions across more categories in these important markets.</p>
          <p>Innovation is also expanding our reach into fast growing consumer trends, especially the rapid growth in the middle class. In India for example, we recently launched Rowson's Reserve into the growing IMFL prestige segment. It's a great tasting brand in a growth segment and given the improvements that we've made to our route to market in the past two years, we are now confident in our ability to access this segment successfully.</p>
          <p>We've also expanded our presence through acquisitions, which had given us leading brands in premium local spirits and beer. Our acquisition of Mey &#x130;&#xE7;ki added over 2 million cases at an operating profit margin of over 40%. In addition, we've folded our international brands into Mey sales organization, which has already contributed to the improved growth rates that we've seen for these brands.</p>
          <p>Serengeti Breweries, which we acquired last year, has delivered a strong performance and in the half we agreed the acquisition of the Meta Abo Brewery in Ethiopia.</p>
          <p>We have now extended our ownership in ShuiJingFang and see a marked increase in the sales outside China now that we have distribution of the brand in duty free.</p>
          <p>Our North American business is our biggest and our most profitable. In the last year, we've made changes to enhance our position. As the leader in U.S. spirits, we've introduced new ways of working with our distributors, which give us an aligned approach across the key growth opportunities. This has already improved our focus and has contributed to improved top line growth.</p>
          <p>We have rationalized our wine business and integrated it into our spirits business. And while the wine category remains weak, we have seen our performance improved.</p>
          <p>We've increased marketing spend behind new campaigns, which has reenergized Smirnoff, Captain Morgan and Tanqueray. Stronger volume growth of our strategic brands, together with moderate price increases, have driven five percentage points of price mix; in turn driving further gross margin expansion.</p>
          <p>While marketing increased as a percent of sales, operating margin improved as overheads fell as a percent of sales. This is efficient growth.</p>
          <p>Given the current economic environments in Europe, we made the decision in 2011 to create an integrated Western European business which could focus on our leading brands and our key customers and to separate our end-market organizations for the faster growing markets of Russia, Eastern Europe and Turkey. Investment decisions would be made centrally for Western Europe, delivering efficiencies in spend and speeding up the decision making process. It also gave us a sharper focus on the biggest growth opportunities.</p>
          <p>We have begun to see the benefits of this new model. In key categories such as rum and vodka, we've delivered strong growth with Captain Morgan up double-digit and Smirnoff up 9%. The economic situation in Ireland, Spain and Greece is reflected in the performance of those countries. But in countries with a more benign economy, we've delivered a good performance and in Germany and France, we've delivered double-digit growth. In addition, our focus on the super premium opportunity has driven over 20% growth in our core reserve brand portfolio across Western Europe.</p>
          <p>As you may recall at our last results presentation, we laid out this slide with our route map for the business over the medium term. This first half performance demonstrates the sharper focus we have brought to bear through the changes that we've made. It's driving the efficient growth we believed that it would. We've delivered good growth in an uncertain world with 7% organic net sales growth and 9% organic operating profit growth.</p>
          <p>With the global economic outlook, whilst improving, remains uncertain and therefore we believe it's prudent to be cautious about the market environment we face in 2012. But this is a good set of balanced first half results. And it has reinforced our confidence in our brands, our routes to market and our teams around the world. We're confident that it's provided us with a good start to the delivery of our medium-term guidance. Thank you.</p>
          <p>Joining me now to take your questions, I have Deirdre, our five market presidents and Andy Fennell, our Chief Marketing Officer. So we'll move directly to your questions and I'll hand over to the operator. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We'll now take our first question from Philip Morrisey from Berenberg. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Paul, you mention in the statement that you've taken selective price increases in North America and I just wanted to confirm that that included the U.S. as well as Canada. And if so, wanted to ask what the percentage of the portfolio in the U.S. has seen list price increases in the period? And indeed, how do you see the prospects for list price increases in the U.S. as this calendar year progresses?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, if I may, on margins in Asia, you've seen strong performance here in the first half and I just wondered how sustainable you thought that 200 basis points plus pace of organic margin expansion might be both in the second half of this fiscal year, but also into fiscal 2013? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Philip. Ivan I suggest you handle the price increase in North America and Gilbert you can handle the margin question in Asia of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Philip. If you look at our results, as you can see we have very strong price mix coming through in North America. I'd say bout a third of it is price and I'm feeling good about the strength of our brands. We are building brand equity where investment &#x2013; reinvestment rates are up and so we are able to now steadily take price on our priority brands. One-third of it, of what you see in the first half price/mix comes through price. We'll see it continue into the second half and clearly as we monitor the improving strength of the marketplace and brand equity strength growing we will use that to guide continued price increase going into next fiscal year as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gilbert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Philip, on your question on margins on Asia, our strategy in Asia is paying off. As I promised you guys when we met last year in May, I said that we will deliver in Asia double-digit top and bottom line and ongoing operating margin improvement and our strategy to focus behind scotch and super deluxe is paying off which is yielding the operating margin improvement. We see still growth in super deluxe scotch and we foresee operating margin to keep improving going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Ian Shackleton from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. You've posted a very good performance in H1 with revenues up 7%. I just wondered, though, you have flagged the most technical effects such as <mark type="indiscernible" /> (39:42) in France, we do have an early Chinese New Year; you've also mentioned Spain I think. I mean if we look to the underlying number I mean how much were those technical effects really worth in this first half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Deirdre, do you want to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ian, the technical effects that we referred to were really talking about the first half versus the second half performance. So there were some. As we pointed out when we released our first quarter numbers, there were some specific technical effects that caused the first half versus the second half to look different.</p>
          <p>I mean, I wouldn't point any specific technical effects across the first half performance that's overall impacting the trends.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So really it was Q1 to Q2?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Q1, Q2 they'll level out. This is a pretty good underlying trend. Now we offered our guidance six months ago. These numbers give us great confidence in that guidance but it's still too early to declare victory here. So we think it is prudent to stay with the guidance that we offered.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Ian, the France and Spain effects are less than 5 million so not material at the Diageo level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. So just to follow up on Nigeria where you obviously flagged &#x2013; you are flagging a bit of a slowdown. I mean how dramatic is that and particularly going to 2012 with the political issues? I mean could we see this going ex growth do you think in 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me ask Nick to answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We saw a bit of a softening in the market in the first half and we were capacity constrained but the additional capacity that we had planned came on stream at the end of November and that's fully operational now. We had the uncertainty of the fuel subsidy removal; that's been by and large resolved now and the market is back presumingly operating normally. And so we were a bit of uncertain at the beginning of January, but that's really pick up now very much.</p>
          <p>The bigger uncertainty I suppose is <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:48), the terrorist uncertainty that we've seen in the north. Hopefully that will be constrained up there. And so I think there is a degree of increased uncertainty but the fundamentals in Nigeria remain the same. It's long-term very attractive; we've got very strong brands. The additional capacity has come on stream and I'm confident in that business there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The other thing I would say about our African business, Ian, is that if you look over the last decade, yes in any given year there was an issue with this market or that market but overall our performance trajectory has been pretty steady. Very dependable and I think that speaks to the diversity of our business in sub-Sahara. So I'm confident that we'll continue to see the growth come through in that region.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Simon Hales from Barclays Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone. Thanks for taking the question. A couple, please if I can. Firstly, Paul I assume that your cautious outlook statement in regards to the economic environment is largely centered on perhaps what we may or may not see in Europe. I mean just building on from your comments to Ian's question, could you just talk a little bit more about the real underlying consumer trends you've perhaps seen through Q1 into Q2, perhaps into the early part of the new calendar year in terms of your core markets and particularly maybe GB.</p>
          <p>And secondly, just with regard to the tequila category, I wonder if you could just talk a little bit more about what's happening in the category there, what's happening particularly with Cuervo's performance and update us, if you can, on any further discussions you've had with the Beckman family and the future of your partnership there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Maybe I'll ask Ivan to talk about tequila but let me give you a perspective on how we're kind of seeing the world. The first thing is we're not seeing anything that you're not seeing. But it is quite uncertain and how things play out remains to be seen.</p>
          <p>That said, start with North America. We continue to see a steady improvement in the economic environment. If you look at the emerging markets, collectively now 40% of our sales, collectively they delivered 18% growth. We're not fundamentally seeing anything different there. We continue to see a rising number of emerging middle class who aspire to our brands and our brand health in these markets is very, very strong. So we expect more of the same there.</p>
          <p>Europe is quite polarized. Yes, we see softness in Southern Europe but our teams in those markets have handled it very, very well. And I feel in Europe we've now got a degree of predictability that maybe we didn't enjoy in the past few years. Once you start to move north, Germany and France is very strong double-digit growth and we can find growth opportunities in Europe. But let's not fool ourselves; it's tough. But in aggregate, I think the fact that we've held our business flat is very creditable to the team in Europe.</p>
          <p>Ivan, tequila?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The tequila trends in the U.S., let's say overall the category is healthy. What you're seeing within the system shifts. You're seeing a shift from gold to silver and in the Cuervo numbers, which we don't break out, Cuervo Silver is doing extremely well and growing nearly double-digit. Gold is under pressure.</p>
          <p>And the second big trend I would say is premiumization. So our higher marks in tequila are doing very well; Don Julio is running very strongly in double-digit growth, very strong in the on-premise. So overall, what you see in our reported numbers on Jose Cuervo also reflects a level destocking in the distributors. The underlying trend on market share is more favorable.</p>
          <p>Regarding our discussions with the Beckman family, they are ongoing. And as you've heard from Paul before, our intention is to secure a long-term participation in the tequila category globally and in the United States.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just building on Ivan's point about Don Julio. If you look at our collection of high-end brands, so the Johnnie Walker Blues, the Tanqueray 10s, the Zacapa, the Ketel One &#x2013; what a stable of them we have. We are seeing in aggregate 25% growth and it's pretty broad-based. It's across many geographies. We see that trend continuing and clearly that has a very positive impact on the leverage that we get through the P&amp;L.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great and thank you, guys. Can I just sort of go back, Paul, to your general comments on the outlook. I mean you didn't mention Great Britain in terms of your relationship in Northern Europe. What's the underlying trend really like in the consumer uptake? I mean have you noticed any real change there in recent months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I see the GB market as quite polarized. I think it's polarized between the southeast and the rest of the country. I think it's polarized between channel; but again, our high-end brands in this market are doing very, very well. It's encouraging that the rate of pub closures has definitely slowed. I think that's positive. And whilst our sales were off somewhat in the first half, the price mix that we saw was very positive. So overall, I would see GB kind of continuing pretty flat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Andrea Pistacchi from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I have a couple of questions on the U.S. please. One, going back to Philip Morrisey's question on pricing in the U.S; you said that you're taking selective price increases and you said that pricing has contributed about one-third to your 5% price mix. Just a little more granularity there; what's &#x2013; I mean I imagine the situation is still difficult, is it, on vodka and rum, in tequila and those core categories. Or is there any pricing going on there?</p>
          <p>The second question is on your mix, which has probably slowed slightly in the quarter. And how I see it there are two drivers of your mix. On the one hand your super premium brand's growing strongly. On the other hand are the low or the sharp declines of your low-end brands. Now going forward on more difficult comps for these premium brands, would you &#x2013; or do you think the current sort of level of mix is sustainable or would you expect a bit of a slowdown?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ivan, I'll hand over to you. I do think we've got to be very careful about going down this rabbit's hole of first quarter second quarter. We've tried to lay it out. Overall, the trends are pretty consistent and there has been nothing that has massively switched between those two quarters, certainly in the U.S. or more generally elsewhere. But specifically to pricing, Ivan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on pricing I would say we are &#x2013; in the first half, we have taken pricing on a number of brands across our categories, brands like Johnnie Walker, Ketel One. Again, we take it by price, by brand and by market, by state. But it's pretty broad-based and as I said I expect that trend to continue because the brands are healthy. They have the equity strength and I'm actually very pleased with how I'm seeing pricing come back into these brands and it enables us to sustain the reinvestment rates that you can see in advertising as well.</p>
          <p>In terms of going forward and the &#x2013; I'm pretty confident that overall price mix we will be able to sustain. If you look at the underlying trends in the industry right now, we're back to that classic chart where the ultra premium segment of the industry in IRI is growing 10%, super premium is growing 7% to 8%, premium is growing at 4% and the value segment is flat or declining. I think our portfolio plays very well to those dynamics. What I'm very pleased about is the strength we are seeing in &#x2013; we talked about it at the investor conference on Smirnoff and Captain Morgan. Those equities are building and you can see it in our results; there's sequential improvement coming through.</p>
          <p>So overall I would say we would probably see the mix, the balance move slightly more towards price, but I would expect mix to continue to be a positive factor as the underlying consumer trends in the U.S. are supporting that strongly. We're also seeing a robust on-trade, which helps the business.</p>
          <p>And as Paul mentioned our reserved brands, I mean in the first half Johnnie Walker Blue was up 35%. It's fantastic to see these top-end brands come back so strongly. And the positioning of affordable luxury, which is what these brands represent, I think is resonating pretty consistently now with the U.S. consumer. And I'm also very proud of the brand building efforts we're putting behind these brands. And so my overall outlook on price and mix continues to be cautiously confident that it will sustain over the next half and into the following fiscal year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ivan. That's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Mitch Collett from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. I was wondering if you could split out the EM growth number you've given between spirits and beer. I guess the contribution of each too, that would be useful as well.</p>
          <p>And then secondly marketing has obviously gone up this half and it looks like you're getting significant reward for that in several key brands. Could you maybe talk broadly about where you see the marketing to sales ratio going long term? I mean you're back to your usual level of spend, could we see it increase beyond here such that you could drive further growth here in the key brands? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have that split at my fingertips. We can see if we can dig it out and get it to you. But I would talk to directionally, and maybe Nick you can speak to this, in Africa, we are seeing very, very strong growth in our beer business. But the route to market that we've created and the organizational strength that we have in our markets is really helping propel spirits sales. And I'll ask Nick to talk to that in a moment.</p>
          <p>In Latin America, basically our business is spirits and therefore that is definitely driving the growth there. And I would say also in Asia, it is definitely tilted towards spirits growth.</p>
          <p>But Nick, why don't you speak to Africa because there's some great examples in Africa of what we're doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, in Africa, spirits grew overall in terms of net sales by 18% against beer at about 12% which is a fantastic performance. And within spirits, Johnnie Walker was an absolute star growing at 32%. The consumers in Africa are the same as consumers around the world in terms of aspiring to our brands. So we make them available through driving distribution, through getting the right format. People will very much buy into them and really love them.</p>
          <p>Now, what's driving that? It is our route to market and we've integrated our beer and our spirits distribution in many of our markets. We did that in South Africa two or three years ago; that's yielding great benefit. We continue to gain market share there in spirits. And over the last 18 months, we've done that in both East Africa and in West Africa. And since we've inculcated beer and spirits together, we've really seen an acceleration of spirits, both across the continent. As I say, Johnnie Walker is spearheading that growth and I expect that to continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and it's notable that your &#x2013; a couple of the spirits brands within Africa have negative price/mix. Is that a function of country mix or is that a deliberate drive to make those brands more affordable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a large part in terms of country mix. As we're seeing the countries' balance change, a lot of that is being driven by country mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think actually when you look at within country the pricing on spirits is pretty robust.</p>
          <p>Regarding your question on A&amp;P spend, we have to recognize that what you see is simply the aggregate result of our strategies, market by market. However, I have to say that I like the profile of our P&amp;L. Our brands are well invested in but equally if we see opportunities for growth, we will keep this momentum going. We see it as very healthy and in the long term interest of the firm. So it's a good profile of investment.</p>
          <p>The other thing that we should never overlook, in emerging markets we have progressively coming on stream many, many millions more of the emerging middle class consumers. And therefore, our footprint, as well as being very well developed, we're set to see very good demographic trends come our way in these markets.</p>
          <p>So to your question on advertising, why wouldn't we continue with this profile? But equally, I do also make the point that our brands are very well invested in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Antoine Belge from HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Antoine Belge with HSBC. Three questions. First of all, sorry to come back on Western Europe and I understand that H1 trends are more really a reflection of the underlying trend than your Q2 versus Q1. But I remember that in Q1, you had mentioned that in the south of Europe you were starting to experience a more favorable basis of comparison. And I'm wondering what &#x2013; it probably has been the case in Q2 so shouldn't we now have a sort of more favorable base for those part of Europe which are doing less well and isn't this indicating that actually Q2 has been a bit weaker than in Q1 on an underlying basis?</p>
          <p>The second question is more on maybe some qualitative comment that you could make on the Chinese New Year on what you're getting from your network in terms of sell out.</p>
          <p>And finally coming back to the marketing questions, just want to make sure I understood correctly so the marketing reinvestment ahead of sale will be a function on what you're achieving in terms of gross margins. I mean if you &#x2013; should we assume that if the gross margin continues to move nicely then there should be, just a few &#x2013; some reinvestments in marketing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean basically let me take the marketing question first. If we see good ideas, we have the capacity to invest behind them. Equally, if our sales growth tracks with our marketing growth, that's also fine given my point about being well invested in our brands. But if we have headroom and we see good ideas we will back them. Andy, do you want to add more color to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that &#x2013; I mean there isn't a magic number for the ratio. We need to do both lean into growth ideas as Paul said, and we've been doing that for a number of years. And we need to use our scale to drive efficiencies from our preexisting investments. We'll continue to do that around the world as you can see in this set of numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding Western Europe, I mean there is an arithmetical consequence here. As we've gone through a certain level of contraction, the performance is less relevant to the total company. Having said that, we're still seeing softness in those markets. There is no sign that they are leveling out anytime soon, but clearly they're a smaller component of the total and the rate of declines is also decreasing.</p>
          <p>Gilbert, on Chinese New Year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Antoine on Chinese New Year, anecdotally consumer demand on our brands in China is still going very strong, especially on the super side &#x2013; super deluxe side of the business. Johnnie Walker Blue Label in the first half has a stunning performance in China, growing higher than 50%, which has been consistent. Over the last six quarters our super deluxe scotch business in China has grown over 40%. So this trend on super deluxe is still going strong and we are still gaining market share, which is great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe a follow-up on scotch in China. Would you consider that in terms of share of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (59:41), so to speak, now scotch is no longer losing market share to cognac in the region?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The way, Antoine, we look at it, scotch is growing and cognac is growing. Now if you look at scotch, total scotch is growing at 3% but most importantly, super deluxe scotch is growing at 12% and this is where we see the biggest opportunity for scotch in the future and that's where we are channeling the bulk of our energy to fuel and keep driving this trend. And this is where we are winning big time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Trevor Stirling from Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, one question. Sorry to give you another Q1, Q2 question Paul. But it's related to China and Asia Pacific, rather more specifically, that there was an apparent slowdown in Asia Pacific and I wonder if maybe Gilbert could just give a little bit of color around that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gilbert, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Trevor, look there is no slowdown in Asia Pacific and the consumer demand on our brands is still very strong. I'm very excited about the prospects of our business in emerging Asia. We see our business growing strongly in India, in China and in Southeast Asia and there is no reason why I see these trends not to continue in the second half.</p>
          <p>And in the developed markets in Asia of Australia and Korea, yes, the first half was challenging but the second half will be better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Gilbert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Melissa Earlam from UBS. Please go ahead. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I've got three questions please. First of all, you mentioned organic sales growth across your emerging markets of 18% in the half. I was wondering if you could give us an idea what your organic EBIT growth was for the EM region.</p>
          <p>Then secondly, you saw a tick up in scotch inventory in the half. I was wondering if you could quantify that and give us an idea of whether this is part of a broader plan to step up your overall scotch inventory. And given that quite big swing in networking capital outflow in the first half, I was wondering if you could give us a broad range for what the change in working capital might be for the full year fiscal 2012. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll ask Deirdre to handle the working capital. On the 18% organic sales growth in emerging markets, the actual profit growth was higher. I think it was about 4 points higher directionally so we're getting a very good mix effect coming through on that sales growth.</p>
          <p>Your second question Melissa was what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Scotch inventory.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Scotch inventory. Yeah, you're going to continue to see us build our inventories in scotch. I've mentioned several times about the favorable demographics in the emerging markets and the lucrative prospects for scotch. We're going to have to make sure that we lay down liquid to serve those consumers and that's what we have been doing and will continue to do. Deirdre, working capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Melissa. I think the overall working capital in the first half we would expect to see about the same. If you look at the underlying growth in the business, we are seeing impacts on the growth in the receivables and importantly we continue to lay down maturing stock given the very strong growth in our scotch business. So on a net/net basis, I would think it would be in the order of about the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's very interesting, coming back to this emerging market issue, we've said for some time that once we start to get the scale we'd continue to ride the demographics. This is going to be a critical engine of growth. We are starting to see that come through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Jamie Isenwater from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone; a couple of questions from me. Firstly, for Deirdre, in terms of the restructuring charges that you updated us on, is the lower cost for this year a shift in timing or are there actually some savings coming through. If so, what's driven that?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, just on C&#xEE;roc and Mr. Diddy, there were some press reports that he was launch &#x2013; going to launch a tequila and I presume that wasn't in conjunction with Diageo. So I just wondered whether there was any contractual obligations around him starting competitive products or whether it's even true? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then Deirdre, and then Ivan, C&#xEE;roc...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:04:37).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the restructuring costs, I mean as you know when we announced those there were some estimates included with respect to the movements. I do not expect that to just be a shift. It is in fact a reduction and it just had to do with the redeployment of some people, some lower overall costs. But the short answer is it is lower in absolute; we're not expecting that to be a timing shift.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On C&#xEE;roc, as you know there's a lot of speculation and stuff written about our partner so I wouldn't believe everything you read. But what you can be assured is as we have structured our arrangement with Mr. Combs, we've obviously talked about the long term of how we best protect Diageo's interests and he his. So without disclosing anything about our contract, I can assure you we feel comfortable about our future with Mr. Combs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>And I'll take our next question from Alex Molloy from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. On the U.K., just coming back on something, you said Paul, down in the second quarter but I think you said to an earlier question that you expect it to continue about flat. Am I reading that wrongly or do you expect a bit of an improvement there in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We did have a weaker second quarter. We wouldn't expect the second half to be &#x2013; to follow that trend. And overall, we think in the round it will be flat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What will change from the Q2 to the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, do you want to talk specifically about the Q2 events?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean I think as we noted in the release we've had a real focus on improving the quality of the shape of the P&amp;L in GB and we've delivered that. So you're &#x2013; on the half, you're minus two at the sales line but you've got four points of operating year in there. A lot of that has come through us having less debt in frequency of promotion on some of our bigger brands like Smirnoff in particular. And yeah, we'll continue to have that focus; it's working for us. So, yeah, minus two to flat, that's the kind of range. We're certainly not seeing any improvement in category or industry volumes in GB anytime soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Ann Gurkin from Davenport. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Ann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have several questions if that's okay. One, I was wondering if I can get a further update on the progress with integration with distributors in the U.S. Is that meeting expectations? Can you give us some more detail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anecdotally, I met with one of our key distributors only last week. They are thrilled with the improved structure that's in place. But Ivan maybe you can go into more detail on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Ann. Very &#x2013; early good morning to you. No, things are going well. We've made very substantial changes in terms of taking our route to market to the next level; more resources, more focused on priorities like beyond premise and multicultural. We've realigned how we go to market, connecting marketing, trade marketing, to the sales execution. Quite a substantial change and I would say we all feel very good about the changes. You can see it in our performance and I think partnership with our distributors has never been stronger and we are really focused on stepping up the executional excellence every day. So I think the Diageo route to market in the U.S is a big competitive advantage and we intend to keep it that way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That is terrific. Second, may I get an update on global inventory levels at distributors? Is there any area of risk or any area of concern?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My sense is not. We obviously, as we go through our half year close, look at that pretty carefully. I don't see any issue emerging there. Deirdre?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nope, I don't see any issues on the distributor inventories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then Deirdre, can you help me with how you're thinking about currency impacts for the year now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had about a 30 million impact in the first half. We expect for the full year to effectively it to net out, so there will be no impact at the operating profit line or it will be minimal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Super, and then finally Paul you &#x2013; one of your key strategies has been realigning resources globally. Where are you versus that strategy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're absolutely on track. If you look in our developed markets and at the corporate level, we have taken resource out, but equally we continue to invest in the emerging markets and I think it's up about 15%. And we will continue to do that to fuel the opportunities that I constantly reference so we're absolutely on track.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Super, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Simon Marshall-Lockyer from Jefferies. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Could you maybe give us a few further indications or insights into whether there's shift or you're seeing any movement between the off trade and the on trade in the U.S. Give us a bit more color on that and how you see things panning out.</p>
          <p>And the second question is on Mey &#x130;&#xE7;ki, could you give us some indication of how the half went in respect to the core business, the Iraqi business. Obviously you're indicating sort of strong demand for the premium brands but how did the Iraqi business go in the underlying performance at Mey &#x130;&#xE7;ki? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ivan, why don't you go to the on premise trends which are positive and Andrew on Mey &#x130;&#xE7;ki?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now the on premise we figure in total is growing about 2% and if you look at total in volume on spirits. The total spirits industry is growing in the two to three range.</p>
          <p>The thing about the U.S., and if you go back to the 2008 crisis, we did see a drop in the on premise then. It is coming back nicely. Overall, you need to remember the on premise is about 22%, 23% of the total business. So I actually see the channel mix stay relatively resilient. You get a little bit of blips as you go through economic cycles but not the kind of dramatic shifts you've seen in some markets in Europe.</p>
          <p>And you also need to remember in the U.S. by virtue of the three-tier system, our profitability in the on versus off is relatively the same. It's a high margin business in both channels and so these impacts are on the margin, they shift a bit but no dramatic change. And I'm very pleased, actually, with the strength of the on premise coming back because it's a good leading indicator as well for the health of the consumer and certainly the help of the beverage alcohol categories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Mey &#x130;&#xE7;ki, very much in line with our business case and that's despite an excise tax increase that we've &#x2013; that's been applied to the category in Turkey since the acquisition. Quite significant market share gain over the last six months will be the other highlight but we're very much on track is what I would say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Olivier Delahousse from Natixis. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everybody. Olivier from Natixis in Paris. Couple of questions; first one is related to the non-cash item regarding taxes. I was wondering if &#x2013; I'm guessing this is related to brands mostly, but more so to the U.S. jurisdiction in terms of tax. I was wondering if, Deirdre, maybe you could comment a little more on that.</p>
          <p>And secondly I was wondering if there were &#x2013; regarding duty anything, any concern regarding increases in other geographies for the two for one threat; a little update on your perspective in that respect. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on the duty point &#x2013; I will hand over to Deirdre regarding the non-cash tax items. On duties, we have to be alert to duties generally speaking around the world. That said, there are certain markets in the emerging market category where we're actually seeing duties come down because they want to eliminate illicit alcohol or whatever. So it isn't always right to look at it through the lens of the developed world. Nevertheless, we keep our eye on this. There is nothing horrible out there that we see lurking but we're going have to be on our game constantly. Cash tax?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's &#x2013; the write-off of the deferred tax assets was related to intangible brand assets. You may recall that at the full year we said that we expected our tax rate, our effective tax rate, to come in line with the cash tax rate. I mean that's effectively what's happened. As you know, the brand IP is owned in multiple jurisdictions and we were able to reach favorable agreements with the tax jurisdiction so that the basis of taxation now is no longer dependent on the amortization of those brands. And that's what caused the write-off of the deferred tax assets; but yet, an ongoing underlying reduction in our effective rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A small follow-up on that if I may. I guess you won't want to comment on competitors or peers but is this &#x2013; can you mention whether these discussions that you have had with the tax authorities have been on a standalone basis or whether they are likely to have been made with other groups in the industry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They were discussions that we had with the tax authorities. They were not industry-related.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Nico Lambrechts from Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there, Paul and team. Thank you very much and it's late in the queue and just two questions. The first is could you repeat maybe the actual cost savings number which you did in your prepared script?</p>
          <p>And then the second question, apologies if I'm going  a little bit deeper down the rabbit hole that mentioned Paul, but the first quarter number, 9%, I think the underlying number was about 6% to 7%; the second quarter 5% growth if we strip out the one-off benefits pre-buying ahead of excise is probably around 4%. Could you maybe indicate if there's, in the next quarter, potential technical impacts, i.e. reversals of the pre-buying in France and LatAm? And if you think that the reported number will be impacted negatively by these technical effects for the third quarter. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Over to Deirdre.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I &#x2013; on the benefits on restructuring, we have said for the full year it was around 40 million. I don't have the precise number in front of me for the first half. It was a little bit less than half because they'll tend to increase through the full year but we expect we're on track for that.</p>
          <p>On the second question, can you repeat the second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just asking are there any of these technical impacts that benefited the first quarter and second quarter and specifically the pre-buying in Latin America and France that will reverse in the third quarter, by the quarter into March.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, as Andrew suggested earlier, the impacts in France and there was some also in Spain, they're not material so we don't expect it to have a material impact on the underlying trends. And as I said earlier, I think the shifts on the first quarter to the second quarter, we're not expecting any of that to be impacting the full year trends in the &#x2013; or the underlying trends in the business for the full year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is it fair to say that the underlying trends were around 6% to 7% in the first quarter, slightly below 5% in the second quarter and that your third quarter will face a much tougher comp than the previous two quarters? And should that have any impact on the quarterly numbers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think I would say as you know, we're not giving quarter-by-quarter guidance in terms of the underlying results. I would say that the trends that we've seen in the underlying performance of the business we believe are sustainable, again given the comments that Paul and the Presidents have already made about the clear macroeconomic impacts that would impact consumer confidence. We are confident in the underlying performance of the brands and the investments that we've made in the brands are delivering the returns that we have expected. It's coming through in gross margin and in operating margin and right now we're not seeing anything that would impact that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much Deirdre.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our last question today from Pablo Zuanic from Liberum Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good morning everyone; hopefully last but not least. And I know it's late in the queue, so very quickly, number one the U.S margins are so much higher than the rest of the company, but the U.S., the North American business is mostly whites &#x2013; it's more white spirits-weighted than the rest of the world and I always thought brown spirits would be more profitable. It's a larger country, more distribution costs, third-party distribution is mandatory; so I'm just thinking why are the margins so much higher or is it that just the other divisions are quite low and they're sort of the outside? That's one question.</p>
          <p>The second question in terms of our &#x2013; at the moment if I look at your numbers in emerging Asia in terms of growth versus Latin America, they're both very similar; high teens, almost 20% on average. When you look out more longer term, which of those two is more sustainable? I mean from outside, when we think Asia, emerging Asia, there's more long-term growth potential but maybe I'm missing something there.</p>
          <p>And the third one and last, when you see all the growth around craft beer in the U.S., premium beer, now that new Bud Light Platinum is supposedly trying to compete with spirits, and I hear apparently ABI trying to launch a malt beverage, a round malt beverage I think with Bacardi, do you see room to do something in that area or even to reignite your RTD strategy there? That's all. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe, Ivan, you can pick up that last point. Regarding the U.S., what I would say and this is not dissimilar for many consumer products companies. The sheer scale of that market just gives a level of efficiency that does allow higher margins. If you think of your media reach, the fact that you can scale organization, a variety things just point to it being generally a more profitable market.</p>
          <p>Brown spirits, particularly at the high end, are seeing some resurgence and bring with them very attractive margins. So we could see this being enhanced.</p>
          <p>I wouldn't want to call the race between, say, Asia and Latin America. Both of those markets have got huge potential and if you look at what has been achieved in our Latin division, whilst Asia does tend to get a lot of the media attention, Latin America has been strong, very attractive growth for a number of years. Ivan, on the craft side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look at the trends that are happening in ready-to-drink beer, the craft space, it's quite an exciting space. I mean innovation does make a difference. And from a Diageo standpoint to North America, this business is still important to us. There's a consumer demand that is actually quite robust. And as we go into the second half we actually, right now, we have some new products in the marketplace, the Smirnoff premium mixed drinks line with products like Screwdriver, just got into the market; doing very well.</p>
          <p>And I have to say I'm also very excited about the Parrot Bay frozen cocktail line of pouches that we've introduced in the marketplace. Early days, but it looks very, very encouraging. This is essentially getting a high quality frozen cocktail in a pouch for about $2. And as you merchandise these products, they're doing extremely well.</p>
          <p>So I think the space is innovation intensive. You're going to have winners and losers and we've seen that in our track record here. But I'm optimistic about holding our position here and, as I said, going into the second half you will see a fair degree of pretty exciting innovation from Diageo in the space in North America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me, try and bring this to a close and first of all thank you for your questions. As I said in the presentation, this has been a good, well-balanced half-year performance. And I do hope that in the last 90 minutes or so I've been helpful to you to understand how that growth has been driven.</p>
          <p>I look forward to meeting a number of you over the next few weeks, but for now thank you for your time and good-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>