<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1211076" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Interim 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-02-12</date>
    <companies>
      <company>586</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Paul Walsh, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Nick Rose, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3">Trevor Stirling</participant>
      <participant id="4">Paul Walsh</participant>
      <participant id="5">Andrew Morgan</participant>
      <participant id="6">Nico Lambrechts</participant>
      <participant id="7">Antoine Belge</participant>
      <participant id="8">Nick Rose</participant>
      <participant id="9">Stuart Fletcher</participant>
      <participant id="10">Ivan Menezes</participant>
      <participant id="11">John Pollaers</participant>
      <participant id="12">Matthew Webb</participant>
      <participant id="13">Christopher Wickham</participant>
      <participant id="14">Ann Gurkin</participant>
      <participant id="15">Gerard Rijk</participant>
      <participant id="16">Melissa Earlam</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thanks for your time today.  Our results today demonstrate that Diageo can deliver growth, even in these challenging times.  We've built a strong business through the right investments, targeted acquisitions and a consistently disciplined financial approach.  As a result, we're driving growth and share gains from our well-managed brands and effective routes to market.  And that's underpinned by our scale as the world's leading premium drinks company.  In addition, in the current environment we are benefiting from the positive impact of exchange rate movements.  And this is likely to continue into the next financial year.  We will continue to invest in this business, marketing activity behind our core premium brands is up, our innovation pipeline is bringing some of our most successful brand launches to market and we continue to build our scale in emerging markets.  The organizational review we have announced today is part of that investment in our future.  It will reduce costs at a time when price increases may be more difficult to achieve and it will remove a layer in the business which means that in an environment where things are changing fast, we remain agile to changing consumer and customer trends.  The whole program is designed to ensure that Diageo emerges from this global economic downturn as an even stronger business for the future.</p>
          <p>The half-year results we issued today cover a period of unprecedented economic change.  However, we've managed this impact and the impact it's had on our business and delivered further growth across the key financial measures.  We've delivered 3% organic net sales growth, media rate deflation and efficiency in promotional spend combined with our decision to reduce spend behind the ready to drink segment has led to 1% organic decline in marketing spend period-on-period while investment measured in activity around our brands has increased.  Operating margins improved further 40 basis points and operating profit grew 6%.  Underlying EPS growth was 9%.  Our reported results were of course much stronger.  Additions, especially in respect of Ketel One, drove two percentage points of net sales growth and three percentage points of operating profit growth.  We're also benefiting from the strength of the U.S. dollar and the euro.  And exchange movements increased net sales by 13 percentage points and operating profit by eight percentage points.</p>
          <p>Moving to cash, we have generated strong free cash flow and returned nearly &#xA3;900 million to shareholders while maintaining our strong financial position.  And again, we have increased our interim dividend by 5%.  Nick is now going to take you through the financial aspects of the half-year performance, both the organic performance and the reported results.  I will then describe the changes we have seen in both consumer demand and the wider business landscape, and how our response to these changes are designed to ensure that Diageo emerges from these challenges with an even stronger business than that we have today.  Nick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Paul, and good morning everyone.  Paul has just shown you a summary of our results; organic growth, acquisitions, exchange rate movements, and the reduction in our tax rate have had a significant impact in the half.  And therefore, I'm going to spend longer than usual going through the details, and in particular some of the financial and accounting impacts.  The first half reported results have been driven by the delivery of good organic growth, delivering our objectives for Ketel One, Rosenblum and Zacapa and the benefit of strong exchange rate movements.</p>
          <p>On an organic basis, volume declined 2%, mainly as the result of our scotch strategy to balance long-term supply and demand by increasing price.  Volume of our scotch brands declined by 10%, but this was offset by 13 percentage points of price improvement resulting from our fiscal 2008 scotch pricing policy.  Volume also declined in ready-to-drink, impacted by our decision to reduce customer stock levels in the U.S. and by the full in RTD volume in Australia.  Against this, we delivered strong overall volume growth in Vodka, Rum, North American Whisky and Beer.  We estimate the U.S. spirits distributor stock levels were higher at the end of the half.  This was partially offset by lower retail trade stock levels.  For U.S. beer and malt-based ready-to-drink brands, we reduced distributor stock levels as part of an ongoing program to bring stock levels down as the ready-to-drink segment continued to decline and to ensure Guinness quality in the on-trade.</p>
          <p>In Europe, stock levels reduced, mainly driven by the reduction in Spain.  In International and Asia Pacific, stock levels were also down.  Overall price mix improvements of five percentage points led to organic net sales growth of 3%.  Ketel One, Rosenblum Cellars and Zacapa increased reported net sales by &#xA3;97 million.  And as this slide shows, exchange rate movements have had a major impact on our results.  The U.S. dollar translation rate has moved from 2.03 in the prior period to 1.66 and the euro translation rate has moved from 1.43 to 1.21.  This has resulted in very strong reported performance in the period, and I'll come on to the outlook for exchange later.</p>
          <p>So, moving now to organic net sales growth by region.  As this slide shows, our performance in International and America was the key driver of total NSV growth.  In North America, the main drivers of the net sales growth were the strong performances of Smirnoff, Captain Morgan, Crown Royal and C&#xEE;roc.  Net sales in International grew 11% with eight percentage points of that coming from the performance in Africa.</p>
          <p>In Europe, the weakness of the Spanish economy and the impact this has had on consumer demand and customer confidence had a significant impact on regional performance.  A gradual slowdown after the summer became a steep decline in late November.  Similar weakness in Ireland and GB, albeit partially offset in GB by our outperformance, also impacted Europe's organic net sales growth.  In contrast, we have benefited from the strength of the Russian market in the half and in Continental Europe are focused on the biggest growth opportunities for our brands, has again delivered top-line growth.  In Asia Pacific, we have as expected seen the benefit of the return through our own in-market distribution in Korea, offset by the fall in ready-to-drink in Australia as a result of the excise duty increase there.  Growth in China and India have driven overall net sales growth of 2%.  Combined with net sales growth, the biggest drivers of our 6% organic operating profit growth were International and North America.  In North America, consumers are switching to premium and standard brands and this has benefited our leading brands in the premium segment, namely Smirnoff, Captain Morgan, Crown Royal.  These brands are already well supported with marketing spend and we're leveraging this spend to deliver margin expansion.</p>
          <p>In Europe, organic operating profit declined 4%. The economic weakness in Spain has led to a significant decline in consumer demand.  This is a high margin market for us weighted to the on-trade.  This decline in demand, especially for scotch, has led to a declining top line and has reduced margin.  In addition, we decided not to fill orders equivalent to about 30-days sales to reduce the risk of customer default in the long-term.  This fall in operating profit in Spain offset operating profit growth in Continental Europe and in Russia.  In international, Africa delivered a very strong performance with growth of 25%.  Tougher economic conditions in Latin America and Caribbean held organic operating profit growth there to 4% and there was a slight fall in operating profit in Global Travel and the Middle East.  In Asia Pacific, we continued to increase marketing spend behind our brands and to invest in routes to market and overheads.  Operating profit was therefore 5% lower in the half.  Corporate costs were down &#xA3;15 million and also benefited from a &#xA3;21 million ForEx credit.  We hold the difference between our budget rate and the actual rate in the period in corporate, although it could in theory be allocated to the regions, and of course this treatment has effectively reduced the organic growth for the regions in the half.  Additions, again primarily with respect to Ketel One, led to an increase in reported operating profit of &#xA3;46 million.</p>
          <p>Exchange movements increased reported operating profit by &#xA3;103 million.  There was a translation benefit of &#xA3;154 million and an adverse transaction impact of &#xA3;51 million.  The current extreme volatility of exchange rate movements means that any under or overhedged positions at the period end can create a significant gain or loss.  This half, we were overhedged, increasing the average transaction rates.  Of course, this impact reverses in fiscal 2010 giving us a positive transaction exchange movement then.  And later, I'll show you the total impact exchange has had on earnings and look at the projections for both the balance of this year and for next year.</p>
          <p>Our marketing spend in the half has been impacted by a number of factors.  Firstly, we've reduced our marketing spend on ready-to-drink brands as a result of the decline in the segment in North America and the decline in Australia.  Secondly, we have seen an increase in our spend in Asia Pacific as we return to our own distribution in Korea.  In the same period last year, marketing spend was undertaken by our third-party distributor.  Thirdly, we've benefited from the deflation in media rates primarily in North America and Europe.  The scope of this deflation varies by market and channel from a 20% reduction in TV rates in some markets to a 5% reduction in print campaigns.  In North America, as highlighted at our Investor Conference back in November, we have changed our focus as a result of the move by consumers from deluxe brands to premium and value brands.</p>
          <p>In the super and ultra premium segments, we're focusing our spend on C&#xEE;roc and Don Julio, and in the premium segment we've increased our spend behind our key brands; Smirnoff, Jos&#xE9; Cuervo and Captain Morgan.  In Europe, we have reduced our marketing spend in Spain as lower consumer demand has impacted the performance of our brands, especially J&amp;B.  However, marketing as a percent of net sales in Spain has increased.  Similarly, spend on our beer brands in Ireland has reduced in line with the category decline.  And in Asia Pacific, we've increased spend behind all of our scotch brands in China, and in India, we've increased spend significantly on Johnnie Walker.</p>
          <p>Moving now to the improvement we've delivered in operating margin. Gross profit increased in the period, but the gross margin declined as raw material costs increased as expected.  We contract for a proportion of our raw material supplies under rolling hedging programs, and therefore, some of our H1 volume was hedged last summer when most commodity prices were trading at all-time highs.  And as we had anticipated, we did see a decline in gross margins, as underlying COGS increases of approximately 7% were only partially covered by price increases.</p>
          <p>In the half, we've delivered 5 percentage points of price and mix.  About 60% of this price mix was due to the increase we put through in fiscal '08 on our scotch brands as part of our strategy to balance long-term supply and demand.  The remainder of the price mix benefit was mainly driven by price increases to cover our input cost increases.  And in fiscal 2010, I would expect to see a lower level of price rises as we've made good progress in rebalancing scotch supply and demand and as cost inflation has moderated.  And therefore, volume performance, especially on scotch, should be stronger than in the current year.</p>
          <p>In the second half, we'll see some improvement in energy costs and some savings on cream and grain costs in Europe.  The refocusing of marketing spend, together with the savings from media rate deflation, improved margin.  And in addition, the actions we have taken to reduce overheads in North America and in Corporate have also improved operating margins.  These overhead reductions were partially offset by increased spend on routes to market in International and in Asia Pacific.</p>
          <p>So moving on to other lines in the income statement.  As this slide shows, the 17% growth in reported operating profit has been offset by higher net finance charges.  There are a number of reasons for this, and so I'm going to take you through them in some detail.</p>
          <p>The significant changes we've seen in exchange rates have been the biggest single driver of the increase in the net finance charges in the half.  In H1 fiscal '08, our average debt was &#xA3;5.3 billion and our interest coupon was 5.8%.  In the six months to December 2008, average debt has increased to &#xA3;7.6 billion, of which over &#xA3;0.9 billion was the effect of exchange rate movements.</p>
          <p>Foreign exchange movements increased our interest charge by &#xA3;44 million in the half.  And at current exchange rates, I would expect that for the full year, exchange rate movements will increase the interest charge by about &#xA3;95 million.  Our average interest coupon excluding the impact of IAS 39 was 6.6%. And at current floating rates, I estimate that our full-year interest rate will reduce slightly to about 6.3%.  Under IAS 39, we recognize the interest &#x2013; in the interest charge, movements in the market value of interest rate swaps at the end of the period.  This increased the net interest charge by &#xA3;31 million -- that's an increase of 27 million over the prior period.  And as previously announced, finance income in respect of post-employment plans will be nil for the current year, having been &#xA3;46 million last year.  Against the same period last year, this represented a reduction in income of &#xA3;23 million.  Movements in short-term intercompany balances under IAS 21 and IAS 39 have increased our finance charges in the half by &#xA3;19 million; that's an increase of 12 million over the prior period.  And again for the full year, at current exchange rates, I would estimate that the application of IAS 21 and IAS 39 will increase our total finance charge year-on-year by approximately &#xA3;40 million, having adversely impacted the half-year charge by &#xA3;39 million -- although again, as I say, this is a difficult figure to forecast.  Other finance charges are &#xA3;28 million in the half, mainly arising from changes in fair value accounting, an increase of 13 million over the prior period.</p>
          <p>These rather unusual accounting movements on our net finance charges do not affect cash interest and this is perhaps best illustrated by looking at our interest cover in the half.  P&amp;L interest cover is six times with cash interest cover at nine times.  This increase in net finance charges caused the increase in PBET to be limited to 5%.  The exceptional charge relates to the Ireland brewing project and I would expect the full year charge here to be about &#xA3;30 million.  As you know, we're reviewing this project to ensure that it can deliver on our financial goals, even in a changed economic environment. And we may slow the project, which would reduce the capital spend both in fiscal '09 and in 2010.  There have been a number of changes in respect of the tax charge for this half, and so I'll take you through these now.  We've been able to deliver a steady reduction in the underlying tax rate since 2007.  In the first half of fiscal '08, the underlying tax rate was 26% and we were able to reduce the full year fiscal 2008 rate to 24.5%.  As you know, our guidance did not anticipate this reduction and there is always a level of uncertainty about tax rates given changes to tax legislation.  And in the six months to the 31st of December, 2008, we were able to further reduce the underlying tax rate to 22%.  However, there are currently some proposed changes again to tax legislation, which may increase this rate to 24% for the full year. And in giving our guidance, we're assuming that this tax legislation will be enacted.</p>
          <p>Going forward, I expect that we can sustain this 24% rate for the next few years. And this represents an improvement against our guidance in August 2008 when I anticipated that the rate would be 25%.  The reported tax charge was 15% in the first half, as we've agreed a number of settlements with tax authorities.  This has given rise to changes in the value of deferred tax assets and tax provisions held in the balance sheet.  And these changes in balance sheet values have to be recognized in the P&amp;L.  As you may remember, in 2006 and 2007 similar movements in the balance sheet values also gave rise to differences between the P&amp;L tax charge and our underlying tax rate.  For the full year, I expect that the reported P&amp;L tax charge will be 17%.</p>
          <p>Our ongoing cash tax rate should also improve slightly to 20%.  However, following a number of years when cash tax paid has been lower than this, in fiscal 2009 and 2010 I would expect that cash tax paid will be approximately &#xA3;600 million which represents a rate of approximately 25% as we make the cash payments associated with the settlements.  Our free cash flow generation remains a key strength.  The reported increase in operating profit generated nearly &#xA3;0.25 billion more cash this half.  The rise in our interest coupon and the increase in net debt has increased our interest paid by &#xA3;59 million.  This is less than a third of the increase in net finance charges, which again demonstrates our financial strength.  There has been a modest increase in the tax paid, but as I said, I would expect this to be up approximately &#xA3;200 million in the full year.</p>
          <p>Working capital increased by 147 million, more than in the prior period.  Inventories increased, in part due to the decision we made to withhold stock on orders we received at the end of December to mitigate the credit risk of some customers and also due to our program to build our maturing whisky stocks.  This was offset by the reduction in the period-on-period increase in debtors, which in this half was over &#xA3;100 million less than last year, mainly due to a &#xA3;50 million reduction in trade debtors.  Our move to a common SAP system around the business led to a significant reduction in payables as we moved to common trade terms.  And this has had an adverse impact on working capital.  As anticipated, capital expenditure increased mainly behind our investment in scotch distilling capacity, and there were fewer disposals in the half.</p>
          <p>As this slide shows, the biggest driver of the increase in net borrowings was exchange, which increased period end net borrowings by &#xA3;1.5 billion.  Spend on acquisitions was mainly the investment we made to increase our shareholding in the Sichuan Chinese white spirit venture and to buy out the remaining 25% minority interest in our joint venture in Russia.</p>
          <p>In the first half, we returned &#xA3;354 million to shareholders through the buyback.  As you'll remember, when we began the fiscal year, we had the capacity to return &#xA3;750 million to shareholders.  In October, we slowed our buyback program as global economic events impacted equity and debt markets.  Since the beginning of the new calendar year, we've not reactivated the buyback.  And in the current volatile economic environment, we believe that our focus should move from balance sheet efficiency to preserving our advantaged financial position.  And therefore, I would not expect that our buyback program will be re-implemented in the balance of calendar 2009.</p>
          <p>So having already described the impacts that individual exchange movements have had on our reported results, I thought it would be helpful to pull them together.  As you can see, the net positive impact of translation and transaction on trading profit and interest was partially offset by the negative of ForEx and mark-to-market movements under IAS 21 and IAS 39.  These do not have a cash impact.  I expect that the positive impact of exchange in the full year will be considerably higher than the first half movements, as you can see.  And for 2010, at current rates, I would expect that foreign exchange will again increase operating profit by more than &#xA3;200 million and increase the interest charge by &#xA3;30 million.</p>
          <p>Reported EPS in the first half was 45.6p per share against 37.6p per share in the first half of fiscal '08.  This is an increase of 21%.  The impact of foreign exchange was partially offset by the impact of IAS 21 and IAS 39, and the biggest driver of the difference between reported and underlying EPS growth is the reduction in the tax rate.</p>
          <p>As this chart shows, underlying EPS growth in the half was 9%; that's 43.4p per share against 39.7p per share in the first half of fiscal '08.  We've again driven an improvement in economic profit, up &#xA3;140 million.  Organic operating profit growth was the biggest driver and increased EP by &#xA3;86 million.  Exchange and the lower tax rate have also contributed to the improvement.  This organic growth has driven the further improvement in return on invested capital, up another 20 basis points.</p>
          <p>So before I hand back to Paul, let me sum up.  The economic climate weakened through the period.  However we've again delivered organic top and bottom-line growth and an improvement in key financial measures, expanding operating margin and increasing our return on invested capital.  Reported growth has benefited from foreign exchange movements and at current exchange rates this is forecast to improve in the second half and to continue into fiscal 2010.</p>
          <p>The reported tax rate and our ongoing underlying tax rate are both lower and we'll also benefit from a reduction in the cash tax rate of about 1%.  The second half will undoubtedly bring more challenges.  However, we're confident in Diageo's strengths, our brands, our global reach and our people.  And we believe we will deliver solid full year organic operating profit growth.  Uncertainty over the trends we will see in the macro-environment makes it very difficult to forecast and give guidance, but we expect to deliver organic operating profit growth for the full year of between four and 6% as we continue to benefit from marketing deflation and as we drive overheads down in H2.</p>
          <p>We have announced a restructuring program, which is designed to ensure that Diageo emerges from this challenging time with improved routes to market, even stronger brand positions and enhanced financial strength.  Anticipated full year savings in both cost of goods sold and in overheads of &#xA3;100 million will accrue largely in fiscal 2010.  The cost to achieve these savings amounting to approximately &#xA3;200 million will be taken as an exceptional charge in the second half. And not all of this will have a cash impact.  Positive exchange rate movements and the lower tax rate mean that our reported EPS growth, even after this exceptional charge, should still be double-digit.  And our continued confidence in the business allows us to increase the interim dividend by 5.3%, in line with our policy.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll hand back to Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Nick.  This half has seen a period of great change, and we're aware that the impact the economic environment has had on the consumer.  For our sector, the gradual consumer slowdown of the early part of the half became much more pronounced in late November and through December.  Against this background, our first half performance highlights Diageo's strengths.  We can manage these difficult times more robustly than many other businesses.  We have a strong business. It's the result of consistent investment behind our brands and markets.  Those investments have built the broadest leading brand range in the industry with the widest geographical reach.  We have very strong and experienced management, and this will be a real competitive advantage as we ensure we come out of this recession as an even stronger business.</p>
          <p>Our first half performance highlights the value we can drive from brand additions.  As Nick outlined, we made a number of decisions in the half, including our recent debt issuances and our decision to slow the share buyback, which have preserved our advantaged financial position.  This will allow us to make the investments which will strengthen our business even further.</p>
          <p>In the next few slides, I'm going to review the way we have managed the current economic climate and look at the actions we can take to manage the impact of the weakening global economy.  The key driver of our first half performance in North America was our strength in the premium spirits category.</p>
          <p>As this slide shows, there has been a slowdown in super and ultra premium segment growth and an improvement in the value and popular brands.  But premium brands have been the most resilient segment and are gaining share in this economic slowdown. Nearly 50% of our business in this segment and we have the leading brands: Smirnoff, Captain Morgan and Johnnie Walker Red.  In the half, we have focused our investment, both marketing spend and innovation on these brands.  In addition, we've been targeted about investment in the super premium and ultra premium segment, focusing on those brands that have strong momentum -- Ketel One, C&#xEE;roc and Nuvo.  Below the premium segment, we are tactically supporting our brands at the value and popular price points at a local level.  In the half, our priority brands have again grown share, up 20 basis points.  And we have held share in total spirits, which outperforms all the major spirits companies in the U.S.</p>
          <p>In beer, we have outperformed the import segment, but we have seen some pressure in Guinness with the shift to the off-trade.  In wine, consumers have been trading down and we have faced challenges, as our wines are more premium.  In Canada, we built on last year's strong performance and net sales were up 10%.  In the U.S. and Canada, media rate deflation was about 10%.  We've captured these benefits and together with action on discretionary overheads, we've delivered a further improvement in operating margin in North America.  New additions are performing well, as they have benefited from Diageo's superior route to market and they have contributed &#xA3;92 million to net sales and &#xA3;44 million to operating profit over the period.  In this half, we've integrated each of these brands into our dedicated sales teams.  And they have delivered in line with our expectations despite current market weakness.</p>
          <p>In calendar 2009, we will continue the strategy we have applied in the first half.  We will focus on our flagship premium brands: Smirnoff, Captain Morgan, Jos&#xE9; Cuervo and Crown Royal.  These brands are those which consumers reach for in today's environment.  In January, each of these brands again performed strongly.  We'll continue to make these brands the focus of our innovation, building on the success of the first half of Smirnoff Flavors and Smirnoff Cocktails and Captain Morgan 100.</p>
          <p>Our marketing spend will be focused on these brands and we will target spend at the at home consumer occasion.  One of the things we will be doing is to use search engine marketing to attract consumers to a website where there can get real cocktail recipes to help them entertain at home.  We are seeing growth in the value end of the category.  We have good brands in this space, such as Popov and Gordon's, and we will activate at a local level so that we can be more responsive to local consumer trends.  In contrast to the general trend in the super and ultra premium segments, we are driving growth in Ketel One, C&#xEE;roc and Nuvo.  Our marketing spend on reserved brands will prioritize these brands as we capitalize on their current momentum.</p>
          <p>Our first half results for Europe are weaker than we'd expected, primarily as a result of the very poor Spanish market.  We anticipated the decline of the market in July through October.  Although we did expect the market to continue to decline steadily through the fiscal year, we did not anticipate what we saw in November and December.  In addition, the fall in sales was driven by the inability of many wholesalers to fund their stock.  In December, we saw wholesalers return stock which we'd shipped to them and we held back orders amounting to about 250,000 cases where we were concerned about the credit risk of the customer.  The weakness of the beer market in Europe, primarily GB and Ireland, has had a negative impact on our performance.  In tough markets, our brands, especially Guinness, have outperformed, but this has not been enough to generate growth.  Russia has continued to grow strongly in the half, and Johnnie Walker and White Horse have both grown share.  Despite the economic weakness and the continued shift to the off-trade, our spirits brands performed strongly in GB, and each of our key brands delivered net sales growth.</p>
          <p>In Continental Europe, focus on scotch and Smirnoff has again led to growth and share gains as France, the world's biggest scotch market, continues to grow; and with vodka, the growth category across the Europe.  In Eastern Europe, where we've seen market weakness, we've improved our share in key categories.  As in Spain, we've operated a conservative sales policy with respect to some customers.  This has negatively impacted our sales growth, but improved our cash position with lower overdue debtors in the period.  We're benefiting from media deflation.  So while spend was maintained in line with net sales, we have increased our effectiveness around strong campaigns.</p>
          <p>As Nick referred to, we enter the second half with reduced stock levels in Europe.  We will monitor these in light of changes in consumer demand and will continue to review customer orders in order to protect our cash position.  Initial indications in GB, which is a key market for us, would suggest that stock levels here are no longer being reduced, as January sales to key customers were up significantly.  In some of our largest markets in Europe, we face a weak economic environment.  To succeed in this environment, we will focus on the momentum we have in our core mainstream brands: Smirnoff, Baileys, Johnnie Walker Red Label and J&amp;B.  In addition, we will use innovation to address consumer shifts.  The biggest opportunity here is the at-home occasion and we've already identified innovation around our core brands for premix and for cocktails.  As I will come on to, some of the highest levels of media rate deflation are in Europe.  In the second half, I expect that marketing spend as a percentage of sales will fall in Europe as we aggressively address these reductions.  We recently announced changes to our organization in Europe.  We removed a layer in the organization to improve the interaction between the leadership team and the markets and to ensure that we share best practice through the region.  This will reduce the cost base in the second half.</p>
          <p>The performance in International reflects continued very strong growth in Africa.  In the half, Africa has not been as affected by the global economic crisis as other continents.  This is only part of the strength of our performance here though.  We're benefiting from the investments we've made in our brands and infrastructure, including production capacity.  We're already seeing the benefit of our new joint venture in South Africa and we have seen each of our brands there grow their share.  In our three biggest markets in Latin America -- Venezuela, Brazil and Mexico -- we delivered strong growth and gained share in scotch with strong performance in Johnnie Walker and Buchanan's and in Rum and ready-to-drink.  Elsewhere, the global economic weakness has had an impact and currency devaluations mean we've had to price up our imported products in local currency in order to maintain hard currency revenue.  This has led to a reduction in volume especially in scotch, but we've delivered overall net sales growth.</p>
          <p>In Global Travel &amp; Middle East, we've seen some impact of the global economic downturn, but grew net sales, a result of our higher pricing policy around scotch.  As we look to the rest of the year in International, we will continue to deliver growth in beer in Africa.  I expect that the global economy will have some impact on Africa's growth going forward.  However, our brands represent an affordable luxury for many African consumers.  And I therefore believe that while the growth rate may slow, Africa continues to present a major opportunity for Diageo.  In Africa, we have driven strong growth from our innovations, Senator, Harp, Foundry cider and in ready-to-drink.  We will continue to build this pipeline of successful innovations.</p>
          <p>In Global Travel, we're already delivering strengthened retail execution in partnership with our customers in many airports around the world, and our program in the second half steps this up even further.  In Latin America, we benefited from the very experienced management team that we have there.  We will continue to drive growth in our three largest markets, where we benefit from our in-market distribution.</p>
          <p>Currency volatility will continue to be a challenge in some markets.  We will continue to take price to cover local currency devaluations as we focus on value.  This may lead to some loss of volume.  However, we've always managed these premium brands for the long term and that will continue to be our strategy.  To partially mitigate this volume decline in the short term, we will activate against some of our value segment scotch brands.</p>
          <p>As in Europe, we've seen an improved level of customer orders in January, which suggests that trade stock levels are not currently under pressure.  In Asia Pacific, we delivered strong growth in spirits and beer, but this overall performance in Asia Pacific was impacted by two factors in the half: the return to a market distribution in Korea and the decline in the ready-to-drink segment in Australia as a result of the increase in excise duties.  At the operating profit level, these two factors broadly offset each other.  Reported volume growth was lower as a result of both factors accounting for six percentage points of the overall volume decline.  Marketing spend was up as a result of the changes in Korea and marketing spend on ready-to-drink in Australia was reduced.  Excluding these two factors, marketing spend increased 8%.</p>
          <p>In the rest of Asia Pacific, our scotch pricing strategy led to lower volume, but net sales increased.  In China, India and Vietnam, we've accelerated growth and grew share.  And even in tough markets in Asia Pacific, we gained share.  For example, in Taiwan, where the scotch market declined, strong volume growth of Johnnie Walker Black Label and Singleton together with price increases drove 20% net sales growth and share gains.  In India, we gained significant market share with Johnnie Walker Black Label and Smirnoff.  The region has been impacted by the global economic slowdown as stock market falls and credit restrictions have affected consumer confidence.  In China and Southeast Asia, we have seen customers reduce their stock levels, which has impacted our sales.  Marketing spend increased in China, and behind our spirits brands in Australia.  In those markets where we have reduced marketing spend, we either maintained or increased our share of voice.  We've continued to invest in the infrastructure of our fastest growing markets and this has impacted overall profit growth.</p>
          <p>In Asia Pacific, we already have an effective strategy in place and as you have seen we are beating the competition in many markets.  As the economic situation further impacts consumers, we will prioritize sales executions and outlet expansion.  There is strong demand for our brands from consumers in many cities where we do not yet have full account coverage, particularly in China, India and Vietnam.  We will expand outlet coverage to new cities, challenging the competition wherever they're present.  To do this, we will build more partnerships and alliances with strategic customers and maximize the efficient use of trade funds.  Our investment will continue in these critical markets behind our leading brands Johnnie Walker and Smirnoff, the launch of Windsor in China and the expansion of Singleton across Asia Pacific. And it will build on its success in Taiwan.</p>
          <p>We are identifying the most cost effective way of communicating with our consumers.  This means more emphasis on digital and relationship marketing.  Asia Pacific is now the most internet connected consumer market in the world and we are taking advantage of that to reach more consumers.  And finally, there's still a significant opportunity for our reserve business in Asia Pacific.  Since we launched Johnnie Walker Gold Reserve in Thailand, we have seen around 10% of consumers trading up from Johnnie Walker Black Label to Gold Reserve, which shows the impact of solid investment behind key reserve brands.  We'll also be driving the penetration of C&#xEE;roc and launching Ketel One in our biggest markets.</p>
          <p>As consumers change, then we have to change the way in which we market our brands and the messages that we have to deliver to them.  Consumers continue to look to trusty brands and this can be reinforced through the use of campaigns which the consumer recognizes.  In Ireland for example, to kick off the 250th anniversary of Guinness we've used five classic ads rather than creating new copy.  This is more efficient way of driving share growth and we save creative costs.  We're taking advantage of media rate deflation, which is currently running at about 20%.  In North America, we negotiated savings in our Captain Morgan and Crown Royal cable slots ahead of the Super Bowl.  Out of home advertising is also cheaper.  We've seen a double-digit reduction in costs in Spain between March and October.  In the U.S., we've negotiated a 20% reduction on existing advertising and we benefited from price reductions where we've purchased new inventory.</p>
          <p>We have also switched our advertising formats and I would expect our spend on digital to double this year.  In Asia, digital now accounts with 25% of all above the line spend and is expected to rise to 40% by the end of the year.</p>
          <p>We have a clear approach to innovation in the current economic climate.  We will innovate around our core brands. The consumer wants variety. That doesn't change during the recession.  However, they are more selective in what they are willing to try and look for tried and trusted quality brands.  We have a competitive advantage in the range of brands we can use as an innovation platform.  In the first half, we saw the benefits that we can drive from focusing innovation on our core brands.  Captain Morgan 100 Proof is already the largest spirit innovation Diageo has launched in North America.  Building on the strong Captain Morgan brand, it extends the brand's usage.  Similarly in Australia, Bundaberg Red has built on the Bundaberg brand, contributing to 43% sales growth in the Bundaberg spirit trademark in Australia in the first half.</p>
          <p>As the consumer shift accelerates from on-trade to the off-trade, we are leveraging the strengths of our spirits trademarks to extend into new consumer occasions at home with things like premixes and cocktails.  Premix offers a convenient, high quality, affordable option to the consumer.  Ready to serve cocktails provide bar quality popular cocktails which some consumers just don't feel confident making at home.  And finally, we will up-weight our innovation activity on gifting and limited additions.  This leverages our brands and generates a rapid return.  Volumes are small, but the margin is very attractive.  The ultimate example is the 12 bottles of Windsor Diamond Jubilee that we will be launching this half at &#xA3;50,000 a bottle.  The target consumer group is small, but their affluence is such that even in the current environment, they do not trade down.</p>
          <p>Before we take your questions, let me just say a few words about how we see the future.  In the first half, we have delivered growth. We've gained share, we've generated cash and we've increased our dividends. This is a strong business.  We have an amazing brand range, the most diverse geographic reach in this industry and an experienced management team.  No one can forecast with accuracy in these markets, but we know the actions we can and will take in this business if the environment we face changes.  Our guidance this morning takes into account these factors.  The decision to issue guidance in the current uncertain macroeconomic climate is of course a difficult one.  Our decision to give guidance for this fiscal year is based on our confidence in our brands, our routes to market and our people.</p>
          <p>These are extraordinary times and we must ensure that the decisions we take as we manage through them enhance our business for the long-term.  It is for this reason that we've decided to implement a restructuring program in Diageo designed to ensure that we emerge to face the future as a stronger business.  The program will cover all aspects of our business.  We expect to implement these changes quickly, but we're not yet in the position to take you through the program in detail, as we now have to enter into a formal process with our employees to successfully implement these changes.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your time today and we will now take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you gentlemen.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  Our first question is from Trevor Stirling from Sanford Bernstein.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning Nick and Paul. Three questions for you please.  The first one, clearly momentum has slowed over the course of H1, and you're implying that it could &#x2013; it's going to get worse in H2.  Is that because you think &#x2013; if I say if Q2 was worse than Q1, does Q3 look worse still or just as bad as Q2?</p>
          <p>Second question, in Russia, you mentioned volume growth had been strong, but you placed the emphasis, Paul, on White Horse and Red Label.  Does that imply there's actually a little bit of down trading going on in Russia from Black perhaps into Red?  And the third thing was, talking about joint ventures in Asia Pacific, clearly, there's been lot of speculation about United Spirits.  I don't appreciate -- that you won't be able to make any specific comments, but in the past, you've always said that you felt much more comfortable in alliances where you had control and influence rather than purely a financial investment. Is that likely to be the case as you look at that investment as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Trevor. First of all, let me handle the momentum question and your point around principles regarding JVs. And then maybe I can hand over to my colleague Andrew Morgan to talk about to Russia.  When we started the fiscal year, we expected a consumer slowdown and there's no question that the vibrancy of the consumer is not what it was 12 months ago.  As I outlined, we didn't anticipate some of the falloff around distributor orders that we saw particularly in November and December.  Now having said that, some of that slowdown in sales to distributors was led by us. As we looked at the financial strength, we did not want to ship and put some of them on cash with order.  But overall, the consumer momentum did soften even further in November and December.  January is a very difficult month to read because it's such a low volume month.</p>
          <p>Having said that, with some of our customers, volumes are quite encouraging.  I think it's so difficult to call the next few months. And as Nick alluded to, we did have higher stock levels in the States, partly because the forward outlook actually made them look high and we wish to consider unwinding that in the second half.  So, in the round, in the round, we believe that we can still grow this business, even with some moving parts in the second half. And we'll have to see, particularly around the Easter period, what the consumer momentum is like. But we still are very focused on growth.</p>
          <p>Regarding joint ventures, you're absolutely right. We much prefer a controlling interest. And whilst I wouldn't normally comment on sort of press speculation, I do want to say this. It is exactly that -- press speculation.  We have said for some time that we wish to increase our footprint in India, but it is very premature to conclude that we will be embarking upon a transaction.  Andrew, you're going to talk to Russia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Trevor the simple answer to your question on Russia is that Red Label and White Horse have been growing faster over the first half than has Johnnie Walker Black. Generally the standard category at the moment does look more positive than the 12-year old scotch sector. White Horse, in particular, though has been driven by a move that we made really to sort of try to follow consumer trends, which is to move to a 50 centiliter size alongside our normal 70 centiliter size. And that price point actually has been enormously successful and actually represents a lot of the growth in White Horse.  So, a bit of flexibility there in moving quickly to match consumer needs has helps us. But standard brands at the moment are more positive than deluxe.  I mean, the good news for us is overall in the six months, our total share of the scotch category is significantly up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We're now taking our next question from Nico Lambrechts from Merrill Lynch.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning Paul.  I've just got one question, because Trevor asked my second question.  Essentially your full year organic EBIT guidance of 46% implies that the second half EBIT that you assume is 2 to 5%. This would also imply that you are planning for a scenario where sales could be negative at the 2% level or in the mid-range of there. Could you elaborate maybe on your assumptions for the full year guidance or the second half and specifically maybe comment which markets which are currently showing relatively resilient sales concern you the most?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Nico.  I will try and offer what I can, but your mathematics are correct in how you've segmented the numbers.  I have to say that it's very challenging in the current environment to predict sales.  Many of the order patterns and the traditional ways that we would assess the business have changed.  People are ordering later, they are reducing inventories. There are many, many moving parts.  But I do believe that the next few months are going to be more testing, and I wouldn't single out any particular markets. Maybe some of the economic data that's coming out of the Asia gives one cause to pause on the projections regarding the growth rates there.  But, yeah, it's a very blurred picture.  The fact that we have offered this guidance is based on the confidence we have in this business and the flexibility that we have through the P&amp;L. And you have seen that we are exercising that flexibility through the launch of this cost restructuring program.  And equally, we're accessing the deflation rates that we're seeing, particularly in the media markets.</p>
          <p>So, I really can't say more than that, Nico.  But we are playing off very low inventory levels.  We're not anticipating that to snap back and we do believe that in the foreseeable future, the consumer environment will remain testing.  That said, we do believe we can grow this business. And of course we'll continue to benefit from currency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up on that and what &#x2013; how is the current economic climate then impacting your business where you have emphasized that the products that Diageo sell is affordable luxury? Why has it so much impacted a bottle of Smirnoff, et cetera. And then just following on from that, what do you think is the medium-term growth rate that you think Diageo could return to when we are out of all of this?  Do we think of Diageo as 7 to 9% medium to long-term or is it the 9%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think when we're out of this, and you all will have a view on when that may be, and when the consumer has regained confidence, I can see us returning to the sort of performance levels we enjoyed a year or so ago.  I think that in the foreseeable future, premium brands will do well.  We are still seeing growth in the ultra premium brands.  We're anticipating that it will be more muted and therefore, we are also activating some of our more price-oriented offerings so that we don't lose out on that opportunity either.  So we've got a very wide range of weapons in our arsenal that will allow us to access growth. And therefore I am confident that whatever the global economy gives us by way of category growth, we will outperform that.  But, I see no reason that when we get through this economic period, we don't return to the sort of growth levels that we've talked about before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  By the way...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, by the way on that, we will emerge stronger because we will definitely have continued to invest behind our brands, our infrastructure and we will have a lean cost base.  Sorry, operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Antoine Belge from HSBC.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, Antoine Belge, HSBC.  Three question. First of all, you mentioned some market share gains. And could maybe give us some flavor on the more significant ones in terms of, first of all, geographies and then maybe brands or product categories.  Second question relates to your restructuring program. I appreciate that you can't say much, but maybe could you mention the main geographic region which would be affected. So maybe give a, like a qualitative feel of the breakdown by geographic region of the 100 million benefits.  Final question is could you may be help us with trying to quantify the impact of Spain in terms of both sales and EBIT? You reminded us that it was a very profitable market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  First of all, I'll ask my colleague Nick Rose to talk to Spain as regards to its impact in a movement.  On restructuring, let me take that one on.  We cannot be specific by market at this point in time.  I've said that what we are embarking upon will cross all markets. And certainly we will be looking at every line on the P&amp;L.  We are confident in the savings that we have scoped, but out of due deference to our employees I think it would be unfair to be more specific at this point in time, and we are still working through the detail.  After Nick has answered the question on Spain, I think it's worthwhile hearing from some of my colleagues region by region around share performance because we are very proud of what we've been able to orchestrate in that regard.  Nick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean a little difficult to give you an exact number in the sense that a number of things are moving around in Spain or were moving around.  As you heard from us in the presentation, there is a consumer demand is clearly what's happening in terms of the channel destocking. There's some of the specific actions we took.  I think if you add that all together, you can very easily come to a number that looks like 20 to &#xA3;25 million.  Or said another way, pretty much all of the decline that we've seen in Europe you could attribute to that order of magnitude in Spain.  So while I think it's hard to land on a precise number, just because of dissecting all of the factors, it's that order of magnitude.  And as Paul said, and I would kind of reemphasize, a lot of that actually happened quite late on in half year.  Again, as you heard us say, a lot of that was around scotch, specifically around J&amp;B. And therefore, we've got a relatively higher margin, if you like, associated with that business than our normal kind of operating margins.  So if you ratio that back up through the P&amp;L, you're going to be more than doubling that impact at the sales line.  So it's pretty significant, very significant in the context of Europe and actually quite significant in the context of Diageo. You could argue easily more than a percentage of our growth lost at the Diageo level because of that movement in Spain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe we can start with Stuart. Talk about some of the share positions in international.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, if we look first of all at Africa, strong performances on share in Nigeria, Cameroon, Ghana. So good share gains across there. Four points of share in the beer market in Nigeria we gained in the first half.  South Africa perhaps the most significant share gain position for us in beer. And in fact share gain across all of our brands and categories in South Africa, where as you know, we're operating in a total beverage alcohol joint venture with Heineken and Namibia Breweries.  If we look at beer specifically in South Africa, we gained four points of share in the last 12 months in that market. And on an MAT basis, we're just shy of 10%.  In the last quarter we got over 10% share of beer in that market.  So, very pleased with the way that our brands Amstel, Heineken, Guinness and Windhoek are doing in that market.  So, share gains in our biggest markets across Africa.  In Latin America, scotch is our most important category and there, in our three most important markets -- Mexico, Venezuela and Brazil -- saw share gains in scotch across the total business there.  So, good share gains both in Africa and Latin America in our core categories and in our core markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ivan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. In the U.S. in the first half, we have beaten every major full-line spirits competitor.  Our priority brands grew 20 basis points in the first half.  If you look at our strategy in the U.S., the sweet spot for the business is on what we call our premium brands. It's about half our volume. Brands like Cuervo and Captain Morgan and Smirnoff and Crown Royal. And all of these are doing very well.  If you look at the last eight weeks including the holidays, as I explained at our New York conference, we've shifted our focus against the premium brands.  We are activating the value brands, brands like Gordon's and Popov, which are doing well.  And we're keeping a selective focus and indeed have great momentum in some of our reserve brands, notably C&#xEE;roc, which is up 300% in the first half.  So in total, the breadth and depth of our portfolio really positions us very well to outperform in the spirits category.  And indeed some of the challenges we are facing have come from smaller competitors at the value end of the business. But we have activated against, tactically against the value end of our portfolio.  So, going into the second half, we feel very confident that we will continue to outperform the category.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Asia Pacific, I'm delighted with the progress we've made. We're winning in 77% of the battlefields in which we are competing. And on a sales weighted basis, that's 85% of the battlefields.  In particular, looking at markets and categories, deluxe scotch and super luxe scotch have, we've made particular share gains.  In China, we've gained overall one further point of the scotch market.  In Korea, on Windsor 12 and 17, we've taken an additional six market share points, increasing our lead in that market by over 10 share points.  In Taiwan, Thailand, we've made particular gains but, in Taiwan particularly around our malt interest.  India, we've gained market share on Smirnoff and Johnnie Walker, principally by leveraging our new expanded sales force in India to a significant increase in number of distribution points.  Our beer business in Malaysia and Indonesia are achieving record share levels with four share point gain in Malaysia and two share point gain in Indonesia.  So, by and large, where we're competing we're seeing very strong progress.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Antoine. Plenty of evidence of market share gain right across Europe, particularly focused on our core premium brands. If I lead with GB, our four core spirits brands in GB grew 5% sales. That represented share gain in a category that's growing as well in GB.  Guinness was again a star from a market share point of view, both in GB and Ireland.  In GB now, we've had 24 consecutive months of share gain of beer and Guinness now represents close to 8% of the total beer market in the U.K.  In Ireland, we actually managed to grow our sales 2% in a market that's down around six in that country and that represented a point of share gain in total beer as well.  I've talked already about Russia's in scotch. Particularly at Christmas we gained quite a lot of share of that category.  In Greece, we gained a point of share in the scotch category, which is the key growth area for us there. And even in Spain, which we've talked about a lot already, through all of that, those difficulties that we had, we did actually gain share of our key category, scotch, in the first six months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>From Cazenove, we will now take our next question from Matthew Webb.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Thank you.  Three questions please.  Firstly, just going back to Spain, and that 20 to 25 million impact number that you've given, is it &#x2013; I know this is a difficult question, but is it possible to split that between the various destocking issues that you faced, and the underlying demand picture.  Second question, I was surprised to hear you talk about strong growth in Venezuela given what's happening to the economy there.  I was just wondering if you could talk about that in a bit more detail, including the outlook for the second half?  And then thirdly, I wonder if you could give a few examples of markets where you have put your prices up to reflect local currency weakness, because I'm actually struggling to think of many currencies that have actually been weaker than sterling over the period?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  I think, Nick, maybe you can take the Spanish question.  Stuart, Venezuela, and then probably between you and Andrew some of the pricing issues.  Nick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean I feel we may be getting into slightly spurious accuracy here.  What I will say is that each of those components is significant within that 20 to 25 million.  There's not one, if you like, that we would say lags behind the other.  So, if you must have something for the model, frankly, I would kind of roughly allocate to each a third, a third, a third, but we are getting into a level of accuracy here that I think I would slightly caution you against.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Stuart, Venezuela?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah Venezuela. Actually, we did see some volume decline, but our net sales grew strongly basically on the back of the price increases that we took, both in the second half of F'08, but also in the beginning of F'09.  So, whilst volume was down three, our net sales in Venezuela were up 10%.  And that strong performance we're continuing to see in January.  Now for the second half, obviously, some uncertainty driven by oil price and also the elections coming up.  So, the second half at this point, we wouldn't be seeing necessarily the same strength as the first half, but who knows.  Maybe I can talk to price increases.  We have taken price increases across a number of markets.  Where we've seen devaluation versus the U.S. dollar in Latin America for instance, we saw a pretty significant maxi devaluations of the Mexican peso, Colombian peso and also the Brazilian real.  In those markets, we have taken price to maintain our hard currency income levels.  In general versus sterling, we have not seen many currencies where we have a significant import business from the U.K. actually devalue, but we have taken price increases, it's true to say, in most businesses, most markets during the first half, both across beer pricing in Africa and spirits pricing, particularly scotch, in Latin America.  So we've continued to take price, maintaining our sterling margins wherever possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.  That's really helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  The market where currency obviously is a current issue in Europe is Russia.  I mean, interestingly, we've not been, most of our business coming -- costs in sterling, in terms of our scotch business, we've not been hit as hard in terms of sterling, ruble as it would have been dollar or euro.  However, we are getting plenty of price, so we took 15% price last year.  We've just, in Feb 1, just taken another 12%.  So, we're staying on top of the impact of any devaluation there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>And now we will move to Chris Wickham from MainFirst.  Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure.  And I just want to move away from current trading.  Could you talk a bit more about the relationship between the distributors and the industry in the United States?  I mean obviously we've seen some consolidation.  We've seen them looking a little bit more powerful.  I was wondering whether you could sort of let us know whether you think there is any significant, any significant shifts or subtle changes which may become significant in the relationship between producers and distributors in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will offer my views, and then maybe ask Ivan to say a few words.  I think we've got to be careful when we talk about distributors because in the U.S. particularly, we're dealing with sophisticated, well-capitalized industry experienced professionals.  In certain other markets, we're dealing with much smaller entities.  So, not all distributors are created equal.  In the U.S., there has been some moves to consolidate.  I would not characterize them as material.  We remain pleased with the relationships that we have, and I think those distributors that carry our brands understand the size of our portfolio in their house and our quest for growth.  Ivan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I would just add I think particularly in these times, distributor strength and route to market of a dedicated distribution system is a huge advantage for us, and indeed is one of the big drivers of helping us drive our performance.  The shift in the distributor landscape obviously we track very closely.  We work very closely with our partners and have very aligned views of where we want to take the business, how we want to build capability in execution, in sales and distribution, and we're very confident about continuing to steer our advantage through the U.S. marketplace as the distribution landscape evolves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Ann Gurkin from Davenport.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="audio gap" /> volume and the potential for price increases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Ann, we only picked up about half of your question.  If you wouldn't mind repeating it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you could focus on North America and comment on the potential for the volume for the category, spirits and price increases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  Ann, if you look at the calendar year 2008, the one we have just completed, we reckon spirits will be up about 1.5%, and probably price mix in the 2 to 3%.  I think going into 2009, we expect that to moderate, probably around 1% volume growth and we expect price mix to also moderate into 2009.  So, some downward shift, but not dramatic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then if I could ask about efforts in Great Britain to improve volume growth in such channels as grocers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew? Did you catch the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I caught the efforts to improve volume growth. Let me comment on that and perhaps Andrew could come back to the second part of your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was to do with penetration of the grocery channel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well those two are conveniently linked.  A big part of our focus in the GB market has been around category growth in spirits, and in particular, the consumer opportunity represented by the at-home occasion, and we've been working with the big grocers in particular, but indeed with all the other channels and trade, as well, to take more of a category growth approach to the business.  And I said earlier, our spirits brands are up 5% in the U.K.  Spirits are taking a share of total alcoholic drinks in the U.K. market as well.  And we're finding that linking and understanding of what motivates consumers at that at-home occasion with also an understanding of how the shopper shops that occasion in the store is leading to some pretty sharp gains in off-take from the shelf frankly, and a combination of the know-how of our customers and our understanding of consumers and shoppers is giving rise to that opportunity.  I would say that's the lead focus for us in GB and it's a particularly successful one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think some of the visibility that our brands enjoyed, particularly in the U.K. but in other markets too in the lead-up to Christmas, was probably the best we've seen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>From ING, we will take our next question from Gerard Rijk.  Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning.  Two questions, if I may.  First question is about your sheet on the Asia Pacific where you say that the accelerated, that we see accelerated net sales growth in China, India and Vietnam, but the focus is on China here.  But at the same time, you see the supply chain destocking happening in China as economic slowdown impacts consumer confidence. Can you elaborate on these two statements? Is it now for you decelerating in China or is it not?  Second question is on Spain. Well you're making there a substantial amount of sales, the decline was 18% in this period. That was destocking. Do you have a number for the consumer, the sales on consumer level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, maybe Andrew, you can answer the Spanish question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And John, if you want to talk about China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You want me go first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Um-hmm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on &#x2013; I mean one way to comment your question on Spain is the way that Nick used, which is to say that about a third of our decline versus last year I think we could associate with consumption decline.  The other two thirds being orders that we did not deliver against out of choice and destocking through the actual decisions made by the trade.  In terms of the trend in the marketplace, overall for the half spirits are down 9% and as much as 15% down in the on-trade in December.  So, we have seen an acceleration of that decline and that applies fairly equally across the different spirits categories.  Beer is down a similar magnitude in Spain as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, let me comment on China.  But let me first start by commenting on the overall environment and then what we're doing about it.  I guess the situation in China deteriorated much faster than anybody expected with the slowdown in the west, destocking, company closures and then an effect on consumer confidence.  But to really understand what's happening in China, we need to look at it geographically.  We're still seeing in the north, in Beijing, in Tianjin, growth in the high single digits.  In the west, around Chengdu and Chongqing, we're also seeing growth and the business is generally holding up in the east around Shanghai, Ningbo, Nanjing.  So, it's an area where we're still seeing some growth geographically.  The south has been the most affected around Guangdong and the Pearl River Delta, which has been most affected by the manufacturing export business closures.  It happens to represent more than 40% of total dark spirits consumption in China. So it's a significant impact.  But there still are geographical areas for growth.</p>
          <p>When we look at it by channel, the traditional trade has been most affected, mostly by frequency of visits to the outlet.  But the on-premise has held up much better than new modern on-trade, which has accounted for about two-thirds of the growth that we've reported in the half.  The off-premise is in growth, although it's only about 15% of our business.  So we remain positive about the prospects in China where we can shift our resources to focus on those growing areas and manage carefully our investment, if you like, in those declining areas.  China will get tougher before it gets better, but the Chinese government, we are confident will be effective in this stimulus plan, but it's not likely to take impact until the second half of the calendar.  So it's really a matter now of being very thoughtful about where we're investing and continuing to expand our footprint.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think my observation is, first of all, we've been able to absorb the shock of substantial destocking and still post growth.  Secondly, we are prudent when it comes to our policy regarding customers and see little point in shipping product where we would have questions around not only when we would get paid, but if we would get paid.  So, we operate a very conservative policy in that regard.  The fact that we can do that, see these stock impacts and still post growth I think is a testament to our business, our people and our brand strength.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We are moving to Melissa Earlam from USB (sic) [UBS]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.  It's Melissa from UBS.  Three questions please.  First of all, regarding the COGS inflation, I just wanted to confirm you mentioned 7% in the first half, and what you expect for the full year '09 and how that will moderate then in 2010 fiscal year?  And the second question is for you perhaps, Ivan, regarding beer versus spirits in the U.S.  It seems that some of the data points in the last quarter or so have suggested that spirits is losing share to beer.  If you could perhaps talk about how you see that impacting your business and whether that's a trend you can confirm? And perhaps opening that question more generally, whether any of your emerging markets you're seeing spirits are losing share to beer?  And then the final question was just some guidance on the working capital outflow for the full year. I know there's quite a big increase in the outflow in the first half. Would you expect that to continue on a full-year basis?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, maybe Ivan, you can handle the U.S. question, and then Nick on COGS and CapEx.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Melissa, good morning.  If you look at the most recent trends over the last six, nine months in the U.S. and kind of the underlying dynamics at work, clearly the on-premise is slowing down and the at-home business is picking up.  Now, within that, the consumer dynamic, as consumers are moving to, I'd say well-crafted, trusted brands and simplicity, and there's no question beer is benefiting from that.  However, what's also benefiting is the premium brands in the spirit space.  So, if you look at what's happening by price segment in spirits, where there's consistent growth coming through is in premium brands. So brands like Smirnoff and Cuervo and Captain Morgan -- that segment of the marketplace -- which in fact plays to the same values as beer does, because a Captain and Coke is as good, in fact better value, than a mainstream domestic beer, easy to make, or Crown Royal on the rocks.  So, it's an environment actually where trusted brands that are, deliver simplicity and confidence are doing well and that shift to at-home has undoubtedly helped beer a little bit because spirits has a stronger share in the on-premise. But in total, we're very confident that our portfolio, the Diageo portfolio in spirits, where 50% of our business sits in that premium brand segment and where we are directing our marketing investments, stepping up our innovation, things like the Smirnoff prepared cocktails, etcetera, is very much playing in that same space.  If it, as it relates to emerging markets, Stuart, do you want to just comment on spirits versus beer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think what I'd say there is in Africa, the continent outside of South Africa is predominantly a beer market.  Having said that, spirits and premium spirits, Johnnie Walker and Smirnoff in particular, we are seeing very strong growth rates as the middle class in countries like Nigeria, in Cameroon, in Angola are turning more to premium imported spirits, Scotch and Smirnoff in particular.  In Latin America, yes, it's a very big beer markets there, as you know, Melissa, but fundamentally, spirits continue to play a very strong role in society in drinking repertoire, both on-premise and at-home. And we don't see a fundamental shift in that right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nick? COGS and CapEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Melissa, on COGS, I think when we came into the year, we talked about an average year of something like 5%, 5 to 6%. Fully expected that to be somewhat weighted towards the first half just because we knew how our hedging program, if you like, had been phased. I would expect therefore to see cost increases or COGS rate of growth be a bit lower in the second half. And obviously, we're all beginning to see some of those key commodity prices come down.  As always, I caution us to get too bullish on that because one of the biggest impacts in our cost of goods is around glass. And glass is not something that reacts in the same way as some of the same way as some of the underlying commodities because of the capacity constraints in the industry.  So do I expect a better second half? Yes. But I wouldn't kind of fully reflect what's happening in the way that commodity costs are dropping.  As we go into 2010, which I think was also part of your question, yes, I would expect to see a stronger downward trend.  And as a proxy right now, we are probably working with 3 to 4% and still working at that.  So definitely as we go into 2010, we will see a lower rate of COGS increases. But frankly, I think we need that because of everything you've heard the team say here about the ability to price in a difficult consumer environment. We are much better to be driving at a much lower COGS rate.  And our restructuring program that we've announced will certainly be helping us in that direction.</p>
          <p>On working capital, you saw the increase in the first half.  I would not expect us to see much more than that in the full year, partly because some of that increase was of our own making, i.e., refusing to ship some of the product that we've made; i.e., we took the order, we made the product, but we refused to ship it.  And our inventory levels are up somewhat of our own making.  And again, as my colleagues here know, I'm looking to get some of that back with them in the second half of the year.  So I do not actually expect us to see a very significant change in the full year from what you saw in the first half in terms of a working capital increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for that, Nick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Melissa. Thanks Nick.  We are going to draw things to a close now.  Can I thank everyone for your time and your support.  I'm sure I will be seeing some of you over the next week or so.  Thank you.  Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>