<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1123463" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-01-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>161</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Andy Wilson, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">H. Lawrence Culp, Jr, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">John Inch</participant>
      <participant id="4">Daniel Comas</participant>
      <participant id="5">H. Lawrence Culp, Jr.</participant>
      <participant id="6">Andy Wilson</participant>
      <participant id="7">Deane Dray</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jeff Sprague</participant>
      <participant id="9">Nicole Parent</participant>
      <participant id="10">Robert Cornell</participant>
      <participant id="11">Steve Tusa</participant>
      <participant id="12">Ann Duignan</participant>
      <participant id="13">Scott Davis</participant>
      <participant id="14">Ajit Pai</participant>
      <participant id="15">Richard Eastman</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Theresa, and I will be your conference facilitator today. At this time, I'd like to welcome everyone to the Danaher Corporation Fourth Quarter and Full Year 2007 Earnings Results Conference Call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. After the speakers' remarks, there will be a question and answer period. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to Mr. Andy Wilson, Vice President of Investor Relations. Mr. Wilson, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Theresa and good morning, everyone. Thanks for joining us. On the call today are Larry Culp, our President and Chief Executive Officer; and Dan Comas, our Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>I'd like to point out that our earnings release is available on our website under the heading Earnings. As our year-end Form 10-K has not yet been filed, we've included as part of the earnings release the fourth quarter income statement, year-end balance sheet and cash flow statement. In addition, we've included data in the press release reflecting our business segmentation, as well as segmental &#x2013; supplemental income statement data to facilitate your analysis.</p>
          <p>Our earnings &#x2013; for the period include the results of operations of Tektronix since its acquisition in November 2007. As we've previously discussed included in Tektronix results are certain non-cash acquisition related charges for purchased in-process research and development and the fair value adjustments to record inventory and deferred revenue which reduced net earnings by 66 million or $0.20 per diluted share in the quarter. In addition, non-cash acquisition related charges in the 2008 first quarter and full year will be approximately $0.05 per share and $0.13 per share respectively. These charges are excluded from our earnings per share guidance to be provided at the end of the prepared remarks. Information with regard to the components of these charges will be included in our year-end Form 10-K to be filed with the SEC.</p>
          <p>Access to a webcast presentation supplementing today's call can be found under the heading of Web Events. This call will be replayed through January 28th and the audio portion will be archived on our website later today and will remain archived until our next quarterly call. Our website address is www.danaher.com. The replay number is 888-203-1112 in the U.S. and 719-457-0820 internationally and the confirmation code is 9944717. I will repeat this information at the end of the call for late arrivals.</p>
          <p>I'd also like to note that in order to help you understand the company's direction, we will be making some forward-looking statements during the call, including statements regarding events or developments that we believe or anticipate will or may occur in the future. These forward-looking statements are subject to a number of risks and uncertainties, including those set forth in our SEC filings. It is possible that actual results might differ materially from any forward-looking statements that we might make today. These forward-looking statements speak only as of the date that they are made and we do not assume any obligation or intend to update any forward-looking statements except as required by law.</p>
          <p>With respect to any non-GAAP financial measures provided during the call today, the accompanying information required by SEC Regulation G relating to those measures can be found in the investor section of our website under the subheading Earnings.</p>
          <p>With that, I would like to turn the call over to Larry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Andy. Good morning, everyone. We are very pleased to report to you that 2007 was another record year for Danaher. On the financial front, revenues grew to over $11 billion, adjusted earnings per share grew 19% and our free cash flow exceeded $1.5 billion highlighted by our record quarterly free cash flow performance of more $500 million.</p>
          <p>2007 saw us consummate the largest acquisition in our history, Tektronix, and we strengthened the portfolio with 11 other acquisitions. In July, we successfully completed the divestiture of our Power Quality business to better focus our efforts on our outstanding growth platforms. All in all 2007 was a good year for Danaher.</p>
          <p>Turning to the fourth quarter, we are very pleased with the continuation of our sales and earnings growth. Our fourth quarter earnings per share was $0.97. Included in the earnings per share results were the negative impact of approximately $0.20 per diluted share of non-cash acquisition related charges for Tektronix, as well as the benefit of approximately $0.05 per diluted share related to reductions of income tax reserves as a result of the favorable resolution of certain prior year tax matters. Absent these two matters, adjusted earnings per diluted share was $1.12 or a 19% increase over last year's comparable adjusted earnings per diluted share from continuing operations of $0.94.</p>
          <p>For the full year earnings per share from continuing operations was $3.72. In addition to the fourth quarter items identified a moment ago, full year 2007 earnings per share benefited from a $0.02 per diluted share gain related to the collection of indemnity proceeds, and a $0.02 per diluted share gain resulting primarily from the impact of income tax rate reduction in certain international jurisdictions. Excluding these gains, as well as the fourth quarter items just mentioned, adjusted earnings per share from continuing operations for the full year 2007 was $3.83, an increase of 19%, compared to 2006 full year adjusted earnings per share from continuing operations. Revenues from continuing operations for the quarter increased 19.5% to a record $3.1 billion. as revenues from existing businesses, referred to as core revenues, grew 4.5%. Acquisitions contributed 10.5% and currency had a positive impact of 4.5% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>For the year ended December 31, 2007, revenues from continuing operations increased 16.5% to a record $11 billion. Core revenues were up 4.5%, acquisitions contributed 8.5% and currency had a positive impact of 3.5%. Year-over-year gross margins for the fourth quarter improved 130 basis points to 46.2%. Several factors contributed to this improvement, including leverage from higher revenues, higher gross margins in our recently acquired businesses, and the impact of ongoing cost saving initiatives. Gross margins for the full year improved 140 basis points to 45.7%, primarily due to these same factors.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A expenses for the fourth quarter were 24.5% of sales, compared to 23.9% a year ago. For the full year, SG&amp;A expenses as a percentage of sales increased 60 basis points to 24.6% due to higher SG&amp;A structures in our recently acquired businesses, as well as increased sales force investments in emerging markets, including India, the Middle East and China.</p>
          <p>Research and development spending as a percentage of sales for the three and 12 months ended December 31, 2007, was 6.9% and 5.5% respectively, as compared to 4.2% and 4.6% a year ago. This increase was primarily due to the mix of newer businesses with higher R&amp;D structures, as well as a $60 million non-cash acquisition related charge for Tektronix, which increased R&amp;D spending as a percent of sales approximately 190 basis points in the quarter and 55 basis points for the full year.</p>
          <p>Operating profit for the quarter was $465 million, including $68 million of non-cash acquisition related charges for Tektronix. After these charges, adjusted operating profit for the quarter was $533 million, a 21% increase, compared to adjusted operating profit for the fourth quarter of 2006. For the full year, operating profit was $1.7 billion, a 16% increase, compared to last year and a 21% increase excluding the non-cash acquisition related charges for Tektronix.</p>
          <p>Operating margins for the quarter were 14.8%, a 200-basis point decrease over 2006. Operating margins from existing businesses contributed 70 basis points of improvement with particular strength in Medical Technologies. The impact of recently acquired businesses, particularly Tektronix and the associated acquisition related charges, had a dilutive impact on the quarter's operating margins. For the year, operating margins were 15.8%, in line with 2006. Operating margins adjusted to exclude the impact of recently acquired businesses and the non-cash acquisition related charges for Tektronix improved 85 basis points.</p>
          <p>Net interest expense for the fourth quarter was $30 million, compared with $25 million for the fourth quarter of last year. This increase was primarily a result of the net increase in borrowings related to the acquisition of Tektronix.</p>
          <p>Our effective income tax rate for the fourth quarter was 26.3%, compared to 23.4% in the fourth quarter of '06. The reduction in income tax reserves in the fourth quarter was offset by the tax treatment of certain non-cash acquisition related charges for Tektronix.</p>
          <p>Net income from continuing operations was $320 million for the quarter, and $1.2 billion for the full year. Included in the fourth quarter full year net income was approximately $66 million of non-cash acquisition related charges for Tektronix. Excluding these charges, as well as the previously mentioned gains in both periods related to the collection of indemnity proceeds, the impact of income tax reductions in certain international jurisdictions and the sales of securities in 2006, adjusted earnings from continuing operations increased 22% in the fourth quarter and 21% for the full year, as compared to adjusted earnings from continuing operations for the same period in 2006, including the gain on the sale of the Power Quality business in July of this year &#x2013; in July of '07, full year net income was $1.4 billion.</p>
          <p>Record operating cash flows from continuing operations were $1.7 billion for 2007, an 11% increase over 2006. Free cash flow, defined as operating cash flow from continuing operations less capital expenditures, was a record $509 million for the three months ended December 31, 2007. This is the first quarter where our free cash flow has exceeded the $500 million mark. For the year, free cash flow was $1.5 billion, a 10% increase over 2006. Our free cash flow to net income conversion ratio for the year was 127% making 2007 the 16th consecutive year in which our free cash flow has exceeded our net income. The Danaher Business System [DBS] continues to be the driver behind the significant and sustained cash flow performance.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditures for the year increased approximately 19% to $162 million. Our balance sheet remains strong with a debt to total capital ratio of 29% and over $230 million in cash and cash equivalents at years end.</p>
          <p>Turning to our operating segments, Professional Instrumentation revenues increased 37% for the quarter to $1.1 billion with revenues from existing businesses contributing 5.5%. Full year revenues increased 22% to $3.5 billion as revenues from existing businesses contributed 6.5%.</p>
          <p>Operating margins for the 2007 fourth quarter were 16%, as compared to 22.3% in the prior year. Absent the negative impact of recently acquired businesses, including the non-cash acquisition related charges for Tektronix, adjusted operating margins improved by approximately 60 basis points in the quarter driven by additional leverage from our sales growth in our Fluke and Water Quality businesses and margin improvement activities in our Gilbarco Veeder-Root business. For 2007 full year, operating margins were 20.1%, a decrease of 140 basis points, as compared to 2006 while adjusted margins, which exclude the items mentioned above, improved 135 basis points.</p>
          <p>The environmental platform revenues for the quarter grew 22.5% with core revenues up 5.5%. For the full year, environmental revenues increased 16.5% with revenues from existing businesses up 6%.</p>
          <p>Water Quality core revenues grew at a high single-digit rate in the fourth quarter led by continued momentum from Hach Lange's process and lab products, particularly in China where we continue to expand our sales force initiatives. Sales across North America were also strong and Hach Lange posted its best quarter of the year with double-digit growth.</p>
          <p>At Trojan, we achieved double-digit revenue growth for the year with strength across most geographies and with particular success in both drinking and wastewater applications. During the fourth quarter, we shipped a multimillion dollar order to Brisbane, Australia addressing the regions initiatives to convert wastewater to suitable drinking water as a result of the ongoing drought in the area. In addition, Trojan enters 2008 with year-end backlog at an historic high.</p>
          <p>Our acquisition of ChemTreat is progressing well with the business achieving high single-digit revenue growth in the quarter, compared to its results in the fourth quarter of '06 as a standalone company. Gilbarco Veeder-Root's core revenues grew low single-digits for the quarter and the year, as we did not see year-end orders materialize in Mexico. Despite restructuring activities in the fourth quarter, GVR improved its operating margins in the quarter by more than 100 basis points, as compared to the same period in 2006 as a result of ongoing DBS improvements in the factory and higher margins from recently introduced new products.</p>
          <p>Moving to Test and Measurement, our new name for our electronic test platform, revenues were up 64.5% in the quarter with core revenue contributing 5.5%. Full year revenues increased 31.5% as core growth contributed 8%. Fluke core revenues grew at a high single-digit rate for the quarter with solid international growth, particularly in China, Latin America, and Australia where sales were up double-digit. During the quarter, Fluke's innovation efforts led of the introduction of the new Ti10 and Ti25 breakthrough products in thermography to bring easier functionality and reliability at a price point that we expect to drive significant growth in the industrial maintenance market. Fluke's innovation efforts continued to gain public recognition during the quarter as the company won Best in Test from Test &amp; Measurement World Magazine for its new benchtop digital multimeter designed in our China Development Center.</p>
          <p>Fluke Network sales were flat for the quarter as a result of several large prior year orders that did not reoccur in 2007. FNET sales finished the year up mid single-digits with particular strength across Asia-Pacific and in Europe. In addition, operating margins improved over 100 basis points during the year.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned at the outset of the call, we finalized the acquisition of Tektronix in the quarter. The integration is proceeding very well. DBS implementation is on track and we are confident we will attain our cost reduction targets. Collaborative efforts between Fluke and Tektronix have already helped identify a number of significant opportunities in both product development and in market penetration. So, we are excited at this point about the progress the team has accomplished to-date and look forward to sharing further successes with you throughout 2008.</p>
          <p>Moving now to Medical Technologies, revenues for the quarter increased 24% to $866 million, compared to 2006 as core revenues contributed 9.5%. Broad-based improvements across all businesses contributed to this growth. For the full year 2007, sales increased 35% to approximately $3 billion with core revenues contributing 8%. Med Tech operating margins for the fourth quarter were 15.3%, compared to 14.6% the same period a year ago. Absent the negative impact of approximately 120 basis points related to newly acquired businesses, adjusted margins for the fourth quarter of 2007 improved approximately 190 basis points over the fourth quarter of 2006, primarily driven by leverage from higher revenues. For the full year, operating margins improved 130 basis points to 13.1%, when compared to the prior year.</p>
          <p>Turning to our Dental businesses, fourth quarter core revenues grew at a high single-digit rate. Sales of the consumables, imaging equipment, as well as our minimally invasive product offerings contributed to this performance. Full year 2007 Dental revenues also grew at a mid single-digit rate. We continue to see excellent results in the Dental consumables business, which enjoyed high single-digit growth in 2007 and significant margin expansion. Growth was broad-based across all major geographies and product categories.</p>
          <p>A great example of this performance was the success of the Kerr Demi Light. For many of you who attended the midyear analyst meeting in September you may recall the demonstration of the portable LED Curing Light, a high-powered compact light used to cure resin restorative materials such as composites, bonding agents and cements. We launched the product back in August and since that time Kerr has recorded sales approaching $10 million helping it achieve double-digit growth in this product category.</p>
          <p>Within Dental Equipment, we experienced geographic strength in North America where we believe we are taking share, partially offset by softness in Asia reflecting a weak Japanese market. Imaging revenues were up double-digits driven by both Gendex and DEXIS two-dimensional panoramic products, as well as the continued robust sales of ISI's i-CAT 3D imaging systems both in the U.S. and in Europe where the product was launched midyear 2007. If we were to include ISI in our core growth calculation for the quarter, Dental Equipment would have increased at a mid single-digit rate.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, KaVo launched Comfort Drive, which is the first handpiece in the market that combines the ergonomics of turbines with the power of electrics. We believe this handpiece will set a new standard in the market and represents an excellent example of using our voice of customer and innovation DBS tools to create what we believe to be a multimillion dollar opportunity.</p>
          <p>At Radiometer, core revenues grew at a low double-digit rate for the quarter and a high single-digit rate for the year, driven by instrument placements throughout the Europe. HUT our point-of-care offering used to detect cardiac markers, which we displayed at our year-end analyst meeting launched in the UK and Australia earlier this month. In the U.S. clinical trials are continuing and we obviously look forward to sharing early market feedback with you in the near future.</p>
          <p>Leica Microsystems core revenues grew at a low double-digit rate in the quarter and a mid teens rate for the year driven by robust microscopy demand, in particular, confocal microscopes. Geographically, growth was broad-based and benefited from a Leica's strong portfolio of new products, which have been brought to market in the last two years. In 2007, Leica generated more than 50% of its revenue from these new products.</p>
          <p>Our Leica Biosystems business continued to enjoy a very healthy growth driven in part by more than 30% growth in our Vision Systems business. This growth resulted from strong sales of the innovative Bond immunohistochemistry advanced staining systems, as well as increased sales of specimen preparation handling equipment, a result of the successful integration of the Vision and Leica sales forces.</p>
          <p>Moving to our Industrial Technologies segment, revenues increased 7% for the quarter to $812 million with revenues from core business up 2.5%. Full year revenues increased 5% to $3.2 billion as revenues from core businesses were up 1.5%. Operating margins for the fourth quarter were 16.3%, essentially flat, compared to the same a year ago. Margins were negatively impacted by new acquisitions, spending for product development and emerging market sales force initiatives, as well as restructuring activities. These cost activities should help drive continued margin expansion in 2008.</p>
          <p>For the year, operating margins increased approximately 120 basis points to 16.9%. Product Identification revenues increased 9% during the quarter with core revenues increasing 3.5%. Product ID full year revenues were up 3.5% with core revenues decreasing 1%. The postal business in 2006 that did not reoccur in 2007 adversely impacted full year core revenue growth by more than 800 basis points.</p>
          <p>Growth in our core marking business was up mid single-digits driven by strong performance in our laser business, which grew more than 20%. The primary growth driver has been the CO2 laser platform, which provides permanent marking on a variety of surfaces through high-speed steered beam technology. This platform, which replaced 17 legacy lasers, now accounts for more than 40% of Videojet's laser business.</p>
          <p>Switching to Motion, revenues were up 5.5% in the quarter with core revenues up 0.5%. For the full year, Motion increased 2.5% with revenues from core businesses declining 1%. Motion's performance continues to be adversely impacted by softness in its tech end-markets, particularly in semicon and electronic assembly. Motion did experience a rebound of bookings in its flat panel display business in the fourth quarter, which bodes well for this market segment in 2008.</p>
          <p>Our OEM elevator business grew revenue double-digits in 2007, a result of robust motor sales to Otis and a new product launch with ThyssenKrupp. Elevator product demand continues to be healthy entering 2008 due to the global conversion to more energy efficient systems and commercial construction demand in the developing world. Motion is pursuing a number of growth opportunities in clean energy and recently announced winning a greater than $10 million contract with H&#xE4;gglunds, a division of BAE Systems, for the design, development, and delivery of an electric propulsion system for military vehicles. Motion's custom-design capabilities for high-powered motors and drives, is proving to be very attractive for hybrid applications in both aerospace and defense markets, as well as in heavy duty and specialty vehicles. We expect to announce additional development contract wins in the near future.</p>
          <p>And finally, moving to Tools and Components, revenue for the quarter was $365 million, down 2%. For the full year, revenues for Tools and Components decreased 1% to $1.3 billion. Operating margins for the quarter were 11.8%, a decrease of 290 basis points from the prior year, due primarily to lower volumes in our Mechanics Hand Tool business with Sears and in our Jacobs Vehicle Systems business. In addition, costs associated with the fire in our Shandong, China hand tool facility, as well as additional restructuring spending in the quarter negatively impacted operating margins. For the full year, operating margins decreased approximately 130 basis points to 13.1%, primarily due to these same reasons.</p>
          <p>The Mechanics Hand Tools revenues declined 1.5% in the quarter. For the year, sales increased 1%. Double-digit growth at Lowes helped to partially offset declines in sales to Sears Kmart during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Looking back on 2007, we see a year where we successfully reached a number of milestones, exceeding $11 billion in revenue, generating more than 1.5 billion in free cash flow and significantly expanding our now $2.5 billion position in Test and Measurement. Looking ahead in 2008, despite ongoing weakness that began in the middle of 2007 in some of our OEM and customer facing businesses, we continue to see strength across most of the portfolio.</p>
          <p>We are, however, well aware of the current global economic concerns in accordingly took some meaningful cost reduction actions in the fourth quarter. In addition, we have developed comprehensive contingency plans within each of our businesses. We are poised to capitalize on growth opportunities and address uncertainties as they present themselves this year and remain confident in our ability to again deliver and outperform in 2008.</p>
          <p>Given this outlook, we are reaffirming our December adjusted earnings per share guidance for the first quarter to be in the range of 84 to $0.89 with full year 2008 adjusted earnings per share expected to be in the range of $4.30 to $4.40 which excludes the non-cash acquisition related charges for Tektronix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Larry. That concludes our formal comments. Theresa, we're now ready for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We'll go first to John Inch with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Larry. Since obviously there has been a lot of consternation around the economy just even in the past few weeks, since the analyst meeting have you noticed a discernible change in any of your businesses either the U.S. or Europe or anywhere else?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, I think since we saw you in December obviously the headlines have been consistently and persistently negative but on balance what we are seeing I think with very few exceptions is pretty steady and a lot of our business leaders are trying to figure out what the newspapers and the talking heads on television are seeing out there. Again not that we're putting our heads in the sand, but you look at the way we've finished with a lot of the businesses, we have about what 2.5 weeks of booking, so it's a little hard to read too much into January. Obviously, we ended up being a little softer I think than we had anticipated at Sears at year-end, I think that's been well publicized. We've seen I think in Asia consistent strong growth. In U.S, I think we've seen a little bit of I would say modest slowing in a place or two, but really nothing that I think would correlate at this point with the headlines that are out there. So, I think we feel good about where we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Larry, if you go back to the recession of '01 when Danaher ultimately had to take a charge and downsize to a degree, I mean, you are much different company, that said there is always I would think as part of your scenario of planning you'd have to be thinking about those possibilities and even the possibility the information you're getting from the field perhaps is lagging or it's being filtered in some manner. Can you talk about just sort of what levers you prospectively are able to pull, if in fact, you start to see some of the demand for your products you know, regardless of where it is, but some of it start to turn south more quickly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, maybe &#x2013; you bet, John and I think it really does start with the portfolio, right? I mean, so many of the wonderful businesses that we have today like our Medical Technology businesses, most of &#x2013; at least half of what we call Test and Measurement, our Environmental businesses are a much bigger part of the portfolio today. So, it's a very different Danaher. I think it's a stronger portfolio than we had last time we saw a slowdown in terms of the economy.</p>
          <p>When we were together in December, what we tried to do in the roll forward talking about our guidance is really give you a flavor for what we have laid in, in terms of flexibility with respect to the investments that we put into the businesses. We also talked about the ongoing cost reductions that we get as a result of persistent application of DBS plus obviously all of the procurement activity that we have going on. As we watch the tripwires, if you will, in all the businesses and we are watching everything we can right now, our own numbers and numbers with our distributor partners, our customers and the like. We will be I think quick to make sure that we pull back on investments that we can do without &#x2013; that we can defer for a period of time while making sure we continue to protect the investments that drive both the short and the long-term growth prospects that we have.</p>
          <p>We talked a little bit in the prepared remarks obviously about some restructuring. It was a bigger program at the end of the year than it was a year ago. We ended up with well over 200 heads coming out of the organization. I think that this is the sort of thing that should be evidence to you, John that we are going to be proactive. We are not going to wait necessarily until it's too late to do the things that we need to do to protect our profitability, our earnings as best we can in a, probably in a more uncertain environment here in '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you and just lastly, this China fire, does that roll through the other quarters this year? Should we be taking down assumptions a little bit in the T&amp;C business or have you pretty much contained and been enable to kind of redeploy the utilization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, we have done &#x2013; the team over there has really done a nice job of getting that factory up and running. So, I don't see it impacting our business over there. As Larry noted, the concern in the tools business is more around the U.S. consumer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks you John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Deane Dray with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Deane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Deane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Larry, just a follow-up on the actions that you took in the fourth quarter, were those preemptive moves that came in towards the end of the quarter or was that something you had planned all along in terms of head count reductions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't say that those were actions that were in the plan Deane. I think as we were adjusting in the second half and certainly, in the fourth quarter to some of the concerns, certainly as we think about the tools business with its exposure to the U.S. consumer, and some of the OEM facing businesses in industrial technologies, we were making adjustments of cost structure, taking actions proactively, really in preparation for '08 more than anything else. It obviously hurt us in the fourth quarter. We spent more than $10 million in the quarter going through those head count reductions and the attendant facility moves. But we thought that was the right thing to do for those businesses, we thought it was right thing to do in frankly, in preparation for '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And I also point out that those charges will also flow through your operating results, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh yeah, by all means, we, call it, restructuring, I think more than anything to make sure people understand that we are on our toes, ready for what may come here, and we are already into not only continuously planning across the board, but taking actions in those businesses where it's appropriate. In many of the businesses, I would say we are prepared but we want to make sure we don't move in a way that hurts our growth prospects in '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Deane, maybe just to further quantify the activities between the restructuring and the fire and most of it being the restructuring activities we took, probably it impacted the fourth quarter margins corporate wide by almost 50 basis points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, and then Larry, with regard to these contingency plans, and I am sure you are hesitant to put specific numbers on it, but just give us a sense of, in priorities of business where and how you can selectively pull back some discretionary spending if it worked out that that needs to be done?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rest assured Deane, I am not hesitant at all to quantify that internally, but for the purpose of this call I think again, it's really a business-by-business activity given really the way we operate, right? We've got strategies and budgets that are tailored to each business and its situation but again, whether we are talking about investments in head count, investments in OpEx our factory structures our overhead structures and alike, we can defer certain investments. We can go after certain costs that exist today in ways that hopefully protect all of the good growth investments that we want to protect for the future but also get at perhaps some of the costs that we carry today that frankly, we don't need, particularly if things do indeed decelerate from this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Deane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Jeff Sprague with Citigroup Investment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll move to another topic but not to beat this theme but just one other thought on what you are observing. Obviously &#x2013; well, maybe not obviously, but many of us would remember that before the prior slowdown Danaher was one of the very first to kind of raise their hands and say some things were going on before other companies did. The mix has obviously changed a lot, but when you look at that little bit of slowing around the edges that you said you saw in some businesses, were those the businesses that were flashing the signal last cycle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think when we talk about where we saw the softness, obviously we had Tools we had Motion last time around as part of a portfolio. Motion was hit hardest because of its exposure to tech and bursting of that bubble. Tools was more consistent given what was happening with the U.S. consumer that go around versus this time around. I think we are watching Gilbarco very closely given that ultimately they serve a number of retailers and obviously, the retailers have the exposure and maybe alter it &#x2013; as a result they may adjust their capital budgets given what consumers are doing. And we are also watching Product ID very carefully. But obviously we didn't have either of those two businesses with us last time around. Those are businesses fortunately we were able to acquire in the downturn from some folks that at the time were I think less prepared to preserve their portfolio, preserve their strategic options when things got soft.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Jeff you will remember the last time, the business where we had the most trouble, the biggest drop, and where we took the largest hit was the Power Quality business...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...which we divested this past summer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Terrific. And then could you give us a little color on how Tektronix performed in the quarter? I am sure it's a little muddy now but what was their organic growth like on a standalone basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, I think I wouldn't say it was muddy, per se. I mean, revenues were &#x2013; I mean, since the acquisition, revenues were down slightly, I think consistent with the soft order book that they had publicized during the summer and the fall. But I think all in all we feel very good about that investment, that acquisition, are excited about the way that team has embraced Danaher, DBS, Fluke and Fluke Networks. I think we are going to be very happy with having Tek onboard here Jeff. I am very pleased we were able to bring them in last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, just finally, on Med Tech, it did accelerate nicely. Larry, you called out a couple things, Europe and a few others but it's always kind of tough to size those as you are bouncing through them. What do you think was really kind of the main standout performer there that kind of drove the uptick in the growth rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think Leica is just &#x2013; they just had a terrific 2007. I don't know how to describe it otherwise, virtually across the board as you look product-by-product and by geography. Radiometer as I mentioned was also very strong. Sybron came in and contributed in the second half relative to kind of the core calculations nicely and we obviously don't &#x2013; we don't yet include fully the vision and the eyes, eye contributions but they were also very helpful here. So, very pleased with the Med Tech performance and certainly, if we are looking at a bumpy ride come '08, thrilled we have got $2.5 billion of Med Tech businesses performing as they are currently.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Nicole Parent with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Nicole.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Nicole.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>At the risk of piling on the macro, I just have one quick follow-up on Europe, when you think about kind of where you are seeing weakness and I think Larry in the press release you alluded to softness on the OEM side is that just largely kind of the tech weakness that you had seen on the semiconductor side, and then with respect to Europe, how you see that playing out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nicole with respect to Motion and the OEM comment, the softness that we've seen clearly has been in tech. I think that &#x2013; I was with the Kollmorgen team just a week ago. That situation is pretty steady right now, it's very interesting. There is some puts and takes obviously. It's not lighting the world on fire with respect to core growth, we've got a number of good verticals like commercial construction working for us right now, the Otis program and the like. But it's steady. It's not deteriorating. And I think that's a really interesting data point, and one we obviously are watching virtually daily. But it's an encouraging sign.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then I guess more specifically on Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say Europe is steady, I would describe it that way with respect to Motion and frankly, the rest of the portfolio, but obviously a geography that we are watching very carefully as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just one last one on M&amp;A, can you just give us kind of a snapshot with private equity out of the market now; have you seen prices come in, would you expect more activity as we roll into 2008, and kind of how you're thinking about it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, well I think that if you go back to 2002 when we bought Videojet, we bought Gilbarco, we made a big add to Water, a tough environment was good for a strategic acquirer. Lots of folks were on the sidelines at that point. And if things do get sloppier out there, I think prices will adjust in certain markets. Obviously, the competitive set will be markedly different. We would welcome that dimension to a slowdown. And obviously, as you saw, Nicole, when we went out and arranged the financing with Tektronix, the slug of equity was really geared toward making sure we were in a position given the uncertainty in the capital markets, to be in a position to be an active strategic acquirer in a downturn. So, as we sit here in early January, the balance sheet is strong. You saw 1.5 billion of free cash. I think we are in a good position to basically run our playbook here from an M&amp;A perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet, Nicole. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go next to Bob Cornell with Lehman Brothers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, would you just flush out the thoughts you mentioned, the combination of Tek and Fluke, just how they are starting to work together, you mentioned some of the opportunities? I mean, can you give us a little more color there please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, well I've got to be little careful because I know there is some folks on the call who are looking for that page of the playbook. But I think what we did, first of all, Bob, as we always do, is plug the senior team in to DBS. They have gotten through the initial orientation. They have begun to do their own kaizen events to get a flavor for what this is all about, they were already on the Lean journey, so this was not a foreign concept to them, they've taken it and just run hard. We obviously have been plugging in our procurement activities as well, really from a corporate perspective but Fluke has the point on that to make sure we get the vast majority of that 40 million in the early round cost reductions as Tek buys now as part of a $13 billion company not a billion dollar company.</p>
          <p>From the strategic perspective, clearly there are opportunities with Fluke and with Tek as they serve the same engineer's bench through similar channels in a number of markets around the world. So, we're working not only on some product ideas but also some channel programs to put the combined strength to its full use. I would say there are also similar opportunities &#x2013; I was out in Colorado Springs last week with our Fluke Networks team as we think about the communications side of Tektronix with FNET. So, again both from a product and from a go-to-market perspective there are going to be things where I think each business is going to help the other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you mentioned -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With time those four pillars just get stronger and stronger as we build the T&amp;M business out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You mentioned the Tek soft order book I mean, have you had chance to do further due diligence on that and have an increased perspective maybe give a little more color around that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the additional exposure that we've had thus, far is very consistent with what they said publicly and what we had discerned in our diligence. We knew that some of the lumpier carrier programs from an order perspective were going to be soft here. I think that's part of our opportunity. It is not as pronounced from a shipment perspective. The other item they had flagged, as you may recall, is the weakness in Japan, which has -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...which has continued.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a comment on the Radiometer new product. I mean, is that in the market? I didn't quite get what the perspective was there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I am sorry Bob. We are now shipping that product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what's the impact, how is it going, that type of thing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's been two weeks. The customers love this product. It's now approved. We are shipping, but it's &#x2013; it literally is the first full month of production. We are &#x2013; I mean, we are as pumped up about that program as we ever have been.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How about the &#x2013; you didn't &#x2013; I didn't hear you say in guidance what the organic growth target was for the year. I think you had guided to mid single-digits and is that still the target?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, I think that's exact &#x2013; there's been no change in that regard, Bob from what we said in December. We thought we would be in that mid single-digit range this year. Obviously, operating as aggressively as we can, we're going to have growth opportunities and appropriately cautiously where we have some of this headline risk out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I will stay tuned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Bob, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Steve Tusa with JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you just run through what you would expect from the different pieces of Med Tech, maybe which would be &#x2013; which you would be more worried about in a tough U.S. environment? I know that this business is thought of as less than cyclical, but I am just curious as to &#x2013; there's got to be some slowing in a couple of them, I am just curious how you are thinking about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think that's right, Steve. I mean, let's be clear, this is the business in all likelihood, will be our best performer in a &#x2013; if the economy does decelerate further, if it's down, if the softness broadens. I would say that Leica and Radiometer, given that they serve research and clinical applications are probably going to be well insulated simply because I think budgets &#x2013; programs that they participate in tend to have a little bit of that longer cycle dynamic to them they, once they start, they are hard to shutdown. They are both going to be coming off very good years, so we need to keep that in mind, but that's really the way I would think about those two legs of the Med Tech platform.</p>
          <p>I think in dental, we obviously have been, we have been benefiting on a global basis from the increased investment in technology by all levels of dental practitioners; consumables more a function of procedures and case loads. We need to be watchful here relative to whether the U.S. consumer dynamic has any impact on the dental business.</p>
          <p>Those that I talk to and respect, who've been in the business far longer than I have, would I think support the assumption in your question that it will be &#x2013; there won't be a lot of impact, but there could be some. So, we want to just watch that given that this is a new business for us and we obviously do have &#x2013; we do have a large presence here in the U.S.</p>
          <p>But I think all-in-all, we like where these businesses are strategically. We think they had a &#x2013; they all had a very good fourth quarter and enter '08 with a lot of optimism, a lot of confidence. We had a couple of kickoff sales meetings so far, and the sales teams are very enthusiastic about the new products and the programs here in '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, as you know, given these businesses are still relatively new to the portfolio and we think we've got a lot more room on the margin side, you know, got over 100 basis points of core margin improvement in '07, and we'd be looking for sort of similar type results here in '08. So, I think if you'll not only steady growth, but above the average OP improvement here for the coming years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, and then you have a different portfolio, you have some of this cost opportunity, is it reasonable to assume, given the last recession, you guys held earnings flat, if you strip out the big extraordinary charge, that you guys with this portfolio would &#x2013; might actually be able to even grow earnings through a, through a reasonably bad recession?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Steve I think that when you look at the portfolio, you look at this team, you look at DBS, come what may, we are confident we are going to outperform. What that looks like, you can calibrate or model it I think in a number of different ways, but we are going to make the right decisions, take the tough decisions and outperform in a tough time if that evolves here, as we try to do in all seasons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet, Steve. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Ann Duignan with Bear Stearns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry to beat the macro thing to death here, but -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But how are you thinking about organic growth by quarter or by progression through the year, Larry? Do you think stronger maybe in the first half because of easier comparables, and then perhaps slowing because of lack of visibility in the back half or do you think that interest rates cuts that are happening now may cause an acceleration in the back half? Maybe you haven't thought about it by quarter, but just the progression of your organic growth and how you are thinking about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, well I think right now, I mean, it's obviously very early in the year. We are watching all of our indicators, talking to as many customers as we can to make sure we understand how they are thinking about budgets and capital plans for the year. I mean, what I'd say, Ann, is that, as we shared with Bob a moment ago and I think we stand by the mid single-digit range for the year that we talked about. I think all in all, we come into the year obviously with first quarter inventories at Sears a little bit higher than I think we would have liked, they would have liked, given the softness during the holiday season. PID on the margin a little softer as well, we'll get an offset as you talk about with Jake Brake, JVS.</p>
          <p>But we need to see how the year plays out. I am not sure that the economics department at Danaher &#x2013; and we don't have one &#x2013; is ready to make the call on what the Fed actions or even the stimulus program that Congress is talking about is going to kick in here in the second half. Obviously, you have got all &#x2013; you have got the monetary and fiscal levers, policy levers being pulled aggressively right now. That has to have positive impact when that hits. I am not sure our crystal ball is any better than anyone else's. We want to be focused on what we can control and go after all of the revenue opportunities we can while being just smart and prudent on the cost side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That's helpful on the Q1 kind of headwinds or tailwinds. On Product ID, I have to believe given how much of that business is consumables, are tied to kind of industrial activity that that business may be one of the first or the early cycle businesses that might see a slowdown in the near term. Is that kind of what you were insinuating on the Product ID side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and yes, and I think that's a spot-on look at where we might see some softening next, if you just look at the Danaher portfolio, and I think it's less on the consumables side per se, but we watch that, but also those the new printers, the new laser printer, our new TTO machine going into a production line I mean, that &#x2013; presumably if it's not a new product introduction, it's something people could defer. So, we try to look at those orders, we look at, we break it down by consumables versus equipment to try to read in to what customers are really going to do here in '08. I think right now, we are watching that very &#x2013; that one very carefully.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The other dynamic, we have with Product ID and it is more within the Accu-Sort business, as you know, that they had some large project business as you know, the last couple of years with the Post Office but also with people like UPS and you know, whether those &#x2013; some of those projects get pushed out in the sort of this climate it's a risk as well. I think the offset there is they tend to be much lower margins than the core printing and consumable piece of Videojet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's very helpful, thank you. I will talk to you offline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, Ann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Ann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Scott Davis with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was wondering if we could take a little bit of a step backwards and talk about Tektronix and maybe remind us how you go to market, you know, how much distribution versus direct, you know, how much channel visibility you have, product cycles, just a little bit of teach-in if you could on that particular business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, well, keep in mind that you really break Tek down roughly, call it, two-thirds, one-thirds, the two-thirds being their core instrumentation business, oscilloscopes and other benchtop products used often in research and development. That's a business that is, Scott, 60-65% direct, the rest being through distribution, and it's in some but not all of the distribution channels where we often are listed, literally, side-by-side with Fluke. So, you'll see, I think, a fair bit of the channel synergy in that part of the business.</p>
          <p>On the communication side, that is principally a direct business. When we say communications, we are typically talking about network operators, carriers and the like. So, it's a business where we have a lot of &#x2013; we have an ongoing conversation with many of the larger customers and obviously, do demand planning and the like with our distributor partners on an ongoing basis as well. And I think that's been a strength of the Tek organization that we are keen to leverage going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And when you think about revenue drivers, is it &#x2013; when you think about is it tech CapEx, is it new product cycles, is it &#x2013; is tech CapEx driven by the ebbs and flows to the equity markets and how much capital these companies have, I mean, it's just an industry that I don't cover, so I am kind of curious?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure, no I am &#x2013; I think you have a number of macro drivers there, but tech is very focused in R&amp;D as opposed to manufacturing and all of these companies obviously are wholly dependent on the next generation product being a winner. So, their demand may fluctuate. They may have to adjust their spending in the factory as a result.</p>
          <p>But in terms of what's happening in the lab on the bench relative to R&amp;D, our work, Scott, suggested that that's a more stable environment and the digital revolution that we see in so many places is really fueling development spending in that regard and in turn, spending for Tek products.</p>
          <p>On the communication side, obviously we see the proliferation of services by the network operators and Tek helps these folks develop and deploy those new services. So, again that's something that we see as really a ubiquitous growth driver around the world for Tek. And it's that combination that I think got us excited. This was a good smart step in a new and adjacent market for our T&amp;M business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that really serves to buffer this natural tech cyclicality that's out there, is that what you are kind of implying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't say that it is completely buffered. I think we acknowledge that to the extent that we serve some of those tech markets, if there is volatility or cyclicality there that we'll be exposed to some of that but it's far more modest in R&amp;D, and so many of the other favorable attributes of the acquisition made this one that we felt very strongly about and obviously, consummated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's actually very helpful. Thanks guys, I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Ajit Pai with Thomas Weisel Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ajit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ajit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Couple of quick questions, I think the first one is just looking at your cash flow, the operating cash flows and free cash flows and as you just mentioned I think your free cash flow has continue to exceed your net earnings by quite a margin. But in terms of growth rate you're looking at 11% growth in your operating cash flow and about 10% in your free cash flow for the full year. How much of that is the fact that it's from continuing operations and is about sort of net earnings include further acquisitions and how much of that has to do with the change in the pace at which you can generate cash flow, the delta between your net earnings and your cash flows growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ajit, I'm not sure exactly I get the question, let me try and you can correct me. We had a very, very strong performance in cash flow for the year. We did not get a lot of benefit from a new acquisition coming in. As you know, Sybron occurred early in 2006 and Tektronix occurred kind of late in the year, so it really was from continuing operations, from the core business that we delivered this very strong cash flow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so when you're looking at the 21% growth in your net income and you're looking at the 10 to 11% growth in your operating cash flows and free cash flows most of that difference can be attributed to what you just mentioned?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and the dynamic of last in &#x2013; from '05 to '06 when the cash flow was up I believe in kind of in the high 20s was because of the timing of the Sybron acquisition when we brought it in, and we got a lot of cash flow that last quarter because of the difference in their year end. We talked about that last year. So, if you look at kind of '05 to '07, which I think is a more representative look when you take out the impact of timing of an acquisition, free cash flow is compounded at about 19% over that two-year period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Okay, then just looking at the quality of your receivables right now and also, the impact on some of the tightening in credit that's happening. Are you seeing any change both in your lenders not just domestically but across the world, any kind of tightening in terms of their ability to lend to you of any sort whether it's a bank's facility or anything at all? And then secondly, for your customers, is there any change in tendency in your customers to actually delay their payments to you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ajit, we have not seen any issues. We are, as you know, an A+ credit Tier-1 commercial paper issuer and we've not had any issues either in the U.S. or in Europe. Regarding the second point nothing that I am aware of, I am sure there are some instances somewhere, whether the tighter credit market is &#x2013; could be impacting a customer but nothing to note.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then looking at your Product ID business, I think you mentioned over here pretty decent growth out of the laser products for marking, and then you talked about the economic sensitivity of this business, I think in response to a question a few minutes ago. How do we think about this business over the next two to three years, what are the sort of major drivers that would sort of reaccelerate growth in this business, do you expect anything in the near-term and do you plan to go from the sort of fixed side and the desktop side in this business more into the mobile side in this business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ajit, we don't have a desktop business in Product ID. We are really, principally in marking and coding in a production environment. So, there is really no opportunity I think in our view absent an acquisition to take that position off &#x2013; out of the production environment into a mobile environment. I think the growth drivers there are going to continue to be good and we didn't have &#x2013; we didn't report the year that we would have liked because of the tough top line comps from '06 because of the postal programs but I &#x2013; frankly, I was thrilled with the year we had in Product ID, particularly at Videojet where they had excellent core growth, good margin expansion. We are making some smart investments that will yield things that we will talk about in '08 and '09. So, I don't think we have anything but good opportunities like the trajectory we have been on in Product ID. It's just a business that clearly had a tough reporting comp in '07 but when you look underneath the covers, they did very well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our final question from Richard Eastman with Robert Baird.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a couple things. Good morning, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Test and Measurement side of the business, the core growth rate at 5.5% was a little bit &#x2013; well, certainly below trend line for the last couple of years. And I know FNET had a couple tough project compares year-over-year, but are you sensing that you are picking up any macro weakness in the Test and Measurement side of the business excluding Tektronix, just at Fluke or Fluke Net?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the short answer, Rick, is no, but again, I think we finished very strong and we have but a couple weeks of orders. So, if something is going to happen this year, we certainly aren't seeing it in terms of our leading indicators, our order books. We tend in the fourth quarter to see some of that noise at FNET, depending on whether there is a big year-end program here or there. So, I didn't read anything, I would encourage you not to read anything into the FNET performance in the fourth quarter. We need to obviously watch what customers do as the year plays out. But I think right now we feel very good about where T&amp;M is excluding Tek for '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just the last question on the Med Tech platform you know, given that we pulled this platform together over the last few years and its been may be skewed a bit towards European based acquisitions, given the cost structures there and the fact that we have been operating in a very good revenue marketplace for the last couple of years, do you feel comfortable that you know, the trailing pace of cost reductions would continue to drive operating margin there if revenue falls off, revenue growth falls off? It's obviously the difficulty in taking cost out of some European operations, do you think you are far enough ahead on that curve that if we see revenue growth slow that we can comfortably deliver on the margin improvement in '08 that we are targeting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we, we would certainly intend to do that Rick and keep in mind, I mean, we talk about these as European headquartered business but their cost structures really span the globe. It gives us an opportunity not only to deal with head count really anywhere not just Europe but also the new product pipeline at Leica, for example, has been an important part of the margin play. Having these companies come in and just buy commodities globally as part of a larger organization hopefully a sharper purchasing organization to boot. I mean, those are all cost levers that we've been pulling, that have been helping drive the margin expansion in addition to the volume. and obviously, are also levers that we think still have future impact on the business almost regardless of the revenue environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That concludes the question and session today. At this time, Mr. Wilson, I will turn the conference back over to you for any additional or closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Theresa. Just as a reminder, the replay number is 888-203-1112 in the U.S. and 719-457-0820 internationally with the confirmation code of 9944717. Thanks again for joining us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude today's conference. Thank you for your participation. You may disconnect at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>