<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1341224" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-10-21</date>
    <companies>
      <company>161</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Matt R. McGrew, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">H. Lawrence Culp, Jr., President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Scott Davis</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">H. Lawrence Culp, Jr.</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Daniel Comas</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Robert Cornell</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Deane Dray</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Steve Tusa</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Steven Winoker</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">John Inch</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Nigel Coe</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Jeff Sprague</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Terry Darling</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Richard Eastman</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Wendy Caplan</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Jason Feldman</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, my name is Corrine and I will be your conference facilitator today. At this time, I'd like to welcome everyone to the Danaher Corporation Third Quarter 2010 Earnings Results Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>Thank you. I would now like to turn the call over to Mr. Matt McGrew, Vice President of Investor Relations. Mr. McGrew, you may now begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and thanks for joining us. On the call today are Larry Culp, our President and Chief Executive Officer; and Dan Comas, our Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>I'd like to point out that our earnings, slide presentation supplementing today's call, our third quarter Form 10-Q and the reconciling and other information required by SEC Regulation G relating to any non-GAAP financial measures provided during the call are all available in the Investor section on our website, www.danaher.com under the heading 'Earnings' and will remain available following the call.</p>
          <p>The audio portion of the call will be archived on the Investor section of our website later today under the heading 'Investor Events' and will remain archived until our next quarterly call. A replay of the call will be available until October 26. The replay number is 888-203-1112 in the U.S. and 719-457-0820 internationally. The confirmation code is 4297828.</p>
          <p>During the presentation we will describe certain of the more significant factors that impacted year-over-year performance. Please refer to the accompanying slide presentation, our earnings release, our third quarter Form 10-Q, and other related presentation material supplementing today's call for additional factors that impacted year-over-year performance.</p>
          <p>I'd also like to note that we'll be making some forward-looking statements during the call, including statements regarding events or developments that we believe or anticipate will or may occur in the future. These forward-looking statements are subject to a number of risks and uncertainties including those set forth in our SEC filings. It's possible that actual results might differ materially from any forward looking statements that we might make today. These forward-looking statements speak only as of the date that they are made. We do not assume any obligation to update any forward-looking statements whether as a result of new information, future events and developments or otherwise.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like to turn the call over to Larry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt, thanks. Good morning, everyone.</p>
          <p>We're pleased to report this morning an outstanding third quarter for Danaher. We grew 12.5% organically in the third quarter as the positive trends of July and August continued through September. Our core growth was broad based across all the segments with professional instrumentation up 15.5%, industrial tech up 16.5% and med tech up 7.5%.</p>
          <p>Our continuing commitment to drive organic growth using DBS in the form of tools and processes to improve new product development and sales and marketing execution, as well as increased investments in those same areas is evident in this strong core growth performance. We are quite pleased with this momentum, and are optimistic about our potential to outperform for the remainder of 2010 and beyond.</p>
          <p>We're winning in the marketplace and serving our customers well as we continue to capture market share in many of our businesses, including Leica, Radiometer, Hach Lange, ChemTreat, Kollmorgen, Fluke, and Tek Communications.</p>
          <p>Geographically, emerging markets were our best performer, up more than 20% in the quarter. Despite difficult comparisons to last year, China grew at a 25% rate in the quarter with our test and measurement, environmental, and Leica businesses leading the way. We also saw strong growth in Eastern Europe, Latin America, and India. Emerging markets now represent 20% of our total sales, up from 12% five years ago, representing a greater than 20% compounded annual growth rate. The U.S. grew low double-digits, and Europe was up 10%.</p>
          <p>The quality of our core growth was evidenced in the outstanding margin performance in the quarter, with our core operating margin improving 310 basis points year-over-year, with each of our operating segments achieving at least 200 basis points of core improvement, a first for Danaher. In addition, we generated over $500 million in free cash flow in the quarter.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we completed the strategic joint venture with Cooper Industries to combine our tools businesses to form Apex Tool Group. Beginning this quarter, we deconsolidated the financial results of the businesses contributed to Apex, and recorded our share of the combined joint venture results based on the equity method of accounting. We also recorded a $232 million after-tax gain in the quarter related to the formation of the joint venture.</p>
          <p>So with that as a backdrop, let me move to the details of the quarter. Today we reported third quarter GAAP earnings per diluted share of $0.95, up 79% year-over-year. Adjusted net earnings per diluted share, which among other items excludes the $0.34 gain related to the formation of the Apex JV, was $0.60, up 33% year-over-year. Revenues for the quarter increased 16% to $3.2 billion, with core revenues up 12.5%. The impact of currency translation decreased revenues by 1.5%, while acquisitions contributed 5% to sales growth.</p>
          <p>Year-over-year gross margin for the third quarter increased 370 basis points, to 51.7%, marking the first time in Danaher's history that we have achieved gross margins in excess of 50%. The year-over-year margin improvement is largely due to higher sales volumes and the benefit of our 2009 restructuring initiatives. Approximately 150 points of improvement in the quarter is attributable to the deconsolidation of our lower gross margin tools businesses.</p>
          <p>Operating margin in the third quarter increased year-over-year to 18%, resulting from higher sales volume and the benefit of our prior year's restructuring initiatives. Included in the operating results was $10.5 million in equity earnings contributed by Apex, which added approximately 35 basis points to our operating margin in the quarter. Absent the Apex contribution, our operating margin was 17.7%.</p>
          <p>Year-to-date, operating cash flow was $1.5 billion, a 16% increase year-over-year. Free cash flow year-to-date was $1.37 billion, and our free cash to net income conversion ratio was 104%. More meaningfully, excluding the after-tax $232 million non-cash Apex gain, our free cash flow to net income conversion ratio was a robust 126%.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we closed or signed two bolt-on acquisitions with aggregate annual revenues of approximately $200 million which are expected to strengthen our test and measurement platform. The M&amp;A environment remains very active, very attractive, and given our strong balance sheet, we believe we currently have more than $4 billion of M&amp;A capacity over the next four to six quarters to expand and strengthen our portfolio, with particular focus on our five growth platforms.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to our operating segments. Professional instrumentation revenues increased 20.5% for the quarter, with core revenues up 15.5%. Operating margin for the third quarter increased 560 basis points, to 21.2%, primarily due to higher sales volume and the benefit of the prior year's restructuring initiatives. Our core operating was up 340 basis points in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Our environmental platform revenues increased 13% in the quarter, with core revenues up 10.5%. Water quality core revenues increased at a low double-digit rate in the quarter. At Hach Lange, core revenues grew at a mid-teens rate, with solid demand across all geographies in our core lab and process instrumentation markets.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, Hach launched the sc200 universal controller which provides maximum flexibility for water analytics by eliminating the need for multiple dedicated controllers and offering plug-and-play capabilities with all of Hach's digital sensors, currently covering 15 different testing parameters such as ammonia, chlorine, and nitrate.</p>
          <p>Trojan core revenues declined at a mid-single digit rate in the quarter as the difficult year-over-year comparison resulting from the New York City drinking water installation more than offset solid growth in industrial, residential and other municipal applications.  However, year-on-year bookings were up double-digits in the quarter.  Earlier this month, Trojan unveiled its most advanced open channel wastewater UV disinfection system to date, the TrojanUVSigna.  The Signa is specifically designed for large scale disinfection applications, making the conversion to UV disinfection easier by reducing the total footprint required, simplifying maintenance and lowering the total cost of ownership, as Signa is three times more energy efficient than similar offerings.</p>
          <p>At ChemTreat, third quarter core revenues were up high-single digits with broad based growth across all major verticals.  Since acquiring the business in mid-2007 we have increased sales force head count by approximately 20% as we continue to dynamically allocate resources to fund their successful sales growth model.</p>
          <p>Gilbarco Veeder Root's third quarter core revenues increased at a low double-digit rate year-over-year with robust demand for outdoor payment solutions and dispensers globally.  Earlier this month Veeder Root introduced a key product for biofuels called the Phase-Two Water Detector, the first and only solution to continuously monitor underground storage tanks and detect ethanol-blended fuel phase separation which can occur when water finds its way into tanks often leading to infrastructure corrosion at service station and costly damage to vehicle engines if undetected.</p>
          <p>Moving to Test and Measurement, revenues increased 32.5% in the quarter, with core revenues up 22.5%.</p>
          <p>Fluke core revenues increased at a high-teens rate in the quarter with solid demand in all major geographies for thermography and our industrial products.  We unveiled a series of new products in the quarter including the 381 Remote Display Clamp Meter, the first clamp meter with a detachable remote display and flexible current probe for easier, faster and safer measurements.  The wireless display featured on the 381 is similar to that on the 233 Digital Multimeter, which we introduced last year and displayed at our year end conference.  This product advancement has been very well received in the field with the 233 Digital Multimeter receiving 12 industry awards since introduction 10 months ago.</p>
          <p>Tektronix core revenues grew more than 30% in the quarter led by demand for oscilloscopes, bench instruments and video test products.  All major geographies were up double-digits led by China and Japan which were both up over 40% year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Subsequent to quarter end we entered into an agreement to acquire Keithley instruments.  Keithley designs and develops electronic instruments and systems geared toward specialized needs of engineers at electronics manufactures and academic institutions where research, product development, high-performance production testing and process monitoring.</p>
          <p>Keithley's instruments are expected to complement Tektronix efforts in distribution channels alongside Fluke and strengthen our general purpose test product offering, a key strategic initiative of the business.  This acquisition, expected to be completed during the fourth quarter, is subject to customary closing conditions including the receipt of regulatory approvals and adoption of the merger agreement by Keithley's shareholders.</p>
          <p>Core revenues from our Fluke Networks and Tek Communications businesses collectively grew at a mid-teens rate in the quarter with solid demand for both our core enterprise tools with Networks and our network management solutions at Tek Communications, including our new GeoProbe G10 platform designed to optimize service for high bandwidth broadband telecom networks.</p>
          <p>During the quarter we acquired Arbor Networks which develops and markets network security and management solutions for cyber-attack detection and mitigation for wireless carrier networks and next generation data centers.  Network security is an attractive and important market adjacency for Tek Communications, is helping secure the communications networks we monitor and strengthen our value proposition.</p>
          <p>Moving to medical technologies, revenues for the quarter increased 31% compared to the prior year period with core revenues up 7.5%.  Med Tech core operating margin for the third quarter increased 330 basis points on a year-over-year basis as a result of higher sales volumes and the benefit of restructuring initiatives implemented last year.  Our overall operating margin of 12.6% was up 450 basis points sequentially from the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Our dental platform revenues increased 10% in the quarter with core revenues up 6%.  KaVo revenues increased at a low double-digit rate in the quarter, with particularly healthy demand for our imaging products including both 3D and intraoral sensors as well as our treatment unit and handpiece instruments.  Sales expanded in most major geographies, led by the U.S. and Asia.  In addition to the strong organic growth, core operating margins were up meaningfully in the quarter, and we feel very good about our ability to continue to drive growth and margin expansion for the remainder of 2010 and beyond.</p>
          <p>Sybron core sales grew at a low single digit rate in the quarter, with strong sales in orthodontia solutions and infection prevention products, offset by lower sales of general dental consumables due to inventory destocking in our U.S. distribution channels.  The inventory destocking issue is now behind us, and we expect to return to historical growth rates in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Moving to life sciences and diagnostics, revenues increased 54.5% in the quarter, with core revenues up 10%.  Leica Biosystems' core revenues increased at a mid-teens rate in the quarter with robust demand for both our advanced staining and core histology systems and consumables.  We saw double-digit growth across all major geographies led by China and Japan and we believe we are growing faster than the market in both histology and advanced staining.</p>
          <p>Leica Microsystems core revenues grew at a mid-single digit rate in the quarter driven by sales of compound and stereo microscopes in the U.S. and China.  We continue to be very pleased with the customer response to our SCN400 slide scanner, which enables Leica to offer its customers a complete digital scanning solution designed to store, manage and analyze digital images addressing customer requirements and offering a compelling value proposition.</p>
          <p>At Radiometer, core revenues grew at a high-single-digit rate for the quarter, driven by solid demand for our flood gas instruments and consumables in North America, Eastern Europe and Asia.  The early customer feedback to the new ABL90 FLEX has been very favorable and in August we received regulatory approval in the U.S., opening up, obviously, a significant market for future growth.  The ABL80 FLEX which is targeted more for the emerging markets also continues to do well in the market.</p>
          <p>We continue to be pleased with the results from AB SCIEX and Molecular Devices, the commercial and technical integration of the businesses are coming together and in particular the AB SCIEX team is very energized by the success of their new TripleTOF 5600 mass spectrometer.  Customer adoption of the 5600 has been progressing well with one of our first wins at the Australian Proteome Analysis Facility, a leading proteomics research institution.</p>
          <p>In July, AB SCIEX announced a collaboration with the U.S. Centers to Support Disease Control and Prevention to improve hormone testing. This collaboration is intended to support the CDC's hormone standardization project for improving the reliability of lab results used to help assess disease risks and monitor treatment.</p>
          <p>At Molecular Devices, growth in the core plate reader business has been solid complemented in the quarter by the launch of the FilterMax and SpectraMax plate reader technology acquired earlier this year.</p>
          <p>Moving to industrial technologies, revenues increased 19.5% for the quarter with core revenues up 16.5%.  Operating margin for the third quarter was 21.1%, a 410 basis point increase compared to the same period last year due to the benefit of restructuring and cost initiatives implemented in 2009 as well as the higher sales volumes in the segment.  Our core operating margin increased 270 basis points in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Product identification revenues were up 20% in the quarter with core revenues increasing 16% with strength in both instruments and consumables and across all major product categories.  Growth in the emerging markets and Europe was particularly strong.  Videojet's product innovations, coupled with their global go to market investments are driving this strong growth performance.</p>
          <p>Motion revenues were up 22% in the quarter with core revenues increasing 26.5%.  We experienced significant growth in all major geographies and markets with particularly good results in industrial automation led by electronic assembly and mobile off-highway.</p>
          <p>Sales of Kollmorgen's AKM and AKD motors and drives have been robust throughout North America, Europe and Asia.  We believe we are capturing market share and ended the third quarter with record bookings for the platform.</p>
          <p>Finally, moving to tools and components, revenues for the quarter decreased 53% due to the impact of the Apex Tool joint venture.  Core revenues for the remaining business were up 5%.  Operating margin for the quarter was 22.2%, an increase of 1,160 basis points compared to the same period last year primarily due to including the equity contribution from Apex in the segment results.</p>
          <p>So to wrap up, we're very pleased with our execution in the quarter.  With DBS's ability to drive organic growth and margin expansion and our increasing exposure to the higher growth emerging markets, we believe we are well positioned to continue to outperform for the remainder of this year and beyond.  Given the continued strength across our businesses, we will be taking the opportunity in the fourth quarter to accelerate some of our planned 2011 restructuring activities.</p>
          <p>We are initiating fourth quarter 2010 adjusted earnings per share guidance of $0.61 to $0.66 which at the midpoint represents a 13.5% increase year-over-year.  For the full year 2010 we are increasing our adjusted earnings per share guidance from the prior range of $2.16 to $2.23 to a new range of $2.25 to $2.30.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Larry.  That concludes the formal comments. Corrine, we are now ready for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We'll take our first question from Scott Davis with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This plus 50% gross margin number is pretty exceptional, as you said, but can you give us a sense of kind of when you think about and knowing we've got a little ways out to get to 2011, what's the sustainability?  I know some of this is Apex but I'm thinking kind of the non-Apex part of it, the sustainability of that type of a gross margin at this revenue level.  Is there costs that come back to the system when you think about 2011 or any other pricing issues that may impact that number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott, I think we would view 50% with this portfolio as is, is something that would be sustainable over time.  Obviously, we'll bring different businesses in above and below that number, I suspect, that will alter the mix.  But if you look at the core underlying drives here, the deconsolidation of Apex is probably worth 115 basis points so we would have been north of 50% even without that dynamic.</p>
          <p>I just think you look at so much of professional instrumentation, so much of what we do in Med Tech and even the margin improvement we've seen in industrial technologies, all contributing to that high gross margin.  And I think that as you've seen in the third quarter as we're alluding to here in the fourth quarter, we can sustain that while and in part because of the acceleration in both the cost restructuring activities as well as some of the growth investments.  So I don't think this is a high water mark never to be seen again, I think it's something this portfolio and this team is very capable of delivering.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  That's kind of what I was trying to get at.  Can we move to AB SCIEX? Because it's obviously a very important business when you think as far as forward earnings are concerned.  You didn't mention about much on it on the conference call.  Can you give us an update on the integration and how things are going there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, well I think we're very pleased with where we are here through three quarters at AB SCIEX.  I think we're going to &#x2013; we continue to see this business deal with the important but unexciting work of getting the two halves of the business stitched together.  It's important for us in a lot of ways, certainly for investors, as we do that, we pull costs out of the business, both one-time costs and unnecessary costs.  I think you see that in the improved med tech margins here.</p>
          <p>Clearly with the introduction and now the shipment of the 5600, we're out aggressively in the marketplace with technology, reinforcing that technology leadership position that AB SCIEX enjoys.  I think we're looking here at a second half, Scott, where I think the team is well positioned to deliver a high single digit growth and get back to those double-digit operating margins that we knew this team was capable of. So I think all in all, while again, it's still early, and a lot goes into the first year with any new Danaher acquisition, particularly an undertaking as significant as this, we feel very good about where that business is and where that business is headed more importantly going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Just real quick, KaVo. It looks like we've turned the corner here.  Can you just give us a sense of kind of the profit profile?  Are you making &#x2013; I guess, a) are you making money in KaVo? But b) with this mid-single digit organic volumes and the restructuring that you've done, how does this kind of match up to the rest of the segment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott, it's still below the rest of the segment, but as you know, this business was breakeven last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll do mid-single digits this year and exit even higher than that, and I think right now we are targeting mid-single digit growth, a high single digit rate, OP rate maybe even 10% next year, and that's including some additional restructuring next year as well, to then to position us again in 2012 for another lift in those margins.  So we're very pleased with the progress, taking longer than we should have, but very pleased about where we are right now with KaVo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll move on to our next question, from Bob Cornell with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks.  A lot of questions. Larry, you mentioned the market share gains and you zipped by those pretty quickly.  Maybe just go back over them, and then talk broadly about what we might expect in some of the other businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  Well, I think that there are a number of places, Bob, where we're doing particularly well.  We've had the opportunity here in the last 90 days to be out with everybody as part of our strategic reviews, as you know.  I think, you just go across the portfolio. I mean Hach Lange is doing very well, broadly speaking. Clearly the step-up in investment in emerging markets in China and beyond China I think is serving them very well.</p>
          <p>We &#x2013; clearly at Leica, particularly at Leica Biosystems with what they do in the histopathology lab, particularly the investments we've made around the advanced staining system, that continues to drive very good growth for us.  Very pleased at Radiometer, and we talked in the prepared remarks about the ABL90 and the ABL80, our two point-of-care core blood gas instruments that have been introduced and doing well.  AQT, our cardiac platform, had a very strong step-up sequentially in the third quarter as well. Gosh, clearly Dexis and the rest of the imaging platform I think is doing very well on a relative basis.  ChemTreat we've talked about, they continue to move right along.</p>
          <p>I highlighted Kollmorgen in the prepared remarks.  We don't often talk about Kollmorgen, but what they've done with their new motor and drive platforms, the AKM and the AKD, we think they're doing very well in certain industrial verticals where they've focused.</p>
          <p>So, I could go on and on.  I'll stop rambling, but I think again, this is really the culmination of a lot of work the team's done to improve our execution capability and overfund those opportunities we think warrant that sort of support.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, a lot of questions, but I guess the thing that caught my attention is your comment, again, you said the 4 billion of potential strategic money to be deployed, and you gave a pretty explicit 4 to 6 quarter being a &#x2013; what shall we glean from that with regard to acquisition activity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't think that we're saying anything more, Bob, than what we've said I think through the course of the year.  We're well positioned to continue to be an active strategic acquirer of businesses that we think strengthen our portfolio, particularly with our growth platforms in mind, investments that we think not only strengthen and build out Danaher, but will generate strong returns for shareholders.</p>
          <p>Clearly we see this current environment as one where there is plenty of opportunity.  We continue to be quite busy.  So I just don't think anyone should be surprised to see us put some serious capital to work in the short to medium term.  That's not a forecast, but just a look into the pipeline and a look to the balance sheet, and obviously a strong vote of confidence in our bandwidth to tackle capital deployments on that scale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A final question from me.  What's a comment on the Apex contribution to '11 in terms of accretion/dilution at this point?  Do you have any better view of the synergies and the outlook there now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob, it'll probably still be mildly dilutive next year.  We're spending a fair amount &#x2013; the venture is spending a fair amount of money right now to go after some costs and also some growth investments.  That'll probably continue through the first of half of '11.  So maybe when we get to the back half it's probably neutral, and then we would expect that in 2012, the venture would be accretive for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll move on to Deane Dray with Citi Investment Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Deane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was hoping we could go through some color regarding the fourth quarter guidance, especially if you could frame expectations regarding core revenue growth.  You're up against still some easier comps, but the idea here is there's upside this quarter, and how much does that carry through in the fourth?</p>
          <p>And then if I caught it correctly, it sounded like you're moving some restructuring actions that would have been done in 2011 into the fourth quarter.  And just frame for us where you expect to do restructuring and what type of payback at this stage you'd be expecting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  Deane, I would just &#x2013; let me talk about &#x2013; let me talk to some of those points.  First, I would just say that the comp does get more challenging here in the fourth quarter.  We really saw the tide come back by this point last year.  We obviously had a better fourth quarter compared to the other quarters last year come year's end.</p>
          <p>But that said, I think that, as we look out towards the rest of the year, I think on a core basis we should be up high single digits.  I wouldn't rule out 10% given the strength of the markets and I think our performance in them.  Certainly, test and measurement and motion are likely to continue to lead the way.  I like a lot of what we're seeing at Leica Biosystems right now, I think they're poised to do well in the quarter.  Product ID, as well, is positioned to do well.  So I think high single digits, possibly 10 would be where I'd call the top.</p>
          <p>We are going to step up in the fourth quarter our, if you will, our quiet restructuring and related activity.  We tend to put 10 to 15 million a quarter into improving our cost structure and obviously accelerating growth investments as well.  I suspect we could be up two, maybe three times that amount in the fourth quarter, given the room I think we'll have to make those sorts of investments, both in improving our cost structure to get a jump on 2011, but also frankly, there are some things we can pull forward that will be good growth investments, getting us ready for 2011 and well.</p>
          <p>So a combination, and I guess what I'm really flagging there for you, Deane, is we obviously had great fall through in the third quarter on &#x2013; close to 45%.  I think we're going to be down with 35% to 40% on the back of those investments in the fourth quarter, but still I think a very, very good outlook for us as we get ready for next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just maybe stating the obvious here, this is very different from the proactive restructuring that we saw you all take in the early stages of 2008.  This is all done from what I would characterize as a position of strength, just being opportunistic here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's a good, accurate description, Deane.  Given the strength we saw in the middle of the third quarter and the way it continued, we really went out to the businesses and said, I think we're going to have an opportunity here in Q4 to pull forward some of the stuff that the business is contemplating to do in 2011.  And as Larry mentioned, we've green-lighted a fair amount of that.  Depending on how the quarter plays out, we might do a little bit more than that.  It is pretty broad-based across the segments, and I think it'll give us a head start getting into '11.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and just last one for me.  Any comment on how pricing contributed in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was pretty consistent with what we've seen in the first two quarters, about a three-quarters of a percentage of price, working in some areas to get that up maybe a little bit higher going into '11, but not a lot of changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's all on the back of new products?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>New products and typically what we get with consumables.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Deane</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from Steve Tusa with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a question on some of the dynamics that happened this year and maybe a look forward a bit.  Is there anything unusual that you think about in driving this year that's going to lead to a tougher comp?  I know there's big projects that come through in water sometimes.  Anything that we need to be aware about on the go-forward basis?</p>
          <p>Second of all, there's been a lot of chatter in the medical community around hospitals seeing weaker patient volumes and it just seems like there's a little bit of risk around the hospital CapEx front in medical and maybe you could just address those concerns as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of any macro items for the businesses in 2011, Steve, nothing kind of jumps to light.  We've had two very strong years at Gilbarco Veeder Root, some of the things were regulatory driven over the last couple of years, so that could be our toughest comp going into next year.  And then, you know, the other items that companies are talking about vis-&#xE0;-vis pension, we don't have a lot there, but it will probably be a little bit of an incremental headwind given the lower discount rate that I think everyone is going to have to use going into '11 and then some of the noise and some of the changes and the tax law changes will be a modest incremental kind of headwind going into '11.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, with respect to some of the hospital based pressures, I think it's important to keep in mind that what we call Med Tech, obviously now our largest segment, half of that is dental, not really a hospital based business, largely a private pay market in most parts of the world.  And the other side, what we call life sciences and diagnostics, has, I think, pretty good balance between both its clinical exposure, research and obviously in the applied space like food and water.</p>
          <p>In the clinical space specifically I think the growth that you're seeing is delivered both at Radiometer where we're very focused on critical care which is a tough thing to cut back on: when you need to go to the emergency room, you need to go, as well as what we're doing in pathology, particularly around oncology with Leica Biosystems.  They are our two leading growth engines right now and I think they are performing well against a current backdrop of some of those hospital pressures that you've talked about.  So I don't think that anyone is necessarily immune, but we're very well positioned to, I think, work our way through that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Then one last question, I don't recall you guys mentioning acquisitions in your press release before on a quarter which is usually pretty succinct statement of that in a press release.  Are you guys having trouble finding acquisitions of size?  I mean, is Keithley kind of indicative despite it being, you know, a nice high return bolt-on, is the size of Keithley kind of indicative of what you guys are seeing or is there just a lack of opportunity on the bigger side of deals, is that why we're not seeing those recently?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, I would characterize the pipeline much as I have in the past, chock full of opportunity both larger and smaller than Keithley.  I think in a typical year or so you're going to see us do a number of deals in and around that hundred-plus range &#xE1; la Keithley, 10 to a dozen that will be smaller and then one or two that will be materially bigger.  That's, again, not a forecast for calendar 2010 but that tends to be what happens in a typical 12 month period.  So we continue to be optimistic about our ability to deploy capital not that the balance sitting there basically generating no income is an issue for us, but we do see a lot of good opportunities to strengthen the quality of this portfolio over the cycle and we intend to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from Steven Winoker with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just first on the core growth exit rates you talked about up at the tech conference that was going on in July and August and we see the final results here but are you seeing a continued acceleration through September and in which businesses are you see the fastest growth over the last month?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, it's been &#x2013; we talked in September that July and August were very strong.  We did not see any change in September I'm not saying it got faster but the very healthy pace of orders continued pretty evenly throughout the quarter.  It's broad-based.  Thinking about where we were in July probably the &#x2013; arguably the biggest lift really came in Med Tech.  In Med Tech we were looking at a 5% quarter.  In July we came out at 7.5%.  Both Radiometer and Leica Bio, which Larry alluded to, we thought would be very good quarters and they were even better than that.  I think the double-digit growth we saw at KaVo was a little better than we thought was going to occur in the quarter and Sybron sort of bouncing back to positive growth also helped that segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And internally when you start talking about what's driving that growth to give you confidence going forward, how much are you thinking is due to the new product introductions that you are talking about in every call, as opposed to other factors, sales force initiatives, etcetera?  Do you think about the &#x2013; how to think about each of those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Steve, I think it's hard to give you a macro answer because the contribution or the break down varies business by business.  Certainly new products are an important part of our story, both on an absolute and a relative basis.  I think clearly new products help gain &#x2013; drive market share.  But the investments we'll be making on the margin have been weighted toward emerging markets.  That gives us that mix benefit if you will.</p>
          <p>And again, I think there's just a lot of energy the last several years behind our DBS growth investments, around new product development and sales and marketing execution.  Even if we're just out selling something that may be three or four or five years old, having more people out, being more effective in terms of how we generate leads, how we prepare those sales people to get in front of customers and help them solve their problems is really all part of the mix.  So I wish I had a better top side answer for you but it's really again kind of a mix of a whole host of different efforts business by business that come together to drive this performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and on the &#x2013; last time you talked about the supply chain challenges and those being sort of the biggest operating challenges out there. What are you seeing there in terms of constraints, electronics, elsewhere and also maybe comment on what you're seeing in terms of material and wage dynamics?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, as a matter of fact, Larry and I were just talking about supply chain yesterday and it was noteworthy as we did our reviews across the businesses for the third quarter and their kind of monthly President's letters, the lack of discussion about supply chain issues.  So it feels like it's gotten better across a number of our businesses, in other words the supply chains, particularly in the electronics area, I wouldn't say it's totally caught up to date, but the issues we were having in the first half have really died down.</p>
          <p>You know, we don't have a lot of exposure to materials, to commodities; it's really more in the joint venture today where they have some of that exposure.  In terms of wage inflation clearly we're seeing that in the emerging markets.  That is a challenge both from a cost perspective but also from retention perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one last technical question.  In the goodwill walk in the 10-Q you had 174 million of write-down and it was associated with dispositions and JV formation.  Am I correct in assuming that was all or almost all the JV or was it other parts of the business where you were writing things down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it was the JV.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />  We'll move on to John Inch with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, John. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning.  So, maybe a question for Dan.  I was wondering, Dan, can we get a little more color around the run rate through sort of the second half of incremental investment spending you guys had articulated in the first half that you were going to make, and I guess maybe how that &#x2013; I'm assuming the extra restructuring you're doing in the fourth quarter, about $0.06 is discrete, right? There was no extra restructuring, if you will, in the third quarter.  Where do we stand.  Like I see your R&amp; D was 6.4% but some of that I think you called out associated with the JV.  Can you just kind of help walk us through those two buckets and kind of how to think about that heading into next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, maybe first on the restructuring side and the incremental growth side.  We've been going through our normal kind of quiet restructuring, which Larry alluded to, kind of the 10 plus million a quarter.  We're going to be stepping up that here in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>On the growth investment side, you know, we could be &#x2013; we could be falling through particularly when you have sort of 12, 13% organic growth.  We could be falling through at 55% given the contribution margins in a number of our businesses, particularly in places like Med Tech and I think that scale down kind of a 40, 45% fall through gives you a sense of kind of the step up for the investment.</p>
          <p>R&amp;D is clearly keeping pace with our growth rate, so we're growing R&amp;D at a double-digit rate in almost all of our businesses.  We're seeing that.  You're also seeing the step up in the sales and marketing particularly in the feet on the street investment, all kind of core adds, particularly in the emerging markets, as well as in a number of cases, converting distribution in emerging markets to direct.  I'm not sure I can roll it up for you, John, and give you a number, but we've had a substantial step up in investment both in the R&amp;D and the go to market here through the first nine months of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you actually accelerating that then, Dan, as you roll into next year or are we going to be at a steady state by the fourth quarter as you roll into 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some of this step up investment in the fourth quarter will be on the growth side.  It's going to again be converting some distribution to direct, we're also stepping up some web-based marketing, go to market activities.  We're probably pretty close to kind of a run rate but again there will be some incremental step up here in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand.  And then just philosophically, Larry, when you first embarked upon building your medical businesses, the market had valued healthcare significantly higher.  Debatably your stock may have lagged a little bit because of your healthcare exposure.  As you look to doing further deals, what is your appetite since this path started toward doing further &#x2013; getting Danaher further down the medical path or would you actually look a little more favorably toward industrial?  I'm just thinking of strategically how you're weighing these things philosophically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, I think when we got into Med Tech five years ago, we were very focused strategically on avoiding some of the risk factors that I think get a lot of coverage today.  Risk factors such as reimbursement, single payor dynamics, let alone certain situations where obviously competition is quite fierce.  I think that's why you see us with the Med Tech segment that we have today, Dental having its own discrete dynamics, where obviously now we're very much a market leader.  In life sciences and diagnostics we've gone into some niche areas, be it critical care or histopathology on the diagnostic side, obviously with Leica and SCIEX, some targeted research applications with very good applied market exposure like food and environmental.</p>
          <p>So, I don't think we have any regrets whatsoever.  I think all these adds have represented, over the last five years, incremental positives for the Danaher portfolio and our potential to drive the top, the bottom and the cash flow through cycles and I think as we go forward here and if we deploy that capital we alluded to earlier over the next year or so, please don't be surprised to see us continue to invest and hopefully invest smartly in Med Tech, not exclusively, because we still want to do things in T&amp;M and environmental, product ID as well, but we have lost none of our courage or our conviction about those opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In other words, think of maybe a bit of a portfolio balance then, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's what you see today.  If Med Tech was a company unto itself, again because of that research, that clinical, that applied market balance, it's &#x2013; it would be a steady ship in any possible storm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Moving on to Nigel Coe with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Nigel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just wanted to kind of go back to the restructuring.  Looks like you're talking about $0.04 of restructuring, just want to clarify a few points.  First of all, that's been absorbed within the guidance you've given this morning?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nigel -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; that's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then secondly, you said pulled through some of the actions for 2011.  Does that mean you're still going to do the $10 to $12 million per quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.  We're not looking to &#x2013; we have to obviously get into all the budgets, but the plan is to then pull forward stuff later in '11 to early in '11.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's fine.  Just wanted to clarify that point.  And then as we get &#x2013; if we go back to last quarter, obviously med tech margins were below 9%, I think you gave guidance of 2 points improvement from 3Q into 4Q. You obviously got that 4 points in 3Q. Do you still think you can approve margins in med tech from 3Q to 4Q?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operationally we can, but that will be a segment that will receive some of the restructuring.  So I expect margins in med tech that would be probably a little bit better than Q3.  But on a &#x2013; hopefully an exit rate better, and part of it being the favorable Q4 seasonality ex the restructuring. You should see another nice step up in the restructuring, though, because of the restructuring.  You won't actually see that in the reported number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's fair to say the bulk of the restructuring will go into med tech?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's going to be &#x2013; if we're talking 40 million plus of restructuring, that's over 100 basis points of margin across the business, and that will be med tech, professional instrumentation, and industrial tech.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's clear.  And then, looking at test and measurement core growth, obviously that's very high levels. I mean, how does that decay?  I mean, it looks like you got weaker comps &#x2013; well, comps get a little bit tougher, but still fairly weak comps going into 2Q '11.  But do you feel &#x2013; so first of all, if you could address that, and then secondly, obviously we're seeing some weakening in semiconductor lead indicators, and you do have a consumer electronics exposure through these businesses.  So do you view that as a negative for test and measurement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think first, in terms of the comps, you're right, we still have &#x2013; I mean, we should continue to have very good performance there, if for no other reason than the comps.  I think what we're finally seeing at Tek kick in is a number of the R&amp;D and go-to-market investments and kaizen improvements that they have laid in, which helps us.</p>
          <p>And I think frankly, despite some of those secular issues that you raised, Nigel, I think this business is just flat out executing better on a global basis compared to where they were two years ago.  So I think that that execution, obviously we've got some portfolio moves here into sectors like video test, obviously, we've made a significant move into service, I think bodes very well for Tek's ability to drive through some of those concerns.  But in terms of what we're seeing, it's really still quite buoyant at Tek and at Fluke right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and so as we get into second half of next year in a more normalized environment, what sort of growth would you expect in test and measurement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if you look at that business all up, it should be mid-single digits plus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Larry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Nigel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Taking our next question, that'll come from Jeff Sprague with Vertical Research Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Good morning.  Just a couple quick ones.  Everything you just said on kind of the quiet restructuring, pretty clear.  I'm just wondering, as you roll all that up, is there any significant, then, restructuring benefit carry-over into 2011, or just the issue of kind of the cadence of the spending that you already talked about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there'll be some incremental positive from the step-up of what we're doing here going into '11 but, that's maybe a couple pennies a share. If it's 20, 30 million of incremental spend here in Q4, should get us sort of &#x2013; almost a one-to-one return in 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How about on thinking about deals, SCIEX in particular, but all the other smaller stuff you've rolled into the 10 base.  As it stands now what kind of aggregated deal accretion do you look at in '11 versus '10?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't want to steal Larry's thunder in December, but clearly the biggest driver there should be SCIEX.  It's &#x2013; with all the transition expense, the acquisition accounting expenses it's probably a mid-single digit pre-tax contributor here and we would expect a sizeable step up there in 2011, as well as some of the recent test and measurements deals, but Arbor Networks and Keithley being contributors.  But again, I'll let Larry roll that up in December.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just housekeeping, in terms of along the lines of rolling up.  What do we do with the tool stub here? Do you collapse it into industrial, or what's the game plan there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Given how small tools and components segment now is, we're in the process of evaluating the segments and I think in the near term we'll be modifying how we present the segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Moving on to Terry Darling with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, just a couple of small cleanups here.  You know, first, Dan, on the professional instrumentation margin, revenue is up a little bit, margin is down a little bit.  Is that just mix that's essentially going on there in terms of the percent margin change there, or is there something else to talk about there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess &#x2013; they were both 21% plus, I guess it's down sequentially very modestly.  Q3 for Fluke tends to be a little bit lower margin seasonally and we probably had some of that, but I could go back and look at that if you like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That doesn't sound like there's anything real significant there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then on this 400 basis points sequential improvement, you sort of talked around it.  I'll just ask more directly, it sounded like the life sciences piece was up more than 400 basis points sequentially and dental was obviously up strong but maybe a little less than that.  Is that the right picture there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there are three or four contributing factors.  One, the fact that the core growth came in at 7.5 versus our guidance of 6% and the very high fall-through we get in that segment, two, KaVo being up over 400 basis points year-on-year, big contributor there. Leica was up over 200 basis points year-over-year, and then SCIEX holds the &#x2013; sort of the absence of some of the acquisition expenses as well as just core basis, a nice step up both in core growth but also operating margin was kind of the fourth factor that helped drive the sequential improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and then, on the core growth, I may have missed this, for dental in the fourth quarter, is that &#x2013; the comp gets, I think, a little tougher.  Does that stay in the upper-singles or did you indicate that's back to the mid-singles?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We thought Sybron would accelerate from kind of low-singles to mid-singles, and KaVo was double is probably going to be mid-single digit to high-single digit, partly because of the comp issue you referenced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Moving on to Richard Eastman with Robert W. Baird.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I'll pick my two questions here.  On the Med Tech side, just curious, when you're looking at the margins there, obviously we have some work to do and plenty of work to do at KaVo.  How are Leica's margins relative to the consolidated Med Tech margin?  Are we still managing that with growth investments?  Are they still below the Med Tech overall margin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rick, they're at low double-digits and we're still working that.  As you know, when we bought it, it was around a 4 or 5% OP business and we still believe ultimately that's sort of a high-teen contributor to the segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rick, just to be clear though, we think we can drive that margin expansion and continue to invest there.  So it's a, you know, we're with that team next week, in fact in Wetzlar.  It's the balance of it has thus far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But there's still plenty of investment opportunities and it's a matter of moving the cost directionally down but investing in the right spots?  That's how we're basically managing the margin there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, given the gross margin there, what we're seeing is if we can just control and kind of keep flat the G&amp;A and the manufacturing expense, we're going to see 100 basis points plus of margin improvement just from the fall through of the good organic growth we're getting there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see.  Okay.  And then Larry, just a question geographically. As we pushed into the fall here, when you look at the three major regions, U.S., Europe, and the emerging markets including China, do you &#x2013; is there anything from a trend line perspective, any of those three markets that you're particularly watching closely at this point, either a slowdown or an acceleration?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we watch them all, Rick. It's hard, I think, to take the 20-plus percent emerging market growth for granted. But having been on calls earlier in the week with both our China and our India teams, they're still quite bullish about the near to medium term. I think that we were very pleased with the U.S. being up low doubles, as it were, and Europe coming in at 10%.</p>
          <p>If I had to pick one of the three that I probably am most concerned about, though concerned might be an overstatement, I'd probably pick Europe just for all the macro factors that everybody else has been talking about.  No particular insight or specific issue in mind there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right, very good.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We'll move on to SunTrust with Wendy Caplan asking the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Wendy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, you talked about sales increases in terms of feet on the street at ChemTreat and elsewhere.  Can you talk about hiring for production workers, other categories like engineering at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The &#x2013; certainly part of the step up in R&amp;D that you see here, Wendy, is a function of hiring scientists, technologists, engineers, both for core technology development as well as new products.  I don't have a specific number there for you, but obviously you see it in the P&amp;L.  I think that part of what you're seeing in the gross margins and the BCMs is frankly very good execution on the shop floor relative to the restructuring coupled with the way we're tackling the step up in volume this year.  So I know we do have an increase in our manufacturing head count but it has been quite modest, hence the productivity gains and in turn the variable margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Larry, are you hiring full time workers or are you hiring temp workers, how should we think about that strategically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that it really is a business by business decision, depending on, you know, the nature of the demand curves.  I don't think we necessarily have a bias in one direction or another, obviously a lot of our businesses now it's also a global call in terms of where volumes are arising let alone being handled from a production perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And one last one, you talk a lot on these calls about new products and new opportunities from those products.  Can you give us some size, size these for us?  Are there any that you would call a, quote, "Breakthrough product," for the company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that at this point in terms of a breakthrough product, you know, again, it's really more moving &#x2013; many of these introductions move the needle for their respective businesses.  Certainly the products or the big product that AB SCIEX launched is a game changer for them, the 5600, no doubt about that.  I think what you're seeing really in terms of the suite of products that have come out here at Radiometer around the AB90 FLEX, the 80 FLEX, as well as AQT is very much a game changer for them and perhaps in turn for Danaher.  I wouldn't want to leave out the BOND introduction at Leica Biosystems because that's driving obviously good growth part of the results here today.</p>
          <p>But what we really haven't flagged yet because we're building the install base is the aftermarket consumable stream, much like Radiometer that we are in the course of building as we build up that install base.  That's a few years down the road still, Wendy, but I think the more we shift the revenue mix at Leica toward consumables, the stronger the contribution that business will be making back, in part, to Rick's question.  I think all in all it's a business by business approach and we've got a lot of good folks executing quite well on the new product introductions this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks, Larry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We do have time for one final question, that will come from Jason Feldman with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So earlier in the call you addressed the hospital budget situation.  But when thinking about the other kind of traditional life science customers: academic, pharma, industrial, do you have any kind of view on how their budgets are going to look next year.  Are they going to be the same, similar type of headwinds or better, worse?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was pleased to read your note yesterday relative to the U.K. trends that looked more encouraging today than they might have earlier in the week.  We're really in the process of pulling all of that together as Dan alluded to.  We'll present our '11 views when we get together in December.  But I think by and large, when we talk about those non-clinical applications, be they research, be they applied, Jason, I think we're still of the view that both at Leica and at AB SCIEX particularly, we're positioned for growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then lastly, quickly on AB SCIEX, you've only had them for a couple of quarters.  New product introductions seem to have been well received but this is a business that had been losing share for quite some time.  Have you noticed already a change in the trend from a market share perspective there?  Or is it too early?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think with the 5600 we're out that business growing at a high single digit rate here in the second half, frankly, that's a rate that they have not enjoyed for some time.  And I'm not convinced the market is growing at that rate so that has to translate, at least mathematically, into share gain and more importantly, frankly, than share gain in any one quarter that team is back on its toes, it's out in the market.  The story is going to take a while to write, but I really like where we are here as we get close to the year one anniversary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That concludes the question and answer session.  Mr. McGrew, I'll turn the conference over to you for any additional or closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Corrine.</p>
          <p>Just as a reminder, the replay number is 888-203-1112 in the U.S. and 719-457-0820 internationally and the confirmation is 4297828.  Dan and I are going to be around all day today for any follow-up calls for the folks still left in the queue.</p>
          <p>Thank you, everybody, for joining us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude today's conference.  We thank you for your participation, and have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>