<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1376517" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-03-09</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7857</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Nathalie Errard, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Louis Gallois, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Hans Peter Ring, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Celine Fornaro</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Ben Fidler</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Avi Hoddes</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Zafar Khan</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Olivier Brochet</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Rupinder Vig</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Jason Adams</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Edward Stacey</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Doug Harned</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Antoine Boivin-Champeaux</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Gary Murphy</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Harry Breach</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Yan Derocles</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. This is the EADS full year earnings 2010 conference call. Louis Gallois, our CEO and Hans Peter Ring, our CFO, will be presenting our results and answering your questions. This call is planned to last about one hour and 30 minutes and should conclude at around 11 a.m. Continental European Time. This includes Q&amp;A which we will conduct after the initial presentation. It is also webcast; we've set a special banner for full year earnings 2010.</p>
          <p>Playback of this call will also be accessible only on the website. The supporting information package was e-mailed to you this early morning with slides, which we will now go through and financial statements. Throughout this call we will be making forward-looking statements. The packages you received contain a Safe Harbor statement which applies to this call as well. We believe you should read it carefully.</p>
          <p>Now to Louis Gallois.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome, ladies and gentlemen. The past three years have been about managing turbulence, program risk, industry weakness and financial downturn while laying the foundation for growth. We did not stand still. We improved our backlog. We cut costs significantly. We achieved strong operational performance and improved profitability in our Space and Defense divisions. We built up our assets and derisked our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Looking at the next three years, we will extract opportunity from a commercial market which, while complex, is now in an up-cycle and we will leverage the strong fundamentals we have already built. Naturally we are alert to potential risk. There is uncertainty over oil and commodity prices and air traffic in North Africa and currency continues to be an issue.</p>
          <p>But on the whole, we see strong momentum in our top line portfolio growth and promising signs for our underlying profitability. What are the building blocks of EADS success over the next three years? First, a financial policy which has given us strategic flexibility through high liquidity, strong cash flow and an ability to finance our ambitions; second, a strong and increasing backlog, which at almost &#x20AC;450 billion is at a record level even post-crisis and provides future profit potential; third, a product strategy which has resulted in innovative and valued offerings to meet critical demands in the aerospace market.</p>
          <p>Look at the early NEO success. Progress on program development is confirmed with significant derisking on the A400M and A380 programs. We have implemented a stop-and-fix approach on the A350 XWB, nevertheless the time schedule remains challenging. It is our top risk program and will need to be closely monitored and challenged in the years to come.</p>
          <p>Fourth, a commercial strategy which will leverage the strong fundamentals we have already built. Our backlog is aligned towards the fast growth regions of Asia and the Middle East and is also well positioned in established markets such as Europe and North America. The improvement in U.S. airline profitability gives us optimism that they will be able to start a new ordering wave.</p>
          <p>A more in-depth picture of our accelerating growth is shown at page four. There you can see our backlog, up 15%; order intake, up a dramatic 81%; and our net cash position, which has increased by 22%. These are the foundation blocks for our future growth. When I look at these strengths and the positive market direction, I see significant upside in mid-term profitability.</p>
          <p>The dynamic economies of Asia and Latin America represent the most immediate and largest areas of demand. This is true for commercial aircraft where demand for Airbus products has returned to pre-recession levels. It is also true for a wide range of security products and services. A more complicated picture is presented by the mature economies of the U.S., Europe and Japan. Here we see a slower growth trajectory on the commercial side and constrained demand for defense and security products. At the same time, the general trend is towards steady economic improvement.</p>
          <p>In overcoming the challenges of the past two years, we have nurtured a flexible management with a successful track record and strong customer relationships in the world's growth markets.</p>
          <p>Despite outside discussions from time-to-time we have created a single company culture, we now share common company values, work more efficiently across borders and have eliminated the national and structural barriers, which grew out of our cross-border merger over a decade ago.</p>
          <p>The value of this achievement can now finally flow into performance improvement. Our unified culture means synergies in knowledge and program management. Our diverse background gives us flexibility to market and adapt our products and services portfolio to specific regional needs. Our shared experience in facing economic challenges leads to a high degree of collaboration and strong risk management systems.</p>
          <p>Now, onto page five where you will see that our 2010 financials exceeded our expectations. The commercial market recovery, driven by the emerging countries, has been stronger than anticipated at the beginning of the year.</p>
          <p>Commercial aircraft orders are significantly higher than expected. The strong backlog management and ramp-up success at Airbus has led to another record delivery year with 510 commercial aircraft deliveries.</p>
          <p>EBIT before one-off is better than expected, thanks to better operational performance across all divisions, including Airbus Commercial. Free cash flow performance far exceeded our expectations, driven by the better EBIT before one-off and inventory management performance, higher order intake and lower customer financing requirements due to unexpected improvement in financial markets.</p>
          <p>Before I hand over to Hans Peter, who will talk you through the 2010 actual performance and the evolution compared to 2009, please turn to page six, the 2011 dividend. The Board of Directors will propose a dividend of &#x20AC;0.22 per share to the Annual General Meeting of Shareholders representing 32% of the earnings per share. The dividend will be paid out of the distributable reserves. Gradual improvement of profitability is the key indicator for better dividend distribution in the future.</p>
          <p>Hans Peter will now walk you through the 2010 financial highlights. Hans Peter, to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to everybody from my side as well and a very early good morning to the colleagues in the U.S.. So we're now on slide eight with the financial highlights.</p>
          <p>2010 financial highlights demonstrate revenue growth of around 7% compared to last year. The growth comes from both volume and mix effects across our core businesses reduced by a negative foreign exchange impact of around &#x20AC;500 million.</p>
          <p>The percentage of completion methodology was resumed on the A400M program based on the allocation of internal milestones. This has resulted in revenues of around &#x20AC;1 billion being booked on the program with zero margin due to the associated provision utilization.</p>
          <p>The EBIT before one-off stands at around &#x20AC;1.3 billion for EADS and around &#x20AC;280 million for Airbus. It benefited from good performance in Airbus legacy programs and our core business activities in the other divisions.</p>
          <p>Compared to 2009, EBIT before one-off was mainly weighed down by the deterioration of hedge rates. Order intake of &#x20AC;83 billion was significantly above the '09 level, driven by the higher level of commercial aircraft orders at Airbus.</p>
          <p>Our order book stands at a record &#x20AC;448 billion, reflecting the improved commercial aircraft momentum. The Airbus commercial backlog benefited from a positive revaluation impact of around &#x20AC;25 billion due to the U.S. dollar closing spot rate that has strengthened since last year, it is from 1.44 to 1.34.</p>
          <p>On slide nine, this slide shows the underlying performance of the business. The EBIT before one-off margin is 2.9% at the group level, which is still not a satisfactory level. To make it easier for you to analyze, we have split out Airbus Commercial. As expected, the underlying performance of the single aisle and long-range aircraft at Airbus Commercial is weighed down by the A380.</p>
          <p>At Airbus, total one-time effects were roughly neutral. The negative impact from foreign exchange was offset by a release in provisions. The other non-Airbus division performance is weighed down by around &#x20AC;120 million in net negative one-time items. The largest proportion are in Eurocopter, which has reported roughly &#x20AC;120 million of negative one-time effect that weigh on the underlying performance in 2010, driven mainly by the NH90 and a restructuring charge for the implementation of SHAPE, the restructuring program.</p>
          <p>The other effects come from Cassidian, with a net charge of around &#x20AC;20 million, which includes the cancellation of a U.K. contract with the fire brigade, as well as a positive foreign exchange effect of about &#x20AC;15 million booked in ATR.</p>
          <p>Up to slide 10 now. R&amp;D rose versus last year, driven mainly by increases at Cassidian for the Cassidian Systems business as well as at Eurocopter across the product range. At Airbus, the increase in R&amp;D for the A350 XWB was roughly compensated by decreases in other programs, especially the A380 and the A330 200-F, so the freighter. The improvement in interest result mainly reflects lower interest expenses.</p>
          <p>Meanwhile, the other financial result improved considerably by around &#x20AC;170 million year-on-year, mainly due to lower unwinding of discounted provisions in 2010 than in 2009. The unwinding of discount decreases due to lower discounted provisions outstanding. The tax rate for the year 2010 is 30% as expected.</p>
          <p>Now onto the hedging portfolio update on slide 11. In 2010, we have taken advantage of the strengthening U.S. dollar by implementing $28.9 billion of new hedge contracts at an average rate of 1.33 versus the euro without collateralization. This has allowed us to slightly improve the overall hedge rate of our portfolio. Over the same period, $18.5 billion of forward contracts matured at a rate of $1.35 per euro. Besides the new forward contracts, EADS invested in foreign exchange options covering a volume of $2.3 billion. Options consume less hedging capacity while allowing for a potential upside from more favorable market rates.</p>
          <p>Our hedge book increased from $60.8 billion at the end of '09 to $70.2 billion at the end of 2010. During the last quarter, we have continued to hedge at a healthy, but slower pace than that of the maturing hedges.</p>
          <p>As our net exposure is hedged for the next two years, we may limit the overall size of our hedge portfolio and adapt the hedging speed accordingly. This should enable us to increase our level of flexibility and hedging capacity with banks in the forward market.</p>
          <p>Quarterly rates for 2011 are provided on page 29. As you already know, we will suffer a further hedge rate deterioration of $1.38 per euro next year, but the good news is the deterioration is lower than in previous years.</p>
          <p>Up to our cash flow now on slide 12. Free cash flow at &#x20AC;2.7 billion is significantly above expectation, thanks to better operational and inventory management performance, stronger pre-delivery payments at Airbus Commercial and lower customer financing requirements than expected. The improvement is driven by working capital. At Airbus Commercial, inventory reduction is driven by delivery patterns.</p>
          <p>The inflow of advances linked to Airbus Commercial activity in 2010 was stronger than expected and is higher than one year ago, particularly in the fourth quarter, reflecting the planned ramp-up in deliveries and higher commercial aircraft orders. This is more than offset by lower advance payments at Astrium and Cassidian compared to 2009, which was driven by the exceptional order intake that year.</p>
          <p>Due to a combination of appetite from lessors and banking market recovery, customer financing generated a positive contribution of around &#x20AC;60 million compared to a 2009 outflow of &#x20AC;400 million. Investing activities consumed around &#x20AC;2.3 billion as expected, mainly as investment ramp-up on the 350 program. A cash contribution to pension assets of around &#x20AC;550 million has been made.</p>
          <p>And now Louis will talk you through the performance of the Airbus division in more detail on page 14.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Hans Peter. In 2010, Airbus achieved another record year for deliveries and the market rebound driven by continuing appetite for growth in emerging markets, led to 644 new firm commercial orders. 574 net orders were booked including orders for 32 A380 and 78 A350 XWB, bringing the A350 order book total to 583 aircraft from 36 customers.</p>
          <p>The A320 NEO was launched in the fourth quarter and has seen early market success. The commercial backlog of 3,552 aircraft translates into a significant volume increase across the commercial product range. The order book of &#x20AC;379 billion benefited from a positive valuation impact of around &#x20AC;25 billion due to the strengthening value of the U.S. dollar against the euro at the end of 2010 versus 2009.</p>
          <p>With 18 A380s delivered as expected the program is stabilizing and we are making significant progress on the learning curve, leading to an improvement of the gross margin per aircraft. On the A350 we have made good progress with the beginning of manufacturing for sub-components and sub-assemblies at section level. However, the time schedule remains challenging. Entry into service is scheduled for H2 2013 as previously communicated.</p>
          <p>In its military segment, Airbus delivered 20 medium and light military aircraft, four more than in 2009, 21 new medium and light orders were booked for CN235 and CN-295, resulting in a 2010 military backlog of 241 aircraft.</p>
          <p>The A400M order book has benefited from a positive adjustment to reflect the customer negotiation outcome. The A330-based multi-role tanker transport aircraft achieved civil and military certification and the FSTA conducted its first flight. The A400M program continues to make progress with four development aircraft flying. The A400M maturity gate milestone passed in February 2011 clears the way to the start of serious production and I am happy to announce that the clearance for the serious production has been given today. Civil certification is planned for 2011.</p>
          <p>Up to slide 15, compared to a year ago, Airbus commercial revenues reflect the favorable volume and mix effect, which includes the higher number of A380 deliveries. The negative impact on revenues from foreign exchange is around &#x20AC;500 million. Two A330-200 aircraft were delivered under operating lease and thus do not count for revenues and margin recognition.</p>
          <p>The remaining two single aisle aircraft delivered under operating lease in H1 have now been sold down the market, bringing total deliveries to 132 aircraft for the last quarter for revenue and margin recognition. Airbus commercial EBIT before one-off benefits from favorable volume and mix effect, pricing improvement net of escalation and Power8 savings. It is reduced due to hedge rate deterioration by around &#x20AC;940 million, cost escalation and costs associated with business growth.</p>
          <p>Consistent with a return to the percentage-of-completion methodology, the internal milestones passed during 2010 have triggered revenues of around &#x20AC;1 billion for the A400M at zero margin. This Airbus military revenues growth is reduced by lower revenues in medium and light and tankers, a favorable delivery mix benefited the EBIT performance.</p>
          <p>Now Hans Peter will talk you through the other divisions beginning with Eurocopter on slide 16. Hans Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Louis. The 2010 net order trend in Eurocopter was stable with 2009 despite a lower level of gross orders because cancellations were also lower at 49 helicopters compared to 105 a year ago.</p>
          <p>Recovery in the civil market is slow, in particular due to the number of helicopters available for sale on the second hand market. Eurocopter has proactively started to adapt to this challenge with its SHAPE program launched in early 2010. Good progress has been made on the reduction of workforce and operating costs.</p>
          <p>527 helicopters were delivered this year in total, including 28 NH90 and 15 Tiger helicopters, double the size we delivered in 2009. The Dutch and French navies received the first NH90 naval version.</p>
          <p>Revenues also reflect the favorable mix from higher support and governmental revenues. EBIT declined 30% compared to 2009, impacted by higher product investment, a negative one-time effect of around &#x20AC;120 million driven mainly by the NH90 and a restructuring charge.</p>
          <p>Eurocopter began flight testing with X3 high-speed hybrid demonstrator aircraft, a key focus of Eurocopter innovation strategy, and achieved the maiden flight of the second EC175 prototype and the Korean Utility Helicopter.</p>
          <p>Onto Astrium now on slide 17. 2010 here marked a year of strong program execution, resulting in revenue performance above expectations, more than compensating the one-time catch-up effect for in-orbit incentive schemes booked in 2009. 2010 milestones include the start of the M51 ballistic missile deliveries for the French navy.</p>
          <p>10 Astrium satellites were launched and are performing successfully and Ariane 5 delivered its 41st consecutive launch success, bringing the total number to six launches in the year.</p>
          <p>EBIT reflects growth and productivity in defense and military services, as well as operational improvement in institutional activities. Order intake reached &#x20AC;6 billion supported by continued commercial momentum so far.</p>
          <p>2010 orders include M51 evolution and maintenance contracts and two optical reconnaissance satellites for the French DGA, as well as the Skynet 5 contract extension with the U.K. MoD.</p>
          <p>Contracts by ESA were awarded to begin the first development phase of Ariane 5 mid-life extension and to undertake initial development studies for a next generation launcher. Astrium also launched a transformation program called Agile to increase efficiency and prepare for a changing competitive environment.</p>
          <p>Now up to Cassidian on slide 18. Cassidian is beginning to feel the first pressure from the home country defense budget situation with some delayed order intake and higher R&amp;D. However, 2010 demonstrated robust performance.</p>
          <p>The German government is expected to communicate on its plans in the spring. In the meantime, a transformation plan is under preparation for the new business environment, which will see growth in the security business.</p>
          <p>Cassidian delivered a strong revenue increase compared to 2009, reflecting higher volume from core and export in Eurofighter and missile programs, and progress in the Lead Systems Integration border security contracts.</p>
          <p>EBIT reflects margin growth in mature programs and significant growth in self-funded R&amp;D for next generation products. It is weighed down by a net negative one-time effect of around &#x20AC;20 million, which includes the cancellation of the Firecontrol contract in the U.K. R&amp;D is focused mainly on unmanned aerial systems and secure communications.</p>
          <p>We continue to investigate requirements and funding solutions for Talarion with customers. We are stressing the need for a timely commitment to the program by governments. A successful first flight for Euro Hawk and continued testing of the Barracuda demonstrator confirm technical capability in this business field.</p>
          <p>Order intake reached &#x20AC;4.3 billion despite a more challenging environment but was below the revenue level. The order book of &#x20AC;16.9 billion remains solid. Cassidian continued its globalization journey, joining forces with Odebrecht in Brazil in the field of defense and security technology, creating an engineering center in India as well as a joint venture with Larsen &amp; Toubro.</p>
          <p>Finally, other businesses on slide 19. Revenues increased by 8% here compared to 2009, driven predominantly by the ramp-up in LUH deliveries at EADS North America. EBIT growth came from increases at ATR and Sogerma but was reduced by higher investment at EADS North America. The increase at ATR included a positive one-time effect for foreign exchange of &#x20AC;15 million.</p>
          <p>The order book of other businesses stood at &#x20AC;2.5 billion. At ATR, order intake was higher than expected with a very active market on the new -600 version, 78 firm net orders and 33 options were booked in the year, bringing ATR market share to around 65% in 2010, confirming its leadership on the segment.</p>
          <p>ATR delivered 52 aircrafts compared to 53 in '09. The backlog stands at 159 aircrafts and production rates are expected to increase in 2011, thanks to a notable improvement in its market and financing environment.</p>
          <p>Addressing a potential key helicopter campaign in the U.S., EADS North America conducted the first flight of its Armed Aerial Scout 72X technical demonstration aircraft in December. It also delivered the 150th UH-72A Lakota Light Utility Helicopter to the U.S. army on time and together with Eurocopter.</p>
          <p>Now Louis will comment on our guidance on page 21.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks, Hans Peter. For 2011 guidance, take the slide 21. It is based on an assumption of &#x20AC;1 for $1.35 for average and year-end closing spot rate. In 2011, Airbus should deliver 520 to 530 commercial aircrafts and its gross orders should be above its deliveries. EADS 2011 revenues should be above the 2010 revenues. EADS expects 2011 EADS EBIT before one-off to remain stable compared to the 2010 level at around &#x20AC;1.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Increasing volume and price improvement at Airbus Commercial are roughly compensated by the deterioration of hedge rates, increasing research and development and less favorable mix of activities at Cassidian.</p>
          <p>Going forward, the reported EBIT and EPS performance of EADS will be dependent on the group's ability to execute on the A400M, A380 and A350 XWB programs in line with the commitments made to its customers.</p>
          <p>Reported EBIT and EPS also depend on exchange rate fluctuations. At &#x20AC;1 for $1.35, EADS expects 2011 EPS to be above the 2010 level of &#x20AC;0.68. Free cash flow is expected to be positive. It is the most volatile item and EADS will give a more precise guidance later in the year.</p>
          <p>In 2012, the group expects a significant improvement in its EBIT before one-off, thanks to higher volume, better pricing and improvement of A380 performance at Airbus.</p>
          <p>Now, a few words to conclude. Our innovative product portfolio is the right mix for the next decade. After several years of significant change within our company, we can now execute on our portfolio strengths in a more focused way. In our commercial business, this means achieving higher rates of profitability. In defense, it means identifying areas where we are the best value provider despite a slow growth environment and where we can be a top player in any future industry consolidation. Here our strategic position as the second largest European defense company affords us real advantages.</p>
          <p>Our strategy of putting money into continuous innovation and product diversity was correct. Our execution, however, was not adequate. Today, execution has now radically improved. Indeed, quality execution is now the organizing principle of EADS management.</p>
          <p>Our Airbus legacy programs continue to perform well. For the most part, we have capped risk on our difficult programs, the A380 and the A400M. We also believe that we have defined the risk parameters surrounding the A350 in a manner, which makes our development horizon more predictable than was the case with our A380 experience, but it is still changing.</p>
          <p>Finally, we have evolved our financial strategy and practices in a manner which gives us the utmost flexibility for organic growth or acquisition throughout the decade. The principles are well known to you.</p>
          <p>First, our consistent focus on liquidity and strong positive cash flow is a strength in its own right. It provides us with investment flexibility. It positions us strategically for any consolidation, particularly in defense, and it demonstrates product management, which is valued by the rating agencies.</p>
          <p>Next, transparent and highly active financial involvement in programs. As we shift towards higher growth mode, we are in a strong position to ensure we have strong returns through efficient management of our backlog. We certainly need to improve profitability and I am quite confident we can achieve this. It is the highest priority of our financial policy.</p>
          <p>Finally, EADS has grown and matured. It successfully adapted to the challenges of recent years by building strong fundamentals. We have a great balanced portfolio across our activities. We are now poised for further profitability in commercial aircraft, provided we execute well on our program. Hence, investors should feel that we enter 2011 as a reliable performer with strong assured management, one with significant profitability upside, given our alignment with the growth of global market demand. 2011 is our year of transition as one company with a future in our sights. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now start our Q&amp;A time. Please introduce yourself and your company when asking your question. Please limit yourself to two questions at a time. And so, as usual, please remember to speak clearly and slowly to help all participants, particularly ourselves, understand what you're asking.</p>
          <p>So Maria, please go ahead and explain the procedure for the participants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, madam. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from Celine Fornaro, Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Two questions if I may. The first one would be on the R&amp;D profile that we should think about for Airbus and the group for 2011, '12 and also over the mid-term?</p>
          <p>And secondly if you could just remind us the A350 milestones that we should expect over the next nine months of this year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Louis, I have the first one and you the second. That's fine?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You do the first one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'll do the first one, yes. On the R&amp;D profile, we have now a level of 2.9 &#x2013; between &#x20AC;2.9 billion and &#x20AC;3 billion of R&amp;D, so closer to &#x20AC;2.9 billion. We will see a little bit of increase for 2011 and probably '12. Not much, but still a slightly increasing R&amp;D profile, probably at around &#x20AC;3 billion or a bit above.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is the increase mostly in Airbus or is it in other divisions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is in Airbus, it is in Cassidian and it is in Eurocopter predominantly. So all three divisions will add some R&amp;D.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the A350, the next major program milestone is the final assembly line start at the end of 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Between now and then is there any design tweaks -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a lot of less significant milestones. We have frozen the development aircraft. We have frozen all system interfaces. We start the manufacturing of sub-components. Systems are entering into qualification and then so on and so on. I could &#x2013; and on the engine side, we will have the first flight of the Trent engine on the A350 flying test bed in the summer of 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Celine. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Ben Fidler, Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, everybody. A couple of questions. Firstly, on the A380, encouraging to hear that you are making good progress there from an industrial perspective. I wonder if you could just somehow help me understand what the scale of improvement in gross margin per aircraft was in 2010, not talking clearly explicit numbers though if you wanted to share those &#x2013; with us please do? But just to understand something around I don't know &#x2013; how you can scale that improvement that you saw in '10, what you see for the level of losses in 2011 on the A380 at the P&amp;L level?</p>
          <p>The second question that I had was just some detail around Eurocopter, if you were able to scale how much the NH-90 charges were? How much the restructuring charges were? And whether you expect both those line items to effectively disappear in 2011 or should we prudently assume a level continues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I didn't get the last one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It was just on Eurocopter, what was the NH90 charge, the restructuring charge in '10? And do you foresee further charges coming at Eurocopter on those in '11?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, Louis, I'll probably make a few comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You could do both, if you want.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the A380, yes, we see clearly improvement, but as we have said before, and this has not changed, the level of EBIT, let me say, negative contribution will not change in 2011 compared to 2010. We are not giving you or not yet giving you any detailed figures obviously on gross margin improvement, but it really looks like the big improvement that we now foresee for '12, '13, and '14 are in reach. So I think we are really making good progress. We have delivered 18 airplanes. The program is recovering from the engine issue we had last year. So everything I think is on the right track. We have continuous support investments to make obviously, so we are not yet at a point where this will decrease for the foreseeable future. But all in all, I think the program really has stabilized.</p>
          <p>On the restructuring charges of Eurocopter...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps we could indicate that on the A380, in 2011, the improvement of the gross margin per aircraft is partly hidden by the fact that we have less provision to release. And there is some compensation between both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On NH90 and Eurocopter probably, so we have I would say on the program level NH90 and another positive one-off in another big program, we have roughly &#x20AC;90 million negative impact. And on top of it we have &#x20AC;30 million of restructuring charges.</p>
          <p>Now for restructuring, we should have catered for what we need under the SHAPE program. So we wouldn't at this point expect that 2011 would add further one-offs here. On NH90 we are progressing as well, but as you can see from the charges, and mostly it is a correction of the margins, a retroactive change, we are still I would say in a somewhat difficult development and ramp-up phase.</p>
          <p>But also on the NH90 you have seen we doubled the level of deliveries which also confirms that we are now really progressing with the countries in the deliveries, which is I think the best sign that the program is also on the right track. So at the time for '11 we have not included any at least additional charges at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. And just to clarify one thing if I could, Hans Peter, you're saying the &#x20AC;90 million is a net number on the NH90? So that's offset presumably with that Korean Utility Helicopter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Which was what, &#x20AC;24 million positive at the nine months</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And we can assume it's a similar number for the full year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ben. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Avi Hoddes, UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone, good morning. Again two questions from me please. The first is looking into 2011, can we expect any net benefit from cost savings, Power8 costs savings over unit cost inflation? That's my first question.</p>
          <p>Then my second question just relates to cash flow, which is clearly the most interesting point in your numbers. Do you expect any further pension top-up payments of the nature that you made in 2010 going forward? What kind of pension number should we assume going forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay. Let me start with the later one. We just, we discussed this pension topic I think some three or four years ago when we started funding the pension obligations in Germany through a pension trust. There is a plan of contributing about &#x20AC;300 million per year. We have just yesterday decided in the board that there is another &#x20AC;300 million this year and that we will review the future probably in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>So this is fully in line with our plans and as I said for the time being &#x20AC;300 million for 2011. On cost savings, on one side and inflation or you could also say some investment in growth on the other side. I would assume for the time being this is more or less a wash. So there is not a significant impact, positive impact coming from it. I wouldn't exclude it but for the time being I think a fair assumption is it's about balanced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Zafar Khan from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and good morning to everybody. I just wanted to focus on the cash flow, Avi asked part of the question, I just wanted to know how you've managed to take out &#x20AC;2.8 billion in working capital, whether that's sustainable and if there's further scope from that side going forward? If you could help me on that I'd be very grateful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we have indeed very good contributions coming from working capital, as you say. For the first time since years if you look into the balance sheet the level of inventories has decreased. So it seems all of our cash management action plans are now really paying off. On one side, really active management of working capital, managing down working capital, on the other side, obviously we still see contributions also coming from the customers in the funding of all these inventories and work in progress.</p>
          <p>So question whether it's sustainable or not, difficult question. I think for the time being we say we expect cash flow to be positive also in 2011. So there is a certain level of sustainability. If you assume that we will have some negative contributions compared to 2010, one of it being on CapEx, so we will see as according to our current plans we will see increase in CapEx by around I think &#x20AC;700 million this year. So we will reach a higher level of CapEx in 2011 and this is in line with guidance we have previously given. So that is certainly one item.</p>
          <p>The second item which will be higher in the future than we've seen it last year is the A400M. We said that the funding profile is not as we had expected previously. So back-loaded, meaning, there is a lack of funding for the next probably three years or some lack of funding, which leads us really to cash out on a higher level than we have seen it in the past. And this obviously then needs to be compensated by I would say cash management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We could add the A350 because we are building inventories for the A350 in the perspective of the opening of the final assembly line at the end of the year. It will not &#x2013; perhaps not be too sensitive in 2011 but certainly in '12 and '13.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just as a follow-on on the cash flow question, is net cash of &#x20AC;12 billion seems like a rather large number to me to be sitting on. How are you going to make your balance sheet a bit more optimized in terms of capital employed? Do you have any plans? So that was my follow-on. And the second question I wanted to ask please was just on the Eurocopter margins. If I look at your competitors, Eurocopter seems to be hugely under-performing everybody else. So what is the plan to get these margins to more peak levels in the medium-term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First on Eurocopter, Eurocopter is engaged in the SHAPE program, which is addressing exactly the issue you are raising, which is the profitability of Eurocopter. Eurocopter is &#x2013; the mix of Eurocopter is changing and we have the increasing part of NH90 and Tiger, which are not the most profitable programs. And they have to compensate that with a cost-saving program and they are engaged in it. Their objective is clearly to reach &#x2013; to go to the benchmark in profitability of their activities. And there is no question about that, it's their first priority. That's clear. And I think SHAPE program is well engaged, courageous and adapted to this target.</p>
          <p>The other question, I prefer to have this question on the fact that we have strong net cash than the other question if we had no net cash at all. And it's a problem of rich, that's not too bad. It means it's giving us capacity, room for maneuver for our strategy Vision 2020, either through organic growth and organic growth could lead us to invest in some new segments in security in particular and also through acquisitions. But as you know I don't want to be under pressure for acquisitions. It means that we are not indicating any time schedule and we are not giving volume targets for acquisitions because we want to do that in a serene environment, not to be under pressure. And we have time for that, but we know also that we have the money for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You've missed out one element, which I thought you might mention, which is cash return to your shareholders. Is that something important for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's not on the agenda for the time being.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the dividend, you have seen that we have made some effort in 2010, for the result of 2010. And we want to continue a sustainable effort on dividend in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Zafar. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Olivier Brochet, Exane. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning to all of you. So two questions. The first one on A400M, can you tell us if there are any changes or any differences in the final agreement that you've reached compared to what you had in March 2010? We read that you had to do some efforts with the U.K. and Turkey especially.</p>
          <p>And second, on the export levy facility, when should we expect that negotiation to close? And is this included in your comment on the cash flow? That's the first one. And the second is on Cassidian. Can you quantify the headwind that we have for this division for 2011, 2012 and how you see the trough margin at this business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps I could answer the first question and Hans Peter the second one. On the A400M, we are globally in the frame of the final agreement of March 2010, which has been renewed the 5th of November, 2010. It means there is no big change, some dates for payments and then so on. But it's a marginal.</p>
          <p>On the ELF, we are in the final discussion &#x2013; very positive and final discussion with U.K. and we are achieving also the negotiation with Turkey, which were the two countries with which we had still to negotiate. And I am very optimistic on the outcome of these two discussions in the next weeks.</p>
          <p>I have no concern &#x2013; no true concern about that. I could say that the other countries the negotiation is finished. French, German, Spanish, we could have some paper to discuss, but the negotiation is finished. It means that globally, on ELF, difficulties are globally behind us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I have a follow-up on that one? In the German agreement, there is a re-export of 13 aircraft, if my memory's right. How is it taken into account?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not taken into account. Germany is paying ELF for 53 airplanes and they are in a frame where they are ordering 53 airplanes. They wanted to export 13 of them. And that is a question which will come later, but for the time being they are paying on the basis of 53.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the ELF is within the guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The ELF also, on the ELF also.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And the ELF is in the guidance of free cash flow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes, absolutely. I think so, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah. The ELF is in the guidance for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cassidian and gross margin development in '11 and '12, so for the time being what we, I think said before, we expect a more difficult year in 2011, which means EBIT is going a bit down and margin particularly is going down because we have some elements which weigh on profit. One is certainly another increase in the R&amp;D level.</p>
          <p>Second one is that the growth in the division or the, let me say, the Cassidian systems, lead system integration business, is now progressively ramping up, I would say can you exchange these LSI revenues against core programs, which are slightly declining. A consequence of that is that the LSI business is at the beginning. We are cautious in the way we are taking margins.</p>
          <p>We are still, let me say, on the learning curve in this type of business. And it will take us some time. So all in all, Cassidian should be a bit lower in 2011 and recovers up to some extent, then in the years after again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of... ?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This will depend obviously on the performance in this export business, LSI business, which I think is the growth segment we see currently, and also the security business. So these are the segments which are becoming very important in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you say that it recovers in 2012, you talk about EBIT, not about margin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I talk about EBIT and margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Rupinder Vig, Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, everybody. I've got two quick questions. Perhaps one for Hans Peter, first of all. In terms of Eurocopter, what should we be thinking about for deliveries in 2011 and any guidance on 2012 as well?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, I know just perhaps pushing Zafar's question a bit further on the whole cash point, there's been some headlines, Louis, that we've seen today sort of saying that you've established contacts. It looks certainly to us from the press, if it's accurate, that you've made a bit more progress in terms of potential acquisitions. Is there anything you can add here? I agree you won't be giving us any volume targets, et cetera. But certainly it seems to me that that's the most definitive statement that you've made in some time about acquisitions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let us start with Eurocopter, if that's fine. First, we wouldn't expect big change in, I would say, the Eurocopter level of profitability. But on the delivery pattern we'll see some changes in 2011 again. So they're based on the book-to-bill we have achieved in 2010, which is below 1 on the commercial helicopters. We would expect as of today at least some decline on the commercial helicopter deliveries. On the other hand, we will increase the governmental programs again in 2011 and reach in 2011 and then 2012 pretty high level and kind of a plateau for this type of helicopters for the future. So that's probably on the delivery pattern. We don't give the precise number, but this is what's going to happen. At the same time, there is a stable support business obviously, which is generating healthy margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On acquisition, I am sorry not to be able to respond to your interest for our program of acquisition, but I don't want to give any precision on the topic because I don't want to make the company under pressure in one way or another. I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rupi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rupi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Jason Adams, Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. I've got two questions. The first probably for Louis. On single aisle production rates, are we still overbooked on 2013/2014 timeframe? And how do you think of potentially raising rates to 42 or 44 a month given the heightened geopolitical tensions and the oil price? That's the first one.</p>
          <p>And then the second one for Hans Peter, back on cash, and specifically net working capital, you talked about some headwinds to net working capital in 2011. But am I wrong to assume that inventories on the A380 program should come down and customer advances at Airbus should be better and so those could be some potential tailwinds to net working capital next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is probably a fair assumption, Jason. So certainly we have some negatives which are probably more than outweighing also some positive movements we might see. Inventories, for the time being, we are in ramping up the single aisle and the long-range program. We have the A380, which is still somewhat ramping up, as you know. So we will certainly not add inventories here, but I think on the single aisle and long range we might see, on an interim basis, some pick-up in inventories on the other side. But, bottom line, I think your logic is right for the customer advances if we assume we are in a continuously strong market this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the single aisle production rate, you know that we are increasing progressively the production rate to go to 40 aircraft per month in March 2012. You are asking the question to know if we are &#x2013; we could go to 42 or 44. We are looking at the market. It's still a very, very active market and we are overbooked for the next years. It could justify at least to think of a new increase of production rate. But we have to take into account the availability of the supply chain, which is the main constraint for that, and also the fact that when you increase it's a &#x2013; the increase of production rate at a certain level could trigger new investment and we have to be careful in that way because we have to be prepared to be flexible on that topic. It's for that we have not taken any decisions above 40 aircraft per month.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one additional comment probably, Jason, related to your oil price question. I think the pressure probably on the upside will increase because it will be attractive to exchange old equipment. And I think Louis said it in his speech that we particularly see the needs in the U.S. here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's clear that the oil price increase is a pressure on short-term for airlines, but on long term it's a pressure to renew the fleet, that's clear. And to go to efficient airplanes and the NEO is exactly the airplane which is adapted to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then a real quick follow-up on that. If we do see an increase in single aisle production, what would be the necessary lead time for the supply chain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's &#x2013; we &#x2013; I can't give you a firm indication on that, but it's a bit longer than in the past because we are at a point where the supply chain is under strong constraint, because the level of production of the A320 but also 737, and sometimes we have the same suppliers, is very high. I could say that it's &#x2013; we were used to say that we needed six months. Perhaps now it's a bit longer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Edward Stacey, Espirito Santo. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. This is Ed Stacey. Two things. Firstly, Cassidian, I just wanted to ask if there's any restructuring charges expected? Hello, can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, whether there's any expected charges in 2011, restructuring charges on Cassidian? And then the second question on the A350 and the stop-and-fix methodology. Does it mean that if you were to burn through all of your accounting contingencies and so have the need for some P&amp;L charges at a later stage in the program, would we see a series of small charges and presumably those are not included in your expectations for 2012 profitability increases, just whether I understand correctly on A350 where we are, that we're still within the accounting contingencies as of now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I probably have the first one. Restructuring Cassidian, yes, we will have some restructuring efforts, which will have to be taken most likely this year. It depends now how we progress on the transformation and restructuring program in Cassidian. They are currently, I would say, conceptually working on it. It's not finished yet. So whenever we are finished, we will give you a number. But you should expect a little bit, yes. 350, you want to say something?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>350, we don't, for the time being, we are not anticipating a cost overrun for the development at this stage. But we are not at the end of the program. Stop-and-fix means that we have milestones and we don't go through milestones if we are not sure that we have solved all issues related to this milestone. And it's a question of discipline. It's not &#x2013; it's a question that we are not progressing in the program if we have not the strong basis for doing that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to follow up on that, is that milestones, is it kind of small things that there'd be one milestone every couple of months, or are milestones just the really big things?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have different milestones. We have, as explained a few minutes ago, we have milestones on systems. We have milestones on engines. We have milestones on aerostructure. But the biggest milestone we have, we have seven milestones from &#x2013; and we are, for the time being through milestone six. And the next one will be the launch of the final assembly line at the end of the year.</p>
          <p>And we will launch the assembly line when we are sure that we have all elements to assemble the airplane, not before. We don't want to begin again what we had on the A380, where we were a bit flexible on milestones and we have been able to engage the new step, the new phase without being sure that we have achieved the proceeding.</p>
          <p>This time we are, step-by-step process, which is much more secure. It doesn't mean that the program is not changing; it's extremely changing technically and certification-wise. But we think that we are managing it in orderly manner and very transparent, knowing exactly where we are and progressing, as I said, step-by-step, milestone-by-milestone, being sure that we are not dreaming when we consider that we are making progress. We have to be sure that we have the evidence that we have achieved the preceding step to go further.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Doug Harned, Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Continuing on the A350, when you describe it as challenging and that you're using the stop-and-fix approach, have you gotten to a level where the challenge is greater than you were seeing three months ago. The language seems to suggest that. So are you seeing a more difficult situation now? And, if so, what aspects of the airplane are you seeing the most serious issues on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't see any change in our language on the last three months. I have to say, if you heard that, perhaps we &#x2013; I was not aware of that. I said exactly the same three months ago. And it was exactly the same when Fabrice Br&#xE9;gier, who's in charge of the A350 inside Airbus, has presented the program to the investor forum. I think we are on the same basis. It's a changing program; we know that.</p>
          <p>And we have only to look at the 787 to know that it's very changing to manufacture &#x2013; to design and to manufacture a composite airplane. Even if we have not adopted all the same scheme as Boeing, we know it's difficult. I could only say that. There is no change in our vision of the program on the last three months. No big events justifying any change in the last two or three months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, that's encouraging. And then on the A380, when you look at 2012 and see an acceleration, I guess, in the improving performance for that program, are there some specific things that you see happening from 2011 to '12 that gives you confidence that you're going to see that performance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I could say on the A380, perhaps I'm overoptimistic, but I think we are out of the woods. Now we have an initial process, which is sustainable. We are increasing slowly the production. We are a bit disturbed this year because we have to take into account delays for engines coming from Rolls because they have to retrofit some engines to adapt this engine to the modification they have decided after the incident of Qantas.</p>
          <p>It means that it's not making things easier for Airbus, but its life. I could say that I am fairly optimistic that the process is now under control and we will deliver airplanes and learn &#x2013; the evolution of the learning curve and the evolution of the gross margin per plane is very encouraging for us.</p>
          <p>And we think that we will see the result in our accounts in 2012 because, at that time, what I said, it means the improvement in the gross margin will more than compensate the fact that we're releasing less provision and that we are still to make some development in service, which also is slightly decreasing in the future. It means that we will have a positive impact in 2012 and for that I think I am fairly optimistic. I don't see a big event justifying that we change our mind on that topic in 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Louis, if I may, what is visible really is that the level, what you would call inefficiencies, is decreasing, i.e., the amount of people being in Toulouse from Hamburg and other sites in the group. I didn't follow up the latest numbers but they were...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're talking about below 500 now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So it's very much down. And also...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...2,000.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And also the level of change requests. So a lot of things are moving, I think, into the right direction visibly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good. Very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Doug. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Antoine Boivin, Cheuvreux. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, everyone. Antoine Boivin, Cheuvreux. Just to follow on a little bit on your last comment, Louis, on the A380. You said that you had less provision to release in '11. Could you give us an idea when you will be able to have a positive gross margin on loss-making contracts on the A380? Is it going to be '12 or then after?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Antoine, I'm not encouraged to give you any figure on the topic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Linked to this question, you were guiding for breakeven point by '14 or '15 on the A380. Have you changed your mind probably '14 than '15?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. We have not changed our mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. My second question is, what about the cancellation of A380 by ILFC? And what do you think of the Boeing 747-8 being selected in China? Does it mean that your order flow will not grow as much as anticipated? So what do you think of it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Chinese deal, I could say only that perhaps there is some link with the visit of Mr. Hu Jintao to Washington with Mr. Obama. I could see some results of this visit. On the first topic, on ILFC cancellation, you know that the management of ILFC has changed.</p>
          <p>Henri Courpron now is much more oriented to medium-sized airplane. It means mainly short-range and perhaps some A330 or this size of airplane. You know that for leasing companies the A380 is a more difficult airplane because it's a highly customerized airplane and it's not so easy to have this airplane going from one airline to another one, and it's costly.</p>
          <p>It doesn't mean that some leasing companies could not be interested by the A380, but the analysis of Henri Courpron is that it's not an airplane very well adapted for leasing companies which wants to have the capacity to resell or to change the airplane from one company to another, to move the airplane from one company to another. This is not affecting our production rate at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And another type of question on the A380, regarding cost inflation. I know that it's a difficult question. You mentioned this having hit the EBIT in '10. What would be the scale of the impact that you have in mind? Is it hundreds of millions of euros or is it dozens of millions of euros that have impacted the '10 figures?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On which program, again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, generally speaking for the group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our escalation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's the scale of &#x2013; no, cost inflation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cost inflation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's the scale of the impact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And how are we compensated?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the scale of the impact is in excess of 300, so it's a three-digit million number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Gary Murphy, Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. A couple of questions, please. The first, apologies to labor on the A350, but I just wanted to clarify the guidance which you said is based on A350 program, for example, being in line with commitments made to customers. Have those commitments to customers on A350 changed at all since the orders were originally placed? And are the customers in some level of dialogue with you about how the program is proceeding? That was the first.</p>
          <p>The second was on A320 NEO and the read-through really to the A320 legacy. I just wondered, with the level of success in order flow that the A320 NEO is achieving, how that leaves you or leave the backlog in terms of delivery for A320 legacy from 2014 onwards, whether we're going to have to see some level of price negotiation by customers or some kind of switch option to the new variant. I just wondered what your views were on that, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, on the A350 commitment to customers, we have a dialogue with customers and we could change some dates depending on what they want and what is acceptable for us, or what we could suggest to airlines and so on. But for the time being, there is no change justifying that we have to take any provision on that. It means that it's not triggering new cost for the time being, the discussion we have with customers on the A350. But we have, it's a normal life on the program to discuss with airlines and to adjust, adapt, taking into account our constraints and their needs.</p>
          <p>On the A320, I could say that the first, we continue to receive orders for the A320, we don't say legacy but we say A320 as it is. And we have no customers shifting from the A320 to the A320 NEO. It means that we keep our order book of the A320 as it is. And we are even increasing it when we receive new orders. And you have seen, for example, the MoU we have signed with IndiGo. There is some A320 and some A320 NEO.</p>
          <p>We have to manage a smooth transition and we know that some airlines continue to be interested with A320, which is giving them full commonality, including engines, and it's of interest for them. And other airlines are the same, could be also interested to get more efficient airplane, even if they paid a bit more, because there is a difference of price between both airplanes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot, Gary. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Harry Breach, Barclays Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good morning, Louis. Good morning, Hans Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. Can I ask my two questions, firstly to follow up on Celine's question? Since the nine month results, there was the industrial launch of the A320 NEO. You said in answer to Celine's question that we would expect R&amp;D to increase a little bit in 2011 and probably also for 2012. Should we be assuming that after 2012 that any reduction in R&amp;D on the A350 is going to be offset by increasing R&amp;D on the A320 NEO? Or is there the possibility that R&amp;D starts to come down in 2013 or 2014? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And the second question is really about pricing in new orders at Airbus overall. When we look back at the last quarter and indeed 2010, can you give us a little bit of a sense on how pricing has improved in general for the new orders that you booked last year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I take the first one, Louis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Please, please, please, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We &#x2013; as I said, Harry, we have now reached almost &#x20AC;3 billion. We might reach the &#x20AC;3 billion in 2011 or surpass it slightly. And then we are plateauing around that level. Probably, say, &#x20AC;3 billion, &#x20AC;3.2 billion for the next two years, '12-'13. And normally in '14, we should see first signs of a decrease of R&amp;D again, which is a little bit already linked to 350, not much, but at least there is already some small decline. But the 350 &#x2013; the NEO is not such a heavy development program for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is no comparison between the size of the A350 and the NEO regarding research and development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to say something, Louis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On pricing on new orders, the evolution is good. I could say that we have no deterioration of the pricing. We feel perhaps some pressure from our competitors, but for the time being we stick to a pricing policy, which is slightly improving and continuing to improve. And in particular, the pricing policy for the NEO is that we have no launching customers. We are straight and there's a new pricing for the airplane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Louis, can I just follow up? You speak about a little bit of pressure, perhaps, from the competitor. Is that in one part of the market or is it across the range?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't elaborate too much on that, because I don't want to interfere with my friends of Boeing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I could say that perhaps they have to &#x2013; they have difficult negotiations with customers on different topics and perhaps they have to take that into account when they are pricing their airplane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Louis. Thank you, Hans Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Harry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Harry. Next and last question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Yan Derocles, Oddo Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, everyone. Just a brief question on the WCR, in fact, a follow-up. I was wondering if you had recovered all the payment delays you were referring in H1 this year.</p>
          <p>And maybe a second one on suppliers, while you mentioned that you were discussing to launch an increase in production rate and you have maybe seen some issues. I was wondering if you have seen some red flag in your supplier base in terms of their ability to execute your production rate increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first one, second one probably is for you, Louis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have not understood the second one, if you could explain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the first one, you, I think, referred to the payment delays we've seen in the first half, which were system related from the French government. This is, I think, recovered until the end of the year or almost recovered, so there is nothing significant which remains.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you repeat your second question, because perhaps I have not &#x2013; I was not attentive enough?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's linked with the supply chain and your willingness to increase the production rate. You've mentioned previously that you have seen some &#x2013; maybe some red flags in your supplier base in terms of their ability to execute. I just would like to have more information on which kind of supplier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's &#x2013; we have &#x2013; I was not focusing on a specific supplier. But when you ask, for example, CFMI for engines, and they have to deliver the 737 increase of production, they have to deliver our engine for the A320, it means that they're under pressure. And for the time being, it's not a supplier with which we have any problem. But you could understand that when you have the two biggest sellers on the market, A320 and 737 increasing production rate with the same suppliers, it makes enormous pressure on the supply chain.</p>
          <p>And we have to be very careful not to go too far. We know that in the past some experiences have not been positive, and you could ask Boeing at the beginning &#x2013; at the end of the '90s and beginning of the new century that they had difficulties with the supply chain when they increased dramatically their production. We have to be careful. And I prefer to have too big overbooking than to commit to ourselves to deliveries we will not be &#x2013; we would not be able to make. And we have to be careful. I am not addressing any specific supplier, even if I could have some of them in mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Yan. This closes our conference call for this time. We are looking forward to talking with many of you in the next weeks. If you have any outstanding questions, please mail us a list of questions so we can revert to you as soon as possible. Thank you and good day to all of you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>