<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1231574" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-12</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7857</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Nathalie Errard, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Hans Peter Ring, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Sandy Morris</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">&lt;Q &gt;</participant>
      <participant id="5">Benjamin Fidler</participant>
      <participant id="6">Winfried Becker</participant>
      <participant id="7">Edward Stacey</participant>
      <participant id="8">Doug Harned</participant>
      <participant id="9">Antoine Boivin</participant>
      <participant id="10">Celine Fornaro</participant>
      <participant id="11">Zafar Khan</participant>
      <participant id="12">Olivier Brochet</participant>
      <participant id="13">Yan Derocles</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the EADS Conference Call on the Q1 2009 Earning Release. At this time, all participants have been placed on a listen-only mode. The floor will be open for questions following the presentation.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn the floor over to your hosts Hans Peter Ring and Nathalie Errard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. This is EADS Q1 2009 earnings conference call. Hans Peter Ring, our CFO, will be presenting our results and answering your questions. This call is planned to last about one hour and 15 minutes and should conclude at 12.15 PM Continental European Time. This includes Q&amp;A, which we will conduct after the initial presentation.</p>
          <p>It's also webcast on our homepage we've set of special banner. Playback of this call will also be accessible on the website, but there is no dedicated phone replay service. The supporting information package was e-mailed to you this early morning with slides which we will now walk through and financial statements.</p>
          <p>Throughout this call, we will be making forward-looking statements. The packages you received contain a Safe Harbor Statement, which applies to this call as well. We believe you should read it carefully. Now, to Hans Peter Ring.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Nathalie and welcome and good morning to everyone to our Q1 call. As you will recall from our recent Global Investor Forum we see 2009 as a complex year and Q1 certainly reflects this. While we have seen several contract cancellations at Airbus and Eurocopter, for example, these have been more than offset by new orders. The pace of deliveries thus far shows no deviations from our internal projections.</p>
          <p>So at this point, we have seen nothing so far which would lead us to alter our single-aisle and long-ranged production rates despite the trend in deferrals in more difficult times. Yet, as we have indicated on several occasions, the macroeconomic environment is still uncertain.</p>
          <p>Recent signs of increased liquidity in the capital markets while encouraging does not alter our sense of caution. We simply do not have as much forward visibility as we would like on demand, customer financing needs and dollar exchange conditions. This means that any forward expectations we offer you must remain limited in time and cautious in outlook.</p>
          <p>We must expect this to remain the case for the balance of 2009, especially towards the end of the year and into early 2010. Hence, our continued emphasis on profit enhancements through cost containments and performance optimization. Cash conversation making every effort to de-risk programs such as the A400M and maintain flexibility to adapt if required.</p>
          <p>So I would ask you to keep these criteria in mind as we discuss our Q1 performance. I will turn now to the main Q1 highlights, but before that please read carefully the Safe Harbor Statement to which Nathalie has already referred on page two.</p>
          <p>On page four, this is where we find the group highlights. So as anticipated, a lower level of commercial activity has become evident in our order intake for the year. However, our order book was more than &#x20AC;400 billion, provides us with a solid bedrock for deliveries for the years to come, underpinning our current production levels.</p>
          <p>We are actively monitoring our backlog, matching our commercial deliveries to our customer needs, with the use of a rigorous internal process. Consequently, we are adjusting our production rates as required for our programs.</p>
          <p>Our level of over-booking, even if declining in the short-term to avoid difficulties with customers, continues to provide a level of protection against deferrals and cancellations. We maintain a solid backlog in our defense and space activities.</p>
          <p>We continue to drive the business towards better integration and efficiency. MTA, so Military Transport Aircraft, is being integrated into Airbus Military, into Airbus as Airbus Military. This integration will bring with it the possibility to optimize program management and resource allocation, while improving internal governance as we move towards our goal of one integrated group.</p>
          <p>I will turn to the financial performance of the Group in more detail shortly. However, I would like to highlight in the first instance that the Q1, 2008 benefited from positive phasing effects. This quarter lower phasing of commercial deliveries, price deterioration and increasing support activity costs identified in our full-year release weigh on the EBIT before one-offs.</p>
          <p>The level of customer financing provided in the quarter remains insignificant. Reported net income after exceptional dollar impact is &#x20AC;170 million. Our free cash flow consumption for the quarter is inline with expectation and our solid net cash position at the end of March will provide a level of protection for our future business needs. And keep in mind, through the release the seasonality of our defense and institutional businesses, whose top bottom-line and cash performance tend to be back loaded.</p>
          <p>Now a few words on the A400M on page five. Firstly, a short update on the development phase of the aircraft. The first aircraft is progressing towards first flight. It is now undergoing systems testing, while the second aircraft is complete and about to begin systems testing. The flying test bed is performing satisfactorily with eight flights now performed and more than 21 hours of total flight time.</p>
          <p>Static test has been achieved on the landing gear and fatigue test is in progress. We are currently in negotiations with our customer and as recently announced by OCCAR the seven launched nations have agreed to a three-month moratorium period until the end of June 2009 including a suspension of PDPs.</p>
          <p>We see this period as an opportunity for all partners of the program to agree on a certain number of outstanding issues, an opportunity to realign and rebase the contract with conditions acceptable by all parties. During this time, a various sets of assumptions will be exchanged between parties.</p>
          <p>These assumptions and resulting potential news flow should not be taken is an indication of the final outcome of negotiations. In the meantime, we will continue to work with our suppliers and partners to confirm a robust timeline including a date for the first flights.</p>
          <p>The absence of a major triggering event in the first or in the quarter to enhance visibility on either the industrial or commercial situation of the program means that the early stage accounting treatment allowed under IFRS 11 is maintained.</p>
          <p>The negative net EBIT impact of &#x20AC;120 million for the quarter does not reflect a complete new estimate of cost at completion, which continues to constitute the single biggest financial exposure to the Group.</p>
          <p>This chart represents an estimation so the 120 of the over costs deemed to be irrecoverable as revenues as well as the foreign exchange adjustment on future costs.</p>
          <p>Now onto the Group financials in more detail, and this starts on page seven. The first quarter results demonstrate a good level or a record level order book of &#x20AC;413 billion, a growth of 3% versus the year-end that provides a level of stability through a period commercial uncertainty.</p>
          <p>The backlog is now benefiting from a strengthening dollar rate due to the revaluation impact at the closing rate of 133 versus the euro at the end of March versus 139 at the end of December.</p>
          <p>The revenues generated by defense activities are inline with the first quarter 2008, and our defense order book remains stable. Revenues and EBIT before one-off were lower versus the first quarter 2008, which were boosted by positive phasing effects.</p>
          <p>Q1, 2008 revenues included the Power-on milestone for the A400M program. Order intake for the period was lower across all divisions except for Astrium, which booked the second batch, the PB batch of 35 Ariane 5 launchers worth almost &#x20AC;5 billion. The largest impact was the reduction at Airbus, which reported much stronger commercial activity in the first quarter 2008.</p>
          <p>Let's now go to slide eight, which gives you a reconciliation of the different adjustments between EBIT and EBIT before one-off, highlighting the material, non-operational and non-recurring items, particularly in the Airbus segment. We have explained the negative net impact to the EBIT of the continuation of the early stage accounting.</p>
          <p>On this slide, we present the growth figure, excluding the negative impact from foreign exchange of &#x20AC;90 million that is contained here in the line revaluation of all LMCs at the end of March spot rate.</p>
          <p>You are aware that, as the dollar and the British pound fluctuate so to our loss making contracts that are revalued at the closing spot rate. Since the year-end, both the dollar and the pound have appreciated in value, resulting in a positive effect from the US dollar, and that is partially offset by a negative effect from increasing pound denominated costs.</p>
          <p>This leads to a positive revaluation of all loss making contracts amounting to around &#x20AC;50 million. The amount is less significant than in previous quarters because as the dollar appreciates in value, there are less aircraft to consider as loss making. I remind you that even at a more favorable dollar rate, there are still some contracts that remain loss making.</p>
          <p>In previous periods, the dollar mismatch impact coming from the reversal of the pre-delivery payments that were cashed in at a more favorable rate than the closing spot rate, and the balance sheet revaluation had a positive impact on our EBIT result.</p>
          <p>This was the case in the Q1 2008. However, we now see the opposite effect in this quarter with a negative one-off impact of almost &#x20AC;200 million on the EBIT result. The EBIT margin calculated using EBIT before one-off is 4.8% at Group level, adjusting for revenues for the recoverable part of the costs on the A400M program.</p>
          <p>So now up to slide nine, R&amp;D increased slightly year-on-year to &#x20AC;562 million for the quarter, driven by an increased at Eurocopter. However, R&amp;D is expected to ramp-up through the year up to around &#x20AC;3 billion. The interest result in line with last year, mainly reflects a lower interest rate, but a higher net cash balance. The interest rate is expected to deteriorate during the year.</p>
          <p>Meanwhile the other financial result increased by &#x20AC;373 million. The increase in the other financial result is mainly due to the revaluation of dollar and pound cash assets, partially offset by a negative valuation of the premium paid for the options.</p>
          <p>The reduction in earnings led to a lower tax expense than last year. The tax rate is at 31% in line with our expectations.</p>
          <p>Now let's move on to slide ten to the hedging slide. Due to the strengthening value of the US dollar the mark-to-market value of our hedge book has decreased by around &#x20AC;1.5 billion compared to December '08. It now amounts to &#x20AC;1.3 million pre tax, negatively impacting equity net of tax.</p>
          <p>As we already stated in March, the volatility of the dollar, the change in mark-to-market and the risk pricing of financial institutions make hedging more difficult or impossible with a number of banks.</p>
          <p>However, despite that we have continued our hedging activity. While $4 billion of hedges matured, 3.5 billion were added in the quarter at an average rate of 132 per euro if we exclude the options. Our hedge book therefore decreased slightly from $68.1 billion at the end of December to $67.6 billion at the end of March.</p>
          <p>We also began to restructure some of the 2011 plain-vanilla euro call options, we added during last summer. We have sold back $1.3 billion of options and entered into plain forward contract with the same maturities, but with much more favorable rates.</p>
          <p>Going forward, we will continue with the combination of restructuring and implementing new forwards to cover our eligible exposure, according to our strict internal procedures.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 11 and the free cash flow. Free cash flow is in line with expectations for the quarter and reflects the lower level of commercial deliveries at Airbus. The significant changes versus last year come from the working capital and the gross cash flow from operations.</p>
          <p>Gross cash flow from operations for the quarter was &#x20AC;658 million. The change versus last year, which benefited from a strong favorable seasonality effect, represents the lower EBIT before one-off for the quarter and less favorable phasing of hedge volume.</p>
          <p>In Q1, the deterioration in working capital reflects an increase in the level of inventories at Airbus due to the mismatch between the current production rates and the under proportional phasing of deliveries this quarter versus the full-year forecast. The level of customer advances for the Group is in line with last year and our current production rates.</p>
          <p>Customer financing now reported as part of working capital, generated a cash flow -- cash inflow of &#x20AC;15 million. Sell downs were realized in the quarter despite the current financial environment. I remind you that the cash outflow for customer financing in '09 should be around &#x20AC;1 billion.</p>
          <p>Investing activities consumed only &#x20AC;225 million this quarter, reduced by the cash inflow form the disposal of our aerostructures activities at Filton. CapEx is expected to increase during the year to around &#x20AC;2.4 billion as investment went up on the A350 XWB.</p>
          <p>The free cash outflow for the quarter was &#x20AC;585 million. However, the level of outflow in the quarter is not representative of the full year 2009 picture. We will dig into each division's performance now and that starts on page 13.</p>
          <p>The former Military Transport Aircraft division and the business unit EFW has been integrated into the Airbus segment with effect January 1st. This newly created Airbus segment also contains the completed aerostructures reorganization. Aerolia and Premium Aerotech which includes the Augsburg activity transferred from our defense division. 2008 figures have been restated to reflect these changes expect -- except for Augsburg.</p>
          <p>Airbus Military is currently reported within the Airbus segment under its former perimeter MTA, but as an interim measure only. From an accounting standpoint, the integration is taking some time. As we progress, this presentation will be updated accordingly.</p>
          <p>On to the performance in the quarter now, a lower level of commercial activity is reflected in the net order intake. However, our focus in the current context is the proactive management of our order book, which stands at more than &#x20AC;365 billion. We booked eight net orders on commercial programs in the quarter and four medium and light military aircraft, two for Mexico and one for Colombia and Thailand. 116 commercial aircrafts and 3 military aircrafts were delivered to 46 customers.</p>
          <p>We will look at the quarter in more detail for the segment on slide 14. Airbus commercial first quarter revenues declined versus Q1, 2008, that was boosted by positive phasing effects from foreign exchange. In addition, this quarter the lower volumes, price deterioration less A400M revenues and weaker customer mix have weight on the revenues. No trend can be derived from the under-proportional phasing effect for long range and A380 deliveries. However, our freighter conversion programs and OCCAR business have seen a significant deterioration in business activity.</p>
          <p>The reduction in EBIT is also driven by the negative impact from foreign exchange effects, higher support activity costs and a charge booked against the A400M program reflecting the costs booked in the quarter deemed to be recoverable -- irrecoverable.</p>
          <p>R&amp;D costs are in line with 2008 levels. The anticipated increase for 2009 versus '08 level is expected to fall later in the year as we ramp up activity on A350. Work began in January on the final assembly line.</p>
          <p>Airbus continues to forge its long-term strategic partnership with China 320 family wings for aircrafts assembled in the China file will now be completed and tested in Tianjin while HAIG, HAI, and Airbus has become risk-sharing partners for the production of major components on the A350.</p>
          <p>Airbus Military revenues and EBIT benefited from an increase in tanker activity that was more than offset by the difference between the absence of the Power8 milestone for the A400M booked in the first quarter '08. And the revenues booked as the recoverable part of the development costs incurred on the A400M program this quarter.</p>
          <p>Our tanker program continues to progress in Airbus Military, the Preliminary Design Reviews for both the UAE and MRTT and the FSTA were passed in the quarter and the first FSTA wing-set is complete.</p>
          <p>Up to Eurocopter now on slide 15, the trend of bookings over the quarter has shown a significant slowdown particularly on light helicopters. Cancellations increased, however nearly all terminations have been successfully reallocated. 66 net bookings were registered versus 299 last year. New orders includes 22 NH90 booked for the French DGA and five LUH for the US Army. Both NH90 and LUH orders were additions within the original frame contract.</p>
          <p>A new military -- Ministry of Defense contract was signed in the quarter, two EC135 for Japan. Despite the low level of bookings, the order backlog remains strong. Eurocopter delivered 93 helicopters in the quarter including two Tiger and eight LUH, demonstrating increasing productivity at the Columbus production line.</p>
          <p>Revenues were up 3.6%, due to an increase in customer services that offset lower serial deliveries. EBIT is stable with the 2008 level. An improved customer mix and an increase in higher margin customer support activities were offset by higher innovation led R&amp;D predominately on the EC175 and the Super Puma. Eurocopter continues its worldwide deployment of its global services strategy with the creation of a new Customer Services Center in Hong Kong.</p>
          <p>Additionally, a Training Services Center has been implemented in Germany to develop, produce and operate NH90 full mission flight simulators. A 15-year contract has been signed with the German Armed Forces in that respect. Eurocopter is reinforcing its presence in Japan and has become the major shareholder of Euroheli its former distributor.</p>
          <p>And now we move to page 16 to Astrium, where we recorded a strong increase in revenues in Q1 '09, with a main contribution coming from navigation and commercial telecommunication satellites and ballistic missiles productions.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, services delivered growth in particular earth observation services. Growth in services for the consolidation of Spot Image increasing profitability in navigation satellites and the ramp up in productivity on the M51 program, all provided positive contributions to EBIT. This growth was mainly or was partially offset by an unfavorable translation effect from the declining British pound to the euro foreign exchange rate and a small increase in R&amp;D.</p>
          <p>Astrium continued to register commercial success with order intake of &#x20AC;5.6 billion. The new batch of 35 Ariane Launchers for use starting in the second half of 2010, confirms the commitment of European space industry to the long-term availability and competitiveness to Ariane 5.</p>
          <p>Arabsat has placed an order to built and deliver in orbit to new satellites, Arabsat 5C and Arabsat 6B. Ariane 5 marked the 29th successful launch in a row in February with the orbit of two communications satellites HOT BIRD 10 and NSS-9. Astrium received acceptance from the Thai space agency for its THEOS system recognizing the expert capabilities in the division.</p>
          <p>So, if we then move on to page 17, to the defense division. I would like to remind you that the aerostructures activity is now consolidated in the airbus segment. DS reported revenues were stable excluding the effects of the aerostructures activity carve-out.</p>
          <p>Growth from Eurofighter and the Plant CML acquisition in the US was offset by the favorable phasing of expert revenues at MBDA recorded in the first quarter 2008.</p>
          <p>EBIT was consequently weighted down by negative volume in the absence of the favorable phasing effects. On the commercial side, DS reports continued success in communication solutions with the award of the DCIS contract for NATO, the expansion of digital radio networks in Brazil and the supply of Tetra solutions for China, South Africa and Bulgaria. It also won a contract to modernize French military identification systems.</p>
          <p>On Tranche two, Eurofighter capability enhancement weapon trials were completed successfully in Spain. The improved operational capability will be introduced in the Eurofighter fleet by 2011. DS is reporting continuing market success in radar technology delivering high-end technologies for MEADS program as well as for air traffic security.</p>
          <p>To establish a real industrial footprint in selected key regions DS forged a long-term partnership in India in the field of defense electronics. DS also created a JV in Abu Dhabi to join -- to jointly develop and market high tech solutions in the field of DS applications.</p>
          <p>Up to slide 18 the other businesses. I would like to remind you here that EFW is now reported as part of Airbus division and 2008 figures have been adjusted to reflect this change. In addition, 70% of Socata was sold to Daher in January; the remaining 30% is consolidated at equity within other businesses.</p>
          <p>The significant reduction in the order book since year-end is explained by the change in consolidation of Socata whose backlog is now removed from the other businesses division. In the quarter a new ordered with ATR was booked at Sogerma as well as new support contracts at ATR.</p>
          <p>Revenues were lower year-on-year due to the consolidation perimeter changes that offset the successful ramp-up in LUH activity at EADS North America. EBIT for the quarter was zero due to some negative foreign exchange effects at ATR and the investment in -- test and services systems in the US.</p>
          <p>ATR has experienced market slowdown in its commercial activity. No orders has been booked in '09 as customers are delaying their CapEx position. Some of the smaller or more fragile ATR customers are facing difficulties to secure financing. ATR had 152 aircraft in its backlog at the end of March.</p>
          <p>Sogerma recorded some commercials success with the launch of a new seat concept at the Aircraft Interior Hamburg Exhibition this quarter in partnership with Lufthansa Technik. However, the business will begin to see some pressure on EBIT starting in the second quarter due to the fall in commercial activity at ATR.</p>
          <p>Now, I will comment on our guidance on page 20. Q1 2009, confirms the trends described at the beginning of the year. Bottom up analysis of the backlog still shows over booking for the next years, nevertheless this backlog and over booking are challenged by the deterioration of the macro economic and traffic indicators. Therefore, we are continuously monitoring the market, customers and suppliers and we continued to apply a rolling plan concept. Besides the commercial backlog, our solid backlog in defense and institutional activities provides a certain level of protection and stability.</p>
          <p>The EADS now expects Airbus to capture up to 300 new gross orders in 2009 even if it is becoming more challenging in the current market environment. Based on a stable delivery assumption in the dollar rate of 1.39, EADS revenues should be roughly in line with the '08 level. Under these assumptions, EBIT before one-off should be down in 2009, but significantly positive supported by robust underlying performance. Compared to '08, EBIT will be negatively impacted by increased research and development expenses, by significant hedging deterioration, price deterioration, increasing customer financing and support activity costs. Partly offset by further Power8 cost savings.</p>
          <p>Concerning one-off impacts, revised industrial plans to complete the A400M program could lead to a substantial charge in the H1 2009 weighing on EBIT if and when EADS has an accurate view of the costs in H1, it will revert to the cost at completion methodology. Any potential positive outcome coming from the negotiation will need to be substantiated before been taken into account.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow for 2009 will reflect some negative impact from lower customer advances at Airbus and some inventory build-up in the last quarter, reflecting the reduction in single-aisle production. The recently announced cut in A380 deliveries will equally challenge free cash flow through inventory build-up which is expected to be medicated by production optimization in supply chain management. We expect to support our customers in financing their deliveries on a discretionary basis in 2009.</p>
          <p>The cash consumption of provisions taken over the recent years will also way on the cash flow. At this stage, with a current level of visibility, EADS is not expecting to consume more than around &#x20AC;1.5 billion of free cash flow after customer financing in 2009, excluding any potential negative impact for A400M program.</p>
          <p>And now we are through the presentation and are ready to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We're now start our Q&amp;A time. Please introduce yourselves and your company when asking a question. Please limit yourself to two questions at a time. Also as usual, please remember to speak clearly and slowly to help all participants, particularly ourselves understand what you're asking. So Hika, please go ahead and explain the procedures for the participants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Sandy Morris from RBS [The Royal Bank of Scotland], UK. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, gosh it's like wining the lottery coming first in the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Sandy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. One, really very simple question, could you just explain the dynamics to me of why inventories build up when we lower the production rate on A380 and A320? Particularly A320 given that we have had time to prepare the supply chain. Could you just explain that so that I understand what might happen in the event you had to take A320 production down again? Please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We have indeed the two issues. The more significant one is certainly the A380 and the adaptation of the delivery rate this year from 18 to 14. And also some decline in 2010. And this obviously because of the longer, much longer lead-time is impacting inventories. Currently for this year, we would expect this to be around 400 million which obviously as I said before try to mitigate through other measures. So we did not change the overall free cash flow number. On A320, you are right. Obviously we try to adapt ourselves as quickly and as fast as possible. But the decline in the production rate only if I remember well, happens just right before the end of the year. And so far this is just a temporary impact I would guess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So if we had to step it down again in FY10, on a sort of three or six-month view because demand fell away, would we then have to expect another quite significant inventory build in temporarily in FY10?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, for some interim during period, yes. Because I mean we are not only talking about the suppliers. There is obviously our own value added and raw material stocks et cetera. And all of that has longer lead-time then simply I would say telling suppliers that the rate is now one, two less than it has been before. So there is some lead-time to adapt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Sandy. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Rabinder Arvag from Morgan Stanley, UK. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Two question if I may, Hans Peter. The first one just on kind of R&amp;D for the full year. You kind of mentioned three billion is your kind of expectation for the full year. What do you thinking in terms of next year and 2011 as we kind of build towards A350 and in terms of profile of R&amp;D by segment I mean how will the split between Eurocopter and Airbus look for the next couple of years. And then just a second question in terms of the backlog. You talked at the very end when you mentioned guidance about the over bookings that are in place. Could you give some indication for the next couple of years of how much is in place there, and how much you have seen fall away. And just kind of building on that point, in terms of customer financing, how much of the customers are actually financed at moment in terms of the second half of this year. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the question. First part is on R&amp;D, and as I said, it's going to be around the three billion, which from today's point of view, would be the peak, also looking now into the next year. So we would see some small probably declines in the years to come. All of these obviously is also subject to the further development of the crisis and to further measures we might also take on R&amp;D in case that becomes necessary, but that is, let me say, that current longer-term outlook. And then I think there was the question to get the numbers between Airbus and Eurocopter, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. You are right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Going into the next years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on Eurocopter, the current level of R&amp;D, if I say current it is 2008 was 134, so 130 million. If we look into the next years, we would expect due to the programs, which are in our pipeline to go up to levels above 200, starting 2010 and 2011. So, and 2009 we will be somewhere in between. So that's the current outlook for Eurocopter, and longer-term, it's even going beyond that. And this is, I would say, also meant to support the strong development we have seen in Eurocopter and some consequences in our product line, but also on R&amp;T, research and technology. On the other side, we are at a level of 2.7 in 2008. I would think, sorry, no that's not, that was EADS 2.2, and would think that this probably might still go up in '09-'010 to levels between probably 2.3 and a bit more to come down later on again to, I would say more digestible levels around two or a little bit in excess of that. So not a lot of change up and down. That answers the R&amp;D question I guess?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>It does, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then on the over booking, and I mean, the level of the over booking as you know we were never very specific about giving numbers on that because it's a moving target. All what we can see, I mean, the over booking relates to single aisle as you know. And this is not changing a lot over the different I would say meetings we have to discuss that issue. Obviously as we approach now more on more 2010, we will have to be more and more cautious, because of the lead times. So we have to be sure that we can deliver finally. In so far there is some tendency or there will be some tendency over the next months that this is decreasing for 2010. But it is still at the level we have seen for sometime now, and also the subsequent years have not changed a lot. So on single aisle, in so far, I think it's still protected through that policy to a certain extent. On long range, as we have said, there is no over booking and if we look into 2010, and probably also a subsequent years what we can see here is especially a weak development on the freighter side of the A330, which might challenge. I would say the deliveries 2010 and probably beyond, but this is too early to say today, as of today the production rate is one, the 8.5 aircraft per month we communicated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Ben Fidler from Deutsche Bank, UK. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Thanks for question time. Two questions, firstly I wonder if you could share with us the scale of deferrals that you saw in the first quarter, on its conference call and Boeing, I know talked about 60 or so deferrals that they suffered from in Q1. I wonder if you able to give us a feel for your number? And the second question that I had was just to understand a little bit more about the A380 excess hedges in the context of the recent production rate cut on 380 and as suppose two parts to that question, firstly was there any excess hedging that emerged in the first quarter '09, just bearing mind that you delivered zero A380s. And secondly as we look to the revised 14 aircraft this year and 20 also for next year, will there be some excess A380 hedge benefit for the full year '09 and potentially even 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So to start probably with the last one, we don't expect excess hedging this year and we didn't see excess hedging in the first quarter. For 2010, it's probably a bit early Ben, because the real question is going to be the ultimate delivery rate. I would say as of now we don't see a big issue coming up there, but let me say the exposure and the level of hedging we have are pretty close for next year already. And this gives you an indication of the fact that if further adaptations would be necessary beyond what you would potentially expect, there might be an issue in 2010. And the subsequent years are not a problem at all. So we still have lots of uncovered exposure. On -- what was the other question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the deferrals that you saw in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the deferrals, scale of the deferrals, as you know we didn't provide you numbers on that, but if I say overbooking has not changed significantly. You can see that there was certainly some activity in and out, but recently at least not such a lot I would say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just to clarify again coming back on A380 point, should I therefore conclude that if you have delivered 18 aircraft this year, you would have actually been under hedged on the 380?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, we are -- in terms of our hedging policy, we are close to hedging the 100% exposure we expect, taking a small margin for potential deviations which we might see. So, going forward we would not hedge today and this is not so much related to this year, but obviously to the next years. We would obviously take some margin based on the firm backlog, because the firm backlog already covers 100% for the next year, next years of the deliveries. In so far you shouldn't expect that if there is some, I would say, decline in deliveries like it is on A380 now that it automatically transfers into excess hedges.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, Hans Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Ben. The next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Avi Hadis from UBS, UK. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Hans Peter. I've got two questions, one of which kind of related to what Rabinder was asking. On the financing, the visibility of it, I think last time you spoke, I mean you mentioned up until the summer or kind of through this summer you had very good visibility on the cash being behind the aircraft on order, but then after that visibility kind of went away quite quickly. How far up through 2009 that you have that strong confidence on the finance back in the aircraft? And my second question which is probably going to be difficult for you to answer. But if you take into account direct help that you've given to suppliers plus the impact that the change in legislation in France and Germany on paying supplies kind of more quickly. How much in cash terms do you think that cost to you in the first quarter? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Okay. First question was on financing visibility going forward. First, we think what the level of say customer financing we have protected now for this year, we should be okay and fine, to cover the delivery volumes we have anticipated. What we can see in the first quarter is that ECA guarantees are working well. So we have rather significant increase on the level of ECA backing. And I think if I am not wrong, I have to look it up probably around one-third or more than a third of the deliveries are covered already by ECA and we would expect this to increase. So we don't actually see a lot of uncovered companies and the airlines. We have some about which I will not talk here. But certainly we will see some, as I said before, we feel pretty comfortable with 1 billion customer financing we have foreseen for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just to interrupt on the ECA when you say more than 33% is covered by ECA and is that ECA backs plus there is cash behind as well setup or is it just ECA is back probably still waiting for the cash to turn out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The cash currently turns out not to be such a difficult issue. A number of banks have returned to provide liquidity based on the guarantees, because of much more attractive spreads for them. So we are currently not so concerned as we have been three, four months ago on that issue. And it works currently pretty well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On your other question, which was the supplier related issue with the payment terms where we have some limitations now coming through in France due to legislation. Indeed this is something which is hurting us on the cash flow side. I would not be able to give you the number for the first quarter. But on a yearly basis, that is easily something which is a few hundred millions for us, now depending obviously on the final, I would say, discussion with the suppliers. So there is an impact, which we need to recover hopefully through other measures. But we will see some impact from that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And sorry again, just to -- just a follow-up, when we say a few 100 million, does that include more direct kind of cash help that you've given to some of suppliers like we've seen, I think for example Klassiker and I think GKN as well maybe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that doesn't include that. But I mean, there are -- so far there are not extensive requests in that respect. So we think we can deal with that within the cash flow forecast we were providing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Hans Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Avi. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Winfried Becker from Oppenheim Research, Germany.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning. I'm having two questions, please. The first is concerning the Q1 EBIT. Could you give us a number on indication by how much EBIT was held by savings coming from the Power8 or the other cost savings programs? And my second question concerning A380. The changes you have announced recently, could you explain to us please, how this is impacted the start of the Wave 2 production for the aircraft? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So impact on Wave 2 , actually I mean the reduced -- the reduction in volumes obviously helps a bit to digest now the next steps of the ramp-up without any question. Where there is no change is in the -- I would say introduction of new airlines into the delivery program, which means the heads of version. This is the most difficult part of the Wave 2 or it was the same for Wave 1, because this means a lot of adaptations to be done by engineering on the customization of the aircraft. And there is no change because the airlines has not changed, so they might have postponed for a few months. But in principle we have the same challenge on the Wave 2. I would say implementation of the tools we have -- we use now et cetera, et cetera. So there is -- I would say volume wise certainly some relaxation, but in the engineering teams it does not change because the heads of version quantity has not changed. On Q1, Power8, we didn't provided an exact number and we will probably follow-up on that one in the next quarters, because it is simply very, very difficult to give you the scientific numbers. A lot of things are flowing through inventories and it's difficult to reconcile. So there is something on Power8, if you build the bridge and in so far our Power8 is progressing as we expect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question Please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Edward Stacey from HSBC UK.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, yes and two questions, and I missed a couple of questions earlier back. If I'm asking something that some already asked then I apologize and please skip over it. But the two questions are, firstly, on the A320 I saw comments on the Newswires from John Leahy yesterday saying that you could go back up to 40 a month at the end of next year. So do you have any thoughts if you are expecting a lot more orders to start flowing again next year or is he &#x2013; or is that just the aircraft that we deferred from this year and that you would need to ramp again next to make up the difference, so A320 re-ramping up, that's the first question. The second one is Eurofighter and the UK government talking about trying to back out. Can you explain how the impact of any customer cancellation on Eurofighter Tranche 3, how the impact gets shared between the different partners on the program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first one, first. Yes, John has talked about that yesterday. I think obviously for the time being at least, the order activity is limited, as I have explained in my presentation already. We would at this point we have not planned for ramp up, in 2010, in late 2010 and we would have to decided on something like this only at the end of this year or beginning of next year. So for the time being it is more a question of managing the backlog. And as I said, I mean there is still some overbooking into 2010. So in a -- in a I would say optimistic scenario where you would say this would materialize in terms of deliveries. There is a theoretic positive threat, I would say that we have ramp up again. But this is not the plan for the time being. Hence before that happens, I think passenger traffic and GDP developments have to stabilize and probably have a tendency to improve again. On Eurofighter UK, I don't want to comment too much. This is very a political subject now as you have seen from the press. So lot of people are putting pressure on the UK to stick to the commitment on the Eurofighter, and there is a contract which foresees significant penalties for nations stepping out and this is then a issue which has to be dealt with between the nations and then in the second step or so obviously with industry. But I would not give you now any indication of what that could mean for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Doug Harned from Sanford Bernstein, US.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. The, two questions. The first question is, when you talked about pricing deterioration, my understanding was that pricing should actually be a little bit better for single-aisle in 2009, although down a little bit for long range. And I am interested if you are seeing further price deterioration then you were expecting last year as volumes have come down and perhaps some slots have been switched. And then second question, I am trying to understand what led to the decision to take single-aisle production rates down to 34 in October. That is -- we're only -- that's only six months out and you had said that there was not much deferral activity in the quarter. So I am just trying to understand how you have seen that production rate change and if you sort of looking at things on single aisle is, making these decisions with the six month lean time in the future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but I mean we are six months or five months before October and in so far, we took the decision to go further down, which basically led us to a situation where the number of protection we have for next years and the years to follow is not, let me say, deteriorating. So we are protecting ourselves at the same level as we had before. That is, I think the logic of the single aisle. On pricing, nothing has changed to what we said in March 1st, so it means indeed as you said the long range is weaker this year, single aisle is not a big difference. So its insignificant compared to last year, which means pricing level have stabilized and probably there is some small pick-up but not significant this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you go forward on that, given that you are expecting about 300 orders this year and this is a weaker environment. Are you seeing more pricing pressure when you look at 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't have the kind of big campaigns currently which might put that kind of pressure on us. So far, I would say, we don't see that yet and we hope we can deal with it this time in the crisis better than we did it last time. I mean that is at least the current target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Doug. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Antoine Boivin from Cheuvreux, France. Please state your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning everybody. Antoine Boivin from Cheuvreux. I have a three question. First one is on SG&amp;A, you had an increase of SG&amp;A this quarter, meaning that the percentage of sales is now 6.5% compared to 4.9%. So could you explain this increase in a context of lower sales? That's my first question. My second one is, the pricing effects not on orders, but on deliveries, you mentioned negative price impact to explain the lower level of sales in Q1. Could you be a bit more specific on that? Is that in terms of millions of euros and when do you expect the prices in deliveries to pick up again? Is it '010 or later on? My third question is, on A400M, you mentioned that charge to be taken in a H1 '09, could you give us an idea of what could be the worst case scenario and if we assume a three years delay in deliveries, what could be the amount to be charged in Q2 '09? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So. Now I have to choose with what I start. I think I should start with the pricing on deliveries. That was what we just discuss on the question of Doug. The number I think was the remaining topic for the quarter. It is around 100 million impact for the quarter. On the SG&amp;A, we have some perimeter impacts. So we have included some companies we had at equity before which is Spot Image in space, we have PlantCML in defense and on top of that we have some phasing impacts on the costs side. So the increase you see here is and on some support costs the increase you see you should not interpret as an indication that there will be deterioration for the full year. So we still have a lot of pressure on our SG&amp;A costs. On the S in the G&amp;A we have some complaint related costs, which are a bit increased also compared to last year. So that I think are the main topics, yes, it was mainly coming from Eurocopter the campaigns and some other divisions. Then the last question, I think you had, was on A400M.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And where we are in the program obviously we stick to early stage accounting, which means there is no number for the time being. What we say in our release it's I think quite clear. It is potentially substantial issue for us so the A400M is probably the program, which is our biggest concern in terms of the exposure or the substantial exposure going forward especially in an event where we do not get a positive out turn in the discussions with our governments in whatever scenario and I think everybody has to be aware of that. So I think we were clear that this is going to be something, which heavily might weigh on us. We had obviously the Board meeting yesterday and we got very clear guidelines on how proceed in the next steps of the negotiations with a customers and this specifically on the commercial side which needs to be addressed. So that is the current status I mean the negotiations are ongoing and have started. You might expect or see some news flow around that in the following probably days or weeks, which in some cases certainly might be technically biased I would say in terms of negotiations in so far don't be overly and too much excited on that, but as I said before the important thing is we have clear guideline under which we will continue to discuss with the customers and obviously we do not want to be more specific about it here on the conference call, but in the next weeks I would say even weeks will be now rather decisive on how we continue and what it might mean for the H1 closing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And just come back on the pricing I'm not sure I've got the point on '010 pricing, have you say that pricing should be better in '010 deliveries?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't make the point on '010. Honestly it was just related to '09 and so far I forgot one thing '010 normally should be a bit better than we have seen it in '09 provided we can deliver on the backlog as it is foreseen currently. There is a slight question mark coming from escalation I think the issue was also addressed from the Boeing side. This topic is not going to impact us this year and we will have to wait how that develops into next year, in so far, there is a slight or small question mark, but in terms of the underlying contracts the pricing is improving.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Celine Fornaro from Bank of America, US.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Two questions if I may. The first one is if you could just give an idea on the pre-delivery payments that you've been securing over the quarter and is the situation getting better or worse from the airline willingness to pay you? And the second one would be on A350 program and the negotiation or the launch aid that you could be receiving in 2009 by the government. So, if you could give us an update on that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. On the last one, Celine, we are in discussion with the government to structure something, which gives us the support. We think is reasonable and allowable. So we are in rather advanced negotiations on that. And we would definitely expect that this is going to be closed this year. It still might take some time, but in an optimistic scenario probably even before mid of this year. So, we are in pretty advanced discussions on that. On pre-delivery payments we have the same level, I would say, of contribution in our free cash flow statement as we have seen or even a better one as we have seen in the first quarter last year. So, it's improving by 1 billion in 2008 and 1.1 billion in 2009, which means basically that airlines stick to their delivery commitment, which I think is good news. It also indicates that there are not significant over-dues. So, all of this indicates that the production program as we expected now going forward is also confirmed up to this point from the pre-delivery payment side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, just as a follow on that. I mean would you now, financing issue seems to have been significantly less than we probably were expecting on the last quarter. Would you now be still concerned about maybe 2010 either issue is shifting towards early 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You mean now the PDP issue or the financing issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I guess it's related</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what I -- what I nearly was afraid off. Okay. So I mean 2010, Celine, clearly I would say is probably a little bit too early to say I mean it all depends on the delivery levels more or less and as you see from PDP inflows in the first quarter this year it was at this level despite the fact that there was rather new order intake. So, it is depending indeed on the question whether we can maintain the level of deliveries or whether we will have to reduce in a reduction scenario obviously then we would expect or should expect that these changes. On customer financing, I mean, this is definitely too early to now give indications for 2010, from what we can see as I said in my introduction financial market shown -- show signs of stabilization in how far this is continuing over the next weeks and months. We will have to follow I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Zafar Khan from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale, UK.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Hello and good morning to everybody. Just wanted to ask question on the cash outflow guidance you've given for full year of 1.5 billion. Just want to know how sensitive that would be to the gross order intake, let us assume that you're only to book say 200 gross orders as oppose to 300 this year. Would that change that guidance significantly or is it immaterial?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's more material, now it would not change a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just a follow-up from Celine's question on the A350 funding, can you just please bring us up-to-date on where we are with the required funding that is in place and what still needs to be found?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't -- the required funding is as we had it in previous programs around one-third of the development costs. And if -- I mean you know that the development costs are in excess on 10 billion. So it would mean that we would look at something between three and 3.5 currently.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Zafar. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Olivier Brochet from NATIXIS, France.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. I have two questions. The first one is on the dollar on the balance sheet. Just to understand the impact that it had on the net cash and on the customer advances. The second question is on the pluses and minuses on EBIT, just to see if there was any impact, any negative or positive impact from A350 penalties, for instance, or A380? And what is the size of the additional support costs that you mentioned? And then other follow-on to Celine's questions on the A350 support that you are trying to build with the government, is that included in the free cash flow guidance that you gave for the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What was the last one again, I didn't...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the A350, the support that you are trying to build with the government, is that included in the free cash flow guidance that you gave for the year, the 1.5 billion..?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. For this year 'no,' because simply this funding source would ramp up over the next years only so nothing which would be significant to be expected in 2009. On A380, 50 penalties, I mean 350 has not changed. So there is no change. 380, the customers has differed now themselves which means we are a little bit more relaxed on the penalty side on A380 now, and might probably see some -- even probably some small reduction on that side, but no significant issues on that side. I think you also quoted support costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, support costs, I mean you would expect that with the growing fleet that is increasing still to reach probably a recurring level only in 2010, or probably even beyond now depending on the further steps of the ramp up. So that is still an issue for us. But I would not be able to now give you precise numbers on that. And then what was the first question again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question is on the dollar impact on the balance sheet and net cash, especially and also customer advances?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, if we look at the balance sheet and also sometimes EBIT obviously, we would have the temporary volume, we have seen last year, that is in Q1 2008 some 250 million. We have PDP, obviously impacts on Q1 2008 and Q1 2009 due to the changes of the dollar rates. The amounts -- I just have to look at -- I don't think I've given the amounts yet. But the dollar rates are 130 -- what is it here 130 for Q1 and 150 for Q1 2008, which is the average dollar rates in the different quarters. And that's probably what I could say on these issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was trying to understand how the rise in the dollar between the closing of '08 and the closing of Q1 impacted net cash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It impacted a lot. I mean -- it impacted through the earning obviously. So through the top line of the cash flow statement, through the temporary excess volume I mentioned before. These are probably the two major impacts and then you have number of balance sheet positions being impacted where I would not be able to give you now precise number on each and every position. But the biggest ones you have were the two first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question comes from Yan Derocles from Oddo France (sic) [Oddo Securities] .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. Take three questions. The first one could you come back on the 380, you stressed that Airbus will take big actions against the negative effect on free cash. So could you elaborate a little bit on this point? The second point on customer financing. Could you speak the &#x20AC;15 million customer financing line on the cash flow between sell down and an additional contract? And finally, a just brief one on Iberia the company just announced a daily on one 340 from October 2009 to September 2010. And I was just wondering if this aircraft was already on, your final assembly line. And if we could see a wide tail this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the last one I'm not aware of that to be honest, so I cannot tell you whether this is now already on the final assembly line if this is correct, so that is something I simply do not know by heart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first one on A380 and the question of the free cash flow impact, what I said before is that we try and we think we can mitigate that through other action, which are mainly coming from supply chain management, and which are obviously coming from further optimization on production that were the two issues I mentioned. And that has to be now in the next months to be elaborated, because as you know the whole deterioration only happened very recently on what was the other question -- the net or gross of customer financing, so cash out on customer financing was 89 cash in was 104.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's -- net it is a rather insignificant number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you everybody. This closes our Q1 call. Please feel free to send us list of questions through email and we wish you a very good day. Good-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Have a nice day. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>