<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1493265" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7857</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Contact-Institutional Investors">Philippe Balducchi</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Thomas Enders</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Harald Wilhelm</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co. LLC">Doug Stuart Harned</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Rupi S. Vig</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies International Ltd.">Sandy J. Morris</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Celine Fornaro</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (UK)">Zafar A. Khan</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Ben P. Fidler</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Cheuvreux SA">Antoine Boivin-Champeaux</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Carter Copeland</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the EADS First Half Year 2012 Earnings Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Tom Enders, Harald Wilhelm and Philippe Balducchi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, this is EADS Half Year 2012 Earnings Conference Call. Tom Enders, our CEO and Harald Wilhelm, our CFO will be presenting our results and answering your questions.</p>
          <p>This call is planned to last about 1 hour and 15 minutes. This includes Q&amp;A which will we conduct after the initial presentation. This call is also webcast. You can access it via our homepage where we have set a special banner.</p>
          <p>Playback of this call will be accessible on the website but there is no dedicated phone replay service. The supporting information package was emailed to you earlier this morning. It includes the slides, which we will now walk through, and financial statements.</p>
          <p>For this call we will be making forward-looking statements. The packages you received contain a Safe Harbor statement which applies to this call as well. You should read it carefully.</p>
          <p>Now to Tom Enders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Philippe. Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Harald and I are very pleased that you joined us for our first investor call in our new roles. Some of you may already have had exposure to me in the old, old days of Co-CEO-ship of this company.</p>
          <p>But before we go to page one, just on a sad note, I'd just like to make a few remarks on the very tragic accident we had on Wednesday where a Super Puma helicopter crashed in the south of France in the hills near Marignane and six of our airmen and crew were killed. We have had yesterday, for all the entire group, a moment of silence to pay tribute to the airmen, to their families.</p>
          <p>And I would like to say that, what is perhaps more important, the crisis management of Eurocopter has been very good internally and externally. And at this point, for anybody who raises the question, we cannot say anything about the reasons of the accident. We will not indulge in any speculations. We assist, as usual, when we have aircraft accidents, the authorities in analyzing, finding out what exactly happened. And I'd like to express our heartfelt condolences to the families of the victims, their friends and the colleagues at Eurocopter who mourn this great loss.</p>
          <p>Well, having said that, let's turn towards the purpose of the call, first half results 2012. What I'd like to say in summary is that our focus, the focus of a new, partially old management team, going forward, will clearly be on program execution. Secondly, on server internationalization of globalization, reference here for instance our decision on the Alabama FAL. And thirdly, on integration, where it makes sense for the group and its business.</p>
          <p>Program execution across all our divisions is, of course, paramount to achieving profitable growth, so key programs in Airbus and beyond will have our utmost management attention.</p>
          <p>I have to say that, at this stage, I feel quite confident that we have all the ingredients, I guess you've read and analyzed already our H1 statement, and we have all the ingredients for what I would call steady momentum, a momentum which should make us a very valuable company in our business sector. And I hope you will agree, particularly after this conference call here.</p>
          <p>Let me point out a few highlights of the first half of 2012. I think you can see that if you look at the performance of the first half year, we are on course to match our, what I would call, improvement trend, the trend towards more and more operational improvement.</p>
          <p>Commercial performance is on track. The first half of the year, Eurocopter, Cassidian, Airbus Military all achieved a book-to-bill ratio of around 1. Airbus has positive momentum still in its commercial activity. The order inflow Farnborough, obviously doesn't match the one we had at Le Bourget last year. But that was, as everybody knows, who knows the industry, very exceptional but it was as expected, it was good and it confirms here also the book-to-bill target of above 1, by the end of the year. That has been the target, just to remind you, that we set out in early January for the order intake.</p>
          <p>We have no problem with backlog. I think you know that. More than 4,400 aircraft currently at Airbus, it's at record level. And certainly provides us with a lot of stability, visibility in an economic environment that is certainly volatile.</p>
          <p>Looking beyond 2012, as already mentioned, the launch of A320 FAL in Alabama, certainly something that should provide us with a platform also for long-term global expansion in the U.S. and beyond.</p>
          <p>Our strong underlying performance in H1 confirms the improvement trend, I mentioned that. We have increased confidence in our outlook, which has led us to refine or to improve our guidance, thanks to solid growth, when you compare that particularly with first half of 2011. And that basically goes for all others, in Commercial sector, Eurocopter, Astrium, all driving the core underlying performance growth.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we are of course, also taking advantage of the more favorable dollar-euro exchange rate by accelerating our hedging activity. Improved rates will help us to strengthen our profitability in the years ahead. Certainly a bit of an irony, but we benefit from the sovereign debt crisis in Europe and the rather low euro.</p>
          <p>What else to say? Yes, we mentioned that. You've seen that in the statement, entry into service of the A350 moves into the second half of 2014. We've taken a charge of &#x20AC;124 million, which we booked in Q2, but that accounts for three months of the second half of 2014. We're doing that clearly to keep the bar high, to keep the pressure up, particularly on our supply chain but also on ourselves.</p>
          <p>And I think we can discuss that a little later, certainly, the 350 remains a challenging program. We should not forget, we are still in the pioneering stage of building carbon fiber aircraft. We knew that when we started that project. And it shows, I think it has shown with our competitor and it certainly shows also with the 350.</p>
          <p>Now, Harald, I think I should hand over to you, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Tom, and good morning, everybody. I want to express my personal welcome to all of you. While I have already had the pleasure of meeting some of you, I'm really looking forward to meeting all of you in the near future. As CFO, I can promise you that our relationship will be one based on transparency and frankness just as it has been in the past with Hans Peter and I cannot be casual about that, as he's sitting next to us to witness this statement.</p>
          <p>As Tom stated, we are very much committed to continuing the path of value creation set in the recent years. From a financial standpoint, this is expressed in our focus on steady revenue and EBIT growth, as well as shareholder value. The same time, we are also committed to prudent cash management, preserving our flexibility for investment, either in organic growth or in selected acquisitions, while at the same time meeting our shareholder expectations.</p>
          <p>Additionally, and to emphasize Tom's point, we'll continue to reinforce risk and cost controls and maintain close monitoring of the risk profiles of each program. Furthermore, the new set-up with my dual role in EADS and Airbus will facilitate transparency of key programs.</p>
          <p>Now let's move on to the financial picture of the first half of 2012 and let's go to page six. In H1, revenues have grown across all of the divisions, which led to an increase of 14% at EADS level compared to H1 2011. The newly-acquired companies in 2011 contributed by around &#x20AC;800 million to this growth. This top line growth, combined with profitability improvements in the divisions, resulted nearly in a doubling of the EBIT before one-off, to &#x20AC;1.4 billion compared to H1 2011.</p>
          <p>Despite the ongoing macroeconomic uncertainties, the order intake was encouraging across all divisions. Note that the H1 2011 order intake included the exceptional orders booked at Le Bourget, particular for the neo. Our order book of around &#x20AC;552 billion provides a solid platform for future growth. The Airbus commercial backlog has been increased by a positive reevaluation impact of around &#x20AC;12 billion due to the appreciation of the U.S. dollar closing spot rates since the end of 2011.</p>
          <p>Let's move to page seven. We can look at the underlying performance of the businesses. The EBIT before one-off margin is at 5.5% at the group level, which confirms our increasing profitability trend. It benefited from improved performance in Airbus Commercial, Eurocopter and Astrium. Operational improvement at Airbus Commercial includes favorable volume and better pricing. Eurocopter performance reflects volume and mix effects from the commercial and support activity. While at Astrium, the growth is driven by productivity improvements and the integration of Vizada.</p>
          <p>This quarter was A350 XWB entry into service, moving into H2 2014. Airbus Commercial booked a charge of &#x20AC;124 million. The wing rib A380 technical fix is under development. The total charges recorded so far in 2012 amount to &#x20AC;181 million, of which &#x20AC;23 million were booked in the second quarter. We still target 30 A380 deliveries for 2012, which means the total charge for the A380 wing rib is still expected to reach &#x20AC;260 million for the full year.</p>
          <p>In the first half, the dollar mismatch in the balance sheet reevaluation had a positive impact on our EBIT result of around &#x20AC;20 million. We have provided you with a complete EBIT before one-off view by division in the appendix on slide 22.</p>
          <p>Up to slide eight. Despite the charges for the A350 and the A380, EBIT remains significantly above the 2011 level. The R&amp;D level is in line with H1 2011. The interest results deteriorated compared to the 2011 level, mainly due to lower interest income related to the lower average cash balance and interest rate compared to last year.</p>
          <p>The other financial result includes an improved impact from the foreign exchange fluctuation compared to H1 2011. This line also includes the unwinding of discounted provisions. Tax rate for the year is expected to be slightly below 30%. Net income stands at &#x20AC;594 million, significantly above H1 2011 level.  Net income before one-off reflects a strong underlying performance, it more than doubled compared to H1 2011, resulting in an EPS before one-off of &#x20AC;1.</p>
          <p>Let's go on to the hedging portfolio, page number nine. The slide shows the evolution of the hedge book between December 2011 and the end of June 2012. You can see how we have used the current U.S. dollar rate environment to improve the average rate in the book to support our future profitability increase.</p>
          <p>During the first half of 2012, we accelerated our hedging activity and implemented $19 billion of new hedges at an average rate of $1.31. In the same period, $10 billion of forward contracts matured at an average hedge rate of $1.38. The hedge book increased from $75 billion at the end of 2011 to $84 billion at the end of June, as you can see from these bars in the graph.</p>
          <p>Also, it is becoming more difficult to find counter-parties with better ratings than ours. Our ability to hedge remains. At the end of June, the mark-to-market of our hedge portfolio was negative at around minus &#x20AC;3.8 billion after tax, compared to a negative &#x20AC;2.4 billion at the end of December. This movement is driven by the evolution of the closing spot rate from $1.29 in December to $1.26 now.</p>
          <p>On to the cash flow page 10. Free cash flow for the first half year is negative at around minus &#x20AC;1.8 billion. The improvement of the operational performance is weighted down by deterioration of the working capital. This is mainly due to a strong increase of inventory, as we continue to ramp up production, while deliveries and milestone achievements are back-loaded in the year, in particular on A380.</p>
          <p>However, the main deterioration at Airbus was related to the first quarter of 2012. In the first half of 2012, low customer financing support of &#x20AC;80 million had been provided. The level of CapEx increased compared to last year, mainly at Airbus and Eurocopter. Net cash also reflects a cash contribution to pension assets of &#x20AC;320 million, as well as a dividend paid out of &#x20AC;370 million.</p>
          <p>Now, Tom will walk you through the Airbus performance in more detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Harald. I think that's slide 12. Okay. Well, Airbus on the commercial side, booked in the first half year now 230 net aircraft orders, and I think it's worthwhile mentioning that H1 2011, said before, included the bookings made at Le Bourget last year where we had an industry record of more than 700 aircraft, driven very much by the neo.</p>
          <p>The activity at Farnborough this year was as expected, included important orders for the 330, for the 320, particularly. I think it's, again, worthwhile noting that we had in Farnborough more orders for the current engine option, for the current aircraft, than for the neo. That proves that the current aircraft options still sells pretty well.</p>
          <p>Also worthwhile mentioning is the order from Cathay Pacific for the 350-1000. Remember we relaunched an improved 350-1000 last year, and one of the most renowned airlines in the world, Cathay Pacific, has now ordered a significant batch of 1000s, certainly an important endorsement.</p>
          <p>We have announced also in Farnborough that we are planning to enhance the 330, the 330-100 and the 330-300, offering longer range, increased payloads, and that should be very attractive on certain routes for our customers.</p>
          <p>The Commercial backlog, I lied to you in my introductory statement, it's not over 4,400, it's 4,388 aircraft, I hope to the date, representing nominally around seven years of full production, well, let's say we have a good order backlog.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we're making progress on the A350, absolutely. Is it as much as we had planned and hoped for in previous announcements? No, that is not the case. We have some hiccups in the productions. I think Didier mentioned that also in Farnborough, that particularly on the wings, with the drilling process on the wings, we have accumulated some delay. This is why we're moving the entry into service into the second half of 2014. We've taken a charge, I mentioned that, I don't think I need to repeat that. Why do we have it a second time in my book, okay? It was already in the introductory statement.</p>
          <p>Military segment, Airbus also has military business, Airbus booked 21 aircraft orders so far, including 15 light transport aircraft, the CN-295 for Oman, for Poland, Egypt, Kazakhstan. We have delivered 7 or 8 this year, the first half. And the backlog that Airbus Military has, that obviously includes the A400M, stands at a respectable 231 units.</p>
          <p>A400M program continues flight testing, has accumulated more than 3,500 flight hours already by the end of the June. But ladies and gentlemen, I think you're aware that due to pertinent engine issues, the IOC, the initial operational capability will be delayed, but we are preparing for the first aircraft acceptance by the French Air Force, still within the contractual date. The contractual due date is the first quarter of next year.</p>
          <p>Closer look at the segment numbers, we compare with the H1 2011, the Airbus Commercial revenues have certainly benefited from favorable volume and pricing effects. 278 deliveries were booked with revenue recognition, compared to 279 physical deliveries, as one aircraft was placed on operating lease.</p>
          <p>The Commercial EBIT, we're separating this, both our EBITs, Commercial and Military, we're separating this to give you more transparency on the Commercial versus Military sector. The Commercial EBIT before one-off is &#x20AC;830 million, has improved significantly over H1 2011. Well, what's the reason for that? It benefited from better operational performance. That does include favorable volume and pricing, pricing net of escalation. There was a small, temporary headwind from the deterioration of U.S. dollar rate at our maturing hedges in the first half, and R&amp;D was stable with pretty much the same level of H1 2011.</p>
          <p>The Airbus Commercial reported EBIT also increased significantly compared to last year. That includes the charge we booked for the 350 delay, as well as the update on the 380 wing rib feet provision. What a wonderful word, wing rib feet provision.</p>
          <p>At Airbus Military, revenues declined, mainly due to lower revenue recognition on the A400M, as well as lower tanker revenues. I think you're aware that we have pretty significant swings in revenues to milestones that bring revenue recognition or not at Airbus Military. It's intrinsic to the business model, so to say.</p>
          <p>There's a very slight dip in Airbus Military EBIT, EBIT before one-off, but I think it's not worth mentioning here.</p>
          <p>I think that's it for Airbus, Harald.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tom. Let's go page 14 to Eurocopter. The H1 2012 net order intake has improved compared to H1 last year, with 195 new set orders this year and the level of cancellations is clearly back to the pre-crisis level. The order value increased significantly compared to last year, mainly due to a favorable mix on EC175 and Super Puma and the first time consolidation of Vector Aerospace.</p>
          <p>The second quarter, the division secured important orders from Kazakhstan, including eight EC145, and a letter of intent to acquire 20 EC725 multi-role helicopters. A contract was signed with Indonesian Aerospace for the supply and customization of six EC725. Revenues and EBIT increased significantly compared to a year ago, mainly to a favorable mix, with more Super Puma deliveries and higher repair and overhaul support activities. It includes also a contribution from the Vector Aerospace business consolidation. The H1 2011 EBIT included a net charge of &#x20AC;60 million.</p>
          <p>Eurocopter underlined its innovation strategy with a roll-out of the enhanced EC130T2, which has been a successful market introduction. Additionally, Eurocopter strengthened its services portfolio with the acquisition of an 80% stake in Sabadell Helicopter Service Centre in Spain. The division is continuing challenging discussions with the German government on the future of its key defense programs, the outcome of which is still open. The Portuguese government has recently announced its intention to enter into discussions with NAHEMA regarding termination of a contract for 10 NH90.</p>
          <p>On the Astrium side, page 15, Astrium order intake reached &#x20AC;2.2 billion in the first half, which constitutes an increase of 29% compared to previous years. In addition, the Vizada integration, the second quarter orders also included an order for Phase 1 of the Solar Orbiter Mission. That will perform close-up observations of the sun. Our U.S. contract for governmental communications services across the Skynet 5 fleet of satellites were also booked in Q2, confirming globalization and export activities already initiated in 2011.</p>
          <p>Revenues increased by 13% compared to last year, mainly due to the inclusion of the acquired Vizada Group into the Astrium perimeter. EBIT increased by 26% despite some front-loaded R&amp;D. The EBIT increase is due to a positive Vizada contribution and margin improvements thanks to efficiency and productivity gains resulting from the Agile transformation program.</p>
          <p>In July, Ariane 5 recorded its 49th consecutive successful launch, marking a world record in terms of reliability for commercial launches. Astrium successfully passed ESA in orbit acceptance test for its first and second Galileo satellites, confirming full qualification and performance and successfully delivered the Yahsat 1B satellite into orbit. The ESA Ministerial Council, due to take place in late 2012 is expected to provide clear perspectives on the future direction of the European space programs.</p>
          <p>On Cassidian, slide 16, Cassidian generated a significant order intake, which at &#x20AC;2.8 billion for the half year, was above last year's level, despite ongoing macroeconomic volatility and flat defense budgets. Order activity in the quarter was mainly driven by Eurofighter, missiles export and a contract with the Alliance Ground Surveillance program, AGS. The latter contract awarded by NATO prime contractor, Northrop Grumman, is for the mobile ground segments for surveillance from high altitude unmanned aerial vehicles.</p>
          <p>H1 revenue and EBIT are in line with the previous year's level, as expected. The decrease in self-funded R&amp;D was offset by continuing investments in globalization and transformation. Following the successful completion of the complex METEOR development guided firing programme, MBDA is now on track to complete qualification and make first production deliveries by year end.</p>
          <p>The division also extended its portfolio with the finalization of strategic alliances. The agreement with Rheinmetall on UAV has been completed. The new entity will continue to support the German armed forces in Afghanistan by providing unmanned airborne reconnaissance services and the division also signed a purchase agreement for 75% of the shares in Carl Zeiss optronics business, which enables Cassidian to develop a future-oriented Sensor House.</p>
          <p>The 2011 combined revenues of both acquired businesses is around &#x20AC;230 million, and encompasses a workforce of approximately 900 people. Cassidian continues to explore export opportunities for Eurofighter in the Middle East and Asia.</p>
          <p>Lastly on page 17, the other businesses, revenues increased compared to last year, mainly due to volume increase at EADS North America and ATR. H2 2012 EBIT improved slightly due to the profitability improvement in the Cabin Interior business of Sogerma. And please remember that the H1 2011 included a &#x20AC;10 million gain from the divestiture of defense security and systems solutions in EADS North America.</p>
          <p>In the second quarter, ATR celebrated the delivery of its 1,000th aircraft, an ATR 72-600 to Spanish airline, Air Nostrum. Furthermore, the ATR 42-600 obtained certification from the European Aviation Safety Agency. The 50-seater turboprop aircraft will make ATR the only manufacturer in this market.</p>
          <p>At EADS North America, the U.S. Army's fleet of 219 UH-72A Lakota helicopters completed the 100,000 flight hour milestone in May, underscoring the program's continued success.</p>
          <p>Now we turn to the guidance on page 19, and back to you, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Harald.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we expect the world economy and air traffic to grow in line with not our forecast, but the prevailing independent forecast and we assume for that guidance no major disruption due to the current sovereign debt crisis, the wars in the Middle East or that kind of event.</p>
          <p>As we mentioned before, our results of the first half year certainly confirm growth and operational improvement and these quite positive dynamics lead us to improve our guidance for this year. So Airbus should deliver, in 2012, around 580 commercial aircraft, including 30 A380 deliveries.</p>
          <p>Cross orders, as I mentioned, should be above the number of deliveries, some in the range of 60 to 65. Don't count John Leahy out too early. The year-end race, what I say, 600 to 650?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Times 10.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Times 10. Okay. Okay. The year-end race in terms of order intake is always exciting. Based on an assumption of a euro-dollar of $1.35, the EADS 2012 revenues should continue to grow by around 10%. And based on the performance in the first half year, especially at Airbus, Eurocopter, Astrium, we expect the 2012 group EBIT before one-off to be around &#x20AC;2.7 billion.</p>
          <p>As a result and with an expected tax rate for the full year of slightly below 30%, the EPS before one-off should now be around &#x20AC;1.90, &#x20AC;1.95. As a comparison, in 2011 we had EPS of &#x20AC;1.39.</p>
          <p>We go forward, the reported EBIT and earnings per share performance of EADS will, of course, be dependent upon the group's ability to execute its many programs, particularly A400M, 380, 350. We mentioned all of them, in line with the commitments we've made to customers. And based on the target of 30 A380 deliveries this year, EADS should continue to generate a positive free cash flow, after customer financing and before possible acquisitions. Okay, this is, I think, all for the guidance.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes our presentation, and Harald and Philippe and I are now looking forward to taking your questions. Thank you very much for your patience.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So we'll now start our Q&amp;A time. Please introduce yourself and your company when asking a question. Please limit yourself to two questions at a time. And also as usual, please remember to speak clearly and slowly in order to help all participants, particularly ourselves, understand your questions. So Mikayla, please go ahead and explain the procedures for the participants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, at this time we will begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And the first question is from Doug Harned of Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions, the first one is could you talk about the A380 and where you see orders and deliveries going? What the trajectory is likely to be now and how that's being influenced by the wing rib crack issues?</p>
          <p>And then as a second question, you talked a little bit about the A350 issues, just so we understand, when you do a three-month delay, how confident can you be in that three-month delay? What are the issues that are leading to that? And what is your level of confidence that you're going to be able to make it in that timeframe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Doug. On the 380, I do expect that we have an exceptional dip in deliveries next year due to the disruptions that we've obviously had with the wing crack issues. But that should be exceptional. I expect that we are not reaching 30 deliveries next year but that in the next years then, 2014, 2015, we'll be well in the 30s in terms of 380 deliveries.</p>
          <p>On the 350, the three-month delay, I said this is primarily, not exclusively, everybody knows we're at that stage, ramp-up stage of production preparation, initial production of the initial aircraft, you have plenty of challenges but primarily due to the wing drilling problems that I mentioned. This is what we are accounting for, but as cautious people we've said H1 &#x2013; sorry, H2 2014 for entry into service.</p>
          <p>Can I be absolutely confident that we have no further delays? Absolutely not. I think that was a rhetorical question on your side. You cannot be absolutely confident at that stage of a program. What I can tell you is that the program management is doing what it can to take on these challenges, solve them one after the other. But you know it is just in the nature of that kind of business and particularly at the end of development and the transition to first production aircraft, series production, that you're also hit always by a lot of unexpected problems.</p>
          <p>So I mentioned we made good progress on the aircraft but yes, we have some challenges, not entirely unexpected.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I could just follow-up on the A380. I'm interested in also how customers are viewing this situation right now with respect to orders. I know John Leahy made the comment at Farnborough that you probably wouldn't be getting the 30 orders you had thought about this year. But how is this issue affecting the timing of orders and what customers are doing there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I can't tell you in detail. I mean that is typically a John Leahy question, he's is not with us here today. But you would imagine that the publicity around &#x2013; and we've been very transparent about it and had to be, about the wing issues that we had, will convince some customers to delay orders. We have campaigns going with quite a few airlines around the world, but I have every understanding for customers who say, wait a minute. I want to see how these guys solve it.</p>
          <p>I think it becomes increasingly clear that we have a solution. We are testing the solutions already. For the forward solution, the full metal wing will go into production. First set of wings, I think, later this year, probably around November, for deliveries early 2014. And we are extensively testing also the so-called final fix for our hybrid rib wings. So the confidence in our company is very high. But we have a solution for the aircraft. Testing is going on and that will certainly improve very soon, I think, also the confidence of potential customers to buy this great aircraft.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next person, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Rupi Vig of Morgan Stanley. May we have your question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just two questions, please. One perhaps for you, Tom, first around cash. You mentioned right at the end of the presentation in terms of M&amp;A. Can you just give us an idea, given the cash position you have, what's your view to increasing dividends further, potential M&amp;A? I mean, how do you see use of cash going forward? And if we do see M&amp;A, any kind of scale you can give us in terms of size or potential focus areas?</p>
          <p>And then a question perhaps for Harald. If we look into the second half of the year for Airbus, can you just give us some idea of how pricing will develop, volume, et cetera, et cetera, so we can get an idea of how the margins might progress as we go through? Given you might get more of FX but obviously, you'll have more 380 deliveries, which will be margin-dilutive you would expect. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well Rupi, this is Tom. Regarding the cash use, I think it's too early to speculate about that. Obviously, we are targeting acquisitions also in the future, but I really can't say. There's quite some stuff in the pipeline but I really can't say at this point what is going to be used for acquisitions and for EPS improvement. Again, we'll cross that bridge if we come to it and we'll communicate on it, but rest assured that we remain interested in acquisitions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to add to that in terms of dividend, I think dividend is to be decided by the Board when we have the actuals for the 2012, but I think the trend has been set in terms of dividend distribution for 2012 and I think this is a good starting point for the policy. We'll look into when it comes to the actuals 2012. To &#x2013; Rupi, to your second quarter on Airbus H2, it's not completely mechanical, I would say, i.e. don't take the H1 Airbus times two. Even so, that would be easier.</p>
          <p>But in terms of my view for H2 in Airbus, we have more A380 deliveries, as we target the 30, we did 10, so you have 20. Unfortunately, it's not at the margin level we would like it to see, hence it is a bit dilutive in the second semester. Usually, the R&amp;D is also a bit more back-loaded in the year as you know, and there is a bit of pricing volatility, which on a quarter-by-quarter basis, is not necessarily representative. So perhaps a bit less bullish in terms of the pricing for the second semester. So, be a bit more cautious in terms of the H2 underlying Airbus performance compared to the H1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Sandy Morris of Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" />...everyone, I'm sorry (42:26). Two, what I hope are simple questions, just on the profile of the hedging going forward which is now a flatter profile, is that entirely opportunistic? Or are you anticipating Airbus revenues going up quite sharply in 2014 and 2015 for the obvious A350 reason? Is that what's driving it or is it just opportunistic because the rates good?</p>
          <p>And the sort of second quick question, really dumb one, is in terms of the conditions of this hedging, were something significant to happen in the Eurozone, could there be any dislocation for you? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Sandy. Thanks for the simple questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The dumb one, particularly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The underlying scenario is certainly not a full break up and I think dislocation is not an immediate thing from an industrial perspective, so clearly our base assumption is that the euro will continue to exist and hence we're protected by the hedge book. As we have it to a large extent, where you can see that, I mean the activity we had been doing in the first six months this year gives a great level of protection against volatility moving forward, at the same time, securing better rates in the book.</p>
          <p>To your first question, <mark type="ph" /> if I get it right (43:55) &#x2013; I mean the quarterly profile of the hedges is a bit difficult, I admit, so let's have a look a bit more on the full-year rates of the hedge book and you have that under page nine of the slides. Clearly, the growth &#x2013; you know the production rates which are decided, and to some extent installed, on the Airbus side.</p>
          <p>Moving forward on the single aisle and on the long range and the 380, I think we also guide in terms of 2015, the 2015 A380 breakeven between 35 and 39 aircraft, and when 350 coming in. But I would say the 350 coming in does not necessarily change the profile of the exposure, and hence, I mean the hedging. So I would rather ignore that part of it and focus on the single aisle, long range and the 380 exposure moving up where we're nicely protected. And in terms of the policy, now we're just hedging for the firm exposure moving forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, thank you. And we've had some lovely days at Eurocopter, so I was very sorry about that news. I mean thanks, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Sandy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Celine Fornaro of Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, gentlemen. One first question from me. Just listening to John Leahy comment at the air show, he counted some, more barriers than usual, assuming that he's always super bullish. So I was just wondering, in terms of management team, how do you &#x2013; what do you read into these comments? And if there are any signs that you've perceived over the last two months, I don't know, in terms of PDPs, how tough is it to secure PDPs, airlines talking about deferrals? If you're comfortable or not about your order books and your over-booking &#x2013; sorry, in 2013 and 2014? So if you could give us a little bit of color around those issues? And I don't know if you want to comment geographically, but that would be interesting as well. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Celine, hi. Tom, here. I'll start off and Harald might assist me in answering that question. No, we don't see any big signs of impending disaster, if I may say so. Our good friend, John Leahy was certainly a little bit depressed in Farnborough, over the fact that he couldn't win this one air show and was perhaps a bit more gloomy than usual.</p>
          <p>Well, look, I mean we're obviously not expecting that things go on like they did, particularly in 2011. We said that before, but I think, and I've just read this morning the conference call yesterday with Jim McNerney. I fully agree with Jim, that we're probably back to steady-state growth in the next couple of years in a global picture.</p>
          <p>And we should not forget, indeed, that we are in a business that is on average growing 5% per year, per annum. There is not only fleet replacement on the plate, but 50% of all these orders that we are projecting for the next 20 years, roughly 40,000 aircraft, over <mark type="ph" /> 100 fleets (47:25) will be for growth. So that environment and with the backlogs that we have today, we're certainly not timid as we look into the future.</p>
          <p>On PDPs, Harald, I think we see no anomaly coming in as normal. Anything else, Harald? Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And other second question. If I could just ask you to comment on the pricing, both in terms of the deliveries going forward from here but also the pricing on the new orders?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Harald?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Celine. Sorry that the answer might be boring but first, in terms of year-on-year, you see there's good underlying pricing performance in the actuals i.e. in the deliveries. Point number two, and I think we emphasized that recently and I will do so again, the <mark type="ph" /> CO (48:27) pricing hold firm since the launch of the neo and we did not see the drop over the cliff. And since the launch of the neo, we got a significant premium on the neo. Again, no change compared to what we guided in that respect.</p>
          <p>Pricing on the 330 is as well, very healthy. And also contributes to the year-on-year improvement we can see. So all in all, we feel comfortable with what we achieved in terms of pricing in deliveries, as well as the pricing in the orders and hence the pricing which sits in the order book. And back also to the question you had before, I mean the order book and the famous overbooking. As you know, we're doing that, is at a good level, which fully supports the production rates moving forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And you didn't comment on the A320 <mark type="ph" /> CO (49:36) pricing, but I guess, can you provide any color on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me to comment, so <mark type="ph" /> CO (49:45) pricing, pricing hold firm since the launch of the neo, so since 2010. And in what got delivered, you see it in the base performance and the <mark type="ph" /> CO (49:59) pricing therefore which we got, will translate into the deliveries to come. So, so far, we don't see a move on that.</p>
          <p>I don't want to fuel any further discussions about the price war. It's not coming from our side. We have a very competitive offering on the neo. The <mark type="ph" /> CO (50:20) is as well a very healthy offering, as you need a lift. There were some slots left in 2015 and 2016 and some 2017, but not at a scary level. So in terms of getting lift this is a good proposition and we're comfortable that we can fill that, however, I mean the last one's coming off the line and I think we said that several times, might come with some discount but I wouldn't see that as a reference for a pricing war.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question is from Zafar Khan of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Good morning, gentlemen. I have two questions please, one on the A380 and one question on the A350. Starting with the A380, could you please give us an update on progress with the loss elimination efforts on the A380? If you could just remind us where we are with that and what's happening with the main elements in terms of the losses. If I remember correctly you were saying to be at breakeven on the program by end of 2014 and you'd suggested that the wing feet issue should not really have any impact on how you quartize those losses. So a little bit of an update on that please, and whether, as before, you expect a big reduction in 2012 or should we be thinking about kind of a linear progression on that? So that's on the A380.</p>
          <p>And on the A350, just wanted to know what the main milestones are going to be going forward into &#x2013; when you get to first flight? Just as <mark type="ph" /> an outsider, what are (52:17) the sort of things that we should be focusing on? And you mentioned in the statement that any future provision on the A350 is likely to be at a higher level than the &#x20AC;120 million we've had for the three months. Would I be correct in thinking that's because maybe you've had a grace period from airlines on these initial delays, but any further delays would attract consequential damages?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I could take that. Let's get started with the last question on the 350. So the key milestones to come is the start of the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (53:02), so the first flying aircraft or the flight test aircraft with a first start later in October and the first flight, as Tom mentioned earlier, by mid-2013.</p>
          <p>Clearly what we have been doing here is to account for the issues we encountered, i.e. the wing build issues. That remains challenging. The objective clearly of the program is to keep the maximum pressure up. I mean, if I may say, you could easily reset things to a much larger extent and then everybody takes the benefit of that. That's not what we're doing. So we keep the maximum pressure up on everybody.</p>
          <p>At the same time, for sure, we're not doing that in isolation without talking to our customers. So our customers are aware of the current situation. We are in a constant dialogue about it. And we are working on our contractual commitment but not, again, in isolation but together with the customers. And the charge which you see here is reflecting the result of both the industrial setback and the contractual implications, however, we do not comment on individual accounts in terms of implications and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (54:35).</p>
          <p>To your question on the 380, let me take that a bit slice by slice, year by year. 2012, we see underlying improvement on the 380, year-on-year between 2011 and 2012. And let me come back also to 2011 before the wing rib issue happened, we saw very good progress on the recurring cost and this underlying improvement on the recurring cost has disappeared due to the wing rib issue. So the wing rib issue causes some intermediate disruption. Therefore, it means some difficulties but it doesn't stall the industrial improvement on the program as such.</p>
          <p>So you have the one-offs in 2012, of the &#x20AC;260 million on the full-year basis. We'll still have some wing rib provisioning in 2013 for the aircraft to be delivered, not yet being in the final configuration. So these will carry another provision, about &#x20AC;50 million, say, in 2013, then that should be over.</p>
          <p>However, as Tom alluded to before, we'll probably see deliveries below 30 in 2013. And so therefore, we will have some headwind in terms of the improvement path, which we thought to have initially for 2013 on the program, as clearly our objective was to go above 30 for 2013 before the wing rib issue happened. So in that respect, the improvement path, all in all, is a bit set back for 2013, however, plan is we're moving into the final forward fix solution on the wing build, with deliveries in 2014.</p>
          <p>Tom mentioned before the wings are already billed in 2013 in the final configuration. We should come back to our flight path to breakeven on the 380 and we completely stick and are committed to the breakeven of the 380 in 2015. I remind the key parameters here, it is at a delivery level of around 35 to 39 deliveries a year, at an exchange rate of $1.35.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a very comprehensive answer. Thank you for that. If I could just ask a supplementary on the A380? If we assume that the underlying losses are running at, say 100, and I'm not putting any unit on that, it's just a number, 100. Could you please tell us how that 100 divides between the elements, such as customer support and industrialization or the fixes that you're doing? Can you give us a little bit of a idea on how that 100 is divided between the various issues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I feel a bit sorry, as I don't know your 100s, hence I can hardly answer it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I mean if I say, the total loss is X because I'm not going to ask you what the loss rate is, it used to be &#x2013; the popular number was a &#x20AC;1 billion, so I'm not going to be foolish and ask you what the number is, so I'm just saying, the number is X, the loss, underlying loss is X. So how does that X split between the various elements? I just want to be able to understand where these losses are coming from. I know you mentioned industrialization, but I guess you got a lot of people out on the field as well and there's remedial actions you're taking. Can you help us with that at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I cannot help you to give you now the evolution in terms of the split on the margin and all of the other elements, detail by detail. I think we guided large in terms of the EBIT contribution of the program, what it was in the past, what we're doing, the one-offs and where we want to be by 2015. And I think we're fully knowledgeable about the importance this breakeven has for our profitability and for your considerations. And I think that gives the transparency and the visibility which is required.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Harald.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have time for two or three more questions. Next questions, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Ben Fidler of Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. A couple of questions please, firstly on the sensitivity to your free cash flow guidance regarding the A380. I wondered if you could just help me understand how many finished aircraft you had in inventory on the 380 at the end of the first half just to help me understand what the risk to your free cash flow guidance could be for the full year 2012, if you end up not delivering the full 30 aircraft?</p>
          <p>And the second question was just to understand how some of the moving pieces we've talked about so far on the call look as we head into 2013? And I know you haven't got specific guidance for that, but if you could just help me understand where the pieces move around, particularly pricing and the level of improvement or no improvement that you see in the underlying A380 loss position in 2013. That would be very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Ben.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So free cash flow guidance for the full year, clearly the 30 A380 deliveries for the full year play a very important role in that. And you can see that in the half year, having delivered 10 aircraft compared to 30 for the year, it weighs down on the free cash flow. I mean the inventory on the 380 is a key contributor to the negative cash flow which we had to face already in the Q1 and also for the H1.</p>
          <p>And I mean, I think you're perfectly familiar with the order of magnitude in terms of per aircraft we are talking about. So just to linear phasing of the build rate of 30 aircraft as they are in the pipeline and they are even, yeah, they are delayed in terms of the delivery. And hence, if they get delivered in the second semester, the 20 aircraft, then we are comfortable that we get to the positive free cash flow. I mean, if you take it from there, I think you can simulate a bit what the sensitivity in terms of the achievement of the full-year cash flow guidance is.</p>
          <p>But not limited to that, I would say is the delivery pattern, you can see was 279, 278 in the revenue line with the stepped-up guidance of 580 deliveries means that the phasing of the deliveries is more back-loaded. Again, these are not aircraft to be built in the second semester. The inventory is already very much around given the mandatory lead-times.</p>
          <p>And in terms of the 380, I understood your question for 2013 related to 380, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It was a couple of pieces. I mean I think we can all figure out what the volume impact might look like in 2013. We can figure out what the FX impact might look like. The missing piece is that we have little visibility on and you have a lot more visibility on, was the development of pricing on delivered aircraft in 2013, and the scale of improvement that you &#x2013; what sort of range of improvement could be expected in A380 losses in 2013, if indeed, any improvement at all in 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Isn't it a bit early to talk about 2013? As I understand, we give a guidance rather at the beginning of the year and not at this juncture of the year but...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'm not looking for specific guidance in that context. It was just to understand how some of the numbers possibly might be moving in terms of order magnitude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben, let me answer another way. I think you know the flight path chart, which is still perfectly valid in terms of the perspective moving from 2012 to 2015. I think as we discussed before, probably, we see a bit of a headwind on 380 here, but clearly we are committed to do our utmost to fight against that. Will we be able to offset it or not? I think that's something we will lean over in the second semester and then conclude when it comes to the guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Maybe one last person.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The next question is from Antoine Boivin from Cheuvreux.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, everybody. Antoine Boivin-Champeaux from Cheuvreux. First question for Tom. Coming back on the Alabama FAL, what are the many reasons for setting up an FAL in the U.S.? And could you rank the different elements which I think are around, which are lower cost, dollarization of cost, flexibility of manpower or get more orders in the U.S. either in the civil or defense domain? That's my first question.</p>
          <p>Second one is for, around on Eurocopter. You showed a very significant revenue growth in H1. Could you give us the underlying growth, i.e. excluding Vector and excluding the dollar element? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Antoine, on the first question you got it all right. You mentioned all the elements that play a role and I will deliberately not make a ranking here, but just to remind all of us that the U.S. market is the largest commercial aeronautic market of the world and will remain so, even if we keep up optimism for the Asian and the Chinese market in particular, will remain though for many, many years to come.</p>
          <p>And second thing is obviously the U.S. is a market where we find a lot of skilled labor, a lot of capability in the supply chain also, et cetera. So it &#x2013; the decision was basically, if I could summarize it, you can't be wrong to increase the footprint, to set up an industrial footprint in the U.S. and that should, in the long run, have a very beneficial influence on our Commercial business, on the reputation of Airbus in the United States.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Antoine. And regarding Eurocopter, so in terms of the year-on-year growth, you can see that revenues went up to close to &#x20AC;2.8 billion from the &#x20AC;2.1 billion, &#x20AC;2.2 billion. So let's say that in terms of the dollar, I don't see that as a significant element. The key driver is clearly the volume and the mix increase on the Eurocopter side. And next to that, the Vector contribution which I would say, however, is below 50% of the year-on-year growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, I think we have time for one other person. More questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All gone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Carter Copeland of Barclays.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, gentlemen. For Harald, on the A350 charge, you said it covered industrial and contractual implications, but it would seem quite small to cover contractual impacts across such a large backlog, I wondered if you might help me understand what sorts of costs, at least on a kind of conceptual level, are included in the charge, and better yet, what may not be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The charge of &#x20AC;124 million is the increase in loss-making contract provision. Any other cost with regard to the program delay, a part of the underlying performance, i.e., very much in the R&amp;D line. So clearly this is the sum of &#x2013; the push to the right, the &#x20AC;124 million, the push to the right, the contractual situation. And not so much update, I would say, on the industrial side, i.e., we don't see a major change on the recurring cost compared to what we had before. So you might say, this is more linked to the net commercial impact due to the delay.</p>
          <p>However, I mean, you might say that the charge is not so significant for the three months. Six months in November 2011, when we announced was &#x2013; for the six months, was &#x20AC;200 million, so you see it is slightly going up and I think we had been warning before and I'd like to make that comment also at this juncture, this number is not representative for any additional charge which might occur in the future if we would be obliged to reset the schedule, for the sake of clarification.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. That's very helpful. Thank you for the color.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>This closes our conference call for this time. If you have any questions, please email Julie, Oliver or myself with your list of questions. Thank you, and have a good day to all of you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Have a great weekend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the conference is now concluded, and you may disconnect your telephone. Thank you for joining, and have a pleasant day. Goodbye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>