<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1296431" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-03-09</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7857</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Nathalie Errard, Head of Investor Relations and Financial Communication</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Louis Gallois, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Hans Peter Ring, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Ben Fidler</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Zafar Khan</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Stephan Maichl</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Edward Stacey</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Rupinder Vig</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Antoine Boivin-Champeaux</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Avi Hoddes</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">David Perry</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Virginie Vacca</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Harry Breach</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Olivier Brochet</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Celine Fornaro</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Jason Adams</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Doug Harned</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the EADS Full Year 2009 Earnings Conference Call. At this time, all participants have been placed on a listen only mode. The floor will be open for questions following the presentation.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn the floor over to your hosts Louis Gallois, Hans Peter Ring and Nathalie Errard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. This is EADS full year 2009 earnings conference call. Louis Gallois our CEO and Hans Peter Ring, our CFO, will be presenting our results and answering your questions. This call is planned to last about one hour and thirty minutes. This includes Q&amp;A, which we will conduct after the initial presentation.</p>
          <p>It is also webcast with certain special banner on our homepage. Playback will be accessible on the website, but there is no dedicating phone replay service. The supporting information package was emailed to you this morning with slides, which we will now walk through and financial statements.</p>
          <p>Throughout this call, we will be making forward-looking statements. The packages you received contain a safe harbor statement, which applies to this call as well. We believe you should read it carefully.</p>
          <p>Now to Louis Gallois.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Nathalie, welcome ladies and gentlemen. In 2009 commercial and microeconomic conditions were difficult, but we were well prepared, and overcame a lot of challenges. We begin some years ago when we undertook the necessary cost and production adjustment to prepare the way for tougher times. For example we launched Power 8, tightened our focus on cash preservation, and secured against the dollar situation through our hedging activity. Our goal was not just to weather the economic storm. We wanted to maintain the resilient industrial platform that would innovate throughout our portfolio despite the pressures on our commercial business.</p>
          <p>Our performance delivered on this strategy, although execution issues and new programs, which unfortunately weighted heavily on our results, partly offset our cost cutting efforts. We successfully manage our cash flow. Astrium and Defense and Security continued commercial success while realizing improvement in earnings.</p>
          <p>Airbus and Eurocopter had slower commercial momentum, yet contributed meaningfully to top and bottom line performance, despite the deterioration in hedge rates. And in the process, we were still able to maintain our R&amp;D efforts to provide our customers with the world most technologically advanced products.</p>
          <p>The biggest risk for us as you know was impact of delays on the A400M. We have an aircraft which &#x2013; we've unquestioned military capability to which our customer are committed and have made significant step to derisking it.</p>
          <p>Let me give you an update of the A400M negotiation when we go to page 4, but before as Nathalie said please take a close look at our safe harbor statement.</p>
          <p>The customer nations and EADS have come to a principle agreement, regarding the A400M Military transport aircraft with intention to amend the original contract accordingly in the coming weeks.</p>
          <p>In this principle agreement, the nation customers agree to: first increase the price of the contract by &#x20AC;2 billion. Second waive all liquidated damages related to current delays. Third, provide an additional amount of &#x20AC; 1.5 billion in exchange for a participation in future potential export sales the so-called Export Levy Facilities. Fourth, accelerate pre-delivery payments in the period of 2010 to 2014, a new schedule of which will be finalized in the amended contract.</p>
          <p>Based on this agreement, an estimated completion of the updated revenues and costs including an assessment of risks leads to an increase of the A400M charge of &#x20AC;1.8 billion pre-tax. The provision stands at &#x20AC;2.5 billion in the balance sheet at the end of 2009. The update of the provision is based on the management assessment and judgment taking into consideration the principle agreement between EADS and the seven nations.</p>
          <p>The notes for &#x2013; to the financial statements comprise more information about the underlying management assessment, which is summarized on the slide. In particular, the Export Levy Facility is assumed to be structured so that EADS recognizes the &#x20AC;1.5 billion in revenues. Reassessment of management assumptions could have a significant impact on future results.</p>
          <p>Now on the group highlights, we have already talked about the proactive management of our backlog in the strong delivery patterns across our businesses in a difficult environment. 2010 commercial momentum is improving, so decision has been taken to increase single aisle production to rate 36 per month from December 2010. The A400M flight test program is progressing well. So development is advancing with the second aircraft entering the flight clearance test phase and the third aircraft now entering outdoor testing.</p>
          <p>Let's focus on the financials. The yearend order book reached &#x20AC;389 billion with Defense up more than &#x20AC;57 billion boosted by important military contracts in the year including Eurofighter Tranche 3A. Group revenues reached &#x20AC;42.8 billion, thanks to our robust deliveries roughly stable with 2008 level. The EBIT before one-off is in line with guidance and stands at &#x20AC;2.2 billion for EADS and at &#x20AC;1.1 billion for Airbus; despite, strong currency headwinds and A380 operational changes.</p>
          <p>Our net cash generation of &#x20AC;9.8 billion is a key success. We efficiently managed our free cash flow which was improved by unexpected government payment in December and lower customer financing needs than expected. The net loss of around &#x20AC;760 million was mainly due to the A400M provision of &#x20AC;1.8 billion and foreign exchange effect. Hans Peter will give you more detail later.</p>
          <p>Let me talk about our continuous effort to foster cost savings and integration first on page six. I will begin with Power 8. As you are already aware Airbus achieved &#x20AC;2 billion in gross savings by the end of 2009, compared to the projected cost base.</p>
          <p>Approximately 8,000 overhead positions have been reduced by the end of 2009, but there is still work to do in 2010. The restructuring plan has been less costly than planned and so the provision has been adjusted by &#x20AC;140 million in 2009 to reflect the change. Supply chain streamlining and logistics integration, as well as lean manufacturing have made solid contributions to a leaner Airbus.</p>
          <p>Power 8+ is now starting and contribution will be made from all divisions. In Airbus it begins with the stretch of Power 8. Other projects in Airbus includes redesign implementation in single aisle and long range programs, off-shoring engineering and manufacturing activities and increasing the level of low cost dollar outsourcing.</p>
          <p>The other divisions are also working on initiatives for operational improvement. Eurocopter is working on enhancing productivity and lead-time reduction which is also an element of the SHAPE program launched in this &#x2013; in the year. Astrium and Defence are working to optimize engineering, production flow and procurement processes.</p>
          <p>Now to mention our progress on future EADS. We have increased &#x2013; we are increasing the gross annual savings target from &#x20AC;200 million to &#x20AC;350 million after a full review of the 120 project which aim to simplify, harmonize and integrate our support functions across the Group.</p>
          <p>The savings run through 10 projects streams from finance to IT, general procurement and facility management. For more precise detail, please refer to the description of objectives in the appendix slide 25.</p>
          <p>And now, I leave the floor to Hans Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Louis. So good morning everybody. We are now on page eight with the 2009 financial highlights. Revenues remained roughly in line with 2008 level. Higher commercial volumes in Airbus and growth in Astrium were offset mainly by lower A400M revenues and negative effects from pricing on A330 commercial aircraft deliveries, as well as from foreign exchange.</p>
          <p>EBIT before one-offs, in line with our last guidance, compared to 2008 higher volumes in Power 8 savings at Airbus will more than offset the degradation of hedge rates, the deterioration of pricing on commercial deliveries and cost increases.</p>
          <p>In addition in 2009, the A380 continued to weigh significantly on the underlying performance. Order intake for commercial aircraft was significantly below the 2008 level, as expected, but the military and institutional businesses recorded strong contribution.</p>
          <p>At Eurocopter the lower number of units booked due to the weak commercial business were more than compensated in value by the large number of orders for military customers including 50 EC725 for Brazil.</p>
          <p>Astrium booked the second Ariane 5 batch consisting of 35 launchers worth more than &#x20AC;4 billion and EADS booked Eurofighter Tranche 3a, and the Saudi Arabia Border Security contract. 2008 included strong inflowing commercial aircraft orders and the order intake for tanker programs.</p>
          <p>Our order book stands at a robust &#x20AC;389 billion despite the revaluation impact at the closing rate that has led to a reduction of around &#x20AC;11 billion.</p>
          <p>Let's now move onto slide nine, where we can look at the underlying performance. The EBIT before one-off margin is 5.1% at the group level excluding early stage revenues on A400M program. At Airbus strong underlying performance of single aisle and long range is weighed down by the A380. Despite our efforts to cut costs our margin is under pressure from hedged deterioration. A lot of you are interested in the bottom-line impact of these cost savings.</p>
          <p>Firstly, they attract on a project by project basis and not only checked. But sometimes challenged and rejected by the project management. Secondly, a precise P&amp;L view is difficult because most of the savings flow through the inventories and therefore hit the bottom-line with a time delay. Thirdly, they are unfortunately partly compensated by some inflation of the cost base.</p>
          <p>Let's now consider the main list of non-recurring items. We have explained the negative net impact to the EBIT of the charge booked on A400M. A380 deliveries have been reorganized and the loss making contract provision has been adjusted by &#x20AC;240 million to reflect this shift as well as an increase in recurring cost.</p>
          <p>We use a compounded rate to revalue our loss making contract provision on commercial aircraft which has been adjusted at the year end, resulting in a negative impact for the full year of &#x20AC;45 million. A400M is not part of the compounded rate, so the associated provision will therefore have more volatility.</p>
          <p>In fiscal year 2009, the dollar-mismatch impact and the balance sheet revaluation had a negative impact on our EBIT result of around &#x20AC;440 million.</p>
          <p>Now, we go to slide 10, R&amp;D increased slightly versus last year, driven by increases at Airbus Eurocopter and to DS. The interest result is lower than last year. The change comes from the decline in interest rates on the financial markets that weighed more heavily on the last quarter. The large part of interest, which is related to repayable large investments, is stable. Meanwhile the other financial result improved slightly by around &#x20AC;50 million year-on-year driven mainly by an improvement in the impact from the revaluation of U.S. dollar and British pound cash assets.</p>
          <p>This line also includes the negative valuation of the premium paid for options and the unwinding of discounted provisions. The A400M provision is not discounted. The tax rate for the year 2009 is at 23% after some impairment of tax assets exceptionally due to the significant loss of 2009 the Board of Directors recommends not to pay any dividend this year.</p>
          <p>Up to slide 11, due to the evolution in U.S. dollar rates, the mark-to-market value of our hedge book is now at &#x20AC;1.3 billion, at a closing dollar rate of $144 per euro. The volatility of the dollar and the risk pricing of financial institutions still make hedging more difficult or unattractive with a number of banks. However, we have successfully continued our hedging activity without collateralization.</p>
          <p>Whilst $16.5 billion of hedges matured $16.2 billion of forward contracts were added in the course of the year at an average rate of $139 per euro. Recently we were able to add some more attractive hedges. Thanks to the strengthening of the dollar. We began to restructure some of the euro call options we added last summer. We sold $7 billion of options of which $4.6 billion were restructured into new forward contracts at more favorable rates. Our hedge book, therefore, decreased from $68 billion at the end of 2008 to $60.8 billion at the end of 2009. We are currently restructuring the remaining options for 2010, so the fluctuation of the spot rates will have an impact on our 2008 EBIT. Before these changes, quarterly rates for 2010 are provided on page 30. You will see that Q1, 2010 will suffer a lot from the hedging deterioration.</p>
          <p>On to slide 12 to the free cash flow, the combination of efficient cash flow management significant inflows from government and in &#x2013; situations in December previously expected in 2010 and lower customer financing than anticipated led to free cash flow generation of &#x20AC;600 million, instead of an expected cash consumption. Versus 2008 the significant change comes from the gross cash flow from operations, which was way down by the lower EBIT before one-off.</p>
          <p>As expected, the inventory build-up in the first nine months of the year has been partly reversed in the last quarter due to the high number of commercial aircraft deliveries. It decreased the mismatch effect between production rate and deliveries for both single aisle and long range.</p>
          <p>The inflow of advances linked to Airbus commercial activity is moderately lower than last year in line with the reduction in commercial activity. Advances increased across the other divisions due to the strong inflow of institutional orders.</p>
          <p>Net customer financing outflow was lower than expected in the year at around &#x20AC;400 million. Investing activities consumed &#x20AC;1.9 billion reflecting an increase in capital expenditure as investment ramped on the A350 program. This is below the forecast due to cutoff effects and Power 8 initiatives. CapEx should increase in 2010. For your information, we have included our future provision consumption excluding the A400M on slide 31 in the appendix.</p>
          <p>Now Louis will talk you through the performance of the Airbus division in more detail on page 14.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Hans Peter. Following the integration of Airbus Military into Airbus, Airbus is now reporting in two segments, Airbus Commercial and Airbus Military. The Airbus Commercial perimeter includes EFW and the completed airbus structure organization. But now excludes the A400M. Airbus Military includes the former Military Transport Aircraft division as well as all A400M activity. Eliminations are treated at the division level. 2008 figures have been restated to reflect the change except for Augsburg transferred from DS.</p>
          <p>On 2009 performance, 310 new firm orders were booked during the year thank to a continuing need for more efficient equipment. Financial markets showed more resilience than expected, heavily supported by ECAs [Export Credit Agencies]. Intensive negotiation on risk scheduling took plus &#x2013; took place but cancellation were limited with only 39 recorded in the year. Due to this proactive backlog management production rates have remained stable.</p>
          <p>In Airbus Military, we booked 18 aircraft orders thereof 15 medium and light military aircraft. In addition Airbus Military underscored its position in the tanker business, major progress were made &#x2013; was made in development of the second batch of three A330 MRTT and the second batch of three A330 MRTT was ordered by Saudi Arabia. The cancellation of the eight A400M by South Africa brings net order to 10.</p>
          <p>Airbus achieved a new delivery record in 2009 with 140 aircraft delivered in the last quarter alone. Ten A380s were delivered including two Wave 2 aircrafts, one each for Qantas and Air France. All deliveries qualified for revenue recognition now on the financial in more detail page 15.</p>
          <p>Airbus commercial revenues were in line with last year. The higher number of deliveries was offset by price deterioration notably for A330 deliveries and the negative impact from foreign exchange.</p>
          <p>EBIT is driven by higher volume and Power 8 savings, but offset by the negative impact from foreign exchange effects, price deterioration, net of escalation, and cost increases. A380 continued to weigh significantly on the underlying performance.</p>
          <p>Beyond the adjustment of the provision, inefficiencies had a negative impact on performance and an adjustment of excess capacity due to the low level of deliveries, weighed on the fourth quarter. These effects partly counterbalance the good underlying performance of the long range and single aisle families. As expected R&amp;D cost increased due to a ramp up in A350.</p>
          <p>Airbus Military revenues benefited from an increase in tanker and medium and light activities, however, they were more than offset by lower revenue recognition on the A400M program.</p>
          <p>The EBIT result benefited from higher tanker activity but lower deliveries and the weaker mix in the medium and light aircrafts segments. The EBIT result reflects the charges taken for A400M.</p>
          <p>The A350 development continued to progress. We have used up some of the previous buffers in the development of the A350 program. We keep the date of the entry into service unchanged. The division marked two successful first flights this year, the A330 freighter in November and of course the A400M in December.</p>
          <p>In addition, the industrial partnership with China resulted in 11 deliveries from the final assembly line in Tianjin to serve the Chinese market. It is a significant achievement.</p>
          <p>Now, Hans Peter will take you through Eurocopter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>And this on page 16. The Eurocopter's broad base of customers, markets and services have so far delivered a level of production against the several market downturn. However, the trend of bookings over the year has shown a significant slowdown with 344 net orders registered versus 715 in 2008. Also they were 20% higher in value. Cancellations amounted to 105 in the year, mainly in the private and corporate segments.</p>
          <p>Total deliveries are expected to be down by around 6% in 2010, production levels will continue to be monitored closely and adapted to market level. 2009 was a record year for military helicopters. The order book finished well above the 2008 level. The French DGR ordered 22 additional NH90, Eurocopter's military capability was proven during the year with the Tiger operating in Afghanistan.</p>
          <p>Revenues for the year were stable at a record level of 2008, despite a lower number of deliveries. Growth from a favorable mix in serial activities and the higher contribution from customer services was reduced by lower governmental and development revenues.</p>
          <p>EBIT decreased 10% below the 2008 level as the positive impact from services and cost saving initiatives was offset by increasing product investment, qualification and acceptance difficulties on NH90 continued to weigh on profitability despite first process improvements. Negative effects from foreign exchange also weighed on profitability.</p>
          <p>Expansion in Asia gained momentum. In December, the EC-175 first flight confirmed the successful partnership with AVIC in China. In Japan, Eurocopter continue to invest and is now the largest player.</p>
          <p>Significant progress was made in services development with the deployment of various flight simulators, service contract awards from the U.K., German and Brazilian armed forces as well as creation of new support facilities in Europe, Asia and America.</p>
          <p>We go now to Astrium on slide 17. 2009, has been the most successful year in the history of Astrium despite the loss of Galileo. Astrium recorded strong commercial success in the year with order intake reaching a record level exceeding &#x20AC;8 billion. Major drivers were the second batch of Ariane 5 worth more than &#x20AC;4 billion, the third production tranche for the M51 and key successes in telecommunication satellites such as the order secured from SES Astra.</p>
          <p>Productivity and increasing efficiency have driven top and bottom line growth. The 12% increase in revenues versus 2008 came from contributions across all businesses. The revenues also include a non-operational positive one-time effect due to a revenue catch-up for in-orbit incentive schemes on commercial satellites with low margin recognition.</p>
          <p>During the year, Astrium services delivered on Skynet 5 a &#x20AC;2.5 billion contract on time and to quality. Astrium is successfully delivering military communication services to the U.K. MoD and is once more ranked among its most reliable suppliers. The division grew profitably for a sixth consecutive year. Key drivers were the increased productivity in earth observation satellites and Ariane 5 production as well as growth in telecom services, that was partially offset by an unfavorable translation effect from the declining British pound to euro foreign exchange rate on Paradigm.</p>
          <p>The level of R&amp;D investment before tax credit is stable in the division. In December Astrium marked the 35th consecutive successful Ariane 5 launch with the in-orbit delivery of Helios 2B and the French defense &#x2013; for the French Defense Procurement Agency.</p>
          <p>Now onto Defence on slide 18, where the aerostructures activity from Augsburg is now consolidated in the Airbus segment, Louis has already talked about it. 2008 figures have not been restated. The order book of &#x20AC;18.8 billion reflects the DS high growth strategy and important contract awards in the year most notably Eurofighter Tranche 3a, the Saudi Arabia Border Security contract and the 1st Export contract in Airport Surveillance Radar to Switzerland.</p>
          <p>On a like-for-like basis, revenues reflect the higher volume of Tranche 2 and exports deliveries for Eurofighter as well as integrated logistics support. DS has delivered a profitable growth and margin expansion to now 8.4%, a combination of growth and margin improvement on core and export for Military Air Systems and Missile programs combined with operational improvements offset a ramp-up in R&amp;D investments in areas such as radar and UAV as well as the aerostructures carve out.</p>
          <p>2009 proved to be a year in which DS made strategic advances in Unmanned Aerial Vehicles activities by supporting the French Army in the deployment of the Harfang System in Afghanistan, by successfully testing the Barracuda demonstrator, and through the completion of the Risk Reduction Study for the European advanced UAV Talarion.</p>
          <p>In missiles, the U.K. and France have launched a joint assessment phase to develop next generation helicopter anti-surface missiles.</p>
          <p>Now on to other businesses on page 19, where I will first remind you that EFW is reported as part of the Airbus segment now. In addition 70% of Socata was sold to DAHER in January 2009. The remaining 30% is consolidated at equity within other businesses. 2008 figures have been restated for EFW, but not for Socata. The significant reduction in the order book and the decline in revenues since year-end is predominantly explained by the change in perimeter.</p>
          <p>EBIT was also lower year-on-year, productivity gains from Sogerma's turnaround are offset by negative foreign exchange effects at ATR and a lower EBIT in EADS North America. Proactive order book management at ATR in a context of a weak customer and financing environment led to 53 aircraft delivered in the year. Of which 23 were delivered in the last quarter as financing issues were resolved. Net orders reached 26 for 2009, cancellations were lower than last year.</p>
          <p>The 2010 production rates have been adjusted downwards by around 10% to reflect the current environment. At EADS North America the LUH program continues its success with a ramp-up in deliveries to 45. All helicopters have been delivered on time or ahead of schedule.</p>
          <p>The new U.S. Tanker competition is underway but as you know lots of EADS will not bid since the RFP is heavily weighing the competition in favor of the smaller 767.</p>
          <p>Now Louis will comment on the guidance on page 21.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Hans Peter. Yes, to our guidance. The group is fundamentally solid to cope with the 2010 economic environment which is improving but is still volatile. This is based on a resilient, actively managed backlog of 3,500 aircraft in Airbus and 1,303 in Eurocopter and strong backlog in the Space and Defence businesses. Based on a number of active campaigns gross orders at Airbus should be between 250 and 300 in 2010.</p>
          <p>In 2010 Airbus expects to deliver to the same level of aircraft as in 2009. Eurocopter should deliver around 6% less helicopters in 2010 compared to 2009. Therefore, using &#x20AC;1 for $1.40 as the average spot rate, EADS revenues should be roughly stable in 2010. EADS EBIT in 2010 will be around &#x20AC;1 billion. The deterioration of the hedge rates will weigh by about &#x20AC;1 billion compared to 2009. A380, while slightly improving, will continue to weigh substantially on the EBIT before one-off, as in 2009. Cost savings and some improvement in aircraft pricing should contribute positively while weaker helicopter deliveries, some increase in research and development and cost inflation will weigh on profitability.</p>
          <p>Going forward, the EBIT performance of EADS will be dependent on the group's ability to execute on the A400M, A380 and A350 programs in line with the commitments made to its customers.</p>
          <p>Provided a sustainable year-end cash inflow of institutional and government business and subject to pre-delivery payment advances in the A400M program, the free cash flow before customer financing should be breakeven. Free cash flow after customer financing should be negative due to customer financing cash outflow of around &#x20AC;1 billion.</p>
          <p>Now, I would like to talk you through our top objectives in coming years. In 2009, we have made substantial progress on putting our key programs back on track. A lot of effort will still be devoted to improving execution throughout 2010. From a commercial standpoint, the A350 has been a very fast selling aircraft, achieving a 38% market share as at the end of 2009.</p>
          <p>However, as with all new aircraft developments, we face development changes due primarily to the technological complexity of the aircrafts. Our focus on margin improvement and cash preservation is now an integral part of our business plan and culture.</p>
          <p>In some cases, we have not achieved the type of margins in select divisions that we would have liked to have seen. So the pressure to improve by findings smart lean cost solutions will continue to accelerate.</p>
          <p>It is critical we manage our pipeline for higher results. We have a more flexible market responsive management in place in all our businesses. We have preserved our liquidity and cash focus. This provides us with flexibility for future investment.</p>
          <p>So, we face 2010 in a position of financial stability and commercial success, despite our program changes. I feel that we can now turn our attention to growth again. And I can say based upon the signals, we read from passenger market and the global economy that we anticipate some growth in demand; growth which we're well positioned to exploit.</p>
          <p>Progressive recovery in traffic and yield especially in emerging markets should first stabilize airline financials before it leads to additional ordering activity. I can highlight the priorities easily, they are consistent with principles we've shared with you before and which we now must accelerate.</p>
          <p>First, innovation is the essence of competitive leadership. Hence we're turning our sights of the immediate future, particularly on actions which will enhance our competitiveness in 2010.</p>
          <p>The A350 is a cornerstone of our future. We're looking at improving the A320 family, a decision on the reengineering will be taken in the next month. We must apply the same breakthrough philosophy to all areas of our portfolio from launches to UAV, including new helicopter concepts based on high-pressure diesel engines. But innovation will lead us to explore new fields for growth and new markets. EADS will focus on bringing innovation to market quicker than in the past.</p>
          <p>Continue to globalize is second. Our industrial footprint, while enclosed in Europe, must be extended further. Partly this is a necessary edge against currency vulnerability. Just as important, we need to exploit the business opportunities by being present in customer markets.</p>
          <p>I want to be clear, the U.S. Tanker decision does not diminish our commitment to the U.S. The enduring strength of our commitment is reflected in the success of the Army's Light Utility Helicopter of which we are prime contractor, and that just celebrated its 101 scheduled delivery.</p>
          <p>And it also can be seen in the many air systems that operate with the U.S. Army, Navy, Air Force and Coast Guards. And finally, I want to make in 2010 more progress in the expansion of services and security in 2000 &#x2013; there are two business areas that could bring us growth and profitability. We will put the emphasis on them in the following years. We will now take your questions. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We now start our Q&amp;A time. Please introduce yourself and your company when asking a question. Please limit yourself to two questions at a time. And so as usual, please remember to speak clearly and slowly to help all participants understand what you're asking. Please go first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> First question comes from Ben Fidler from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead with your question now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, two questions, if I could, please. The first one just on the EBIT guidance the &#x20AC;1 billion, just if you could help us understand what is included in there, in terms of is that a clean number? Does that include further provision risks? And any indication of the level of further provision overhang risk that you may have included in that would be tremendously helpful.</p>
          <p>And the second question that I had, which is to help me understand your expectations for the rate of the ongoing A380 above the line operating losses, what sort of rate do you see those falling, not just in 2010, but as particularly we look into '11 and '12. I guess the key is at what stage does A380 become breakeven?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the guidance Ben we have not included any additional, what you call provisional risks. We have given you a guidance which is not aggressive, I would say, particularly if we would accomplish all of our targets. It does not include any provisioning issues. Louis, you want to go to the A380 question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the A380 my answer will be extremely short. We are not giving indication on the rate of production for 2011 and '12; we are only saying that it will be increased compared to 2010. I remind you that in 2010, we expect to deliver 20 airplanes. We have delivered three airplanes on the first two months. On breakeven for the program, we are not giving the date, we are &#x2013; airbus is working hard to recover on the cost of the airplane to be able to be breakeven as early as possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ben. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Zafar Khan from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale, London. Please, it's your turn now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much indeed. Ben has asked the one about the A380 underlying loss, but I guess I can ask a couple of others which I find interesting. Can you please help us with this comment you made about using up the buffers you had on the A350. How much contingency had you put in place, which you now say you have used up? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And the second one is just on your EBIT guidance. I am interested in the statement you make about going forward. The EBIT performance is dependent on the ability to execute on the programs. I guess, in any company when they give a guidance that depends on executing whatever they're doing correctly. So why have you put that in as a statement within your guidance? And exactly what do you mean by that? And I guess the &#x2013; what would help us understand exactly what you mean by that is what kind of probability would you put on meeting the commitments to your customers on those three programs? Are you 75% confident on that, 50%, 90? That would help me understand what that statement really means.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the buffer of A350 we are talking of the time schedule buffer, not on contingencies in the program but on the timing of the program. And it's clear that we have consumed part of this buffer. And it means that the program is a changing one. But as I said we stick to the present time schedule for the first delivery in July 2013. But as I said, the buffers are now more limited than in the past.</p>
          <p>On the EBIT guidance, we are &#x2013; you are right. Every guidance is linked to the fact that we are able to execute. That's clear. But as you have been aware that in the past we have not been clearly able to reach our targets in the implementation of some programs, we are a bit more cautious. But we have no probability to attribute to the success of our program management. It's the main, the main operational priority for us is to recover good program management. It's clear that this program is identified as a priority for all divisions, including Airbus. Fabrice Br&#xE9;gier is COO of Airbus, is in-charge for the account of the whole EADS of program management recovery program. And I think the A350 is demonstrating that we are making progress.</p>
          <p>I think on the A400M we have made huge progress in 2009, even if we don't see the consequences immediately, but the &#x2013; organization of Airbus Militaries, the introduction of new processes in the management of the program are giving us encouragement for the future. If I could say that the probability to answer &#x2013; to try to answer your question, the probability to be able to implement our program as we expected is increasing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's encouraging, but if I look at the 2010 guidance that you've given of 1 billion of EBIT, if I can split the Group into Airbus and non-Airbus, the billion suggests to me that you expect only a breakeven in Airbus. Am I getting something wrong there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you are right. We could consider that because of the Eurocopter commercial activity, perhaps the non-Airbus division will be a bit below 1 billion. It means that Airbus is not far the breakeven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how do you achieve that, deliveries are going to be flat?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Zafar, I'm sorry. But we need to give two questions per person. Thanks for your understanding and thank you for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Stephan Maichl from LBBW. Please, may we have your question now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Stephan Maichl from LBBW in Stuttgart, good morning. Two questions if I may. The first one is on, maybe could you give us a kind of mid-term EBIT target for Airbus taking into account A400M margin dilution ahead? Second question maybe could you give us an EBIT margin outlook for non-Airbus business in 2010, especially maybe for Eurocopter, having in mind the 6% delivery decline expected? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hans Peter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think mid-term EBIT target, but we have not said anything in our release. Obviously, what you can see from the decisions we make is, we are getting more confident going forward, that's why we raised the production rate end of this year. Certainly 2010 &#x2013; and by the way we always said that it's not new, 2010 is certainly the most difficult year, as we go through the current crisis externally but also in our programs.</p>
          <p>So 2010 certainly is difficult and 2011 we will start recovery, but it's a &#x2013; I would say probably also difficult year. And then 2012, '13, '14 if the current market development is concerned, I think it's going to be &#x2013; to grow in terms of bottom-line to some significant extent. So that's what you should expect.</p>
          <p>On the non-Airbus businesses, yes, Eurocopter indeed has 2010 as the most difficult year, because also we have a good order intake last year, it is on the big helicopter programs where deliveries start only in 2011 because of lead times. So the commercial helicopter decline we have seen on order intake will hit the top end of bottom line in 2010. So it will be below what you've seen in 2009, somewhat significantly. And then Eurocopter will return with probably 1.5 years delay to the old, rather favorable I would say profitability pattern again.</p>
          <p>Defense and Space, there is some growth on top and bottom line in 2010, particularly on the Defense side. And on the other businesses due to ongoing weakness in the regional aircraft market we should expect some decline for 2010 as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. So 5% EBIT target at Airbus is achievable in the long run?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I did not...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>5% EBIT margin for Airbus might be achievable in the long run?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are not giving you a precise number today but certainly depending a bit on the dollar environment we should be at those target sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Edward Stacey from Execution Noble. Please go ahead with your question now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Two questions please. Firstly on vendor financing, it seems you're suggesting about 1 billion of financing requirement in 2010. I was hoping you could just talk the bigger requirement for 2009; if you can just talk about what are the underlying assumptions, whether the increase is driven by lesser export credit financing in the mix or whether it's driven by the overall external financing market getting harder? And whether you've thought about sort of how high it might go if the external credit markets are maybe even worse than you thought what might be sort of an upper limit for that requirement in 2010?</p>
          <p>And then the second one is just on the contracting structure of A400M. I think some months ago Tom Enders was quoted in the press as saying that fixed price contract structure itself was untenable whereas it seems with this agreement we're still in the same structure but just with a bit more money throw in from the government. So is there something that's changed that makes the program now less risky that made you decide it was after all okay to go ahead with that structure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me first answer the question on vendor financing, and Louis you could probably take the A400M. Vendor financing, we have taken the same level of let me say protection in budget for 2010 as we had for 2009 at the beginning of the year. It does not mean that we intend to spend the money. Vendor financing is a topic which we decide in our risk management committee on a case-by-case basis, so a very intensive discussion whether it make sense or not and obviously we apply very strict rules to that. But as I said, the markets probably recover but we still see weakness in the profitability of airlines. So, it's more related to the questions still are airlines able to fund all the equipment they want.</p>
          <p>Certainly, we will get similar level of ECA support in 2010. That's at least the assumption today. And then you have still another &#x2013; how much is it 65%, if I compare it to 2009 which has to be taken by the market and that's quite a significant number. So, it's a little bit the same logic as we had in 2009. We protect a certain budget for that in our plans and then we try to limit the expenses as much as we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the contractor structure for the A400M, Tom's statement was targeting more new contract than the present one. In the present amended contract for A400M, we stay on the basis of fixed price. But you &#x2013; through the agreement we have with the nations we have been able to rebuild some contingencies inside the program which are giving us confidence in our capacity to achieve in the present envelope. And certainly we have to continue the process of improvement of our program management and the team is doing that. But I'm, in the frame of the new &#x2013; the amended contract, I'm confident that we're able to reach our targets and to stick to the envelope of financing we've forecasted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Rupinder Vig from Morgan Stanley. Please, it's your turn now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Just two questions, please. Firstly, just on R&amp;D, one of the reasons why your free cash flow guidance 2010 is lower than '09 is due to the increased R&amp;D. I mean, how much will R&amp;D come in for the year, is it going to be higher than the kind of 2.8 to three billion you've previously talked about?</p>
          <p>And then secondly just on the decision to ramp-up to 36 aircraft from December, could you just give us a bit more color as to why December, is that as quick as you can get it done or is that when you actually think the airlines will be in a position to actually start taking more planes, just a bit more detail around that, please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>R&amp;D, very shortly, it's a very small increase we expect in 2010, so a little bit of increase but not much. And what was your second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question was the rampup of the 320. We &#x2013; Airbus is taking decision considering the number of airplanes he has to deliver, and certainly taking the decision today, it could have been possible to anticipate a bit, the ramp-up of production, but we don't need that for delivering in 2010. We have rebuilt some over-booking for 2011, justifying the fact that we increased production at the end of the year. We're doing that on the basis of deliveries expected.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Antoine Boivin from Cheuvreux. Please go ahead with your question now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, Antoine Boivin-Champeaux. Two question, please. If I look at your guidance for '10 and the comment you made on the dollar impact and R&amp;D. And taking into account the other items which are sometimes positive cost savings and pricing and negatively cost inflation, I end up with the cost inflation impact of around &#x20AC;400 million. Could you confirm that this is the type of cost inflation impact you have and what kind of visibility you have on this item? This is my first question.</p>
          <p>My second question is linked to A400M. Could you tell us, even if we don't know exactly the timetable of the pre-payments but could you tell us the cash outflows, cumulated cash outflows you expect from '010 to '014 on the A400M as a holder? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cost inflation, yes indeed that's what we say within the guidance that there is an impact, which is indeed several hundred, whether it's the 400, I would not confirm at this point, Antoine, but it is a significant number and that obviously compensates the efforts we see and also the success we see in some of our improvement programs. And then if you look at the guidance as we discussed before, we have some declines in Eurocopter. We have some declines due to small increases in R&amp;D. So these are issues which need to be compensated on top, obviously, of the big hedge impact we see.</p>
          <p>On A400M, Louis, should I?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, yes, yes, yes you could. Cumulative &#x2013; cumulated cash flow...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cash flow...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>for 2010-14...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you read the release and what we say in our notes, the PDP schedule for the new program set-up is still to be finally agreed within the contract amendment, the current willingness of the parties is to advance. The PDP is now linked to the new contract schedule with a target obviously to have not too much cash burden as we go into the next years. We cannot yet give you now a more precise figure, but that is at least what was discussed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question was on the cash outflow...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not on the cash inflow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no cash &#x2013; the cash outflow. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is supposed to cover the outflow, ultimately as you know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just to come back, sorry to come back on your first answer. In terms of cost inflation and visibility on this important factor what kind of visibility do you have?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of what? Can you say that again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The visibility on cost inflation because there could be a mismatch in between the year, the index as an annual real cost inflation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, Antoine, we have seen that phenomenon every year. So it's not new and what we said when we projected the Power8 targets was it's against the projected cost base. So that is part of that. And if &#x2013; let me say a number which is north of probably 200 million and it depends in the different years, so that's what I can probably say to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Avi Hoddes from UBS. Please, it's your turn now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everybody. I have three questions, first of all I just wanted to get clear in my mind the Power8 provision adjustment, was there a 100 odd plus million benefit to Airbus profit in 2009 from that adjustment? I guess the second question is on PDP payments financing. How are you seeing that? I mean in the past you said airlines are paying you on time. But are they struggling to do that? I mean what's your view on that and I guess somewhat adjunct to that, was there any benefits or otherwise to Airbus profit in 2009 from customer financing provisions or gains and if you could numerate that, that'd be great? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question is for Hans Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Power8 adjustment, I mean on Power8 you are right. It's some 100 million plus we have released it within the one-offs. You find on the reconciliation slide in the booklet. It is because first of all we spend less money on severance payments that is probably the major part. And then there was also some reallocation from overhead people working on overhead positions into more productive, and last but not least, a big chunk of the 8,000 people Louis talked about is on subcontractors and C2 as we say in France, so we heavily have reduced on that side which literally has not a real big cost. So, all of that together leads to that reassessment of the provision and the release.</p>
          <p>On PDP financing, we have not seen changes within the last few months. So PDP financing is at least as it concerns requests to us on a negligible low level, so nothing really unusual. What is also probably interesting is the level of overdues and if I talk about overdues it's always on PDPs in Airbus, because the payment is &#x2013; upon delivery it's not in question so there is no overdue on that.</p>
          <p>So PDP overdues, there is also no change in what we've seen now for the last say 18 months since the crisis started. So we are at a normal level nothing unusual for the time being. In other words, customers are able to honor the commitments. Obviously we had to reschedule a lot of positions we talked about that but all in all, I think no particularly unusual situation at this point.</p>
          <p>And impact customer financing in 2009 &#x2013; coming from customer financing on EBIT in 2009 is some, not a big figure, minus 60.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's also included in one-off, Avi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from David Perry from Goldman Sachs. Please, it's your turn now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, gents. Just couple of things. I am just a little bit confused on actual cost savings in your guidance, mainly in Airbus. Can you just tell me please in 2010, what incremental cost savings you think benefit EBITA in '10? It would also be very helpful if you could give me the cost savings incrementally expected in '11 and how much of that will be consumed by FX if that's possible because you've got a number of plans and I sort of lost track of what's coming through?</p>
          <p>And then the second question is if you launch a re-engining of the A320. Can you give us a rough idea of what that might cost you and when that might start to come through in R&amp;D? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Power8...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actual cost saving.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have not given you a number in the release as you've seen it and I am not giving you a number now. And one of the reasons is what we described is that a lot of it is flowing through inventories and so far is only hitting the bottom line with somewhat significant delays particularly on the long lead time program. So no precise figure on that, but obviously the savings at this point are expected to cover what we call cost increase and inflation more or less. On what was your second question...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just the same thing in '11.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The re-engining of...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Re-engining, yes, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just &#x2013; sorry just before that &#x2013; just before that, can you &#x2013; on 2011 what is your FX hit that you are expecting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The FX hit, I mean we have not given a number yet. But we will lose another $0.05 based &#x2013; or 0.04 to $0.05 based on the hedge book of today, and then you can easily recalculate what it means. There will be &#x2013; there is still some open exposure in 2011 and it will obviously depend finally on at which rate we are able to cover that exposure. And there is still some options left, which if the dollar is strong enough, we might restructure in the course of 2010. So and so far there is still some dollar volatility, but we can already now see that we will see, I would say at least another 0.04 to $0.05 deterioration for 2011, which means if we take our rule of thumb 1 billion on $0.10 it means around 500 million probably. But we have to keep in mind that with increase of top-line we will increase exposure as well. So it might be a bit higher. But anyway this is the rough number, I would guess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, is it fair to say in 2011, the incremental cost savings you'll achieve will be above 2010 with the new plans coming in or roughly the same?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the big step in what we call now the Power8 plus in future EADS savings programs is coming through in 2012. This is the targeted year for that. So I would not expect '11 to be materially probably different from 2010. But I cannot give you a precise guidance on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the re-engining of the A320 we have not clear for the time being frozen evaluation of the cost because we have to know exactly what we are doing, and Airbus is working on it. Certainly, it will be in addition to the development R&amp;D of Airbus, but in a much more limited way than if it were a new program, it's clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But it's incremental, you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's incremental, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just very quickly just a clarification Hans Peter, you said...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hans Peter is &#x2013; has different body language. You can see it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the A400M...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, he wants to contradict me, but he was right &#x2013; because he did for the sake of EADS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now on R&amp;D, if you look at R&amp;D expenses slowly into the next year, there will not be a big change. So I think that is the interesting information for you. In other words, there will be some decreases in some other areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's clear that we are consistent Hans Peter and myself, it's clear that it's an increase of R&amp;D expenses, but it's compensated by the decrease of all another programs and it means kind of stable R&amp;D for the next years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's very clear. And then just very quickly, Hans Peter you said on the finance line there was no discounting of the A400M provision, going forward will there be a discounting and what will that be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's not &#x2013; there will be no discount on that program simply because of the structure of the contract. So there are different IFRS rules.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Virginie Vacca from S&amp;P. Please, the line is open now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning, two questions, if I may. Louis, two years ago I think you gave us an estimate of the export market for the A400M, which was I believe roughly equivalent to the client &#x2013; to that of the client's nation, so let's say 200. Two years later, we have a price increase, more delays; and more importantly, we've seen Lockheed-Martin quite successful in a number of countries. Iraq, Oman, Qatar, recently Tunisia. So I'm just wondering, where does your estimate stand at the moment? And how do you expect to make the aircraft profitable, among others? Has anybody touched upon the topic of the aftermarket service contract for the aircraft? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the A400M has certainly a strong potential for export. And it's much more than the present contract of 180 airplanes.</p>
          <p>I think you can easily double if not more the market for export of the A400M when you consider two things. First, the number of C-130 to be replaced in the world; and second, that even with the increase of price, we have agreed with the nations, the A400M remains cheaper per ton transported than the C-130 and the C-17, with much higher capabilities.</p>
          <p>It means that we have a winner for the export market with this airplane, if we are able to manage properly the program. We have a true winner for the market. I am extremely optimistic on the export capacity of this airplane, even in the United States.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Harry Breach from Barclays Capital. Please, it's your turn now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning, Louis, Hans Peter and Nathalie. My two questions are, firstly on the A350, I think that on the baseline dash 900 model, the milestone called Maturity Gate 6 was due in December or possibly January. Can you tell me how we achieved that milestone yet, and did we achieve it on time? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And my second question is, when we think about A380 and the loss making contracts on that, I know from what you told us at Seville that you released the provisions on each loss making contract, so they are EBIT neutral initially, then they become EBIT negative and then EBIT positive later in each loss making contract. Can you give us some idea of when those first contracts, the major LMCs are likely to go into their negative EBIT contribution phase? Is that going to start this year or next year, and how big a drag is it if you can help me with that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question will be for Hans Peter because it is more complex. And the first one on the A350, the MG6 milestone is in process and it's for this quarter. We will &#x2013; the process is engaged, it's not done in one day because we have to address different element of the airplane. But clearly, the MG6 milestone is for the first quarter of 2010, and you understand that the first quarter is not far the end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Louis, was it originally scheduled for December? Or was it always...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes, we &#x2013; yes, you are right. It was in December. We began the process in November and it took longer than expected. But for the time being, it's not changing our view on the time schedule of the airplane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hans Peter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On loss making contracts that is a tricky question, Harry, as you know. So, if we &#x2013; if one of those contracts is getting out of a loss making provision say because for example the dollar has strengthened. You would then immediately fall back to something where you recognize the cost along the learning curve. In other words at the beginning rather high cost always compared to an average contractual value and that in such a case would negatively impact in terms of the placing your bottom line. If that was your question but I am not quite sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, no. Hans Peter if we look at the dollar where you would mark-to-market at the end of 2009, clearly some contracts will still be LMCs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For those contracts, they will for the initial deliveries be a zero margin as you release the provision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But then they will be go into loss before going into positive EBIT. If we think about all of these contracts together, they will add up to a significant negative drag on EBIT. And what I am trying to understand is when is this impact really going to start to hit us if we can understand that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not prepared to answer that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't &#x2013; I am sure we'll make the calculation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll come back to you and discuss with you exactly how that works.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks Hans Peter anyway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will come back to you next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Olivier Brochet from Natixis. Please, your line is open now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning to all of you. So the first question relates to the litigations notes that are in the accounts. And I would like to understand a bit more about the background on the arbitrage request against EPI, and especially on the timing elements and what is it related to? That's the first one.</p>
          <p>And the second one is on the 2011 delivery increase for A320s. I would like to understand a bit more about where the increase is coming from, is there any specific areas that are driving this additional demand from airlines? And also in terms of the export &#x2013; the impact on the results, is it fair to say that in my modeling, I should consider that on the one hand I have a lower hedge level than in 2010? So less hedges and higher exposure and the difference I should use current market rates for the &#x2013; for my modeling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Listen, I think, I should immediately say yes. The open exposure you apply to what your dollar forecast would be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's exactly how it works.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you are going to hedge that very &#x2013; in the very short-term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are hedging that as we approach the delivery position. So I would guess that most of it, I mean, we have never hedged, let me say 100%. We always keep some margin to the expected exposure and so far there is always a small open exposure. But yes we would &#x2013; the majority of it would be locked in before we reached deliveries. And hopefully dollar is volatile and strengthening for sometime, so that we can lock in better rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On increase in deliveries and whether there is additional demand, I mean, what &#x2013; I would not say there is much additional demand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No, not at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've seen that the demand, Louis has explained it in the guidance, is between 250 and 300 aircrafts. So it's pretty low compared to the previous years. What it is, is actually that we feel more comfortable with the backlog.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure we are reducing the rate of production to &#x2013; from 36 to 34. We have rebuilt some overbooking for 2011. And we are feeling more comfortable with this overbooking in a way which is leading us to increased production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you are basically receiving PDPs for this overbooking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We are receiving PDPs and we have contact with the airlines, confirming their wish to receive the airplane 2011 and we have to deliver them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on EPI?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On EPI, you know, that we have a lot of claims and counter claims with our suppliers is not unusual in very costly program for every body, because we are not alone to have financial impact of this program in our accounts. I think companies like Thales, or engine manufacturers or Sagem could have the same problem as us. And it means that there is a lot of claims and counter claims and we are taking that into account in the risk of the program, but also we have some arguments for to counter claim against some of our suppliers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it will be a story, we are just at the beginning of the process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you can drive into 2011 and beyond.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh. Yes, yes, yes, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Far beyond.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Celine Fornaro from the Bank of America. Please it's your turn ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. My first question would be on pricing please, both on the pricing of the new deliveries for 2010, and how we should think for single aisle and the wide bodies. And also on the pricing on the new orders that have been locked in, and what's the pricing outlook for 2011. So, if we are going through a gradual improvement or the 2011 pricing is actually being compromised?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we are &#x2013; with 2009, we were at bottom of the swimming pool for the pricing and we will progressively recover, because the orders we have taken between 2007 and 2009 or '10 are with better pricing and we will see that in our result, I hope, not in 2010, but progressively in '11 and '12. I have to say that for the time being, the pricing is not deteriorating, which demonstrates that we're not chasing the orders, but we want to protect our pricing, it's our priority more than get orders &#x2013; new orders. And I think our competitor is doing the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And my second question would be on the U.S. bank. Now, with the decision that you're not going to be bid for DRSP, will there be any charges that you have to incur and does that change your view of &#x2013; I understand for Eurocopter, but I'm more thinking about Airbus and developing some production presence in the United States?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the cost, I think it's a...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will not be a significant impact. We did not capitalize significantly costs in the current competition up to now. What we still have to settle is the cancellation which was given to us &#x2013; when was it in, last year or the year before &#x2013; last year, I think it was canceled. So, we are in discussion with the administration in the U.S. to settle the claims. But you should not expect material impact on the results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the American market, the American market is the biggest in the world for defense and security and it's clear that we want to be able to compete in this market. I think we have &#x2013; we have demonstrated that we were able to &#x2013; even as a prime contractor to win to for helicopters, but also for other equipment and we will continue our effort in that way. This is only what I can say on that point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Jason Adams from Nomura. Please it's your turn now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everybody. I actually have three questions, but I promise they are all very quick. First, I was wondering if &#x2013; could you confirm the A320 rate increase? Is that coming from your Chinese production facilities or European production facilities? Secondly, I am wondering why Hans Peter &#x2013; if you knew that the A380 would be loss making in 2010, why didn't you recognize any additional provisions in '09 or take a charge? And then the third question is, with the hedge rate deteriorating by 0.04, $0.05 in 2011, do you see any scenario where Airbus could be &#x2013; could do better than break even in 2011? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the A320 is a Chinese production as to grow progressively to four airplane pay amounts. We're in the process of increasing this production and you know that these airplanes are mainly priority for the Chinese market and it will be the case. We don't change our production rate in China if we go &#x2013; come back to 36 it will be in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On A380, this is I mean the losses we see currently and the burden we see in our results is coming from things which are not capitalized, related for example to development, continuous development of new versions for customers, continuous support cost. We have significant continuous support effort to keep the fleet flying with our customers. And then finally we have inefficiencies which we have not capitalized and under recovery of fixed cost because the production rate is not at the level we have, I would say, envisaged with the &#x2013; with all the installations and toolings we have. So, that are the main categories. And then breakeven in 2011....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are not giving any guidance for 2011, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Had to try.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now take our last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question comes from Doug Harned from Sanford Bernstein. Please, it's your turn now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I'm interested in the A330 when you talk about it, first question, when you talk about taking rates up on A320, could you talk about what the outlook now looks like for rates on A330 and as part of that particularly the freighter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The A330, this airplane is a very good airplane, it's a good seller. We keep the production rate around 80s which is extremely significant and so freighter version you know that the freight market has been impacted by the crisis but this is slightly &#x2013; is progressively recovering and we will deliver our freight in the next year. And we expect to receive new orders but for that we need to see recovery process of the economies more confirmed I have to say that. The freight market is recovering, but the operators are not increasing their equipment, they are first to fill the present equipment and so that we are not expecting many new orders in 2010 and perhaps in '11 on freighter, but we will deliver the airplane ordered.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then as a second question on the A380, can you talk about where the program stands now? Because whether this is &#x2013; what the issues are you are seeing, what the difficulties are to, in overcoming them? Are we still dealing with things around the digital mock-up? Where does this stand and what's the progress likely to be from a technical standpoint?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the progress in the management of the program and the implementation of the assembly of the airplane are rather significant. And I could &#x2013; I could not have said that last year. I think the second part of this year has seen some result from measure taken at the beginning of the year. We see that the outstanding work per airplane is decreasing. We see that the number of modification in the process is decreasing. We see the efficiency making progress. We are not at the end of our work on it.</p>
          <p>But I think what Airbus has done in 2009 is encouraging and could give new result in 2010 on our capacity to reduce costs for delivering this airplane, it means to reduce the amount of resources we have to put on each airplane to assemble it. We will see and we follow that very carefully at the level of EADS. It's the job of airbus, but we're following that very carefully at the level of EADS. But I have to say for the first time, we have the feeling that we are now progressively back on track. The next target is to come back to the costs forecasted in the program. The learning curve is too high, as you know and we have to progressively to come back to the average costs expected. It will be done in the next years. I don't want to give you any indication on that topic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But are there any specific overwriting issues or is this just a broader &#x2013; you got to do a lot of things better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I could say that it's number of issues we have to solve one by one and it's for that, there is no one main issue blocking something. Its process we have to stabilize. It's the number of modifications in the assembly line we have to reduce and it's &#x2013; this process is engaged in an encouraging way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This closes our conference call for this time. Thank you and good day to all of you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>