<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1537718" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-02-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7857</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Philippe Balducchi</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Thomas Enders</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Harald Wilhelm</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Christian A. Laughlin</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Rob Stallard</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Oliver J. Sleath</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Celine Fornaro</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Plc">David H. Perry</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Ben P. Fidler</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Rupi S. Vig</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co. LLC">Doug Stuart Harned</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies International Ltd.">Sandy J. Morris</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA">Tristan Sanson</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the EADS Full Year 2012 Earnings Conference Call. I am Susana Bolter, the operator for this conference. Please note that for the duration of the presentation, all participants will be in a listen-only mode, and the conference is being recorded. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity to ask questions.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to your hosts, Tom Enders, Harald Wilhelm, and Philippe Balducchi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. This is EADS full year 2012 earning conference call. Tom Enders, our CEO; and Harald Wilhelm, our CFO, will be presenting our results and answering your questions.</p>
          <p>This call is planned to last about an hour-and-a-half. This includes Q&amp;A, which we will conduct after the initial presentation. This call is also webcast. You can access via our homepage where we have set a special banner.</p>
          <p>Playback of this call will be accessible on the website, but there is no dedicated phone replay service. The supporting information package was e-mailed to you earlier this morning. It includes the slides, which we will now walk through, and financial statements.</p>
          <p>Throughout this call, we will be making forward-looking statements. The packages you receive contain a Safe Harbor statement, which applies to this call as well. You should read it carefully. And now, to Tom Enders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Philippe. So, good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Well, 2012 was certainly an interesting and partly even exciting year for EADS, and I think also one of the most important years. Just in passing, we had a major management transition. We tried a big merger project, and we ended up with an agreement on a new governance, new shareholder structure for the company which we believe is very important going forward.</p>
          <p>But on the financials, I think our 2012 financial performance demonstrates pretty good revenue momentum with healthy underlying operating margins as we continue our path towards our target, our ambition of roughly 10% return on sales for 2015. We grew our top line by 15% compared to 2011, and that's entirely due to the commercial momentum in the commercial business.</p>
          <p>We grew the underlying operating margin to 5.2% &#x2013; 5.3% before one-off charges for programs, restructuring, portfolio de-risking, I believe Harald in a few minutes will further elaborate on that. And ladies and gentlemen, we do recognize that our future top-line performance, which is pretty good, must be reinforced by bottom-line improvement. I'd say that's underlying this year and I think that will be a recurring theme for our presentation this morning and we are in a good way here.</p>
          <p>To do this improvement, we are focusing on portfolio de-risking, for instance, in Cassidian, we have taken efficiency measures that should bring long-term returns to the bottom line and also, I should say, medium-term returns to the bottom line and add value to the group. We will also closely monitor the risk-reward ratio or the risk reward balance of new contracts we add to our backlog. We learned some healthy lessons in this field in the past without further elaborating here. And of course, we will continue to focus on our key development programs, in particular, the Airbus A350 XWB to contain &#x2013; to reduce the embedded risks as much as possible.</p>
          <p>And lastly, we will keep enhancing cost avoidance and quality improvement. By the way, we created a major quality initiative &#x2013; group-wide quality initiative last year like we did with program management some years before. So, we'll keep enhancing quality, cost avoidance, particularly on legacy programs, deliver on the commitments of the existing contracts. All these, ladies and gentlemen, I think we can summarize as margin enhancement through strict risk monitoring, cost and quality control.</p>
          <p>We see 2013 as a year in which EADS will take further substantial steps forward across the group, not just in any particular division only, to drive the bottom-line performance and generate higher returns for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Now, if we take a look at 2012 on the next charts here, this is the business overview. I think we demonstrated that we could manage a tough macroeconomic environment and still deliver strong financial results. Neither the Eurozone crisis nor the general sluggish global growth nor our merger attempt, I should say, have impacted our commercial momentum.</p>
          <p>We are well-positioned to capture growth in the commercial market due to pretty good diversification of our backlog. And despite the declining defense environment, our order momentum for defense products across the company remains strong.</p>
          <p>Let me add one sentence here. I've found it quite remarkable compared to just recently the revenues in defense for the group which amount to &#x20AC;12 billion. So, this is not a small defense business, at least number two in Europe.</p>
          <p>That the revenues are stable over last years, 2010, 2011, 2012. You will find in many defense companies, that revenues are shrinking. I think we are in such a position, because we have a healthy product portfolio, a product portfolio of products that customers need even as they cut back defense expenditures due to their mission requirements.</p>
          <p>The 2012 results occurred against the backdrop of what I also believe was a smooth management transition for the company. And the new management team was all actively involved in the turnaround process of the prior years, by the way focusing on execution, significantly improving program management across the group.</p>
          <p>So, while we had a management transition from Louis to me, from me to Fabrice, from Hans Peter Ring to Harald Wilhelm, these are all people that have been working in the group in various positions with a lot of experience before. And I think that you could see that management transition was also smooth across the company and its top management has matured.</p>
          <p>Our financial team in partnership with our operational units has focused quickly on what we believe is our number one priority, that is delivering meaningful increases to our EBIT results in the coming years. And all our divisions are aligned and focused around with flight path to grow margins.</p>
          <p>As we focus on profitability in our corporations, we are currently conducting a strategy review that examines &#x2013; let's put it that way, drivers for future growth across the board and across the board of our portfolio, and we look forward to updating you on strategy later this year.</p>
          <p>I think I said that already publicly, I do intend to or do not intend to close the strategy discussion with the current board. We'll get a new board voted by the extraordinary shareholders assembly on the 27 of March, and it obviously makes much more sense to conduct and to conclude the strategy review with the new board.</p>
          <p>This brings me to the final and very pivotal point for the company of 2012, our change in governance. As announced in December, the old core shareholder pact is being dissolved. A new board of directors, independent directors, directors who have a strong industrial background, I mean, you've seen the list. We have released that to the media some weeks ago, its information.</p>
          <p>Under the proposed new shareholder system, the influence of governance will be fairly limited. We'll be moving to a free float of more than 70%. And as I mentioned, the shareholder assembly end of March is poised to approve the new governance and the proposed board composition, as well as authorize a share buyback of up to 15% of outstanding shares, and Harald Wilhelm will be able to elaborate on the share buyback in a few minutes.</p>
          <p>And the point on the governance, I summarized it in the press conference before, saying we got the governance that was originally designed for a merged BAE-EADS, and now this is the same governance basically but without BAE and it was designed for a normalized company and that is what we are implementing right now. The new shareholding system, ladies and gentlemen, is designed with one thing in mind particularly, namely to allow EADS management to operate this company as a normal company to the best interest of our customers, to maximize its value and to enhance the attractiveness to the shareholders and shareholders, I'd like to emphasize, globally.</p>
          <p>Now, if we come to some of the division business highlights. At the Airbus, we saw our production adjust to a strong demand for our products, i.e., we saw further ramp-up, completing 588 commercial deliveries last year plus an additional 28 military aircraft, tanker and medium light transport aircraft. Anyway, that's a new record at the commercial side of Airbus. We've started delivering the 320 since the end of the year, since December, with the new winglets. We call it sharklets, as you know. And this is one steppingstone towards the A320neo family in a few years.</p>
          <p>350 development is on track for first flight this summer based upon a revised schedule with final assembly line now fully operational. I think it's the third aircraft that is now in assembly. What else? Yeah, power-on of the aircraft, MSN1, is already the case for some time. The latest development is that EASA has certified very important, obviously, the engine, the Trent XWB, just a few days ago, after, by the way, intensive flight testing.</p>
          <p>We have resolved the wing issues on the 380 with repairs ongoing on deployed aircraft, interim fixes as we call them. And we have also not just designed but also tested the so-called final fix and the design modifications for the new production standard. And from early 2014 onwards, we will then have in production the new wings, which will be fully metal &#x2013; full metal jacket, full metal wings.</p>
          <p>The function and reliability testing of the A400M was quite a drama last year, because we had to repeat it due to engine problems. But at the end, it worked out quite well but it led to a slight delay in deliveries from Q1 to Q2. So, we're currently preparing to deliver first A400M to the French Air Force in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Eurocopter, on the commercial side, we've seen very impressive commercial dynamics. The market has particularly endorsed EC130, the new EC145 T2 helicopters. The NH90 has achieved the so-called Step B that paves the way for further delivery ramp-up. And particularly interesting and important and impressive at Eurocopter is the strong role that product support services play in order intake. I think, Harald, that was something like 47% in terms of order intake in 2012.</p>
          <p>At Astrium, important event in the life of our space business with the European Space Council, the ESA Council, I think, it was in November. It was important because in fall, there was some reductions in ESA's budget decided, most of the programs and the bulk of the budget was reconfirmed, which was not a walk in the park given the current fiscal and budgetary environment in Europe. These decisions reaffirm Astrium's place as one of the top player in global space, not only in Europe, and they have also in operational terms, in terms of deliveries, produced seven successful Ariane 5 launches, I think we never had more launches in a year, and nine satellite deliveries.</p>
          <p>Cassidian is delivering very well on its core business. What's the core business of Cassidian? The core business is military aircraft-related products support and services, avionics. Very good margins, also an increase of order intake from 2011 to 2012.</p>
          <p>And that, ladies and gentlemen, in what I think we would all agree to call a challenging business environment, the Cassidian division has restructured under the new management that we put in place in September. Organization is much more simple. As a matter of fact, the new restructuring program is under the headline of simplify.</p>
          <p>And I think that's very important, simplify, not only mean people understand the organization better, it also means be leaner, to take costs out and let all that's essential to focus also that division very much on bottom-line improvement in the coming years. We have decided personnel reductions. You've seen the numbers. And these reductions, the 850 in particular, have resulted in one-off costs that you find in the so-called one-offs that Harald will elaborate on a little more.</p>
          <p>As far as the commercial environment is concerned, I think we have an order intake of more than &#x20AC;100 billion booked in 2012; to be precise, &#x20AC;102.5 billion booked. The military part of Airbus, Airbus Military, Eurocopter, Astrium and Cassidian all recorded year-on-year increases in order intake, and Airbus Commercial under John Leahy's leadership exceeded its order target, booking 914 gross orders for 2012.</p>
          <p>What else can I say here? Well, 2012 orders include 100 320 family aircraft AirAsia and 20 additional 350 and 5 380s for Singapore Airlines, which were all booked in the fourth quarter. So, if there's any uncertainty about where we were booking these in the old year or in 2013, I can confirm that they were booked in 2012.</p>
          <p>Airbus Military has achieved good order intake, particularly for MRTT. India was &#x2013; is a success. Well, I should say we are obviously in discussions, in negotiations with the Indian side. We are the preferred bidder to supply 330 MRTT aircraft.</p>
          <p>Eurocopter, we had 469 helicopters booked in 2012, marking what is the division's third consecutive yearly increase in units ordered. I mentioned already some of the products and the significant level of services in the order intake. We continue to book orders with our defense and public customers, ladies and gentlemen, despite the challenging market environment. This highlights, I mentioned that before already, the attractiveness of our products.</p>
          <p>Astrium achieved a good level of order intake, particularly in services, more than &#x20AC;1 billion, including the Vizada subsidiary that is now fully consolidated in Astrium. Cassidian order intake increased 21% compared to 2011 level. Even though it's still under book-to-bill ratio of 1, it's driven &#x2013; the order intake is driven mainly by very profitable Eurofighter and missile export businesses. You might remember that in December, Oman signed a contract for the purchase of 12 Eurofighter Typhoon aircraft which is, I think, yet to be reflected in the order book.</p>
          <p>EADS' backlog now stands at &#x20AC;566 billion and the commercial backlog of the Airbus stands now at, as we speak, at more than 4,700 aircraft, which is certainly a new industry record. And as you see in the slide, the geographical diversification of the backlog leaves us pretty well positioned to take advantage of different regional growth rates, or I could turn it the other way around and say it is &#x2013; that it shows that we can de-risk our portfolio, because we have not all our eggs in one regional basket, but we are very well positioned particularly in the growth market.</p>
          <p>The backlog coverage is robust in all segments. There's an exception perhaps of A380 where we certainly need to work harder in 2013 to increase order intake. Now, I think, Harald, I stop here and hand over to you. Over to Harald Wilhelm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tom, and good morning to all of you, in particular, the one in the U.S. Now, let's dig a bit into the financials. 2012 has been a year of strong top-line momentum and healthy underlying operating margins. We continued our growth trajectory for revenues, EBIT and EPS before one-off and performed better than expected with respect to the free cash flow generation.</p>
          <p>The revenues increased by 15% compared to a year ago, and that's mainly driven by the higher volume and the more favorable U.S. dollar rates in Airbus Commercial, but as well as the increase in revenues in Eurocopter and in Astrium, which was largely driven by the services business, including the acquisitions of Vector and Vizada in 2011. All in all, they contributed &#x20AC;1.5 billion of revenue in 2012.</p>
          <p>Despite the overall defense environment, defense revenues are stable since 2010 at around &#x20AC;12 billion, and that's thanks to the mix of the series and development programs as well as long-term defense contracts. The EBIT before one-off grew by 68% compared to 2011, up to &#x20AC;3 billion. Again, this was driven by strong underlying performance at Airbus Commercial, as we move towards the targeted next level of performance in Airbus.</p>
          <p>Overall, Eurocopter and Astrium also delivered absolute increases in EBIT before one-off. The EBIT before one-off margin for EADS now stands at 5.3% return on sales in 2012, and that's another major step on our flight path towards 2015. The improvement in underlying operational performance has, of course, contributed also to the bottom line. The EPS before one-off has grown to &#x20AC;2.24 per share, taking into account around 819 million shares outstanding. Year-on-year, this represents an increase of around 61%.</p>
          <p>As anticipated, the free cash flow performance in 2012 before acquisitions was lower than in 2011, however, still significantly positive due to a high level of deliveries and strong cash flow collection in the fourth quarter. Our free cash flow conversion has been impacted by the increase in CapEx as we ramp up on our development and sales programs, predominantly at Airbus and Eurocopter.</p>
          <p>The 2012 performance is an excellent platform for future growth in top and bottom lines, and therefore, providing the means to continue investments in our future while managing our cash and providing attractive returns to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>On page 9, you can see that we achieved these improvements without compromising on the investments in our future. As anticipated, the self-funded R&amp;D remains stable from 2011 to 2012, with a major focus on development programs, in particular A350 and in Eurocopter.</p>
          <p>The self-funded R&amp;D remained stable at a plateau of around &#x20AC;3 billion after taking into account that around &#x20AC;370 million of A350 development costs have been capitalized under IAS 38. Self-funded R&amp;D as a percentage of revenues has reduced however overall.</p>
          <p>The level of CapEx increased to a peak of &#x20AC;3.3 billion reflecting the ramp-up in the development and the series programs as we build the capacity for future volume driven top- and bottom-line growth. That also includes the capitalized R&amp;D under IAS 38 I just mentioned before.</p>
          <p>Despite the strong growth in revenues, head count is growing at a much slower rate of just about 5%, reflecting the structural make-or-buy nature of our business and our overall efficiency measures and gains.</p>
          <p>And final point on that slide I'd like to emphasize, we continue very marginal customer financing gross exposure. Despite the record level of commercial deliveries, the EADS exposure is stable. It was at 2011 level, and has fallen significantly as a proportion of revenues. That demonstrates ongoing support of our products and continued appetite for asset-backed financing despite the macroeconomic issues.</p>
          <p>On to page 10, to the one-offs. We have gone through the improvement of the underlying of the business. However, &#x20AC;820 million of one-off charges had been booked during 2012, which has reduced the overall bottom-line growth significantly. That slide focus on these as well as on the EPS performance.</p>
          <p>On the other side, &#x20AC;522 million of the charges were booked all in all in 2012. As anticipated, &#x20AC;251 million were booked on A380-related cost for the wing rib repair. The A350 charge of &#x20AC;124 million to reflect the latest program update is unchanged since the H1. We are making good progress, but the program remains challenging and there is no room left in the schedule. The charges for the Hawker Beechcraft closure of &#x20AC;76 million was already booked in the third quarter, and the negative dollar mismatch and balance sheet revaluation of &#x20AC;71 million is also reflected here in Q4.</p>
          <p>At Eurocopter, the ongoing negotiation of certain contracts to governmental customer has resulted in a charge of &#x20AC;100 million booked in the fourth quarter. And at Cassidian, &#x20AC;198 million of charges were also booked in the fourth quarter to reflect restructuring costs in line with the business transformation, as well as a charge in relation to risk assessment of various contracts, in particular, in the secured systems and solution business. The full detail of one-off adjustments in the P&amp;L is provided in the annex.</p>
          <p>In the 2012 interest result, we saw a deterioration which is mainly due to a lower interest income and that is due to &#x2013; or the function of or due to the high quality of our investments in 2012 on which we do not compromise. The 2011 interest result, as a reminder, benefited from a positive one-time release of &#x20AC;120 million due to the termination of the A340 program. The other financial result includes an improved impact from the foreign exchange revaluation compared to 2011. This line also includes the unwinding of the discounted provisions.</p>
          <p>The tax rate for the year is 27%, which is lower than expected due to a positive impact from reassessment of impaired tax loss carry-forwards. Despite the exceptional charges booked in 2012, EBIT increased by 29% and net income by 19%. The reported EPS has grown by more than 18% to &#x20AC;1.50. This is a basis on which the 2012 dividend will be paid. We are fully committed to aligning the underlying operational performance improvement to the actual performance improvement as we look forward.</p>
          <p>Slide 11 shows the evolution of the hedge book between end 2011 and 2012. You can see how we have taken advantage of the more favorable U.S. dollar rate environment to benefit the average hedge rate in the book, supporting our future profitability increase. During 2012, we accelerated our hedging speed and activity and implemented more than $30 billion of new hedges at an average of $1.30. 2013 exposure is fully covered and the open exposure from 2014 to 2016 has significantly reduced at more attractive rates, which increases EADS resilience against FX fluctuations in the near to medium term.</p>
          <p>During 2012, at the same time, $22 billion matured at an average of $1.36. And therefore, the hedge book increased from $75 billion end of 2011, to $84 billion by the end of 2012. At the end of 2012, the mark-to-market of the hedge book was slightly negative at around minus &#x20AC;500 million before tax, compared to negative of &#x20AC;2.4 billion a year before. That improvement is mainly driven by the favorable evolution of the hedge rates secured in the portfolio.</p>
          <p>On the cash side, page 12, gross cash from operations have been very strong and reflects the underlying performance in the year. The free cash flow before acquisitions of almost &#x20AC;1.5 billion in 2012 exceeded the expectations. A traditional end of year seasonal payment pattern has been very strong, but not by chance if we may say, we pushed hard for that.</p>
          <p>It resulted in a strong positive swing in the fourth quarter working capital, thanks to the high delivery performance and stream of advances and receipts from our commercial and government customers. The CapEx reached &#x20AC;3.3 billion, as I mentioned already before, in the year, reflecting the investments in our future growth while customer financing support remained at a very low level in 2012 net.</p>
          <p>We finished 2012 with a net cash position. I think it's the new record high again of &#x20AC;12.3 billion after dividend payment of &#x20AC;370 million in 2012 and the cash contribution to pension assets of around &#x20AC;850 million. The gross cash balance at the end of 2012 is more than &#x20AC;17 billion, and we have an additional credit facility of &#x20AC;3 billion. The strength of our company and our access to debt markets continues to be acknowledged by the rating agencies and respective ratings.</p>
          <p>A fundamental element of our financial strategy has been to ensure as strong as possible liquidity position to fund the investments while preserving the flexibility to return value to our shareholders. Our policy to remain in a strong liquidity position will remain unchanged even after taking into account our proposal of the buyback of up to 15%.</p>
          <p>Now, let's have a look at the divisions. On Airbus, slide 14, you can see that the operational performance was strong both on Commercial and the Military side. At Airbus Commercial, strong revenue increase of around 19% is driven by the record level of deliveries achieved in the year, including 30 A380s, 585 deliveries were booked with revenue recognition and another three were placed under operating lease. The revenues also benefited from a favorable U.S. dollar rate. And in Airbus Commercial EBIT before one-off, the improvement significantly compared to 2011, and it benefits from the favorable volume and pricing net of escalation. It also includes an appreciation of the U.S. dollar rate over the maturing hedges in 2012 that were better by around $0.02 compared to 2011.</p>
          <p>I've already talked to you about the one-off charges mainly for the programs reflected in the reported EBIT during the year, which weigh on the overall earnings increase at the division. In Airbus Military, revenues decreased by almost 15% to 2011 despite stable deliveries, and that's driven by lower revenues on A400M, as well as on the tankers. However, the strong improvement in EBIT in Airbus Military comes from a more favorable delivery mix with margin improvements from more maturing programs.</p>
          <p>In Eurocopter, revenues grew 16% year-over-year, and this despite lower helicopter deliveries in particular for the ones &#x2013; EC135 and Ecureuil. The revenue increase was driven mainly by higher repair and overall support activities and the full-year inclusion of the Vector Aerospace business consolidation. Higher NH90 and also Super Puma revenues also contributed to that increase.</p>
          <p>The root cause for the recent Ecureuil incident has been identified, and a program is in place to implement a retrofit approved by EASA. Eurocopter continues as well to work in close collaboration with investigation authorities on further identifying and explaining the root cause of Super Puma incident. The EBIT before one-off increased by almost 10% year-on-year, and that reflects the revenue mix and an increase in R&amp;D expenses as expected. The EBIT includes a charge of &#x20AC;100 million in the fourth quarter as explained already before.</p>
          <p>Astrium, slide 16, revenues went up by 17% year-on-year driven by growth in services and thanks to the Vizada contribution. 2012 revenues reflect the strong execution performance, what Tom already mentioned earlier, with nine Astrium-built satellites and seven Ariane 5 launches.</p>
          <p>The EBIT before one-off improved by more than 7% compared to 2011 and the division is seeing efficiency and productivity gains coming through the operational performance from the Agile transformation program. However, higher investment in research and development and globalization efforts as well as some integration costs for Vizada have weighted on the operating margin year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Cassidian, slide 17, if we look at the underlying performance in 2012, revenues were stable compared to 2011, but the EBIT before one-off was below as expected due to investments in globalization and transformation despite the lower R&amp;D expenses. The comprehensive business review by the new management team has now been concluded and resulted in the &#x20AC;198 million charges that we explained earlier. Cassidian now has a healthy platform to deliver improving margins on that basis.</p>
          <p>In the other businesses, page 18, we see revenue increase compared to 2011 in EADS North America and ATR. The 2012 EBIT before one-off, however, was stable compared to 2011 level and that's due to less favorable revenue mix. Going forward, due to the business proximity, both ATR and Sogerma will be reported in the Airbus division.</p>
          <p>Now, Tom, back to you for the dividend and the guidance statement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Harald. Ladies and gentlemen, first to the dividend, in line with the progress we made in 2012, the EADS Board of Directors is proposing an increased dividend of &#x20AC;0.60 to the Annual General Meeting of shareholders, which should happen in May.</p>
          <p>And as we already said, we also intend to buy back up to 15% of our shares to be authorized by the extraordinary meeting with shareholders on the 27 of March. Sorry for the confusion. We hope that we won't make that a recurring thing in the company that we have more than one shareholder meeting during the year, but this year, it is essential.</p>
          <p>Now, the guidance for 2013, let me go through this in some more detail. As you see, as the basis for the 2013 guidance, we do expect at this point that the world economy, air traffic to grow in line with the independent forecast, which I think you all know, and we assume no major disruption due to debt crisis, wars and what have you.</p>
          <p>So, in 2013, the new commercial orders or the gross commercial aircraft orders should be, again, clearly above the number of deliveries, even before we ramp up deliveries, and should be in the range of 700-plus aircraft. That's one assumption.</p>
          <p>The other is that Airbus delivers between 600 and 610 commercial aircraft in 2013. Due to lower 380 deliveries, however, and assuming an exchange rate of &#x20AC;1 to $1.35, EADS revenues should see only moderate growth in 2013. So, we'll take a bit of a break, but we do estimate, Harald, that in 2014-2015, the momentum will increase again.</p>
          <p>We stretch the 2012 the margin improvement, the underlying margin improvement in 2013. We target an EBIT before one-off of &#x20AC;3.5 billion and then earnings per share before one-off of around &#x20AC;2.50. Again, this is prior to the proposed share buyback.</p>
          <p>If we exclude the well-known wing rib feet impact of the A380 program in 2013, which by the way should be and that's already very predictable at around &#x20AC;85 million, because it's based on the 25 deliveries that we plan. As we go forward from today's point of view, the one-offs in 2013 should be limited to potential charges of the A350 program and foreign exchange effects linked to, how do you call that, Harald, PDP mismatch and balance sheet revaluation.</p>
          <p>I have to &#x2013; I mean, Harald said before, I have to underline here obviously, the Airbus A350 program remains challenging, particularly at this juncture, but we're preparing for the first bird taking to the skies and then testing, certification, preparation of first deliveries. Any schedule change now could lead to an increasingly higher impact on provisions. The rather inexpensive way of de-risking the program, obviously, that was more in the past as we approach deliveries, coming closer to deliveries, charges, if there were any further schedule change, would be increasingly higher.</p>
          <p>We aim at a free cash flow breakeven after customer financing and before acquisitions in 2013. Breakeven only because we still think that we have a lot of burdens in 2013 in terms of capital employed, inventory increasing, for instance, on the 350 program and so on. But that after 2014, basically, also, the cash flow should be higher. I know, Harald, we are not give any guidance beyond 2013, but this is just a perspective.</p>
          <p>What else? Conclusion part, conclusion chart. Well, I think the result in 2012 is good. But on the other hand, we certainly do recognize that our top-line performance must be further reinforced by bottom-line improvements. The main goal now really is focused on that. It means we focus on the reported EBIT. We expect the &#x2013; as I said before, the so-called one-offs or the exceptionals to significantly reduce in 2013. Our primary focus is on program execution across the group. This goes for development programs, 350 mentioned. It also means delivering on commitments to all our commercial, military, and public customers. We need to address risk, notably, commercial supply chain and operation risks via a very active enterprise risk management.</p>
          <p>The goal is to deliver improvements to the bottom line results along with addressing one-off costs. We have aligned each division around lean practices, which enable continued margin growth. I think this is important to understand, we're not just relying on bottom line growth in Airbus. We have clear plans in place and every confidence at this point that we can execute these plans for further profitability increase in all other divisions as well.</p>
          <p>I think we said it earlier already, we are still conducting our strategy review. We look forward to updating you later this year after discussion with an approval &#x2013; hopefully an approval by the new board. It doesn't make any sense for me to conclude the strategy review with the old board. Our board as of end of March after the EGM will be roughly 50% renewed, and this is when we will continue with our strategy discussion.</p>
          <p>And in the meantime, I'd like to underline, in case there is some of you who are afraid of this after what you experienced with us in 2012, that we will not embark on any major M&amp;A activity.</p>
          <p>We're looking forward to working with the new board and governance structure. And this structure, in my humble view, ladies and gentlemen, is one which should reassure all investors of our focus on value creation as the standard for business decisions at the EADS Group. In addition, as you can see with our dividend proposal and also our share buyback project, EADS can and will deliver substantial return to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>So, all in all, I think we can be quite satisfied with what we have achieved in 2012. Rest reassured that we are mindful that more work needs to be done, but we are not yet there. It's a step on path to higher profitability, benchmark profitability. So, we need to do more to increase our performance. That next-level performance is our focus starting with 2013.</p>
          <p>I think this is long enough, extensive enough. We stop here, and over to you again, Philippe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, Tom. Thank you, Harald. So, we will now start our Q&amp;A time. Please introduce yourself and your company when asking a question. Please also limit yourself to two questions at a time. And also, as usual, please remember to speak clearly and slowly in order to help all participants and, in particular, ourselves understand your questions.</p>
          <p>So, Laura, please go ahead and explain the procedure for the participants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Mr. Christian Laughlin from Barclays. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. This is Christian Laughlin from Barclays. Just two questions, please. Number one, can you provide some color on pricing in general? And A320ceo in particular, what sort of directional trends are you seeing?</p>
          <p>And number two, can you elaborate a bit on the decision to revert to nicad batteries for the A350, and what are the risks and benefits of making this trade-off, I guess, around weight and technology as well? And kind of a follow-on to that, does &#x2013; if Boeing fixes the problems soon with lithium and you stick with nicad, is there some sort of big performance differential you'll see perpetuate between A350 and 787?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Christian, I'll take the first one on the pricing. Overall, I mean, we're satisfied with the pricing level which we could see in the order intake in 2012. As your question is particularly focused on the ceo, you know from the Global Investor Forum, I think we alluded that the remaining slots to be sold is a pretty remote number, and since then it came down, so it is below 300 from today's point of view.</p>
          <p>And we want to sell that at a reasonable price and margin. However, I have to say that some behavior we've seen in the marketplace right now does not suggest to be completely rational given the large order book, I think, both players have. We watch it. We might react on a case-by-case. I think the impact might not be large as we're talking a remote number of deliveries and we definitely will not move into what some might call price war here. And globally, that has not applied to the neo where we saw healthy pricing in 2012 where we've got the premium again as we told you in 2011, and that sits at healthy pricing level. However, I think also on the neo, I mean Boeing still needs to catch up in terms of numbers since launch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the famous battery question, I guess we're having a lot of battery experts in the industry and then the analyst community these days. That decision was taken out of prudence. I think we all know that the root causes for the events on the 787 &#x2013; the batteries of the 787 to the day remains unknown. We have always had a Plan B, because we knew that was new technology, lithium-ion technology, not without challenges.</p>
          <p>And I think we owe it to our customers obviously, but like in other areas, we de-risk our program as much as we can. And there's no doubt, we have plenty of challenges ahead of us. We're basically two years behind the 787. Flight testing is only starting soon and so on and so on, but if there are areas where we can de-risk the program, we do it. That's our obligation with respect to customers and also obviously the shareholders. And that is why we've taken this decision.</p>
          <p>In terms of burden, what I can say, I mean, the weight difference is something like 60 kilograms. So, it is one passenger I mean, I think, that is &#x2013; the risk reward ratio here, I think, is certainly intact. Nickel-cadmium batteries are well proven in the industry. I think we can &#x2013; we know we can integrate them and we certainly do not exclude that we will &#x2013; if the technology matures, if root causes are known, if corrective actions have been taken, that we will put the lithium-ion batteries on the 350 somewhere in the future. We'll fly more some of our test aircraft. I mean, our guys, our engineers are confident at this point that these batteries are safe. They are not the same batteries. It's not the same supplier. It's a different chemistry. It's a different design. The battery units are better spaced and so on and so on. But nevertheless, again, this is de-risking the program. This is why we've taken the decision, and I think quite a few airlines have commended us on this decision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Robert Stallard from Royal Bank of Canada. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. First question is on Airbus on the A350, Fabrice commented in December that a couple of your suppliers were still giving you some concerns, particularly Spirit. I'm just wondering if you could give us an update on any progress that's been made there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on Spirit, I mean, we're working very closely with them. We have deployed quite a few people to support them. Also, over in the United States at Kingston on the latest report, I've seen this battery situation is somewhat improving. Harald, do you have additional on that? I think that's the situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are there any other suppliers that are on your sort of watch list for causing risk?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, at that stage of a program, by the way, not just in development programs, also in previous programs, we always had lists and there's more than one name on these lists of the suppliers that present us with challenges. So, no different here on the A350, but I think so far, we've been quite successful in working with these suppliers to reduce the risk and to restore confidence in their timely supply and in the quality of their supply.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then secondly, Harald, obviously a significant increase in the dividend this year. I was wondering if there's a metric that you're looking to, maybe as a percentage of earnings or free cash flow, as your dividend payout going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we commented that we were committed to an increase of shareholder return. I mean from the payout ratio of 35% in 2011, so now with that proposal to the AGM made by the board, we're stepping up to the 40%. I think &#x2013; I mean, this is a good benchmark number in this sector, but also in the industry. And I mean the basis for the dividend payment, this is clear recommendation from Tom and myself to the board and fully supported is the reported EPS.</p>
          <p>And as we move forward, I mean for sure, we want to grow not just the EPS before one-off but put a lot of emphasis on reported EPS. And that growth in the EPS combined with dividend policy which is yet to be defined by the new board, so don't take that as a policy statement here. I mean, this is the dividend payout ratio for 2012. However, I think that gives a very attractive return to shareholders in terms of the EPS growth and DPS growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Oliver Sleath from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Morning, gentlemen. Just two questions, please. Firstly, can you just elaborate a little on the financing environment that you're looking for 2013, just given the export credit rules tightening, if there is any pressure from that, and what proportion of Airbus deliveries for 2013 are now financed?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, I wondered if you can just quantify the pricing improvement roughly that you're expecting in A320 and A330 deliveries in 2013 and 2014? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the financing conditions, I mean you could see 2012. I mean, the level of support we had to do was very, very remote. I mean, that I think is a strong demonstration that the market is intact, you're right. I mean, the terms and conditions for ECA financing in 2013 are tightening up. The loan-to-value ratio goes down and the margins go up.</p>
          <p>However, still we see that I mean the ECA financing for 2013 will be at the level of 2012, around 25%. And I mean let's bear in mind the overall still historically lower interest rate level. I mean, we're watching the delivery situation, the financing situation of the deliveries, as you know, in our watchtower process. I don't have any particular concern for the financing of aircraft in 2013.</p>
          <p>I mean, one exceptional thing in 2013, you might not be surprised by that, but I mean with American coming out of the chapter 11 and the announcement of merger, we'll start delivering aircraft and some of them are under operating lease. So, that's something we'll work upon in 2013, but I'm sure there's going to be good market appetite also for these.</p>
          <p>And on your second question on the pricing evolution in delivery year-on-year, clearly, I think we saw a pretty strong pricing momentum from 2011 to 2012. I see it a bit lower from 2012 to 2013, and let's talk about 2014 when it comes to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Ms. Celine Fornaro from Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, everyone. Two questions, if I may. The first one would be on the A350. If I could just comment on the language where you say there is no room left in the schedule. It's clearly stated in the press release. That's pretty strong wording. And we know that there are still challenges with Spirit. The engine certification was slightly later than expected. Also, you have the battery switch. I mean, how should we think about all this and why not booking the delay now as you have the opportunity with this battery switch rather than phrasing all this very doom and gloom on the 350 program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Celine, Tom speaking. I think this company has a track record, at least in the last five years or so, that we are very transparent with our challenges. And this is just a state that a development program of that magnitude, of that size is, obviously, not over the hill but is still facing a lot of challenges, a lot of &#x2013; certainly, at this point, unspecified challenges.</p>
          <p>I think we're doing well so far, but little delays on engine certification is really not significant. We do not expect, by the way, a delay from the change of batteries for the aircraft, which we deliver to our customers. This is why &#x2013; exactly why we've taken the decision right now in order not to impact the schedule with all the incertitudes and uncertainties around the battery question.</p>
          <p>So, no, there is nothing specific at this point. We're not hiding anything, and otherwise rest assured, we would certainly have taken additional provisions. We just think we owe it to you and we owe it to the shareholders to be very clear about that. And both of us who know the industry know that a program like that remains risky until even after delivery up to the ramp-up phase and this is what we are highlighting here.</p>
          <p>And as you know, we've de-risked the program quite successfully over the years. We've learned lessons from previous mistakes we've made on the 380. We have taken certainly lessons also from mistakes that a competitor has made, the recent switch of batteries is just one example. So, now overall, we feel pretty good with the program, but we know that additional delays could happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Tom. That's very clear. And my second question would be on Cassidian, and how do we think about the charge that was related to the portfolio so the contracts in there, and if we can be assured that there's been a proper review on each program within the business and there shouldn't be any more provisions to difficult contracts or difficult pricing on any other contracts are there, so that it really has been a cleanup from that perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, the 850 people, the concurrent charge, that's been one of the first decisions that the new management has been taken. And by the way, it's a proactive decision to improve the bottom line even if the top line is flat or might even shrink in the years to come, who knows exactly. The main business in Cassidian, I mean, it's a little bit like the 320, 330 business in Airbus, it is the bread-and-butter business. The military aircraft business, the missile business, the related product support and avionics business is very healthy, is having very good margins.</p>
          <p>We are reviewing and the new management under Bernhard Gerwert is reviewing the other business areas, particularly the so-called integrated large systems business. And we have taken action here already and charges are partly to cover that going forward. And I think the charges you see, the extraordinary charges in 2012, to the best of our estimates at this point cover the difficult spots or the loss-making business in Cassidian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. David Perry from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. Good morning, gentlemen. Can I just say first thanks for the much improved presentation; that's much appreciated. It's much easier to follow the numbers. My question is this, the share buyback of up to 15%, I know it needs to be ratified by the EGM so you may be limited on what you can say, but given the share price move since you made the announcement, do you still think you could be close to the full 15%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David, first of all, for the comment and I see the IR team smiling. They did hard work, I think, to improve the focus of the messages. So, thanks for that. On the share buyback, as you say, <mark type="ph" /> I mean the (1:03:58) EGM to authorize the share buyback of 15% &#x2013; up to 15% as such. And if I may complement, it is then up to the new board to decide finally on the terms and the conditions and the process and the timing of that share buyback. Clearly, we will push hard for that decision to be looked upon as quickly as possible, but it can by construction only happen after the 27th of March.</p>
          <p>I mean, how do we look into that? I mean, from a substance point of view, clearly when we announced it in December, market terms and conditions were a bit different, &#x20AC;26.7, if my memory is correct. This morning, I think we are &#x20AC;36 and beyond. So, we're happy about that, but I mean, as for any other investment, you factor that into account. But let me say other than just the recent share price evolution, for sure, we need to balance out that all other, I would say, stakeholders are aligned in terms of what we are doing.</p>
          <p>So, just to share a bit the reflections which we have in these days, I mean, for sure the equity side would wish us I assume to go ahead with the full 15%. I take that as an assumption for granted. But I think we also need to watch out that we're not losing the credit side. I'm not concerned about that, but rather than the hard metrics, I think it's also important that we convey a message that we continue a sound and cautious financial policy. And these factors, I think, we need to lean upon, I mean, in the weeks to come, as I said before, with the new board and then come to conclusion.</p>
          <p>I mean, what is the appropriate number, what's the appropriate price? What is the appropriate process and timing for it? And that will, I think, size the total envelope of the share buyback. Is it &#x20AC;3 billion, is it &#x20AC;4 billion or whatever the number is, it will be? One thing, Tom, under your control, I think we can say even so, we saw a very strong share price movement over the last weeks and months now, we are committed to the share buyback of up to 15%. We're not putting that aside, and we'll bring that for attention and decision of the new board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. I think I speak for all of us on the phone probably that we'd like to see the full 15%. Can I just ask one more follow-up question? You paid much more into the pension in cash than I was expecting. Is that a one-off or is that a new run rate, the &#x20AC;856 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean that's about say &#x20AC;300 million above the historical run rate, if I may say. What did we do here? I mean, in a nutshell, we looked at the entities which are so to say non-cash-generating units, and that's typically chiefly headquarters, if I may say. And so we took opportunity of the financial flexibility to fund that in 2012, and therefore, the gap is funded for headquarters. Chiefly, that's what it is. And therefore, I don't see that as a recurring item moving forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Ben Fidler from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. Couple of questions. Firstly, just a follow-up on the buyback, I'm still a little bit confused about the message you're trying to get across in that Harald, you mentioned that the new board may well define whether the number is &#x20AC;3 billion or &#x20AC;4 billion. I mean, is the number that the board decides going to be a billion-euro number or a percentage number?</p>
          <p>And the second one is just one on timing around that buyback. Will the buyback commence post the EGM and the board approving it or will you wait for Lagard&#xE8;re and Daimler sell-down to actually kick-start the process? I think I've got a question on A350 which I'll come back on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I may say, I think we should not narrow down, I mean, the options for the new board and in particular new members coming to the board by giving too many thoughts at that stage. But in terms of limiting factor, I mean, I rather see it, I mean, the size rather than a share price number, if that answers your question. And in terms of the timing, I think we will look on the timing purely from the point of view what is good for the company and then Lagard&#xE8;re, I mean, who is first will decide what they're going to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. On A350, with no room left in the schedule, I guess, the question is really around what in your view is the biggest risk at this juncture? Is the biggest risk in the next few months coming up to first flight? Or do you see the bigger risks after first flight, during that flight test program, during the process of redesigning and change of battery technology, the production ramp-up, et cetera? At which phase in your view at the moment do you see the greatest risks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, once again, Ben, I mean, the battery issue is a de-risking measure. It's not a measure that should add additional risk to the program. But I speak very frankly and openly, I mean, my experience tells me that it is very hard to predict at this juncture whether you're over the hilltop or whether you can still hit some severe roadblocks. I mean, if you look at the 380, if you look at 787, you will find no particular pattern.</p>
          <p>You take a couple of other programs and look at the issues they've ran into, you will find that it's the unexpected that hits you quite frequently. Now, this is not to &#x2013; I don't want to spread gloom and doom around the program, certainly not. I'm very happy to see that we learned essential lessons from previous programs and particularly the final assembly is proceeding rather smoothly.</p>
          <p>Yes, there are some supply chain issues, but I would say that program certainly look particularly at the ramp-up phase. I mean, the ramp-up of the program like that with the high carbon fiber content in particular, this is certainly a challenge. Not one that is &#x2013; I mean, not a challenge that is insurmountable but here we &#x2013; let's put it that way, it ain't over until it's over. And it's only when we are in cruise mode in production, and this is still a few years off, as you all know, then you can say, yes, we've made it.</p>
          <p>So, we are vigilant. We are prudent. We burned our fingers in many ways on the 380 and on other programs. We're watching what the competition is doing. And so far, I think it's &#x2013; given the challenges on this program, it's going pretty well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And then maybe a final question, if I could just squeeze a quick one in. Airbus Military saw a significantly higher level of profitability in 2012 than I was expecting. You talked about the higher maturity of the programs, et cetera. This sort of high-double-digit level of EBIT, <mark type="ph" /> &#x20AC;98 (1:12:30) million, is this sustainable or is it a little bit of a one-off in 2012 and we shouldn't think about that number being sustainable going forwards?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben, if that would not be sustainable, we would not &#x2013; we would report it as one-off. No, I mean, Airbus Military, I think despite all of the challenges on the A400M is, I think, on the medium and light business a great job. The tankers, as you know, are still in the early phase of deliveries. We had a bit less in 2012 than in 2011. 2011, we delivered a lot of stuff to Australia, 2012, a bit less. So, you remember the &#x2013; one of the boom incident we had late in the year, that caused a bit of setback on that. But the underlying business on the medium and the light is providing very healthy and sound margins. There is aerostructure business in there, I mean, the same thing. And Domingo Ure&#xF1;a &#x2013; I mean, you will not be surprised, I mean, being &#x2013; having been the Power8 Chief before, is pushing Airbus Military hard to improve year-on-year performance. So, I'd rather see that as sustainable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ben. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Rupinder Vig from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning, everyone. Two questions, please. One, just around working capital and cash. Harald, in your guidance for 2013, could you just give us an idea of what you think about working capital? Obviously, if I look at 2012, you did very well at managing working capital given the things going on in the business. So, what's the view around 2013 to get to your kind of breakeven guidance there?</p>
          <p>And then, second question, just around the A380, with the resolution of the wings and the permanent approval upcoming, how do you feel about your guidance for a book-to-bill of one on the A380 this year? I mean obviously you've had got a good start in terms of order flow in general, but are you still happy with the book-to-bill of one or could we perhaps even more once we get comfortable that all the A380 issues are resolved? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rupi. I mean, on the cash flow 2013, I mean clearly the improvement in EBIT will translate also into significant improvement in the operating cash flow. However, in 2013, let me highlight a few elements why we see the FCF at a breakeven level. I mean, continued investment into the ramp-up of the programs, I mean, on the Airbus side as well as on Eurocopter side.</p>
          <p>We are starting the industrialization phase of the 350, which means more of the flight-test aircraft nearing completion. You will not be surprised that this is expensive stuff and that's what comes into the CapEx. But next to that and beginning of the industrial aircraft, either ones which will be delivered than later, I mean, 2014 and beyond.</p>
          <p>At the same time, A400M is still structurally in underfunding situation. The loss-making contract provisions, so that gets consumed unfortunately without the same level of cash inflow, but as well working capital buildup on the A400M as we start the deliveries in 2013 for the four aircraft and then ramp up further in 2014.</p>
          <p>And last but not the least, let me say on 380 side, the bitter &#x2013; the unfortunate thing is that 2013, we're going down to the 25. However, we plan to go up, 30 say, 30, for 2014, and then the working capital investment for these 2014 deliveries need to be done in 2013. So, that weighs as well on cash flow a lot. And you know what the number is per aircraft so take that times 5 so it gives you very quickly a sizeable number.</p>
          <p>We will push it hard as I think we demonstrated throughout 2012, but that's what I see right now. And at that stage, I also would like to caution a bit about the phasing of the cash flow in 2013. The phasing of the 380 deliveries, I mean, the 25 is again more back-loaded. And overall, also, the phasing of the other stuff is more back, so probably we'll see cash flow evolution I hope a bit better over 2012. That would be good for all of our nerves, I think. But in principle, I mean, the profile will be probably rather cash flow negative in the early quarters, I mean, throughout summer and then start to recover towards the end of the year.</p>
          <p>On the 380, I mean, comfort on the book-to-bill. I mean, John had a target, I think, for 2012 of 30, which we obviously missed. So, the book-to-bill, I mean, on 2013 is a bit lower but still challenging, I would say. But clearly, we need to get some orders. I mean, here, I'm totally transparent with all of you. We know that the 2015 breakeven target is going with 30 aircraft to be secured. And here, we still need to complete some bookings. And I mean, time is getting shorter to get that done, it's not 25 which we have to secure for 2015. This is obvious. But, I mean, there are slots open. So, we need to get them into the order book pretty soon in 2013, and then make sure that the flow thereafter is also sustainable at a rate of 30. And in the current context still, I mean, in particular, in Europe, in the CapEx situation does not &#x2013; or the financial situation does not allow for a lot of CapEx flexibility among some of the key airlines, as you know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rest assured that Fabrice and John are working and the teams are working hard on that, how to get the sales up again, and certainly the wing rib problem has not added to the reputation of the aircraft. So, we have to rebuild the reputation. I think we have a good chance to succeed looking at the very positive comments of most of the airlines who are operating the 380 now, and we have to focus particularly, I would say, on the Asian markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Doug Harned. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First question for Tom, you've come a long way here getting to the new governance structure, and I think this is a great achievement, but at this stage, when you look forward, how do you see decision making as different? And that's in terms of how you think about operations, investment, cash deployment, how will it be different with less government influence?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, I'd like to say, Doug, that it's sometimes the myth around EADS that the governments have been pulling the strings. That is certainly not true, and I think you know that government interference has been very rare in the last 12, 13 years that I'm at the top management of EADS. But I think there was a possibility particularly with a new government coming in, I'm talking about the German government, that the governance could go in the wrong direction, that we would have a shareholder pact with operational influence and operational levers between governments.</p>
          <p>Now that we have avoided and the governments wisely have agreed not to press for operational influence, to be content with largely a shareholder and investor position with some limited rights, golden share like rights. I have to say that we have been already very much supported in running the company as normal as possible in recent years, particularly by the independent directors who are really the backbone of the present board.</p>
          <p>And certainly, if we look forward to the board composition and you've seen the names, independent people with strong industrial experience that working with this board, if anything, it will improve the situation to run the company like a normal one. And I think it's important, I guess, for investors to see very clearly now that with this government &#x2013; governance, there will be no undue government interference.</p>
          <p>Now I separate that, Doug, from the question of government influence. In our industry, in the aerospace and defense industry, there will always be government influence. You have strong government influence in the U.S. You have it in the UK. I think I gave the example in the Global Investor Forum in London that if a major U.S. aerospace company wanted to merge with another major U.S. aerospace company, it would certainly not just to go ahead without consulting the government. They would consult with the Pentagon, with the White House, with the Congress, et cetera. That kind of influence due to customer position, due to regulatory powers in government and so on will always be there. No different for us in the new company. But the important thing is that we have been successful at splitting shareholding from operational decision-making or operational interference in the new governance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So are there specific areas where &#x2013; and I understand there's always going to be government influence at some level. But are there specific areas, say, around operations, that you may be able to think of differently now than you would have before with the old structure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know. I think you will see that also in the financial figure. You might see that in the dividend policy and the share buyback and stuff like that, that for reasons were not really seriously considered in the past. I think you see already first signs of more freedom of maneuver of the management to lead this company and to emphasize financial parameters in the interest of inventors and the company, of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, second question on the A330, as you look forward on that program, you've been planning at 10 a month. You've looked at 11. I know the Chinese have been an issue around that. How does the backlog look here right now in terms of how far out you can support that 10 a month, could you go to 11 still?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the backlog is still almost or even over three years, as far as I remember, the last time I checked, so that's pretty considerable. Time and again, Doug, we have erred on the upsides of this program and I'm sometimes teasing my colleague John Leahy about his many predictions about the imminent demise of the 330 program. Fortunately, we've been wrong about that time and again, and just in recent years, we felt a bit more bullish about that to even increase the ramp-up. It's a fine aircraft. We'll make it even better with the new light variant, should be very attractive even with the 787, even with the 350 on certain routes. And I'm very happy we have a successful aircraft in our series production and will remain there for quite some years to come, that's for sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Sandy Morris from Jefferies. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning, everyone. Here you go changing the presentation totally confused me this morning. Two quick questions. One, is 25 A380 deliveries this year better, worse or neutral for profits or losses on that program relative to 2012, so did those fewer deliveries really move it up or down?</p>
          <p>And the second thing is I know you're recruiting labor in Airbus and I know that many of your suppliers are incurring start-up costs on A350. Will you be carrying significant non-series cost overhead on A350 through 2013? Thank you very much. And I'll tell you what I think about buybacks over a drink.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sandy, hi. Now, you depressed us altogether here, but okay, we'll deal with that. On the 25 delivery, the 380, how do we look into that. I mean if you put the wing rib issue aside in 2012 and in 2013, I would say that I mean despite the lower number of deliveries in 2013, we're still making some progress, I mean, from 2012 to 2013, I mean, for sure, not necessarily on volume leverage, but I think we'll continue effort the cost side on the RC and the NRC side. I mean the real step-change then on the 380 towards the breakeven is kicking in in 2014 and 2015. That will be really the decisive two years to get to the breakeven.</p>
          <p>With regard to A350 start-up costs, yes, indeed, I mean according to our accounting rules and IFRS accounting rules, we start to incur cost on the 350 outside in the pure RCs and for development aircraft and the first series aircraft. I mean this is to prepare for the ramp up. It is &#x2013; I mean all of the production facilities which got installed and which are not yet running at the capacity they're designed for. And I think as a matter of prudent and conservative financial policy, we're charging that to the P&amp;L in 2013 and we do not capitalize that. You know what I mean.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean that would the end of me if you capitalize things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:28:50)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm delighted you don't capitalize things. Keeps it very clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we have a hard time to explain to you but, I mean, our margin is, say, &#x20AC;3.5 billion in 2013. And when you look in real accounting, it's minus &#x20AC;5 billion or so. I wouldn't wish to do that. But that's up to you guys. So, I think we say so we're here and that's the way we charge that. And we see that charging coming up in 2013 and that will then grow in 2014 and 2015, as we start to enter into service and the ramp-up of the production facilities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Harald, could it be some hundreds of millions of euros? I mean, is it that big or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's talk about that over a beer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Splendid. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And we'll take one last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The final question comes from Mr. Tristan Sanson from Exane BNP Paribas. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, everyone. I have a question actually on the transfer of ATR in Sogerma in the reporting of the Other division next year. Is it just a financial reporting change or does it imply some kind of supervision or integration of both companies within Airbus? Can we expect some efficiencies on program management or commercial synergies here and how do you apply it to ATR when you own 50% of it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, already in 2012, Fabrice was in charge in, let's say, in persona to oversee Sogerma. And then with the management change, I mean, we had recent reshuffling in the governance of ATR with new members coming into the general assembly &#x2013; the shareholder assembly, sorry, and the supervisory board, and it happened so that these people are closer to Airbus. And therefore, I mean, ATR will also be reported inside Airbus. I think there's also some operational benefits around bringing the two closer together.</p>
          <p>And as well on the Sogerma side, I mean, with some of the Sogerma business, I think, there's trans-business proximity and, therefore, it makes sense. The way we are going to report out in the future, I mean, in terms of segment also, that's not being decided yet. So, we'll come back to that later this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, this closes our conference call for this time. If you have any additional questions, please feel free to e-mail Julie, Christophe and myself with your list of questions. Thank you and a good day to you all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>And buy EADS shares. I'm not sure if it's too late.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the conference call has now concluded and you may disconnect your telephone. Thank you for joining and have a pleasant day. Good-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>