<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1491881" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>61998</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Investor Relations">Alejandro Giraldo</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Javier Genaro Guti&#xE9;rrez Pemberthy</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Financial Comptroller">Alberto Vargas</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Exploration">Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez Convers</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Transportation">&#xC1;lvaro Casta&#xF1;eda Caro</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Vice President-Downstream">Pedro Alfonso Rosales Navarro</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch Valores SA Sociedad de Bolsa">Frank McGann</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Nathan G. Piper</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Santander CCVM SA">Vicente Falanga Neto</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="BTG Pactual CTVM SA">Gustavo Gattass</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Brasil CCTVM SA">Fernando Valle</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Tudor, Pickering, Holt &amp; Co. International LLP">Anish Kapadia</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Daniel Sensel</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Tudor Pickering Holt &amp; Co. Securities, Inc.">Matthew Portillo</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Interbolsa SA (Broker)">Juan David Pi&#xF1;eros Arenas</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Q2 2012 Ecopetrol S.A. Earnings Conference Call. My name is Claire, and I'll be your operator for today. At this time, all participants are in listen-only mode. We will conduct a question-and-answer session towards the end of the conference call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded for replay purposes.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to your host for today, Mr. Alejandro Giraldo. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone, and welcome to Ecopetrol's second quarter of 2012 financial and operational results conference call. Before we begin, it is important to mention that the comments by Ecopetrol's senior management could include projections of the company's future performance. These projections do not constitute any commitment as to future results, nor they take into account risks or uncertainties that could develop. As a result, Ecopetrol assumes no responsibility in the event that future results are different from the projections on the conference call.</p>
          <p>The call will be led by Mr. Javier Guti&#xE9;rrez, CEO of Ecopetrol. Also participating will be <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:17), Acting Chief Financial Officer; H&#xE9;ctor Manosalva, Executive VP for Exploration and Production; Pedro Rosales, Executive VP for Downstream; &#xC1;lvaro Casta&#xF1;eda, VP of Transportation and Logistics, Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez, VP of Exploration; Camilo Marulanda, VP of Growth and Strategy; and Alberto Vargas, Financial Comptroller of Ecopetrol.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call to Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alejandro. Good afternoon. Thank you all for participating in this conference call. Initially, we will present the highlights of the second quarter, followed by summary of our key financial results, main figures of the business segments and the milestones of internal consolidation. Then, we will review the outlook for the third quarter of 2012, and finally we will close our presentation with a Q&amp;A session. So let's start with slide five to review our milestone in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Though Ecopetrol faced challenging events and difficult international economic conditions in the second quarter of 2012, it continued its progress in its growth strategies, increasing its production and achieving strong financial results. The corporate group reached in the second quarter a production of 762,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day, mainly due to the increase in production of Chichimene, Piedemonte, Gibraltar and Casabe fields versus the second quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>Total sales volume of Ecopetrol grew 9% compared with the second quarter of 2011 as a result of the rise in the exports of crude oil and natural gas. The export sales prices decreased in line with the decline in the international prices. However, our strategy of diversifying benchmarks and destinations for our crudes supported our margins.</p>
          <p>With regards to exploration, Ecopetrol Am&#xE9;rica, Inc., and its partners submitted the most competitive bids for six new blocks in the Lease Sale 222. Additionally, we continue advancing in our modernization projects of our refineries and expansion of our transportation infrastructure. The higher production offset the lower oil prices during the second quarter of 2012. Thus, Ecopetrol reported a 7% growth in revenues and a 9% increase in net income, while EBITDA rose 3%.</p>
          <p>Finally, two milestones for the midstream were accomplished in the second quarter of 2012. First, the incorporation of CENIT, our new subsidiary, who will supply the transportation and logistical needs of the oil industry in Colombia. And second the financial closing of the Phase I of the Bicentenario Pipeline with a syndicated loan amounting to COP$2.1 trillion.</p>
          <p>And now I will turn the presentation to Alberto Vargas, who will comment on the financial results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez. Good afternoon, everyone. Let's turn to slide seven. Financial results in the second quarter of 2012 were affected by the decrease in the oil prices. Notwithstanding, Ecopetrol managed to improve its financial results in comparison to the second quarter of 2011, mainly due to increase in production.</p>
          <p>Starting on the left side of the slide, you can see how in the second quarter total sales rose compared to the same quarter in 2011, driven by higher exports. Total cost of sales plus operating expenses grew 6%, mainly due to the increase of 11% in fixed costs as a result of higher maintenance activities, contracted services related to larger production, and higher labor costs. Also the variable costs increased mainly due to, first, larger imports at high prices of naphtha to be used as diluent and low sulfur diesel to supply the local market. And second higher transportation costs as a consequence of greater volumes exported. It is worth mentioning that those transportation fees for exporting, previously recorded as a commercial expense, are now accrued as variable costs.</p>
          <p>The operational expenses grew mainly as a result of agreements with the police force to protect our operations. Consequently, operating income amounted to COP$6 trillion in the second quarter of 2012, equivalent to an operating margin of 41%. In the non-operating results, the loss of COP$0.5 trillion was mainly due to the impact of provisions made as a result of the lower returns of the fund which covers the pension liabilities.</p>
          <p>Net loss from the Group subsidiaries under the equity method in the second quarter of 2012 amounted to COP$33 billion as follows: refining and petrochemical subsidiaries accounted for a loss of COP$159 billion; upstream subsidiaries added an income of COP$64 billion; transportation subsidiaries COP$32 billion; and corporate subsidiaries COP$30 billion. Finally, net income amounted to COP$3.7 trillion in the second quarter of 2012, which is 9% higher than in the same quarter of 2011. EBITDA grew 3% amounting to COP$7.1 trillion. EBITDA margin was 48%.</p>
          <p>On the next slide number eight we find another view of the company's cash flow and balance sheet as of the end of June. The initial cash balance was COP$17.4 trillion, and cash generation from operations during the second quarter of 2012 amounted to circa COP$15 trillion. COP$16.3 trillion of the company's total cash flow were deployed to fund operations during the quarter, COP$4.9 trillion for the payment of dividends and COP$2.3 trillion for capital expenditures. The ending balance of cash and investment was COP$9.3 trillion.</p>
          <p>Regarding the balance sheet, total assets amounted to COP$86.7 trillion and total liabilities COP$36.2 trillion. The liabilities decreased due to the payment of dividends in April and the first installment of equity tax and surcharge. Financial debt was equivalent to 15.7% of total liabilities, while debt-to-EBITDA ratio for the last 12 months was 0.19. During the quarter, there was no additional indebtedness. Finally, the equity increased mainly as a result of the net income reported in the second quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>Now, let's turn to the main aspects of the results of the Corporate Group shown on slide nine. In the second quarter of 2012, the Corporate Group reached solid financial results. Total sales for the Corporate Group amounted to COP$16.5 trillion, compared with COP$16.3 trillion in the same quarter of 2011. Group's net income amounted to COP$3.7 trillion and EBITDA was COP$7.5 trillion, while EBITDA margin was 45%.</p>
          <p>Now, let's move on to slide 10 and review the main figure of our subsidiaries. In the second quarter of the year, the highest revenue before accounting eliminations came from Reficar with COP$2 trillion, Hocol with COP$921 billion, and Equion with COP$511 billion. Highest net income came from Equion with COP$182 billion, followed by Hocol with COP$76 billion, and Ocensa with COP$43 billion. Subsidiaries with the highest EBITDA in the second quarter were Equion with COP$170 billion, Hocol with COP$160 billion, and Ocensa with COP$147 billion.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll turn the conference to Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez, who will comment about the main results of our E&amp;P segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Please, let's move on slide 12, which summarizes the highlights of the E&amp;P segment. Let's start with our production results. In second quarter, the Corporate Group achieved a gross production of 762,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day, a 5% increase compared with the same quarter of the year 2011, and 3% higher than in the first quarter of the year. Production was affected due mainly to restrictions on the availability of transportation infrastructure. The growth in production between the second quarters of 2011 and 2012 was led mainly by the increase of 16,000 barrels per day in Chichimene, 6,500 barrels equivalent in Piedemonte field, 4,000 barrels equivalent in Gibraltar, and 4,000 barrels equivalent per day in Casabe.</p>
          <p>Regarding exploration in second quarter of 2012, Ecopetrol completed an exploratory well Caronte, whose results remain under evaluation, and then five strat tests, of which one, Akacias EST-1, show hydrocarbon presence and four were dry. Hocol drilled one exploratory well, Felido, which was dry, and five stratigraphic wells. As for the Caribbean offshore activity, so far well conditions have not allowed to start drilling Mapale-1 well. This well has been rescheduled for the third quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>Internationally, the drilling of exploratory well, Parmer, in the U.S. Gulf Coast began in June. Also, in second quarter, Savia drilled the Colan-1 well, whose results are being evaluated. Additionally, in June, Ecopetrol Am&#xE9;rica, Inc., together with its partner, Repsol USA, Inc., Murphy, Apache Corporation and Samson Offshore, submitted the most competitive bids for six blocks in the Gulf of Mexico during the Lease Sale 222. The Bureau of Ocean Energy Management will award the lots in the coming months.</p>
          <p>Our 2012 drilling plans remain unchanged, that is, to drill a total of 42 exploratory wells, 37 of them in Colombia, three in the U.S. Gulf Coast and two in Brazil.</p>
          <p>Finally, let's review the financial results of the Upstream segment. Net income of the segment in second quarter was COP$3.8 trillion. Overall, results were driven by the higher production. EBITDA amounted to COP$6.5 trillion, equivalent to an EBITDA margin of 69%.</p>
          <p>Now, I will turn the call over to Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez, who will comment on the incorporation of CENIT.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Please turn to slide 13. One of the milestone of the quarter in the midstream strategy was the incorporation of CENIT, a wholly-owned subsidiary company specialized in hydrocarbon transport and logistics in Colombia. This new company will supply the strategic transportation and logistical needs of Colombian oil industry, resulting from the increase in hydrocarbon production and higher sales of crudes and refined products, both in Colombia and international markets. The new hydrocarbon transportation scheme generates important advantages for Ecopetrol by allowing the company to have a strategic focus on its business, allocate higher investment to other key segments, and ensure the profitability of the transportation activities.</p>
          <p>CENIT also will guarantee Ecopetrol the capacity for transportation and handling of its hydrocarbons. The new subsidiary will receive all of Ecopetrol's transportation assets, including the interest held in Ocensa, Los Llanos Pipeline, Bicentenario Pipeline, and the Colombia Pipeline. As a result of this process, CENIT will be responsible for marketing, planning and development of the transportation system, formulating new business opportunities. Ecopetrol remains as the operator of the system responsible for preventive and corrective maintenance, loss control, contingency plans and project execution.</p>
          <p>With this, I will turn the call over to &#xC1;lvaro Casta&#xF1;eda, who will provide an update of the results of the Midstream segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez. Let's review the results of the segment in the second quarter of 2012. Net income amounted to COP$99 billion. Although transported volumes of crude oil decreased in the second quarter, revenues went up as a result of higher transportation fees in the year and higher volumes of products transported. Cost of maintenance projects and depreciation increased due to higher activity. Also net income was reduced due to the accrual of equity tax in the second quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>EBITDA amounted to COP$219 billion. Regarding our main project, the Phase I of Bicentenario Pipeline between Araguaney and Banad&#xED;a reached a 55% progress as of June 30. About the contingency program during the quarter, important progress was achieved at the plants worldwide, communities and local entities, as well as in the international benchmarking of the emergency action plan. Finally, on integrity program we can highlight progress in infrastructure monitoring, risk analysis of pipelines and risk mitigation <mark type="indiscernible" /> (19:43).</p>
          <p>With this, I will turn the presentation over to Pedro Rosales, who will comment on downstream results starting with refining.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. Let's move on to slide 14. In terms of our operation, the refinery throughputs in Barrancabermeja decreased in the second quarter of 2012 compared with the same quarter of 2011, mainly due to the scheduled maintenance of one crude unit in April. In Cartagena, the refinery throughputs were reduced due to less availability of Ca&#xF1;o Lim&#xF3;n crude oil caused by lower deliveries of the pipeline.</p>
          <p>In spite of the lower throughput, gross margin in Barrancabermeja increased in the second quarter of 2012 compared to the same quarter of 2011 due to higher yields of medium distillates and better valuation of products, especially fuel oil. Otherwise, gross margin of Cartagena refinery fell due to the reduction in gasoline output as a result of the maintenance of the cracking unit and the lack of Ca&#xF1;o Lim&#xF3;n crude, causing a production increase of fuel oil and naphtha instead of diesel.</p>
          <p>Given the improved output of valuable products and better realization prices in the Barrancabermeja, financial operation results of Refining and Petrochemicals segment improved in the second quarter of 2012 compared to the second quarter of 2011, reaching an EBITDA of COP$252 billion. However, the segment reported a negative non-operational result due to the loss reported by Reficar and the impact of the exchange rate. Then net result was minus COP$202 billion.</p>
          <p>Regarding the main refining projects, in the first half of 2012 the expansion and modernization of the Cartagena refinery reported 68% progress and the upgrading of the Barrancabermeja Refinery 11% advance. Finally, the master plan of utilities in Barrancabermeja reported 46% progress as of June 30.</p>
          <p>Now please turn on to slide 15 to review the sales and marketing results. Total sales volume grew 9% between the second quarters of 2011 and 2012 due to the rise of crude oil exports. Exports growth was driven by higher availability of Magdalena blend and Vasconia crudes. During the second quarter, we continue with the strategies of diversifying markets and referencing our crudes to benchmarks that generate more value to exports.</p>
          <p>Regarding the destination of our exports, in the second quarter of 2012 there was an increase in the sale of our crudes to the U.S. Gulf Coast and Europe, as well as higher volume of products delivered to Far East and the Caribbean.</p>
          <p>Finally, the sales and marketing segment presented in the second quarter of 2012 have dropped in revenues due to the lower sale prices. In spite of this, net income was COP$5 billion compared to a net loss of COP$37 billion in the second quarter of 2011. This loss in 2011 was due to a higher peso revaluation and the result of the hedging operations.</p>
          <p>I now will turn the presentation back to Mr. Gutierrez, who will comment on the milestones of the internal consolidation initiatives and the corporate social responsibility in the second quarter of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Pedro. Let's start by our results in HSE. The accumulated accident frequency rate in the first half of 2012 was 0.97 accidents per million working hours compared with 1.14 in the first half of 2011. Those encouraging results strengthen our commitment of a safe and reliable operation.</p>
          <p>Regarding science and technology, our research institute was granted with two new patents in Columbia in the second quarter of 2012. Additionally, economic benefits amounted to $141 million as a result of the implementation of technical solutions developed by our research institute together with different teams around the company.</p>
          <p>Finally, as part of the commitment with communities, Ecopetrol invested, in the first half of 2012, COP$46 billion in corporate social responsibility initiatives focused on education and culture, citizenship and democracy, and local competitiveness.</p>
          <p>Finally, let's review the outlook for the third quarter of 2012. Please move on to slide 19. Ecopetrol will continue on its path to achieve all of our strategic goals for 2012. Regarding exploration, Equion, our subsidiary, will start drilling the Mapale-1 well in the Colombian Caribbean offshore. In production, we are forecasting the production of the Corporate Group to average around 780,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day in 2012.</p>
          <p>In transportation, we will continue achieving progress in our infrastructure projects and strengthen the initiatives aimed to improve the integrity of the transportation systems and contingency plans. Regarding the Bicentenario Pipeline, Ecopetrol and its partners expect to start line-fill at the end of this year. We will also continue consolidating our new subsidiary CENIT to ensure the beginning of its operation in 2013.</p>
          <p>In refining, we will continue with the progress in the modernization of both Cartagena and Barrancabermeja refineries. Also, thanks to the scheduled maintenance made in the first half of this year, we will be able to ensure the operational reliability and throughput of the refineries. We also shall continue all efforts to maintain the improvement of our HSE performance, as well as the safety and reliability of our operations. Regarding our commercial strategy, we will continue searching for market opportunities in order to reach the best realization prices for the increasing amount of crude oil export.</p>
          <p>Now I open the session to questions from our participants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. For the Q&amp;A session, we will take questions from the first three participants. Then we will provide the answers to the questions, and we will then move again to questions from the next three participants. So, Claire, we will now take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of Frank McGann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Yeah, just a couple of things, if I could. One is in terms of transportation costs. I was just wondering, in Colombian pesos or in dollars, in millions or billions, however you prefer just to give it, the total cost that you identified that were related to security issues in the quarter and whether you see those as continuing at that level or a higher level perhaps in the future. Second, from a production standpoint, maybe you could quantify the effects of the pipeline interruptions in terms of how much that affected the quarter, and just have a little bit better idea on how much effect that had. And then, thirdly, in terms of production growth from here, what are the key fields that will be driving the growth in the third and fourth quarter that will help you get to your production target for the full year? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Nathan Piper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A key question for me is the approval process in Colombia. Clearly, some of your fields have not progressed in terms of production increases due to not getting the water handling facilities, and that's why I understand is getting the approvals in place. And so I'll be interested in your comments on how the approval process is working currently, what influence you could have on increasing &#x2013; or making the process move more smoothly.</p>
          <p>And then lastly, despite cutting your 2012 production to 780,000 barrels a day from 800,000, this still appears to me to be quite an aspirational target. How confident are you of that number, and really should we be thinking about production range that you hope to get to where this is perhaps the top end? But the key thing for me is how is the approval process working in Colombia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Nathan, just to clarify the questions, the first one is basically on the approval process on environmental licenses for the field. Nathan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nathan please. Nathan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He is not -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Nathan, <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We will take the next question then from the next participant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Christian Audi. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Actually this is Vicente from Santander also. I have a few questions. First of all, you said that your target for Ecopetrol with subsidiaries is 780,000 barrels. What about for Ecopetrol S.A. only, do you have that number? Also regarding the startup of the Bicentenario Pipeline, you said that you expect that for the end of 2012, you guys have specifically what month are we talking about, December?</p>
          <p>And one last question. I thought I heard in the Spanish call that you said that the environmental issues that you had during this quarter they hurt your production in about 8,500 barrels per day. Is that it? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So we'll now start with the questions from E&amp;P answered by Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez. We will start with your first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Frank. This is Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez. Frank, regarding your second question, what is the main effect for the interruptions in the pipeline, we quantify the amount in 10,700 barrel per day. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Average.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Average.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Average for the semester.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Your third question -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe &#x2013; it's important to mention, maybe you remember, during the first quarter it was 17,000, and during the second quarter it has been around 6,000. In average we have right now 10,700. Yes, that is important to mention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. With this clarification, Frank, your third question regarding which fields &#x2013; or there in which fields we will put a lot of effort in order to fulfill the goal, let me tell you that actually the fields are Castilla, in which we are working in facilities, then Chichimene also working in facilities. We are waiting for the approval of the environmental license in the Rubiales and Quifa fields, to get the commerciality in the Ca&#xF1;o Sur, to drill more infill wells in Casabe, and finally to get commerciality from the Akacias discovery.</p>
          <p>Okay. Nathan, regarding your question how the approval process of the environmental license is affecting our current production, yes, there are some delays obtaining the environmental license. We have rescheduled some of these delays, so we &#x2013; in the forecast, in the timeline those issues are already accounted. Okay?</p>
          <p>Okay. Nathan, your question regarding how confident we are regarding to get this 780,000, it was the answer that I just gave to Frank McGann, is in which fields we put a lot of work in order to get that number.</p>
          <p>And a question for Vicente. Okay, Vicente, what is the target for Ecopetrol itself. Let me tell you, the target is 730,000 barrels equivalent of oil per day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now the questions on E&amp;P. Now we'll move into transportation to answer the question on ODC and transportation costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pedro Rosales will answer the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. About the transportation costs, our cost target in Colombian pesos, the cost associated to security are under the budget that we planned in our plan, and then we don't expect an increase in that costs in this year. About the schedule of Bicentenario Pipeline, our recent update of the project maintain the target to begin the line-fill of the pipeline by the end of this year if our plan for construction are developed, as we expect, with the support of the army.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And when we refer to the end of the year, we are telling the end of December.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the end of December of 2012, yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So now we'll take questions from the next three participants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from the line of Gustavo Gattass. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Guys. I had two questions here. The first one has to do with the cash costs that you had in the quarter for the E&amp;P unit, okay? So this is Ecopetrol S.A. E&amp;P. And if we just divide the cost number by the number of barrels that you had, you saw something like $4.5 increase in costs in the quarter, in spite of having a higher production number. I just wanted to understand if there was something extraordinary on those costs, or if there was something extraordinarily low in the first quarter costs for comparison purposes. So that's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question, just with regards to the production side of things, I don't know if it would be possible for Enrique to just touch on the important milestones that are necessary, and when do you think they play out for those fields that were mentioned as contributing for the growth, especially the facilities at Castilla and Chichimene, which, as I understand, might be the biggest part of the contribution here. Okay. Those are my two questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So now move to the question from the next participant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next comes from the line of Fernando Valle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, guys. Just two quick questions. The first one is on the CapEx. I think you said on the Spanish call that your CapEx is as you planned, but it's actually around 25% to 30% below your expectations for the year. I just wanted to understand if that's by design, or if there is any impact from the delayed environmental licenses, et cetera, and what we can expect for the end of the year.</p>
          <p>The second question is on the transportation side, I just wanted to understand, you said you have 10,100 barrels per day impact on production. What's the timing on getting that back on line, and what are the costs associated with bringing that back? That's it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Fernando.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fernando, can you repeat the second question, please? Okay. We'll go ahead with the question for the next participant, and then come back to clarify Fernando's question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Anish Kapadia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good evening. I have got three questions, please. Firstly, given your lower production for 2012 and also high impact exploration wells coming in dry on CPE-2 and CPE-8, are you considering as yet bringing down your 2015 production guidance?</p>
          <p>The second question is on Akacias. When do you expect to test the second and third well, and how confident are you in the 90,000 barrels per day production number that you provided at the Analyst Day? And my final question is, can you give what the gross production was on Castilla, Chichimene, Rubiales and Quifa, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So we will start with the answers for the questions on E&amp;P answered by Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Gustavo. Your question regarding the important milestones in order to get the growth goal, let me tell you. We are working in the facilities for Akacias, and we expect by middle August to get that facility in place. Okay? Second important milestone is to start the installation of the STAP station also in order to get that field Castilla in &#x2013; to get &#x2013; we expect to produce like 16,000 barrels additional.</p>
          <p>Also we are working in a portable facility approximately 10,000 barrels in Chichimene. We expect to complete by middle of August. Another milestone is to get the environmental license for Rubiales, which is 400,000 barrels, maybe between August and October. And finally, also to get the environmental license in order to handle 1 million barrels in Rubiales, where in order to get &#x2013; 20 wells we expect to get by November of this year. Okay? So those are the most important milestones to ensure the growth in these fields. This is for Gustavo.</p>
          <p>The question &#x2013; the answer for &#x2013; Anish? Okay. Anish? Anish, let me clarify something. You mentioned that according to the results of the CPE-2 and CPE-4, what do we think in order to reach the goal in 2020. Let me tell you, those wells are strat test, that means those wells are in order to get some knowledge and information in the area. So those wells are really not accounted for these goals. So in summary, we feel pretty comfortable and confident to get the goal in 2020. Okay?</p>
          <p>Second question is regarding when we take the Akacias 2 and 3. Those wells are really in the midst of mines waiting for approval to be tested. As you are aware, we got the governmental license. So, let's say &#x2013; I don't know &#x2013; in a few weeks we take a list. Regarding the production for second quarter of Castilla, we produced 15,500 barrels in Rubiales, plus Quifa we produced 120,000 barrels per day, and basically the questions addressed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that answers the questions on E&amp;P. Now we'll move to transportation and the effect on 10,000 barrels, and when we will be on track in terms of transportation <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:49).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the transportation, the effect is due to the interruption of the production during the previous week take to recover the infrastructure. But once again, the infrastructure is recuperated, we will soon return to the current levels of production. This is &#x2013; that way it is transitory effect, and as we informed in the first quarter, this is mainly due to the time during which the pipeline was out of service in January and in part of February. But &#x2013; it was the two main periods in which we were affected because basically during the second quarter attacks mainly in the April and we haven't had that recently, but we haven't had really an important attacks on the pipeline. But mainly we are affected only if stock capacity is not enough to reserve the production during the time we take to recuperate the infrastructure. But as soon as we recuperate, we return to recovery level in production. But originally it's very important to take into account that we have stock capacity to control production during several days to recuperate infrastructure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now I'm going to the questions on financials, on the cash costs and E&amp;P, and also the question on the lower CapEx situation for exploration, any possible effects on environmental licenses. Alberto Vargas will take the call &#x2013; the question on financials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good afternoon. This is for Gustavo. Your question is terms of cash cost, yes, in the second quarter we had some reasons that increased the cash cost per barrel. Those reasons being mainly that we had to buy to increase our importations of naphtha to be used as diluents for our crude. Also, we got higher maintenance costs to attend our security issues in some of our pipelines, plus we increased our cost coming from fields in which we are non-operators.</p>
          <p>Okay. Now for Fernando on your question on CapEx decrease. Main reason being a delay on our exploration campaign in the Ca&#xF1;o Sur field.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now we'll take questions from the next three participants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from the line of Daniel Sensel. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, Good afternoon. I just have a quick question regarding debt. I see that total debt went up by around $400 million. Can you tell us if you got any new facilities and what were turns of those? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Can you repeat the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Daniel, <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; hear me now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>You may proceed, Daniel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, my question is that, I see that gross debt went up by $400 million. You can provide some details about the terms of the new facilities that you received?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Daniel, we understood your question. Now we'll move to the next participant and come back to you with the answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Matt Portillo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Just three quick questions from me. The first one has to deal with the gas production. Could you talk a little bit about what has led to an increase in gas demand in country, and how sustainable you think your production numbers are from the second quarter going forward through the rest of the year?</p>
          <p>And then I just wanted to clarify on the Rubiales field from a production perspective. I think you said 120,000 barrels a day growth from Rubiales and Quifa combined. Looking back on last quarter, that looks like it's been relatively flat quarter-over-quarter. I just wanted to clarify that. And if you could give any other color around what permits you are waiting for specifically on for the water handling. And then finally, I think just wanted to see if you could give us the gross production numbers for the Chichimene field for the second quarter. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Juan Pi&#xF1;eros.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Just two questions from me. Can you provide more details about the results you had on Akacias stratigraphic one, and how it compares to the results you had on the first exploratory well in this block? And which were the results of the Itauna 2 and why did you record a loss of COP$115 billion in Ecopetrol do Brasil?</p>
          <p>Second question, are there going to be more maintenance or stoppages at the refineries this year?</p>
          <p>And third question is regarding the Bicentenario Pipeline. It will be connected to the Ca&#xF1;o Lim&#xF3;n Pipeline, and we have seen an increase in the frequency of attacks to this pipeline. So how this will affect future operations? How critical it would be an eventual disruption in the Bicentennial? How much would you rely on this Bicentennial in 2013? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll start answering the question on E&amp;P. Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez will take the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Juan, regarding your first question &#x2013; actually you have two questions. The results of Akacias strat one, as you will know, is an exploration well in which we have some hydrocarbon presence, and this is the information that we can release. When we test a well, it happened in a short period of time we can deliver information.</p>
          <p>Second, your second question regarding Itauna 2, why Itauna 2 was accounted in the books and what &#x2013; actually Itauna 2 was drilled in order to prove the extension of discovery of Itauna 1. This main target was find dry, but we find we have hydrocarbon presence in oil formations. So these information is being used in order to define the geological model, and in that way we can propose the Itauna 3 next year.</p>
          <p>Okay. This is for Juan Pi&#xF1;eros &#x2013; no, for Matt Portillo. For Matt, let's start from the question number two, number three, and then I will go back to the number one. Number two, you asked specifically what kind of permits we are waiting in order to continue &#x2013; to increase the production. You are right, the permit is <mark type="indiscernible" /> (54:59). And your question regarding Chichimene, Chichimene production, okay, the figure for Chichimene for the second quarter is 44,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day.</p>
          <p>And the final one, your first question regarding gas production, the increase in gas demand of the country, the final one, let me tell you, the total gas production equivalent was in the second quarter just for Ecopetrol was 112,000 barrels equivalent oil per day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gas production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It's Pedro Rosales. About the gas production, what you say in the report is that in the semester we are affected with a new decree that allows the producer to sell the gas royalties. As a consequence of that Ecopetrol has a lower amount of natural gas to trade in the domestic market. During the first semester of this year the difference is approximately 10,000 equivalent oil barrels per day that is in the same period of 2011. However, this amount only represents 1% of the local sales income and doesn't have any material impact in our results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe additionally, it is important to mention that it basically corresponds to the royalties that we have been acquiring to the National Hydrocarbon Agency. And really our role in that case is mainly like a trader. But it is not really in terms of the size of our economic basis because in terms of our business really we have been attended with our own production. And as we are waiting right now, the production must continue increasing, mainly considering that during the next month we are going to have some additional production from the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (57:39) new project that maybe going to be in operation in two months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Two months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Two months, right. And in terms of the demand in the country, the company has been registered an increase of around 7% annually. But additionally, it's important considering that we are looking for increasing our exports, and additionally presently the minister have announced new plans to connect new carriers to the gas service in different parts of the country. In that sense we consider we have a stable increase in terms of the gas demand in the country and the opportunities outside.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. About the next question is we expect to have stoppages in the refineries in the second half of the year. We only have one scheduled maintenance during the second semester in one of our cracking plants in Barrancabermeja. They are <mark type="indiscernible" /> (59:01). But the output from this unit will be replaced by the production of other cracking units in the refinery, which we have higher yields. Then we don't expect a real impact in our production of gasoline for this case. Then in general we don't expect any impact from stoppages for planned turnarounds in our plants in the refineries.</p>
          <p>And finally about Bicentenario Pipeline, what can we expect. As we talked before, our projection is that we will begin the line-fill of the pipeline at the end of this year. Then it will have any impact this year in our production or in our transportation number in this year. If there would be any impact, it can be next year when the pipeline would be in use. But at this time we are working with the different authorities to provide the better protection to that infrastructure to avoid that we have impact in the operation in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now take the final question in terms of financing <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:00:36) answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Daniel. In regards to increase of the consolidated debt of Ecopetrol, that amount is related to the disbursement that has been down under Reficar transaction with the US EXIM Bank. As you know, we closed the facility in late 2011, but disbursement has been done throughout this year. It is same that is going to happen in the Bicentenario Pipeline as long as the disbursement are done throughout the remaining of this year. So you will see increases in that from now on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So unfortunately we have run out of time. This is the last answer. If you have additional questions, you can contact to us at the Investor Relations. Thank you all for participation. And we remind you that we will be hosting our Investor Day in New York and London in the month of September. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may now disconnect. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>