<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1512957" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>61998</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Investor Relations">Alejandro Giraldo</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Javier Genaro Guti&#xE9;rrez Pemberthy</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Adriana Marcela Echeverri Guti&#xE9;rrez</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Exploration">Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez Convers</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Transportation">&#xC1;lvaro Casta&#xF1;eda Caro</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Supply &amp; Marketing">Claudia Luc&#xED;a Castellanos Rodr&#xED;guez</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Ita&#xFA; Corretora de Valores SA">Paula Kovarsky</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="BTG Pactual CTVM SA">Gustavo Gattass</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Nathan G. Piper</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Tudor, Pickering, Holt &amp; Co. International LLP">Anish Kapadia</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Santander CCVM SA">Vicente Falanga Neto</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan CCVM SA">Caio Carvalhal</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Ecopetrol's Third Quarter 2012 Financial and Operational Results Conference Call. My name is Ian, I'll be your operator for today. At this time, all participants are in listen-only mode. We will conduct a question-and-answer session towards the end of the conference. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this call is being recorded for replay purposes.</p>
          <p>Now, I'd like to hand the call over to Mr. Alejandro Giraldo, Head of Investor Relations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone, and welcome to Ecopetrol's third quarter 2012 financial and operational results conference call. Before we begin, it is important to mention that the comments by Ecopetrol's senior management could include projections of the company's future performance. These projections do not constitute any commitment as to future results, nor do they take into account risks or uncertainties that could develop. As a result, Ecopetrol assumes no responsibility in the event that future results are different from the projections on the conference call.</p>
          <p>The call will be led by Mr. Javier Guti&#xE9;rrez, CEO of Ecopetrol and also participating will be Adriana Echeverri, CFO; Hector Manosalva, Executive VP for E&amp;P; Pedro Rosales, Executive VP for Downstream; &#xC1;lvaro Casta&#xF1;eda, VP of Transportation and Logistics and Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez, VP of Exploration and Claudia Castellanos, VP of Supply and Marketing.</p>
          <p>I would now turn the call to Mr. Gutierrez.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alejandro. Good afternoon. Thank you all for participating in this conference call. Initially, we will present the highlights of the third quarter, followed by summary of our key financial results, as well as milestones and drivers of the business segments and internal consolidation. Then, we will review the outlook for the fourth quarter of 2012, and finally we will close our presentation with a Q&amp;A session.</p>
          <p>So let's go to slide five to review our milestones in the third quarter. In the third quarter of 2012, Ecopetrol faced up the challenges from the operation in Colombia in the oil and gas sector. The corporate group's production included affiliate in subsidiary companies reached in the third quarter 743,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day, mainly due to the increase in production of Chichimene, Casabe, La Cira-Infantas and other mature fields in the Middle Magdalena region as well as of our affiliate, Equi&#xF3;n and Savia, Peru.</p>
          <p>On our commercial activity, in the third quarter of 2012, we had a reduction of 3% in total sales volume, mainly due to the lower sales of natural gas from third-party royalties and reduced availability of crude oil for exports. These were partially offset by higher export prices for crude oil.</p>
          <p>Our revenues were almost 1% higher than in the third quarter of 2011. The decrease in the net income compared to 2011 was mainly due to the one-time amortization reversion of the petroleum investment of the Chichimene field in the third quarter of 2011 amounting to COP$618 billion. If this adjustment have not taken place, the net income of the third quarter of 2011 would have decreased 9% instead of 23%. We were able to achieve important milestones in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>In exploration and production, it is worth mentioning the three discoveries, one of them in the deep waters of the US Gulf of Mexico. Through our affiliate, Ecopetrol America, Inc., the drilling of six A3 exploratory wells, a successful development campaign from Equi&#xF3;n, allowing this company to increase production 24%, and finally, that 13% rise of Savia, Peru's production.</p>
          <p>Regarding our commercial activity, we highlight two events. First, the signing of a contract to deliver heavy crude oil to one of the many refineries in India, and second, the record exports in September reaching 17.5 million of barrels. I also remark the upgrade of the outlook of our writing from stable to positive made by Standard &amp; Poor's.</p>
          <p>In our corporate social responsibility, I highlight two relevant achievements. For the second year in a row we are part of the Dow Jones Sustainability World Index and we reached a record with the lowest index of accident frequency. As you can see, though it was a less favorable quarter, we achieved significant progress in different areas, and we remain confident on accomplishing our goals in 2012.</p>
          <p>Now, I will turn the presentation to Adriana Echeverri, who will comment on the financial results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez. Good afternoon, everyone. Let's turn to slide seven please. As mentioned, we experienced an increase during the last 12 months in the export crude oil prices, offsetting the lower sales volumes in Colombia and abroad. The financial markets decreased due to lower sales growth and the higher operational costs. Fixed costs rose, mainly due to higher maintenance activities for production, transportation and refining infrastructure, as well as larger costs linked to the management of higher water cost and sediment required to maintain the production, especially in Castilla, Rubiales and Quifa fields. Variable costs rose mainly due to higher cost of hydrocarbon purchases and the higher average cost of volumes sold as a result of the addition of the transportation expenses.</p>
          <p>On the operating expenses, there was a decrease of 3.8% when compared with the third quarter of 2011. That was due mainly to lower exploration and project expenses as a result of less dry wells and lower cost of seismic studies. Consequently, operating income amounted to COP$4.9 trillion in the third quarter of this year, equivalent to an operating margin of 34.5%.</p>
          <p>In the non-operating results, the loss of COP$204 billion was mainly due to, first, the exchange rates loss of COP$21 billion in the third quarter of 2012, compared to a profit of COP$328 billion in the third quarter of last year and, second, a provision increase <mark type="ph" /> for losses of a pretended (08:32) self-generation electricity charge for the Association Contracts of Cusiana, Cupiagua and Cravo Norte. Those charges were partially offset by the better results of the group subsidiary under the equity method which amounted to COP$311 billion in the third quarter of 2012, compared to COP$134 billion in the third quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>As mentioned by Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez before, when compared the third quarter results of 2012 and 2011, you can observe a higher decrease in the net income due to the effects of an amortization reversion of petroleum investment in the Chichimene field made in the third quarter of 2011 amounting to COP$618 billion.</p>
          <p>If this one-time adjustment had not taken place, net income in the third quarter of 2011 would had amounted to COP$3.6 trillion instead of COP$4.2 trillion, and the variation of the net income in the third quarter of 2012 would have been minus 9.3% instead of the minus 23% that we are observing. Accordingly, net income amounted to COP$3.2 trillion, equivalent to net margin of 23% and an EBITDA margin of 44%. The return on assets amounted to 17% and the return on equity, 28%.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, number eight, we find an overview of the company's cash flow and balance sheet as of the end of September 2012. The initial cash balance was COP$9.3 trillion, and cash generation and other sources added COP$14.2 trillion that funded the operation, the CapEx and the payment of the second installment of dividends to the government. The ending balance of cash and investments was COP$9.4 trillion, of which COP$2.6 trillion are earmarked for the payment of the third installment of ordinary dividends and COP$1.3 trillion for the extraordinary dividend, both for the government. These dividend payments were scheduled for the last quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>The indebtedness remained low during this period, with 12 month debt-to-EBITDA ratio of 0.2. As previously mentioned, the positive financial ratios of Ecopetrol, as well as the upgrade in the outlook of the Republic of Colombia, led the rating agency Standard &amp; Poor's to improve the outlook at &#x2013; of Ecopetrol from stable to positive in the third quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>Now, let's turn to the main results of the affiliates and subsidiaries shown on slide number nine. Group's net income amounted to COP$3.2 trillion and EBITDA was COP$6.9 trillion, while EBITDA margin was 42%. In general terms, affiliate and subsidiaries of Ecopetrol, especially those in the E&amp;P segment, improved their results in the third quarter of 2012. The higher net income before eliminations came from Equi&#xF3;n with COP$203 billion and from ODL with COP$165 billion. These better results are mainly due to the strong revenues of the companies. In line with this trend, higher EBITDA before eliminations came from Equi&#xF3;n, with COP$321 billion and from Hocol, with COP$222 billion.</p>
          <p>The bigger losses were reported by companies which are still in exploration stage, such as Ecopetrol America, Inc. with COP$72 billion and Ecopetrol Oleo e Gas Do Brasil, with COP$13.6 billion. Finally, Reficar recorded a negative result of COP$12 billion due to a lower refining margins during the period.</p>
          <p>Now, I turn the conference to Mr. Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez, who will comment about the main results of our E&amp;P segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Please, let's move on to slide 11, which summarizes the highlights of the E&amp;P segment. Let's start with our production results. In the third quarter, the Ecopetrol Group achieved a gross production, including affiliates and subsidiaries, of 743,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day, a 1.6% increase compared with the same quarter of the year 2011. The growth in production between the third quarters of the year 2011 and 2012 was led mainly by the increase of 14,000 barrels per day in Chichimene field, 13,000 barrels in mature fields in the Middle Magdalena region, and 6,000 barrels in Casabe field. It's important to mention that other companies of the group, Equi&#xF3;n and Savia, have been carrying out a successful development campaign that increased their production in 24% and 15%, respectively.</p>
          <p>Regarding exploration, in the third quarter of the year 2012, we reported three discoveries; Embrujo-1, in the east part of Ca&#xF1;o Sur Block; Aullador-1, in the Middle Magdalena Valley, both of them in Colombia; and Parmer in the deep waters of the U.S. Gulf of Mexico. Also, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (14:37) which was in evaluation in the previous quarter report, show higher carbon presence.</p>
          <p>Moving on the financial results of the Upstream segment, revenues rose 6%, due mainly to high sales price of crude oil. However, the high charges of amortization and depreciation, as well as the cost of the transportation of hydrocarbons, caused a drop in the net income and the EBITDA in the third quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>Now, I will turn to &#xC1;lvaro Casta&#xF1;eda, who will present the results of the Midstream segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Enrique. Please let's review our operational results. In the third quarter of 2012, transported volumes of crude oil fell 6% as a result of, first, the lack of availability of Ca&#xF1;o Lim&#xF3;n-Cove&#xF1;as and Transandino pipelines. And second, the operational failure that affected the pumping station in August, causing a stoppage of around four days in Ocensa.</p>
          <p>We are fully committed with the expansion project and the development of technical solution for transporting heavy crude oil. The construction of the Phase I of Bicentenario pipeline at the end of the third quarter reported a 59% progress. We expect to <mark type="ph" /> start line fill (16:19) in the first half of 2013.</p>
          <p>With regard to Cenit, progress was made in two objectives. First, in the process of transferring Ecopetrol's interest in Ocensa, ODC, ODL, OBC and Serviport. And second, in the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (16:42) related to the staffing and implementation of IT solutions.</p>
          <p>Now let's review the financial results of the segment in the third quarter of 2012. Our revenues increased due to the higher fees and a larger volume of transported products. However, the bigger cost of investments and maintenance led to a reduction of the net income and the EBITDA.</p>
          <p>With this, I will turn the presentation over to Claudia Castellanos, who will comment on Downstream results starting with refining.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. Let's move on to slide 13. Both the refinery throughput and the utilization factor in Barrancabermeja refinery increased in the third quarter of 2012 compared with the same quarter of 2011, mainly due to higher mechanical reliability and no major maintenance during the quarter. Cartagena Refinery had a throughput at similar levels than in the third quarter of 2011, but utilization factor decreased due to operational restrictions in the crude unit. Regarding margins, there was an 11% drop in the gross margin of Barrancabermeja between the third quarter of 2012 and 2011, as a consequence of higher cost of crude oil which is referred to the export basket of Ecopetrol that was higher during the last quarter. This situation also affected Cartagena's gross margin with a higher impact due to the use of the larger portion of light crude oil into its fleet. Regarding the main refining projects, at the end of third quarter of 2012, the modernization of Barrancabermeja refinery reached 12% progress and the utility master plan 52%.</p>
          <p>In addition, the Cartagena Refinery modernization, an expansion plan reached 71% progress as follow, detailed engineering 97%, procurement 92%, module fabrication 100% and construction which began October 2011, 31%.</p>
          <p>Let's now review the financial results, which were lower than the ones of the third quarter 2011 due mainly to the decrease in the sales price of the products in the Colombian market versus the cost of crude oil. The EBITDA of the quarter was positive COP$109 billion, with a net loss of COP$95 billion.</p>
          <p>Now please turn to Slide 14 to review the sales and marketing results. Total sales volume decreased 3% between the third quarter 2012 and 2011, mainly due to the lower sales of natural gas. This reduction was generated by the lower availability of gas royalties given that under Decree 2100 of 2011. Some gas producers began to commercialize directly the royalties since January 2012. Additionally, as of July this year, Ecopetrol started trading the gas royalties on behalf of ANH without ownership right over them.</p>
          <p>It is also important to highlight that during September Ecopetrol reached a new record in export of 70.5 million barrels, of which 15.6 million were crude oil. The main destination of our crude-oil export was the US Gulf Coast. It is worth mentioning the increasing share of Far East parties from 6.5% to 14.3% and Central America from 3.3% to 10.3%.</p>
          <p>Regarding products, the higher volume of export was to the Caribbean. Also, deliveries of fuel oil to Far East rose from 7.6% to 17.1% and to the East and West US Coast from 7.7% to 17% between the third quarter of 2012 and 2011.</p>
          <p>I would like to highlight the export contract with one of the most important refineries in India to a total amount of 12 million barrels of Castilla crude to be delivered in six shipments of 2 million barrels each.</p>
          <p>Regarding the financial result, the sales and marketing segment presented in the third quarter of 2012, a 2% drop in revenues due to lower volumes sold. Operational and net results were affected by the higher cost of imported diluents and the use of the trucks to move crude and diluent.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll turn the presentation back to Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez, who will comment on internal consolidation and corporate social responsibility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Claudia. Let's go to slide 16. Let's start by the remarkable results in HSE. The accident frequency rate in the third quarter of 2012 decreased to 0.65 accidents per million working hours, a new record in Ecopetrol. This result is in line with the trend of improvement of the last year's. We also reduced the number of environmental incidents due to the operational causes going from 13 in the third quarter of 2011 to 5 in the third quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>Regarding science and technology, during the quarter, our research institute was granted one patent in Colombia and 2 in Russia. Additionally, a start of our commitments with communities, year-to-date, Ecopetrol invested COP$104 billion in corporate social responsibility initiatives, 73% more than in the same period of 2011. Out of this amount, 48% was allocated to local competitiveness, 38% to education and culture, and 14% to citizenship and democracy.</p>
          <p>It is worth mentioning that for second year in a row, Ecopetrol is part of the Dow Jones Sustainability World Index. The assessment was better than 2011, with improvements in all the aspects, especially in the environmental area, and our score is higher than the average for the oil and gas companies in that index.</p>
          <p>Finally, let's review the outlook for the last quarter of 2012. Please move on to slide 18. In spite of the challenges, the company expects to fulfill the goals of 2012. In exploration, we will continue with the positive dynamic of the third quarter, and we expect to drill a total of 60 wells in 2012, including those of our subsidiaries and affiliates. Regarding production, growth will continue to be led by our fields in Llanos and the Magdalena Valley. In transportation, we will complete the expansions in three main systems, 10,000 additional barrels per day in Oleoducto de Colombia, 27,000 barrels per day in Ayacucho-Cove&#xF1;as 16 inches line and 10,000 barrels per day in Oleoducto Transandino.</p>
          <p>Regarding the Bicentenario pipeline, we estimate to close the year with a 75% progress and complete the transition and preparation phase of Cenit in order to begin operations in the first quarter of 2013.</p>
          <p>In refining, by the end of the year, we plan to have a progress of more than 80% in the modernization of the Cartagena Refinery and to obtain the approval of the environmental plan for the Barrancabermeja modernization project. Maintenances in two cracking units and one polyethylene plant are scheduled for the last quarter. With these maintenances, we will assure the operational reliability and the throughput of the Barrancabermeja refinery. About our commitment to air quality and continuing improvement in quality of fields we distribute, we are ready to be the first Latin American country in which the total delivered diesel will be very low sulfur, it means with less than 50 parts per million as of January 1, 2013.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter will mark a milestone in the reliability of natural gas supply because of the new operation of the Cupiaga gas plant and the gas pipeline, Cupiaga-Cusiana, which will provide 140 million cubic feet per day of new supply. Also, new compression facilities and additional production in <mark type="ph" /> Juahita (28:08) field will be in operation. We also shall continue all efforts to improve our HSE performance, as well as the safety and reliability of our operations.</p>
          <p>With regards to financials, no debt is required for the remaining of the year, as the internal cash generation of the company will form operations, investments and dividend payments. Additionally, following the guidelines of our strategic plan, we will maintain the required return on investments.</p>
          <p>To summarize, I want to state that Ecopetrol has the ability to adapt to the environment and that the achievements of the third quarter, together with our strong operations, give us the confidence on our reporting positive results by the end of 2012 to our approximately 500,000 shareholders.</p>
          <p>Now, I open the session to questions from our participants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Please stand by for your first question, ladies and gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ian, hi, just a quick reminder. For the Q&amp;A session, we will take questions of one participant at a time. And please, no more than two questions per participant. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have a question for you here. It's from the line of Paula Kovarsky, [Ita&#xFA; BBA]. Please go ahead, Paula, you're in the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. All right, let me start with two questions then. The first one, if you could just give us a little bit more color on why production was a bit smaller than expected this quarter? And what exactly do you guys intend to do in the fourth quarter so that the target is maintained? The number for the fourth quarter looks quite challenging. Ecopetrol will have to produce like close to 900,000 barrels a day to be able to meet the targets. So what are the main sources of growth? And in case of the third quarter, in the particular case of the Rubiales field, why such a small growth? So that's question number one.</p>
          <p>And question number two, could you comment on the cash needs and if you intend to maintain dividends at current levels of 70%, or if there's any plans to reduce that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the questions. Initially, Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez is going to comment in relation with the production, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Paula.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me summarize which initiatives we are going to complete in the last quarter in order to increase production. Let us start, for Castilla, in Castilla, we expect to increase around 9,000 barrels. And basically we will carry out <mark type="indiscernible" /> (31:45) wells in order to reach the <mark type="ph" /> Q1 formation (31:48), as well as to improve the facilities in that field. In Chichimene field, we expect to increase production around 13,000 barrels. And basically the plan is to drill new wells, as well as to put in place some facilities. And for Rubiales, you're right, the increase looks not high as we expected, but basically it's because, as you know, the license that we got is only for 500,000 barrels and we filed the papers for 1 million, so we expect to increase <mark type="ph" /> gas (32:32) in around 5,000 barrels. The oil field's mainly located in the Middle Magdalena region, say, Casabe, <mark type="ph" /> Genito (32:42) and others, we expect to increase 13,000 barrels per day.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, in gas, we expect to increase in Cupiagua an equivalent production of 23,000 to 24,000 barrels per day. Basically, the plan is to start up the plant in Cupiagua. In Guajira, we expect to increase equivalent of 10,000 barrels per day and the plan is to putting in production or putting in working the new compression project. So basically I can tell you what kind of initiatives we expect to put in place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Paula, in line with the figures that are presented by Enrique, we are confident to keep the goal that we established for the annual average as we presented in the last quarter, considering dollars numbers that are presented by Enrique. In relation with the cash, I'm going to ask Adriana to answer the question, but let me first to present a comment in relation with the dividends policy. Maybe it's important to remember that in accordance to the &#x2013; what is called the manifesto of a statement of the &#x2013; our &#x2013; of the government as the larger shareholder of the company and which is established in the <mark type="ph" /> gold commerce &#x2013; of Colombian gold commerce (34:31) and considering that we have covered our obligations in terms of the capital of the company, the management, including the board of directors, have the obligation to present a proposal to distribute at least 70%, that is the number what we have been considering in our projections. But it will be necessary the administration could present to the general assembly the possibility to review the distribution, but up to now we haven't considered the necessity to present that kind of request to our assembly. But if it would be necessary in the future, it would be the possibility to present, but up to now, basically we have been acting in accordance to that regulation that applies to the company.</p>
          <p>Adriana Echeverri, our Financial Vice President, is going to comment in terms of the cash needs. Adriana, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez mentioned, in terms of our projections, we keep an eye on the dividend policy, which is 70% for each one of the years, taking into account that we have no more requirements in terms of cash, given the strong cash generation of the company. What we try to do is to keep in mind a mix of the projects, to have strong cash generation through the different quarters of the year.</p>
          <p>For this year 2012, we are envisioning that we do not have any cash needs for finishing the year because the cash generation is going to be enough to supply the funds for not only operations, but also for CapEx and also the dividends that are still pending to be paid to the national government. So we have no indebtedness operations for this year at least. So far &#x2013; if we take into account the budget for year 2013, it has not been approved yet by the BOD, we do not yet &#x2013; we do not know yet exactly what the cash needs are going to be for year 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just a quick follow-up on the production question; is there &#x2013; you mentioned Rubiales is only 5,000 barrels a day and then Quifa, is there an expectation for Quifa to contribute as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Paula. The Rubiales, 5,000 and Quifa, Ecopetrol net working interest will remain with 24,000 barrels per day, flat for rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much for your question. We have another question for you. This one's from the line of Gustavo Gattass, [Banco BTG Pactual S.A.]. Please go ahead, Gustavo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon, guys. I had two questions here. Actually, I had a lot more, but I'll come back in the future, if we can. The first thing I needed &#x2013; actually wanted to check with you guys, was if you could give us any update on your in situ combustion testing at Chichimene. My impression is that it has been happening, or being tried, for a little while and we haven't really heard anything on it. I was wondering if you could share some thoughts on that.</p>
          <p>And my second question, I just wanted to understand a little bit about your lifting costs. You did make a point that you are seeing higher water cuts and you did make a point that you are seeing higher transportation cost with regards to the trucks. But is there any component of the lifting cost that we're seeing right now that you think are going to be offset and are going to be lowered? Those would be the two.</p>
          <p>If I could just put in a very short one for 2013? I just want to check when we might get a production guidance for 2013 from you. That's all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Gustavo. Enrique is going to comment in relation with the in situ combustion project in Chichimene.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Gustavo. Let me give an update to you about how the pilot Chichimene is going on. Basically, the feasibility stage has been completed. That means that we carry out a lab test as well as RTO, which is Rapid Temperature Oxidation program. We build a <mark type="indiscernible" /> (39:30). We are working in the basic engineering. We started with the long-lead items purchasing and we expect to start the detail engineering. Let's put in <mark type="indiscernible" /> (39:47) we expect to complete it by the year 2014.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gustavo, Adriana is going to refer to the lifting cost. But first, I would like to <mark type="ph" /> preside (40:06) that we still don't have estimation for the 2013 production. We're going to consider the approval of the budget to the board of directors in the &#x2013; the next November. Adriana, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Gustavo, in terms of the cost, we take into account the variation the last year. The main portion for that comes from diluent. Let's remember that we are increasing our production of heavy crude oil. So that implies that we have to use more diluent for transportation of this heavy crude oil. That's the first part. COP$464 million pesos is the cost in the last year for that diluent. In second term, we have also these water treatment costs that you mentioned, and we have that particular situation for Castilla and Chichimene, which are directly operated by Ecopetrol, but we also have that for the Rubiales field. And those treatment costs of water are going to stay, as we are increasing production in those fields.</p>
          <p>However, which one is the one that we are expecting to be lower? Tanker trucks. As long as transportation systems are available and become more available in terms of different situations that have affecting them &#x2013; have affected them, we expect that those tanker truck costs for transportation be reduced. But in terms of diluent, water treatment, maintenance and the ones that I already mentioned, those ones are to stay as long as we have now analyzed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perfect. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Gustavo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your question, Gustavo. We have another question for you. This one is from the line of Nathan Piper, [RBC Capital Markets]. Please go ahead, Nathan. You're in the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there, guys. I guess I want to talk about the elephant in the living room. And the approval process in Colombia continues to stop production progress, both on Castilla, Rubiales and many other projects. I wonder if you could give us a bit of color around how the approval process might change over the next six months. And indeed, what influence Ecopetrol has in speeding up the approval process in Colombia so that the industry can continue to grow production?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Nathan. I think what is important to mention is that the environmental licensing process has been improving, and what is important to understand is that, during the last year, we have like a kind of transformation process. Maybe it's important to remember that a new state agency was created for the approval and development of the environmental process. It was the national authority for the environmental licensing. But additionally, it is important also to remember that the previous minister of household, territory and environmental was split and right now, the new environmental and territory minister, of which the national authority is part of, are under the process of consolidating and strengthening. But the licensing process has been improving and practically, we are not suffering any delays right now in terms of the approval of the environmental, but what is important to mention that now we are submitted to a more rigorous process, considering that the social aspects have been acquiring more important and more relevance in terms of the communities. And the socialization process and need in terms of the part of the &#x2013; the participation of the communities also is going to imply maybe additional times for the approval process.</p>
          <p>But, what we have been observing during the last months is continue improving in terms of the process and additionally, the government is also developing several activities to strengthening the national authority and to guarantee efficient process for the future. And additionally, we, as a company, have been more strict in terms of how we would develop the studies, how we develop the socialization process and additionally, being more rigorous in terms of the fulfillment of all the requirements of the process. And considering we having had some impact, but really what we can consider &#x2013; opinion that we have right now is that the process is under improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I mean, obviously, due process is very important in any country, but specifically on the Castilla and Rubiales fields, which are important for your production growth targets, will &#x2013; what's your expectation on getting the appropriate approvals to allow you to install water handling? And how long, once you get the approvals, will it take to actually build the water handling facilities and allow you to increase production, because clearly you're having to manage your well stock currently?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the modification of the environmental program, we are expecting that, the approval, by part of the &#x2013; national environmental authority is going to be at the end of November, the beginning of December.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Nathan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you, Nathan. I have another question for you. This one is from the line of Anish Kapadia, [Tudor, Pickering, Holt]. Please, go ahead, Anish, you're in the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, yes, I had two questions. One on reserves and then just wanted to follow-up on a few more things on production. On the reserve side of things, I was wondering, do you think you'll be able to achieve 100% reserve replacement or more in 2012, given what seems like a relative lack of exploration success? And how much do you potentially think you can book from CPO-9 and Ca&#xF1;o Sur? And just related to that, what is the timing for the CPO-9 test?</p>
          <p>And on the production side, I'm still struggling to see how you'll get to an average of 780,000 barrels a day. It looks like you'll need &#x2013; you'll need at least 850,000 barrels a day in the fourth quarter. I can see that &#x2013; I can see how you split out the growth, but it seems like there's still going to be risks from Castilla, Chichimene, Rubiales and other fields, in terms of getting to that growth target. So just trying to see, why you're so confident that you'll get to that growth target and if you still remain confident in your longer-term targets, given the problems that you've had this year. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Anish. Enrique is going to take the answer to the reserves, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Anish. Regarding your first question, reserves, we are pretty confident we'll achieve the &#x2013; our <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:03) 100%, based on the current production on the field, mainly Castilla and Chichimene. Let's put it in this way, let's say that the CPO-9 and Ca&#xF1;o Sur <mark type="ph" /> commercialities (49:23) will be, in place next year, but more than lack of success in exploration. So in that sense, your question, answer is, yes, we will achieve the 100% replacement rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anish, as we have mentioned, we are confident of our guidance of 780,000 barrels of average production for 2012. If you consider the numbers to which Enrique referred, the increase of our production in several of the fields. But I would like to emphasize, in the case of the Cupiagua, that is a new gas production plant with a capacity &#x2013; with initial capacity of 140 million cubic feet per day that represent around 24,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day. If you consider only this number and our projected increments in the rest of the fields, we are confident of the guidance of 780,000 barrels for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And can I just follow up on that? In terms of the production <mark type="ph" /> price of (50:43) for Castilla, Chichimene and Rubiales, where do you see each of those fields peaking out in terms of production, and when?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Anish, expected production for Castilla by the end of this year is around 126,000 barrels per day. And basically we'll get you this number, we saw wells, I mean, reaching the K1 plus facilities. Chichimene, we expect to finish the year producing around 60,000 barrels of oil per day, basically, with new wells and facilities. Rubiales, when this &#x2013; this is the one in which we got license approval for 500,000 barrels per day &#x2013; actually it's 400,000 barrels, excuse me. And we expect <mark type="ph" /> 1 million (51:47) is the one in which you can notice that the increase is not as high as expected and it's 110,000 barrels per day. On the other hand, Quifa will produce 25,000 barrels per day, flat for the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for your question. We have another question for you. This one's from the line of Christian Audi, [Santander]. Please go ahead, Christian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Good afternoon, guys. This is actually Vicente. You guys mentioned that your operations were interrupted for four to five days during the quarter. What happened there exactly? And how much did it affect, in terms of barrels of oil per day, in your average production?</p>
          <p>And then second question is a follow-up of a previous question made here. And you mentioned that you expect to reduce your trucking costs. Do you guys have an estimate of how much would that be in terms of dollars per barrel? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. Yes, we have an interruption, the Ocensa system and it has a large impact. You consider that the current capacity that we are transporting in Ocensa is around 600,000 barrels per day. And due to the problem in the control systems, the facility was out of the operation by five days. Five days. It means that during those days we have shortage of around 80,000 barrels per day, daily. It was a impact there around Ecopetrol's production. But if &#x2013; and in terms of the quarter, it was 7,000 barrels per day, in terms of the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, 7,000.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of the period from January to September, it represents 2,600 barrels; for the quarter, 7,100 barrels per day, yes. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>7,000 barrels per day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>7,000 barrels per day, okay, for the quarter, yes. Sorry &#x2013; up to date, it represents 2,600 barrels per day in average if we consider the period from January to September.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Does this answer your question, Christian (sic) [Vicente] (55:29)...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Yes, it does.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Adriana is going to refer to the trucking cost. Please, Adriana?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Christian (sic) [Vicente] (55:41), as I already mentioned in a previous question, we do not have an estimation seeing trucking costs increase, will depend on the availability of transportation systems. So, the more available [indiscernible] (56:04) those systems where we have low transportation costs, the lower the transportation costs we will on trucking. So really in this last quarter, we had several different impacts for different operational and some other causes, that led us to have that high cost. However, I have to mention that, that is not a normal behavior of that type of trucking cost [indiscernible] (56:34). So if nothing happens, that trucking cost and that transportation cost that we have had there with the so high increase in this last quarter should not remain if the systems are available.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Christian (sic) [Vicente] (57:00).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have another question for you. This one's from the line of Caio Carvalhal, [JPMorgan]. Please go ahead, you're in the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. I think most of the topics were already addressed. And I just wanted a quick update on <mark type="indiscernible" /> (57:14) the security issue in Colombia. We &#x2013; I mean, correct me if I'm wrong, but I believe we already proceeded some improvement in the third Q in terms of pipeline disruptions, in terms of days of pipeline disruptions we had in the third Q. We saw some improvement in relation to the second Q, however, not as good as we've been seeing since 2006 or 2007. My question is, the indication you have so far for the fourth Q are in relation to an improvement on the third Q numbers? Or do you believe that &#x2013; I mean, we know we just had October, but if you could just give us some color <mark type="indiscernible" /> (57:51) what are your perspectives? We understand that the peace talks that started in Oslo are expected to last at least one year. I mean, is there any type of ceasefire or any type of suggestion of a relief in disruption during <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:10) do you expect &#x2013; I mean, the problems remain until the close of the negotiation? And that's it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Caio, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:22) we lost your <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:26) please repeat the questions? We followed the part on the attacks, but we missed the last part. Please repeat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'm sorry for that. I think the connection was bad. I just wanted an update. We understand third Q showed some improvement in relation to the second Q, but I want to know about October, what is the indication for the fourth quarter if you're going to see something similar to the third quarter or even better than that? And what are the expectations for the situation until we have some conclusion of the peace talks that started <mark type="ph" /> in Oslo? (58:54). I understand it's expected to last at least one year, so what we could expect from now on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It's two part. The first part what I want to mention is that you can observe is that we have been improved in terms of the delayed production. And if you observe during the first month we were presented a loss in production of around 10,000, 12,000 barrels per day. But the situation has improved due to the &#x2013; all strategies and all the work that we had developing with the authorities and also due to the reduction in terms of the recuperation times, but also in terms of the technology, work with the authorities and so on, with the social activities and in that sense, you are in the last quarter the impact of the attacks in terms of the production was only around 3,000 barrels per day. That means that &#x2013; yes, or it's strategies in conjunction with the works with the different authorities and different correlatives has resulted in a lower lost production due to the attacks to the infrastructure.</p>
          <p>On the other side, yes, in terms of the peace negotiation process, what is important to mention that <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:00:49) government has established, the process continue &#x2013; even continue during the war. And clearly, the army in Colombia, the military forces continue with its pressure to the guerillas, yes, and we can assure we are not going to have an impact, a reduction or increase in terms of attacks to the infrastructure. But really what I can confirm is that we continue working very hard with our &#x2013; with the authorities and the <mark type="ph" /> severance (1:01:30) related with this process to continue improving in terms of the lost production. But really, we can't make any commitment or any comment in terms of the impact of the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:01:43). Maybe in that sense, we can may refer to the official statements that are established by the President Santos and the official <mark type="ph" /> in charge of the problem (1:01:55).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for your question. There's no further questions at this moment in time, so I'll hand back to the speakers for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thank you, all, for your participation. For additional questions, you can contact us at Investor Relations and good afternoon. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so ladies and gentlemen, that concludes your call. You may now disconnect. Thank you for joining us. Do enjoy the rest of your day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>