<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1454996" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-02-16</date>
    <companies>
      <company>61998</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Investor Relations">Alejandro Giraldo</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Javier Genaro Guti&#xE9;rrez Pemberthy</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Exploration">Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez Convers</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Transportation">&#xC1;lvaro Casta&#xF1;eda Caro</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Vice President-Downstream">Pedro Alfonso Rosales Navarro</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Adriana Marcela Echeverri Guti&#xE9;rrez</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Banco JPMorgan SA">Caio Carvalhal</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Frank McGann</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Nathan G. Piper</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Tudor, Pickering, Holt &amp; Co.">Hubert van der Heijden</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Denis Parisien</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Interbolsa SA (Broker)">Juan David Pi&#xF1;eros Arenas</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to Ecopetrol's Presentation of the Fourth Quarter and Full Year Results for 2011. My name is <mark type="ph" /> Derrick (0:08), and I'll be your operator for today. At this time all participants are in a listen-only mode. We will facilitate a question-and-answer session at the end of the conference. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded for replay purposes.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Mr. Alejandro Giraldo, Investor Relations Director. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone, and welcome to Ecopetrol's fourth quarter and full year 2011 financial and operational results conference call. Before we begin, it is important to mention that the comments by Ecopetrol's senior management could include projections of the company's future performance. These projections do not constitute any commitment as to future results, nor do they take into account risks or uncertainties that could develop. As a result, Ecopetrol assumes no responsibility in the event that future results are different from the projections on the conference call.</p>
          <p>The call will be led by Mr. Javier Guti&#xE9;rrez, Chief Executive Officer of Ecopetrol. Also participating will be Adriana Echeverri, Chief Financial Officer; H&#xE9;ctor Manosalva, Executive Vice President for Exploration and Production; Pedro Rosales, Executive Vice President for Downstream; &#xC1;lvaro Casta&#xF1;eda, Vice President of Transportation and Logistics, and Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez, Vice President of Exploration.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez, CEO of Ecopetrol.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alejandro. Good afternoon. Thank you all for joining us in this conference call. Initially we will provide a summary of our key financial and operating results for the year 2011. Then we will review the outlook for 2012. And finally, we will answer questions from participants.</p>
          <p>So let's start with slide five to discuss on our performance in 2011. In 2011, Ecopetrol achieved the best financial and operational results in the history of the company, which once again demonstrates our commitment to deliver on our strategic goals and generate value to our stakeholders.</p>
          <p>Starting with the operational results, in the Exploration and Production segment, the Corporate Group achieved a new record in production of 724,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day, rising 18% compared to 2010. Along with higher production, the proved net reserves at December 31, 2011 grew 8% up to 1.86 billion barrels of oil equivalent and the reserve replacement ratio was 164%.</p>
          <p>In terms of exploration, we drilled 39 exploratory wells in Colombia and reached a technical exploratory success rate of 48%, which does not include wells under evaluation as of December 31. Successful wells in Colombia are located in the Llanos Orientales, mainly in the Ca&#xF1;o Sur block as well as in the Magdalena Valley.</p>
          <p>International successful wells were drilled by Savia in Peru, and partner and operator in the Logan-1 well in the U.S. Gulf Coast. In line with the rise in production, transported volume by pipelines grew 16%, reaching an average of 1.2 million barrels per day, mainly due to the expansion of the ODL and ODC pipelines. Additionally, we are on track with modernization projects of our refineries.</p>
          <p>The financial results were also historically high, driven by the growing production, effective cost control and favorable market environment. Group's revenues grew 57% up to COP$66 trillion, net income increased by 90% up to COP$15.5 trillion, and EBITDA rose 80% and amounted to COP$30 trillion</p>
          <p>The Strategic 2012-020 Plan was reviewed with growing investment allocated to exploration and production and focused in Colombia. Production targets remain unchanged, with a goal of 1 million barrels of oil equivalent in 2015 and 1.3 million barrels in 2020. Estimated CapEx amounts to US$80 billion, of which 75% is financed with internal cash generation.</p>
          <p>Also in 2011, the company achieved two key milestones in its capital markets strategy. The successful second round of equity offering with proceeds of COP$2.38 trillion and a investment grade ratings granted by Standard &amp; Poor's and Fitch. Moody's had granted investment grade to Ecopetrol since 2009. Finally, a major milestone in corporate responsibility was becoming part of the Dow Jones Sustainability Index as one of the 12 oil and gas companies included in the World Index.</p>
          <p>Now please turn to slide six to review the progress of our investment plan. The all-time high investment in 2011 was the driver to achieve the record operational and financial results. CapEx was 20% higher when compared to 2010 and came to US$7.2 billion. Capital expenditure allocation by segment was the following: 50% to production, 15% to midstream, 14% to subsidiaries, 8% to exploration, 6% to acquisitions, 5% to refining, and the remaining 2% to corporate and supply and marketing initiatives.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn the call to Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. In slide number seven, I would like to summarize the main achievements of the Upstream segment. In the year 2011, we reached outstanding results in this segment. The substantial CapEx allocated to E&amp;P has lead to sustained double-digit production growth. And increased activity in exploration <mark type="ph" /> amount (8:14) with a technical success rate of 48% for the Corporate Group and a reserve replacement ratio of 164%. Additionally, we have initiated exploration of unconventional resources.</p>
          <p>Now let's review in detail exploration results. 21 A3 wells were drilled by Ecopetrol in Colombia, of which nine proved hydrocarbon presence and nine is stratigraphic, with evidence of hydrocarbon in five of them. Also, 10 appraisal wells were drilled.</p>
          <p>Hocol, our Colombian subsidiary, drilled seven A3 wells, with hydrocarbon presence in two of them. And 13 is stratigraphic with hydrocarbon evidence in 11 of them. Internationally, Savia Per&#xFA; drilled seven exploratory wells in the Peruvian offshore, confirming evidence of hydrocarbons in five of them. Two wells were drilled in the U.S. Gulf Coast, proving hydrocarbon in the Logan well. Finally, two wells were drilled in Brazil by our partners, the Agua Viva-1 and the Ilha Do Mel wells because, which were plugged and abandoned. Finally, at the end of the year Luna well was being drilled. This is the third step of our strategy to incorporate reserves from unconventional reservoirs.</p>
          <p>Regarding production in the year 2011, the Corporate Group achieved a big gross production of 724,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day, growing 18% compared with the year 2010. This figure is lower than our target due to the impact of a harsh rainy season on the infrastructure, as well as operational and logistical restriction. And finally, limitations on the availability of transportation infrastructure.</p>
          <p>In the last quarter of the year 2011, the Corporate Group production averaged 742,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day, a 14% increase compared to the same period of the year 2010. The production growth was led by the increase in Castilla and Chichimene fields, which accounted for an average annual production of 110,000 barrels and 32,000 barrels per day, respectively. Rubiales and Quifa fields added to Ecopetrol a gross output of 113,000 barrels per day, and Nare field produced 16,000 barrels per day. In summary, we continue with fast pace on delivering a strong result.</p>
          <p>Now review in the slide eight the reserves addition at the close of 2011. Proved net reserves as of December 31 of 2011 amount to 1.86 billion barrels of oil equivalent, an 8% increase compared with year 2010, with a replacement ratio of 164%. The rise is due mainly to the extension of the proven area, revision on previous estimates in some fields and acquisition of Equion.</p>
          <p>It's important to mention that in the statement of proved reserves as of December 31, 2011 there are no additions from any of the discoveries in Colombia and abroad announced in the past two years due to well discoveries are still under appraisal and development activities.</p>
          <p>Between 2008 and 2011, Ecopetrol increased its net reserves by 63% from 1.14 billion to 1.86 billion barrels of oil equivalent. During the same period, the net production increased 64%, as we were able to add reserves at the same pace of production.</p>
          <p>Now I will turn the call over to our &#xC1;lvaro Casta&#xF1;eda, who will provide an update on our midstream operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. Please turn to slide nine. 2011 was also a strong year in terms of increasing our transportation volumes and expanding our infrastructure in crude and product timelines in storage and port facilities. It was also a challenging year mainly due to the difficulties caused by the hardest raining season ever in Colombia.</p>
          <p>Let me now review the highlight for our segment. In 2011, the transportation capacity grew 13% for crude oil and 27% for refined products. Those increases were mainly due to the expansion of the crude lines of Ocensa, Vasconia-Cove&#xF1;as ODC, Apiay-Porvenir, Ca&#xF1;o Lim&#xF3;n-Cove&#xF1;as, Ayacucho-Cove&#xF1;as, Rubiales-Monterrey, the product line of Pozos Colorados-Gal&#xE1;n, the starting of operation at Poliducto Andino, the optimization of pumping systems, and the use of drag-reducing agents. Additionally, storage capacity for crude oil up in Altos del Porvenir and Banad&#xED;a and for naphtha in Ayacucho.</p>
          <p>Also the storage capacity grew from 470,000 to 770,000 barrels per day in the Cove&#xF1;as Port. In line with the increases in capacity, 2011 total volume of crude and products transported by pipelines rose 15%, up to 1.2 million barrels per day, of which 76% account for crude. Crude and delivered volumes transported by truck reached 93,000 barrels per day in 2011.</p>
          <p>Regarding the Bicentenario Pipeline, at the end of 2011, the Banad&#xED;a terminal was already completed, and the line between Araguaney-Banad&#xED;a reported a 44% progress. In spite of all the programs and activities designed and developed according to our integrity assurance model, during the last quarter of 2011, the transportation infrastructure was badly affected by the heavy rainy season due to the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (16:07) events the 11 and 23 of December, respectively.</p>
          <p>The Ca&#xF1;o Lim&#xF3;n-Cove&#xF1;as pipeline and the Salgar-Cartago product line was affected due to the landslides caused by heavy rains that saturated the ground. The incident in the Salgar-Cartago line affected nearby communities in the Dosquebradas municipality.</p>
          <p>In order to anticipate potential events that might affect the transportation infrastructure, and consequently have an impact on the residents nearby, it is required to maintain our technical, human and economic efforts. Therefore, a project was implemented and two existing programs will be enhanced: the Dosquebradas project, the pipeline integrity program and the contingency program. The main objective of the Dosquebradas project is to restore housing and living standards of the community affected by the incident.</p>
          <p>The pipeline integrated program aims to strengthen the covered integrated assurance model of the company. Finally, the program that will improve the capability of managing contingencies to minimize potential effect on communities and the environment. I want to ratify that the company is fully committed to assure the reliability and safety of its operation, while continuing to expand its <mark type="indiscernible" /> (17:59) capacity to meet increasing requirements to transport goods and products.</p>
          <p>Now, I will turn the presentation over to Pedro Rosales, who will comment on downstream results, starting with refining.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. Let's move on to slide 10. In summary, 2011 was also a very positive year. In terms of our refining operation, margins sharply improved. Additionally, important progress was achieved in the modernization of our refineries, which are key projects of our strategic plan, not only due to the size of the investment, but also from the expected positive impact in the total stability of this segment.</p>
          <p>Operational results improved due to higher price differentials of products related to crude oil. Refining margin of Barrancabermeja Refinery grew 40% compared to 2010, up to US$11.22 per barrel. Also, in spite of the scheduled maintenance of one cracking unit in the fourth quarter, the Barrancabermeja Refinery throughput remained almost flat compared to 2010.</p>
          <p>Regarding the main projects on December 30, the financial closing for the expansion and modernization of the Cartagena Refinery was completed with a group of export credit agencies and commercial banks for an amount of US$3.5 billion. Ecopetrol offered the lenders a contingent warranty for payment of any amounts that Reficar may lack for debt servicing. This project, that allows Cartagena Refinery to double its crude processing capacity, reported an advance of 54% at the close of the year.</p>
          <p>Additionally, the Board of Directors approved the Phase III of the modernization project of the Barrancabermeja Refinery. It is worth mentioning the beginning of the selection process for contracting the site preparation and the awarding of the purchases of long lead items. The project had a progress over 85% in environmental licensing process. Finally, the market plan of utilities in these refineries, which will update the infrastructure for the supply of steam, air, water and energy, reached a 41% progress as of December 31.</p>
          <p>Now please turn to slide 11 to review the sales and marketing results. In terms of sales and marketing, 2011 was also a very strong year. The favorable market environment, the higher production and a successful strategy in terms of diversification of markets, as well as referencing our crudes to Brent and Maya benchmarks strengthened the Ecopetrol's presence in international markets, generating higher revenues.</p>
          <p>Let's now review in detail the highlights of these segments. The growth in sales volumes during 2011 was driven by the rising crude oil production, mainly of heavy crudes. In order to obtain better prices, Ecopetrol increased the use of Brent and Maya indexes for crudes and reduced WTI benchmark. In fact, there were no exports indexed to WTI in the last quarter of 2011. Therefore, the price of export baskets increased 38% for crude oil. Additionally, the export basket grew 37% for products and 25% for natural gas when compared to 2010.</p>
          <p>Total sales volume grew 17% in 2011. Export sales, including sales to the Cartagena Refinery, accounted for 67% and local sales for 33% of total sales. Exported volume, excluding sales to Reficar free trade zone, increased 33% boosted by the higher sales of Castilla and Middle Magdalena sour crudes and larger exports of natural gas to Venezuela.</p>
          <p>In 2011, Ecopetrol sales and trading strategy continued with its focus to increase its exports to more profitable markets. Despite the decrease in exports to the Far East, the increasing volumes sold to non-traditional destinations for our crudes of Caribbean, U.S. West Coast and Europe offset this situation.</p>
          <p>Finally, local sales volume dropped 3% during 2011 due to lower natural gas demand from thermal power generators and fewer deliveries of propane and LPG due to some pipeline problems during the harsh rainy reason. At the closing, Ecopetrol sales and trading strategy has proved to be successful in terms of capturing additional value from improving market conditions, as well as opening new markets for our crudes and products.</p>
          <p>I now will turn the presentation back to Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez, who will comment on the milestones, on the internal consolidation initiatives, and corporate social responsibility in 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Pedro. Let's turn to slide 12. 2011 was a challenging year for our organization. We faced very unfortunate incidents, which affected the community with loss of human lives. However, on the other hand, we had the lowest accident frequency rate in the history of the company. This is a significant milestone in HSE and a clear evidence of the efforts undertaken in the last years. Therefore, the incidents that took place in December of 2011 affecting the cities of C&#xFA;cuta and Dosquebradas strengthened our commitment of improving the safety and the reliability of our operations.</p>
          <p>In spite of these <mark type="ph" /> repeatable (25:42) events, HSE results improved in 2011. The accident frequency rate was 1.02 accidents per million working hours, the best historical results for the company and 35% lower than in 2010. In the last quarter of the year 2011, the rate was even lower, reaching 0.94 incident. There were 41 environmental incidents from operational causes, remaining unchanged versus 2010.</p>
          <p>Also, it is worth mentioning that Ecopetrol invested COP$214 billion in social initiatives, a 34% increase compared with the year 2010. Other key internal initiatives allowing savings in supply chain amounted to COP$381 billion in 2011.</p>
          <p>Lastly, in 2011 Ecopetrol became part of the Dow Jones Sustainability Index, where starting September 8 Ecopetrol joined to the group of 10% companies with the best sustainable performance out of the list of 2,500 public companies.</p>
          <p>As a closing for this section, I want to re-emphasize that Ecopetrol remains totally committed to a clean and safe production as a key element of its strategy.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn the presentation to Adriana Echeverri, who will comment on the financial results for the year 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez. Good afternoon, everyone. Let's turn to slide 14. During 2011, Ecopetrol financial results achieved a new record in terms of revenues, net income and EBITDA. This was driven by the increase in production and the higher prices.</p>
          <p>On the left side of the slide, it seems that in 2011 total sales went up 54% compared to 2010. Export sales rose 33% excluding sales to Reficar free trade zone. Total cost of sales plus operating expenses grew 20%, mainly due to the rise of 45% in variable costs as a result of larger volume of products imported, mainly naphtha to be used as diluents, and purchases of crude from the National Hydrocarbons Agency.</p>
          <p>In addition, rising crude oil production led to higher transportation costs. Fixed costs increased 19%, mainly because of higher depreciation in contracted services related to larger production and development of new fields.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses increased 34%, mainly due to rising administrative and commercial expenses related to transportation of exported crude. As a result of these factors, operating income amounted to COP$24 trillion in the year 2011, which is 82% increase compared to 2010, and the operating margin was 43%.</p>
          <p>Moving to the non-operating results, the loss of COP$1.2 trillion was mainly due to the negative results of hedging of crude oil differentials, which were partially offset by the exchange rate gains and the income coming from subsidiaries accounted under the equity method. Net income amounted to COP$15.5 trillion, which is 87% higher than 2010, while EBITDA amounted to COP$28 trillion.</p>
          <p>Now let's take a look to our segment results on slide 15. On this slide, we find that the Exploration and Production segment reported COP$15 trillion of net income in 2011, led by the spike in production and high crude oil sale prices. EBITDA for this segment reached COP$26 trillion.</p>
          <p>Refining and Petrochemical segment was benefited mainly from high margins of products. This segment reported a net loss of COP$600 billion, while EBITDA was targeted in COP$507 billion compared to a negative EBITDA of COP$218 billion in 2010.</p>
          <p>Transportation segment financial results were lower in 2011 than in 2010 due to the effect of maintenance costs and services required to repair the damages caused by the harsh rainy season, as well as <mark type="ph" /> damage (30:57) to the infrastructure. Net income reached COP$354 billion and EBITDA of this segment was COP$991 billion. Finally, Supply and Marketing segment recorded a net income of COP$226 billion and EBITDA amounted to COP$706 billion.</p>
          <p>On next slide, number 16, we find an overview of the company's cash flow and balance sheet as of the end of December. Ecopetrol began the year 2011 with COP$5.5 trillion in cash and tertiary investment, and received COP$2.2 trillion in cash from the second round of the equity offering. Operations generated COP$54 trillion. We used COP$13 trillion of the company's total cash flow to fund capital expenditures, COP$35 trillion to operations, and COP$6 trillion to pay dividend. This and other net cash flows resulted in COP$9.2 trillion cash and investments balance at the close of the year.</p>
          <p>Moving to our balance sheet, total assets amounted to COP$85 trillion and total liabilities COP$30 trillion. In the last quarter, total liabilities increased mainly due to a provision of COP$3.9 trillion for income tax generated by the higher net results. Financial debt was equivalent to 7.2% of total assets and to 20.4% of total liabilities, while debt-to-EBITDA ratio for the last 12 months was 0.22.</p>
          <p>Finally, the equity increased 32% in 2011 as a result of the rise in the net income and the addition of paid on capital as a result of the second round of the equity offering, offset by losses in the valuation of investments in Empresa de Energ&#xED;a de Bogot&#xE1; and ISA.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 17, we will review the results of the second round of the equity offering that's took place in 2011. This second equity offering was addressed exclusively to Colombian investors as ruled by Law 1118, and a total of 644 million shares were allotted, equivalent to close COP$2.4 trillion. As announced, the proceeds are to fund CapEx of the strategic plan of the company. Results from the offering were remarkable, given the difficult market conditions that we had to face during the offering.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to the main aspects of the results of the Corporate Group shown on slide 18. In line with Ecopetrol's results, in 2011 the Corporate Group reached record financial results. Total sales for the Corporate Group amounted to COP$66 trillion, which is 57% more than in 2010. Group's net income amounted to COP$15.5 trillion, with a contribution of COP$4 billion coming from the results of our subsidiaries. This represents a 90% increase with respect to year 2010. Group's EBITDA was COP$30 trillion, 80% higher than in 2010. EBTIDA margin was 46%.</p>
          <p>Now let's move on to slide 19 and see the main figures of our subsidiaries. In 2011, the main contributions to revenues before accounting eliminations came from Reficar with COP$7 trillion, Hocol with COP$4 trillion and Equion with COP$2 trillion. Highest net income came from Hocol with COP$630 billion, followed by Equion with COP$427 billion and ODL with COP$82 billion.</p>
          <p>Total contribution of the companies of the Group total net income was COP$552 billion as follows: upstream subsidiaries added COP$585 billion, transportation companies COP$58 billion and corporate companies COP$82 billion. On the other hand, refining and petrochemical subsidiaries reported a net loss of COP$173 billion, led by the loss of Reficar. Subsidiaries with the highest EBITDA were Hocol with COP$1.2 trillion, Equion with COP$459 billion and Ocensa with COP$299 billion.</p>
          <p>With this, I now turn the conference back to Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez to make a review of the progress in Ecopetrol's strategy since we launched the business plan back in 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Adriana. Turning now to slide 20, we can track the remarkable performance of Ecopetrol since we launched our strategic plan back in 2007. The growth in production, the higher profitability and the lower accident rate has been remarkable, especially in 2011. These results drive us to continue growing to fulfill our goals to 2012.</p>
          <p>The increased level of investments has leveraged the growth of the company. From 2008 to 2011 total CapEx amounted to US$33 billion, of which 54% billion was allocated to exploration and production, 32% to downstream and midstream, and 14% to acquisitions. So as you can see, Ecopetrol was able to meet and even exceed the goals initially set forth.</p>
          <p>Production grew 81% between 2007 and 2011. The company's proved reserves rose 54% between 2007 and 2011. Along with the production, transported volumes have increased 70% since 2007. Together with the fast pace growth of the company's operation, there was also a significant improvement in HSE. And most important, there has been a profitable growth. Along the years Ecopetrol increased its EBITDA and return on capital employed, and also its margins. With this solid base we face the future with a strong commitment to continue delivering on our promises to stakeholders. Now, I will like to recall some highlights about our business plan between 2012 and 2020.</p>
          <p>Let's move now to slide 22. As we announced in November of 2011, the strategic plan of the company was reviewed and updated, increasing the CapEx allocation to exploration and production, and decreasing the funding requirement from debt issuance.</p>
          <p>In summary, we reaffirm our main target to produce 1.3 million clean barrels of oil equivalent by 2020, which means with no accidents, nor environmental incidents, in harmony with our stakeholders and with profitable growth. Of this production, around 50% are expected to be of heavy crude.</p>
          <p>Estimated CapEx amounts to US$80 billion. Approximately 85% of the total CapEx is allocated to exploration and production, and 15% to refining, transport, commercialization biofuels and organizational consolidation. 90% of the investment is earmarked to project in Colombia. The remaining 10% will be allocated to exploration and production projects along the U.S. Gulf Coast and in Brazil and Peru.</p>
          <p>In order to achieve the production target, the average reserve life shall be 10 years in 2020 by adding 6,200 million barrels including royalties, and raising the recovery factors to 34% by means of enhanced oil recovery and improved oil recovery technologies. In line with this growth, transportation capacity shall expand to 1.7 million barrels per day.</p>
          <p>On the Refining and Petrochemical segment, the company will carry out the modernization and expansion plans of Barrancabermeja and Cartagena refineries, as announced. These investments will allow having cleaner and more valuable fuel production that adds value to heavy crude.</p>
          <p>On biofuels, the production target is 450,000 tons per year in 2020. 2020 the company also expects to have a strong midstream business, with integral transport and logistics solutions that's guarantee an excellent quality service and <mark type="ph" /> an adequate (41:25) transportation of crude and products to all companies. Every business segment shall comply with the three-year return on capital employed criteria for the investments included in the plan as follows: 28% in exploration and production, 11% in transportation, and 13% in petrochemicals. Refining rates will range between 9% and 11% in 2025.</p>
          <p>Regarding the resources on funding based on the current forecast for hydrocarbon prices and the strong cash generation of the company, the strategic plan is expected to be financed 75% from internal cash generation, 16% with debt and 9% with primary share offerings as part of the capitalization process. Our strategic plan is sound based on a commitment to produce 1 million clean barrels of oil equivalent in 2015 and 1.3 million clean barrels of oil equivalent per day in year 2020.</p>
          <p>Let's move on to slide 23 to detail the main projects entailed in our CapEx for 2012. The investment plan approved for 2012 amounts to US$8.5 billion, of which US$7.5 billion are expected to be invested directly in Ecopetrol and US$1 billion through companies of the Corporate Group. This amount does not consider any potential acquisitions, which will be evaluated on a case-by-case basis by the administration and the Board of Directors when required.</p>
          <p>94% of the CapEx is allocated to projects in Colombia, and the remaining 6% is to exploration and production projects along the U.S. Gulf Coast, Brazil and Peru where Ecopetrol holds interest. US$4 billion are allocated to production in order to reach an average level of 750,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day 2012. Ecopetrol's Corporate Group's production is expected to achieve an average of 800,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day. Roughly 57% of the investment will be carried out in the Llanos Orientales region.</p>
          <p>Exploration segment should invest US$1.4 billion, including the drilling of 42 wells, of which 37 will be in Colombia and five abroad. Of the Colombian wells, 28 wells will be drilled in the Llanos Orientales region, while others will be drilled in the Magdalena Valley, Catatumbo, Piedemonte and the Caribbean offshore. The company will also continue searching for unconventional resources starting in the Middle Magdalena region.</p>
          <p>In refining, petrochemicals and biofuels, the estimated total CapEx amounts to US$1.8 billion, of which US$0.6 billion will be contributed by Ecopetrol and US$1.2 billion by Reficar. The investment will be allocated primarily to the industrial services project, operational improvement plan and the upgrade of Barrancabermeja and Cartagena refineries. Investments in biofuels are included to contributions to Bioenergy.</p>
          <p>Transportation investments amount to US$2 billion, including contributions to the subsidiaries, Oleoducto del Bicentenario and Oleoducto de Colombia. Also, US$318 million are allocated to other investments, including research and development and information technology. Those investments entail <mark type="ph" /> US$116 million (46:35) for, among others, testing air injection technology at Chichimene field and other investment in new upstream businesses opportunities and the continuity of the operations.</p>
          <p>Finally, the CapEx for the Group's companies amounts to US$4.5 billion, of which Ecopetrol will provide US$1 billion. The remaining sources should come from cash generation of each company, commercial financing and the contribution of third parties or partners.</p>
          <p>Let's close the call with some highlights about the outlook for 2012 in slide 24. In 2012, Ecopetrol will continue on its path to grow and achieving all of our strategic goals. As we mentioned, we forecast production for our Corporate Group to average 800,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day. Regarding exploration activity, we expect to drill 42 exploratory wells, 37 in Colombia, three in U.S. Gulf Coast and two in Brazil.</p>
          <p>In transportation, we will continue with our infrastructure projects, and along with our partners we expect to complete the first phase of the Bicentenario Pipeline by the second quarter of 2012. Also, capacity in Transandino Pipeline will be increased to 85,000 barrels per day, as well as in the product line of Pozos Colorados-Galan to 120,000 barrels per day.</p>
          <p>In refining, we will continue on track with updating and modernization projects of our refineries, expecting to reach in 2012 at least 85% and 10% progress in Cartagena and Barrancabermeja refineries, respectively.</p>
          <p>Regarding our commercial strategy, we will keep our efforts to diversify destinations to our exports, and locally we will promote natural gas consumption for vehicles and industries. In biofuels, we shall make progress in Bioenergy on most industrial and agricultural aspects in order to produce ethanol in the first half of 2013. We also shall continue all efforts to improve our HSE performance, and the safety and reliability of our operations.</p>
          <p>As final comment, 2012 is a year with new challenges, not only in delivering growth and profitability, but also in the improvement of our operation. The positive results of 2011 build the confidence in our organization's capability of delivering on future goals for all of our stakeholders.</p>
          <p>Now I open the session to questions from our participants. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And our first question is coming from the line of Caio Carvalhal from JPMorgan. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. I have a specific question related to the crude price, to the realization of crude price. I see in the slide 11 that you managed to increase significantly, 38% year-over-year, and you mentioned that this is mainly connected to the inclusion of the Brent as a reference in the 2011 basket. I would like to understand a little bit how does it work, and how is it &#x2013; how you managed to increase your crude price higher than the average of WTI and Brent without, of course, changing the quality of the crude? Is it just a matter of trading? How does it work? Because, I mean, ideally if that's an advantage, why not index more than 24% going forward to Brent rather than Maya or WTI? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Caio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Caio actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for your question. And Pedro Rosales is going to take the answer, and if it is necessary, Adriana is going to complement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Pedro, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. You see in our numbers, we have a movement from our indexes. That is mainly caused by our way to develop that sales. Mainly, our function to do that is to obtain the best price of our crudes. Then what we are doing is to review which is the best alternative to realize our crude. Then the reference is only &#x2013; the index that we use is only one of the factors that we take into account. At the end, the objective function is the best price for our crudes. Then because of the situation of the WTI in the Cushing area, our benchmark moved to Brent or Maya, because we have the possibility to obtain better prices for our crudes. But this is a situation that evolves depending on the situation of the markets, and what we are doing is to search which are the best alternatives to realize our crudes and the markets that needs that crudes and pay more for that crude. That's the way, and the result is the index, but is not the way to obtain the price. It's only the result of the process that we do to obtain the better price for our crudes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And additionally, maybe it is important to mention that we have a important increase in the heavy oil production the last year. It was the main source of our increase in production and different in the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (54:18) spread, reviews we compare the heavy oil with medium and light crudes. It is also influencing that situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is coming from the line of Frank McGann from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hello. Good afternoon. Just to focus a little bit more on exploration, particularly in Colombia, you're going to drill 42 wells. I was just wondering &#x2013; 37 in Colombia. I was just wondering if you could perhaps give us a little bit more information on Ca&#xF1;o Sur. And exactly where we stand in terms of declaration of commerciality and potential quantification of that area? And where will most of the 37 wells be drilled during 2012, any particular regions or blocks that you're focusing on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Frank. We're going to refer to where we are going to drill the 37 exploratory wells, but additionally we're going to make some comments about the Ca&#xF1;o Sur block in particular. Okay? Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez is taking the answer, Frank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Frank. How is it going?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Frank, we will drill, as you mentioned, 43 wells &#x2013; 42 wells next year; 28 of them we will drill in Llanos, three in the Middle Mag Valley, two offshore, two in the Upper Mag Valley and one in <mark type="indiscernible" /> (56:00).</p>
          <p>Regarding &#x2013; I mean, how many in Ca&#xF1;o Sur? We will drill, let me say, like more than 13 of them in Ca&#xF1;o Sur, and the main idea is to complete the appraisal stages as well as development. As you know, we &#x2013; in Ca&#xF1;o Sur, we are completing <mark type="ph" /> certain (56:27) activities at the moment, one is exploring, other one is appraisal, and other one is producing in early production facilities. So, I mean, the whole idea behind this campaign is to complete, as soon as possible, the evaluation of the area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Do you have any idea when we might have information as to the potential size of the block or the discovery?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Frank, as you know, we need to declare commerciality in the area, and we are focused mainly in the east part of the Ca&#xF1;o Sur. So hopefully by &#x2013; maybe by the third quarter of this year, we have at least one or two commercialities and we can release some information regarding about the size of the discovery. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Frank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is coming from the line of Nathan Piper from RBC Capital Markets. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I wanted to ask you one specific question around the OBC pipeline, and really around how confident you are that you will complete the Phase I of that at the end of Q2. I think you talked about June as being a target. And then after that, if I could ask you a little bit more about your ambition to increase your reserve's life. Although you have increased reserves quite a bit, your reserve life remains around about the six or seven year level. What in particular is going to increase your reserves to the extent that you'll have 10 years reserves life that you're looking for? Maybe I'll start &#x2013; ask about the pipeline first, and then explore your reserves growth second?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. First, thank you, Nathan. We are going to refer to the Poliducto and Bicentenario operation date. And then we're going to refer to the strategy to increase our reserves during the next year and going to the relation of 10 in the year 2020. Okay. Pedro Rosales is taking the first part of the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Nathan, good afternoon. For Poliducto and Bicentenario, our target is to begin that operation in the third quarter of this year. We are making all the efforts in the technical aspects. The construction is running well, but we have some difficulties that are &#x2013; we are managing to obtain that target to begin at the third quarter of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe it's important to mention, and Pedro could correct me, that right now we have another advance of around &#x2013; 45%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>45.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>45%. Maybe up to now we have construct, er, 100 kilometers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The land &#x2013; the total &#x2013; maybe you remember the total -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Length.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Length of the land is 230 kilometers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. In relation with reserves &#x2013; okay. In relation with the reserves &#x2013; okay. The strategy -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess what I'm trying to get to on the reserves is that obviously, enhanced oil recovery is going to be a key aspect of your reserves increases. And I just wonder if there is a technology that you're more enthusiastic about, or where you think the big reserves adds are going to come from, to let you achieve the reserves life you hope for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. In terms of the reserves, we have a three-folded strategy. The main part is based on the increase of the recovery factor in the current areas. Right now, we are in a reference number of around 16% and our strategy is going up to 34%. And second, we are &#x2013; based on the exploratory activities, we have been strengthening our portfolio and around approximately 2,800 million barrels are coming from exploratory efforts, part from the conventional resources and part from the unconventional resources. And approximately 1,600 million are from the national market &#x2013; from the national areas and 800 million for the international areas. The growth numbers, Enrique, would complement in relation with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I would like to add that the 95% of production comes from primary recovery. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is coming from the line of Hubert van der Heijden from Tudor, Pickering, Holt. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Could you discuss about &#x2013; on the exploration appraisal side a little bit more about the appraisal process at CPO-9, and when would you expect to potentially declare commerciality there and start full development? And also, is one of your &#x2013; or when do you expect some of your budgeted wells to hit new exploration targets on this block?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Hubert. Enrique is taking the question, but it's important to remember that CPO-9 is in the exploratory stage &#x2013; continuous exploratory stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Hubert. Basically in CPO-9, we are in the process of appraisal, as you mentioned, and we are waiting for a environmental license in order to complete at least three wildcats or exploratory wells. Hopefully, we got the license coming soon. Then we drill Akacias-2 and Akacias-3. And also &#x2013; sorry, in that sense we expect to, maybe by the third quarter of this year, have some information that allow us to ask for commerciality. Okay? Regarding other activity in the block, we plan to drill the well <mark type="ph" /> Umadaya with H, Umadaya (1:03:40) Southwest also maybe by the second quarter of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That is helpful. Thank you. And one other question. Looking at the natural gas price increases, I was wondering, is this mainly driven by stronger local market pricing power? Or is it driven by exports, and how should we think about natural gas pricing realizations going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Hubert. Pedro Rosales is taking the answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good afternoon. Our price &#x2013; the prices of our natural gas are defined according to the contract that are taken into account. The main source for our natural gas is to fund by <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:04:39) of the country and the price of that gas is referred to a basket that is composed by the price of the fuel oil and by the price of the natural gas from the Henry Hub. Then the prices for the previous period of that basket increases as the fuel oil increase, then the price of our general basket increases too. The export price is referred as the same &#x2013; at the same price of that sales. The total basket take advantage of the increase of the fuel oil in the previous period of six months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is coming from the line of Denis Parisien from Deutsche Bank. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much for taking my question, and congratulations on the strong results. I'm wondering about your financing plans in 2012. Will you be coming to international bond markets? Will you be doing something in the domestic bond markets and lending markets? And are you going to be doing more equity raising this year? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Denis. Adriana Echeverri, our Chief Financial Officer, is taking the answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. For the financial year 2012, we have not thought of any new approximation to international bond markets or equity rising <mark type="ph" /> thing (66:28). We are already done the last round of our capitalization programs last year. This year, the main financing will come from our cash and internal cash generation resources. And we will also &#x2013; are planning on the divestment of certain non-strategic assets, and that's part of what we have for this year, but no capital markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Denis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is coming from the line of Juan Pi&#xF1;eros from Interbolsa.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Just had one question. Regarding the proved reserves that you recently reported and the addition that comes from improved recovery, I wanted to know why this last item was significantly lower from the addition that you achieved in 2010. So I want to know, how are the improved recovery projects advancing? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Juan. Okay, just a minute. Maybe you can be more specific in terms of what figures are you referring, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. In last report, you added 15 million barrels from improved recovery, and in 2010 you reported 47 million barrels. So I wanted to know why there is a drastic decrease in this item, and you know that this is one important source for reserves addition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just a minute please, Juan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Enrique Vel&#xE1;squez, Juan. The figures come from Cantagallo and Casabe fields. And these &#x2013; I mean, those fields are in the second stage. So, as you know, I mean, first stages are better, so we are working in improved recovery technologies and &#x2013; I mean, we expect this year to continue improving. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Going forward, what can we expect from these items for reserves addition? Do you expect that other fields, different from Cantagallo and Casabe, add more reserves?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it could be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Juan, currently we have more than 21 pilot projects for water injection for our fields in Colombia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, I show no further audio questions in queue. I would like to turn the call back over to Mr. Guti&#xE9;rrez for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Mr. Giraldo, our Relations Capital Director.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So thank you all for participation. For any additional questions, you can contact us at the Investor Relations Department. And have a good afternoon. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that concludes today's conference. We thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>