<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1247110" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Interim 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>45590</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Pierre Gadonneix, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Daniel Camus, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">Dominique Lagarde</participant>
      <participant id="3">Jean-Louis Mathias</participant>
      <participant id="4">Bernard Dupraz</participant>
      <participant id="5">Vincent de Rivaz</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, welcome, and welcome for being with us today before the summer break. In a context that is deteriorated by the global economic prices, you'll be hearing about our financial results attesting to the excellent resilience of the group's &#x2013; EDF Group's business in the first half-year.</p>
          <p>Revenues, slightly under 35 billion, is up 8.2%. EBITDA at &#x20AC;10 billion is up 12.2%. Net attributable income has been stable around &#x20AC;3 billion, with the net debt reaching &#x20AC;36.8 billion, up 12 billion versus year-end 2008, most of which &#x2013; i.e., 10.8 billion linked to the acquisition of British Energy as previously announced. And Daniel Camus will let you know later our debt-to-income ratio is in line with the average in the industry. Thanks to our financial structure, we've been able to benefit doubly from one of the best ratings in the industry environment to access to the financial capital markets of all types under excellent conditions. And as you've noted, we've been able since the beginning of the year to borrow &#x20AC;14 billion on the various markets including the successful corporate bond issue reserved for private investors. That collected over the &#x20AC;3 billion from approximately 300,000 subscribers.</p>
          <p>The financial results from the first half-year does demonstrate a sound financial performance, characterized by a sharp growth of our international business, boosted by the integration of British Energy since the 1st of January this year. Let me add &#x2013; and that is not including the accounts yet, that we currently have two deals currently being finalized, one in Belgium with a stake to takeover at SPE, the second largest energy operator in Belgium; and in the U.S., the acquisition of half of the Constellation's nuclear facilities. Both deals will be consolidated by the end of the year, and they will be boosting this dynamics of profitable growth outside of France.</p>
          <p>Of course we are undergoing a period of crisis that is affecting all industries. The energy industry of course is affected as well, perhaps not as much as others, but still affected in at least two ways. The first impact is lower prices; secondly, lower volumes. Looking at prices, the significant drop in electricity prices on European wholesale markets has dropped 30% between half-year one 2008 and half-year one 2009 as shown on this graph. This was &#x2013; the price drop was differentiated depending on the markets, with the three major markets shown here, U.K., France and Germany, which had &#x2013; which really at different levels have now converged to the current levels. And lower consumption of electricity as well as natural gas concerned primarily the industrial sector, perhaps less domestic consumption, explaining that the decrease in consumption is highly differentiated depending on the countries.</p>
          <p>In France, the consumption decrease was least significant, first of all because of the proportion of domestic users who've only reduced their consumption by approximately 2%; and of course, climate &#x2013; the climate conditions that were favorable to us with a cold winter, meaning that lower consumption in France is limited at less than 1% while it is more significant in the rest of Europe. Based on this today, I can tell you that for EDF the global crisis we're suffering has had an impact of less than 2% on our financial accounts, much more limited than in other industrial sectors. Zooming in on France, naturally what is clear in France is that we are perusing the resumption of capital expenditures as announced, the policy that was initiated in 2005 and reaching a common point in 2009, most likely 2009 will be the year where we'll be investing the most even though we'll continue to invest in future years.</p>
          <p>And these resumed CapEx over the first-half of 2009 is reflected by a growth of 36% versus last year, up to 3.4 billion. This 7.5 billion of CapEx planned in France are intended first of all to improve the availability of the generation assets. And these investments of course are essential to reach our target of KD availability of 85% by 2011, this is investments. We'll also prepare for the extended lifespan of our generation plants in terms of maintenance and the CapEx also are designed to continue improving the security of our networks. Out of the 7.5 billion, you see nearly half of which &#x2013; in dark blue here on the graph, nearly half of which are allocated to network quality, the amounts of which are set by the regulator. So, a sharp growth that means &#x2013; we're investing, you see, as compared with 2006, we're investing twice as &#x2013; much more than twice as much as in 2006, both in the network regulated sector and for the generation assets.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> the first half-year 2009 was affected by a number of exceptional events. I'll only mention two of which &#x2013; namely the storms earlier this year, which affected the southwest of France with major impacts. We're estimating a cost of approximately &#x20AC;100 million for the EDF. Second major or exceptional event are linked to the strikes that took place at &#x2013; primarily at our ERDF, the distribution subsidiary, and in our power plants. The impact for the half-year is approximately &#x20AC;270 million, linked primarily to a loss of nuclear power generation of approximately 7.6 terawatt-hours.</p>
          <p>In spite of that, I'd like to confirm that industrial dialogue has been continuing within the company in a very constructive manner. We've made major progress, we've signed a number of important agreements during the first half-year. And since this is linked to the availability of our power plants, we have in particular signed an agreement to readjust working organization during the maintenance shutdown on our nuclear reactor in order to reduce the duration of the shutdowns, which of course in turn contributes to improve the availability of the plants.</p>
          <p>Internationally now, the dynamics of our business has been largely confirmed and international business has been driving our results upwards, primarily due to the integration of British Energy in the U.K. since the 1st of January, as well as the excellent performance of British Energy, EDF Trading as well as EDF &#xC9;nergie Nouvelle, in wind and solar driving these results upwards. International sales have grown nearly 15%, i.e., five times faster than <mark type="inaudible" />. And EBITDA or gross income internationally has grown 40% versus the first half of last year due primarily and boosted by the integration of British Energy.</p>
          <p>In terms of business, we are reaching a level very close to what I had indicated a couple of years ago, namely that we are truly becoming a genuine international group and approximately half of our business is now apparently outside of France, which in fact puts us in -- on the same level with the major peers in our industry. Today, we can indeed say that EDF has become an international group whose expansion is driven by a profitable growth strategy outside of its historical volumes. This option to go international was in fact the only choice that can guarantee the industrial future of the company, both because of the liberalization, that means that market losses on historical markets must be offsets by international growth, but also &#x2013; this is also an opportunity with the nuclear revival and the development of low CO2 technologies where EDF's ambitions to be a leader and that will be the battlefield for the benchmark technologies of the future. Clearly, we can now confirm that the acquisition of British Energy has created value and it's in line with EDF's development strategy.</p>
          <p>In the U.K., this acquisition has turned EDF Energy into the leading British electricity operator. It has also turned EDF into the major operator of nuclear revival in the U.K. Today we enjoy the size and the necessary skills to build a series of four EPRs with a targeted commissioning of the first EPR reactor in 2017. I have recently met with Prime Minister, Gordon Brown, together with main nuclear leaders in the U.K. and I have been able to confirm the British authorities' determination to reach this goal of commissioning the very first nuclear reactor in 2017, which will be essential for success. There can be no expansion of nuclear power without major political commitments of state governments. This is true everywhere, in China, France, in the United Kingdom and everywhere else. I thought somebody was going to say Abu Dhabi, but nobody did.</p>
          <p>More seriously, the integration of British Energy is a tremendous success that has continued at a stepped-up pace. I am very pleased to be able to tell you that and to report that the operation of all British Energy nuclear reactors has started again during the first half-year. In other words, the entire portfolio &#x2013; nuclear portfolio is now in operation for the first time since October 2007 leading to increase of British Energy generation of 34%, hence a result that is somewhat better than we had even expected.</p>
          <p>And all of this together means that the contribution of British Energy to our operational &#x2013; operating income, EBITDA, expect &#x2013; exceeds our expectations, in excess of &#x20AC;900 million over the first half-year, i.e., nearly 10% of the group's EBITDA. These highly satisfactory results attest to the high quality of British Energy's assets, and when I'm saying asset I mean both industrial assets as well as Human Resources whose know-how and expertise has been confirmed and acknowledged. Hence, this acquisition that we made at a price comparable to other deals in this sector has proved to be profitable and value creating for EDF.</p>
          <p>The entry of Centrica in the capital of British Energy, you remember that Centrica proved this acquisition with a symbolic discount of 6% versus the price we paid for a minority stake. This has completed this assessment. In addition, the Centrica deal will enable us &#x2013; while receiving &#x20AC;1.2 billion in cash, will enable us to take over the control of the second largest Belgium energy operator, namely SPE.</p>
          <p>And all though you already know it, I'd like to repeat here today that the British Energy transaction did not cost $0.01 to French power consumers or tax payers. It was financed by borrowings and by the operating cash flow of British Energy, which will cover the full financial costs linked to the acquisition debt.</p>
          <p>I'll now ask Daniel Camus to present the financial results in detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So, good morning. Since we've something like 50 people connected on Internet, I think for the courtesy and <mark type="inaudible" />, most of them outside France I think, I'll try to do my presentation in English language. To make it with translation at a distance is always a bit more challenging. I can do some of the Q&amp;A in French afterwards.</p>
          <p>So, if I start maybe next slide with a quick &#x2013; a bit more I'll try, but little bit slower in a bit more detail since some of you probably have a need for better understanding of some of the numbers. Just to explain, on sales, like as you see increases 8.2%, 4.9% on an organic basis and close to 15% outside France, so way slower in France, 2.8%. And to explain this I will come back to the international part of the business in a minute, but if I explain in a few words, the breakdown of this 2.8% in France, I would say, it's 1.3% in electricity, 1.5% in gas and other services. I mean it's just bidding up the cash position, but with small margin. On electricity, I mean the 1.3% can be read like this. It is a positive impact of price and tariffs of 3.5% and a volume decline &#x2013; volume mix decline of 2.2% to explain the 1.3. I mean obviously, in the present tariffs most of it is tariff. Out of this 3.5, 3.3% is tariff.</p>
          <p>On &#x2013; as far as EBITDA is concerned, you see the various <mark type="inaudible" />, yeah, 12% increase, 40% if you include BE. I just explained the 9.041 does not include BE. The 10.1 billion includes BE. So when I quote 2.4% organic growth, it is excluding BE, it's a comparable parameter and we've done this additional computation at the bottom for the simple reason that the BE data pro forma on top of it as it's published at the end of March, so we have <mark type="inaudible" /> everything. So, if you have BE on both sides, the organic growth of 2.4% becomes 6.6% and 11% becomes 21% on &#x2013; overall, and I think so that you have the global dynamic, it's pro forma, it's already audited, but these are the real numbers, so I can't say so.</p>
          <p>Obviously France shows a totally different development, declining 1.8%, strongly impacted by several unfavorable factors and I would say showing despite that strong resistance because as you would see &#x2013; but clearly a different <mark type="inaudible" /> France and I would be more detailed on each of them in a minute.</p>
          <p>EBITDA, now to the next level of income, I mean net income &#x2013; if the slide would move. So, EBIT increasing 14%, this is the impact of one &#x2013; we've only one exceptional of significance in these accounts, it is the contribution of our right in Emosson into Alpiq, 303 million pre-tax, 209 million after-tax, so basically included in the EBIT. Net income as reported, it just happened to be on an equal level, 3.1%, despite what happened in France during this semester, and if you restate the standard way just restating Emosson, I mean that's the only one, as you see we had 2.92 billion on a constant perimeter for slightly decline &#x2013; of 4% as we had said that net income would not increase.</p>
          <p>FFO, good development, I'd say positive surprise also for us. I see &#x2013; as you know we concluded at the end of the year on a negative free cash flow, I mean 2008. At the end of June, we've an FFO of 6.9 billion and a free cash flow after working capital and CapEx of 1.7 billion, an increase of 1.2 billion. You have in the three bullets at the bottom, the three key explanations; better earnings, better FFO, 0.5 billion, and improvement in networking capital of 2.2 billion. And in there you have &#x2013; you may remember that at the end of the year we had a very negative impact about <mark type="inaudible" /> the cost in EDF trading and optimization. So we've the reversal of the margining calls and the development of raw material prices obviously is up. So, out of this 2.2 billion, you have 1.6 billion that are basically the contribution of the very negative impact on working capital of last year in terms of margining call. CapEx, a negative, since it is an increase of 1.5 billion or 35% in France.</p>
          <p>So, for the &#x2013; now I'll start with international activities. Obviously, as Pierre said, we're now going through a very positive momentum, any percentage you can take and analyze here shows that there is a good and strong momentum in existing activities as well as in British Energy, the newcomer in the group. I mean you see 11% organically and EBIT even stronger. We also stress the point, and as Pierre said before, that CapEx are self financed. Today, if I can quote only two numbers, existing parameter, the CapEx &#x2013; FFO of International was 2.2 billion and the CapEx in the same period was 2.1 billion, so fully financed during the period.</p>
          <p>So, let's start with the U.K., which is clearly the growing component of EDF in this semester. As you see, there are &#x2013; <mark type="inaudible" /> the times in the past some weaknesses in the &#x2013; in this case, we have good strong solid numbers. Sales increasing 15% organically, EBITDA increasing 27% helped by a small impact of IAS 39, we see that organic growth becomes 10%. But globally, I see good &#x2013; delivered very good numbers in production and a good resistance in the networks, I mean despite the current economic environment in the U.K. that is pretty deteriorated. As you know, it increased by 2% during the period and you see that be &#x2013; that the orange part of the chart be now represent roughly 60% of the total EBITDA of the group in U.K. Pierre already touched it &#x2013; touched on that &#x2013; upon that in his presentation. You'll see you have the exact numbers of output related to British Energy. We had planned that, but it is better when you can confirm it. Every reactor is now online, an increase of output from &#x2013; nuclear from 20.3 to 27.3 terawatt-hour plus 34%, EBITDA also obviously in strong growth, 936 million during the period.</p>
          <p>Maybe, a few minutes as we had promised on PPA, what we're calling the PPA, I mean basically the purchase price allocation. We had promised that we would deliver or present to you this breakdown with the six months numbers. I mean the purchase time, I know it's basically a lot of work and the set of data at least now have been fully audited. Basically, let's &#x2013; I'll just walk briefly through each part, so I think everybody understand what's behind it. Historical value is what it is for existing nuclear plants. The 7.5 billion reflects a very detailed computation, reactor-by-reactor, price projection, quantities, I mean basically assessing the economic value of that existing fleet, at least 7.2 billion, a few more technical adjustments. I mean fair value of commodity contracts, this was basically a negative valuation of mark-to-market of the trading book at the time, a few others, the two major ones is evaluation of the brand. These are immaterial and also some inventories included to see roughly 600 million. The deferred tax liability related to the plant revaluation, obviously these appears with time as the depreciation of the new fixed assets levels happen over time during the existing life span of the plant. So this becomes zero at the end, but the recognition of a deferred tax. The difference &#x2013; I mean 7.2 billion, the difference is I think the goodwill, I do not need to explain. So &#x2013; but the goodwill is a reflection that has been also computed and very slowly documented and sustained are basically of essentially three major contributors. Part of it is the recognition of the additional &#x2013; part of the additional value related to the new build, okay, another second component is the recognition. We use various scenarios, but we are very comfortable on that front of various scenarios of potential life extensions of existing plants and obviously valuation of some of the synergies.</p>
          <p>All of this computed to 5.3 billion. 5.3 billion represents 42% of the purchase price. And if you look at the full balance sheet of EDF, it makes our total goodwill is now at 6% of the total goodwill, which actually is the lowest number of the whole industry by far. It's a factor as obviously it's just a way to measure it, to 12.6 billion purchased price or 13.5 billion in euro, all included.</p>
          <p>Now, a few words about &#x2013; this is for the U.K., a good start, as you know good business dynamics. ENW has shown, I mean our three large listed entities have already published their numbers, ENW, Edison, EDF &#xC9;nergie Nouvelle, just a few reminders. EBITDA &#x2013; I mean the best way to characterize the performance of the ENW is as a good and &#x2013; good strong resistance in a very difficult market. I think Germany is doing even more poorly than France economically. And if you just drill on one number, if you look at B2B, I mean industrial customers, their consumption declined 11% in Germany, excuse me 21% in Germany, despite a decline of 21%, basically out also with some IAS 39, slight plus in there, the company has been able to repeat plus 2%, the level of EBITDA achieved last year.</p>
          <p>Italy, I would say &#x2013; also I mean Italy, as you've seen on the charts of Pierre before, in terms of decline of consumption, it is the most rate I mean overall and I would say Edison that is a pure producer is even -- been more exposed to that trend. Out of the 13.8%, Edison represent 9.5%, a decline. So &#x2013; and if you &#x2013; it's not on that chart, but despite that and as they started the year something like minus 40% in January, February and been steadily through massive actions on OpEx and CapEx and they have been able to basically come back to minus 10%. And as you know, in their guidance we stated the objective to be stable, repeat last year's performance, despite this difficult timing. And if you take that net income, it's not on the chart, under 22 million for the semester, which is then 20% above last year with some benefits of tax impact.</p>
          <p>Just on <mark type="inaudible" /> what's happening on hydrocarbon, I mean gas. This is the consumption by &#x2013; of gas by industrial producers and customers in Italy has declined by 22% in S1, which is the lowest level ever reached since World War 2 in Italy. I mean that's &#x2013; and they managed to do minus 13% in that environment in cash flow. I would say battling the case <mark type="inaudible" /> and I would say protecting the EBITDA with a repeat of last year's performance.</p>
          <p>As you know, we will now breakdown other international and other activities to give more visibility. On other international, which essentially now you see for 70% at Central and Eastern Europe, good numbers, Poland is a major driver, but also not <mark type="inaudible" /> remaining activities in Brazil, all did pretty well. Other activities, I know it's literally made out of three components, one is EDF Trading, EDF &#xC9;nergie Nouvelle and Dalkia. Dalkia, stable and an EBITDA of 145 million in the semester for us, totally stable. EDFT, again year-after-year delivering improved performance, increased 11%, which is 570 million in this number for the semester; and EDF &#xC9;nergie Nouvelle I see the numbers have been released yesterday, and she has basically grown double-digit, very successful basically, some say, ignoring the current environment, but very successful as a result of the development plan that basically unfolds both in wind and solar with an EBITDA progression of 64% and net income progression of 53% for the semester. I see nothing to add, but a good growth driver also for the group.</p>
          <p>Now let's come to France. I mean France needs a bit &#x2013; few more explanations obviously. So, number are not you know as positive as international. I mean it's clearly slower growth, here you have the basic numbers, 1.8% decline of EBITDA. CapEx, you know the numbers, 3.4, and basically impact of few factors of external origin and some that are more internally driven.</p>
          <p>I'll start with the top line and go through the cost items one-by-one. On top line, because first of all production. On production, here you have the usual breakdown, your peer quarter before, the 7.6% terawatt decline, this is significant, and this has an impact on this &#x2013; in the semester of 270 million. If you could ask yourself, is there another impact to expect for the remaining of the year because there is some disruption on &#x2013; maintenance plans of the plant, the answer is yes, there is also an impact in S2, in H2. In H2, we &#x2013; for the full year we expect an impact of 450 million, including 270 in H1. One word about the Kd and availability factor, the definition of EDF historically or has it been this way, does not include environment or social unrest computation. Our statement here today is, it is the underlying objective and the plan &#x2013; our maintenance plants we can show you, a few questions on that we can discuss after, remains at 81% and the objective in 2011 is obviously at 85 is also concerned &#x2013; confirmed.</p>
          <p>Now to &#x2013; on the demand side; on the demand side I think two messages, we had lower production but we had also favorable weather conditions. I mean for this year it was a bit better than last year. The message to keep in mind here, you see the impact &#x2013; included the impact on the end customers, basically minus one point &#x2013; and it's of course minus 1% on the semester. I see decline in industrial customers, but also obviously always offset by the residential consumption and users.</p>
          <p>Now a few words will be on &#x2013; I'm sure you have a few questions on that, on the detailed P&amp;L. The first one is &#x2013; okay, first impact &#x2013; two exceptional impacts, one is social unrest, the other one storm, okay. The social unrest has basically lowered production, loss of opportunity, lower margins and translated into lower sales, <mark type="inaudible" /> (33:180) is diminished to the magnitude of 270 million. So, that's where the impact is.</p>
          <p>So, now to &#x2013; it's the only explanation I can provide now. So, on the 250 million of energy and fuel purchases, maybe I'll provide you the breakdown because I know some of you follow it very slowly. The first one is basically <mark type="inaudible" />, I mean basically the loss &#x2013; as buying losses &#x2013; network &#x2013; for the network has been done in 2008 prices, therefore higher prices, has a negative impact of 225 million. Fuel, fossil fuels also impact us, negative 275 million, buying natural gas is not a negative, but it's an increase of 200 million. And the CSP this time had a favorable impact at that level because of market prices of standard positives 365, it was a computation of the four elements you should earn through 250 million.</p>
          <p>So, now the OpEx line, I mean OpEx is impacted by one pure exceptional, I mean the storm, okay, that is as exceptional as it gets, 150 million impact, Pierre mentioned it before, and also by a few other increases. I mean I think one is the acceleration of maintenance and commitments and new activities for 120 million, but also an increase in personnel cost exceeding slightly 5%. Out of it salary increases represent 2.8% and that's slightly more than 5%. Out of this, salary increases are 2.8% and a few other factors such as social protection and so on, so basically first factor, storm, 150 million; second is personnel costs, 200 million; maintenance and our new activities, 150 million; and then a few other, 50 makeup for 520 million. I'll take a bit of time because I know it's &#x2013; we get a lot of questions and I just wanted to have a straightforward explanation.</p>
          <p>Now, to conclude, a few words about the financials and the debt level and the balance sheet structure of the group. In terms of &#x2013; you have applications and sources of funds in the charts. Gross CapEx 5.6 billion for the semester, it was in front &#x2013; funded by an FFO of 6.9. So, that's a good start. Dividend, remaining part of the dividend paid and clearly a debt increase that is exclusively related to the funding of acquisitions. Out of the 12.2 billion, 10.8 billion are BE related, you may remember we had spent already 2.7 billion the year before, total 13.5, but you have also a few minor ones. <mark type="inaudible" />, our share 0.5; Deppendorf in Germany, NBV, 0.4; and Alpiq, 0.2 in a few others; in total 12.2. So this contributes to an increase of debt that we had exactly planned at that level, 13.6 billion. It does not include the proceeds of net SP Centrica, so you should deduct 1.2 billion, so the real number is 35.6 billion. We have planned it at 36 or exactly, so we &#x2013; internally, so we're tracking exactly where we are.</p>
          <p>The debt of &#x2013; just one message, obviously since you always -- maybe some of you're establishing your own model for BE exist for six months, the cash generated by BE cover, it's CapEx but also basically the interest charge are in &#x2013; compared to it, so &#x2013; and then matter of fact BE had an FFO net positive of 220 million in Q1 &#x2013; in H1, okay. So that's the result of the good start.</p>
          <p>As far as ratios &#x2013; rating is concerned and balanced overall, so our debt-to-EBITDA at 2.4, so Pierre will come back to it and we've stated it in several meetings with some of you. Clearly, our objective is to stay within a range of 2.5 times to 3 times, that's our commitment. Our commitment is also to protect a strong rating. We have today AA &#x2013; equivalent AA plus and A plus stable, okay, but one of the best combined rating of the industry and we intend to protect it. There are some steps toward that goal. And as you have seen, we've been able to tap financial markets, in some types of the worse time of financial markets on a continuous basis. We've raised more than &#x20AC;14 billion since January. So it was a good diversification reopening the U.K. &#x2013; U.S. dollar market, reopening the yen market, going to retail <mark type="inaudible" /> and that has been really pretty basically very steady. And at the end of the day, we improved the duration of &#x2013; the average duration of our debt to 6.7 years, okay. We increased it average 6.7 years and we lowered our average cost of debt to 4.4%. That said, so to conclude just one, our balance sheet at 250 billion, I mean basically the only changes I could comment on, some of them relate to the technical integration in those numbers of British Energy and <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>So far for the numbers, maybe now Pierre, a few words to the perspectives.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd now like to talk about the future and our goals for the future. First of all &#x2013; and that's the first place to start, we are going to continue improving our operational performance. The resumption of investments, the CapEx program that we mentioned earlier we place and it is parts and parcel of this target. For the year 2009, we're planning to invest likely below &#x20AC;13 billion, over half of which is in France, 60%. By these investments we intend to maintain and develop over time our industrial assets. Concurrently, we want to peruse the operational excellence performance program launched last year, ambition's to make &#x20AC;1 billion in gains on EBITDA by 2010, two-thirds of which are in France. This year we &#x2013; our forecast for France is &#x20AC;600 million in gain for the full year.</p>
          <p>Lastly, our daily performance is based on an ongoing industrial dialogue between labor and management to establish a relationship of trust, which are traditional among labor and management within EDF. The second priority, following a significant phase of external growth and acquisitions, which we continued over the past few years with excellent results in 2008, we are now moving on to another phase where we wish to focus on organic growth and synergy gains. In particular, I would like confirm our target of &#x20AC;220 million in synergy gains under &#x2013; in the context of the British Energy integration by 2011, synergies that are to be gained both within British Energy Group in the U.K. as well as between EDF Energy and EDF Group as a whole.</p>
          <p>We've also mobilized our efforts to finalize the two major acquisition deals that have been announced that are ongoing, and we expect to be finalized by the end of the year. I'm speaking about Constellation in the U.K. &#x2013; excuse me, in the U.S., and SPE is <mark type="inaudible" /> two deals that fits fully within the group's international strategy, both of which should produce major synergies, one by consolidating our leadership at the nuclear revival on international markets, how can we become the leader in the nuclear renaissance internationally; and the second deal will of course boost our positions in Belgium as well as in the heart of Europe.</p>
          <p>Our third priority and goal is to boost our financial performance and flexibility. In order to improve our financial flexibility, of course performance will be a part of that, but we've also announce and I've announced and I wish to confirm it and target &#x2013; of the target &#x2013; excuse me asset disposable plan. Our goal is for this asset disposable plan to reduce the group's net debt by at least &#x20AC;5 billion by the end of 2010. As Daniel has just explained, we are intent on sustaining &#x2013; on keeping the best rating in the industry in order to continue enjoying access to capital markets under excellent conditions.</p>
          <p>Of course our financial performance is also contingent up on a number of key factors. I spoke about capital investments, but then also it is contingent up on the achievement of our operational performance targets. And our performance will also depend on the increases of prices and tariffs for electricity in Europe and in France. I spoke about the need to resume investments in order to consolidate our industrial assets in France and to sustain the competitiveness of our production equipment over time.</p>
          <p>We've already spoken of our investment prospects on the mid-term together with financial outlook, and I explained what was advisable from an economic standpoint for the company over the coming years. On the short-term, I obviously understand the concerns linked to purchasing power in difficult times, but it is of course up to the government to define the pace and level of these price increases over time.</p>
          <p>In addition and in continuation with these &#x2013; this work, we've also started to look at the trends on the French electricity market further to the report published by the Champsaur Commission. This report has been published, it is public report, and it recommends limited amount of power to be made available to our competitors from the base load generation from our nuclear assets. I have said and I would like to confirm today that EDF is perfectly open to transition mechanisms similar to those recommended by the Champsaur report.</p>
          <p>Obviously, under the reconditions provided firstly that these mechanisms are limited in time, which is the very purpose of the Champsaur report, which is speaking about a proposal &#x2013; a transitional proposal, so limited in time, limited in volume as well and naturally as reported by Champsaur Commission provided that the selling price reflects the actual full economic cost of the electricity produced by our existing nuclear power plants.</p>
          <p>When I mean complete total cost, the idea is that &#x2013; to say that we need to be able to finance without resorting to additional debts to finance over the coming years all the capital expenditures necessary to operate the existing generation facilities in France including the assets linked to the long-term commitments of a nuclear day as well as linked to the extension of the life span of these plants in order to ensure the security of supply. All of these proposals are included in our program and recommended in the report, but it is essential to remember them since they're an essential component of the balance of the French electricity system.</p>
          <p>To conclude on our financial performance, let me confirm our outlooks for the full-year 2009. When I say confirm, I mean confirm what they have just told us, but also confirm what we said earlier at the presentation of the full-year 2008 results earlier this year. The group's EBITDA will be boosted by an improved international performance and more specifically by the contribution of British Energy to the financial results, hence growth of the group's EBITDA. Secondly, regarding the organic growth of our EBITDA, this organic growth will remain moderate in view of the current economic crisis that we are now all familiar with, been aware of. As with net income, excluding any exceptional events, we will not grow in view of the impact of the continuing capital expenditures on our net income.</p>
          <p>Moving on to our fourth and final target and priority, namely the contribution of EDF to the major concerns shared and published today in various countries regarding the security of supply and climate change, i.e., our contribution to sustainable development.</p>
          <p>We have now laid the basis of our future expansion in this area. In France, this involves the success of model EPR Flamanville <mark type="inaudible" />. And in future, this will &#x2013; also involves the future of the EPR in Poly in partnership with other major European operators.</p>
          <p>In the nuclear sector, internationally, this involves developing a series of EPRs in partnership with major local industrial operators. And our ambition is to turn EPR into the benchmark technology, taking over the existing technology of our existing base.</p>
          <p>In the field of renewable energy and energy efficiency, we must continue our ongoing commitments and this &#x2013; in this respect let me give you a figure &#x2013; give you an idea of the order of magnitude, sometimes not always understood. Over the coming three years, we will be investing as much in the field of renewable energy as in newbuild nuclear. In particular, the subsidiary, EDF &#xC9;nergie Nouvelle, both in the wind power, photovoltaic solar power as well as investments in hydropower and as much as in the newbuild nuclear, i.e., in the EPR reactors.</p>
          <p>To illustrate this I would like to mention the performance of EDF &#xC9;nergie Nouvelle, Daniel Camus spoke about their financial performance, but let me add that few days ago EDF &#xC9;nergie Nouvelle announced a partnership with a U.S. solar panel manufacturer, First Solar, to develop jointly a solar panel factory in France to become the largest solar panel manufacturer in France. This is a turnaround in EDF's policy to respond to current expectations and opportunity.</p>
          <p>Last but not least, EDF continues to prepare for the future by innovation. We have major ambitions and initiatives in the field of new technologies for energy management, particularly based on the emergence of smart networks of which &#x2013; on which we've been working with ERDF, in particular with the current tests going on. This also includes development of partnerships with major carmakers to promote the development of electrical vehicle as well as hybrid plug-in vehicles, because we're firm believers in these, and lastly this includes devolvement of seawater turbines, some of which will be installed offshore in Brittany at Paimpol. In all areas and many others, EDF is focused on the energies and technologies of tomorrow.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, let me repeat the trust and confidence I have in our group. In this energy sector that is undergoing consolidation, we can say that the positions now acquired by EDF and the capital expenditures that have been initiated will comfort leadership in the energy sector of the future.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to ask Dominique Lagarde and Jean-Louis Mathias to join us on stage. We have another &#x2013; other management members here, and we can now answer all your questions. We've also being receiving a lot of questions via Internet. I'll try to fit them in as we discuss. Some of them are basically principal conditions, accounting questions. Let's take the first question from the room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. it's Pali Hahn UBS. You said, you think that Champsaur Commission's proposal are reasonable, if they are time limited, volume limited and cover your economic costs. What does this mean in reality? What is the time limit? I think they are talking about ten years. Is that a reasonable time limit? And then what's your internal estimates on what are the kind of volumes we're talking about here ad what is your view on that &#x2013; your current economic cost? That's my first question. I have two more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And second one, how should we look on these strikes, what's making you confident of that this is a one-off? <mark type="inaudible" /> climate is clearly getting worse and if I understand, there were less than 100 people of the 25,000. What kind of actions are you taking in order to make an insurance of that? And third, how has the economic crisis affected your plans? What we see on many other companies is that demand is down, cash is king, they are taking actions. Are you taking any action?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. On the first topic, about Champsaur, first obviously, the implementation of the Champsaur proposals belong to the government and probably it will require legal actions. So clearly, it's government and parliament responsibility to draw the consequence or the implication of the Champsaur report.</p>
          <p>Clearly, the government is working and the French administration is working on this topic, and it requires some negotiation between the French government and Brazil competition authorities to make a proposal, which can be accepted by competition authorities, because it's &#x2013; clearly the challenge is to build something, which is acceptable by competition authorities, which require that it must be something transitory between a monopoly situation to the competitive situation and I expect that these negotiation are now developing on the level.</p>
          <p>I think I made public the challenge that we are facing, which means in France that there is a need for an increase in investment. The French need for investment &#x2013; the need for investment in France are required because we must invest to improve the quality of our network and improve also the efficiency of our plants, and the magnitude has been already mentioned. In 2009, we will invest 0.5 billion. It is probably a peak in the development, but it's 2.5 more times &#x2013; 2.5 times what we invested four years ago. And of course in the mid-term we must have sustainable financing means to finance these investments.</p>
          <p>And &#x2013; sorry, and you mentioned on the social issue, do we expect and do we act to make social climate in French &#x2013; in France the best we can expect of course, yes. Dominique?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we've prepared that the next period in I would say two or three ways. The first one is to &#x2013; that we have prepared the agenda of negotiation for the following working norms at the national level with our unions. It is already done and it will be precise at the beginning of September. And second point is that we are mobilizing our local management to develop negotiation at the local level and especially <mark type="inaudible" /> like quality of life and working conditions on sites. And as said, we are implementing currently the decision we've taken after our negotiation during the first semester and of course it has a positive impact on the local climate in our unit. I cannot say that it will be enough to avoid any strike, obviously it depends on our &#x2013; of course our confident way of negotiation, but not only that because we are in a more global economic and social context, which is not facilitating.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, to answer your question what are we doing in the crisis. First of all, we've done in strike and storm, but overall the economic dynamic of Europe today has impacted to a very limited amount. I mean we have even computed the loss of EBITDA or loss of earnings, if you are at France and all the other European countries, we come to something like 1.5% of EBITDA, I mean really like minimal. So, I think we have been good &#x2013; we have been resilient in France. Basically, we've done very thorough computation. We're close to zero impact I mean in EBITDA translation, okay. So &#x2013; however, we clearly need to be proactive and I think we are already, to control CapEx, OpEx, I mean just a few examples. We started on an international basis <mark type="inaudible" />, for example have reduced its CapEx by 40%; it has really maintained OpEx flat. ED&amp;BV is doing the same thing. So &#x2013; and it's part of the earnings improvement.</p>
          <p>In France as Pierre said, we're basically all the &#x2013; I mean also internationally, all the large acquisitions are behind us. We have concluded on the &#x2013; on SP and on Constellation. That's pretty much &#x2013; we are not going to do other major acquisitions. We also in CapEx at <mark type="inaudible" /> but this is not going to continue to go I mean &#x2013; and we said we monitored it very tightly. So, this is all integrated in an operational excellence where we'll continue it over time. So, we've monitored that tightly. Sometimes we cannot influence all of it, I mean the exceptionals are what they are and I think we do not plan to extend social unrest I mean by definition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />. I've got several questions &#x2013; six questions apparently, said the speaker. The first one concerns the Kd, you lost roughly two points of Kd &#x2013; you apparently lost two points of Kd in 2009. Is this is a real loss, is it just falling back or is it a reduction in comparison with what you planned? And will you do 80%, 81% in 2009?</p>
          <p>Could you come back to the two billion swing in WCR? Could you give details of that? I don't think I understood all the different underlying elements of that.</p>
          <p>Disposals, third question, five billions worth &#x2013; here we're moving into the group policy, are you considering a part of RTE in that? And then the second question, what is the position of the CGT Union with whom you're having a few problems? I think the CGT Union has opposed this. And then, is the CGT also opposed to the disposal of the transmission part of activity in the U.K.? What are you putting into the five billion and what would you like to see?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lots and lots of questions, well, three basic &#x2013; but all right, Kd, working capital &#x2013; all right, the KD, let me try and answer that. No, actually, I will ask Jean-Louis to answer that and also say a word about our ambitions and how we are going to get there.</p>
          <p>Let me just say a few words about the method employed here. By definition, the Kd availability ratio only reflects the technical performance of the plants. That is to say, when you have environmental factors you may have seaweed turning up in the history of the <mark type="inaudible" /> and this stops a power station working. When you've got social unrest, then all this has an impact on production, but it doesn't have an impact on availability, which by definition measures the performance of the operator. We are well on the path, which we fixed for ourselves.</p>
          <p>Just now we talked about labor unrest, I think what is paradoxical here is that we negotiated, back in the spring time a big agreement whereby we could implement new systems for piloting plant outages. This is something which is done in parts of the United States, and we also negotiated new systems for preventive maintenance, which will be bearing its fruit pretty rapidly in terms of availability, and also you will see this reflected in the investment which is going up. And then as far as the assets, the facilities are concerned, their availability will be improved. So, we've really done the groundwork for future improvements, improvements which are planned and which are built into our program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a target of 85% Kd in 2011. This is not going to be the end of the road however. I've already said that we can't hope to achieve the level of performance of the American power stations, which for structural reasons are at 95% availability. Given the size of the nuclear facilities in France, every 12 months we have to reload half of the facilities whereas in the rest of the world they do this every year and a half, two years. On top of that we have power stations, which are modulated and this is when you're going to have hiccups and problems, but all of this can be measured in terms of four to five points of Kd. What it means is that all the investments, all the working methods, all the labor relations, these are things which you've worked on and which coming together will produce results, which we are fully confident in &#x2013; reviving investment, let me say, is part and parcel of the overall solution, it is not the only part but it's a key part.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On WCR, yeah, just a few words to explain this. We have &#x2013; the 2.2 billion improvement breaks down to a negative WCR consumption, at the end of last year 1.9 billion and as you pointed -- total of 2.2 billion, 700 million in France, and 1.5 billion abroad. EDF Trading is in &#x2013; artificially contributes to the plant at 2.2 billion, you've got 1.6 billion. With margin calls, which were returned at the end of last year, the volumes on commodities finally went down. So, cash is being mobilized, it has been freed up and this is the reversal of the position at the beginning of the year. And <mark type="inaudible" /> variations and prices were &#x2013; electricity and gas price is in fact up. We do see volatility on raw materials prices, which we don't have full control over.</p>
          <p>Now this &#x2013; I would maybe take another few questions here from Internet.</p>
          <p>Yes, let me answer you question on disposals first. Let me confirm what I announced. I said that as a target we had disposals 2009, 2010, the impact on the debt would be &#x2013; a five billion impact on the debt. I said the same thing as part of the recovery plan, which we implemented between 2005 and 2007. We did what we said we would do. We actually brought in 5.7 billion. Without having said in advance what we might be disposing of, let me tell you that the names, which you are quoting, I'll not deny, I'll not confirm either.</p>
          <p>You've mentioned companies I'm not saying anything about that, no comment whatsoever. We want to ensure that the companies which we will sell off and we can sell off part shareholdings &#x2013; don't forget that. We're transferring 20% into British Energy, that's part of the asset disposal plan, but this is coming on top of the total. This is the kind of operation, which we can do. Just give you an example here, we don't have to sell off all our shareholding and in any case we will always want to safeguard our expansion model. It works well and we want to ensure of course that our overall strategy is not endangered, whether it be in France or abroad.</p>
          <p>Yes, I've got a lot of questions coming in from Internet. One question very quickly, is a technical one, when will the company will be applying the -- the answer is in 2010, but our assessment is there is no significant impact for the time being. Another one is &#x2013; relates what is the impact of the talk-time provision or release of provision in H1 2009 accounts related to talk-time. The answer is, as you know we have a cumulative talk-time provision of two billion. The cash release payment, compensation in H1 has been 600 million. So basically, our best assessment today, by the end of the year we will have cashed out 1.8 billion out of the billion.</p>
          <p>Maybe I could hand over to Pierre now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions here concerning Flamanville, let me just read this, the Flamanville three project is behind data. Can you confirm its commissioning at the end of 2012? And the financial expenses of Flamanville, are they capitalized? The answer is, yes. Maybe Pierre could answer the question about the timetable, yes, Bernard Dupraz could maybe give a few facts and figures about this project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is a big project as you know. The EPR is the biggest project developing new technologies in France. It's one of the biggest projects underway currently in France. We have modified our estimation over the cost. I think I said it last year or just under a year ago. At that time I said that our &#x2013; the estimation of the project cost was roughly &#x20AC;4 billion, and currently we're working to stick to the budget target and also the timetable. The project is moving forward. Every time there are problems to be overcome, we do our best. In fact we do overcome these problems. You have to understand that this kind of project is something, which contributes to more such projects being developed in the future. We want to ensure that the EPRs, which we work on outside France will be as close or similar as possible to the one we have in Flamanville, so that Flamanville will be the leader in the series and everybody in the world has understood this I think, all our potential partners and so everybody comes along to see Flamanville and they want to use our Flamanville experience. Now I think you all have noticed that even in the projects where we are not &#x2013; which we are not associated with people come along to ask us questions about Flamanville. Let me ask if Dan want just to say a few words about how this project is going.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bernard Dupraz is in charge of engineering and the installations. Yes, it's one of the biggest projects in Europe. On this site we have 1800 people and this was &#x2013; and we've take on &#x2013; we've brought in three shifts over the past few weeks in order to speed things up. This is one of the commitments we've made. So, a very big project indeed.</p>
          <p>We have run into a certain number of hurdles, two have already been mentioned. The first one concerns the digging of the tunnels, of expelling waste into the sea. We decided to use tunneling methods to do this. Now, this tunneling system has been working since June. We have got the first 30 meters, which have been dug. So the problem we had there has been overcome.</p>
          <p>We also met back in 2008 another problem in laying the liner. This is a metal sheet which covers the whole of the pre-stressed concrete, which covers the nuclear reactor. These are problems or this particular problem was also overcome, unlike the tunneling problem, which is different from one site to another. This question of the liner is typically a part of the learning curve, which you have when you're working on this kind of project. We've overcome this problem now and now we know that on an EPR you have to work in a particular kind of way in order to lay this metal sheeting. So, all this has led us to maintain the target, which you have oftentimes stated, of commissioning Flamanville 3 in 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I'm <mark type="inaudible" />, I have three questions. Another one regarding your EBITDA guidance for 2009, which hasn't changed in spite of the cost of &#x2013; labor unrest costing you approximately 3 percentage points in organic growth, so, what is this offset with? Secondly, on British Energy, can you give us the amount of the PPA expense on the first-half, the PPA expense for the first-half and for the full-year? Give us an indication on the taxation, the tax rate for the Group, because from my understanding it's not deductible. And lastly, in terms of hedging for 2010 and 2011, how many terawatt-hours have you sold in and at what price? This is the information that British Energy used to publish in the past.</p>
          <p>Thirdly, regarding the debt, this is the first time that you gave a range of net debt over EBITDA publicly at least. Can you give us figures, taking into account provisions for pensions of EDF employees, this is something where agencies are looking at and most of your peers are publishing? It's for Mr. Gadonneix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll ask Daniel to respond on the financial questions and financial structure. Then I'll ask Vincent de Rivaz to answer on these questions regarding the performance of British Energy and EDF Energy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is to do with recognizing items within the group, now regarding EBITDA guidance, we had given moderate growth as guidance. Now, we've reached 2.4% for this first half, in spite of unfavorable impacts of the storms and labor unrest. We're talking &#x20AC;420 million, which we've absorbed and offset, so that we can end up with 2.4% of debt resilience. For the end of the year and for you we said there would be some effects that would carry over on the labor unrest for a total of 450 million. So, typically we are in a calendar schedule for EBITDA, which is not linear. As you know, the second half is always slightly down in absolute value, but it's just the first half of the year, but simply we've full control.</p>
          <p>Now, international business, it should stick with the same momentum that we're having today. We're 'quite confident for EDF Energy. We're very confident as I said earlier that Edison will continue to pick up its performance to return to the previous levels, same thing for ENBW. So, international business will continue. In France we are seeing effects of OpEx evolutions and trends that will not be repeated in the second half. So, <mark type="inaudible" />, we remain quite confident on our ability to deliver moderate organic growth on the EBITDA.</p>
          <p>Now, PPA &#x2013; to respond to your question on the PPA, I'll give you on an annual basis because it will be fully audited, so if we talk about a semester basis. So, for &#x2013; important of course for the financial community, we've revalued our assets. So, when we model &#x2013; in the modeling if you will, there are two determining factor, the increased depreciation tax, which is significant, approximately &#x20AC;1 billion for the year, that is over the existing life span of the e-power plant and then same magnitude for the following years. Regarding financial expenses, that is the cause of the debt &#x2013; related debt, 410 million for British Energy for the half-year and then on an annual full year basis will &#x2013; should be around &#x20AC;900 million, and next year after Centrica &#x2013; of course Centrica will de-leverage the entire transaction. So, we will &#x2013; we took payers closer to &#x20AC;700 million in financial expenses, that is the basis of our own forecast.</p>
          <p>Regarding the debt level, we've never published the leverage provisions for pensions, retirements and so on because that's not what we use to pilot the -- leave us, if you will, nuclear provisions and so on. Every time what we do is &#x2013; every time we have had &#x2013; have an allowance of 2.8 billion for dedicated assets, for instance I'm talking about economic debt naturally, every time we increased by 100 and then we put 100 in assets across the board. So, this is how we highlight the group's economics, if you will, based on the financial debt. We can give you additional details if you would like on future trends. But we have allowances of approximate &#x20AC;2.8 billion a year for dedicated assets and every time we do that we add the counterparty assets, which is recognized perfectly well by rating agencies.</p>
          <p>Anything to add on British Energy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Vincent de Rivaz answering the question. The question that was asked regarding the production &#x2013; generation efficiency of British Energy power plants, we said that compared with the first-half of 2008, the output of British Energy has gone up nearly 34%, as we said earlier. Why is that, well two main reasons. The four reactors you may remember that for nearly 500 days have been shut down for major refurbishment. All four are now put back in operation, put it simply all of British Energy reactors are now operational. As for other reactors, they've also performed well and better overall in this half-year versus the previous half-year. And as regards what will be happening in the second half of this year, we're confident that it will be in line with the first half.</p>
          <p>Let me take this opportunity, because &#x2013; justifyingly, so we're stressing the new news, that's British Energy, but let me add that the rest of British Energy's business, whether gas-fired or coal-fired plants, commercial businesses, network businesses, all of them have performed extremely well in the first-half 2009, particularly the generation and supply sector in terms of sales revenue and EBTIDA growth, excellent performance. So, it's not surprising to see that the good performance of British Energy and good performance of EDF Energy, all of this combines to give you an excellent performance for the new group, the new EDF Energy Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question of Mike. The question has to do with hedging for 2010 and 2011. Volume and prices, how much have you sold your nuclear power?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You said that British Energy used to publish these figures from what I understand. Now what I can say is that our hedging policy for British Energy will gradually be incorporated within &#x2013; into the group's heading policy. We're working in the U.K. on our business model and hedging policy. That was boosted by this acquisition. Among the guidelines of the group, we are adding this hedging policy naturally. Regarding the price at which we are selling our electricity, I'm sorry, but we are not used to give you &#x2013; give details &#x2013; much detail about that.</p>
          <p>For 2009, regarding volumes we still have three 3 terawatt-hours to sell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Additional Internet question on Flamanville, what are the amount of budget excess?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Simple answer and I confirm what I said earlier, in other words we stick with our &#x20AC;4 billion target for Flamanville. It may be surprising, but you've seen on new projects budgets that are well above that, but that's because Flamanville is a project that was finalized in 2005 at which time we benefited from economic conditions dating back to 2005. And it's true &#x2013; perfectly true that today including in those projects where we're involved we are looking at &#x2013; and as I said earlier when we spoke about the price of future electricity &#x2013; future prices, the new projects, yes, the cost will be higher than Flamanville, but Flamanville we are in line with our budget.</p>
          <p>Next question, in the U.K., what was the cash impact of sales of land in the U.K. and will cash flow be able to continue to contribute to the financing of British EPRs. Vincent, could you respond to the London sales and will the U.K. government contribute to finance the British EPRs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Will the British government contribute to finance the EPRs, well, maybe you should ask the question to the British government, and I think they will answer the same thing we will. As the Chairman says however, beyond this particular issue, what is extremely important is that in order to achieve our goals and particularly the goal of being the first operator to start the first newbuild reactor in the U.K. and to be the first builder who will be building the largest number of plants in the first wave of newbuild, our goal is &#x2013; which is our goal and we've received &#x2013; we have obtained full support of the government and government administration who have organized to help us solve problems, issues of &#x2013; planning &#x2013; issues of any kind that really require a strong cushion, a strong drive from the British Government, and that support we had received. We have major contacts even with the opposition party.</p>
          <p>Remember that by the 6th of May, 2010 there will be general elections. There again we're feeling that there will be a continuum in terms of support from the British authorities regardless of who they are, support to our new bill program, regardless of the results of the elections and I can make no prognosis on that.</p>
          <p>Regarding the sales of land, things are relatively simple. We bought and we're going to sell. What we'll be selling and this matter of fact &#x2013; that will be the results of the auction sales that was done by the Nuclear Decommissioning Authority last spring. What we're selling is the land that we had purchased in the area of <mark type="inaudible" /> that was sold in an auction together with the T&amp;A lands, and so we of course benefited from the successful auction sales and clearly we'll have net proceeds from this particular transaction and of course that will &#x2013; the goal &#x2013; the ultimate goal was not to make a couple &#x2013; thousands of millions, even though that will be the result.</p>
          <p>And in addition, we've also purchased the Bradwell land in line with our strategy, mainly we want to secure under all possible scenario for EPRS &#x2013; for EDF in the first newbuild range. And that was in line with the commitment that we have made. We are planning to sell either the HM site or the <mark type="inaudible" /> site, that is an ongoing process, a procedure that will include several milestones, but in particular the main milestone in the order, that is the publication of the National Policy Statement that will issue a clear and strong message on the need for a newbuild nuclear, as well as the list of the first eligible sites, i.e., the site strategic assessments. And depending on the landscape that will be clearing up in the fall, then we will be developing our actions.</p>
          <p>The only commitment that was made by British authorities regarding financing the reactors is one of the responsibility for decommissioning on the existing facilities. That is the only commitment they have made. And then a newbuild nuclear we will handle, just like in France financing as well as paying for future dismantling cost.</p>
          <p>Now the question that is raised, this is something that's been raised by many everywhere, is to have a long-term tariff signal that will ensure the competitiveness of nuclear power. And that involves the price of CO2 and that is one of the subjects that I discussed with Prime Minister, Gordon Brown. What will be happening at the Copenhagen Conference is of major importance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A number of financial questions, one of it &#x2013; two questions, what amounts remain to be paid and what amount are we talking about in terms of external growth, SPE, BG&amp;Y and so on, by the end of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me summarize that. On Centrica, you are familiar with the amount, now exchange rate and its factors are in our favor. The price that we have had signed with Centrica, that's down 6% versus the acquisition price &#x2013; look at that discount. Since then we've had a 10% appreciation of the sterling, which has literally offset the proceeds in euro, but that's the figure that we've already published, a net figure of 1.2 billion. We're talking about deleveraging EDF by 1.2 billion. So, that leaves Constellation and EWE, which is &#x2013; with an impact of &#x20AC;1 billion for EDF and Constellation, 2.5 billion additional remaining to be paid, but again the exchange rate with the dollar is in our favor ever since the beginning of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Last financial question, performance of the first half of your fund dedicated to decommissioning of power plant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Response is 4.1% while our benchmark is 3.7%. So, we've done better than our benchmark since the beginning of the year.</p>
          <p>Question from Mr. Chopra. We'll start with the left side of the room, then we'll move onto the right side of the room and see if that works out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions; number one, I'd like some clarification on your comments at the press conference this morning regarding the dividend policy, I saw that you announced that the dividend policy would be in line with our peers. Could you perhaps qualify your comment? Are you talking about being in line on the payout that historically &#x2013; was that 50% on ordinary shares, any growth or yield in how you qualify your peers and what sector and what industry?</p>
          <p>Second question, regarding the trends of synergy gains and cost, could you give us your estimate on the increase of personnel expenses, social benefits in France in particular? You talked about increased wages over the first half, I would imagine that bargaining talks only &#x2013; will only be closed in the third quarter. Can you give us more detail?</p>
          <p>Thirdly, you've confirmed your operational performance again targeting one billion between '08 and 2010 &#x2013; excuse me, between 2007 and 2010. Year-end 2008, if I remember right you'd already reached 300 million in synergy gains of 600 million in 2009. What drivers and what factors do you intend to use to offset the all &#x2013; the excess cost of wages that perhaps were not expected or not planned for 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On dividends, we've been very, very conservative, very cautious. We are proposing to the shareholders a dividend payout in line with the practices of our peers. I won't give any figures, but you know them better than we do. So, you are asking a question even though you already know the answer. But clearly, this is what we are saying today, in line with the practices of our peers; our peers in our sector naturally. There I can be very precise in my answer, peers in our sector of industry.</p>
          <p>On costs, now we have a rather fast increase of cost in France and within the French <mark type="inaudible" />, but we have a significant exceptional events, non-recurring events that will not be repeated even though some of them will have an impact on the second half. But where are we focused, that is excluding any non-recurring items, we're focused on &#x2013; and that constant scope of business naturally, we want to have an OpEx space of approximately 3% in France, which was not the case as of late June.</p>
          <p>Regarding the operational performance, cost reduction program, just to add a couple of things to what Daniel just said. This is exactly the way you can interpret and read the increase of OpEx for this half-year removing any exceptional items both in terms of increase of wage cost and storm-related costs. Some items will come over and above explaining what Daniel just said regarding a potential possible trend of around 3%, namely new businesses particularly in the field of services and gas, but that will also deliver some EBITDA and on the other hand the fact that industrial maintenance cost for nuclear facilities naturally is reflected by an increase in CapEx, but also has an impact on OpEx.</p>
          <p>And obviously in place of that and in view of inflation, we also have this operational excellence program. I confirmed the figures that you gave, and yes, we were slightly below 300. We're now targeting 600 by the end of the year and one billion in synergy gains for 2010. Drivers <mark type="inaudible" /> they're both drivers at central costs. I mentioned earlier nuclear drivers such as different management, maintenance shutdowns or maintenance policies, working methods and so on, but that also includes our whole series of local projects, so we've actually inventoried something like 700 projects now identified to modify the fundamental basic working processes, if you will.</p>
          <p>We've engaged in in-depth cultural change, very different from the previous attitude that was a top down cost reduction program. Now we're talking about a program that is bottom up, starts from excellence &#x2013; expertise in the field to produce and to deliver financial performance. We've given you new figures by 2010, but the cultural change will be such that the program will continue and the program is not dying out at all because of major breakthroughs that are delivered in the way we manage the company and the business. It means that all of this is actually self-sustained and boosting itself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to explain that the increase in provisions of 11 billion at the end of 2008 and the end of H1 2009, now the answer is quite simple. 8.9 &#x2013; almost &#x20AC;9 billion worth of which is the provisions, taking it back from British Energy. We've restated the fuels of provision for the different parts of the installations, but it's basically nine billion therefore and it's counterpart on the asset side, we need to have a guarantee, the decommissioning by NLF. So we have a credit for 6.4 billion. So, that explains the total. The rest &#x2013; in fact the rest is related to movements due to the volume of EDF.</p>
          <p>Other questions, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> from Deutsche Bank. One first question on the CapEx, could you give us an indication of the gross CapEx at the end of the year? Bear in mind that you are trying to make savings. And then could you say something about the CapEx in France out with the networks? I understand the increase in CapEx in France, but what part of the CapEx is linked to Flamanville? What percentage has to do with maintenance? Are we seeing a speeding up of maintenance CapEx because of that &#x2013; are you prolonging the life cycle of the plants or what? Could you just talk about that?</p>
          <p>Second question is top three, nobody said very much about this. What impact does that have on your accounts? How can you situate the increase in CapEx in the light of this? <mark type="inaudible" /> where did you situate the network losses in this?</p>
          <p>Third point, there are some divisions which are suffering in Italy. Are you considering a write-off at the end of the year or is that just off the cards? And maybe a final question about the USA, you have not talked about the States, but are you achieving your objectives?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lots of question there. In terms of investment, let's look at the investments in France and internationally. Let's focus on France, we've got the figures for investment in H1, can we show that? Well, theoretically we can if we just find the right slide, somebody could find that. Well, let me give you the main figures here. So, for France, 3.4 billion for non-regulated activities. Out of that non-regulated is 1.6 billion. Out of 1.6 billion, you've got production of 1.5 billion. We're still talking about France here, all this is France. Now for the difference between the total, 5.4 billion is the difference is international. Flamanville at this point in time, we've spent just over two billion, 2.1 billion. This is for the end of June CapEx on Flamanville, just over two billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now for investments in France, this is a point that I've to clarify. Basically, the figures which Daniel has just given, demonstrate that half of the investments in France concern regulated activities, just over half. There we are, we've got it. So, the network activities represent in total about one half. So, you've got the breakdown there. So, the total of France, 3.4 billion, network activities of 1.5. Now the investments in the network activities are covered for distribution and carrying the electricity, they are covered by the TARP rules. That is to say, the tariffs are lay done by the regulator. Taking into account the investment levels, but this is fully integrated into the balance sheet of EDF and after that for France, non-regulated activities in France we don't have the details, but in fact roughly 50% of this figure, two-thirds of this is represented by maintenance, one-third is a development, and here we're talking about Flamanville plus the co-generation projects of combined cycle. And turbines &#x2013; we're finished with turbines. Yeah, we've got a few turbines left.</p>
          <p>For maintenance we have work on hydroelectric, thermal and for nuclear we're talking about major maintenance programs, changing the generator, for example, and this kind of work started basically back in 2005, 2006.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just finishing off on CapEx, what are we considering doing at the end of the year? We said for CapEx we're between 12, 13 billion and this was a peek figure. So this &#x2013; that's what remains.</p>
          <p>You had two other questions, potential write-off and then something about the U.S. Now, potential write-off... Well, if there is one it's not what we are aiming for. In Italy, the fair market value of our shareholding goes well beyond what we imagined to start with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just say few words about the U.S.? All right. Now for the USA, just a bit of basic information here. We are moving forward, there were two pieces of information we have for Constellation. Now, the figures are published of course. Over the past few weeks there has been a significant turnaround in the cash situation, very significant improvement in fact, and a continued reduction in the counterparts. So, in terms of profitability, they will be talking about these figures. I don't want to preempt them. But at the time when we are talking about Constellation, the stock market figure was just 23, it's gone up by &#x2013; it's gone up to roughly 30. No particular problem on that.</p>
          <p>As for the situation with the regulator, there are lots of authorizations to be obtained in the U.S. We've got the Federal Authorization for energy, we've got that green light, we've got the go-ahead from the Competition Authorities. We've got the okay from the overseas investment authority. We are in the final stages of authorizations. We've got to still talk a bit with the nuclear authorities. The only real difficult subject, as you've probably read in the press, is what's coming out of Maryland. The Public Service Commission of Maryland has said that they actually have authority and they still see if where is &#x2013; what they have said, there is a potential influence of EDF on a regulated business. That is what they say. In fact we're not bringing any kind of control, this 49.9 situation in the nuclear situation. But well, there is certain number of hearings ongoing. So far we have announced that the hearings should be winding up Q3. That's what we're shooting for, but there is going to be a bit of bumpy right ahead of us in Maryland. Well, these two operations I mentioned, this &#x2013; the disposal to Centrica and the acquisition of a Constellation, we said &#x2013; I said that we were expecting these questions to be settled by the end of the year because this procedure is ongoing. Now, in both cases we are confident that these questions will be settled by the end of the year, but it is true that's in the U.S. the things are slightly more complicated than in for example the U.K.</p>
          <p>Any more questions, yes, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="inaudible" />. Two questions, the first concerns your network, are wages still in line with what you planned and are you in touch with the CRE to talk about I think that the overall wages is supposed to be part of the manageable, controllable costs. And how was this request received, if you didn't even make it? And what about the tariffs, Champsaur has been interviewed on this in the parliament, there was a parliamentary hearing on this, how do you measure the enthusiasm you see in parliament for pushing your electricity prices up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this is why I talked about it just now. It's something which &#x2013; it's important to make understood, all of the figures reflect the performance of the regulated part of a sector, that's important, but this is managerial part of our activity and the <mark type="inaudible" /> is deeply attached to this managerial aspect of our work.</p>
          <p>Now, we have a word to say when the shareholder is asked to approve our budget. Maybe I could hand over to Jean-Louis or to &#x2013; on this because as you know we are very vigilant about these kinds of questions, but the financial equilibrium of the regulated activities is guaranteed by the activity and remuneration, which is laid on by the regulator. Now the regulator has decided to authorize a strong growth in investment. Now what's new is that there is more investment in the regulated sector and the regulator has an &#x2013; requested an increase of the tariffs for carrying the electricity, which would passed on it to the consumer. If there was a price increase announced one day anything we announce would include the passing on of the TARP.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about the OpEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the question of the way and which the regulator works here, the regulator has agreed or approved setting up a special account, which will limit a certain number of the risks, for example, risks to do with the price of buying back the losses. Now, this is quite considerable sometimes. Let's not get carried away here. The regulator has laid down requirements in terms of productivity. There is an incentive system here. If we do better than the target laid down by the regulator, then that's great, if we don't then we lose. And believe me, when I tell you that the shareholder pressure is quite legitimate and understandable, and the shareholder will be wanting us to do better of course than to do not so well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe that we are coming to the end of the time slot, which is allotted for Internet. Maybe just a final question from Internet, Daniel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the four billion of the <mark type="inaudible" />, does this include the capitalized financial expenses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer is no, but the 54 of the megawatt cost &#x2013; the &#x20AC;54 of the megawatt-hour, this cost includes the financial expenses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now just to conclude very nice question indeed. Why are you not ambitious with EDF &#xC9;nergie Nouvelle compared with some of your competitors, which are turning this kind of activity into real growth driver?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just repeat something which maybe you didn't hear. The conclusion &#x2013; in the conclusion I made just now, I told about this. The visibility of our commitment is not as yet sufficient. I have decided that EDF will become a leader in renewable energies. We're talking about solar energy. There we intend to be the first operator to develop PV energies, not only in France but abroad. So, through EDF &#xC9;nergie Nouvelle this is what we intend to do. Over the next three years, we will be investing in solar and wind energy over &#x20AC;4 billion, in fact it is 4.5 billion over the next three years, which is almost as much as we're investing in the new nuclear power stations <mark type="inaudible" />. So it's a major commitment, which we're making. And this translates into double-digit growth for EDF &#xC9;nergie Nouvelle, but the first figure is this is quite unusual.</p>
          <p>I want to underscore this because we believe that this is a profitable sector with very strong growth prospects. It is very important that EDF appears internationally and nationally as a leader in all shapes and forms, meeting the requirements of sustainable development. That is to say a leader in the production of energy, which does not produce CO2. This is the thrust, which brings together and binds the guiding principles of EDF over the years to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much indeed for your presence, for you questions and let me wish all of you an excellent and very happy summer holidays. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>