<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1168707" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Interim 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-08-01</date>
    <companies>
      <company>45590</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Pierre Gadonneix, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Daniel Camus, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">Pierre Gadonneix</participant>
      <participant id="3">Jean-Louis Mathias</participant>
      <participant id="4">Daniel Camus</participant>
      <participant id="5">Jean-Louis Matthias</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. It is a great pleasure that I am with you again today for this conference to present the Half Year Results for 2008. Let me first of all address an issue that of course you all have in mind. And I would like to confirm what we stated last night &#x2013; late last night. Following in-depth discussions, we feel that -- and after listening to the requirements and demands of all parties, we feel that the conditions, particularly financial conditions that would enable EDF to expand in Great Britain are not met today.</p>
          <p>For obvious reason, the companies &#x2013; because the companies that were considered may be listed on the stock markets, you will understand that I cannot say anymore than this on these perspectives in the UK.</p>
          <p>Let's now take a look at our half year results. The half year results are in line with the guidance that we gave last February. As you see here on this slide, operating income has been growing. Sales reached over &#x20AC;32 billion, up 6.4% versus the first half in 2007. And on a like-for-like basis constant scope and exchange rates, organic growth has reached 9.1%</p>
          <p>EBITDA reached &#x20AC;9 billion, with an organic growth of 3.9%, and net income, attributable income slightly over 3 billion, down 12.8% versus half year one 2007. And excluding non-recurring item, the decrease is minus 3.7% versus last year. Slight decline that reflects a mechanical and short-term effect on our account of the faster pace of our investment program that is intended to consolidate, strengthen, and durably so, EDF's industrial positions.</p>
          <p>Few words about the context in which we are working. Everyone is aware, of course, that the half year results, of course, were reached in a context of sharp rise in a number of commodities, in particularly hydrocarbons, of course, fuel energy prices, that includes coal as well, versus last year. Oil has gone up in excess of 60%. Natural gas and coal have gone up over 75%. Logically, these trends have led to a fast increase of the electricity prices on the wholesale market everywhere throughout the world and particularly in Europe. And, depending on the cases, it has not always been possible to pass-on these wholesales prices to the end customers.</p>
          <p>In this general environment, European regulatory context has continued to change over the past six months, with three major concerns largely shared by everyone, namely security of supply, a fight against climate change as well as concerns regarding purchasing power and competitiveness.</p>
          <p>In a number of our &#x2013; in a number of countries, precautionary measures or preventive measures have been adopted and implemented in order, among others, to safeguard the lowest income household. In France, the French parliament has recently adopted a provision designed to extend by one year the TaRTAM or transition tariff.</p>
          <p>The TaRTAM is what this transition tariff is called. And that is &#x2013; this is a mechanism, transitory as its name says, that concerns on number of utility companies. Naturally, this decision will have an impact on the group's financial results and we'll come back to that later on.</p>
          <p>Regarding climate change and fight against climate change, decisions have been adopted in the favor of a lower carbon emitting energy mix, which naturally comforts EDFs position on a European level. The targets that are shared and agreed by all European countries, namely to reduce CO2 emissions and new guidelines to promote renewable energy sources or carbon free energy sources, all of these have been confirmed.</p>
          <p>The revival of nuclear power has confirmed itself in a number of countries, primarily in the UK as well as in a number of other European countries and a number of countries elsewhere in the world. And we'll come back to that later on. This is a topic of course where EDF intends to play a leading role.</p>
          <p>Let's get back to the United Kingdom. Let me confirm and reassert our ambition to become a key player of nuclear revival in the UK. In fact we've been working on this for the past three years and since then we've adopted a number of decisions to reach this goal. Let me remind you that slightly over a year ago, we filed jointly with Arriva a certification request for the EPR based on the Flamanville model and we are quite confident that this certification permit should be granted some time in 2009 by UK authorities.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we have ordered a number of key components, large components, to build the first two EPR units in the UK. Orders have been placed already. Last, but not least, we've also acquired a number of sites located in the vicinity of a number of nuclear sites in the UK either belonging to British Energy or to NDA. And this was done through EDF Energy, our British subsidiary. I remind you that EDF Energy is one of the key operators in the electricity market in the UK.</p>
          <p>Last word about this context and changing contexts, we had a piece of good news yesterday. We've finally at long last received from the European Commission an agreement or the approval that we were hoping and counting on. There were discussions going on with Excelsium and our colleagues, members of Excelsium so that we can now implement the contract signed between EDF and Excelsium, a highly innovative contract that will enable us to meet all the interest and concerns of the concerned parties, electro-intensive industries in the Excelsium consortium and EDF on the other side.</p>
          <p>Lastly, major progress has been made in the field of developing an integrated European energy market. The interconnection plans that have been discussed for a long time have been progressing well. They are all intended to strengthen solidarity between the countries. Electricity exchanges are also coming together setting up mechanisms for market coupling. And let me repeat once again, EDF as a leading European player in the electricity market has everything to gain from such an integration in Europe that will further strengthen our leadership in Europe.</p>
          <p>Let's now move on to the actual results. In this context financial results have continued to grow both in France and internationally. In France, our sales are up 8% driven by the growth of volume sales, particularly with end customers naturally and, to a lesser extent, driven as well by trends in rises in prices and tariffs.</p>
          <p>EBITDA growth is positive although moderate, plus 1.3% due largely to higher cost; energy purchases fuel &#x2013; fuel purchases and increasing cost, of course, in our purchasing obligations, which we were unable to fully pass on into the prices and rates.</p>
          <p>Internationally, we have enjoyed a significant growth of our sales, plus 10.3%, and EBITDA has grown significantly as well, plus 9.2%. Internationally, of course, there's much greater contribution of higher costs, fuel, coal and so on, but we were able to pass on, in a differentiated manner, in tariffs and rates that have grown faster and higher than in France. EDF trading has performed very well. EDF trading is our subsidiary with EBITDA growing over 80%.</p>
          <p>I'd also like to stress the success of our renewable energy subsidiaries called EDF Energies Nouvelles. The success and growth illustrates the major benefits and the success of our strategy as integrated electricity operator.</p>
          <p>Before going into details with Daniel Camus later on to look at the various aggregates of our income let me stress another point on our CapEx program. We have significantly increased our capital expenditures in order to maintain and develop our industrial advance. Our operating investments, at group level, have grown up 36% versus the first half of 2007. For the first half '08 &#x20AC;4.1 billion were invested. Strong growth dynamics therefore, the goal of which is to strengthen our positions in our major businesses and our major markets. Of course on the short-term, these investments will have an impact, or have an impact on the growth of our net income. Nevertheless they will be guaranteeing our future operational performance.</p>
          <p>And I'll give the floor to Daniel Camus for more details on the various aggregates and items of the half year results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>First sales, 32.2 billion, a substantial growth plus 6% in published figures, plus 9% organic growth. The only scope effect that deserves to be mentioning on the EBITDA is the exit of Mexico of the consolidation scope, Mexico accounting for &#x20AC;320 million less in terms of consolidated sales. With the variance in the EBITDA &#x2013; on EBITDA that accounts &#x20AC;60 million less in our EBITDA.</p>
          <p>These are the only significant changes in our scope beside from conventional currency, particularly due to the pound sterling. So, plus 9% organic growth EBITDA, up nearly 4%. Better than expected, slightly better than expected. In late February we'd explained to you that we were below the guidance. Actually we've done better, plus 3.9%. Which means that by the end of the year, we're now confident that we will be delivering an EBITDA of around 3%, slightly better than expected therefore.</p>
          <p>Same thing for the year figures, that is excluding the TaRTAM transition tariff effect, which I can go into greater details later on, if you wish. EBIT, net income attributable 9.5, 12.2 with two extraordinary items and with a strict definition. These were special events in 2007 that did not recur in 2008.</p>
          <p>The first one was the provision that was recovered on the renewal of our meters, 450 million and that is not recurring this year. The second is the capital gains of &#x20AC;110 million from the disposal of ED-Nor and there again that was extraordinary last year.</p>
          <p>So after adjusting for these two elements, net income has gone down 3.7%. We had said that it would probably not grow and we should continue along this downward trend for the rest of the year.</p>
          <p>Sales and organic growth, everywhere in Europe and even in France, we'll see the sales have grown. You see 8% in France, 23 in Italy, 16 in Rest of Europe, 7 in Germany, driven by different factors. But outside the France, driven essentially by commodities impact and gas prices which we're not always able to pass on, particularly in Italy.</p>
          <p>Let's take a look at the details country-by-country. 3.9% EBITDA growth, let's see how that breaks down. Impact of sales, excluding exchange of scope, you see 1.9 billion. Fuel and energy purchases over 1 billion in addition.</p>
          <p>In France, this growth extends &#x2013; exceeds 12%, 12% more in fuel purchases linked to our PPAs and cost income and loss.</p>
          <p>Internationally, plus 7%. That is part &#x2013; a breakdown for the 1.045 billion. This is &#x2013; in Italy, &#x20AC;600 million was the additional gas purchases.</p>
          <p>OpEx, although it's not very significant on the group scale, it represents 4.9% growth. OpEx by definition, that includes personnel expenses as well as other external purchases, plus a number of miscellaneous items and others 335 less. And strong growth as &#x2013; but less than the sales growth due to high material and commodities cost and some changes in the OpEx.</p>
          <p>Let's take a look at the breakdown per countries. In France, sales have gone up 8%. Gross margin has gone up more 6%, in spite of the increased material costs.</p>
          <p>OpEx have &#x2013; mean that over the period EBITDA withstood things but has grown only 1.3%. Adverse regulatory measures, and this, of course, has had a major impact in France, but TaRTAM, transition tariff impact, is &#x20AC;200 million on the first half and I'll come back later on to that.</p>
          <p>Impact as well from the pension reform and supporting measures and I will come back to that later on.</p>
          <p>Brief comments on this new graph to show the dynamics of EDF staff line over this half year period. On the left production generation, on the right sales portfolio.</p>
          <p>Generation, good news here is that nuclear generation and hydraulic production have gone up 3.7 terawatt and 2.3 terawatt respectively out of a total of 8.4, so high volume growth, as you see slightly less on fossil fired, down 0.5%.</p>
          <p>On the right hand side of this slide, sales and staff consumption, the mix was perhaps less favorable but that was basically a mechanical effect. High growth of the market plus 2% over the half year, 2% in France is a major figure, and sales to end customers up 13.9% in green here is a 6.5% growth, much more than just proportional of sales to end users.</p>
          <p>Net sales here you have of course VPPs and market sales that &#x2013; there again we have the TaRTAM transition tariff effect minus 5.9 terawatts. And if we break that down, some of you analysts perhaps look and monitor this figure, minus 5-out of this minus 5.9 we have 2.4 plus of EDT -- VPPs excuse me. Net market sales have gone down 8.3, plus 2.4, minus 8.3. Normally we should end up with minus 5.9. So that is &#x2013; those were the dynamics of our top line. Now this in terms of analyzing the sales, you see the volume impact in euros, over &#x20AC;900 million.</p>
          <p>Transmission climate effect &#x20AC;125 million. Net market sales, you see they're also translated &#x2013; this is translation of a previous graph minus 449. Prices in tariffs, minus 469. Out of that tariffs that have increased last year contribute up to &#x20AC;156 million, a third of this 469 effect of prices on tariffs.</p>
          <p>Sales of natural gases and services, up there again. These figures continue to grow significantly. We had &#x20AC;425 million in gas sales over the half year.</p>
          <p>So this is it for sales revenues, let's analyze the EBITDA in France. Sales, we've seen that. Purchases of energy and fuel, we already mentioned that earlier. There are two major impacts in this case.</p>
          <p>Effect due to regulations, in particular purchasing obligations, which have grown significantly, &#x20AC;168 million. Network losses have also increased and CSPE, with a negative impact of &#x20AC;326 million after hedging. So nearly &#x20AC;600 million, 594 which are linked to higher market prices.</p>
          <p>Two other items for OpEx, personal expenses, other external consumption. If you add up these two they have gone up 7.8%, you double up 174 plus 294. So, 7.8% of course is a sharp increase in spite of the ex &#x2013; operational excellence cost reduction program. That is in line with our goals; two different conveyances. Personal expenses plus 4.6% including the pension reform impact. We had told you that we would have an impact of anywhere between 200, &#x20AC;250 million for the year. As of late June we reached 105 million.</p>
          <p>Other external consumptions, the major item is linked to maintenance cost, up &#x20AC;123 million, including &#x20AC;44 million. Net up 1.3% excuse me 1.8% slightly better than what we're expecting. Sales revenue have gone up significantly. The mix is moderately favorable as gross margin has gone up plus 6%, but OpEx have grown due to maintenance cost and the pension reform more than the ordinary average in France.</p>
          <p>Second aspect of EBITDA is international business. As Pierre said earlier, figures have moved up and grown satisfactorily, plus 10% of sales revenue, plus 9% for the EBITDA in organic growth.</p>
          <p>With two or three major contributors of course growth of sales naturally is something we've seen in virtually all European countries. The growth rate &#x2013; some of them are well beyond, that with growth rates well beyond the French price increases, but a major impact on sales. In Italy, where we had base load only, or in Germany where we have some nuclear but we also have gas, gas and coal and of course we've &#x2013; that's had a major impact in the UK. We're highly dependent on gas, hence we are suffering from higher cost in gas and coal, some of which we can pass on to end users but not all the time.</p>
          <p>So that was for the overall picture. Let's now take a look at the main subsidiaries.</p>
          <p>I am satisfied to say that EDF Energy got off to a good start this year even though last year was difficult and that was due to the gas volatility and the hedging system. We heard it was quite difficult but at the beginning of the year EBITDA is up 6.8% and that is due to the increase in the tolls that was accepted last year, 4.2%. That's network fee increases, but also an increase in tariffs in the UK. It's the second tariff increases in the UK. The one in January was up 6.9% and the second increase, that was announced a number of days ago, which is 17% for electricity and 22% for gas, before what happened with British Gas yesterday. So as you can see, the regulated market and the non-regulated markets are more intact and so there is growth there. And we trust that we can do something in the UK till the end of the year. More than last year we think we're going to have a big growth.</p>
          <p>What about EnBW now?  EnBW will publish their own accounts. Some of you know what the situation is like. Now they've posted an organic growth, or in terms of sales is more than 7%. EBITDA is almost 2%. And the big power companies in Germany adjust their EBITDA, we are now familiar with this like RWE. They have posted 9.5% of their EBITDA. Our definition is more restricted if you will, the way we measure EBITDA.</p>
          <p>So a satisfactory trend I can say with a slight increase for electricity and the gas performance is stable. Now there's the impact of the decrease concerning the network fee increases. &#x20AC;16 million, that's the impact of the decline in network fees.</p>
          <p>Right, a few words about Italy now. Now, we're getting to what we wanted to do in Italy. We started, I mean, the performance is what counts compared with last year. As you know when Edison post their accounts every quarter we had many regulatory measures in Italy and that was difficult for us.</p>
          <p>I can tell you that if we look at sales, it was up 13%, but EBITDA was going down during the first quarter by 22%. Now it's only 10% today, minus 10%. But before the end of the year, we would like to do what we achieved last year. That's for Italy, that's for Edison. So good electricity performance, plus 4%.</p>
          <p>But in terms of gas, as you can see clearly here, the situation has been quite difficult. Minus 34%, that's for EBITDA. And in addition to extra taxes that were stacked on what we already have, as you know, there's been Robin Hood tax which was &#x20AC;70 million on net sales during the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>So, we've been catching up since the beginning of the year in Italy, and it's seems that H2 will be better therefore.</p>
          <p>Now the Rest of Europe, the Rest of Europe. It's not the Rest of Europe really, but you will see that usually we say this in our group. The Rest of Europe is growing fast. And therefore, if we look at EBITDA, this is the equivalent of EnBW's and Edison's EBITDA cumulated figure, more or less. So, as you can see, there's strong growth, at least in three ways, as Pierre was saying before.</p>
          <p>EDF Trading is growing fast and the second one is something we've been experiencing since the beginning of the year. As you know the beginning of the year had an extraordinary performance level. And if you look at the table there, down the slide, we have a margin in trading which is almost 80%. It's true for coal. I'll give you two figures. The coal margin was up 230 million during the first half and the electricity margin was up 200 million during the first half. So as you can see, all in all, 430 million in this dimension. So an excellent performance that we manage, of course, carefully.</p>
          <p>EDF Trading is &#x2013; as the backing of the French base. And we optimize the scope of EDF Energy and we can reap the fruit of all this little-by-little. This is quite encouraging. To which we can add the fact that we fine tune our business. We have a risk policy which is very stringent, if you will. We know that the markets are volatile, which is good for us to take very smart positions. But I can tell you that we control all risks. That's the first growth factor we have.</p>
          <p>The second growth factor is Eastern Europe. There are two countries that have grown fast, Hungary and Poland during the first half of the year. As you can see here, the figures reached more than 20%. This is a trend that we have had now for several half years.</p>
          <p>The third factor is EDF Energies Nouvelles. They have not yet posted their accounts, this is a listed company. But we know what the figures are like. They're all good. All the indicators are in the green. So this is a good growth instrument for EDF.</p>
          <p>We've got photovoltaic business and the wind business. But we can tell you more about this, if you're interested.</p>
          <p>So three growth factors in the Rest of Europe. So all in all, up 28%, that's for EBITDA for that scope.</p>
          <p>Net income, I have three comments to make on this. First, amortization is up, and that's due to our investment program or capital expenditure program. 100 million is the extra charge for us during the first half of the year, in France mainly. The other items are the ones we know, the ones I described before, that is the renewal provision and the capital gain for ED-Nor.</p>
          <p>And as far as financial income is concerned, good results. As you can see, there is an increase, but there's a mechanical aspect to it. The debt has increased by &#x20AC;2 billion, but the financial charge or cost has decreased by &#x20AC;10 million, so we know how to finance the company. So the 100 million increase is just mechanical, it's due to the pension charge and the nuclear impact. And, as you know, the impact of financial markets is &#x20AC;135 million only, that's the net figure for the group.</p>
          <p>We can then turn to net income, before we talk about cash flow. There's not much we can say. There's the tax rate, which 32.4% for the first half. And for the rest of the year, we think we're going to have 32%. So no surprise. And group's net income from ordinary operations is the one which is posted here, 3 billion. And therefore a decrease of 3.7% for net income, which is above &#x20AC;3 billion, which, in this context, is something that shows how solid the group is.</p>
          <p>I can then end with the free cash flow and the debt. As you can see here, we have the normal restating of tax and financial expenses, FFO 6.4 billion. This is what we had last year the FFO, funds from operations. The working capital requirements have increased enormously, due to two factors. The first one is linked to EDF Trading with the market electricity low. Now the situation is such that, for the time being, there's a call for margins, margin call. So this is going to use up a cash &#x20AC;800 million during this period. The stocks were up &#x20AC;600 million, that is gas stocks, coal stocks. That's the increase 60, 70, or 80% for coal. So a fast trend. So two factors, 4.1 billion is for capital expenditure, our Chairman mentioned this before. So we are on the tracks &#x20AC;36 million as we said. The evolution during the period will be, well, by the end of the year &#x20AC;11 billion for capital expenditure. And free cash flow is at &#x20AC;500 million.</p>
          <p>Now few words about the net financial debt. It has increased. Well, free cash flow after capital expenditure is up &#x20AC;500 million and dedicated assets, as you know we're building our portfolio. We'll have 2.8 billion at the end of the year. We already have 1.3 billion after six months. And at the end of June, the amount is 9.1 billion, that is dedicated assets that have been set aside. And the end target for us is 2010 as you know.</p>
          <p>And then the dividends, that's the second part after giving an installment is 1.3 and then we have disposals of assets negative 0.2, acquisitions plus 0.6. Therefore the debt we post is more than &#x20AC;18 billion at the end of June. We will have more than &#x20AC;20 billion at the end of the year. These were the main figures. Now, I think, the time has come to perhaps answer your questions if you have any. But before that we're going to listen to Pierre Gadonneix again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Daniel. Now to wrap up, I think you've noticed that the half year results show that the progress we have achieved is better than the one we had planned. Therefore, if we look at fully year, which is what Daniel Camus mentioned and this is what we said in February, the organic growth objective we have for EBITDA will be more or less 3%. And apart from the fact that the transition tariff will last longer, the evolution of the net income should be impacted by our major capital expenditure program and net income could therefore perhaps remain flat in 2008, if we compare it with 2007, so no increase.</p>
          <p>And to perhaps answer the question that you might ask on this, and to anticipate your questions, I would like to say few worlds about the regulated tariffs on the selling of electricity in France.  As you have probably appraised the operating costs we have, a subset -- the volume of investments have gone up due to the fact that the price of commodities and raw materials have increased like the hydrocarbons, and also due to the fact that we've decided to speed up with the setting up of new generation capacity and also to the fact that we've decided to maintain and service our networks. This being the general context, and so as to cover for these costs, I've asked the public authorities to increase the regulated tariffs which will be differentiated depending on the different groups of customers we have. I want to do this yet in compliance with the public service contracts we have for the end-users. That is an increase which will correspond to the inflation rate maximum. So there are ongoing discussions with the public authorities today in France.</p>
          <p>And that is to answer a question you might ask, you might have asked. Now with Jean Mathias and Daniel Camus, we are quite ready to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. I have two questions to ask. First, what about the amount of synergies that you think you will have, thanks to the acquisition of British Energy, when will you get these synergies? And my second question is, now the second reactor of Flamanville is controlled by ASN, I wonder how many reactors will be controlled in this way in 2008? And what about your load factor, where will it be in 2008 and 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Well, to answer your first question concerning British Energy, there is not much I can say about it, but of course we have discussed with these operators on a number of topics.  But in the light of what I said at the beginning of my presentation, I do not wish to mention these discussions more. As far as your second question is concerned, that is what we have done with the Flamanville EPR. I don't think there is anything special about it, but Jean-Louis we will tell you more about this, Jean-Louis Mathias.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now you've not mentioned the EPR, but the Flamanville 2 reactor, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The construction project we have, is this what you mean? It is not an EPR then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At present, there is defect on a transformer, faulty transformer for the Flamanville 1 reactor, which is such that we have to have a back up so that we're safe with Flamanville 1 reactor, so the back up is made by Flamanville 2. It's the normal type of back up procedure, so there are no special difficulties in terms of security and safety. Now of course it's all based on the availability, the up-time of these reactors and this is the only thing I can say, the only impact. I don't know if you wanted me to discuss the up-time or availability of reactors in a general way.</p>
          <p>Right, so I can say few words about this.  As you have probably seen and as Daniel said not long ago, we intend to increase our power generation by 3.7-terawatt hours compared with the other half, that is the second of half of 2007, that's the nuclear power and that's due to the fact that we make a better use of our nuclear power plants, the ones that we currently operate. This is easy to understand.</p>
          <p>If you look at weather conditions during the first half, it was a lot colder than first half of 2007. So if we look at availability in our generation base, that's going to be -- it was impacted by something, an event which is, the fact that some steam generators were cleared, we did that with two during the first half, three will be cleansed during the second half of the year. So that has an impact of 2% on up-time or availability of this installed base.</p>
          <p>And also we've had series the anomalies, events that happened during the first half of the year concerning electrical installation for some alternators for some units that we called 1300 units. We know this phenomenon and in 2006 we started investing in this more specifically. The impact of these two phenomena is such that we don't need to change our objective, the objective being 85% in terms of the availability of the installed base by the year 2010 and 2011.  Of course in the light of all of these events, I can tell you that we will perhaps not have a linear type of progression and we will probably not do this is as quickly as expected. Thank you.  Any more question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. I have three questions, if you will. First one regarding your annual targets maybe I didn't understand you well. You said that early in the year you managed 3%, I would say growth slightly below 3% over the year, year-on-year.  Now you're talking about the EBITDA growth slightly above 3% over the year excluding the transition tariff impact?  Did I understand you right?  And in that case, what is -- what will be the transition tariff impact over the year?</p>
          <p>Second question has to do with the TaRTAM transition tariff.  From what I understand, you have a cap price for what you're paying to third-party generators, right?  Now the comp prices, are they above these cap prices?  Could that cap price be revised, and in which case, what impact would it have?  Can you give us more details on that?</p>
          <p>Third question, like to go beyond just say the UK.  Obviously you are not &#x2013; you didn't say anything about Belgium, you had made a proposal and you've not commented on that venture. Of course it's closed the door, so that closes the door in Belgium.  Consensus seems to be you're not going to go to Spain either.  Can you tell us about your ambitions, the ambitions that EDF had initially at the time of the IPO?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Daniel Camus will answer your two questions and I will answer the third question. Daniel Camus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the guidance, what we had said, yes, is that earlier in the year we were very concerned with a number of things going on. And for transparency reason, we explained that we were giving guidance slightly below 3% at best. Now you've seen here the results for the first half year in spite of major cost increases, particularly for the French OpEx, we nevertheless did say that we were quite confident that by the end of year, we should reach at least 3%. So, I'd like to confirm that. So, clearly this is better than what we were expected.  And as regards the concerns that we had earlier this year, international business is doing quite well and much better, basically everywhere better than we were expecting.</p>
          <p>On the TaRTAM transition tariff, let's spend a few minutes on that. Since the announcement of the extension of the transition tariff that was published in -- as of late July, like all other regulations, this of course follows the pace of laws and amendments adopted by the Parliament.</p>
          <p>Let me just add this. Today as I'm speaking, we don't have all the parameters needed to quantify the exact impact of this expansion of the TaRTAM. Let me try to guide you perhaps, to give you an insight of what the impact could be. This is of course depending on enforcement decrease, volumes, concerns around 41 terawatts, wholesale prices as specified, which of course are dependent on offsetting of competitors compensated by CSPE, that depends on the reference tariffs as well, that is used as a basis to calculate the TaRTAM tariff, and other variables that we have no control over. We've done our best to estimate things as best as we can.</p>
          <p>Today, the order of magnitude that we have in terms of impact, the expansion of tariff, that would be an impact for 2009 as well as 2010. Today, the most significant impact of course is compensation of competitors, the reason being that market prices, wholesale prices have reached extremely high levels today. Of course it will depend what they've -- level they've reached. But we estimate the 2009 impact between 600 and &#x20AC;700 million for compensation of competitors. And we've estimated an impact between 200 and &#x20AC;300 for 2010. Of course, depending on one shot supplies sourcing by the end of 2008, that may change. Then again, the enforcement decrease will give us more details by the end of 2009 -- 8, excuse me.</p>
          <p>Now this is a measuring instrument that we also use internally, there's a wholesale impact, price impact of &#x20AC;10 per megawatt hour, represents approximately &#x20AC;150 million in annual impact. I'm talking about the TaRTAM transition tariff. So &#x20AC;10 per megawatt hour will represent a total impact of approximately 150 million. And when I talked about 3%, of course we're excluding this purely exceptional TaRTAM effect, naturally. Answer to your third question is given by Chairman Gadonneix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is linked to our expansion strategy. As shown by our financial results, we have confirmed this strategy. We have basically three orientations. The first orientation actually is to strengthen and consolidate our positions in Europe, where we already are present. Second orientation in our expansion is to act as leaders in the revival of nuclear power in Europe and in the world. And in that area, we have vision to be the number one. We believe we are the leader. We want to be the leader in this renaissance of nuclear power throughout the world. Third orientation is the promotion of renewable energy sources. Let me try to illustrate that we are moving ahead and quite significantly in all three directions.  Consolidation in Europe as you've seen, we have our CapEx program is even better than expected, 30% in excess of what we had planned. So we're clearly and soundly engaged in this path. This is true for France, it is true for all of our subsidiaries as well.</p>
          <p>Expansion in Europe, let me -- consolidation of our position in Europe. Let me mention the transaction we haven't discussed yet, namely the EnBW German subsidiaries acquired 23% of EWE which is number five in the electricity market in Germany. So there again we are bolstering our position in Germany and quite significantly so. In the rest of Europe, in the Benelux countries, another example is the projects we -- joint projects with DELTA, called Sloe. It's a joint project, namely intending to build and operate jointly a cogeneration plant. And final example, the project of Edison in Italy, which is planning to build a combine gas -- combined-cycle in Greece. So consolidation of European market position, that is going well, and moving forward.</p>
          <p>I've told you about our projects and prospects for expansion in renewable energies. In that respect, we're quite pleased.  Of course, we can not disclose the account of EDF Energies Nouvelles, because they will be publishing their own account. But I can always tell you that we're very, very pleased with the growth of EDF Energies Nouvelles and renewable energy businesses, primarily driven by wind power. And via these Energies Nouvelles subsidiaries, we envision to play a major role as well in solar photovoltaic power, which actually would be increasing the pace of our business plan for Energies Nouvelles, EDF Energies Nouvelles.</p>
          <p>Last but not least, let's say a few words about the nuclear developments internationally. We have identified four target countries. This is something we already told you, some two years ago, and we're currently moving forward in all four countries. These four target countries are China, where we have a partnership signed with one of major electricity operators, call CGNPC, local Chinese operator. And we will be co-developing and co-building two nuclear plans in Taishan in China, Peoples Republic of China.  I'm really confident for this project and several dozens of EDF staff members are already onsite to clinch the partnership.</p>
          <p>In addition, our partnership in the US with Constellation has been boosted there again.  We have several dozens EDF staff members working in the US. We have moved faster here because we've reached the licensing phase which is the ultimate phase, not the ultimate phase, the initial phase, where in China, in Taishan we already have bulldozers out there getting ready for the -- to lay the first cornerstone. The site was chosen less than a year ago and we already had bulldozers out there, while in the US we've reached only the licensing process with Constellation.</p>
          <p>In South Africa we're expecting the results of the call for bids that was launched by ESKOM. We submitted a bid to -- as a supplier but what we'd like to do is to clinch a partnership with ESKOM, provided of course that ESKOM, the electricity operator in South Africa chooses the EPR. And last target country is the UK, of course, and I reassert and confirm once again that I feel that the British market will be the -- leading the number one market for nuclear power plants over the coming decade.  So the first investor in your nuclear power plants, that's us, EDF, we also intend to also be the leader in the leading nuclear market that will be developing in the UK.</p>
          <p>Last but not least, another reminder something, I've already told us before, expansion via acquisition is just a means to reach our goal and this will need -- this will rely on the three prerequisites which are very close to my heart and I will remain firm, I will stand firm. And let me repeat myself, we want to be welcome in the country.  When I say welcome, it means that local and national public authorities regard our presence there as a positive signal for their own energy policies and political policies. Secondly, it has to be consistent with our own industrial strategy, and among others I have decided to grant a priority to nuclear power in our industrial expansion strategies. Clearly we want to give preference, we want to use our asset as nuclear experts and we want to play a major role in international development for nuclear power.</p>
          <p>In Spain for example, we absolutely do not intend to have any major operation or any major expansion in Europe that would not be consistent with these three rules I've just given you. And in Spain, we do not intend in particular to take any kind of significant positions as rumors have said.  We have no intention of acquiring any position in Iberdrola.</p>
          <p>Last but not least, the conditions for acquisitions or investing abroad, and that is the third prerequisite, must create value for EDF. Let's be clear, our financial conditions must ensure that the new contributor will create value within three years. Thank you for asking this question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's another question we've received via Internet, same question we've had. Jonathan Constable from Lehman Brothers had asked the same question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question from Cr&#xE9;dit Mutuel-CIC. Four questions on the nuclear power. Okay, one of the criteria is to be welcome, but if we're waited until -- if we wanted to be welcome everywhere, we probably would not...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me do it again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me ask the question again. Okay, nuclear power, let's forget British Energy, the way for the British government to get rid of that. Do you have other visions of that, particularly from the NDA, but we didn't really understand that's the way the British government wanted to play things out?</p>
          <p>Second question, you said that you were -- you asked the French authorities for an increase of regulated tariffs that would not exceed inflation rate. The inflation, what is inflation rate?  I imagine it's no longer 1.5%.</p>
          <p>Third question, a lot of rumors, ridiculous rumors, so ridiculous question we said that some of the German banks wanted to get rid of EnBW.  Is that absolutely ridiculous? It is so ridiculous that you never had that in mind and forget it let's not even talk about it?</p>
          <p>And last and fourth question, very technical question, something I misunderstood. When you look at OpEx and personal expenses going up, what about the pension amounts?  150 million, is that in line with your expectations or has that drifted away from your expectations?</p>
          <p>And then Jean-Louis Mathias talked about a problem with electrical insulators, this a surprise.  Are you discovering things as you're cleaning things up and maintaining things?  Of course, you have more concern for security, you're finding new things that go wrong, malfunction.  Is it something that you expected? I was kind of surprised to see that there were problems there, and except for extraordinary items there is a major distortion between the growth of EBIT and the growth of EBITDA while everything else stands similar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll try to answer you question. On the topic of being welcome, I'm saying aloud what everybody is thinking, if you're an electricity operator, this is a highly sensitive topic in all countries and it's becoming more and more sensitive. What I'm saying is bit more and more -- in other words, no country, no state, no government today in the world can afford to be -- not to be interested in the energy policy.  It is not true, you cannot go to invest as an electricity generator or just like you would to produce shoes or any kind of consumer goods, that is not true, that is not the case. I've said it again and will repeat it. So when we go to a country, we will invest in that country only if at the top political level, the government of that country welcomes us with open arm, and that is always true without any exception.</p>
          <p>Edison, you mentioned Edison as an example, I'm very glad that you did.  Takes me back four years ago, I know that we were experiencing a very difficult situation, you all remember four years ago in Italy.  And because of that difficult situation, it meant that at the time we were not welcome in Italy.  I sat down, negotiated and among the people around the table, we -- there were Italian public authorities and government authorities. The coincidence is that at the same time, we settled the Edison issue, we became investors and at the same time we found an Italian partner and at the same time coincidentally we also were there developing a partnership with the major, the main Italian electricity operators, namely Enel. And I think today we can say safely that we are welcome in Italy. Thank you for asking that question, again.</p>
          <p>Second question, in the UK, are we welcome in the UK?  Well, the answer is obviously yes. We've had in-depth talk for the past three years with the British authorities. We are of course making sure that the licensing process on the EPR continues and moves forward as quickly as possible.  And as you probably know, we also need to have sites and two have sites to build new power plants.  The key priority, or rather, for the first wave of construction is to have access to sites that are already nuclear sites. It's true in all countries, it's much easier to build a new nuclear power plant next to an existing nuclear power plant.</p>
          <p>So for the past three years we've been investigating things to identify the best sites in the UK.  And the British authorities had in fact done a similar analysis.   Today, these sites, the major sites close to existing nuclear plants, either belong to NDA or to British Energy or to EDF Energy. Lot of talks have already taken place between the three partners and discussions will continue so that we can speed up the beginning of this nuclear renaissance in the UK. And I can assure you that yes, we are welcome by the British authorities.</p>
          <p>Let me add to that, in the UK we have a situation that is rather special and exceptional. Let me tell you an anecdote, and I don't think that would happen in many other countries in Europe and the world. Initially, London Electricity was the name British subsidiaries and Vincent de Rivaz and his team did -- took a poll to find out what name we could question to the subsidiaries so that it would have as much visibility and credibility as possible. The answer to that survey poll was call it EDF Energy. Just the way to show you how welcome we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Germany, just a few words. The rumors in Germany, as you know there's been many, many of rumors all over the place. This is a non-issue in Germany. On the contrary, EnBW is a mature subsidiary, excellent covenants in the company overall with the shareholding structure you're familiar with, management staff was recently renewed, Chairman, Financial -- Chief Financial Officer was appointed just a few days ago, financial results are fine, turnaround is now bearing its fruit with excellent financial results.</p>
          <p>Priority of EnBW today is growing, growing in and out of Germany. In Germany, this is reflected -- this recent strategy is reflected with the stake that was recently acquired in EWE, which is the fifth largest German electricity operator. So by creating an alliance that opens up for new opportunities in terms of joint future projects, excellent opportunities, I believe.  And outside of Germany they're looking at Turkey, wind power outside of Germany with a number of other projects. The priority is now to grow and EnBW is a major vector and an excellent company in &#x2013; by and by. So there is what  I would call it, that's a non-issue, pure rumors, nothing else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's take a look at your other questions on nuclear power. Well, there are many technical aspects. We could look at all the details, but there's something that is key when it comes to our policy when we look at nuclear power plants in France. Of course, our number one priority is safety and security. This is known, this is credible and this is something that people recognize in our group. This is one of the reasons why EDF has an excellent image as a nuclear operator.</p>
          <p>Now, if we were to look at the performance of our installed base, we have two objectives that we have to meet simultaneously. I mean it, simultaneously, because sometimes there might be conflict between the two objectives, so we'll see how we can optimize the situation. The first is the utilization rate. Now you're familiar with this, you sometimes ask questions about the availability of power plants. The up-time, that is when the nuclear power plants are available should we need them. The second element is the life cycle of the nuclear power plants, their duration, if you will. This is very important for the business model of ours, for EDF's business model. So, now that we've decided to increase our capital expenditure, we've decided to modernize our nuclear power plants installed base. We optimize the current situation and we prepare the ground for future. This is what Jean-Louis mentioned before.  When we decide to revamp and modernize the installed base in some components like the alternators, now what we do is that we have an impact on the availability coefficient, but also we prepare the future. So, we try and optimize these situations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A few words about inflation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the inflation rate. Well, I don't want to say too much about this. I don't want to give you figures, otherwise this would lead to useless discussions, to be clear. But as I told you, this -- I've made my request, this is all.  The figures would be posted in due time.</p>
          <p>Thank you. Oh, many questions, many questions. Right, I'll have to give you shorter answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could ask a question in English, are you continuing to hold talks with the Board of British Energy, and would you consider a hostile takeover a bid for the company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My friend, I'm sure that you do not expect an answer by yes or no to your question. Obviously, I cannot answer your question, because we are in a situation, in an environment which is controlled strictly, because all the companies you mention are quoted on the stock market and I cannot make any comment of that type. I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've never conducted any hostile takeover.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well generally speaking I'd like to be welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, to be welcome means, hostile is not...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We prefer to welcomed than in an hostile environment. That's sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, next please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have some questions to ask. You mentioned Iberdrola, but the Courts in Spain have asked you to express yourselves, will you go there? Will you go to Spain? Would you do something or not? Can you say that nothing will be done with or about Iberdrola?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will not give you more comments on this. I've already expressed my thoughts. However if I have to go there I will go to Spain of course. I will respect the State of Law. I will respect the State of Spain and the Basque Region. There's a question that was asked on the web. Many people ask questions. Andrew Meade asked a question, Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>About 11 billion CapEx will be spent on by region in France and by network versus generation [French] .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd like to recall to answer this question concerning CapEx. That in terms of annual distribution, were inline with the CapEx we had before, now this is multi-annual type of cycle, there's no erratic change from one year to the next. So &#x20AC;36 billion is what we have, there's &#x20AC;11 billion this year, so it's 20 billion in France, 16 billion outside of France and 20 billion in France. In this we have 75% for the regulated business and maintenance business in the non-regulated markets. So the details by Pierre Gadonneix before, is a good indicator if you want to make projections for the end of the year. Any more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes please. Good morning. I have three questions. First when you adjust weather conditions, due you think that large industrial companies use less electricity or not? Secondly, could you tell us more about the pricing in the Excelsium contract for your consumers? And thirdly, what about the fact that some countries want to tax the profit made by utilities? Could this change your investment programs in some of these countries?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, to answer the first question, we can tell you, most of the growth will be from the mass market. But we've not seen any change in the trends concerning industrial customers. The trend has not changed and of course, the transition types will impact the consumption of industrial customers but in terms of volumes, there's not much I can say. Your second question was about Excelsium. There's nothing new about our pricing. The Excelsium deal is such that EDF will have an electricity price which is quite good in the light of what we have usually on regulated types and this is totally in keeping with the development costs we have in the nuclear sector. In the eyes of the Excelsium partners, they have access to energy at a price which is quite interesting.</p>
          <p>No Excelsium members have enough weight to consolidate the progress of &#x20AC;3.6 billion which will be necessary for all the companies that belong to Excelsium. Now the discussions we've had with the European Commission, as we said, were about the fact that some clients could pull out from Excelsium after 10 years. So the issue was all about this. How can Excelsium manage this risk that is with available energy? And therefore the discussions were on the way to hedge the risk for Excelsium. We have a role to play of course. But there's a counter part to this, that is, we have indexing solutions which are favorable to us. So if we look at the economics of this deal, nothing was modified after the discussions that took place in Brussels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To answer your third question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You mentioned new taxes on utilities here and there, could this happen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course it could happen anywhere. I think you were thinking about the tax paper in Italy which is the Robin Hood tax. It's not just for the utilities or the energy sector, it's for all sectors. So we have to adapt to the local situation of course. Now I'd like to come back to something we said before. Sometime ago I said that I put a request for tariff increase, a price increase in France, what I said is that this increase we would be asking for would be differentiated depending on the sectors. And as far as the domestic market is concerned, we would do this in keeping with a public service contract and in keeping with inflation in general. So to be more accurate, when I meant inflation, it was for the residential market that is for everybody. Otherwise, for the other sectors, what I meant is that the increase could be above inflation rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A question asked on the internet. Someone asked the question to Jean-Louis about the growth in sales in France.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said, there 's a sharp increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it due to the fact we sell to new customers, we sell new applications or is it the old one's who consume more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said before, it's mainly due to the weather conditions. And as you know, the growth, excluding weather conditions is in between 1.5 and 2% annually. This is the regular increase we have in terms of electricity consumption in France.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, please. Hello, I have three questions to ask. First, your gains of EBITDA this year, you have said 3.9 for the first half of the year. In May, you said the performance would be better during the second half of the year compared with the first half. Does that mean that your 3% objective is conservative or do you want to be more conservative during the second half of the year, more than what you were in May? Now secondly, a question concerning your trading, what's the absolute value that you would say is a conservative figure for the whole year. And finally, the pension reform, do you know how this will impact your balance sheet, the special pension reform, you've shown the impact on the P&amp;L what about the impact on balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are very careful, so as I said, this is our best estimate. We trust, we are confident, the trend as you know in France is correct, a bit better than what we had planned and abroad it's better. So we are quite confident that the growth will be in the order of 3%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what about the pension reform and the impact of this pension reform?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is a very technical topic but the reform was led with a very clear rationale. It should be neutral on the P&amp;L and neutral on the balance sheet this. If this is the case, if we look at the balance sheet on the P&amp;L impact, the net-impact that is personnel expenses and other items is &#x20AC;120 million, but it's neutral on the balance sheet. I think the only gap is 100 million before and after. In the total of &#x20AC;18 billion so that's why I said neutral. Now a few words about EDF trading, I chair this subsidiary and I can tell you that it is very difficult to make any forecast, but during the first half, we've had good results. Some elements are external elements, like the fact that markets of volatile and we have a risk hedging policy which is good enough. And there are more lasting elements, like for instance the fact that for two or three years we have developed a coal business that means we have capacity in Dutch harbors. We are the first coal importer in Europe via EDF trading from Europe. So this business line is a good development center if you will. Now concerning electricity, we've improved enormously. Mainly, well of course, we did good things in the past, we had good links between France and EDF trading, but we've made good progress and this was good for both companies. We did that in 18 months between EDF trading and EDF Energy. So this will be quite positive, it will have a positive impact on the bottom line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our business model is based on the fact that we want to consolidate business lines like EDF trading and other activities like energy <mark type="inaudible" /> or renewable energies with our commercial objectives. This is quite pertinent, a relevant approach which makes sense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have two questions to ask. First about the United Kingdom, you've ordered components for the first two units. It really shows that you're quite ambitious in the nuclear sector in the UK. Now I might have the impression from the outside that you're forced to buy British energy which is not really quite comfortable for us as analysts. Now should there be an agreement which would meet your financial objectives, well if it cannot be net sorry. Now have you been thinking about a joint venture? Do you think that this is a good option or have we turned the new page? I have a second question to Mr. Camus, can you tell us more about financial costs, they've increased during the first half of the year? Could you tell us more about pure financial expenses and other costs? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in terms of the first question about the United Kingdom, I don't have the feeling that we are forced to be the buyers or that there's going to be a forced sale, not at all. For three years we've been looking around at a number of scenarios, and as you said, we bought components. In the past we would also buy land as well. Now, Vincent Direva and his teams thought about this a while ago, years ago. At that time we were not totally certain about what we would do in the future, but what is for sure is that we would want to be the leaders in developing the nuclear sector in the UK.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about the financial expenses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can give you all the details. Now there are three factors that count as I said before, stability of gross debt and pure financial expenses minus &#x20AC;10 million as I said, while the debt is growing to .1 billion 2.6%. Second factor, 135 million as I said earlier, that is the impact of financial crisis, depreciation in the financial markets, on the securities portfolio that we have of course, it's very, very little. Third negative factor is growth of readjusting charges &#x20AC;106 million negative impact, nuclear provisions 45 million, labor expenses and accruals were 45, excuse me, &#x20AC;49 million that was the breakdown.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Deutsche Bank. First question has to do with the regulation of transmission and distribution of electricity in France. We adjusted a number of things with switches, often with tariff increases, so what could be the financial impact for next year if things are adjusted more even, particularly on supply adjustments for electricity and what type of yields or returns are you expecting? Second question is on disposals. Do you have any assets that you'd like to be selling-off at the end of the year that you would regard as non-strategic ie Dalca or any other financial interest perhaps? Other question relating to the development of your peak load capacities, particularly for certain, fossil fired plants, can you tell us more? And then lastly what are the reserves that you have, particularly as far as the supply necessary for the electricity generation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The TURP negotiations, that's the French jargon for T-U-R-P, this has to do with tariffs, that U is for utilization, R is for Raison Network Public. This is the third-party access rates, basically.  In French we call it the chop talks. Now you've heard about it naturally for gas, before we talk about the electricity simply because the regulators calendar to update these particular rates has been postpone. I believe we have anywhere between six to 12 month postponements. So negotiations have just started for us within regulator. Indeed, we will see how the access tariffs for the network for third parties. That is, how much will network users pay to access our network.</p>
          <p>And the idea, virtually in all countries, is to have a tariff &#x2013; a third-party tariff, if you will, that will be set by regulators and public authorities of course. Everybody has role to play, everybody has to agree to begin with regulators and public authorities. So, they will set on these third access rates, at a level that will remain stable, most likely for the next three or four years. So today we're working with the tariffs that were defined two years ago. I think they were extended one year, it was what, two years plus one or one year plus two, or one year plus one.  I forget the German.</p>
          <p>In any case, talks have started for the readjustment of this third-party access rates. In these talks, of course there are a number of factors, namely what is the level of investment capital expenditure that is needed and desirable to improve the network and what will be the impact on third-party access rates? These discussions are starting now, so no major official positions have been adopted.  All I can say is that roughly third-party access cost for -- accounts for approximately 40% of total cost, I believe. No, no, for residential &#x2013; no, if you add distribution plus transmission, it accounts for 60% of the total cost for end-users for residential customers and half for industrial customers. So the impact on the residential, really it will depend, of course, if you're a residential customer or if you're an industrial customer. That is the breakdown of transmission and distribution costs on the final price.</p>
          <p>On disposals, as we, at the time of the IPO, I had committed to disposals up to &#x20AC;5 billion. That was my commitment at the time. And this -- we have completed, finalized and fully completed our disposal program and we even exceeded the 5 billion, we went up to 5.7 billion in disposals. So that program is now over, and we have announced -- not announced any new disposal program.  On key closed capacities, sir, Jean-Louis Matthias will answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You remember that we had made a committed indeed to recommission four fuel-fired units over a three-year period. This year we will be reconnecting to our grid and the work is in line with the schedule. One unit in Avalon and one in Porscheville accounting for approximately 1,300 megawatt together. Then we have a combustion turbine program, approximately 500 megawatts that will be connected to the grid next year. And we're not talking about peak or base, but it's rather semi-base load.  By 2010 we're planning to commission the combined gas cycle, 400 megawatt in Blino, and in 2010, 2011 we're planning to renovate the Martik power plant.  This is fuel --- excuse me, the oil-fired plant, that will be renovated to coal and that will account for approximately 800 megawatt, excuse me, it will be oil-fired converted into gas-fired at Martik, 800 megawatt will be the capacity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions from Internet, JPMorgan in particular. What your building potential of the site? What's the timings? So how many sites have been acquired by EDF Energy in the UK?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course we can't respond in great details, but let me repeat. If you take the three site owners, NDA, British Energy and EDF Energy, you can estimate that, Vincent, correct me if I'm wrong, most likely all three together we have the potential of around ten nuclear power plants, more or less, roughly. Our ambition is to build at least four in the first wave of construction, so this is where we stand today. And the outcome of that means that necessarily there will be talks between these three partners. Three more questions.  Countdown.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question from Levy Financial.  I have a question on wind power.  Unless I'm mistaken, the wind purchase price which is $82.17 per kilowatt hour, that is wind power purchase price, is basically close to the Paronex electricity, but sharply below the peak load rates. Can you tell us what will that change in the market, this increase in power, wind power that is coming onto the market?  And can you speed things up in France, can you tell us about your strategy?  Will it have an impact on customer billing?  And can you give us an idea about results for next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, the wind power that is produced by wind farms and the price at which it is sold to EDF, basically to the grid where the subsidy in between, of course that is paid by the CSPE, which is the French subsidy for EDF, of course this is a neutral impact.  But there is a difference that is being paid and that difference compensated by the subsidy, does exist. The price at which we're purchasing or buying back wind power is well above the current prices at which we sell the electricity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The CSPE compensation subsidy is between the &#x20AC;82 per megawatt hour and the wholesale market price. It is designed to offset that difference. Once, when the two prices get closer then the impact of wind power on the CSPE subsidy will decrease naturally. Of course, there are other impacts that have a role that forces the CSPE up, but the wind power impact goes down. But for us it doesn't change anything from the standpoint of profitability of wind power for a company like EDF Energies Nouvelle, since their business plan is based on these &#x20AC;82 per megawatt hour. And so EDF as an operator of wind power, doesn't change much, because the CSPE is adjusted based on changes in prices. CSPE, if you will, is a buffer.</p>
          <p>Will the CSPE subsidy disappear next year? Answer is no. Now, in the CSPE you have offsetting for coal generation power, of course, that is gaining an importance and is not going to go down in view of gas prices. And then of course, you have a second factor -- second component that is with the distributed power systems, as well as isolated power systems, oversea territories, island territories, Corsica, and in this case CSPE also is used to offset the excess cost for the operators. For the voltaic power, of course, that will be added in the future, so CSPE will not be disappearing. Question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding British Energy, have you actually closed the doors or perhaps go into talks resume? Then you also talked about conditions for acquisition. What was missing in the British Energy deal? Last question, for Iberdrola you said that you would not be acquiring any significant stake in Iberdrola.  Does that mean that non-significant or smaller minority position is something that you're considering acquiring even if you do not have full control?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now these things, of course, all deal with listed companies on financial markets. This is all under the oversight of financial market authorities. You will understand that I cannot make any further comments on that. As for the UK, all I'm saying is that the conditions are not met today for any major development. However, our ambition and our determination still remain. As for Spain, I have nothing to add, no comments. Sorry. Last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question from Lessico.  Sorry to insist, but I like to get back once again on British Energy. Can you confirm that the EDF Board has given you approval for that transaction? Second question, are you considering any future without British Energy? Another question, the series of nuclear incidents and the media coverage and impact particularly on Precastan, is that something that worries you in the context of your strategies to be a key player of nuclear revival?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All I can confirm is that the EDF Board of Directors met yesterday and that the Board has approved the half year results and that's why I'm here before you today, to tell you about it. That is all I'm authorized to tell you. On your third question, two elements of our performance.  It is a key point to make sure that nuclear is acceptable. The big, big challenge for this nuclear revival is not restarting nuclear power, is not technical, it's not a technical issue. There are several technologies that exist, all of them being competitive and cost efficient. The issue is how to make nuclear power acceptable to public opinion, and this will require two key drivers. Number one, responsibility and accountability of the states, the state authorities. It is true for electricity, but even more so for nuclear power that electricity and nuclear power will not develop without the involvement of state governments, regulations, counter-power, checks and balances, disclosure, transparency, systems mechanisms that will gain the trust of the population.</p>
          <p>Second key driver, to ensure that you have an operator whose image and visibility is one of reliability and transparency. And what I believe is essential in the nuclear sector is what we're able to succeed in France. Of course, we have full safety, safe nuclear power. We have no major incident for the past 40 years when we commissioned the first power plant. So we have a long-term visibility and feedback on our safety. But more importantly is transparency. We at EDF work in the nuclear sector in full transparency, with a key role being played by the French Nuclear Safety Authority. And that authority is fully impartial, no one is discussing that. EDF systematically communicates and releases communiqu&#xE9;s on incidents. Now, level zero incidents, we have several dozens a year, level one we have between 0 100, a couple of dozen. And we always talk about it, everybody has access, we talk about the smallest thing.  Of course media coverage becomes sometimes media hype depending on the context. But what is happening just confirms how important it is for us to continue to be transparency. And it is absolutely not a challenge for us, It is not questioning this transparency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We will stop here.  Thank you for your questions. Thank you for being here. I am perfectly aware that I was not able to comment in detail to some of your questions. But I trust you will understand well. Thank you for being with us and thank you for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>