<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1490494" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>45590</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Henri Proglio</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Executive Vice President-Finance">Thomas Piquemal</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the web conference of EDF Half Year Results. This will be recorded and webcast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Here is the Chairman Proglio with Tom Piquemal. We're pleased to greet you here at this conference on EDF first half year 2012 results. In view of the format adopted, <mark type="ph" /> I'm going to give (1:27) slide of this presentation accessible on the EDF website.</p>
          <p>Take a look at the key figures for the first half year 2012. In tough general context on global economy or operational constraints, I can say that EDF has achieved sound performance. Sales over &#x20AC;36 billion, i.e., a growth rate of 8%, 7.1% organic growth. EBITDA has grown 4.6%, or in excess of &#x20AC;9 billion, 3.3% organic, growth driven by renewable energies and distribution in France, with a net income up 4.6% reaching &#x20AC;2.768 billion and a net income excluding non-recurring items in &#x2013; growing 10.3%, reaching &#x20AC;2.945 billion. Hence, excellent performance and growth over the half year.</p>
          <p>We have recurring progress in EDF profit, excellent performance, satisfactory, particularly since the second half year will turn out to be more complicated and we'll get back to that. At June 2012, net debt reached &#x20AC;39.7 billion, including the Edison takeover and the effect with a CSPE deficit of &#x20AC;4.5 billion. Net debt-to-EBITDA ratio is 2.5. Thomas Piquemal will detail these figures later on.</p>
          <p>Before that, I would like to say a few words about our operating results you will find on slide five. We note a growth thanks to an activity &#x2013; diversified business portfolio, and that is vis-&#xE0;-vis result demonstrated in a difficult context, where the overall growth demonstrates the relevance of a diversified portfolio derived from the EDF specific integrated model. Remember that the exceptional output of nuclear production had offset hydropower &#x2013; decline in hydropower linked to historical drought.</p>
          <p>In the first half year 2012, we've noted the exact opposite focus in particular in the second half for easily understandable reasons. Nuclear output in France and in the UK, particularly in the second half year, had a high number of days of outage. This was extended with &#x2013; this was compounded with extended shutdown periods, particularly in May and June, and Thomas will tell us more about that. These outages, of course, have disturbed the output down 10.6 terawatt hour in France versus last year, meaning we revised our target of output down to 415 terawatt hours versus the 420 to 425 terawatt hour plan.</p>
          <p>This relative decline in nuclear output, after a particularly high output in 2011, is now challenging our sustained CapEx policy, particularly the replacement program on large components that has already proved fruitful. In the UK, similar to France, output has gone down 1.2 terawatt hour, but the target in excess of 55 terawatt hour is maintained for full year 2012. Conversely, renewable energies enjoyed sustained growth, first of all, with growth of hydraulic production, plus 42%, up to 6 terawatt hours, an increase due to the efficient management of water pool. We also benefited from a much more beneficial climate conditions, and you will have noted that in France the second quarter was extremely rainy.</p>
          <p>Continuing with renewable, EDF Energies Nouvelles also enjoyed an excellent half year with high wind and solar power output increases in Europe and North America, plus 25% in wind power, plus 40% in solar power, thanks to favorable climate and commissioning of new solar wind &#x2013; three more solar farms will be commissioned in France in advance of the schedule. Over 2,450 megawatts in capacity are under construction <mark type="ph" /> in the world (6:24), without including the new acquisitions by EDF Energies Nouvelles in South Africa and Morocco.</p>
          <p>Lastly on operating performance, the distribution business was sustained by higher volume linked to the climate conditions of the half year, as well as increases in transmission tariffs in late 2011. So apart from the nuclear output, operating performance are indeed up to par, demonstrated the benefit of our diversified generation mix that we can smooth out any changes in climate effect with the adequate output. This results from CapEx up to &#x20AC;9.5 billion, up 22.5% versus last year's half year one. Two-thirds of the CapEx was in France with an increase of 30% in the investment in quality of our grid. The half-year also enjoyed major growth in France and in Europe. We rolled out in five key countries where EDF has a strong presence and footprint.</p>
          <p>Slide six shows the various positions and drivers of testing to our vitality. European position, to begin with, we have boosted our positions in five key countries. Let's start in France, where EDF has two major industrial construction sites that are some of the largest in the country and Europe, namely the LNG terminal at Dunkirk and the Flamanville 3 reactor. At Flamanville, we've already discussed it, of course, and I won't dwell much more on it. Just to say that the ASN, the French nuclear safety authorities, has approved the control command system, and over 90% of the civil works are now completed at Flamanville.</p>
          <p>At the LNG terminal at Dunkirk, this is European scale, of course, construction sites with the participation from Fluxys 26% and 10% share &#x2013; stake held by Total. The LNG terminal will be connected to France and Belgium, a unique dual connection, and will account for 20% of the French and Belgian consumption of natural gas. 13 giga cubic meter and it will be able to accommodate the largest LNG tankers in the world. It is due to be completed in 2015.</p>
          <p>It is the second largest industrial construction site in France, over &#x20AC;1 billion, as well as in terms of number of hours worked on the site. It is also a major opportunity for the <mark type="ph" /> Nord Pas-de-Calais (9:09) region. 88% of all the contracts or the terminal were awarded to local contractor, deepening our anchorage in the local territory.</p>
          <p>The challenge of this terminal has &#x2013; will have two direct benefits. First of all, build a diversified natural gas portfolio to supply our own electricity power plant. And secondly, boost EDF's presence in the gas market by the side of our European partners.</p>
          <p>And still on the subject of major industrial site, the success of EDF Energies Nouvelles should be mentioned, where three out of the four tenders were won by EDF Energies Nouvelles with the creation of 7,500 direct and indirect jobs. So Flamanville, offshore for EDF Energies Nouvelles, the Dunkirk LNG terminal &#x2013; these are significant job-creating construction sites.</p>
          <p>But we are also extending elsewhere, outside of our domestic market. In Italy, in particular. We have moved over new steps and we take over Edison, which is now a platform to develop our gas business worldwide. Following the takeover of Edison on last April 24, in line with stock market regulations, we have launched a public share offering on the remaining 20% stock that will be closed on August 3, after which EDF will own over 90% in Edison. Major transaction that gives us a leadership in Italy, since Edison is the second largest gas operator and number three electricity, with 7 gigawatts of output capacity that we now fully control and that will complement our own production capacity.</p>
          <p>Major challenges, of course, that met our vision on the energy future. Dunkirk. Offshore Italy gas projects therefore that are being conducted jointly and concurrently in order to secure our supply, particularly once the noisy supply will be exhausted.</p>
          <p>Another country of major importance is the United Kingdom with three key development projects. First of all, last May, the presentation by the British government of the new law on the Energy Market Reform, installing the contracts for difference, encouraging investments in low carbon energy, including nuclear power. The conditions remain to be defined, and depending on the economic conditions, we will be able to take the final decision whether we will be investing or not in new nuclear build before the end of the year. Authorization to extend by seven years the lifespan of the AGR power plant versus the planned date when we acquired British Energy in June 2009.</p>
          <p>Lastly, the testing on the commissioning on the first unit of the CCGT plant in West Burton in the Nottinghamshire with total capacity of 1,305 megawatts. The three units will be fully commissioned by the end of this year. As you see, EDF, as a leader in France, in Italy and in the UK is continuing its growth to secure strong positions in the service of the entire European Union.</p>
          <p>This strategy, it also applies to two other countries where EDF holds a sound position. Poland, a major market where we've been present for the past 14 years with almost 4,000 employees. We are the largest foreign investor and the third largest electricity producer, with 24% of the Polish market share. We supply 10% of the electricity, 15% of district heating.</p>
          <p>In Poland, we're also one of the leaders in biomass generation, with 1.5 terawatts of electricity produced from 1.2 million tons of biomass. So strong positions of EDF on the Polish market.</p>
          <p>Similarly in Belgium, we're generally not &#x2013; don't speak about Belgium too much, even though we are the second energy leader in the market with Luminus. We hold 80% of national production, 20% market share, 1.5 million customers, and over 2,000 employees.</p>
          <p>So this is a brief summary of our strong positions in Europe, in view of late &#x2013; the developments over the past half year. Recent takeover of Edison and EDF Energy Nouvelles, which were completed at the right time, have boosted our expertise and capacities, complementing our unique model of integrated operator. EDF is much stronger today in the world of electricity with strong &#x2013; experiencing a strong growth in demand.</p>
          <p>I'd like speak about a business that is not well-known, but highly strategic. A more cost-cutting activity, if you will, which is essential for the supply and demand balance of the production facilities in Europe, namely EDF Trading. Backed by physical assets, EDF Trading is the Group's interface with the energy markets. <mark type="ph" /> A master (14:50) player and leader in the wholesale electricity market in North America and Europe, the role of EDF Trading is predominant in order to manage, optimize the supply and demand of the entire generation portfolio of EDF.</p>
          <p>In 2011, EDF Trading negotiated over &#x2013; traded over 4,000 terawatt, 560 billion in natural gas, 500 million tons of coal, and over 300 million tons of CO2 were traded by EDF Trading. It enables us to capture as much value from EDF's asset, with first from negligible asset, namely that EDF Trading is very &#x2013; is not capital intensive. This enables us to confirm our short and medium-term guidance and targets that Thomas Piquemal will later on discuss these in detail.</p>
          <p>Thomas Piquemal is taking over.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Henri.</p>
          <p>I'm now going to take you through half yearly results in some detail, beginning with the presentation of our accounts, main figures, and of course the accounting methods that we have applied for the first half year, which are, in fact, exactly the same as the previous half year, with the exception of commitments to staff after employment we have restated the 2011 and published this on our website. This restatement being intended to anticipate a standard and to limit the volatility on our P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>Now in terms of scope of consolidation, we are fully consolidating Edison. This is &#x2013; we have 80% in our economic interest and fully consolidating it, but we'd be fully consolidating it from the end of May. We have 50% contribution to our P&amp;L up until the end of May. The key figures you already have, Chairman Henri Proglio has given you those figures. Growth is good on the first half of 2011. EBITDA of &#x20AC;9.075 billion, up 3.3% in terms of organic growth, have a Group share up 4.6% to &#x20AC;2.768 billion, and the regulatory non-recurring operations up 10.3% to &#x20AC;2.945 billion, that's again by comparing the first half 2011.</p>
          <p>This is also better than our expectation. You may remember that, we expected operating income to be stable by comparison with the first half of 2011 due to the scheduled output in France and the UK. Well, we've fared better than expected for two main reasons. First of all, the good containment of our costs in France and in the UK. The second reason being the remarkable performance of EDF Energies Nouvelles by comparison with the previous half year.</p>
          <p>Again, I will give you details on <mark type="indiscernible" /> (17:54). Debt is &#x20AC;39.7 billion, that is 2.5 times our EBITDA, that is the ceiling we set ourselves in terms of debt ratio. This &#x20AC;39.7 billion includes the &#x20AC;4.5 billion cumulative deficit with CSPE and the first consolidation of Edison for over &#x20AC;2 billion, that is the full consolidation of Edison's debt at June 30. There was also an unusual impact on our working capital requirements because of the climatic conditions, but again I will elaborate on that in few minutes.</p>
          <p>On the next chart you see how our sales have grown. On a like-for-like basis, that growth is 7.1% organic growth, driven by growth in France, growth of &#x20AC;1.2 billion. This is partly due to prices, but also due to the cold weather in the regulated sector. Another country posting high sales growth is Italy, up &#x20AC;500 million due to the increase in prices in the market, but this increase did not improve our margins. On the contrary, margins continued to deteriorate in Italy in the first half year.</p>
          <p>EBITDA growth of 3.3%. This is thanks to France's contribution of an additional &#x20AC;359 million. The deterioration shown here in the UK is, in fact, an optical effect or an accounting effect, if you prefer. This is because we have discontinued accounting for a certain number of assets that were recognized in the first consolidation of British Energy's balance sheet, and of course this has had a &#x20AC;100 million effect on EBITDA. And, of course, scheduled output during the first half of 2012, may I &#x2013; we &#x2013; actually the UK performance is, if anything, better than we expected. Italy down 31%, I told you that margins continued to deteriorate over the first half year.</p>
          <p>And on the right hand side, EDF Energies Nouvelles saw its EBITDA rise &#x20AC;141 million over the first six months, again by comparison with the corresponding period in 2011. So EBITDA up 3.3% on a like-for-like basis. Depreciation and amortization was pretty much flat on the previous period. Two effects offsetting one another. On the one hand, an increased allocation to depreciation and amortization, because we've continued to increase. But on the other hand, the positive effect of the extended life of AGR portfolio, that's an extension of over seven years booked to the first half year.</p>
          <p>Impairment and other operating income and expenses was a total loss of &#x20AC;194 million &#x2013; again, I'll elaborate on that in a few minutes &#x2013; giving us EBIT growth of 2.9% to bring EBIT to &#x20AC;5.602 billion.</p>
          <p>On the next page you will see that financial expenses were absolutely flat by comparison with the first half of 2011. Again, financial interest, because of our higher level of debt was offset by a certain number of capital gains on securities and financial income that we booked for the first half year.</p>
          <p>Income tax is higher in absolute terms, but the effective tax rate is comparable with the corresponding period. In 2011, we booked a certain number of non-recurring expenses last year, which has an artificial effect on income tax. Sharp increase in the share of net income from associates, up 30%, in particular OTE, which we fully own, but which is consolidated by the equity method. In this instance, sharp increase in net income largely due to the cold weather at last February. Overall, EDF net income rose 4.6%. And when we factor out non-recurring items, the net income rose 10.3%. This is EDF net income after income tax that we apply the payout ratio for our dividend. As you know, our objective is a 55% to 65% payout ratio.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the page on non-recurring items net of tax, a negative &#x20AC;177 million in the first half year compared with almost zero in the first half 2011. In fact, last year we had the positive effect of a capital gain on &#x2013; in <mark type="ph" /> BVD (22:53), which was offset by a certain number of adverse effects, main of these being a provision for our subsidiary Dalkia. Now these various impacts cancel one another out in the first half of 2011, whereas in 2012 the main negative element was the additional impairment that we had to book on our stake in CNG in the U.S. Now, this impairment is a reflection of the deterioration that continued, in particular because of the price of gas and electricity, and of course the forward curve which continued to decline obliging us to book an additional $300 million approximately.</p>
          <p>Also on this slide, you see that the takeover of Edison entailed an expense of &#x20AC;51 million. This is the net figure on the first consolidation of Edison's balance sheet. Obviously, the accounting items are much more complex than one would imagine from this item. We had to reappraise Edison's balance sheet at June 30, and the reappraisal of the various assets by comparison with the acquisition price and by comparison with the cost carried in our accounts, led us to book a rather marginal amount, in this instance of &#x20AC;51 million, this will in the future be offset by synergies that we will generate with Edison.</p>
          <p>Now going to comment our performance in &#x2013; beginning with France and moving on to other areas of the Group, beginning, as I said, with France. Due to more numerous scheduled outputs during the period and extended contribution to nuclear output, which was down &#x20AC;392 million for the year, very largely offset by better hydro production, which rose &#x20AC;276 million. The weather effect on the Group was a net adverse effect. The cold period had a positive effect on EDF's EBITDA, but a negative effect in France, because the need to hedge ourselves at higher prices than the price we sell to our clients. And the net impact of the two actually was an expense of over &#x20AC;100 million for the half year.</p>
          <p>Now to give you an overall vision of the cold period, you would have to build in the positive impact on OTE, which, as I said earlier on, is carried on the associates item. This was very unusual weather, but the impact was also due to very good control into optimization of EDF Trading and optimization more generally in France.</p>
          <p>Tariff and market prices rose by almost &#x20AC;400 million, that's the EBITDA figure. This was mainly due to the distribution price, the TURPE as we call it, or third party access price. Conversely, the amount of energy in this <mark type="ph" /> memory (26:14) regulated sale price is set globally with various components, of course. But the energy component made a very small contribution of &#x20AC;80 million over the first half year.</p>
          <p>We also benefited from the small increase in market prices over the first half year. OpEx were well-ranging. Operating expenses rose &#x20AC;230 million over the first six months, partly &#x2013; in fact almost half of that increase can be attributed to the various measures in the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (26:51) plan announced quite some time. Again restated, of course, but the increase in operating expenses in France was actually lower than inflation, which I think is a good evidence of how well we have kept our cost under control in the first half year.</p>
          <p>Other effects concern ERDF, particularly the rate of loss recorded, and the end of the TaRTAM mechanism that I will not dwell upon. I don't think there is any need to dwell on the TaRTAM transitional tariff, which ended on the end of June 2011.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the next page, which is the electricity balance in France. This shows us sales on the right hand side within the market reform, the 30 terawatt hours NOME. I'll stay on the right hand side of this chart just to explain the consumption, the199 terawatt hours, which was up 6 terawatt hours solely due to climate effects, which is why consumption rose by approximately 8 terawatt hours overall. The minus two &#x2013; the remaining minus 2 terawatt hours being largely due to a slight decline in our market share. What I will point out is that in this first half year, consumption &#x2013; and it's unusual not to comment, consumption was stable. Of course, restated for seasonal climatic effects, but with stable consumption or even actually down somewhat in the industrial sector.</p>
          <p>On the left hand side, we have generation and purchases. You see that nuclear generation was down 11 terawatt hours. We expected a downturn of about 8 terawatt hours, but this is a sharper downturn because of a rather difficult month of June that I will comment in a few minutes. Hydropower rose 6 terawatt hours. This is the reason behind the large variation in EBITDA in France.</p>
          <p>Nuclear production is shown on the next page. Nuclear generation very similar to the previous half year. We expected a decline of about 8 terawatt hours because of the scheduled outages. Now this was a sharper decline because of the month of June. So what happened to June? We had extended outages, particularly with the N4, but &#x2013; and a number of additional verifications that we carry out in conjunction with the ASN, French nuclear authority. As a result, our expectations were revised downwards, but the previous objective was in the range of 420 to 425 terawatt hours for the full year.</p>
          <p>On the next page you' see that our shutdown program was busy in the second half of 2012 than in the second half of 2011. We've had extended shutdowns. You see the different color codes and unexpected shutdowns &#x2013; or unplanned outages, should I say, but this should be completed in August or September at the latest.</p>
          <p>Hydropower output rose sharply, rose in fact 41.8% in the first half year. It rose in the first three months of the year, and it then gathered pace in the second half of the half year. Very good production, very good generation in the first three months. You see on the next page actually which shows the hydrological conditions on a curve. In fact, the half years were almost reversed. The trend has certainly reversed in late March, early April.</p>
          <p>The hydrological levels were very low at the start of the year by comparison 2011. But as I said a few minutes ago, hydropower output rose, which is evidence of the fact that we managed our hydraulic reserves very well. Two optimization programs in late 2011. This was also made possible through conditions that were very close to optimum in the second half of the half year. We now have hydrological supply that are almost an all-time high, which maybe just to confirm are hydropower output objectives for the full year 2012.</p>
          <p>In the UK now, our operational performance was in line, or if anything, fractionally above expectations. Now, you wouldn't believe when you look at the variations, because EBITDA was down 16.1% on a like-for-like basis. However, do let me stress the fact that this needs to be restated. We've been restating the impact of the fair value adjustment on the British Energy balance sheet acquisition. This is purely accounting effect that applied to our first reassessment, so restated for now, we are down 8.3% on a like-for-like basis.</p>
          <p>This was <mark type="ph" /> also slightly (32:14) due to the scheduled shutdowns, planned shutdowns, those had virtually no impact on our margin. The actual volume in the B2B segment, which is a very, very competitive market, was slightly down. I can now confirm our objective to increase our output in the UK, this is by comparison with 2011. Performance at the end of June is perfectly in line with that objective.</p>
          <p>Now, I showed you an electricity balance sheet or electricity situation, which does not require any particular comment. I've already mentioned that the B2B portfolio has been slightly eroded. But on the left hand side, you will see that there is an increase in fossil-fired output to &#x2013; this is probably because of the more favorable spread over the period.</p>
          <p>In Italy, the sales growth of 16.5%. Well, Edison and Fenice did not lead to an increase in EBITDA, which, on the contrary, was down 14%, which is evidence of the fact that our margins continue to deteriorate. The challenge for us in Italy is to renegotiate our gas contracts or to obtain arbitrage in our favor. The schedule is continuing. It's one of the big challenges facing us in the second half year, and we are awaiting decisions for two out of three contracts between now and the end of the year.</p>
          <p>The takeover of Edison  is now fully in effect. Since the end of May, we have had almost 80% of the capital in Edison, which we fully consolidated since that date &#x2013; that's May 24, 2012. This deal is in &#x2013; has been in line with our objective, that is to take control of Edison, while limiting as far as possible the total disbursement. We've kept that to within &#x20AC;100 million.</p>
          <p>Now the impact on our debt stems mainly from the consolidation of Edison's existing debt. So &#x20AC;100 million is due to the fact that we purchased 50% of the holding company that we didn't own. But beforehand we had 50% of Edi Power, as a result of which overall EDF has taken control with a very little cash-out disbursement of less than &#x20AC;100 million.</p>
          <p>Provisional purchase price allocation has been carried out. We've revalued the brand. We valued the assets, and overall I should point out straightway that in future periods, this revaluation of the balance sheet will have a very marginal effect on our accounts. No impact whatsoever on EBITDA and very little impact on EDF net income, and even that will be offset by the expected synergies that I've already alluded to.</p>
          <p>So the Edison electricity charges on the next page, not many comments required. I want to say that output and purchases were down at Edison because of the levels in the reservoirs and local rainfall. But beyond this specific case of Edison, I think more importantly, we should say a few words about the Italian market, where consumption has fallen sharply in electricity. This, of course, is to be a restated for seasonal effects. But overall the output of renewables increased, which has driven our margins down and had a squeeze effect on the combined gas cycle. This has all been expected, so it was all expected at the time of the takeover, and as I told you the real challenge for us in second half year is renegotiation of our gas contracts.</p>
          <p>Now other international, you see EBITDA is down on a like-for-like basis, that's an organic decline of 17.2%. I think one thing that can be said, one of the constants in all these regions is the negative trend of the economy on the one hand, but also regulations, be it in Belgium with the price freeze, be it in Central and Eastern Europe with Hungary the end of cogeneration subsidies, Slovakia with low distribution models, Poland particularly in biomass fuel.</p>
          <p>All this added to the impact of lower prices in the U.S. All this combines to explain the decline of EBITDA in our activities elsewhere in the world, be it in Continental Europe, the U.S. or in Brazil, despite the fact that the comparison with 2011 is very difficult. 2011 hasn't been an exceptional year. 2012, so profitability declined due entirely to a scheduled shutdown of our turbines for maintenance purposes.</p>
          <p>And other activities, performance was quite remarkable. EBITDA grew 28.4%, driven largely by the good performance of EDF Energies Nouvelles, which saw its contribution to EBITDA rise over 70%. Generation in wind power and solar, as the Chairman said earlier on, has improved, and of course there has been very good strong sales of structured assets, which are among our EDF Energies Nouvelles traditional activity. EDF Trading's business was down slightly, but in line with expectations. This was because of difficult market conditions, particularly in North America.</p>
          <p>This excellent operational performance explains, well, along with tight control of our financial expenses and a tax rate that remains stable, all of which explains the significant improvement of our operating cash flow, as you see on the next slide, plus 10.4% up to &#x20AC;1.756 billion, which is the free cash flow negative in spite of the increased EBITDA, due to CapEx, of course, but due to deterioration of the working capital requirement. You see the increased working capital requirements has been a net cash-out of &#x20AC;2.5 billion over the period.</p>
          <p>This includes the high CSPE offsetting increased &#x20AC;687 million plus two other effects. One was just atypical effect on the accounts receivables in France due to the atypical climate and weather that we had in December and June. December 2011 was particularly mild, and the month of June 2012 was particularly cool, meaning that our accounts receivables are very atypical at these two days accounting for approximately &#x20AC;700 million linked only to this weather effect. Another point of deterioration of the working capital is into Edison, with an increase of &#x20AC;500 million nearly in the Edison's debt due to deterioration of the working capital, linked partially to weather and seasonal effects in the securitization of our accounts receivable as well as late payments in Italy and in Egypt.</p>
          <p>So these explains a major impact on the working capital, some of which will be remedied by the end of the year, or simply atypical due to one-off weather effect. CapEx are up by &#x20AC;1 billion. Our total CapEx goal for the full-year, as I said earlier, is approximately &#x20AC;12 billion for the full year.</p>
          <p>In the half year this &#x20AC;1 billion increase in CapEx arises from three major areas. First of all, renewable plus &#x20AC;455 in investments, which is the &#x20AC;455 linked to our CapEx program in the U.S. primarily and since we still have a number of subsidies to investments there.</p>
          <p>In the UK we invested &#x20AC;351 million more than in the half year one 2011, again, due to primarily to the fact of some construction projects in renewable energy and faster pace of investment in nuclear new build.</p>
          <p>In France, sustained capital investments as well, particularly in the networks, where the overall CapEx budget was up 11%, including 30% on quality and safety of our networks, meaning that all of which explain the nearly &#x20AC;1 billion increase in CapEx. Negative cash flow, as I said, &#x20AC;1.8 billion, dedicated asset allowance &#x20AC;400 million, dividend paid in cash &#x20AC;1.2 million. The first consolidation effect of Edison, as well as acquisitions and disposals &#x2013; excuse me, let's get back to Edison &#x20AC;2.4 billion, that's the effect of the price consolidation.</p>
          <p>Acquisitions and disposals, meaning which &#x2013; all of which explain the increase of debt from &#x20AC;33.3 billion up to &#x20AC;39.7 billion as of June 2012. This debt, I remind you, also funds the CSPE deficit &#x20AC;4.5 billion. This is the CSPE tax deficit that we have to carry and we are not being compensated for. The debt is also used to fund main development projects up to &#x20AC;11.2 billion, which is important to focus on. I think there is very multinationals that finance so much CapEx in development in order to secure the future.</p>
          <p>Out of these &#x20AC;11.2 billion in development CapEx, this is broken down into &#x20AC;2 billion in renewable energy and &#x20AC;9 billion &#x2013; over &#x20AC;9 billion in other projects, nuclear new build in France, in the UK and China, CCGTs, West Burgin in the UK, which is currently in the testing phase, or in other areas, in particular gas infrastructure, such as the Dunkirk LNG terminal, as the Chairman said earlier. So the debt accounts for 2.5 time our EBITDA, which is the maximum debt/EBITDA ratio that we have set for ourselves ceiling. And for that reason, we intend to continue and intensify our efforts to find a solution to the CSPE deficit. For the past few weeks we have started talks with government authorities on the CSPE tax. We also intend to revise expenses and investment program by the end of the year, and this is why I cannot confirm all of our guidance target as announced in February this year and confirmed again in the current trading &#x2013; Q1 trading.</p>
          <p>You know our targets. We want to have an average annual growth of EBITDA between 4% and 6%, average annual growth of net income between 5% to 10% and the dividend payout of 55% to 65%, with the net financial debt/EBITDA ratio cap at 2.5 times adjusting to &#x2013; intention to preserve our sound CapEx and figures.</p>
          <p>For 2012, our targets are in line with the guidance given, with a dividend forecast at least stable for this year. And as I said earlier in the Q1 conference, the key challenges are the renegotiation of the Edison's gas contract in the second half of this year. This will be the key issue. And as I said, this is an assumption that we have included when confirming our guidance targets for full-year 2012.</p>
          <p>I'll now finish with this presentation, and we'll now take any questions you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll move on to the Q&amp;A session. Could the operator please remind the people on the phone about how they should proceed to ask questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First question from the web from Credit Suisse, Michel Debs. Can you give us an update on the IPO or the takeover of Edison and the latest developments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The public share offering will be closed on August 3 that is currently ongoing. We're waiting for the outcome of this share offering to see what we decide, because since, as you know, this is mandatory share offering. All I can say is that I read an article &#x2013; statement by one of the minority shareholder that he would be indeed selling his shares. And this is why Chairman Proglio said earlier that if we would end up over 90% of the capital, but I have no comments to make on the process itself. We're waiting for the end and we'll take any decisions whether we take any decisions on the listing or not after August 3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question from Nomura. Can you confirm the renegotiation of the two gas contracts will generate &#x20AC;600 million in gains in the second half? What other contracts will remain to be negotiated and what will be the calendar?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x20AC;600 million is the assumption, yes, that we are using in our 2012 forecast. The two contracts currently negotiated are one with Qatar and one with Libya. The third remaining contract will be with Algeria. We're hoping either some sort of arbitrage or a new negotiation in 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In view your good performance in the first half 2012, why are you not increasing your guidance for the full year 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said earlier, our results attest to significant efforts that we've made to keep cost under control, major assets as well, to speed up a number of disposals in the field of renewable energy. We are already giving you bracket, 5% to 10% growth of net income. Now these brackets &#x2013; going beyond these general &#x2013; these brackets 4% to %6, 5% to 10%, would be useless actually, particularly since we are also reviewing our nuclear output downwards to 415 terawatt hour. I already said that we give priority to grow our net income. I've already said that, but beyond that I really have no more comment to make.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question regarding the CSPE utility tax in France, &#x20AC;4.5 billion is the CSPE amount. What are your forecasts for the year-end 2012, and what kind of possibilities to settle this tax deficit that you are considering to solve the issues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>CSPE increases are virtually &#x20AC;1 billion every year. It was approximately &#x20AC;700 million over the first half year. The big issue is to negotiate to get remuneration of the &#x2013; our handling of the tax itself. In other words, not to have an impact in our P&amp;L account by the cost &#x2013; the collection cost on the CSPE. You can imagine these are significant costs. And now the &#x2013; we also want to smooth out recovery of these funds, so that it will not impact increase &#x2013; or increase the bill, hence our ability to keep control over the energy bill within &#x2013; for consumers, and we also want to ensure that we can recover these amounts as early as possible over time. So we have started talks with public authorities. This is one of our key priority actions and it should be solved by the end of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question from JP Morgan. Question to Thomas Piquemal. In the first quarter you gave us &#x20AC;8.5 billion in EBITDA and &#x20AC;2.5 billion in net income. The figures as of end June are high, of course, but much better than the first quarter. What are the effects that benefited this performance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pure accounting effect and changes in accounting methods, as I said earlier in my introduction. And then two major impacts, as I said, control over operating income in France and the UK with massive efforts on cost control that were carried out throughout the first half year. Renewable energy that did quite well, thanks to high volumes in output, higher than expected. Thanks as well to a number of sales of structured assets that were closed, one of which in advance of what had been expected to take place only in the second half. And, of course, currency effect approximately &#x20AC;18 million, there again it was difficult to predict this currency effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question from Martin Young from Nomura. In France, what are your expectation in terms of increase in the ARENH prices, and the potential calendar of such price increases for the ARENH third party price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is very difficult. As you know, the ARENH price that has been set up by the so-called NOME law on the French market opening.</p>
          <p>Now this price was set, and in order to change the tariff, it means that the difference between the ARENH price &#x2013; that is the selling price &#x2013; and the market price should be reduced. It means that first of all, we need to have increases in tariffs, whether they are called blue, yellow or green. In other words, these are customers or industrial tariffs.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, to have the indexing mechanism taking place with the ARENH price, and this will not happen in 2012. Meaning that this is a dual trigger negotiation topic. Negotiation with public authorities to increase public prices, and then increases of the ARENH price itself, to be decided by the public authorities, that will be the consequence of higher selling prices.</p>
          <p>That's all we can say for the time being. You can imagine that talks are ongoing. There is no way to anticipate or speculate on the final decision by the government.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Further question from Arnaud Joan from Cheuvreux, also on the ARENH price. What are the assumptions about ARENH price increases that you are using in your guidance for the period 2012-2015?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do not give details on our assumptions. We have set a framework. We have set targets for ourselves. And over the past quarters and half year, we have delivered these frameworks, brackets and so on. But I will stick with that, and I do not wish to detail all of these assumptions, particularly since we have ongoing negotiations with public authorities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Questions from Michel Debs, Credit Suisse. Can you give us an update on the progress of your synergy program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, this is one of the reason actually why we have been able to keep control of our operating expenses with strict cost control. The synergy program is continuing. You will have &#x2013; there is an annex that is available on the website showing the breakdown of the different synergy gains. Over the first half year, we've gained approximately &#x20AC;300,000, slightly ahead of our targets for the year.</p>
          <p>But apart from the synergy program, we're also working hard to control specific costs well-identified throughout the Group. Again, I won't dwell on that. But I've spoken about some costs on the IT systems, in particular. We've identified other potential gains where &#x2013; that will deserve to be worked on. And we're starting to see these program bear fruit. But the transformation synergy, as announced in July 2011, is progressing well and quite smoothly and positively.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question on Edison from <mark type="ph" /> credit side (55:01). There are rumors on the fact that you might have to impair some of the assets from the Edison assets. The question is this &#x20AC;51 million that you mentioned in your slides, will that be the only visible impact as related to the asset impairment or revaluation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have revised and we have revalued and consolidated Edison's balance sheet into our account. Following this audit done with auditors, confirmed by our statutory auditors, the impact in our account is &#x20AC;51 million. Further to these first initial valuation audits, we then have 12 months, if I remember right, to finalize, in line with accounting standards, this allocation of the purchase price.</p>
          <p>I have no knowledge of any items that wouldn't make us change any of that. This is why, based on the information that I have in the current context, there is no reason to see any up or down trend on this particular aspect.</p>
          <p>And beyond the highly complex accounting system that I really don't want to get into details, unless you insist, but I will say in this transaction, we bought &#x20AC;0.89 the Edison share. We have reduced our total cost of acquisition, and our average price for Edison's acquisition is now very close, plus or minus &#x20AC;15 million, of the value as we valued in the books of the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question. Edison linked to negotiation on gas contracts and guidance. Question from Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole. Out of the &#x20AC;600 million EBITDA in 2012, what will be the recurring portion of arbitrage and how much will be a one-off effect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Once again, these arbitrage talks are ongoing and significant challenges for the Group. I cannot comment in detail. But our assumption, as I said, we have already given you the major guidance, but I do not intend to detail either our assumptions or anything else on that particular topic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bertrand Lecourt, Deutsche Bank, is asking, could you tell us again what is the financial guidance on the EBITDA? You had &#x20AC;15.4 billion, &#x20AC;15.5 billion that was the guidance for 2012. Does that take into account the renegotiation of the &#x20AC;600 million Edison gas contract? Second question I'll ask later on. Can you answer this question first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to give you the guidance in percentages. You can then do to the calculations yourself.</p>
          <p>What I would say is that <mark type="ph" /> the compares with the (58:08) consensus published on our website &#x2013;  I'm comfortable with the figures in that consensus, and in terms of EBITDA and the net income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the follow-on to Bertrand's question is how do you expect EBITDA and net income to impact distribution in 2011, all things being equal in terms of weather? And what would the possible impact be of the <mark type="ph" /> Excelsium (58:30) contract on the second half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we already gave a lot of details on our prospects and guidance. I'm not going to go into too much detail. They performed very good in the first half year due to <mark type="ph" /> COF (58:50), but &#x2013; for various reasons, but we have well-contained our costs. We have good control of our fees. We expect this to continue in the second half of the year. We expect ERDF to continue to fare well in 2012 &#x2013; to continue to grow on 2011.</p>
          <p>As for Excelsium, well, we'll see. I've already commented our objective of debt/equity, and our commentary so far suggest that we will meet that objective. We are working on our cost. We are working on our investments.</p>
          <p>And the fact that for a number of weeks now &#x2013; and the Chairman gave you the details earlier on, on the CSPE discussions &#x2013; I think that is our commitment to stick to this debt ratio and to continue to have a very strong financial situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Two more questions before moving on to audio. First of all, the lower nuclear production, how come? And secondly what will be the medium-term impact on the Kd?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, okay. Extended shutdowns, of course, this is &#x2013; maintenance is taking longer than intended, particularly with the N4 stage. This is since June, and the solving of these problems will in some cases be completed in August or September at the latest.</p>
          <p>So these are two to three-month delays, as I said, with certain tranches only. These are very powerful units, particularly the N4 unit. This is why we are reducing our nuclear objective.</p>
          <p>And then the second question was the Kd factor. Okay, the impact on the future Kd factor. Well, the impact for 2012, we are talking about extended shutdowns, and of course there will be no impact on the future Kd factor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again on nuclear energy, could you give us your vision on the operational investment plan for nuclear energy over the next five or ten years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I can't. I can't because I told you we were going to review it between now and the end of the year.</p>
          <p>We're not changing our objectives or investment in security and maintenance. But as for nuclear in general, there are other considerations, other aspects. And as far as investment is concerned, I think we have to review our investment between now and the end of the year. So I'll answer that question later on, probably in February of next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said earlier on, when &#x2013; <mark type="ph" /> this is second last (1:01:45) question. Given the good performance of the renewables business, what development plans have you got for renewable energies in the future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the renewables, the plan to develop renewables in the future will depend, of course, on opportunities in the countries we operate in.</p>
          <p>As you know, it's a highly international business with concentration on a number of our priority countries. So the converging of our objectives between the EDF and <mark type="ph" /> EGF renewable energies (1:02:23) is coming to fruition.</p>
          <p>We have very ambitious objectives, but we also have plans to control our investments in CapEx. This is part and parcel of the Group's financial strategy.</p>
          <p>When I say that I mean two things. The &#x2013; well, EDF Energies Nouvelles, in its sphere of influence, <mark type="ph" /> while the development research of sites (1:02:52) the negotiations, which are vital for this type of business, the quality of projects, the ability to design these projects, to champion them and to bring them to a successful completion. The approval of the site and management of the production assets &#x2013; between all these, the ownership of these assets, be they photovoltaic or wind-powered, isn't the most important consideration.</p>
          <p>Now where we see traces in our 2012 accounts, where we have designed, built and operator of these facilities, is more important to us than the actual patrimonial ownership of these assets. Of course, this is not a problem and goes pretty much hand-in-hand with the disposables and process with the attendant capital gains. This is in line with the Group's ambitions of having a good control of the technology, being at the origin of this development, while continually managing on an integrated basis the &#x2013; <mark type="ph" /> that's the strategic side (1:04:10) of what we are doing.</p>
          <p>Yes, we have a very ambitious development plan, much more so than what the net CapEx would suggest &#x2013; the &#x20AC;150 million to &#x20AC;200 million allocated to EDF renewable energies. That's carried on our accounts. But the rest could be significantly higher than it currently is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One final question from <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:04:31) Credit Suisse. What would EDF's financial policy be with regard to Edison? Do we plan to get Edison back into investment-grade category?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Group EDF has a very significant amount of cash at its disposal, so the refinancing of Edison isn't an issue.</p>
          <p>This is something we're looking at in great detail, and I'm afraid at this juncture, I can't really comment how we will handle the current financing, except that we'll wait for the due dates or maturity dates and see how the analysis works out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, we're now going to ask the operator to remind listeners of the possibility of asking questions over the line, and we will then proceed to take our first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have a question, the line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm from Exane. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:05:51). Three questions please. First of all, what is your view about the technical possibility of closing down the two tranches of Friesenheim without any impact on the stability of the network?</p>
          <p>My second question, concerning your debt. Are you maintaining your debt of &#x2013; a debt/equity ratio of less than 2.5 by the end of the year?</p>
          <p>And thirdly, the payment of an interim dividend in cash, is that a possible variation in the equation?</p>
          <p>One third question, if I may. In the first quarter, you expected net income from recurring operations. If all things being equal, do you maintain that guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for Friesenheim, I'll take the answers &#x2013; questions. It's Henri Proglio.</p>
          <p>OTE transmission subsidiary submitted a report on the stability of the network earlier in the year. And yes, for the balance &#x2013; to have a balanced network in France. But this balance could only be achieved if generation capacity of a similar type is installed in Alsace. So this was a necessity to balance the network.</p>
          <p>This is partly because of the French network, but also interconnections with networks in neighboring country. So that's the dimension that we have to build into this question. I'm afraid I can't go any further than that in my effort to answer your question.</p>
          <p>As for the financial questions, yes, our objective is to continue to have a debt/EBITDA ratio of below 2.5. We will continue our efforts with the CSPE and review our net investments and expenses. The objective being to be below a multiple of 2.5 times EBITDA.</p>
          <p>As for the dividend, the objective &#x2013; payout objective is 55% to 65%. And I'm afraid I can't comment as to whether that will be in cash or in securities. But beyond that, I can't comment whether it will be in cash or in shares.</p>
          <p>But I can point out one thing. That is because I think I have read a few rumors <mark type="ph" /> and arrows (1:08:18) here and there. In all events, there is no question of minority shareholders being obliged to accept a dividend in the form of shares.</p>
          <p>Now in the hypothesis of EDF deciding &#x2013; and I'm not saying that this is the case or this is something we plan to do. I am talking purely theoretical terms. If EDF Group were to decide to propose that the dividend be paid in shares, minority shareholders would, of course, have the option of taking this in cash. This is one of the stock market rules, and that's the way it is. So there's no question of minority shareholders being obliged to take the dividend in securities.</p>
          <p>But as I said, all things being equal, we could reach possibly &#x20AC;4 billion. But if you look at 5% to 10% growth of net income, and of course subject to various accounting modifications I mentioned, you see we get around the &#x20AC;4 billion mark.</p>
          <p>But my priority, however, is to give you a vision between now and the end of the year that would be in line with the leverage we have. So as I said, 5% to 10% growth of net income. That's the range. 5% to 10%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Line is open for <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:09:43).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. I have three questions. My first question is in terms of <mark type="ph" /> EFEN (1:09:50). Could you give us some breakdown on EBITDA? Because the seasonal effect, it can be quite strong in some areas?</p>
          <p>My second question concerns <mark type="ph" /> EF (1:10:03), if you could give us your rate at the end of the year, just to give us some idea about your P&amp;L?</p>
          <p>And my final question, in terms of Dalkia. What about Dalkia's contribution to EBITDA for the first half year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dalkia's contribution for the first half of the year is down fractionally. It's down fractionally because of the number of provisions that were booked on our receivables account in Italy. From memory, I would say it's around &#x20AC;30 million. I'd have to check that figure, though. Approximately &#x20AC;30 million.</p>
          <p>As for the Group's income tax, the effective tax rate is approximately one-third, 33%, which is pretty consistent with what most people have in their models. And EDF Energies Nouvelles, we're getting that information, it's on the way. I'd say we're looking at a contribution of around &#x20AC;100 million in terms of DVAS.</p>
          <p>Now seasonality can have a variable effect on DVAS, but we expect an acceleration of the program in the second half year. This is why EDF Energies Nouvelles' investments are quite high in the first half, but over the full year, we will be looking at less than &#x20AC;1.2 billion investment in the field of renewable energies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no more questions on line, but I have an Internet question. Could you develop the consequences of the development of the energy market for EDF in Europe. This is a question from Myriam Cohen of Alphavalue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the British government has decided to take a new approach &#x2013; take a new approach via contract called contracts for difference. This is like a contract for guaranteeing inflows. This is contract at a foreseeable price with foreseeable revenues per megawatt. If you like, this is revenue for operations and this comes within a bracket. If we exceed that range, if the market is sufficient to fund developments, then the operator will refund the surplus to the public authorities. If, conversely, market conditions are not as good and are actually below the bottom of the range, well, then there would be a supplementary income that will come in the form of subsidies. And this is an issue that's currently being discussed, but we still need to define through negotiations the actual bracket itself.</p>
          <p>There are a number of factors that contribute to the definition of this range. Obviously, in close conjunction with the market, because as you know the British want us to be very, very close to market conditions, because competition is of the essence in determining the economic balance of the energy market. Now the British have also planned what they called a carbon floor. This is the floor price of carbon, which also plays a role in determining this price range. There is a whole series of settings and adjustments and parameters that will help us achieve this economic balance in the UK bid for nuclear power or for other forms of energy.</p>
          <p>So it's an issue that's currently under discussion. I don't think I can elaborate on any rationale, given the negotiation is underway. This, of course, will take place in the second half of the year before the major projects of other decisions concerning to launch major projects becomes a topic of -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now have another audio question. Emmanuel Turpin from Morgan Stanley. Emmanuel, you have the question. Mr. Turpin, you have the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Emmanuel Turpin from Morgan Stanley. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:14:41-1:16:25) 5% discount rate is a good assessment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer the first question about CapEx, how come our performance is higher than expected. Well, quite simply, because we committed ourselves to a maximum debt ratio of 2.5 times EBITDA, because financial ratios is essential for the Group, given the development of prospects. But also because we have some very big challenges ahead of us, be it the ARENH, be it discussions with the CSPE, and they are but two examples among a number of others.</p>
          <p>Given the fact that our goal is to comply with a well-controlled debt ratio, it's important to review a number of the aspects of our financial trajectory, be it in terms of costs or investments. I'm afraid, unfortunately, I'm not able to say anymore at this point in time. This is something that has begun and will continue right up to the autumn. I will tell you, by February at the very latest whether there have been any changes, that's of course February 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about the discount rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is no issue with our statutory auditors, because they have certified the accounts at June 30. Now this rate will be reviewed as always at every cutoff on the basis of market conditions and the long-term conditions of the underlying obligations. We simply apply accounting principles, and for the moment I have no reason to announce any change in the discount rate. But it will, of course, be reviewed as always when we cutoff the accounts at the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Returning to debate on energy discussions with the state, the energy debate is about the country's strategic energy orientations, nothing to do with the way we apply or the way we carry out our public service mission. We'll see how it goes, but it's a debate about France's energy strategy, probably be a number of considerations in terms of energy saving, in terms of networks &#x2013; intelligent networks and so on, so all matters relating to the energy sector in general.</p>
          <p>Well, depending on our negotiations with the state, and of course this will depend on price tariff management related areas, such as the CSPE tax or other. But it's not a technical or philosophical discussion about the country's energy future. These are negotiations that will have to take place in a much shorter framework with a very, very clear framework of applications. I hope this all goes quickly, and I hope that these discussions continue and enable us to reach the decision by the end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>This is the end of the phone &#x2013; questions from the phone. The entire Investor Relations staff will be available for you for any details or technical questions. So all that's left for me to do is to thank you for being with us, and we'll see you in November for the next quarterly presentation. Thank you again for being with us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>