<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1455793" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-02-16</date>
    <companies>
      <company>45590</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Henri Proglio</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Senior Executive Vice President">Thomas Piquemal</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Economist, Director of Strategy and Prospects, &#xC9;lectricit&#xE9; de France SA">Jean-Paul Bouttes</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Senior Executive VP-Generation &amp; Engineering">Herv&#xE9; Machenaud</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Emmanuel P. Turpin</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. I bid you welcome for this Presentation of the 2011 Annual Result for EDF. The top management of the group is with us today and will be pleased to take any questions you may have later on.</p>
          <p>As usual, together with Thomas Piquemal, we'll summarize the highlights of this year. We'll start with the topical events and there was a lot of current events this year. Our priorities for 2012, we'll say a few words about that later on. And then, Thomas will give you more detail and Jean-Paul Bouttes, Vice President for Strategy, will tell us about renewable energy sources. And, of course, we'll give you ample time to ask any questions and reply to them.</p>
          <p>So, let's start with the year 2011. As you know, we enjoyed sound performance, particularly outstanding that the context was &#x2013; and the economic context was particularly difficult. Beyond the financial crisis, of course, that was declared last summer, we'll only mention the Fukushima accident with consequences that were not neutral naturally.</p>
          <p>In spite of these exceptional events, revenue reached &#x20AC;65.3 billion, up 2.7%; EBITDA, &#x20AC;14.8 billion after impact of the TaRTAM; organic growth of 6.6%, reflecting the excellent operational performance of France and the UK.</p>
          <p>The net recurring income has grown 13.4% particularly due to a 75% growth of our EBIT.</p>
          <p>Net income, attributable income, they reached &#x2013; excuse me, they reached &#x20AC;3.5 billion, up 13.4% particularly due to a 75% <mark type="ph" /> gross EBITDA (2:21) as I said. The attributable net income exceeded &#x20AC;3 billion and was multiplied by 3 versus last year. Lastly, we're closing the year with a sound financial structure, with a debt/EBITDA ratio of 2.2.</p>
          <p>This enables me to tell you that we have reached, if not exceeded, our financial goals. Indeed, I said exceeded since our EBITDA is actually above the top bracket. We have met our target for debt/EBITDA ratio with a net debt accounting for 2.2 times EBITDA. Based on these excellent results, we will propose a dividend payment of &#x20AC;1.15 per share equivalent to 2010 to the Shareholders' Meeting.</p>
          <p>So, these are the key figures for 2011 just to give you an idea of the year. But I'd like to now dwell a little bit on the why and the how of these figures. How did we manage to restructure our performance in a tough environment with a very volatile international electricity market and extremely difficult macroeconomic conditions? We have worked hard, and the highlights of 2011 are there to attest to it, starting with the one that is closest to my heart and namely the operational performance.</p>
          <p>So, we've reached these results and starting with the excellence of our industrial efficiency and performance. Three highlights. First of all, in nuclear generation in France, we have exceeded the ambitious targets we had set for ourselves. Performance studies are the more remarkable that the 10-year inspection calendar was not favorable with nine 10-year visits in 2011 versus five in 2010 increasing by definition the planned shutdown &#x2013; of our shutdown. But in counterpart the replacement program for large components in the plants has enabled us to reduce significantly the number of plant outages. Thus the output has reached 421 terawatt hour exceeding our targets even though they had already been increased twice during the fiscal year.</p>
          <p>In addition, we have also increased our Kd availability factor up to 80.7%, a record growth never before achieved within one year since our 58 reactors have been in operation. And if you remember that we created a big event in early 2011 by connecting our 58 reactors to the networks between the 9th and the 15th of January.</p>
          <p>The tried and tested performance of our nuclear fleet has revealed two key items. The first highlight is that we were able to respond without any problem and flawlessly to the consumer demand, as demonstrated last year with historical peaks. We exceeded the 100,000 megawatt on several occasion last week.</p>
          <p>Second highlight is that this nuclear output has offset the lower hydropower output in 2011 which was the year &#x2013; the driest year for the past 22 years.</p>
          <p>With these climate conditions that are more and more erratic, we clearly see the benefit of a diversified energy mix, the one we had been claiming. Second key highlights illustrating our industrial performance in nuclear is in the UK where we also exceeded our target with 55.8 terawatt hour in output. Lastly, third example of our improved performance this time in distribution, the sharp improvement of the quality of our networks has enabled ERDF to reduce the outage time by nearly 17% down to 70.6 minutes, thanks. All of this was achieved thanks to an on-going investment policy in 2011 with &#x20AC;2.8 billion invested, i.e., 10% more than in 2010, to improve the quality and reliability of the distribution networks. So, these were the examples I wanted to share with you regarding our improved operational performance.</p>
          <p>In another area, let's talk about clarification of our stake holding. And we, there again, we kept our commitments. As you know, we are in the habit of saying what we'll be doing and doing what we said we would do. After the unwinding of complex projects in late 2010, I'm talking about Germany with EnBW and the U.S. with Constellation. We also completed two major transactions, reflecting our desire to control, keep control of our fate. The first transaction and I've already explained it to you before, is the takeover bid of 100% of capital of EDF in Energies Nouvelles in May 2011. This transaction has now been closed, is fully successful. We now own 100% of EDF EN which enabled us to reassert EDF's commitment in favor of low carbon energy and our ambition to reach by 2020 a diversified energy mix with 25% renewables. I'll tell you later on more about that.</p>
          <p>Second transaction that will be a key challenge for 2012, that is clarification of our situation in Italy with a takeover of Edison's control. There again, I'll detail that later on because these decisions are fully in line with our strategy, a strategy that was announced last May, and I would like to reassert. The strategy must be in the service of EDF's ambition of becoming the world-leading electricity operator with a diversified energy mix. And within this mix, fossil-fired power has a full-fledged role to play since the target set is to reach 25% for the group, i.e., a growth of 7 gigawatt up to 10 gigawatt by 2020.</p>
          <p>We also want to pursue modernizing our fossil-fired fleet. In France, to this purpose, we commissioned the first one CCGT last October at Bl&#xE9;nod, 430 megawatt and conducted the first trials of a CCGT in Martigues. That is due to replace an oil-fired power plant.</p>
          <p>In Poland as well, where we have a huge construction project for a super critical 900-megawatt coal plant that will &#x2013; with the high performance technology supplied by Alstom. This power plant is intended to replace the four older coal unit at the Rybnik power plant by a much more efficient unit with output efficiency of 45%, among the highest in the market.</p>
          <p>In addition, and this is essential, as soon as you talk about coal-fired plants, thanks to EDF's technology, it will significantly reduce CO2. And in terms of innovation, of course, and the record-high consumption have made everyone aware of that, we just signed a partnership with General Electric to develop a gas-fired plant, new generation plant. It will enable a maximum output to be reached within 30 minutes. This will be a major asset to face the consumption peak, particularly in severe cold spell.</p>
          <p>The first power plant of this type will be built in Bouchain in Northern France in order to extend the lifespan of an EDF site there. While we, of course, boosting our output in fossil-fired, securing of our supply in gas is essential, particularly to supply our gas-fired plant.</p>
          <p>Two major projects were initiated in 2011. First of all, the construction of the Dunkirk LNG terminal that was just started. A huge $1 billion investment shared between EDF, Fluxys, and Total, it will mobilize over 18,000 people for commissioning plan in 2015. The second initiative has to do with our &#x2013; 15% stake holding by the side of Gazprom, ENI and Wintershall in the South Stream gas pipelines that should connect Russia with Europe by bypassing Ukraine.</p>
          <p>For EDF, this entry into South Stream presents, is very consistent strategically with all of our major stakes in 2012, namely to turn Italy via control over Edison into the future gas platform.</p>
          <p>Edison and Italy, of course, at the core of EDF's gas strategy. As you see here on this path, Italy is the point of convergence of many gas infrastructure, including the South Stream pipeline as you see here on this slide. It's also another factor of course linked to the major role of Italy that results from that in securing this supply &#x2013; the gas supply for Europe, as well as the existence of numerous project outside of Italy, in particular, with Turkey and Greece.</p>
          <p>Hence our ambition, logical ambition, of course, to want to turn Edison and Italy into the group's development platform in gas around the Mediterranean basin. This transaction has now been approved by all political arenas which is essential, of course, for a public utility company like EDF in the energy sector. It's also been approved by all Italian shareholders of Edison. And just a few hours ago, we finalized that agreement with our Italian partners.</p>
          <p>Let me say a few words to pay tribute, if you don't mind, in memoriam of Giuliano Zuccoli, CEO of A2A and Edison, who passed on last weekend. He was a tough partner, and he was a boss of exceptional stature. And I have for him the greatest respect. His disappearance has occurred at the time when we were on the brink of finalizing this major project. All that was lacking, as you know, is the approval from the competition authorities on the final price. With this transaction, EDF thus becomes the second largest gas operator in Italy throughout the gas supply chain exploration, production and marketing which naturally will benefit the entire group. And currently, EDF will become the third largest electricity operator in Italy with control over 7 gigawatt of generation capacities. This transaction presents a major benefit with a financial major &#x2013; positive with a limited financial impact for EDF Group and Thomas will tell us about it.</p>
          <p>Finally, this is a win-win transaction since EDF will also benefit from stable shareholder structure, with a major shareholder, who is a major player in the energy industry, offering access to the major partnerships such us the recently negotiated partnership with Gazprom. No need to say anymore, the strategic aspect is obvious. The financial package is quite satisfactory for all parties, and we will recover control of our own destiny.</p>
          <p>I think it's important to devote a few minutes to that. It was important, just like it is just as important to now look &#x2013; address the second major aspect, namely the nuclear power. Nuclear was only possible if it's safe. The Fukushima accident has shown this absolute necessity. In France, as in the UK, the nuclear safety authorities have carried out the necessary audits, and the proper level of safety of our nuclear equipment has been validated. In France, the Nuclear Safety Authority have carried out test on all of our equipment.</p>
          <p>Another major highlight for our industry is that the nuclear fleet is mobilized to serve the nuclear fleet, as well as its international clients. An important step was passed in July with the technical agreement and the commercial agreement signed between EDF and AREVA based on three essential components, continuing to optimize EPR, maintenance and operations of existing nuclear equipment and the management of the fuel cycle.</p>
          <p>Now, there was a new agreement between EDF and AREVA on the long-term supply of uranium to EDF, setting up a complete and operational partnership with projects to build new reactors. Three major projects have made good progress, Flamanville and &#x2013; which is now on the agenda is scheduled for 2016. So, already, a good portion has been developed.</p>
          <p>Taishan in China, developed in partnership with CGNPC with AREVA and the largest Chinese companies in civil engineering. The dome was laid in October, very symbolical of this type of works, showing the achievement over seven years mobilizing over 2,000 people.</p>
          <p>In the UK, where we are the number one electricity power generator, we're continuing with our ambition to build four reactors. Last July, the parliament ratified our program to build new nuclear, launching a reform of the electricity market, setting up certain favorable conditions for investment in low-carbon energy including nuclear. We're talking about setting a floor price for coal and setting up for carbon and setting up long-term contracts to guarantee the stability of nuclear prices over the years.</p>
          <p>As I said, 2011 clearly showed our ambition in the field of new energy with the takeover of 100% of EDF EN. One-third of our investments in 2011, &#x20AC;3.9 million, were devoted to developing new production capacities in wind and solar; amount of investment that was comparable to that of new nuclear. 2011 was a record year for commissioning EDF's projects in wind and solar energy for nearly 800 megawatts bringing it up to 3,500 gross megawatts in terms of wind energy capacity and 415 megawatts for solar.</p>
          <p>This also concerns other renewable energy such as marine energy. This was shown with the first marine current turbine close to Paimpol Br&#xE9;hat at a depth of 35 meters. Four to five marine current turbines to supply 2,000 to 3,000 households which should lead to a full set of equipment in 2013 for the first time ever in the world.</p>
          <p>Innovation, as you can see is an unending source of energy for EDF EN which is now at a turning point in its history. EDF EN is a fine history of a company and entrepreneurs. Once again, I'd like to pay tribute to P&#xE2;ris Mouratoglou and David Corchia for the remarkable performance of EDF Energies Nouvelles. A new page will open up, and I'm happy to receive Antoine Cahuzac, who is now General Manager by the sides of Jean-Louis Mathias who will be Chairman. They will be taking on the responsibility of an exciting and high-potential business with remarkable and highly mobilized development teams. EDF EN is one of the world's leader in renewable energies, operating in 13 countries, with operating and financial results that were exceptional in 2011.</p>
          <p>2011 was a record for commissioning in wind and solar energy. At the same time, the construction of new production capacities has been launched, accounting for nearly 1,800 megawatts as of the 31st of December. This shows our wish to growth, as can be seen in EDF EN's response to the bid for offshore wind energy. EDF EN has made four applications, combining the higher skills, very ambitious projects. And if we were selected, this would mean creating 7,500 jobs if we were to win this bid. We're awaiting for &#x2013; awaiting reply next April, significant development projects in the same field in offshore wind energy in the UK.</p>
          <p>So, that's it for the main highlights in 2011 showing the clear progress made by the group and showing our priorities to a large extent for 2012. I'll try to be brief for 2012 because a lot has already been said. When I say, I'll try, it's because there are so many new developments for the future of EDF, but nevertheless, I'd like to conclude about the major priorities for EDF in 2012. It's simple and can be said in three words: investment, innovation and employment.</p>
          <p>Without investments and without innovation, there can be no growth. Investments are the driving force for a winning industry. Whether there's a crisis or not, to ensure the future, you must be able to invest with lucidity. One thing is sure. Investment is not something you can play around with especially when it comes to security. This is the part of EDF's behavior and we did not wait for the Fukushima disaster to invest as we should in nuclear safety, nor have we sacrificed the investment required for the development of our group. I'm talking about investment of nearly &#x20AC;11 billion.</p>
          <p>Operating investments up by 13% between 2009 and 2011. Between 2009 and 2011, the gross CapEx increased by 13% to reach over &#x20AC;11 billion of which two-thirds is for France. And that portion is constantly increasing. Of course, nuclear maintenance and maintenance for the &#x2013; and the distribution networks benefited from this increase, accounting for &#x20AC;4.7 billion on their own. Investments in nuclear maintenance in France increased by 48% in three years and for networks, up by 17%. And we shall continue to serve our priorities in 2012.</p>
          <p>In France, and this no surprise, our priority is still to continue to improve our industrial performance to attain our new power generation and nuclear capacity for 2012, at least equivalent to 2011. Taking into account the replacement of large components, steam generators in particular, calling for long and complex shutdowns. In addition, with two new 10-year inspections scheduled this year, there are additional shutdown days to take into account these 10-year inspections.</p>
          <p>At an international level, major investments in new nuclear with the decision to invest in the UK as we have already pointed out. Another challenge faces us on the other side of the channel, with extension of nuclear lifetime, EDF Energy has had new technical studies to extend the lifetime of the AGR networks by seven &#x2013; of the AGR reactors by seven years of average versus five years announced in 2010. This must be approved, of course, by the British safety authority.</p>
          <p>There are other countries that are getting prepared to launch new bids to develop new nuclear and as I said before, we shall be present.</p>
          <p>For gas, Italy will be the priority of course, I explained why earlier. One point must be stressed, the importance of the perfect integration of Edison and strong synergies between Edison and EDF. The construction of the terminal Dunkirk terminal will call for the skills of the Edison engineers who built the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (24:56) terminal.</p>
          <p>In renewable energy, Jean-Paul Bouttes will tell us more about our strategy. I'll only say that our international growth in wind and solar energy must be based on complementarity in the countries where EDF and EDF EN operates. But benefiting from EDF's knowledge in electrical systems and in specific engineering expertise we will see growth in high potential zones for wind and solar energy. We are looking for opportunities in the solar market in the United States, market that is growing particularly fast.</p>
          <p>In France and in the UK in offshore wind energy, we're waiting for a reply to major bids. And in the field of solar energy, 2012 will be the year where major projects will be rolled out. We also plan to develop major projects in the great hydropower, similar to what we have achieved in Laos, in South America, in the Middle East, as well as in Asia.</p>
          <p>In networks, we'll continue partnerships at international level. After signing a contract in Russia with MRSK, a significant contract for delegated management, ERDF will consolidate its cooperation in China with the main distributor of electricity in the Jiangxi province, about 40 million inhabitants with considerable needs because the electricity consumption has doubled over the past five years in this province.</p>
          <p>To be able to know how to invest, it also means allocating the budget required for research and development. EDF is a key player in research in energy. EDF must remain so, of course. The increase in our research project shows this will, investing &#x20AC;500 million in research, that's a lot of money, a significant effort and priority.</p>
          <p>To give you a few examples, heat pumps, a field where EDF is the leader, with a particularly innovating concept of compact high-yield heat pumps, or in smart grids with power line carrier systems developed by our R&amp;D department, recognized as an international standard which is very important for the deployment of smart meters, innovation in renewable energies of course in producing more competitive panels for photovoltaic energy.</p>
          <p>Let me tell you a bit more about Photowatt, just to make things quite clear as regards photovoltaic energy. EDF Energies Nouvelles R&#xE9;parties has just filed an application to take over Photowatt activities, the only French manufacturer of photovoltaic silicon-based cells which will be under receivership since November 2011.</p>
          <p>Since 2008, it has been a joint shareholder in PV Alliance, a research and development company in photovoltaic technologies, including a very high level technology with a terrible name, hetero-junction. This is important because if although we're not there for vertical integration but EDF ENR's application seemed logical to us given this particularly buoyant technology and the need to support the development of the industrial fabric that is close to our business.</p>
          <p>Hetero-junction can enable the production of high-yield silicon solar cells in excess of 20% replacing the current technology in the future. This led us to set up a real industrial channel. This bid was subject to the takeover of 100% of PV Alliance and obtaining an exclusive global license on hetero-junction. This will enrich EDF ENR's portfolio of activities.</p>
          <p>Within this framework, once again, there are many positive aspects, and I think they must be recalled. EDF's responsible attitude, helping to develop innovative and competitive technologies in France, EDF's responsible attitude maintaining in France, the innovative fruit of French research and this is something that we're often not good at preserving. EDF's responsible attitude. Lastly, and that this operation has allowed us to create a competitive business in France and also making it possible to save jobs.</p>
          <p>To conclude, I would like to say a few words about the topic that's of great interest to me, our group's social ambitions.</p>
          <p>Those of you who know me have heard me say, ever since the first day I took over my job that EDF's ambition in terms of human resources and labor is one of my priorities, and I haven't changed. It's a great reason of pride. EDF has been a net recruiter. In four years, we've recruited 20,000 people including 1,600 in 2011 in nuclear, 1,400 in distribution, 450 in our commercial activities.</p>
          <p>In 2012, we will be hiring approximately 6,000 new people in France and nearly 540 in the UK by EDF Energy. As a reminder, today EDF employs 100,000 people in France and nearly 160,000 in the world. But 30% will be retiring, i.e. one job out of two in the nuclear sector. We, therefore, have considerable stakes in the field of training, particularly when you know, the high level of technical expertise required by our business activities. And my determination is that at EDF training should be accessible to all, that EDF becomes a model of social ladder by taking part in renewing the skills, as well as fostering the integration of young people. &#x20AC;485 million will be devoted to training in 2011, i.e., more than 8% of our payroll expenses. This is why we're fostering work-study apprenticeships, which is insufficiently practiced in France, since it reveals talents within the company.</p>
          <p>And I will close with a major project that will be the platform of our labor ambition, namely the creation of the EDF Campus at Saclay, which you see here on this slide. I'm very proud of it. I'm very proud of it. It will be essential for EDF to strengthen its mission as a public utility company, creation of skills, training and so on. This will be a multidisciplinary, a multicultural campus. Each year, it will host 15,000 trainees from simple apprentices to seasoned managers of all nationality starting in 2015. This 25,000 square meter campus will be the largest European platform for vocational training in the energy sector with investments in excess of &#x20AC;100 million.</p>
          <p>This is what I wanted to share with you. Investment, innovation, employment, three key words that trace out the ambition of EDF, a conquering company, committed and placing very high its responsibility of industrial companies in the world today and tomorrow. Thank you for your attention. I'll now give the floor to Thomas. After which, we'll come back to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. I'm now going to detail our results for fiscal year 2011, also confirm our prospects and outlook for the years 2012 and 2015. I'll tell you that our targets for 2012 are perfectly in line with its outlook. And finally, I'll come back with a few major steps of the group's development over the past two years.</p>
          <p>Our results, you're familiar with them. Our Chairman Proglio just gave you the key figures. I'll simply come back to the fact that they are higher than expected. As I said, just a year ago, a bracket for EBITDA anywhere between &#x20AC;14.7 billion and &#x20AC;15 billion before the TaRTAM exceptional, we've reached 15 plus 6.6% in this four to six bracket. Our consensus on the net income from operation at &#x20AC;3.3 million, we've reached &#x20AC;3.5 million, i.e. 13.4% more versus last year.</p>
          <p>I've given you debt/EBITDA ratio from  2.1, 2.3 including Exeltium which we didn't get but we've reached 2.2 in brief well above our target. Let me explain why. First of all, growth of EBITDA, plus 6.6% as I said, before the TaRTAM transition tariff, thanks to high performance from France, plus &#x20AC;140 million in France and plus &#x20AC;153 million in the UK.</p>
          <p>In other words, you look at the organic growth, and to analyze it by major businesses in France separating the non-regulated, i.e., generation optimization -. That is the non-regulating sectors since RTE has been equity accounted, that concerns primarily ERDF. Here you'll see 6.3% is the organic growth. Thanks to ERDF to whom we owe this great performance, plus 4.3% at ERDF, performance reached not only with perfect OpEx control but billing for the very first time, thanks to what we obtain under the NOME law and negotiations about the feed-in cost for PV solar producers. We've also reduced the cost of losses in spite of climate in 2011 that was milder than 2011</p>
          <p>Good performance of regulated sector plus 3% in the UK plus 8.5%, inversely in Italy, minus 25% in EBITDA. This is due to the fact that margins continue to shrink in Italy both in electricity and gas, in line with expectations as a matter of fact. And in spite of these figures, Edison's figures are higher than what it had been forecast for 2011.</p>
          <p>Other segments, internationally, we've also grown, plus 19.5% as you see. Thanks to this 6.6% growth of our EBITDA, thanks to reduction of the depreciation and provisions for renewal, which has been reduced from &#x20AC;6.9 billion down to &#x20AC;6.5 billion. EBITDA from recurring operations before these elements has grown 14%.</p>
          <p>Why is it that depreciation provisions for renewal is down even though, as you know, the group is continuing its capital expenditures? Well, there are two main factors. First one is because, in late 2010, in the UK, we were able to get an extension on the life span of two reactors, meaning that we decrease by &#x20AC;150 million, the depreciation with a longer life span. Two, as well the fact that at ERDF, there are &#x20AC;200 million less in depreciation than accounted for in 2011 after we fine tuned our statistical calculation on the value of the assets at ERDF. So, plus 14% in current EBITDA, you see which, of course, explains an increase in our net income of 13.4% at &#x20AC;3.5 billion versus &#x20AC;3.1 billion last year. Operational performance, the impact of depreciation reduced, as I said earlier, lower financial interest that went from 3.9% down to 3.8% minus 3%, better turnover of dedicated assets and variable recognition in 2011 that was profitable regarding our debt. Net result group share is &#x20AC;3.5 billion you see, and up from last year when we had some extraordinary event. We had &#x20AC;2.7 billion in exceptional expenses last year, &#x20AC;1 billion in the UA, (sic) [U.S.] &#x20AC;900 million in Italy and a number of other non-recurring items. Today, they are negative at &#x20AC;510 million of total non-recurrent event. &#x20AC;253 million is the capital gains from EnBW disposal. In Italy, we recognized an additional depreciation or impairment charge of &#x20AC;304 million. &#x20AC;250 million is accounted by the goodwill spread between the sale price of Edipower in Edison and the capital gains in Edison.</p>
          <p>Dalkia International, minus &#x20AC;135 million that was recognized in the first half year. This is depreciation of our Italian subsidiary. Something new for the second half is Alpiq, minus &#x20AC;320 million. This concerns 20% of our capital stake in this Swiss company, so it's 25% of impairment &#x2013; goodwill impairment that was recognized by Alpiq. &#x20AC;260 million at ERDF. This is a positive impact after re-estimated the lifespan of a number of assets, in particular, the BT cables with a lifetime extension from 40 years to 50 years. So, that based on historical base and allowance for depreciation, we recognized a non-recurring gain of &#x20AC;266 million for a total of minus &#x20AC;510 million in non-recurring charges.</p>
          <p>Let's take a look at the performance country-by-country and business-by-business. Let's start with France, as I said organic growth of EBITDA of 6.3%, price effect, of course, plus &#x20AC;100 million for the market, the tariff impact, if you will. But you see here on this bridge graphic plus &#x20AC;558 million that actually offset the lower hydropower output.</p>
          <p>On the left side here, nuclear, the output was 13 terawatt hour in excess of last year, while hydropower went down 12 terawatt hour. This is almost a disastrous year in terms of hydropower output. It depends on the climate, filling of the dams, but thanks to the high performance of nuclear assets, we were able to offset the loss in hydropower in 2011.</p>
          <p>On the right-hand side, you see the sales here. This is for &#x2013; the first time we show that, these are the ARENH-based, price-based sales, 31 terawatt hour. That is the volume of electricity that we sold in the second half, minus 31 as I said &#x2013; minus 41 terawatt hour is the net sales for end users and we've also had a few changes in key account sales.</p>
          <p>Remarkable performance of our nuclear asset, as Chairman Proglio said earlier. You see here on this graph, it was made possible because the total number of outage days went down to 4,125 days versus 4,435 in 2010. On the gray section of the graph, you see the planned inspection. That is the 10-year maintenance inspection that are planned in normal were up. That is the effect of the fact that we had more of these 10-year inspections, nine versus five in 2010. In spite of that, the number of outage days has gone down, particularly unplanned outages, which is the result of better preventive maintenance of major maintenance CapEx program.</p>
          <p>So, you see 310 days less. Our goal for next year is to continue improving our management of planned shutdowns to continue the technical rollout, to better manage our shutdowns, particularly on the COPAT the unit shutdowns. That program will be fully rolled out starting in 2013 with full effect in 2014. So, high ambitions for 2012. Remarkable results in 2011 with a Kd factor of 80.7% in spite of the fact that we lost 1.5% of Kd due to the 10-year visit.</p>
          <p>So, even though we have great ambitions for 2011, we remain cautious with 420 and 425 terawatt hour for 2012 in terms of total output. We remain cautious because even though we have less 10-year inspection, two of them were postponed slightly over 2012. And in addition, we have long-term shutdowns because we'll be changing two steam generators this year versus one last year. So, it is a major replacement but that will secure our Kd availability factor for the future.</p>
          <p>In the UK, remarkable growth as well in the field of nuclear output, plus 5.7 terawatt hour, i.e. plus 15.5% more output. Of course, in 2010, we had a number of unplanned outages in Sizewell in particular, but nevertheless, we had remarkable output, maximum record production, I think, that had been reached over the past five years or six years. So, remarkable output performance in 2011.</p>
          <p>Beyond a favorable price effect, sales volumes have gone down as you see here in the electricity balance that I will show you because we lost some market shares in B2B clients. Where we measure the trend in the British performance is to analyze the growth of EBITDA before the impact of the accounting figures prior to the acquisition of British Energy. Accounting calculations at the time of the opening balance at that time, so that in 2010, we had a favorable effect of &#x20AC;324 million that went down to &#x20AC;322 million and will be negative in &#x2013; excuse me, &#x20AC;122 million and that will become negative.</p>
          <p>So, the line before these accounting items, you see we had a growth of 22.1% growth of our EBITDA before the impact of the fair value adjustment, attesting to the excellent operational performance of our British business in 2011. Nuclear output, plus 8 terawatt hour. And on the right-hand side, these are the sales volumes. You see, we lost some B2B volumes. This is a highly competitive segment, as you know, in the UK, structured sales, minus 14 terawatt hour. These were contracts that we inherited, loss-making contracts that we inherited from British Energy that are now being canceled out little by little.</p>
          <p>In Italy, as I said, minus 25% at &#x20AC;592 million in EBITDA versus &#x20AC;801 million. Edison, as you know, has run into a lot of problem, particularly in the gas segment. The fact that the take-or-pay contracts have to be renegotiated. So nevertheless, we reached that performance even though Edison, including Edipower, has exceeded its target of &#x20AC;900 million for 2011. They've actually reached virtually &#x20AC;1 billion.</p>
          <p>Other international segments, EBITDA has grown 19.5%. All segments have grown, but it should be noted the excellent performance of Belgium which is up improved margin in all segments, electricity and gas. Excellent performance as well of our Brazilian assets with an excellent year, thanks to highly favorable market conditions and export capacities towards Argentina.</p>
          <p>In other business segments, trading &#x2013; EDF trading is up. As you see, 3.3%. Excellent organic performance but also the fact that the nuclear output exceeded our expectations and our tradings teams actually optimized perfectly these excess output in all markets. Other segments, Tiru and Dalkia are down 7.9% due to lower profitability of Dalkia in Italy and Czech Republic.</p>
          <p>EDF Energies Nouvelles has increased its EBITDA by 17.4%. In 2011, EDF Energies Nouvelles reached its target of &#x20AC;560 million in EBITDA for the year. A target that was in line with the plan we analyzed at the time of the takeover before the summer. And EDF EN fulfilled its goal in 2011 with record commissioning over 692 net megawatts were commissioned in 2011, a record year; excellent operational performance.</p>
          <p>And now, let's analyze the group's cash flow in 2011 is negative at 1. &#x2013; the previous year, which is not comparable because we collected the first advancement for Exeltium with &#x20AC;1.7 billion, minus &#x20AC;1.5 billion in cash flow for the group in 2011. That figure can be explained mainly due to two effects in 2011. The deficit for the CSPE was aggravated. The CSPE meaning something we have not been compensated for is &#x20AC;3.8 billion end of 2011 versus &#x20AC;2.8 billion at the end of 2010 costing us &#x20AC;1 billion in cash flow.</p>
          <p>The second effect in 2011, we continued our investment efforts. Gross investments are up by 8.4% at &#x20AC;11.1 billion. With these special efforts in the field of nuclear maintenance in France, moving from &#x20AC;1.7 billion to &#x20AC;2 billion in investment but also, in distribution at ERDF, the total investments are up by 10%. Nevertheless, a sharp increase in improving the network quality plus 25% divestments in 2011 versus 2010.</p>
          <p>We also continue to develop new capacities, almost &#x20AC;4 billion, &#x20AC;3.9 billion with investment s in renewable energies that were superior, greater, 33% of new capacities developed, and new investments, 33% in renewable energies versus 29% in nuclear. Now given negative cash flow of &#x20AC;1.5 billion and &#x20AC;300 million dedicated activities for the payment of dividend and the acquisition of EDF EN for &#x20AC;1.5 billion, the debt should have increased but it decreased by &#x20AC;1 billion in general, thanks to disposal of EnBW which we collected almost entirely for its sales price at the beginning of the year in 2011. The debt is therefore declining at &#x20AC;33.3 billion versus &#x20AC;34.4 billion last year.</p>
          <p>Our debt, just a few words about how it's formed, mainly bond issue, bond debts. We continue to extend the average maturity of our debt, now reaching an average that's greater than 9 years, 9.2 years to be precise, and all of this by lowering the average coupon now at 4.3% versus 4.4% the year before. We're still benefiting from a very high level of liquidity at &#x20AC;25 billion.</p>
          <p>I conclude this presentation for 2011, highlighting as I said before, last July our synergy in transformation project to optimize our cost and to seek greater efficiency throughout the group. I gave all the details in July 2011 of this program. What I can tell you today is that we have achieved 28% of the target announced for 2015. 28% meaning &#x20AC;705 million in savings, made &#x20AC;600 million in OpEx, &#x20AC;100 million in CapEx. And it's thanks to this program that we're slowing down the increase in our OpEx, an increase that is necessary because we are reinvesting. And when you reinvest, it's not &#x2013; it's also about investing in maintenance for French nuclear plants. So, we're well underway to achieve our target well before 2015.</p>
          <p>A few concrete examples regarding synergy. Synergy, which exists in combined gas cycle, we set that up in France and we're using existing synergies between the French and the UK project in West-Burton which will be commissioned at the end of the year, as well as spare parts. These are concrete examples of synergies that can be carried out at the group. That also applies to nuclear between the British and the French plants. I won't go any further to these examples but they're quite significant, enabling us to optimize our cost space.</p>
          <p>As I said in my introduction and I can confirm, for 2011 &#x2013; 2015, this was announced in July 2011 with an average growth in EBITDA of 4% to 6%, 5% to 10% for the average annual growth of net income before the impact of the Edison acquisition with the opening balance sheet for Edison quite simply because the work is in progress and I can't give you an example &#x2013; concrete examples today. But our objective is to have current result up by 5% to 10%.</p>
          <p>All of that, with our net financial debt over EBITDA that's under control, lower than 2.5. Over the period, a payout rate of 55% to 65% <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:47) payout to be as proposing to the general meeting in May will be in the middle, 60%.</p>
          <p>For 2012, our targets are in line with this trajectory, and we plan to pay out a dividend that will be at least stable. I'll also confirm that after the works carried out to take into account the Fukushima disaster and the Nuclear Safety Authority studies, we can confirm that the total investments will be lower than equal or &#x20AC;50 million in 2015, fully in line with the path that I had announced in July. As I said before, I'd also like to tell a bit more about significant developments by the group over the past two years. Over the past two years where the group experienced significant transformations. Two years ago, EDF had 46% of EnBW, jointly controlled without planning to take it over. We sold it, collecting over &#x20AC;7 billion with &#x20AC;250 million in capital gains in 2011.</p>
          <p>Two years ago, EDF had a joint venture with Constellation in the United States. This agreement with Constellation was renegotiated end of 2010 eliminating the put, acquiring 100% of Unistar, preserving its interest as a part of CENG with a reconfiguration of the company's operations, but defending EDF's energy continued in 2011 with CENG because we took part with respect to the merger with Constellation so as to defend our interest, our interest with respect to the CENG joint venture, thanks to which we obtained additional governance rights so that we can preserve the entirety of our CENG joint venture. The Chairman pointed this out earlier. We acquired 50% of capital in EDF Energies Nouvelles. Two years ago, we had 50% and the remaining was listed on the stock market. Now, we hold all shares and integration is now successful and you also know that we carried out the Paden operations signed a few hours ago. This operation is quite simple. Enabling a total control of Edison by EDF. Simple, because it was carried out in four steps. First of all, the acquisition of 50% of TdE, the holding company through which we organized a joint control over Edison with our Italian partners. For about &#x20AC;700 million. So the Edison securities is valued at &#x20AC;0.84 per share, given they take of debt about &#x20AC;600 million in the holding company, we're talking about nine times EBITDA in 2011 for Edison.</p>
          <p>The second step consisted in disposing of Edison's 50% stake in Edipower to Delmi, for &#x20AC;600 million. Delmi had taken over &#x20AC;550 million in debt financed by Edison that, therefore, to Edipower given a multiple of 10 times the EBITDA.</p>
          <p>The third step, commercial deal which consisted signing our gas sales contract by Edison to Edipower covering 50% of Edipower's needs. And lastly, the last transaction which is still subject to approval by CONSOB, with the launch of a mandatory public tender, the remaining capital of Edison, at a minimum price of $0.84 per share. In all we'll hold at least 80%, maybe 100% of Edison, if all remaining shareholders provide their stakes.</p>
          <p>Impact on our debt, over &#x20AC;2 billion in the absolute, quite simply because we were consolidating 1% of Edison, whereas today, we consolidate on 50% of Edison. Between 2.2 and 3.1, depends on the success rate of the OPA between 0% and 100%.</p>
          <p>The impact on our credit ratio is quite limited at about 0.1 times EBITDA, for net income, it's neutral. Of course, before taking into account the opening balance sheet, about &#x20AC;50 million in synergy per year primarily in trading, even though this was not the main reason for this transaction. The synergies are primarily in the field of development and consolidating our strategy with Edison at the heart of our group strategy.</p>
          <p>Two outstanding conditions: confirmation by the CONSOB that the price of the public tender should not exceed &#x20AC;0.84 per share; and also, regulatory authorizations of two types. First of all, the European anti-trust authorities for the full takeover of Edison by EDF and the Italian anti-trust authorities concerning the Edipower transaction, so waiting for a final completion for summer 2012.</p>
          <p>The EDF Group now has stronger areas for growth. I spoke about Edison and the heart of the group's gas strategy. Of course, you also have the case of renewable energies with EDF Energies Nouvelles. And now, I'll give the floor to Jean-Paul Bouttes, who will tell us more about our strategy, the EDF Group strategy in the field of renewable energies. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everyone. As Henri probably pointed out, EDF has a strong commitment in renewable energies in line with our vision as the leading electricity operator of low-carbon energy in 2020, 75% of our production plant will be without carbon with 25% renewable energy, including hydropower. Now, our long-term vision is for low-powered electricity at global level to protect the climate and to ensure secure supply. And renewable energies are part of the solution, playing the key role with control over energy demand and with nuclear.</p>
          <p>So, the challenge is to reconcile economy and growth, on the one hand, and on the other hand, the climate change, and therefore, to keep the cost of electricity under control. To do so, we must deploy renewable energies at the right time, in the right place and with the right mix, at the right time, by drawing a distinction between a really competitive renewable energy such as hydropower or land or onshore wind, and those that still need to bring about progress, to lower costs, for example, offshore wind energy or solar concentration.</p>
          <p>In the right place, in areas with over 3,000 hours of wind per year as in the case in Mexico, onshore wind is already competitive, whereas in Europe with 2,000 hours of wind per year, this excess cost today the same for photovoltaic solar. In sunny areas such as California, we're close to being competitive. In Northern Europe, with two times less sunshine, less than 1,000 hours per year, of course, we're further away from the &#x2013; being in the right place.</p>
          <p>So, with the right mix to &#x2013; batteries, for example on energy storage, intermittent energies are complementary. Sources that complement base-load power sources nuclear, gas and coal are in competition.</p>
          <p>And therefore, with the dynamism and agility of EDF EN as you have just seen, with the results, we have a strong basis for our development. That's the first step for our growth which we will supplement with a second growth with growth drivers, thanks to synergies in three areas, international development, engineering and R&amp;D.</p>
          <p>In international development, two key areas, complementarity, consistency; complementarity between the countries where EDF and EDF EN operates. The drivers for the choice of geographies for EDF EN consist in finding growth, where it does exist. This was done in Europe and in North America and, of course, we plan to continue and to develop in this area. This is what we did by seizing opportunities in countries that are rich with wind, solar energy and where electricity needs are rising, in Mexico, Canada, Turkey, with an increasing number of projects. Also in Morocco or in South Africa, where we plan to take part in calls for tenders. Consistency, too, by pragmatically developing geographical synergies between EDF and EDF EN. Using the presence of EDF in Poland or Brazil, for example, to facilitate EDF EN's growth and vice versa.</p>
          <p>Second area, mobilize EDF's engineering capacities so as to develop high performance industrial solutions and to continue to keep risk under control. Our response to the offshore call for tenders that we've spoken about before in France is a good example in terms of the right choice of technologies, identifying the high performance turbine over the years with Alstom after an in-depth research with intrinsic quality of the machine and on the quality of the industrial organization. In terms of navigating uncertainties with systematic measures in terms of wind research and the seafloor inspection, the two key points.</p>
          <p>And lastly, in terms of industry by setting up partnerships with competent and seasoned operators such as DONG or developers like wpd Offshore and Nass&amp;Wind. Of course, in terms of the local industries, there's also the possibility of &#x2013; we already mentioned of creating 7,000 jobs in France.</p>
          <p>Lastly, our ability to innovate in R&amp;D are key to drive new technologies in the future. In photovoltaic energy, R&amp;D is fully committed for key technologies, for competitive panels of tomorrow with thin strips with <mark type="ph" /> Nexus and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (64:43) the research institute and development in photovoltaic energy with the French research institute and high-yield silicon technologies using hetero-junction as was pointed out. And to continue to work with the CEA and with Photowatt through PV Alliance.</p>
          <p>In sea energy, we're talking about improving offshore performance and technological breakthroughs with floating wind turbines and in marine as well with the marine current turbines off of Paimpol Br&#xE9;hat. Also to improve performance in the network and in storage too with sodium-sulfur 1 megawatt batteries in Reunion or smart grids too in Lyon with the pilot projects in Lyon, , Nice and with a project <mark type="ph" /> milliner (65:39) for energy management on islands.</p>
          <p>In closing EDF EN its momentum, dynamic, skills, expertise, motivation of the staff, its results is actually the foundation and the driver of our ambition in renewable energy. The synergies that I've briefly described in international growth of engineering and R&amp;D, all of that should open up profitable and sustainable prospects for growth at EDF EN with genuine growth drivers in line with the group's corporate international strategy.</p>
          <p>Last but not least, based on the needs, expectations and resources of the country, jointly with that and by keeping our risk under control on new technologies and breakthroughs. These were my closing words. I'd like to take you for your attention and I believe it is now time for Q&amp;As.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The floor is open, says the Chairman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Credit Suisse. I have a question &#x2013; two questions actually on Edison, particularly on renegotiation of the existing gas contracts. You said that they did create some problems this year. What are the prospects in that terms and what would be the financial impact?</p>
          <p>Second question. Can you give us an idea of the EBITDA trend you expect from Edison over the next three years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the gas &#x2013; Edison's gas contracts, yes, this is indeed the key challenge for the Edison results in 2012. Only this year, the results actually confirmed their targets for the ongoing year, i.e., having an EBITDA that is in line with the figures for 2012, approximately &#x20AC;1.2 billion. Half of which is highly dependent on the ability to close the ongoing arbitrage on the long-term contracts. So the overall impact is approximately &#x20AC;600 million expected in 2012. All, depending of course on the final closing of the transaction by EDF. But if we believe that if we expect that the transaction will be closed at the end of June, the effect for us would be 50% of that figure for 2012.</p>
          <p>Can I give you a long-term EBITDA outlook? No, not really. Not at this point. Their transactions will be finalized in the coming months and then we will have plenty of time to announce the effects, the impacts of Edison's integration, definition of our strategy and so on at that time only we'll be in a position to comment on future figures for future years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question from <mark type="indiscernible" /> (68:58), I have three questions. Number one is linked to tariff rates methodology that will be supporting the tariffs in the future in <mark type="indiscernible" /> (69:10) report, the French government has mentioned that it likes the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (69:16) method to define the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (69:19) price &#x2013; third-party access price. Do you have ideas of how the tariffs will be determined and what methodology will be used?</p>
          <p>Secondly, regarding the Kd availability factor for nuclear plants, can you confirm your 85% target for 2015? And could you detail what will be the impact of the safety measures to be implemented regarding &#x2013; that is the recommendation from the stress tests and the recommendation from the ASA? What will be the impact on that Kd factor? Thirdly, could you give us first elements of the first PPA impacts on Edison <mark type="audio gap" /> (70:01)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take the question on tariffs. I imagine you're talking about the ARENH price, not just any kind of tariffs, right? Or are you talking about electricity rates or the ARENH third-party access price? If that is the case, let me briefly remind you what it is. The price at which we sell our electricity to our competitors for 15 years, 25% of are nuclear output. That is what the ARENH means.</p>
          <p>Now, in the past, an eternity ago, a year ago, I was explaining to the number of parliament commissions to explain that &#x20AC;46 per megawatts was the basic production price from our nuclear output. We spoke about that last year. You may remember.</p>
          <p>Now, months have gone by, number of events, Fukushima, among others, and the French Cour des Comptes has looked in-depth at the cost of ownership, complete cost of 1 nuclear megawatt from the existing asset and they reached the figure of &#x20AC;46 per megawatts &#x2013; excuse me, &#x20AC;49.2 per megawatts.</p>
          <p>Okay, there's been some update in considering the impairment values and so on. We're not that far from these 49.7% but these had two consequences. First of all, to demonstrate and show that nuclear power is the most competitive energy in Europe in terms of total cost of ownership and that is important figure. I'm talking about the existing French nuclear assets, of course, that were the benchmark.</p>
          <p>Second point is that, we cannot keep on too long with the ration of selling one-fourth of our production output for 15 years based on non-economic prices. As discussion we had public authorities saying we need to have a starting point and an ending point. Starting point that means that it has to be connected with some sort of existing parameters. The <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:12:22) time itself, the price there was &#x20AC;42. So, while I negotiated I said, okay, we'll accept, we'll make the effort. We'll start from that level and we'll come out pretty slow, slow up towards total cost of ownership by 2015. That was the deadline set by the French public authorities to have a fully deregulated market.</p>
          <p>So &#x20AC;40 for a limited period of six-month after in discussion, negotiations, public authorities decided to accept my &#x20AC;42 as of the 1st of January, 2012, and that's now, so the iron price is currently &#x20AC;42. After six-month period, it was at &#x20AC;40. And then quite naturally, of course, we could all agree that it would be legitimate for the iron price to reach the &#x20AC;49.5 or &#x20AC;49.7 in total cost of ownership by 2015. That is at least my own vision. So, that's basically what I can reply regarding the ARENH third-party access price. Any other method would be, let's say, surprising, not defendable economically and very difficult to legitimize or analyze as being rational. So, that would be my answer on the ARENH tariff.</p>
          <p>So, the Cour des Comptes report, confirms the estimates that we had given actually earlier, both in terms of competitiveness and economic cost. And Thomas will give you more specific answers on the Kd. 92%, that was the winter Kd, that's maximum utilization of assets, very high value actually, and very satisfactory. I think we can congratulate our teams for that for the very substantial growth of the Kd availability factor that's been going on steadily for the past 18 months.</p>
          <p>Future progress on the Kd, Thomas will answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Unfortunately, I can't give you precise figures on that quite simply is because we're currently working with the French nuclear safety authorities to define the calendar for the future works. I can only give you an answer; and that calendar, the schedule should be normally defined by the end of the first half year, and then I can give you more precise figures, of course. And of course, we remain cautious in 2012 in terms of Kd target, but I'll give you a more &#x2013; much more specific answer in July when we meet again.</p>
          <p>Regarding your question on the impact of the PPA, purchase agreement, opening balance sheet for Edison and all that, there again, it's premature, too early to explain that. But I can tell you that at Edison, we have excellent assets, first of all, the brand itself. And we intend to analyze that very precisely all of these assets to define the opening balance sheet for Edison. I also don't want to get into counting technical details. There a lot of transactions will be closing in the first half. But overall, apart from the opening balance sheet for the future, there will be no significant impact on fiscal year 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question. I'd like to come back on few other conclusions of the report by the Cour de Comptes. First of all, the Cour des Comptes set at approximately &#x20AC;5 billion out of the &#x20AC;10 billion estimated CapEx post-Fukushima was already in your long-term CapEx, you still have &#x20AC;5 billion. I know you're discussing and negotiating the calendar. But can you tell us how these $5 billion will be spread out over time? And what driver do you believe you'll be leveraging over the next three or four years, so that you don't increase your total CapEx that is capped as &#x20AC;15 billion, so will you be postponing some of them or reduce others?</p>
          <p>Still again &#x20AC;55 billion is the estimation of the Cour des Comptes over the next 12 or 13 years, can you confirm this figure? In other words, are you going to stick with CapEx annual pays that are &#x2013; be more or less at the level of the past years i.e. approximately &#x20AC;4 billion? And lastly, the Cour des Comptes' work in depth in the terms of nuclear provisions? The report questions whether the impairment rate on these provisions is not too high at 5%. In view of uncertainties on the underlying portfolio I'd like to know what EDF's CFO believes in that topic?</p>
          <p>And the final question, you mentioned that regulated business in France benefited from the first feeding billing for against the cost of photovoltaic solar power? Lastly, reduction of &#x20AC;200 million in renewal &#x2013; provisions for renewal, this I imagine is a sustained level, I guess. And do you believe that we can go further regarding the accounting trends in this renewal provisions and have you progressed on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, &#x20AC;15 billion maximum by 2015. That I confirm, and I also confirm the outlook for the &#x20AC;55 billion in CapEx that has been reviewed and estimated by the Cour des Comptes. Out of this &#x20AC;55 billion, &#x20AC;10 billion can be called safety improvements. Out of this &#x20AC;10 billion, &#x20AC;5 billion are already planned in the context of the work that was planned for extending the lifespan. There were differences that will probably have to speed up the base of this than &#x2013; faster than initially planned. But we're fine-tuning these figures again and we're also waiting for the schedule that the ASN, Nuclear Safety Authorities, will be defining.</p>
          <p>As for the drivers, we can leverage. We have several. That's why I'm confirming this &#x20AC;15 billion. We can optimize our CapEx. And we're talking about net CapEx as you would have noted and I'll stop here on the definition of what a net capital expenditure can mean. So, yes, &#x20AC;55 billion as estimated by the Cour des Comptes. That means that the investment efforts in the French nuclear fleet will increase. I've already told you that in July, but it will continue, and that is the trajectory that was analyzed by the Cour des Comptes leading to the total cost of ownership calculated for the nuclear asset at &#x20AC;49.5 for nuclear output.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, is the provision for 5% is a little bit high in terms of the yield on dedicated assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it all depends what periods you analyze. We believe that in view of the calendar of cash out for these assets, that will be spread out over tens of years. We believe we need to analyze a period of underlying assets, bonds and equity much longer than just five or six years. When you look at the bond and equity yield, we're talking about 5%. So, we believe that this discounting rate is perfectly justified.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As for feeding cost for PV solar power, I believe, &#x20AC;150 million. Provisions for renewals, minus &#x20AC;200 million this year versus last year, we still had approximate &#x20AC;200 million, is that sustainable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Since all of that derives from a very precise statistical model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Will there be other effects in the future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't tell you at this point. The only thing I can tell you is that the ERDF teams are working very hard to further fine tune that statistical model for the time being. It is overall comprehensive per major categories of assets, of course; but it is overall. In other words, it is now identified concession contract per contract and we intend to further fine tune our statistical model to understand what's happening for each concession contract. And remind you that the law says no provisions for renewal should be recognized for assets to be renewed after the end of the concession contracts. So we're continuing to work on that and hopefully we can tell you a little bit more on that topic in July.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Natixis. Two questions; first one, has to do with the agreement of AREVA used on the long-term supply agreement for uranium. There's an option that is mentioned in the press release regarding possible investments in mining projects. Could you shed some light on this and what type of amount are you thinking about possibly investing? Second question has to do with the agreement with Riverbank Power that you signed a few days ago to develop hydropower, pumping and storage plus dams. Could you give us some ideas on that type of investments in terms of size, and amount?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Herv&#xE9; Machenaud will answer on the AREVA questions regarding the uranium supply contract signed with AREVA, prospects of cooperation in the cycle <mark type="audio gap" /> (82:14) Herv&#xE9; Machenaud, as you know, is Senior Vice President In-Charge of Generation &amp; Engineering.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've signed an agreement, yes, regarding supply for existing assets from &#x2013; of AREVA. So, we've agreed on the long-term contract for the period 2014-2020 with possible extension up to 2030. We've also agreed on the possibility that has not been finalized yet, but we're still working on it, of a mining interest where we would take a 10% stake, that would give us access to 10% of the supply in that particular mining asset that covers a number of various mines scattered geographically, but more specifically in Africa. This is a minority stake where would we invest; first of all, that guarantees us a secure uranium supply over the long-term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On hydropower, more generally renewable energy in the U.S., what is our strategy in the field? Renewable energy in the U.S., yes, it is one of our major avenue for growth in the U.S. and in North America, particularly so that this is a sector where there are high synergies between enXco teams, very talented and EDF Trading North America teams based in Houston who are perfectly familiar with the local markets and are fully capable of optimizing all of that, particularly in terms of energy saving certificates. This context, of course, hydropower plays a full-fledged role. I won't go into details. But we do have a titled power project in North America. We also have a portfolio of smaller projects, hydro or storage projects. Some of them are more substantial, but that is a major priority for growth and extension for us in the U.S.. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Actually, I have three questions. Now, you took care of Germany, you're now taking care of Italy, you solved the RTE case, what is your next big case, Mr. Proglio? In the U.S., my vision is somewhat different. You said you settled your problem with the U.S. There's no nuclear new build in the U.S. Well, two power plants can be potentially restarted in states where prices are regulated. But UniStar has been walking around and changed hands for the past few years. But in the U.S., you don't have a license as an operator. So, could you not settle things, once and for all, and then go to countries where you have a real demand?</p>
          <p>Then, you talk about &#x20AC;140 million positive impact regarding the extension of the lifespan by five years. Have you done some modeling on simulation of what the impact would be if the same thing happened in France? And finally, dedicated asset portfolio, a lot of volatility, have you moved forward on assets contribution as you did with RTE, perhaps contributing some real estate property?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was important to settle the problems that deserve to be coped with, problems that resulted from previous commitments, previous positions made by the group. Now, some of them were obvious. We have to finalize negotiation with the U.S. to secure the group on the U.S. case and negotiations and the put option that had a $2 billion impact in terms of risk and that was settled and solved quite smoothly. A number of topics that you mentioned were out there on the horizon as well. But basically it was rather delicate topic. Historically, we were in situation of close partnership with our local authority's partner that was in Germany in the Baden-W&#xFC;rttemberg land with EnBW. We have 45% stake, high, but minority nevertheless. It was difficult choice to make, particularly since, on the one hand, as you know I had announced my wish not to remain eternally a minority shareholder in that group because we wanted to have some control over our destiny.</p>
          <p>And the acceptability of ramping up our stake in EnBW did not look very good. Secondly, Germany was going through turbulent times in terms of political options regarding their energy mix and we were very much aware of that in a pre-election climate that was quite tense, particularly in certain lenders in Germany and in particular in Baden-W&#xFC;rttemberg. So, that is the general context back in 2010 as regards EnBW.</p>
          <p>The choice was to exit this stakeholding and that decision was not that easy to make. Internally, it was a difficult decision that we have closed &#x2013; we had established close links, close cooperation between the EDF and EnBW teams. A lot of our top level managers were fully committed and engaged in this cooperation. Basically, the industrial and international venture that was this EnBW partnership was deeply rooted into the philosophy and the strategy of the group.</p>
          <p>So, choosing or opting for exiting this cooperation was tough, difficult and even painful. Yet, at the same time, I felt that it was legitimate to do it. And I endorse my own responsibility to exit at the time when I had the feeling that the most likely outcome would be that either we would be relegated in a position of passive minority shareholders or that political decisions would lead to revising energy policies that would not really be very favorable for our company or for EnBW. So, in any case, the decision was made, the option was taken, the deal was closed very quickly and the results, as you see, is &#x20AC;7 billion in cash for the benefit of the group and without any bitterness basically. Current situation of EnBW is indeed very, very tense for all the reasons you're familiar with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Italy was complex. 11 years of negotiation, that's difficult. We had been negotiating since 2000 with the Italians on the Edison shareholding with episodes that were more or less tense. In the second half of 2011, we finally had an opportunity to take out a strong position, controlling position, in this company, a company with strong presence in the territory and deep roots in Italy, with a national and not just a local presence.</p>
          <p>We had to obtain approval by our partners there too, with a strong minority, about 40% approval by the public authorities, because we are a public service operator and we feel comfortable only when we can carry out our business responsibly in the climate of mutual understanding and acceptability, and lastly, the economic conditions must be there for the negotiation to be carried out.</p>
          <p>I pay tribute to Chairman Zuccoli earlier and send this sincerely, in tough complicated negotiations with a tense economic environment, conditions that were ultimately satisfying for everyone. And now, we're in a very strategic country for the reasons I pointed out earlier in terms of geostrategy, in the sense of geography and the great &#x2013; and the major supplies for Europe from Russia, in Middle East, Central Asia. I believe that this position as a majority shareholder and integrating Edison in EDF will have a significant impact in terms of the development of our business and synergies, industrial, professional, economical, in terms of improving teams, in terms of development, in a very important zone for our business. These countries, therefore, in the Middle East, Central Asia and Southern Europe, but I think that EDF will increase Edison's extremely strategic position in the coming months.</p>
          <p>It was therefore important to think about it and there are other projects that were &#x2013; well, there are many projects in progress, industrial partnerships, we spoke of those, linking us to major French players, but they are not the only ones. For example, the major partners in very Eastern Europe, major partners in Asia, historical &#x2013; historic and others, and will enable the group to develop significantly in the coming years.</p>
          <p>This strategy with a focus on the international space of major industrial partnerships and other partnerships will occupy good portion of EDF's strategic vision and, therefore, the group's general management in the future. Of course, all of our growth that we have spoken very little about in upstream, production, power generation, the major partnerships with major countries. We spoke not enough about the UK, an extremely important country for the group, Central Europe, an extremely &#x2013; well, potentially a strong zone. So, there is a lot of negotiation in progress. Building a very ambitious vision for the future of EDF Group and with the possibility of significant value for our group and therefore for its shareholders. We have many requirements to success, technology and research, human resources, which are our key for success, organizations, things to be built. So, these are the major areas, where I will be &#x2013; on which I'll be spending a lot of time, not to speak of the commercial aspects, development or new forms of development. We've been taking too much of other physical aspects, upstream, power generation, grids.</p>
          <p>You must also take on board the added value, downstream. Now, there is commercialization, optimization, trading, new commercial offerings, structuring, and innovative vision, and new growth, optimization for energy, new energies that we spoke very little about that too. So, there are many areas that EDF has a clear ambition. We will come back to tell you more about that with you at more precise working sessions. Now, strategic vision by the group is ambitious and has the means to be ambitious. And we need to set other forums where we can speak with you about these outlooks over a period that will be medium and long term, and not just over the coming months. That's all I can tell you. I'll give the floor to Thomas for more precise questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a question to United States on nuclear in the United States. Well, nothing has changed, except that the changes in gas prices are now going in the right direction, since spoke about that the last time. Nothing has changed in that deregulated environment such as in Maryland, with the price of energy still high with high volatility and shale gas United States outlooks, in terms of investments in a considerable project, such as new nuclear, are very remote.</p>
          <p>But EDF has spent a lot of money in this field. Our objective &#x2013; we've had the provision in 2010, but our objective is not to lose what has been acquired, know-how, especially, applications for licenses. We have been working on this with AREVA, which is continuous efforts to obtain an EPR license into United States. Our objective is to reduce expenditure, because passed on as an expense every year without losing what we have acquired already and especially the teams' know-how.</p>
          <p>Yeah. Then you have two questions on finance. What impact on the write-down of a 10-year extension of the French nuclear plants? Our accounting system is based on a 40-year lifetime. Sometimes, you read here or there that there may be risks, that there may be higher provisions if this or that study on the deep storage, for example, were to show an estimate that was higher than ours. So, we can see the potential risks were down &#x2013; were declined. But there's very little talk about the potential for an improvement in our results, if we obtain an extension of our lifetime from 40 to &#x2013; or 60 years.</p>
          <p>Thank you for that question. But to answer that question, there's several impacts; impact on amortization, on provisions, impact to the total cost price that was rest &#x2013; with respect to your question about the Cour des Comptes. But what I can tell you this &#x2013; is this, if we were to try to reason based on current amortizations, it can go up to &#x20AC;2 billion in decline in amortization, which is very significant as compared to the total amortization. But, once again, I don't want that figure to be used in models, because we're fine-tuning our calculations. And if you wish, we can tell you more in the future.</p>
          <p>Do we have other projects to optimize dedicated assets with real estate in particular? Yes. We believe that by diversifying more dedicated assets play a significant role by putting 50% of RTE, that allowed us to have a minus &#x20AC;5 performance in 2011 in a tough environment to the high volatility on the market. And we plan to continue to diversify our portfolio to areas, continuing with infrastructures, but also in two new directions; real estate and investments in shareholders' equity. You may have noted, as a matter of fact, the plan to create an investment fund for SMEs, small businesses in France, nuclear &#x2013; SMEs in the nuclear business. And we have confirmed our will to invest about &#x20AC;50 million in this fund, a fund that will be amongst the dedicated assets.</p>
          <p>As for real estate, we reserved a small portion of our dedicated assets to this type of assets. We're proposing to put our own assets that would mean a change in the decrease, and I can make no comment on that today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm from the newspaper Les Echos, and I have several questions. Could you tell us about discussions with CGNPC and AREVA for the French and Chinese nuclear plant? AREVA, apparently, is defending its own reactor, and what's the calendar for these talks? And also, this future reactor, will it be built one day in France?</p>
          <p>Regarding Fessenheim, the 2050 Energy Commission is compliant with your strategy regarding reactors' lifetime. If that vision were applied to Fessenheim, will you continue with works, and what's the specific calendar for works conducted at Fessenheim? What about renewable energies, do you plan to work with &#x2013; to become the leader in France? And a question for Mr. Piquemal, can you tell us about free cash flow for the end of 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Discussions with AREVA and our partnership with AREVA is extremely close. The project with the Chinese is moving forward nicely as three party &#x2013; partnership between CGNPC, AREVA and EDF to develop in medium capacity, third-generation reactor. So, in these areas, good progress has been achieved in the perfect climate of cooperation. I wouldn't go much further than that. Bear in mind that that will lead us to technical considerations with respect to the partnership as regard to type of technology to be adopted. Well, that should be done in perfect cooperation with the two other partners. The project, right now, completely is well on its way.</p>
          <p>As regards Fessenheim, yes, works are in progress, as you know. We successfully passed the 10-year inspection for the first reactor, which is now reconnected to the network of the second as well, which has been approved by the nuclear authorities in France, the ASN, for 10 years. The second is a 10-year inspection is now reconnected to the network. And I believe that the opinion shall be given by the ASN in the near future. And I'm very confident that this opinion will be positive, extending the lifetime for 10 years at Fessenheim.</p>
          <p>This is &#x2013; and this is subject to the final decision by the ASN. But the two reactors saw two 10-year visits. And then, post-Fukushima, inspections will be conducted in due time in compliance with the agreements and the requirements of the ASN. The ASN, well, they're fully compliant with the opinions that we expressed ourselves. That's all I can tell you about Fessenheim, which is a plant that, like the others, meets and will meet the requirements of the safety authorities in every respect &#x2013; with constant improvements, because, as you know, it's day-to-day business for the group, as well as for the ASN.</p>
          <p>As for renewable energies, we have posted our ambitions which are significant. We plan to be strongly present in this sector. This is one of our important sectors for the group strategy internationally and is therefore important for us to have consistency being banked by important players making this development possible. As for the rest, I'll call on Thomas to answer about free cash.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For 2012, your question based on &#x2013; about free cash flow, changes in indebtedness, we expect an increase in debt by about &#x20AC;1.5 billion to &#x20AC;2 billion with respect to a base including Edison. I said that the impact of the Edison acquisition could go up to &#x20AC;3.2 billion due to the consolidation of 50% of the debt.</p>
          <p>Let me seize this opportunity, if you permit, to give you more details on this figure, because I received a question on the Internet asking me to explain. The impact on the debt of the Edison acquisition, I said between &#x20AC;2.2 billion and &#x20AC;3.1 billion. It just so happens that we're consolidating for the first time 100% of the debt plus &#x20AC;2 billion. And then, the purchase of the top and the sale at the bottom increases our debt by &#x20AC;200 million. Because at the top is &#x20AC;1.3 billion investments, at the bottom the disposal of &#x20AC;1.1 billion, so &#x20AC;2 billion plus &#x20AC;0.2 million. And that the impact of the OPA between zero and 900 plus million euros, that's the further question on the Internet.</p>
          <p>Now, to come back to the question raised by <mark type="ph" /> Mr. Matila (107:25), we expect our debt to increase. As I said before, it could go up to &#x20AC;1.5 billion, if we have Exeltium for one simple reason. In 2012, we'll be increasing our investment efforts. We believe that our investments will be at around &#x20AC;2.5 billion, higher than in 2011, because of greater investments in French nuclear and, also because of the final investment decisions provided for in the figures that I pointed out for the UK, and with the launching of the Rybnik project in Poland which the President &#x2013; the Chairman spoke of and by continued investments in the grids. This is why our debt should increase in 2012 versus 2011. Let me remind you that we have a 2.5 ratio between debt and EBITDA and this will be attained in 2012 because we'll be even below 2.5, even below 2004 in 2012 for the debt to EBITDA ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take a few questions maybe over the Internet. From Mr. De Blic [JPMorgan] on ERDF, where have you reached in terms of external financing at EDF and the negative impact on accounting EBITDA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At ERDF, it's not really the accounting EBITDA but in the tariffs where we should receive 7.25% but we also have discounts. Works are in progress and I think I point out earlier that this will be a part of the troop four negotiations that are just beginning. I'd like to insist though that the review of the contractual framework, the tariffs, accounting, that takes a lot of time. And we do not have all the results as yet. But let me specify one thing, is the considerable effort made over the past two years by ERDF's team to better control changes in its royalties for the second consecutive year in 2011 and 2010 are down, thanks to a better control on the execution of contracts. And I think this needs to be stressed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question from Mr. De Blic, what is the impact of Edison on 2012? The objective of 4% to 6% is adjusted for that impact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It takes into account the integration of Edison with an integration as at the end of June. What impact will Edison have on our EBITDA? I've said this before. The objective is &#x20AC;1.2 billion in 2012, 50% of which linked to renegotiating gas contracts. It's just that you need to adjust also 2011 to make it comparable to what I just said for 2011 by adding &#x20AC;200 million in EBITDA for 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, that's it. A question on Edison's debt, Mr. Moulder [CreditSights]. I answered that question. A question on assumptions for tariffs. We will not answer that for 2012. A question from Mr. Martin Young [Nomura] on the ARENH. I believe that the &#x2013; our Chairman, Henri Proglio, answered that question earlier. And a question from Mr. [ph] Charlton (111:02) on the CSPE, the amount of CSPE due to us at the end of December?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x20AC;3.8 billion versus &#x20AC;2.8 billion at the end of 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A question from Mr. <mark type="ph" /> Becker (111:16) on tariffs and nuclear. I think that Mr. Proglio spoke about that earlier. A question on what would happen depending on the results of the elections. I think we would answer that one. In the U.S., a question from Mr. Moulder, CreditSights. In the United States, you worked with Exelon to grow your U.S. nuclear business, demonstrated a huge appetite for new nuclear, especially in Maryland.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we do not accept &#x2013; expect at this stage any cooperation in our project in Maryland with Exelon. Maybe in the future in the nuclear new build field with a long-term view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's it for the questions over the Internet. Emmanuel Turpin [Morgan Stanley] have a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like to come back to nuclear power generation and your Kd objective. You said that you had the objective of 85% but you expected talks with the ASN to discuss any impact. This information can create emotions if the Kd declines that can reduce your model significantly. Could you tell us more about what could occur after talks with ASN? Would you talk about the temporary reduction in Kd factor because of an excess CapEx, changes for Fukushima over the next three or four years or is it about the structural reduction by taking into account new constraints for maintenance? And how could you offset a lower Kd factor by increasing your dispatching rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's always extremely complicated to reply to questions on the impact of the decision taken by the ASN Nuclear Safety Authorities. Just by respect for the ASN, it's difficult for me to say that whatever they decide, it will not have any impact on anything.</p>
          <p>That falls under the competence or rather I would call that being provocative. And by simple respect for the ASN authorities, I cannot comment on the ASN's decision. ASN is an authority that is fully independent and free to decide what it deems necessary to demand from operators in France. So, seeing that our relationship with the ASN are relationships of trusts, is obvious because we live on a daily basis with the ASN. It's not like a tax inspector that comes once every 10 years. This is a continuous relationship. Hence, necessarily, an ongoing cooperation between expert specialists without being complacent at all, but a real relationship of respect and daily cooperation work.</p>
          <p>When we released our report to the ASN Authority, in line with what had been requested and anticipated, regarding both the condition of the assets and any recommendations we could be making in the post-Fukushima era, that report was immediately published online. So you were informed about it. The ASN put it online. So report recommendations and recommendation that will be released by the ASN, that demonstrate convergence between the ASN and EDF Group on the necessity.</p>
          <p>So, when we give you targets or ambitions on our investments in terms of maintenance, availability, load factor and so on, we integrate &#x2013; we embed, if you will, the daily expectations and anticipation based on our understanding of what the trends in availability should be. So, I cannot comment on anything that would be of a speculative nature. Mr. Machenaud will add on to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To reply to the specific question regarding whether the consequences of the ASN decisions would have structural impacts on the Kd in the post-Fukushima. The big challenge at stake is the workload, if you will, which is considerable. That is the issue that Thomas Piquemal expressed earlier, namely a period of heavy investments that requires tight organization, improvement of the efficiency of our reactor, maintenance shutdown.</p>
          <p>The issue of Kd in previous years was linked in essentially to so-called unplanned outages. What we're talking about are planned, scheduled shutdowns. And the more maintenance work there is, plus, of course, the more these planned shutdowns will be considerable in terms of volume and time. But the perspective is to reduce the unplanned outages, hence to restore optimum and maximum availability for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A question to Mr. Proglio and Mr. Piquemal. Emerging market. Your debt is going to go up &#x20AC;1.5 billion in 2012. It didn't go down a lot between 2010 and 2012. So what strategy are you planning to reduce the group's debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not so much the absolute value of the debt increase. It's compliance with the key ratios. That's what should be looked at. This is why I gave you a mid-term commitment, i.e., go &#x2013; be below 2.5 times EBITDA. Mind you that among the group set, we have &#x20AC;3.8 million in CSPE tax credit as of the end &#x2013; year-end 2011 and we're financing this tax credit via the debt. So, being able to settle this CSPE tax credit issue is a major challenge.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we have the best rating in the sector and we intend to keep that rating. That's why I'm saying that what is important is compliance with the ratios rather the increase of the debt in absolute value.</p>
          <p>Your question on assets disposals. Well, we have a net CapEx outlook. We have a little bit more disposals in 2011, &#x20AC;400 million versus &#x20AC;100 million in 2010, but no comment on the rest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe we can move on to other questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I believe that we were able to answer the questions you have. Thank you for your attendance. Thank you for your attention. And we'll see you soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>