<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1508190" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-11-06</date>
    <companies>
      <company>186</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Investor Relations">Patrick Fitzgerald</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">David N. Farr</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Frank J. Dellaquila</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co. LLC">Steven Eric Winoker</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Longbow Research LLC">Eli S. Lustgarten</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Scott R. Davis</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Deane Michael Dray</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Securities International, Inc.">Shannon O'Callaghan</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Vertical Research Partners LLC">Jeff T. Sprague</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Langenberg &amp; Co. LLC">Brian K. Langenberg</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Wells Fargo Advisors LLC">Rich M. Kwas</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Stephen Tusa</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Julian C. Mitchell</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (USA), Inc.">Adam Michael Baumgarten</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">John G. Inch</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and thank you for standing by. Welcome to Emerson's Investor Conference Call. During today's presentation by Emerson management, all parties will be in a listen-only mode. Following the presentation, the conference will be opened for questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> This conference is being recorded today, November 6, 2012.</p>
          <p>Emerson's commentary and responses to your questions may contain forward-looking statements including the company's outlook for the remainder of the year. Information on factors that could cause actual results to vary materially from those discussed today is available at Emerson's most recent Annual Report on Form 10-K as filed with the SEC.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to our host, Patrick Fitzgerald, Director of Investor Relations at Emerson. Go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Joe. I am joined today by David Farr, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of Emerson; and Frank Dellaquila, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer. Today's call is to summarize Emerson's fourth quarter and fiscal year 2012 results. The conference call slide presentation will accompany my comments and is available on Emerson's website at emerson.com. A replay of this conference call and slide presentation will be available on the website after the call for the next three months. I'll start with the highlights of the quarter as shown on page 2 of the conference call slide presentation.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter sales increased 2% to $6.7 billion with underlying sales growing 5%. Robust growth in Process Management was driven by energy investments and recovery of sales deferred from the Thailand flooding from which we have now fully recovered. Record gross profit margin of 41% in the quarter expanded 140 basis points from the prior year and operating profit margin of 20.4% increased 130 basis points. Earnings per share of $0.39 reflects the impact of a $0.72 goodwill impairment charge related to businesses impacted by telecommunications and information technology industry weakness.</p>
          <p>Excluding the impairment charge earnings per share of $1.11 increased 7% from prior year. Yesterday, Emerson's Board of Directors increased the first quarter 2013 dividend by 3%. After down sales and margin in the first half of 2012, our business has executed well to deliver a strong second half amid weakening global economy.</p>
          <p>Next slide, P&amp;L summary. Again, net sales grew 2% and underlying sales increased 5%. Recovery of sales deferred by Thailand flooding help drive strong volume leverage and a 130 basis points of operating profit margin expansion. Net earnings of $282 million includes the $528 million after-tax goodwill impairment charge which was $592 million before tax. We repurchased 5.6 million shares in the quarter for $269 million. Reported EPS declined 61% and excluding the impairment increased 7%.</p>
          <p>Next slide, underlying sales by geography. In the fourth quarter, underlying sales in the U.S. grew 2%, Europe was flat, Asia increased 8% with China flat, Latin America grew 18%, Canada grew 10% and the Middle East and Africa grew 19%. Total underlying sales increased 5%. Currency translation deducted 3% for net sales growth of 2%. Full year 2012 underlying sales grew 3%. Currency translation deducted 2% for net sales growth of 1%.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 5, profitability detail. Gross profit margin of 41% expanded 140 basis points driven by volume leverage, mix and cost containment benefits. As already mentioned, the operating profit margin of 20.4% improved 130 basis points. Goodwill impairment of $592 million and $31 million in currency transaction losses were the primary items bridging to pre-tax earnings of $593 million. Reported tax rate of 49% reflects the low deductibility of the impairment charge. Excluding this, the rate was approximately 30%.</p>
          <p>Next slide, cash flow. Fourth quarter operating cash flow increased 4% and capital expenditures declined slightly resulting in free cash flow growth of 6% with strong conversion from earnings. Working capital as a percent of sales increased from the prior year as higher receivables related to higher end of year sales offset solid inventory performance.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 7, business segment detail. Business segment margin improved 140 basis points reflecting strong volume leverage and cost containment benefits. Changes in corporate expense were primarily driven by the impairment and higher stock compensation compared to prior year. Reported pre-tax earning margin declined from the impairment. Excluding this, pre-tax margin expanded 100 basis points.</p>
          <p>Next slide, Process Management. Process Management net sales grew 18% and underlying sales grew 21%. By region, U.S. was up 16%, Asia up 21%, Europe up 11%, Latin America up 46% and Middle East and Africa up 42%. Strong conversion of backlog from the Thailand flooding supply chain disruption helped sales, along with robust investments in the oil and gas, chemical and power industries. Segment margin of 24.3% expanded 200 basis points primarily driven by volume leverage and cost reduction benefits.</p>
          <p>Full year 2012 underlying sales were 15% for Process Management with margin at record levels. Continued end market strength is expected to support solid momentum into 2013.</p>
          <p>Next slide, Industrial Automation. Industrial Automation net sales declined 6% with underlying sales down 2%. By geography, the U.S. and Asia were flat, Europe was down 5%, Latin America up 3%, and Middle East and Africa down 20%. End markets were mixed across the segment with the power-generating alternators and industrial motors business weakest. Underlying sales grew modestly in the fluid automation, electrical distribution and mechanical power transmission businesses. Segment margin of 17.5% expanded 280 basis points benefiting primarily from cost containment programs and lower restructuring expense.</p>
          <p>Profitability was strong, resulting from a well-positioned cost structure and favorable mix. In the near-term, the European fiscal crisis will remain a challenge for Industrial Automation.</p>
          <p>Next slide, Network Power. Net sales declined 4% and underlying sales decreased 3% with the U.S. down 7%, Asia up 5%, Europe down 9%, Latin America down 4% and Middle East and Africa down 14%. Global telecom and information technology weakness persisted resulting in a double-digit sales decline in the embedded computing and power business. Data center end markets were mixed among geographies but challenging overall especially in Europe. Segment margin of 11.6% declined 190 basis points due to volume de-leverage and other cost increases but improved sequentially 130 basis points. As mentioned in this morning's press release, the embedded computing and power business continues to face unique market and technology challenges. We have decided to pursue strategic alternatives including a potential sale of this business.</p>
          <p>Next slide, Climate Technologies. Climate Technologies net sales decreased 4% and underlying sales declined 3%. By region, the U.S. was down 4%, Asia down 7%, Europe down 1%, Latin America up 6% and Middle East and Africa up 17%.</p>
          <p>U.S. residential, commercial and refrigeration markets were weak especially in the transportation refrigeration market. Asia reflected mixed trends across markets and businesses with China down 7% and Europe remained soft.</p>
          <p>Segment margin of 18.5% expanded 150 basis points despite the sales decrease on a well-positioned cost structure and favorable mix. Global end markets remain stable but soft, a trend expected to continue into the first half of 2013.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 12, Commercial and Residential Solutions. Commercial and Residential Solutions net sales were unchanged with underlying sales up 5% as the Knaack business divestiture deducted 4% and currency translation deducted 1%. By region, the U.S. was up 2%, Asia up 17%, Europe flat, Latin America up 11% and Middle East and Africa up 35%.</p>
          <p>The commercial storage and food waste disposal businesses reported strong growth as U.S. construction and renovation demand remain steady. Segment margin of 21.9% increased 130 basis points benefiting primarily from cost containment programs. We expect North America residential end markets to continue to improve into 2013 resulting in good sales growth at solid profitability for the Commercial and Residential Solutions segment.</p>
          <p>Next slide, fiscal 2012 highlights. As briefly mentioned, full year net sales grew 1% and underlying sales increased 3% with emerging markets increasing to 36% of total sales.</p>
          <p>Record gross profit and operating profit margin reflect continued innovation, portfolio management and cost repositioning efforts. Reported EPS of $2.67 reflects a $0.72 goodwill impairment charge. Excluding this charge, EPS of $3.39 grew 3%. We also completed the 56th consecutive year of dividend increases with 16% growth in 2012. After a challenging first half of 2012, we finished the year with strong execution and solid operational momentum moving into 2013.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 14, the 2013 outlook. Global economic growth continues to trend downward but still moderately positive. The pace of growth is unusually weak for this stage of a recovery cycle and uncertainty in the U.S., China and Europe is resulting in cautious business investment. At present, there is no obvious catalyst for economic growth acceleration. Based on current global economic conditions, the 2013 outlook is as follows: reported and underlying sales growth of 0% to 5%, EBIT margin 10 basis points to 20 basis points of improvement, earnings per share growth mid-to-high single digits from a base of $3.39 in 2012. We expect the majority of sales and earnings growth to occur in the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>And with that, I will now turn it over to David Farr.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Thank you there, Pat. First, I want to thank everybody for joining us today and we appreciate your interest and your support of Emerson. Secondly, I also want to congratulate Frank Dellaquila. The Board today promoted Frank to EVP and CFO, an EVP title and so he's now gone up a notch and his conversation will be adjusted downward accordingly. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>...you're always welcome for that. And then most importantly &#x2013; by far most importantly, I want to thank the entire global organization for delivering extremely strong second half of our fiscal year after the unique and enormous shock that we took in our supply chain for many of our businesses coming from the Thailand flood.</p>
          <p>As you all know, the first half of this year was down in sales, earnings margins and we rallied the folks around the world. The organization fought back and recovered nicely with a very strong second half and I want to toast and thank all of the individuals around this company who made that happen. Especially led by Frank and Ed Monser and the business leaders because without their effort, we would not have made that second half happen and I appreciate that. It gets us into great position relative to the year where we face right now in 2013 with again a lot of uncertainty, but I'll talk a little bit about that.</p>
          <p>Unfortunately, this year in 2012, the underlying volumes of the company due to the weakening economies as the year progressed, was significantly lower than we thought originally. We ended up the year a little bit over 2.5% underlying sales growth. Stronger second half because of the floods impact, but overall, it's basically down four points from what we thought we are going to see and we presented in February of 2012. So a much weaker economy impacted us and then we had the floods and it really had a challenging situation for the whole company.</p>
          <p>As I look at the fourth calendar quarter, there's a lot of uncertainty out there between the whole fiscal cliff here in the United States, the European situation, and the continued impact of that recession and slowdown and I would say stagnation in Europe; the Japanese situation, which is clearly uncertain and also weakening. And then, a little bit of uncertainty relative to China and what the next-generation leaders are going to do relative to the globe &#x2013; their global investments and also investments to stimulate their economy.</p>
          <p>As we look at current order pace, it's a little bit weaker. Our backlog still very positive. We are clearly in looking at uncertain and challenging business times for the next six months and we are going to plan accordingly. As we look at our current makeup of the year, given the very weak first half last year because of the Thailand flood, we expect again this year to be a first half-second half with 70% to 80% of our earnings per share, I'll say it again, 70% to 80% of our earnings per share in the first half of this year. And obviously, the remaining part in the second half. It will be very difficult at this point in time to say what's going to happen in the fourth quarter, given the fact that people are being very cautious and I'm also a bit concerned that people will shut down early in the month of December on &#x2013; based on inventories or weak demand. And so I am very nervous about the fourth calendar quarter.</p>
          <p>We still see continued growth in 2013, pretty much in line to what we see this year &#x2013; we saw this year. We do not see a global recession at this point in time. We are looking at as we talk about 1% to 5% underlying sales growth with a good midpoint about exactly what we did this year, around that 2.5%, 2.6% level. That's a good midpoint. We are seeing a current forecast level and pace of gross fixed investment of weaker in 2013 on a fiscal year basis than we saw in 2012.</p>
          <p>We clearly have the uncertainty with the fiscal cliff and that one bothers us right now relative to what's going on. Even if they do resolve the fiscal cliff and I have no idea how they're going to do that, I personally believe the spending in the U.S. will be negatively impacted both at the government level and then also at the consumer level if they go about raising taxes.</p>
          <p>So our plan right now is have slight margin improvement, EPS in the mid to single high &#x2013; single digits with strong leverage, in particular, coming from Process business and recovering Residential and Commercial Solutions business. We will give more detailed segment information at our February meeting, not today. I gave you more than I normally would give you in the fiscal year guidance, but that's where we sit at this point in time.</p>
          <p>On the positive headwinds and tailwinds, we see right now the big headwind for us right now is pension. With the discount rate at 4%, unbelievably low for U.S. discount for pension, we will have a negative P&amp;L impact of $65 million on our pension. We are in good shape with the pension, but clearly with the low discount rates we have to fund additional monies and we have to expense that and also put the cash in. But the cash funding would be about the same level we did last year, around $150 million. Just the pension expense will be higher.</p>
          <p>Restructuring, we are in good shape. We have gone through two very, very big years. In 2013, we're looking at restructuring in the $70 million to $80 million level, down from current 2012 and then also down from the 2011 expenditures.</p>
          <p>We do have the new, what we call the performance share, the four-year program, which we have every so often, we have an overlap year. And this &#x2013; and 2013 will be an overlap year. The Compensation Committee and the board awarded the performance share awards, which are a four-year program. They awarded those and there will be about $120 million impact on the year as we have an overlap &#x2013; the overlap year. It's clearly depending upon the stock price. And if the stock price goes up, that number obviously goes up. But that's good for everybody as long as the stock price goes up.</p>
          <p>But net-net, we're looking at a year pretty much like we just faced without the catastrophes. We are underlying sales growth low single-digit, some good leverage, good cash flow, strategic investments, and running in an environment where right now that everyone is concerned about what &#x2013; where the economic growth is going to come from. Fundamentally, I believe the United States has to lead the world out of this recession, this global downturn. And we do have the capabilities in North America &#x2013; in Mexico, U.S., and the United States to lead this economy out for the world. But until that happens, we will stay and I would say in a very sluggish economic environment at this point in time.</p>
          <p>So with that, I would like to turn the floor over to questions and open the line to ask questions of either Pat, Frank or myself. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Steven Winoker with Sanford Bernstein. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Steve, before you ask the question I do &#x2013; Frank Dellaquila just pointed something out that I do need to clarify very quickly, 70% to 80% of our EPS increase, not a total EPS, but 70% to 80% of our EPS increase for next year will be happening in the first half. Thank you, Frank. Not the &#x2013; increase, not the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I know, it's the growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I just wanted to &#x2013; Frank pointed out and I misspoke and thank God, I'm not on live TV somewhere around the world or something like that, you know?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Steve, what's your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So first one, just again on the guidance, the pension and the stock-based comp if I put them together, feel like 4% to 5% impact of &#x2013; on growth, EPS growth for next year. And if that's true, then at the high end of your guidance, talk about mid-single-digits, 5% top-line, high-single-digit 9% bottom-line plus I'd add back the pension and stock-based, so now I'm talking about low to mid-teens EPS growth off of that 5% if I ex out the pension and stock-based. How should I &#x2013; how are you getting that much leverage or how are you thinking about that much leverage in the business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, let's clarify what I consider high to mid. I would consider 7% a high mid-single-digit EPS growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I grow &#x2013; if we grow underlying sales at 5%, we will get more than two-tenths leverage. Pretty simple.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I know you guys have a tendency to run, you're sort of like people in my family say 'oh, you go ahead and spend' and you just run right up to the top number to the credit card. So you just ran right up to 9%. And so what I classify high single digit maybe a little bit different than your definition. So your credit line's stopping let's say at maybe 7.5%, okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Dave. I promise not to spend it before you deliver it. How's that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You got it. Thank you very much. I just want to make sure you understand that credit card balance there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Second, maybe a higher level question on the portfolio. I mean given your comments in embedded and so seeing that exit and given the M&amp;A environment, right, what &#x2013; how do you see the portfolio changing and transforming over, say, the next 12 months as opposed to longer term? Or 12 to 18 then, what is, you know?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I &#x2013; at this point in time, our focus, well obviously clearly find the right partnership and proper way to exit the embedded power and computing. We'll do this, as you know, we have &#x2013; we'll do this in an orderly process, one, to protect that business and also to maximize the value for the shareholders. It will take us throughout most of this year to do that.</p>
          <p>And then relative to the acquisition front right now, we're looking primarily at small &#x2013; again, small bolt-on-type acquisitions, nothing significant. We're planning, as we review with the Board today, basically around that $500 million level again. So there's not going to be anything structurally changing at this point in time. The folks in Network Power systems are very much focused on integrating and getting that business back on track. The Process guys have their hands full with underlying growth. Our Climate Technology folks really have their hands full right now relative to sorting through how that market's going to recover in some time in 2013. So very much focused on status quo, nothing significant from the acquisition front at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can I just follow that up on the data center; with the Board review when you talked about the difference between embedded computing and power versus data centers, even though we're in a weak data center timeframe right now, what were some of the major &#x2013; you talked about strategic and market differences &#x2013; when you talk about those very different segments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll talk about that in February. That's a little bit more than we want to discuss in a phone call like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, it's &#x2013; there's a lot going on in the data center world right now with, obviously with the new hyper-scales and the &#x2013; the hyper-scale data centers and also with the &#x2013; basically what's going on in the telecommunications data center infrastructure, stuff like that. That's something we'll get into in February where we can throw some information [up and give you that.</p>
          <p>But I think in the short-term, the data center marketplace will be still quite, I think will be challenged because there's not a lot of growth going on out there and there's a lot of fundamental change happening in the marketplace. So we're looking at, I think, in the next six months, probably a challenging data center environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Steve. Good forward &#x2013; look forward to seeing you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Eli Lustgarten with Longbow Securities. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Eli, you out there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'm here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm here, okay. Just, what was the underlying growth of Process in the fourth quarter if you etch out the catch-up from the Thailand? I mean where &#x2013; what kind of comparison are we looking at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean it &#x2013; what was the total underlying sales growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was up 21%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>21%? I think if you &#x2013; it's going to be high double-digit, I mean, you're probably talking &#x2013; I mean we &#x2013; trying to track that, Eli, to be honest, is sort of like catching sand that's falling in the air. But it's clear, you know I would say you're probably taking about $100 million, or &#x2013; $100 million out? $120 million off that so you're talking about high double-digits. So we had extremely strong underlying sales growth even ex that business and all that, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So we're looking at a double-digit capability for 2013 on the basis of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think &#x2013; I talked about this before. Right now, the backlog, the order pace says that we should be able to do that. We &#x2013; I'm always concerned about projects being slowed. We have not seen that yet. Our order pace, our backlog demand, everything, still very strong and then through this month here. However, I think there's a point if there's some uncertainty and let's say that something does happen to the U.S. economy and it does take a dramatic drop off, then you could see some of that slowdown, which we don't see right now. But I think that the pace of business, the backlog would say, yes, you could do north of 10% again. I am right now are &#x2013; probably would say more cautiously that in my base forecast, which would be that mid &#x2013; that 2.5% underlying growth rate, we can probably do more like 7%, 8%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. With the strategic alternative for Network Power, the focus has to be how are you going to replace &#x2013; anything you sell these days unfortunately is dilutive...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...so if you intend to be buying back shares throughout the year to offset the eventual dilution of that or wait till it happens? Or do you hope you're making acqui &#x2013; enough acquisitions to offset? Or how do you plan to offset the dilution of that because that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We intend, at this point in time, our current plan with the cash flow generation is to buy &#x2013; we're planning around $800 million of shares, share back &#x2013; buyback. We will start within a couple of days here; after we file our reports and we have the clear of this marketplace, we'll go back out. We stopped about at the end of the fiscal year because of the impairment charge, we did not want to go out during the time period that we knew that we had an impairment charge. So we will go back out here in the coming days to start buying, but &#x2013; our target is to buy around $800 million shares this year, which will clearly offset any dilution we have from this business. And depending on, if we have more cash we'll &#x2013; and the market says that &#x2013; we'll actually buy more. But right now, that's what we're looking at, Eli.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And we will get the details of how much creep we have from the incentive program overlap or so, or how much you'll be issuing in tax rate change? And any of that would change at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean the tax rate number, I'll give you exact. I mean right now, we planned last year at 32%. We did a little bit better than that as the year closes out. Right now, I would assume we're around that 32% again. From the share count, there's very few new shares going out. The share, from the new performance share program, we have to earn it to get them. So right now, our share count will drop based on buying $800 million shares back, so our share count dropped this year. Frank, how many shares did it drop?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About 20 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About 20 million. So our shares dropped this year on average, and I would expect our shares to drop again next year on average depending on obviously what that stock price is. But our share count has been dropping year-by-year as we buy the stock back. We are not a big issuer of stock, we have &#x2013; we obviously have employee stock programs, but we're not a big issuer of stock.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Eli, all the best to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question is from the line of Scott Davis with Barclays. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Dave, have you seen any evidence of any kind of backlash in China from the Huawei comments that Congress made about not wanting to buy Chinese telecom equipment. I mean is there anything that puts your business at risk over there and just general backlash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we have not seen any backlash. We have extremely good relationships within China. The Congress comments on Huawei obviously were &#x2013; are quite strong and obviously from an all American corporate perspective, but we have not seen any big issue there. They know that, that was not us talking; that's the Congress talking, it's a little bit different situation. So our relationship in China is very good. I think that the key issue for us right now is this new leadership that's coming on board. As we have talked about, where are the investment dollars going to come? And I think their degree of freedom that they have of investing that money is less than they've had historically. So we are looking for &#x2013; in our case this year, we're probably looking for 5% to 10% type of growth this year in our China businesses after a weak 2012. And it's not uncommon for us to come back and we see some of those marketplaces already starting to come back, some stability there already.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and that's helpful. Second, just on Industrial Automation, you had a nice improvement in margins. It wasn't really clear in the prepared remarks how much you can really attribute to favorable mix versus cost. And if it's cost, how much of it's structural cost? I guess the other way of asking the question is, is this business taking a step-up in kind of structural margins because of some cost actions you've taken, or is this more temporary?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've taken, as you know &#x2013; up to the very end, we've had a lot of restructuring in our high cost structure both here in the U.S. and also in Western Europe in the Industrial Automation business. So the majority of the margin improvement is a structural change and is &#x2013; we should see a good margin next year; we've had a huge step-up there this year. We also had the Byrd Amendment moneys that helped us a little bit. So they have to overcome that which I think was around $40 million some odd &#x2013; $43 million. But there &#x2013; I would expect them to have a slight margin improvement again next year. And they're not going to &#x2013; you're not going to see much growth in that business in the next two or three quarters. But they have structurally improved the operating performance of that company back to where it has been historically. So I think you're going to see pretty good margin from them, though the marketplace &#x2013; because they're very strong in Europe and obviously some of the other markets have weakened a little bit &#x2013; so I expect these guys going to be fighting for volume all year long. But they have their cost in great shape right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Helpful. Thank you. I'll pass it on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome. All the best to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Deane Dray with Citi Research. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Deane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Dave, just wanted to make sure you did vote today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I did. I actually voted. Yes. I guarantee I voted. I voted a couple weeks ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I heard you say a couple of times.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple times? Well, you know, I try &#x2013; I can't do that. But I did &#x2013; I voted a couple weeks ago. My son was home for his break &#x2013; fall break and I took him down there. I voted absentee and he voted &#x2013; because he's at school, so. I knew I was going to be at the Board meeting tonight, there was no way I could get down there this late, so I did already.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, good to hear. Now, I was hoping you could expand the comments on climate. Pretty mixed results across all the end markets or more likely more negative across all the markets. But then the outlook on the commercial and resi side is you're expecting resi to improve. So how do you get resi improving without a better look at resi HVAC?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, that is the issue. We fundamentally believe that there will be an improvement in residential spending in North America in 2013, ignoring any economic shock or huge drop off in the U.S. economy. The issue for us right now is getting stability within the China market, which we're starting to see from that business, which is important, which we haven't seen. I do not see any recovery in Europe at this point in time in our climate technology. On the transport side, which has been the most recent deterioration in the business pace from a global transportation both in trucking and then in also container, that marketplace is in a downward cycle. And that probably will go for another 6 to 12 months.</p>
          <p>So at this point in time, we would expect the industry to stay very tight, be very lean and then come the typical recovery period which would be more March, April timeframe, I'm anticipating that the housing market continues to solidify and we'll start seeing some recovery in our climate technology business in the second half of the year. In the first six months, it will be still a challenge for these guys and they've got their costs in line and I &#x2013; there's not going to be any growth, it's just a very tough marketplace all around the world. That's how we look at it right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is there any comments regarding the impact of the storm, both negative and part of the rebuild?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From our own underlying business there's obviously there was very minor impact. Obviously, we have businesses up there doing the day-to-day. We obviously have our service organization in there right now working with the key customers. Would there be any &#x2013; you're not going to see any significant impact both in sales and profitability both positively or negatively, I would say net-net, in the next three, four months, it will be positive and in the long-term obviously as they rebuild that will be helpful. So we have short-term things that will be positive for us. But it's in the ordinary course of the business. So it's a net positive for us at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you can't quantify that from there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I can't because it's hard to say. It's not something that you can quantify, it's sort of like trying to quantify back in the 2008 stimulus number. I mean that was sort of a waste of effort by everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question is from the line of Shannon O'Callaghan with Nomura. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Shannon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Dave, so the 41% gross margin, obviously a big number. I mean you have some favorability in Process going on in the quarter. I mean how do you view the sustainability of that type of gross margin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I decided I was going to get some tea. I just walked out, you know, my <mark type="indiscernible" /> (34:23), I was wandering over to get some tea. What I would say right now is that based on the current mix of businesses, based on where our cost structure is sitting right now and the current price-cost structure we see; we're probably anticipating another 50 basis points improvement in GP margin in 2013. Based on everything I see right now, how we finished. I mean the 41% is based on a very high volume and a catch-up and a good leverage point, but I see right now the run rate &#x2013; my gut tells me as I finish that year out and we wrap up 2013, we're going to be looking around a 40.5% GP margin next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on restructuring, I mean you did a $119 million this year, an elevated year. You're already seeing some good payback from prior restructuring. What do you think your year-over-year benefit's going to be in 2013 from the actions you've taken this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From a &#x2013; I mean I don't &#x2013; normally I don't quantify that, but it &#x2013; from the standpoint of &#x2013; if you look at the businesses both in the Industrial Automation and then also Network Power Systems, you're going to continue to see a better margin from that restructuring. So you're &#x2013; we'll be getting a good payback this year. I mean my gut tells me that we will spend $70 million or $80 million and we'll get a little bit more back than that in savings based on what we spent last year. You won't &#x2013; if you spend $70 million, $80 million this year, you don't &#x2013; you get a little bit back, but we're going to get a good carryover from what we spent last year. So we should be well north of that $70 million, $80 million in benefits and that's obviously part of where I'm getting my GP margin improvement. That's why I made that statement because I see at least 50 basis points of GP margin improvement going into this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. That helps. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Jeff Sprague. Just one moment, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeff, you out there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm having trouble with the line. Go ahead, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Can you guys hear me okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we can hear you, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Sorry about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's okay. You gave me time to get my tea.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Make sure you're not putting in anything in that tea. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I talked to the board a lot yesterday so my throat's a little stressed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just thinking about the comment about there is no obvious catalyst and we need leadership in the U.S. I mean not to, kind of, get on the soapbox here or anything but you're kind of in a defensive crouch. A lot of companies are kind of in a defensive crouch. I mean, how dramatically do you think actually things could change if there's a favorable outcome in the election and then how quickly could it change and is it right to characterize you and corporate America kind of in a defensive crouch?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we definitely are in a defensive crouch. We have &#x2013; as you know I refer to it, not a defensive crouch. I talk about the range, you hear me talk about pulling the range. So we've got the range way back. What we're going to need, not only do we need, we'll obviously within the next 24 hours and hopefully sooner than later get clarity on the election, and who is going to be the next President of United States, this great country. What we then need is, okay, we need the leaders of this country to get together and sort out how are we going to fix the long-term fiscal structure of our government. We can't afford what we are doing right now and we have to fix that. The leaders need to see that. And I think so there will be either a great &#x2013; depending on what party you are involved with, great amount of excitement and then there will be or there will be a great ugh.</p>
          <p>However, the big issue for all of us is what are we going to do in Washington relative to not only the issue relative to this nightmare fiscal cliff that's been set up by the inability of the Congress and the President to deal with this issue. So we also have to lay out what is the next 20-year or 15, 20-year program to recover this country from a fiscal standpoint, get the spending back on track, get the income back on track and to encourage long-term investments. So you're going to see business CEOs will say okay, we now know who the President is, okay, now what are you going to do in Washington. And then based on that, I think, if you had &#x2013; if we see a very positive pro-growth, pro-U.S. investment environment, you would see some time in the second half of 2013 starting to see things flow. People will not get carried away and start to say, hey, I'm go and spend &#x2013; up my spending like 20% because of this. You will see some impact in the second half of 2013, which would tee up, I think, a much stronger 2014, 2015. Jeff that's just as how I see it right now. And I don't see any, any &#x2013; okay Dave spend 20% more next year because of election results tonight or 20% less. I don't see any impact. However, what I want to see is resolution to getting this country back on a sound fiscal spending income track. Period. And that's what CEOs want.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. That's helpful. Just back to Network Power, so you actually exited at a pretty good margin rate. I mean should we &#x2013; so is restructuring going on there, there's some seasonality, I mean, do you think about pulling on this Q4 rate or do we step down and build our way up going forward? How do we think about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we &#x2013; from the standpoint of Network Power historically, the first quarter margins are &#x2013; I mean we will &#x2013; we've obviously got some margins going the right way, but first quarter margin will go back a little bit, but we will &#x2013; we are not going to go back to a level that we saw last year in that first quarter. So I'm looking, Frank show me the numbers right now, so we're look &#x2013; we should see a continuing improvement in the first quarter depending on the rate of restructuring, but we should see continuing improvement in the profitability of this business as we go &#x2013; the whole Network Power segment into this first quarter, second quarter.</p>
          <p>We saw sequential improvement in the third, we saw sequential improvement in the fourth. Yes, it was down versus prior year but they have their cost structure in place and we've seen a reasonable stability relative to the order pace. So I feel that we're going to see continuing improvement throughout the year and then we'll end up the year at a better profit margin for this business than obviously we finish this year, again moving back up towards &#x2013; I'm trying to get the whole Network Power &#x2013; I mean I &#x2013; we want to get back up into that above 10% range. So hopefully, we'll get to that 11%, 12% top of the range. That's what I see right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the write-off was solely un-amortizing goodwill. There's no amortizing intangibles that went away as part of the write-off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I mean I always wish they only wrote-off the intangibles, but unfortunately when they go through and revalue the business, they do everything, both intangibles and also the goodwill. So this &#x2013; there won't be any change in that intangibles delta that &#x2013; Frank, was there any change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's a goodwill write-off, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Goodwill. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Only goodwill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's one of those things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just finally, we can do the math but I should take quite literally the notion that an $8 million share repurchase can offset the dilution?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, $800 million; $800 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, that's what I meant, $800 million can set off the dilution from exiting embedded power?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Easily.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Easily. Okay. That's what I thought. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Brian Langenberg with Langenberg &amp; Company. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a couple of things. First, Network Power, can you talk a little bit whether mix helped you or hurt you understanding you did a lot with structuring. Second of all, can you talk about the benefit or what have you of price cost and climate in the quarter? Then the third question, I noticed that Q &#x2013; quarter-over-quarter, receivables were up almost $400 million, sales were up a little bit over $200 million just walk us through the puts and takes in the working capital, please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. The first one is the mix did not help us and Network Power in this quarter. The climate business &#x2013; what I call the precision cooling business really did &#x2013; did not have a good quarter so therefore that's a good margin business that did hurt us. The mix overall when I look at the Network Power would not be a good sign. So we overcame bad mix and through the restructuring and the efforts there we did get an improvement in profitability. So that was the negative for us. Relative to price cost and climate, at this point in time, the price cost was slightly green for us in the &#x2013; our fourth fiscal quarter or the third calendar quarter. The &#x2013; it will continue to be slightly green in this quarter coming up and then we are going through the negotiations and most likely that will go back into other neutral type of mode at that point in time. But right now with the material decline and net material inflation and the price increases we had in place we are slightly green. So that helped us a little bit, but it wasn't huge, let's put it that way, slightly green. And the third question you asked, oh, yeah, oh, receivables, okay, that is an issue. We had &#x2013; couple of things happened to us as we had a very strong last basically 40 days of shipments as we made this quarter, as we geared up to make this quarter. So we had a lot of sales shipped out in the last couple of weeks in particular that we are collecting those receivables now and the quarter end of this year on Sunday. So our cut off for collections for us with the banks is basically Friday. So we have a lot of shipments going out as we drove to make &#x2013; drive that backlog down and make the quarter and the sales. Obviously, everything above or nothing illegal just from the standpoint, that's how the quarter unfolded, and that caused us our receivables to explode and you'll see we will have a good first quarter cash flow and that receivable numbers to start winding back down. There's nothing extraordinary. We did not &#x2013; from bad debt standpoint or any &#x2013; and considering that we're in good shape, we've analyzed the heck out of it. We have nominal bad debt in this company. We're talking nominal. And so we're in pretty good shape as though we did have a huge surge in receivables as you pointed out. Inventory...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...payables were in good shape.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Rich Kwas with Wells Fargo Securities. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Good afternoon, Dave. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Rich.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mix for Process, how are you thinking about that for 2013? You had a pretty good year in 2012. I know there's some disruption but how are you thinking about MRO versus solutions, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now, with a record backlog starting the year with very strong North American investments in oil and gas and we have still pretty good mix. So I would expect, we are sitting at record levels of profitability. I would expect that we would still be able to get a slight improvement based on the current pace of business and based on the current mix. So I feel &#x2013; as I said, I think it was Eli asked me the question about if you just look at the raw numbers, you could say we should be able to do 10% plus in Process growth next year. Though I have, in my base plan of that basically midpoint of that 2.5% to 2.6% I am talking about underlying sales growth, I think that Process could have a slowdown and some push-outs. So I'm looking more in that 7% to 8%. But right now, the mix is really good for us and obviously the technology mix and MROs I mean that helps our margins as you can tell both in the GP and the OP levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. And then a question for Frank on the stock comp. So when you look back to fiscal 2010 you had a big increase in corporate and other and that was the last year we had the incentive comp. If the stock price stays where it is today, what's the kind of the bogey in terms of the year-over-year increase on the incentive comp?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>$120 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About $110 million, $120 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>$110 million, $120 million, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It depends on if the stock price stays right here but we're hoping the stock gets up to $75 and then that number would be a lot larger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, thanks. That's all I had. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Steve Tusa with JPMorgan. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just trying to reconcile all the moving parts here. This year, you guys did, I guess, 3% to 5% EPS growth on about 3% underlying. You said this is going to be somewhat of a similar year. You've got the stock comp, you've got the pension, I guess, offset by a little bit lower restructuring. So I guess the &#x2013; what kind of &#x2013; despite those headwinds, what kind of gets you back to a similar year this year even to the high end? Is a combination of volume and then, I guess, restructuring saves in the business? I'm just curious as to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...if you did 3% EPS this year on 3% underlying, why at 3% underlying are you going to do better than 3% EPS this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple things. One, we will not have &#x2013; there is a lot of cost of disruption in that business this year as we try to recover it and try to recover from that standpoint of the Thailand floods. Secondly, as I look at it right now the mix that we'll see, we see our growth coming next year again from Process, but also from our residential &#x2013; Commercial and Residential business which is also a pretty good profitability market. And I also look at just from a mix standpoint; I see a reasonable level of margin improvement this year. And our thoughts as we get higher volumes, I think we'll go towards that higher or that high single digit and in the middle, I mean, I think we will do a little bit better from the leverage standpoint. So I feel at that 2.5%, we'll do a little bit better than we did this year and that's where it comes from, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So when you say mid to high-single-digits, you're talking about something like 4% to 7%, is how we should think about it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe 7.4%. If you're going to give that credit card, I can't remember who asked me that question, I take that credit card up to $7,400; but it's definitely not going to be a $10,000 credit line there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And then on the EPS growth, just to make sure we're calibrated here, there's a lot of moving parts in the first quarter. But you said 70% to 80% of the EPS growth which, I guess, implies about 10% growth in the first half and I would assume the first quarter is obviously the strongest given the comp you have, but I guess is that kind of a linear step-down from 1Q to 2Q?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Or is it 1Q <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:37)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I said, we're saying 78% of the &#x2013; obviously the delta increase next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so it'll be in the first half. Now, the issue really boils down to &#x2013; I am very &#x2013; as I said in my comments, I am very nervous about the fourth calendar quarter. I still believe &#x2013; I believe the 78%, I am very nervous and I &#x2013; that's why I have not given any guidance like on a quarterly basis because I am little bit nervous that we have a significant customer base that we could really slow down in the month of December on it and because of the uncertainty out there and especially if we get into a discussion post-election about this whole the fiscal cliff and restructuring of what's going to happen in the U.S. government and this thing gets into a logjam and all of sudden you start seeing that they are going to let this thing happen. You're going to &#x2013; that &#x2013; I think that will create a lot of &#x2013; even more uncertainty from the company standpoint and the customer standpoint and it could really slow down that market in December. So I am a little bit nervous about giving what I would call EPS estimates for the quarter because of that. I just &#x2013; I would agree with you the first quarter if you look at this from a pure economic standpoint, we would say that would be a &#x2013; my biggest increase would be that first quarter because it was the shock last year. But I'm also very nervous about the uncertainty around this fourth calendar quarter. So I feel good that we will have 78%, it's hard for me to say that I'm going to have more in that first and less in the second but I'd tell you. So I know I'm not helping you much but I am just telling I'd be very careful there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just one more question on the order rates. They bounced around, it sounded like you had a &#x2013; sounds like you had a lot of book and ship in the September quarter, because the order rates were I mean reasonably negative on a three-year trailing basis. How is kind of October playing out so far?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have not seen October, but what you did see in September, we reduced our backlog. You're going to see our backlog dropped significantly in the month of September, in the fourth quarter. So we had built a backlog, as you know all year long and the whole issue was to get that backlog down. I still believe as the total company, we ended up the year with a little bit higher backlog, but we significantly reduced it. Frank, do you know how much we reduced the backlog roughly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple hundred million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple hundred million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think about $200 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, let's say, right now, Steve, I don't have the exact number, say $200 million is the placed order, that's how much we reduced that backlog.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (51:52)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, in the 4th quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So just assume around $200 million that we reduced in the quarter the backlog. So a lot of that improvement came from &#x2013; not from the current orders but the backlog.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All the best to you, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Julian Mitchell with Credit Suisse. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot. Yes, the first question was really on the margin progression. I mean you talk about 10 basis points to 20 basis points of operating margin growth in fiscal 2013. You grew about 20 bps in fiscal 2012 with a similar revenue growth rate. It sounds like the gross margin should be up 50 bps. It sounds like mix should be good in 2013 from Process and some of the construction facing businesses. So what is it that sort of dampens that drop through on the EBIT margin line aside from just the pension and stock comp issues, or is it really just those two things <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:50)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those are the two issues right there. Those are the two big issues at this point in time, Julian. As if we &#x2013; as we get above that 2.5% to 3%, we will have pretty good leverage and obviously I think that &#x2013; and then that margin would be a little bit &#x2013; that margin delta little bit &#x2013; be a little bit higher there. I mean there is some moving parts going on at this point in time, but right now, I think we're looking at a little bit better progression relative to growth from the standpoint of looking at the disruption and we're looking &#x2013; going in the year with a &#x2013; our cost structure in very good shape right now. We have a reasonable backlog. And so I think we're operating right now &#x2013; is pretty good. I am more concerned about the external shocks going on in the global economy more than anything else at this point in time and how that that will impact us for a month or two as things get sorted out. So that's why I am being a little cautious there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then just on the restructuring side of things, I mean you said that 2013 will be a bit lower run rate than 2011 and 2012, but if you're very worried about the top-line why wouldn't you keep going at an aggressive restructuring cost?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because I think &#x2013; we &#x2013; as I've laid out the restructuring we needed to get accomplished and what we think we can get accomplished with next year, $70 million, $75 million is the right number for us and I would say that, that &#x2013; right now as I look at what we see going forward in the next couple of years, that probably is going to be the range we're at right now as we manage. I don't have anything that forces me to accelerate that even higher. We've had two very big years of restructuring; actually two and a half very big years of restructuring, and so now I'm in the mode of trying to stabilize this and say, okay, let's get a pay back for my shareholders in that restructuring.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks. And then just a very quick follow-up, Network Power, the sort of the decremental margin was pretty big in Q4, and you call out some cost increases as a reason for that. I just wanted to check what those were.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have that off the top of my head. Pat, do you...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, it's nothing in particular. It's just kind of typical business inflation that occurs and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...nothing out of the ordinary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Take care, Julian. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of John Inch with Deutsche Bank. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And it looks like John disconnected. Could you re-queue, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, you out there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>He's out of the queue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's go to the next caller.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's go to the next guy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Mike Wood with Macquarie Group. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Adam in for Mike. You talked about looking for 5% to 10% growth in China businesses in next year. Can you talk about what that growth was in fiscal 2012 and sort of which business will be driving that growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Negative. It was negative by 4%. It's in the &#x2013; we gave that number out today. It's minus 4%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can you talk about which businesses you expect to be strongest next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would expect the Process business to be stronger next year based on the record level of bookings that we had in China in the second half of fiscal 2012. I expect to see a recovery in our Climate Technology business, which was hit pretty hard last year. I expect to see whether some of the investments I'm seeing right now will impact our Network Power China business. So I expect to see a reasonable recovery there. And I don't expect to see much recovery in Industrial Automation at this point in time. So that's what I see at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have John back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, are you out there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one moment. With Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Dave, can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I can hear you, but you've been running around outside and you're trying to escape on us, huh?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I've got magicJack and it doesn't really work for these phone calls.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I won't make any comment about that. But magicJack? Whose fixed line are you stealing off of right now, yeah? Okay, John, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just storm survival tactics. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's true. I apologize. I forgot about that. You had extraordinary circumstance. So I thought maybe you tapped into your neighbor's line or something like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I still did that. Okay. Process, Dave, you made a comment about you haven't seen projects slowing in Process. I wanted to ask you because ex-Process, you have seen project deferrals I think bigger projects amongst oil and gas types of activities. So if you're not really seeing that, suggests you're taking share or maybe there is something about the Process industry that's perhaps different than flow or other aspects of that? Could you talk about a bit, like the sustainability of your oil and gas piece in Process, what are you thinking right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now, based on the current order pace and the current backlog we see in the execution, our &#x2013; right now, our oil and gas business should see another very good year. As you know, I don't look at from one &#x2013; a 12-month period, a one quarter share gain, but I think as you look back at the last two years, where we've had 15% plus growth in sales in a good marketplace, but I think that you're going to see that we did pretty well, we held our own and maybe did a little bit better than average. So I feel good about the position in right now. I feel extremely good about the technology, I feel good about our record levels and investments we're making there. So we are obviously &#x2013; every once in a &#x2013; you get in the zone and we're in the zone right now and sometimes you fall out of the zone. But we're in the zone, let's put it that way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That makes sense. Dave, if you haven't seen October in a lot of detail, I'm just curious given kind of what's transpired in the economy, there was some slowing significantly amongst other companies in September, why do you still think that there is no U.S. recession coming or pending in 2013? What's your gut tell you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My gut tells me that they will come up with some level of, what I'd say, compromise on the immediate fiscal cliff that will cause the U.S. economy to be slower or stay slow &#x2013; at a slow pace in 2013 but not go in a recession. I mean we're real close to a stall speed right now. We're, as you all know, we're growing somewhere between 1% and 2%, and that in the U.S. economy is basically a stall speed. Yes, it's stepped down and I think that if I look at my order pace in North America probably in total, yeah, I would say that we probably had another weak month in October, but I don't have those numbers yet. I just don't &#x2013; I won't get them for another four or five days here. But my gut tells me right now that they will take some action to mitigate the dramatic drop-off of going to the fiscal cliff; however, if they don't, then you're going to have a dramatic pullback in a range even more relative to spending and that will create a deeper hole. So I don't think we're in a recession right now. I just think we're in a very &#x2013; what I would say low growth, 1% to 2% type of growth period at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As if things do deteriorate, what's sort of your thought process with respect to what buttons or levers you might like to pull? For example, would you want to be more aggressive in M&amp;A or share repurchase? I'm sort of &#x2013; I'm thinking of the context of prior recessions and your own experience as CEO of the company and so forth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think from a standpoint of &#x2013; I don't know &#x2013; in the short-term, we need to be more aggressive on &#x2013; if we went into recession. I mean obviously that would have a knock-on effect to the companies maybe you would have a better chance of making some of the acquisitions happen. That would be more of a second half 2013, early 2014 type impact. If we went into a downturn and obviously the marketplace got hit pretty hard and we had &#x2013; we generate strong cash, clearly, we could obviously ramp up that share repurchase. We would then fundamentally cut back on our &#x2013; what I'd call it even more of our discretionary spending which we right now based on a, say, 2% to 3% top &#x2013; underlying line growth rate you have &#x2013; you are starting to build-in to drive that so you can always go after that. But that's why we are going to keep things extremely tight here in the near-term because of the uncertainty relative to the &#x2013; what's going to happen here as what &#x2013; Congress get back working after the election. That's where we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>I need to wrap it up here. I need to go to another meeting. And so again, I want to thank everybody for listening today. Thanks for your support and thanks for really sticking with us as the year went on. I know it was not a normal year with a first half, second half, but the operations guys did execute very well and we finished the year at record levels of profitability and record levels of earnings. Unfortunately, we have a little impairment issue relative to the business, the one business. But as we talked about it, we will deal with that issue as we go forward here in 2013. And again, I want to thank all of the executives out there around Emerson for making this year happen. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>